<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1165275" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1022</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1">James Singh</participant>
      <participant id="2">David Hayes</participant>
      <participant id="3">Roddy Child-Villiers</participant>
      <participant id="4">Marco Gulpers</participant>
      <participant id="5">Julian Hardwick</participant>
      <participant id="6">Alex Molloy</participant>
      <participant id="7">Alain-Sebastian Oberhuber</participant>
      <participant id="8">Patrik Schwendimann</participant>
      <participant id="9">Warren Ackerman</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Parker</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jeff Stent</participant>
      <participant id="12">Alan Erskine</participant>
      <participant id="13">Nicholas Sochovsky</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker>
        <plist>
          <p>&lt;&lt;James Singh, Executive Vice President, Finance and Control, Legal, IP, Tax,</p>
          <p>Global Nestl&#xE9; Business Services&gt;&gt;</p>
          <p>Thank you, and good morning, everyone. Welcome to our half-year conference call.</p>
          <p>As usual, I'll take the Safe Harbor slide as read. As you know, our roadshow this year is not until September 1st and therefore today's presentation will be a little longer than usual.</p>
          <p>The first slide I would like to clearly demonstrate the high quality of our first half-year performance. Once again, the first half of 2008 has seen us deliver the Nestl&#xE9; model with above average -- above target organic growth of 8.9% and an EBIT margin increase of 60 basis points, reduced to 30 basis points by currency translation. This performance demonstrates our ability to deliver even in challenging times.</p>
          <p>Our Food and Beverage business continues to be the driver of growth and profitability, with organic growth of 8.9% and a 50 basis point improvement in the EBIT margin, reduced to 30 by the currency impact.</p>
          <p>The catalyst for this performance has been our Billionaire Brands continuing to show broad-based above-market growth. Key drivers included the execution of our Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy, our focus on Popularly Positioned Products, and our super premium businesses.</p>
          <p>The major corporate news in the first half was the announced sale of 24.8% of Alcon completed in July, the accelerated share buyback, and we expect to divest in 2008 businesses with sales of approximately CHF 1 billion.</p>
          <p>On the operational side, we continue to drive higher levels of efficiency and effectiveness, with a focus on speed and discipline in execution.</p>
          <p>Finally, by way of introduction, we have improved our full-year guidance, now with a higher organic growth forecast, now to be at least at the level achieved in 2007. We are also now expect an improvement in reported EBIT margin as well, as in EBIT margin constant currency.</p>
          <p>On the next slide are some key numbers not already mentioned. Absolute sales growth was 3.8% due to the impact of currencies. The EBIT improved 6.1% to give a 30 basis point improvement in margin, to 13.8%, or 60 basis points constant currency. The same 6.1% improvement in the net profit gave a 20 basis points improvement to a net profit margin of 9.8%, and earnings per share increased by 8.6%.</p>
          <p>We get so used to talking in basis points that it is sometimes worth reminding ourselves of the absolute numbers. After all, we create value for our shareholders not in basis points but in Swiss francs, which have appreciated considerably against other currencies.</p>
          <p>Sales increased by CHF 2 billion to 53.1 billion. The EBIT increased by 400 million to CHF 7.3 billion. The net profit increased by 300 million, to CHF 5.2 billion. This demonstrates significant progress despite commodity headwinds, negative currency effects, and a difficult economic environment in general.</p>
          <p>We believe that a key to success today is sustained profitable growth, rather than a high level of volume or of price, a mix between volume and price influenced by cost pressures and also impacted by how you are managing your cost base.</p>
          <p>Today's results demonstrate once again the strength of our Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy, but also the ability of our markets to adapt their execution to different competitive environments. To be simple, our markets aim to deliver profitable growth through a mix of rate and pricing. How they do that will depend on the environment in which they find themselves.</p>
          <p>As you know, the 1990s and the early part of this decade were characterized by raw material deflation. Not surprisingly, therefore, our markets were very focused on RIG [real internal growth]. The result was that our organic growth has been more weighted to RIG, which has averaged 3.6% over the last 12 years, than to price, which has averaged 2.3%. Today, however, our markets need pricing to help compensate cost pressures, which they must do, otherwise, their RIG would not contribute to profitable growth. In fact, the result would likely be unprofitable growth.</p>
          <p>With that in mind, let's look at the drivers of the first half year sales. You've seen the numbers in the press, so I'll just talk Food and Beverage. RIG was 3.2%, and pricing 5.7%, to give the same organic growth as the Group, 8.9%. The impact of acquisitions less divestitures was 3.3% positive. The main contributors to the acquisition number were Gerber and medical nutrition. The disposals were a basket of canned milk, private-label ice cream, frozen food, and pasta sauces.</p>
          <p>Currencies were 8.2% negative. The average exchange rates for key currencies are at the back of the presentation. Overall, Food and Beverage sales rose 4. -- 4% to CHF 49.3 billion.</p>
          <p>The make-up of the organic growth is slightly different from what some of you were expecting. The important thing is that it is -- it was comfortably above our annual target for the Group of 5 to 6%, and it outperformed by 300 basis points our 12-year average of 5.9%. This is a strong start to the year, which demonstrates the good momentum in our business.</p>
          <p>Let's go now to the EBIT margin development. Here is our usual visual on how the EBIT margin has progressed, half one 2008 versus half one 2007. Margins are ahead of consensus, though some of the line items differ a bit.</p>
          <p>I'll start with the cost of goods. In line with our guidance that we would see significant cost pressure, we have reported a 190 basis point increase. There are two negative influences. First, increased input costs, and we stick with our agricultural commodity guidance of approximately CHF 2.2 billion of additional full-year cost pressure on a 2007 sales basis.</p>
          <p>Second, we achieved a 20 basis point improvement in cost of goods in the first half of last year, and as you might remember, because we took pricing ahead of cost pressures, the 2007 comparative is therefore somewhat artificially low.</p>
          <p>There are, however, four positive influences: first, the effect of our efficiency programs; second, our pricing; third, our ability to leverage our fixed costs as we grow the business; and fourth, the mix evolution of our businesses.</p>
          <p>Next, distribution. These costs fell by 30 basis points. This is perhaps the most surprising number. There are a number of points that have enabled us to more than compensate an environment of  record oil prices. First, more than a third of the distribution costs are fixed, so we get a scale benefit from our growth. Second, efficiency benefits. Third, there is a mix effect, particularly as a result of the performance of water and ice cream compared to half one 2007. Fourth, the numbers reduced in basis points by the strong pricing element in our sales, as there is no commensurate increase in distribution cost.</p>
          <p>Next, marketing and administration. This has fallen by 190 basis points to 33.3% of sales. The split is that marketing is down 120 basis points, to 26.1% of sales, whilst administration is down 70 basis points, to 7.2% of sales.</p>
          <p>Our reduced spend as a percentage of sales should not surprise you, as I guess you are now familiar with this positive trend. I know that some people instinctively think that it is a bad thing when a company's marketing spend falls as a percentage of sales, and that this reflects poorly on the numbers. So let me tell you why I don't have any concerns over the quality of our profit performance.</p>
          <p>The downward trend in marketing costs as a percentage of sales reflect three key influences. These are: efficiencies, mix, and leverage.</p>
          <p>First, efficiencies. For example, the focus on our Billionaire Brands, and the drive for bigger, better, bolder innovation brings greater efficiency in marketing spend. Beyond that, we are achieving cost efficiencies in all areas. This is clearly a good thing, and we still have room for improvement. An example is that we are working with customers and others on mutually beneficial ways to improve our returns on trade spend.</p>
          <p>Second, mix. There are obviously influences, like near 40% organic growth in Nespresso, more than 20% organic growth of our PPP products, 11% organic growth in Nutrition, all with a little or no trade spend. 18% organic growth in emerging markets which tend to have below average trade spend. But there is also the benefit of our SKU rationalization program which continues. This targets underperformers, and these will most likely have higher than average trade spend.</p>
          <p>The third is leverage. We have quite significant fixed costs, as we are focused on controlling these costs. We therefore get leverage from our growth. Also, our organic growth is 300 basis points above our 12-year average, whilst our RIG is in line with the average. That means the difference is due to pricing, at over 5% in 2008. At a risk of stating the obvious, you do not increase your marketing spend in line with your pricing. Turning to our consumer-facing brand support, that is, our media spend and consumer promotions. This spend increased by 7% in constant currencies, reflecting significant activities in support of our brands in the market.</p>
          <p>To conclude on marketing, I am comfortable that today's results demonstrate that our people around the world are giving our brands the support that they need to win in the marketplace, and to deliver sustainable strong performance.</p>
          <p>Turning to administration &#x2013; administrative costs. The 70 basis point improvement is a good achievement. It reflects efficiencies and leverage of fix cost and the impact of our pricing. This remains a focus area for cost savings as part of our war on waste.</p>
          <p>Moving to R&amp;D, we continue to increase our investment. You may have heard that we are opening an R&amp;D center in China this year. The result of all this is a 30 basis point improvement in our reported margin, to a record first-half number of 13.8%.</p>
          <p>I have already mentioned the 30 basis point currency impact on the Group's EBIT margin. I am not going to detail the impact on the individual zones or product categories, but the biggest impact is on Zone Americas and those product groups with big profitable business in North America, such as Nutrition, Waters, and PetCare.</p>
          <p>In summary, on the EBIT margin, these are good, quality numbers. The EBIT margin is up 60 basis points before the currency effect, achieved while continuing to invest in the development of our brands and ensure the longer-term sustainability of the Nestl&#xE9; model.</p>
          <p>I'd like now to dive down into the business performance, starting with our total Food and Beverage business. We continued to perform well in all areas of the world, with Europe achieving 5.2% organic growth, Americas, 9.9% and AOA, 14.2%. Our emerging markets achieved organic growth of 18%, with the developed markets at mid single digit. These are strong numbers relative to their respective markets. Let's look at them in more detail through traditional primary reporting.</p>
          <p>This overview slide demonstrate the strength of our performance across the world, with everywhere, bar waters, achieving organic growth at least within our 5 to 6% target range. In addition, all the zones achieved higher organic growth than last year, as did Nestl&#xE9; Nutrition.</p>
          <p>Lets go into the details, starting with Europe. Zone Europe achieved 5.8% organic growth and 2.3% RIG. These are strong numbers, reflecting the continued improving performance of this zone. There were good first half performances in particular from Soluble Coffee, Confectionery, PetCare, and Culinary. By market, the Great Britain region was the standard performer, with high single digit organic growth, France, Germany, and the Iberian region are achieving higher organic growth than in 2007. Eastern Europe continued to deliver double-digit organic growth.</p>
          <p>Turning to the zone's EBIT margin, there was a 30 basis point improvement to 11.7%. The main contributors were leveraging our growth, as well as efficiencies in efforts to reduce structural cost.</p>
          <p>On the road show on the 1st of September. Luis Cantarell, the Executive Vice President for Zone Europe, will give you background into the key drivers of the zone's improving performance, as well as touching on some of the issues that seem to be in front of mind for you, such as the retail environment, private label, and demand trends. Hopefully, however, today's numbers have reassured you that our European business is in good shape and making progress.</p>
          <p>Next is Zone Americas. Zone Americas achieved 11% organic growth and 3% RIG. There were strong performances from PetCare, Shelf-Stable Dairy, and Soluble Coffee, as well as from the smaller categories such as Ready-to-Drink Beverages and Biscuits. Strong performances were recorded by Ice Cream and Frozen Food. In North America, the organic growth momentum was maintained, with the acceleration in PetCare compensating the slowdown in Ice Cream. Latin America continued to deliver very good growth and our RIG is strong.</p>
          <p>Turning to EBIT, there was a 40 basis point improvement in Zone Americas' EBIT margin. The main drivers were strong organic growth as well as &#x2013; at 11%, as well as efficiencies.</p>
          <p>Zone AOA reported 13.1% organic growth and 4.5% RIG. These are strong numbers, above the full-year 2007 level, for both RIG and pricing. The bigger categories all achieved double-digit organic growth. Major emerging markets such as Greater China, Indonesia, South Asia, Africa, and the Middle East are all double-digit, as are the Philippines and Malaysia.</p>
          <p>Japan slipped into negative territory after a positive start to the year. This is a reflection of the 2007 comparisons, and we expect to bounce back due to a strong launch program in soluble coffee including NESCAF&#xC9; Dolce Gusto, and in confectionery.</p>
          <p>I'd also highlight our Popularly Positioned Product strategy, known as PPP, affordable products for consumers at the base of the income pyramid. This will be a growing market as incomes increase and more consumers start to buy branded products for the first time. For the moment, however, PPP is proving to be an effective defensive strategy. Some consumers are migrating to Nestl&#xE9; PPP brands from Nestl&#xE9; non-PPP brands.</p>
          <p>Our PPP products are effectively a safe haven for our consumers as they migrate, offering them known quality, taste, and nutritional content. We recorded 40% organic growth in PPP in the zone in the first half. There was a good performance also in Zone Americas from PPP.</p>
          <p>Additionally, in Zone AOA, our Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy designed to benefit from a growing consumer awareness of the importance of healthy eating, is also showing strong defensive qualities, with consumers reluctant to give up on recognized brands that contribute to a healthy lifestyle. Equally, premium products are proving resilient with middle- and higher-income consumers who are able to cope with the rising cost of living.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Zone AOA's EBIT margin. It was unchanged relative to first half 2007. This was a good performance, given the significant cost pressures and a dilution from foreign exchange. They have done a great job capturing scale benefits from growth, working on their overhead structure, their factory cost, and trade spend efficiencies.</p>
          <p>Nestl&#xE9; Waters reported negative 1.1% organic growth and negative 3.1% RIG against a 10% organic growth comparative in first half 2007. This performance reflects a slowdown in the category in our bigger markets in part due to economic conditions and in part to perceived environmental issues around bottled water. That said, we expect to see an improvement during the rest of the year as new initiatives benefit performance.</p>
          <p>In North America, branded products lost share in supermarkets, but Nestl&#xE9; brands continue to do well en masse, particularly Nestl&#xE9; Pure Life in Wall-Mart. Nestl&#xE9; Pure Life is now established as a national brand and is taking share from regional waters. In Europe, the industry suffered in France particularly for the reasons already mentioned. Our emerging market businesses continue to achieve organic growth above 20%. The two Billionaire Brands, Poland Spring and Nestl&#xE9; Pure Life, achieve positive growth.</p>
          <p>The healthy hydration offered by bottled water is an ideal fit with the Group's Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy. The US market is growing faster than more mature European markets, and per capita is 20% lower than in Western Europe. So there continues to be significant long-term growth potential in North America, as well as elsewhere in the world.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Nestl&#xE9; Waters' EBIT margin. It would have been a tough year even if the only challenge had been lack of growth. Unfortunately, it is also challenged by increased PET and distribution costs. That said, the result would have been worse but for the good work on efficiencies across all lines -- all cost lines, and some excellent work by the PET buying teams, as well as our industry leadership in light-weighting bottles.</p>
          <p>Next is Nestl&#xE9; Nutrition. This division achieved 11.1% organic growth and RIG of 5.5%. Growth is in line with our target of 10%, and above last year. It was achieved despite SKU reductions as we merged portfolios between our existing and acquired businesses. We expect grow to stay around the target level at year-end.</p>
          <p>This strong performance was driven by outstanding growth in Infant Nutrition, double-digit in The Americas and AOA, and reflects positive share trends. Particularly impressive is that the RIG, not just the organic growth, is double-digit in many emerging markets, including China, Africa, South Asia, Brazil, Mexico, and others. Jenny Craig has returned to sustainable growth levels after an outstanding start to the year.</p>
          <p>The 20 basis point EBIT margin decline for the division is less than the dilutive effect of the acquisitions, Gerber and Novartis Healthcare Nutrition [Novartis Medical Nutrition]. They improved their EBIT margin, and are ahead of our merger expectations. The base business continued to &#x2013; its trend of improving margins.</p>
          <p>Other Food and Beverage achieved trend at 3.3% organic growth, and 20.3% RIG. The EBIT margin was up 150 basis points to 20.4%. There were good performances from all the constituents: Nespresso, Cereal Partners Worldwide, and Beverage Partners Worldwide.</p>
          <p>I'll summarize quickly on the primary reporting. Back in June, the financial market was focused on slowdown in the emerging markets. In July, it was focused on slowdown in Europe.</p>
          <p>What do our first half numbers show? In Europe, organic growth is almost twice the level at the end of last year. In Zone AOA and The Americas, it is significantly above last year. Nestl&#xE9; Nutrition is also ahead, with only Nestl&#xE9; Waters weaker.</p>
          <p>I am sure you recognize that Nestl&#xE9; is differentiated on several fronts: our chosen product groups, the strength of our Billionaire Brands, the productivity of our R&amp;D, the depth of our presence in markets around the world. Nestl&#xE9; is uniquely positioned, more resilient, with momentum and agility to progress in spite of the current conditions.</p>
          <p>Let's move to the product groups. Just even a glance at this slide reinforces what I've just said. It also gives you two key messages. First, Nestl&#xE9;'s strong organic growth performance is broad-based. All categories, bar one, are positive. Most are at high single-digit or double-digit organic growth.</p>
          <p>Second, regardless of one of our traditional high-growth businesses, Nestl&#xE9; Waters, being negative, our organic growth is at one of its highest levels ever. This demonstrates that Nestl&#xE9; combines the characteristic of a resilient defensive play with those of a potent growth play.</p>
          <p>Let's go into a bit more detail. Powdered and liquid beverages achieved 14% organic growth with 9.4% RIG. The product group's EBIT margin increased by 20 basis points, to 22.9%. All the categories reported double-digit organic growth, based on RIG that range from mid to high single-digit. Soluble coffee reached double-digit organic growth in The Americas and AOA, and high single-digit in Europe.</p>
          <p>Growth in Europe was broad-based across our portfolio, from value to premium NESCAF&#xC9;, as well as mixes. Successful launches in second half of last year provided momentum, whilst the re-launch this year of our freeze-dried premium and super-premium variants should provide continued impetus.</p>
          <p>NESCAF&#xC9; Dolce Gusto continued to develop well, with over 1 million machines sold, and new markets will be entered into later this year. In Asia, our NESCAF&#xC9; variants, NESCAF&#xC9; Protect and Body Partner, with functional benefits performed well.</p>
          <p>Powdered Beverages was double-digit in AOA and high single-digit in the other two zones, also helped the strong nutritional -- helped by the strong nutritional benefits of MILO and Nesquik. Nesquik accelerated growth in Europe is the result of the launch of lower sugar variants in line with our Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy. Nespresso's organic growth remained near 40%, and its first half sales reach 1 billion for the first time.</p>
          <p>Milk Products including Ice Cream achieved 12% organic growth, with RIG of 1.8%. The EBIT margin improved 70 basis points to 11.2%. The driver of growth was the milk business at about 20% organic growth, double-digit in all three zones. There was a solid foundation of RIG above 6% based on a strong innovation and renovation program. It was particularly strong in Latin America. Our business in North America, primarily COFFEE-MATE and CARNATION, continues to grow rapidly. COFFEE-MATE is benefiting also from its rollout into new markets, and is now in over 50 countries around the world.</p>
          <p>Turning to Ice Cream, overall the RIG moved from being about flat earlier in the year, to being negative. The US ice cream market is down, and has seen higher pricing and pack downsizing. In Europe, we've had an increasingly tough half, in part because of the 2007 comparisons. Our global shares have held up generally well, however, we had our top three markets, including the US, we have seen improvement there. The smaller businesses in this categories, Cereal Partners Worldwide and our JV with General Mills, achieved organic growth around 7%.</p>
          <p>Prepared Dishes and Cooking Aids reported 5.4% organic growth, with 0.9% RIG. The EBIT margin was down 70 basis points to 11.4%. The culinary business, mainly Maggi, was outstanding, with near double-digit organic growth and strong performances in all three zones.</p>
          <p>In Frozen Food, the slowdown in North America is related to different pricing strategies between us and our competitors. We have moved up prices for Stouffer and Lean Cuisine in response to raw material pressures. On the other hand, Hot Pockets is starting to see the benefits of the new strategy following the change in the team back in February 2007. Its growth is positive with seven new launches this year. We expect the North American Frozen Food to improve in the second half, driven by market initiatives that have already been launched. European Food and Chill businesses benefit from good performances by Wagner and Buitoni pizzas.</p>
          <p>Confectionery reached 7.7% organic growth, with 1.7% RIG. The EBIT margin has improved across all zones, and is up 180 basis points to 10.8% of sales. The UK market performed well, with double-digit growth and a good improvement in EBIT margin. This reflects the success of our focus on the Magnificent Seven brands as well as the resizing of our big facility in Europe. We are now going through a similar brand review in our big US business, and this has an impact on the product group's growth as we focus on fewer SKUs and brands.</p>
          <p>Elsewhere, the re-launch of KitKat in Western Europe has been a great success, demonstrating the importance of renovation in this category. KitKat is also performing well in emerging markets such as India, the Middle East, and Russia, and has achieved 15.4% organic growth globally.</p>
          <p>Our focus on Nutrition, Health, and Wellness saw the brands, the launch of Nesquik bars with calcium in Mexico, Chile, and Turkey, as well as the launch of Combina Com whole grain cereal bars in Brazil. Rowntree's and Bon Pari jelly ranges meanwhile continue to show good growth, benefiting from communication on 25% fruit content.</p>
          <p>On the EBIT margin, we expect a similar trend to last year, due to raw material pressures and seasonal effects.</p>
          <p>PetCare continues to perform well, accelerating to 10.9% organic growth, equally split between RIG and pricing. The EBIT margin declined 40 basis points, mainly due to raw material pressures in the US. The margin development will be better in the second half as we get the benefit of first-half pricing and other actions.</p>
          <p>There was double-digit organic growth in both Americas and AOA, and high single-digit in Europe. This is a strong broad-based performance, driven by key brands such as Beneful, which has 28% RIG, and Bakers with 18%. Many other brands, including super premiums like Fancy Feast and Gourmet, are in the 7 to 8% range. There was also a series of successful launches, such as Cat Chow Healthy Life -- Healthful Life in the US, which validate our Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy in this category. The business in Zone AOA is worth particular mention. Following a clean up on the product mix in 2007 and a decision to focus on six key markets, we're seeing very strong volume growth, as well as double-digit organic growth.</p>
          <p>Pharmaceutical Products, primarily Alcon, reported 9.6% organic growth with RIG of 8.5%. There were good growth and EBIT performances by the key constituents Alcon and Galderma. The gain from the partial disposal of Alcon will be booked in the full-year numbers in net other income. The contribution to minorities will increase to reflect the larger percentage of Alcon now held by shareholders other than Nestl&#xE9;.</p>
          <p>I'll say a few words about our Food Service business, Nestl&#xE9; Professional. It is not on this slide, as the sales of Nestl&#xE9; Professional are included in the relevant product groups. It achieved 7.6% organic growth, with RIG of 2.1%. This RIG is impacted by a global refocusing of the business' priorities and accompanying significant SKU rationalization program.</p>
          <p>Our AOA business is performing very well, a double-digit growth in markets such as China, India, and Southeast Asia. We are not seeing any material impact on this business from the economic situation. We are the largest branded manufacturer in this industry, but are only a small player in a large market. We therefore believe that we have sufficient new business opportunities to more than compensate for any economic slowdown.</p>
          <p>Finally, on the product groups, as I said, a brief glance at this slide shows you the strength of our portfolio today. That strength is also very evident in the performance of our Billionaire Brands. I've already covered this in my product group review. The picture here is very positive with over half of our Billionaire Brands achieving 10% and more, in terms of organic growth. In Nutrition, Milk Products, and Powdered and Liquid Beverages, all the Billionaire Brands are double digit.</p>
          <p>Our commitment to managing for the longer term means that our portfolio is only going to get stronger, as we continue to invest in our products and brands, in R&amp;D and innovation, in new distribution channels and business models. So whether you're a bull or a bear on economies, Nestl&#xE9;'s doing the right to create shareholder value in the shorter and longer term.</p>
          <p>Briefly, the P&amp;L down to net profit. There are one or two lines to comment on. Financial income is down, reflecting a lower level of liquidities. The benefit in taxes is a mix of lower rate of Alcon and a great -- and a greater rate to one-off tax credits, rather than one-off tax expenses, relative to the first half-year at the Group level. Overall, net profit increased by 20 basis points to 9.8%.</p>
          <p>I'll finish my review with a brief look at the financial position. Our operating cash flow is CHF 3.5 billion. This number is down from last year, reflecting increased working capital. This increase was primarily as a result of higher raw material cost. Additionally, there were increased stocks held as a part of our factory restructuring. These are only first-half numbers and there are some good reasons for this working capital performance, but I'm not satisfied at the current levels, and will be looking forward to a better outcome by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Our net debt position, seasonally high at the half-year, at CHF 25.8 billion, will reduce during the second half to below the level prevailing at the end of 2007. We are accelerating our share buyback, and we expect to spend about CHF 2 billion more by the end of 2008 than would have been the case if we were running it on a straight-line basis over the three year period. This means that by the end of the year, we would have completed about 13 billion of the CHF 25 billion program.</p>
          <p>I know that many of you will devote your energies to working out approximate Q2 organic growth numbers, and will draw your own conclusions. For me, however, energy's better spent, or rewarded, by focusing on our initiatives to drive sustainable profitable growth across the entire portfolio. In any given quarters, numbers are influenced by comparatives, the timing of marketing initiatives, and by events such as an early or late Easter. They do not necessarily signpost for us either a deceleration or an acceleration.</p>
          <p>What matters is that the first-half organic growth numbers, above level achieved through 2007 and comfortably above our longer-term targets, demonstrate that we have strong momentum in our business. Furthermore, they have been achieved whilst also achieving a 60 basis point improvement in our EBIT margins, reduced to 30 by currencies. High top-line growth combined with a strong EBIT performance, that's the Nestl&#xE9; model.</p>
          <p>We said in our full-year results press release that we have moved far beyond the traditional food industry, and that our success is more driven by our ability to innovate and launch new added-value products and services in line with our Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy, than it is by raw material prices or the economic environment. I think today's numbers demonstrate the truth of that statement.</p>
          <p>To end, we have slightly raised our outlook. We expect organic growth to be at least at the level achieved in 2007. We also expect to achieve an improvement in our reported EBIT margin, as well as in constant currencies.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over you to Roddy to take your questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, your question-answer session will now begin. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Before we start the questions, just a correction. I just wanted the audience to know that Roddy is here also. I'll take the questions. Thank you. Any questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Our first question comes from the line of David Hayes from Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David Hayes from Lehman. Two questions, if I can. Firstly, at the risk of doing what you just said, in terms of breaking down the first and second quarters, just focusing on Nutrition. It looks like the RIG there went from about 10.2% in the first quarter down to 1.3. Quite a big drop for an area that perhaps you might expect to be stronger from a volume mix perspective. Can you just talk us through whether there is any specific drivers in the second quarter there and whether you'd expect the shape of that to revert back in the second half?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is on cost savings. Should we assume that the cost saves have been achieved pretty evenly through the year? So I'm guessing, based on some previous comments, you had CHF 500 million-ish of cost saves in the first half, and then similar for the second half. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David. I would say, with respect to Nutrition, the anomaly was more or less Q1. The previous quarters were all around 10% organic growth. We are now around 10%. That makes the first half-year another strong period for Nutrition. We expect the year to end at around 10%. The business is in great shape, and it's improving towards the 10 to -- 10% organic growth top line, and progressing towards the 20% EBIT target.</p>
          <p>In terms of your question on cost saves, I would say that our cost saving program is on track to achieve the CHF 1 billion that we had indicated before, but more heavily weighted towards the -- slightly more heavy weighted towards the end of the &#x2013; second half, more or less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Just going back to the Nutrition part, in terms of the shape of Nutrition, we should assume that 10% is achieved with kind of a skew towards price rather than RIG? So RIG kind of 2, and price 8? That kind of shape? Is that fair to say, in terms of comparing first quarter versus second quarter shape?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I wouldn't -- I wouldn't split -- get into splitting the elements of organic growth. I would say that the business is on track to deliver about 10% organic growth for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to be clear, not all the savings go into the COGS line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. The next question comes from the line of Marco Gulpers from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, all. Two questions, if I may. The first question is on, what are your expectations with respect to pricing for the Group in the second half? Do you still need to recover further pricing into the second half?</p>
          <p>The second question is again on the nutritional business, if I may. You are expecting indeed organic growth around the target for fiscal year '08. Could you still take us through what happens with respect to the regions, then, on Nutrition? Where did you see the slowdown occurring in the second quarter versus the first quarter? And also, provide a bit of an update on Jenny Craig and Performance Nutrition. Where was the slowdown specifically coming from? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say, with respect to your first question, we're trying to emphasis the point that the focus is on profitable growth, versus volume or pricing. We believe the key to our success is profitable organic growth, and depending on the circumstance, the mix will change, as you have seen during the course of the last 18 months. So we will not give you any kind of split between pricing and RIG for the second half.</p>
          <p>On Nutrition, I think I would say we have seen very good performance in most of the key markets, with some slight softness in France and Germany. Other than that, I think the business is doing very well, in a very balanced way.</p>
          <p>On Jenny Craig, I think we started the first quarter pretty close to 40%, and that's not a performance that we expect from this business on an annualized basis. So the slowdown was anticipated to a more or less, trying to achieve to a level more sustainable for the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A follow-up question, if I may, on -- have you seen any inventory build-up ahead of price increases in your business within Nutrition? That's the last question. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to be clear on this, we do not see Q2 as a slowdown. We see Q1 as an unsustainable level of growth, and Q2 a normalizing effect on the Nutrition business. This is not a slowdown trend, it's simply a normalizing effect, and we think we are around the level now in terms of organic growth where we'll be at the year-end, around -- around the 10% target level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for you question. The next question comes from the line of John Cox from LAM Banking. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I have a couple of questions for you. Just to start on some of the trends you're seeing. You're saying that premium is holding up pretty well, but you're obviously reporting some sort of downtrading into PPP. Can I take that to mean that there is some pressure on the middle ground, as it were, in some of the markets? And I wonder if you can just talk it through, particularly maybe in Europe and the US.</p>
          <p>Now the second question is on inventory. I think previously you've talked about potentially an absolute decline in working capital. Obviously today's figures -- that was not a case. Just trying to get some guidance for the year as a whole in &#x2013; on working capital. Should we be plugging in that sort of 1 billion-odd additional that seemed to be -- that you seem to have pointed to in H1? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks John. In terms of trends, where our PPP offers our consumers an opportunity to move from the traditional Nestl&#xE9; products to PPP, for us that's a &#x2013; that's very positive, in the sense that we get the benefit from any trading-down that is taking place there.</p>
          <p>But, inasmuch as there are some elements of that, what we are noticing is that new consumers are the key driver to the growth in our PPP products. So yeah, there are areas where there is a degree of trade-down, but I don't think it's a material to really describe it as a trend as such. What we are happy about is the fact that we have the business model to allow our consumers to do that.</p>
          <p>On the inventory, there are two elements to the inventory. First of all, there is the cost impact on our inventories. Now, you will recognize that last year this time, the full effect of the costing that took place over the last 12 months just began, at the beginning of perhaps April or May of last year. So there was virtually no acceleration of the cost effects in our year-end inventory &#x2013; or six months inventory last year.</p>
          <p>This year, we're seeing 12 months' impact of those increased prices in our inventory levels. So there is going to be increased cost in our inventory. Now, there is a temporary build-up, because in some areas, for example, in Europe, where we are restructuring one of our major manufacturing facilities, we have had to do a temporary build-up in some areas to facilitate those changes. That is the area that I would like to see, that we will work very hard to reverse in the second -- in the second half.</p>
          <p>What I must say, however, is that if you look at our total inventory, which as I said is significantly influenced by cost increases, the total inventory is lower by 10 basis points relative to our sales and where they were last year. So there is an element of the inventory build-up where we have to be diligent during the course of the next four or five months to remove from the current pool.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just as a follow-up, can we roughly say then maybe half of that inventory build is caused by the higher commodity prices, etcetera, and half from this &#x2013; the restructuring in the industrial network? Is it roughly half/half, or is it maybe two-thirds costs and one-third on the factories?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't -- I won't be able to give you that information. What I could tell you though is that the element that relates to the build-up will not be there at the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just add one thing on the PPP? John talked about pressure on the mainstream business. In the press release we tell you that the PPP products overall grew about 20%. These are obviously primarily in emerging markets. We also told you that our emerging market business has grown overall about 18%, so clearly we're achieving a lot of growth outside PPP in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Also, we've also told you in the past that our PPP business has profitability in line with the non-PPP products in the same categories. So we don't see this as anything other than a positive trend, and it demonstrates that we're doing the right thing strategically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Julian Hardwick [ABN Amro]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. I just wonder if we could go back to the marketing development? Would you be able to help us by isolating the impact of some of the trends that you commented on as lying behind that particular lever, and how much came from &#x2013; as a result of mix, and how much was a reduction in trade spend?</p>
          <p>And consumer marketing looks as though it is still down meaningfully in basis points terms. I mean, I would guess, certainly we are talking about something like 60 basis points decline. Is that broadly right? And within that, how much -- what was the evolution of media spend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. Thank you, Julian. First of all, our marketing, what we call marketing, incorporates several -- is a bundle of marketing-related cost. It includes our trade spend, it includes our advertising and consumer spending, it includes our marketing administration, our marketing departments, sales forces, etcetera. So there is a basket of activities that are in that pool, and that is why it is nearly 26% of sales.</p>
          <p>What I would say is that I'm convinced, we are convinced, that we are spending in a very focused way, very creative way, to support our brands. And I could assure you that the activities to do that are increasing. So specifically with respect to what we call advertising and consumer promotion, our activities are increasing, but we are finding better ways, creative ways, to get better value for money, and we are very focused on what brands, where and how and when, we support.</p>
          <p>Now what I could also assure you is that we'll continue to drive for efficiencies in this entire bundle of cost. And so, what I'll &#x2013; on one hand, I would like to assure you that we continue to drive for efficiencies, and this is no exception, this year is no exception. But on the other hand, we are not -- we are fully supporting our brands to make sure they remain competitive. We did several launches of new and innovative products. So in the end, we continue to win in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Julian, I don't know if you missed the number, but we said on the call that our consumer-facing spend is up 6% in constant &#x2013; sorry, 7%. Even better. Even better, 7% in constant currencies. And I would just say again, that this whole talk about percentage of sales, when you got 5 -- over 5% pricing, it's the wrong comparison. It's completely the wrong comparison. There is no increase in your marketing spend because you got 5% pricing in your sales line. This is not the right comparison to be making.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. I take your point on that. But this is a relative gain and some of your peers are increasing their consumer marketing as a percentage of sales. So I mean, if you're reducing yours, there may be good reasons, as you say, in terms of improving efficiencies. But it would be helpful to have some sort of number, just to sort of &#x2013; to support the reassurance that you have given us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Julian, is -- I can't speak for our peers, but what I could say is, for us, it's not how much you spend, it's what you get for it. And clearly, you're looking at the performance of our larger brands. I mean these are outstanding performances by our key brands that drive the performance of this business. So we are very happy with where we are and what we continue to do to drive that competitiveness of our brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would even go further and I'd say, if it hadn't been for all the marketing support we put behind our brands, we wouldn't be able to get the 5% pricing. We clearly are giving our brands the support they need.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I just ask a question about &#x2013; and I appreciate you don't want to talk about the &#x2013; how pricing and the volume split is going to evolve in the second half, but can you just talk to us about the scale of further price activity that you need to take to offset your commodity cost increases, as far as the second half is concerned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that &#x2013; this is a very general statement &#x2013; is that we have implemented to a large extent most of the pricing that we need to take this year. However, we continue to take pricing, because as you would have seen in the marketplace, commodities continue to go up. And we must take price increases to &#x2013; or find a way to offset the commodity cost, because that represents the quality of the performance of our business. So I would say most of our pricing actions are today in place, but I do not want to tell you that we are not going to take further price increases this year. We will, if we think that that's the right thing to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that would probably suggest, as we roll through the second half, that the contribution from price is not going to accelerate from where we are in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that's &#x2013; I suppose that's your conclusion, Julian, so....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, would you care to comment on my conclusion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've already said we're not going to break this down into two pieces, but I mean, your conclusion seems to have a good degree of logic to it. There are categories, and in PetCare, we took pricing in June, for example -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; so that will clearly work its way through the second half of the year. It's very category-specific, what we're doing in terms of pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for you question. The next question comes from the line of Charlie Mills from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, it's Alex, in fact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick one on input costs. At your seminar in June, you talked about stabilization of input costs in the second half. The index which you show in your presentation, of course that's spot prices, also looks still as though it's off nicely. And I think comments earlier in the year, you've said you expected input cost pressure to be more in the first half than in the second half. Is that still the case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think what we said to you with respect to agricultural commodity costs, we still maintain that for this year the impact, the additional cost to our business this year will be about CHF 2.2 billion, slightly heavily weighted to the first half. But I think the focus will be on the annual amount. We believe we are &#x2013; that's the number we will be pretty close to at the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And just a follow-up on the marketing questions that have been asked. Does the way you guys account compared to peers have quite an impact on these percentage-of-sale comparisons? In other words, if peers reduce their promotional activities, we won't see it, because it's netted off on sales, but with you guys, you see it in lower volumes and lower costs in marketing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. There is a major difference between &#x2013; as I said, in our bundle of marketing costs is all our trade promotions. And I think, when we talk about promotions, we need to be &#x2013; we need to differentiate for all purposes, what is trade and price promotions, and what are consumer -- brand and consumer promotions? Our trade promotion, yes, it's &#x2013; that's &#x2013; we are gaining efficiencies, as I explained in the first part of the conference call, what are some of the drivers of that, the mix and the different parts of the world, different businesses, etcetera. So that's why we are showing significant efficiencies, due to many activities, many actions, mix efficiencies, etcetera, in that part, and it's having an influence on the total numbers we're reporting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And just a final quick one. On that increase in &#x2013; 7% increase in constant currency on what I think what you call consumer-facing promotions, what proportion of that 26% is that? I think you've indicated in the past that pure media spend is about 5% of sales. Is that what you mean, or is it a larger bundle of costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good try, Alex. We haven't gone there before, but a good try. That 7% is on consumer promotions and media spend, but we haven't broken out what the -- how much that is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One thing you could be reassured, Alex, it's not coming down. It's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. Our next question comes from the line of Mr. Alain Oberhuber from MainFirst. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jim. Good morning, Roddy. Two questions on Europe, mainly here in Western Europe. Have you had &#x2013; have you already seen a trading down from the consumers? And on the other side, in the US, as the economic environment is even worse there, have you seen a trading down in the US? And in Europe again, private-label increase there?</p>
          <p>The second question is about the Dairy organic growth mix between price and volume. It was heavily based to price increases. Are you expecting, for the second half, that that price volume mix will change more for the favor in volume, as we have seen powdered milk commodity prices to come down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Alain, thanks, and let me just deal with the first question. They are -- our business reflects progress overall, in all our brands, in both our mainstream products, our PPP, our super premium -- and our super premium products, and also our out-of-home business. But in, I would say, in one or two categories, there is an evidence of -- there is evidence of trading down.</p>
          <p>For example, in the US and in Western Europe in particular, I would say there is a bit of trading down in the Water segments, as people move to more affordable water products from the mainstream or premium-priced products. And that is why we have lost share in the US in retail, and marginally in retail in Europe. However, the offset to &#x2013; the partial offset to that is Nestl&#xE9; Pure Life, where the brand is growing at a &#x2013; in high double-digit, where people are moving now to Nestl&#xE9; Pure Life, and we have had remarkable performance in the mass merchandising area, especially Nestl&#xE9; Pure Life, in the US at Wal-Mart. So there is an evidence of trading down in the Water business.</p>
          <p>Also in the US, I think frozen food is more of a value story in these times, and what we have seen is that, particularly in that category, the frozen food category in the US, consumers have trading down, not to lower quality -- high quality, but lower price points. And that has impacted the performance of our Stouffer's businesses in that market. Now we have implemented changes and adjusted our price points, and we're starting to see some good results in that area. So, yes, there is &#x2013; there are evidences in some areas of trading down, but generally, as you've seen, our business is in pretty good shape.</p>
          <p>Now in Dairy, here again we're not going to get into the mix of price or volume, but I think most of the dairy prices, I think the cost impact we have seen manifest themselves, and therefore, we have taken significant pricing. That's why pricing is so high in this category. I would think pricing will more or less abate itself, in terms of new pricing action, for the next half. But please bear in mind that the pricing that has been taken will continue for the year, so....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alain, you mentioned private label, and obviously Luis will talk about this in more detail on the road show, and I've seen some statistics that show that private label has gained about 0.2%, I think it is, share points, from an organization called Planet Retail. But you can see from our performance, both our RIG and pricing is above last year's levels, so we're clearly not being impacted by that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. Next question comes from the line of Patrik Schwendimann from ZKB [Z&#x3CB;rcher Kantonalbank]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrik Schwendimann, Z&#x3CB;rcher Kantonalbank. Good morning, Jim, good morning, Roddy. What do you see as the biggest risks for 2009 for Nestl&#xE9;? That's my first question. And secondly, regarding the tax rate you had in the first half, at 24.2%. What's your best guess here for the full year for that &#x2013; for the tax rate? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I would say, I do not see, and I think we do not see, any catalyst for change with respect to the external environment. I mean there is the expectation that things will start to improve early next year. But the risks that prevail in our business today are those that we have to manage, and with the expectation that it would likely continue well into next year. So what we're doing, as we've said earlier, is that, we have a good defensive posture, but also a very aggressive growth stand, and I think we are able to demonstrate that we can make progress, based on the momentum we have in our business, on our ability to deal with the different things that occur outside of our control. So, the risks you see today are -- we are expecting those to continue well into 2009.</p>
          <p>In terms of our tax rate, I would say the tax rate for the first half is influenced primarily by tax saving measures implemented by Alcon, and to a lesser extent, at the holding company level, last year we had some tax expenses, this year we have minor tax credits, so a company of our size, you will see that tax credits this year versus expenses in 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is the best guess for full year -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The actual -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>-similar to last year, which was 25%, roughly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, last year-end was 25.3%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Now, for the whole year, I would say, given the impact of the proceeds from the Alcon disposal, that our tax rates will be high teens, but below 20%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And without the Alcon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And without -- the underlying tax rate will be, I would say, about 27, about 27%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. Next question comes from the line of Warren Ackerman from Dresdner. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Warren Ackerman here at Dresdner. I was just wondering whether we can go back to the administration costs within the P&amp;L and the 70 basis point improvement. I was just wondering, Jim, whether you could give some examples of what you've actually done to improve that line, and what you actually think the optimal administration costs as a percentage of sales could be for Nestl&#xE9;, i.e., should we be expecting to see an ongoing benefit from that line?</p>
          <p>And second one is a very &#x2013; a point of clarity really, on the share buyback. What is the reason for the acceleration this year, and is it simply a pull-forward from '09 to '08, or could the 25 billion number in totality be exceeded? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Warren, thanks for your question. On admin cost, this was one area, as was said before, it's an area where we needed to experience better performance. Remember last half-year performance, Paul made that comment. Now we have always focused on managing our admin costs, but with the growth rates that have been occurring, I think we might have slipped a little.</p>
          <p>What we are doing now, we are targeting the growth of our admin expenses well below the organic growth target, so we -- as continue to grow, we will continue to target lower levels of evolution of our fixed cost. And we are doing that in admin and in other areas where there are fixed cost. So I would say that we will continue to experience a positive trend in this area. We don't really have a target. Obviously the absolute level will depend on the size of our business as we progress over the next years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But presumably, you get diminishing returns. I mean, would something like the 5% admin to sales, would that be realistic, or would there be structural constraints to get to that kind of number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well a lot of it has to -- will depend on the mix of the business, too, you know, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're &#x2013; and that's only the product mix, but the regional mix. But I would say we will continue, we -- our focus is to make sure that our admin expense does not grow at the same rate as our organic growth. That's -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And share buybacks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The share buyback, I mean, the point here is that, we had said before that the CHF 25 billion would be acquired evenly over the 36-month period. And what we're saying is that, given the acceleration or the increase level of acquisition of the buyback program, we will, at the end of this year, be closer to 13 billion out of the 25, versus if you took a 36-month running average, you will be about 11 billion. So that's where we get to the 2 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, no, we are not -- it is part of the 25 billion, and yes, if we do this, we will likely finish earlier than the 36 months. And when we get there, we'll have to look at &#x2013; look and see what needs to be done beyond that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you remind me of what your authority is on the share buybacks? Do you have the authority, if you wanted to down the line, to increase that, or would you need to get more share &#x2013;  would you need to get approval for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; this is a matter for the Board, and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a legal limit, which I think is -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; 15%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>10%. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Warren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. Next question comes from the line of John Parker from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Did you give a figure for organic growth for emerging markets overall? Did I hear you, or if not, can you do that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was 18%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was 18%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>8...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>18. 1 -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>18% for organic growth in the emerging markets. Thank you. And would you care to venture a RIG pricing split for that 18%, or presumably pricing is somewhat higher, but are you able to give any sort of guidance there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think as &#x2013; John, with due respect, I think we will stick to our original guidance in terms of total organic growth. No, unless &#x2013; I don't think -- the key here is that we are making excellent progress in the emerging markets, as we are in developed markets, five mid single-digit organic growth numbers in the developed market is an exceptional performance in these times.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Sure, sure. Just wonder why you're a little bit reticent about giving any sort of second half guidance on the RIG pricing split? I mean this is something you've been relatively happy to do at times in the past. What's kind of holding you back here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not holding back. We're just being, I think, sensitive to the different economic environment in which we currently operate. The pricing is driven by what's happening in areas that we don't control, especially in pricing, in commodities, in fuel oil and fuel by-products. So our focus is really what is the character of the growth we need to drive the Nestl&#xE9; model, the business performance? Therefore, trying to get into a discussion as to what is price and what is mix, as a guidance is, I would say, is difficult and perhaps not value-added.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I see. So it's &#x2013; because it's not predictable in the current climate, but your message is, what is predictable is delivery of the overall numbers. Fine. Understood. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, John, it's also &#x2013; it's very complicated. I mean, when we have, as we said, PetCare with evenly split RIG and pricing, and then you've got Dairy with a very heavy weight to pricing, and every other category has its own different mix, and they're all evolving, and then out will pop the average, which is the Group number. But it's a very difficult thing for us to forecast accurately, even in times of low volatility, and this is now high volatility today. So I think there is not much to be gained from it, particularly when the focus is on profitable growth which is the combination of both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your questions. Final question comes from the line of Jeff Stent from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just sort of following on from that, on your focus on sustainable profitable growth, do you have any sort of volume thresholds for the Group as a whole, or by category?  I'm just thinking about, as we move forward, as you sort of play the balance between securing volume and having to increase price to maintain/increase margins? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff. Our guidance is on organic growth. We've said as a company, our longer-term objective is to deliver sustainably 5 to 6% organic growth. We are not likely to go back to the area where we were targeting RIG as an objective, as we said in the earlier part of the discussion. In times when agricultural materials were in a deflationary &#x2013; at a deflationary level for an extended period of time, we had to focus on making sure that our volume evolution was robust. Today, we do not believe that we're going to get into a deflationary agricultural commodity environment anytime soon, and therefore, we have to focus on profitable growth, and that's &#x2013; I think that's the essence of our discussion this morning, that our focus is on driving growth profitably with a combination of volume and price, recovering increases in commodity costs, or other elements of cost that are having a significant impact on our cost base.</p>
          <p>So that's why we do not want to be drawn into a discussion of pricing versus volume. I think we want to focus on total growth, and total profitable growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just add -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your question is a very good question, and the way that we manage the Group, this issue is handled locally in the markets by the market heads, and then by the individuals running the categories in those markets, and is their job to find the right balance between pricing and RIG market shares and profitability, to ensure they deliver on their top-line and bottom-line targets that they've got, and to do it in a way to protect the sustainable profitable growth of the business in that market. And that's what they're paid for, and that's what they do. Okay? And it's &#x2013; that's how we run here. We don't run it from the top down, and set some sort of volume target as you called it, or volume threshold, as you called it. Okay? It's a very &#x2013; this is very much devoted to the markets where they are able to execute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question. Next question comes from the line of Alan Erskine from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Alan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just have a question on &#x2013; it's really a clarification. Jim, when you talked about the margin guidance for the year, didn't &#x2013; was my interpretation right, that you said that you now expect an increase in reported EBIT margin? In other words, that previously you'd been confident of an improvement in constant currency, but now you're confident of also an improvement in reported. And if that interpretation is right, can I just ask, as a follow-up, why if, as you say, the restructuring is going to be more weighted to the second half, but the input cost inflation was more weighted to the first half, would it not be reasonable to expect that you should do better in the second half in terms of margin evolution, than in the first half? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we didn't talk about restructuring in the second half. But be that as it may, what we have said in terms of our guidance is that we are now saying that our EBIT margin will improve in reported -- on a reported basis, as well as in constant currency. You will recall that our previous guidance, as we have always done, is in constant currency. And you have seen, in the first half, that we have delivered on both. And therefore, the first half performance has given us the confidence to now come to you and say that we expect, not only an improvement in constant currency, but also an improvement in reported margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just ask &#x2013; I think consensus is for 30 basis points improvement for the full year, which I would assume is on a reported, not a constant currency, basis. So are you comfortable with that consensus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well let me &#x2013;  I think the consensus was about right for the first half, on both organic growth and EBIT margin. We have slightly outperformed the EBIT margin. But it varied from what we reported on the points in between. So, inasmuch as we believe the consensus was about right for organic growth in EBIT, there were differences in the line items between sales and EBIT, and therefore, sure that you will all want to review your numbers after today's discussion.</p>
          <p>A number of preview notes highlighted that the second half will be less impacted by input cost than the first. Some even described it as a sweet spot. When we coined the phrase "a sweet spot" in the first half of last year, it was to describe the time lag before the rising material cost impacted our cost of goods. That time lag is there, also, when raw material start to fall. So we don't believe in the second half sweet spot, nor do we see a catalyst for any improved economic environment in the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>However, as I said, we are confident in our own performance, which, as we have demonstrated today, is enabled by Nestl&#xE9; differentiating qualities and strategy, and its speed and discipline in execution. Our guidance is clear, therefore. We have good momentum, and will achieve organic growth at least at last year's level. We will also deliver an improvement in reported EBIT margin, as well as in constant currency.</p>
          <p>So based on this analysis, I would like to conclude therefore by saying that I believe that our full-year EBIT margin and our organic growth will not be materially different from the current consensus. However, I need to say that we do not see any catalyst that will change, that what has been projected currently &#x2013; what has been projected currently.</p>
          <p>I hope that answers your question, Alan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes &#x2013; and just a -- so basically what you are saying is that, you're not going to see a reversal of the very beneficial circumstances you had in the first half of last year, that the second half of this year is going to be another challenging year, but one that you're comfortable with in terms of what market expectations are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Currently, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question. Next question comes from the line of Nic Sochovsky from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi guys. Just a couple of points of clarification as well. The Forex hit to margins of 30 basis points negative in H1. Assuming current exchange rates, would that be the similar sort of hit you're expecting for second half?</p>
          <p>And then a second point, you talk a lot about your agriculture cost being at 2.2 billion. What about when you take account of packaging and oil-related costs, what sort of figure should we be looking for, because I imagine they're set to still inflate, H2 on H1. Could you give us a sense there as well please, for more of the total cost inflation figure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just on the foreign exchange, Nic, we believe that the currency impact in the second half will be significant, albeit slightly lower than the 30 basis points that we experienced in the first half. So -- because the Swiss franc remained one of the strongest currency in the world. And in a lot of situation, we are seeing that continuing, and I think it will hold up for the balance of the year. But we believe that there will be a -- the impact will be marginally lower in the second half.</p>
          <p>On agricultural commodities, as we've said before, the annual impact on agricultural commodities based on 2007 sales level, will be about 2.2 billion. There are of course other increases, based in other areas, packaging, PET, and so on. But I think our major focus, we &#x2013; plus our efficiency program, I think if &#x2013; we are managing those parts very well, and also the agricultural commodities as you have seen with respect to pricing. But I would not want to get into the details of packaging and other elements at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I was --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have obviously taken it into account in our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Then just finally, the billion of savings that you're talking about, those efficiency savings, does that include the efficiency savings you're seeing within the marketing  line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. All over the company. The entire &#x2013; all lines of our P&amp;L.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. There are no further questions in the queue. I will now hand you over to Mr. Singh.</p>
          <p>&lt;&lt;James Singh, Executive Vice President, Finance and Control, Legal, IP, Tax,</p>
          <p>Global Nestl&#xE9; Business Services&gt;&gt;</p>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for your questions. It is clear that our focus on value creation is working, evidenced by profitable growth. We had margin expansion, levering scale and scale for greater efficiencies in all areas of our operations.</p>
          <p>The Billionaire Brands' strong performance is driven by R&amp;D-influenced innovation and renovation. Excellent all-around performance, organic growth in emerging markets at 18%, mid single-digit in developed markets.</p>
          <p>Investing where growth is, for example, an R&amp;D center in China, close to 1 billion consumers, and with access to top local talent. Increased cash returns to our shareholders through the accelerated share buyback program. All these, and more, contributing to sustainable value creation, and to making Nestl&#xE9; a reference for financial performance.</p>
          <p>With respect to performance outlook, we have guided to higher levels of performance with organic growth at least at the 2007 level, with EBIT margin improvement, both reported and in constant currencies. Of course, all these add up to progress to another year of delivering the Nestl&#xE9; model.</p>
          <p>I would like to thank you very much for your interest in Nestl&#xE9;, and good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that will conclude the Nestl&#xE9; 2008 Half-Year Results Conference Call, and you may now disconnect. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>