<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1401332" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>40448</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President, Global Corporate Accounts">Loren Singletary</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman, President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Merrill A. Miller</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Executive VP &amp; Head-Media Relations">Clay C. Williams</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Dahlman Rose &amp; Co. LLC">James D. Crandell</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Robin E. Shoemaker</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Kurt Hallead</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Chase Bank NA">David Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Simmons &amp; Co. International">William A. Herbert</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the National Oilwell Varco 2011 Second Quarter Earnings Call. My name is Dawn, and I will be your operator for today's call. And at this time all participants are in a listen only mode. Later, we will conduct a question and answer session. Please note that this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Mr. Loren Singletary, Vice President, Global Accounts and Investor Relations. Mr. Singletary, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dawn, and welcome everyone to the National Oilwell Varco's second quarter 2011 earnings conference call. With me today is Pete Miller, Chairman, CEO and President of National Oilwell Varco; and Clay Williams, Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Before we begin this discussion of National Oilwell Varco's financial results for its second quarter ended June 30, 2011, please note that some of the statements we make during this call may contain forecasts, projections and estimates, including but not limited to, comments about our outlook for the company's business.</p>
          <p>These are forward-looking statements within the meaning of the Federal securities laws based on limited information as of today, which is subject to change. They are subject to risk and uncertainties, and actual results may differ materially. No one should assume that these forward-looking statements remain valid later in the quarter or later in the year. I refer you to the latest Forms 10-K and 10-Q National Oilwell Varco has on file with the Securities and Exchange Commission for a more detailed discussion of the major risk factors affecting our business.</p>
          <p>Further information regarding these as well as supplemental financial and operating information may be found within our press release on our website at www.nov.com, or in our filings with the SEC. Later on this call, we will answer your questions, which we ask you to limit to two in order to permit more participation.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn the call over to Pete for his opening comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Loren, and welcome everybody to our second quarter 2011 earnings conference call. Earlier today, we announced earnings of $481 million or $1.13 per fully diluted share on revenues of $3.51 billion. This profit is an 18% increase over both the second quarter of 2010 and the first quarter of 2011. We are very pleased with these results and believe they reflect a preference for our products and services around the world and a continuing operational excellence of our employees. Clay will expand upon these numbers in a moment.</p>
          <p>Additionally, we announced a record capital equipment order intake of $2.96 billion to give us a quarter ending backlog of close to $8 billion. In the past two quarters, our new order intake has exceeded $5 billion. I would like to thank our worldwide sales force for their outstanding efforts in achieving these record order intake results.</p>
          <p>On a more somber note, I would like to offer our condolences to our Norwegian friends and coworkers on the loss they've suffered Friday at the hands of a madman. The thoughts and prayers of everyone at National Oilwell Varco are with the people of Norway today.</p>
          <p>At this time, I'd like to turn the call over to Clay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Pete. National Oilwell Varco produced excellent results in the second quarter, posting revenues of $3.5 billion and earnings of $1.13 per fully diluted share for the period. Our quarter included transaction charges of $4 million pre-tax and excluding these earnings were $1.14 per fully diluted share.</p>
          <p>Operating profit excluding transaction charges was $712 million or 20.3% of sales; higher than we expected due to the strong margin performance of Rig Technology which offset expected seasonal margin declines from Petroleum Services &amp; Supplies and Distribution Services stemming from breakup in Canada and flooding in the Bakken area.</p>
          <p>Margins in these two segments also faced some additional mix challenges which I will detail in a few minutes but nevertheless performed well to meet the rising needs of our customers. Strong demand in the North American shale plays and good international activity contributed to solid results for both segments.</p>
          <p>Like others in our industry, we have been witnessing a steady migration within North American shale activity. Gas prices have remained range bound in the $4 neighborhood since 2009, below the average for the 2003 to 2008 period, leading to levels of gas drilling about 40% below their 2007, 2008 peaks. However, declining gas rigs have been more than offset by growing levels of oil-directed drilling which has risen sharply to levels not seen in 25 years, fueled by sustained high crude prices.</p>
          <p>Together with rising deepwater production from the Gulf, the 400,000 barrels of oil per day flowing from shales have resulted in the first increases in U.S. oil production in a generation. The great migration of activity from gas to oil has created new opportunities for our operations along with new challenges as we reposition our assets and workforce to continue to meet the pressing needs of the petroleum industry.</p>
          <p>As a result, both Petroleum Services &amp; Supplies and Distribution Services segments are expanding rapidly into new geographic areas to build out the infrastructure required of us. The Bakken region of North Dakota and Southern Saskatchewan, the Utica and Marcellus shales across the upper Midwest and the East Coast, the Eagle Ford shale of South Texas are pulling workers and iron into new frontier regions while oil productive regions of old, like California, the Rockies, the Permian Basin of West Texas are experiencing new growth.</p>
          <p>Our service operations are busy investing and repositioning to be where our customers need us, adding solids control equipment and generator sets to new field locations, opening tubular inspection and drill pipe repair facilities in growing regions, and investing in our large fleet of downhole drilling motors and bits.</p>
          <p>Likewise, our factories for products needed for oil production in these regions are expanding and reconfiguring to meet the evolving needs of our customers. For example, we're adding a new coil tubing mill, which should start up in the fourth quarter, to produce larger two-inch and two-and-three-eighths inch diameter coil tubing to accommodate lengthening laterals in these horizontal wells.</p>
          <p>We're investing in new artificial lift technologies for liquid wells. We're expanding our fiberglass pipe plants to offer composite pipe solutions to operators dealing with rising water production and corrosion challenges. We have invested in new well service pump technologies and machinery and additional flow line of products for pressure pumpers within our Mission Product line. We are also benefiting from strategies undertaken during the downturn to improve our supply chain and efficiency in areas like drill pipe manufacturing, where we have shifted production of tool joints to lower cost areas in Latin America.</p>
          <p>PS&amp;S and Distribution Services also continued to expand overseas. For example, Tuboscope coating and inspection facilities in Brazil, Mexico, Abu Dhabi and Oman; Star Fiberglass pipe plants in Brazil and Oman; new Mission and well site services operations in Brazil and Russia; new XL Systems facilities in Africa; expansions in Dubai and Saudi Arabia; and new drill pipe manufacturing capabilities in Abu Dhabi.</p>
          <p>In short, we are preparing for growth in the face of a massive industrial transformation. The application of new horizontal drilling and hydraulic fracturing technologies that turn shales into productive oil and gas reservoirs, which will play an enormous role in the world's energy equation through the 21st Century.</p>
          <p>This transformation is steadily gaining footholds internationally. As entrepreneurial petroleum producers and national oil companies apply technologies refined in the shale laboratories of North America to promising basins on other continents. NOV intends to play a major role in this important transformation. And speaking of massive industrial transformations, another parallel effort is underway to find new sources of energy from the earth's oceans. With 60% of our planet covered by deepwater, our industry will require a massive fleet of deepwater rigs to explore and produce petroleum well from this exciting frontier area.</p>
          <p>Exhibit A is NOV's record level of orders for rig equipment during the second quarter. Clearly our customers are beginning to share our longstanding view that many, many new rigs are required to advance the deepwater effort. And they're investing heavily in the tools required to develop these offshore resources.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter, Rig Technology segment booked new orders of $2.963 billion, up 30% from the first quarter of 2011 and quadruple the second quarter a year ago. Bookings included drilling equipment packages for eight drill ships, six jack-ups and a large production platform. None of the rigs were for Brazil.</p>
          <p>Revenue out of backlog totaled $1.390 billion, yielding a quarter-ending backlog of $7.7 billion, up 26% sequentially. As of June 30, 84% of this backlog was for the offshore and 16% for land. 84% of the orders are bound for international markets and 16% for domestic markets. For the remainder of the year, we expect approximately $2.8 billion of the June 30 backlog to flow out as revenue. Another $4.3 billion is scheduled to flow out in 2012 and a $600 million balance in 2013.</p>
          <p>Overall, the segment gained modest pricing leverage through the first half of the year in the 6% to 8% range as we face rising costs for steel and other inputs. Numerous buy-ins like hydraulic fittings and transmissions are very tight, with long lead times...</p>
          <p>Competition has been tough, but we have been fortunate to win a good number of new orders, owing to NOV's comprehensive offering of leading technology and skillful execution.</p>
          <p>We've also been able to maintain good progress billing schedules on these long-lived projects to minimize our own working capital investments in the projects and improve our capital efficiency. By increasing our customer's investment in the projects as construction proceeds, these progress billings mitigate the risk of potential cancellation should we face another sharp downturn like we did in 2009. As a reminder, we face cancellation of only a very small fraction of our orders following the downturn two-and-a-half years ago.</p>
          <p>Recent orders have been concentrated in the most experienced shipyards, those that constructed most to the offshore rigs bought between 2005 and 2008. Specific yards had developed high levels of expertise in the construction of jackups in Southeast Asia and the construction of semis and drillships in South Korea.</p>
          <p>Other yards around the world who dabbled in offshore rig construction a few years ago have landed comparatively few orders recently, highlighting an evolving market preference for highly experienced yards for the execution of these complex projects.</p>
          <p>Building an offshore rig is a much more complicated to undertaking than, say, a tanker or a freighter. The legs for a jackup, for instance, require tight tolerances and complex assembly operations. And inexperienced yards missed deadlines over the past few years as they've learned the hard way just how tough it is to build an offshore rig. Real-world experience in building rigs over the past six years have made drilling contractors smarter about the selection of their vendors.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, competition among highly-experienced Korean yards for floaters has been intense. These yards have been active building a variety of industrial vessels, tankers, freighters, LNG vessels in addition to a smaller drilling rig business for many years.</p>
          <p>In 2008, the credit crisis and economic downturn slowed orders for all vessels. And these yards saw their backlogs for all vessels declined significantly as they work through their large backlogs. The recent uptick in demand for drillships is offering a way for the Korean yards to refill their backlog holes, and they are hungry and aggressively pursuing any and all drillship projects.</p>
          <p>But in comparison to Singapore yards, they have much bigger holes to fill. As a result, their pricing leverage has been limited thus far while the jackup builders in the Far East have met with more success in achieving price increases on new jackups. Both regions are demanding progress billings more consistent with our own and don't appear to be offering the 20% down, 80% at delivery specials seen several months ago.</p>
          <p>Slack capacity in South Korean yards coupled with strong desire to replace tanker and freighter backlogs with rig orders have prompted these yards to sign up for aggressive build schedules and tighter deadlines, generally shaving 10 months or so off the construction schedules of just a few years ago. NOV's order inquiries for offshore drilling equipment packages have continued to be strong through the first few weeks of July, and we hope to post another strong order quarter in Q3.</p>
          <p>We're continuing to work closely with various shipyards, including EAS in Northeast Brazil, the Atlantico Sul yard, to participate in the Petrobras orders. We're also continuing to invest heavily in Brazil to support the growing fleet of offshore rigs at work there and to help meet local content goals for the new rigs.</p>
          <p>Our long-term FPSO outlook remains very strong, given that we are tracking dozens of potential projects around the globe. While second quarter FPSO turret orders improved sequentially, overall they remain slow, which we believe will persist through the next few quarters due to the very long cycle time required to sanction these projects.</p>
          <p>FPSO orders pivot on E&amp;P decisions to move forward on billions of dollars of development CapEx, not just for the FPSO, but also for the development drilling programs, subsea wellheads, manifolds, and riser expenditures. And those decisions typically require extensive reservoir modeling, FEED studies, economic forecasting and financing. Predictably, they don't go as fast as rig building decisions.</p>
          <p>So, in the meantime, we are busy integrating our APL business into NOV and assembling a broader array of NOV products into an FPSO package concept.</p>
          <p>The land rig market appears to be getting stronger. We've got 13 large complete land rigs this quarter, along with individual components for dozens of other newbuild land rigs, mostly targeting shale plays in the U.S and Canada. Our outlook for orders remains bright with the reemergence of three- to five-year term contracts for high capability rigs for shale plays in North America. And we expect international orders for land rigs for the Middle East and the Far East to increase in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Our backlog for land equipment jumped 22% sequentially to $1.246 billion due to a combination of strong land rig sales and high demand for well intervention and stimulation equipment. Demand for coil tubing units, pumpers, blenders, cryogenic nitrogen equipment is surging for pressure pumpers, serving the many active shale plays across the U.S. and Canada. And we were pleased to add frac sand handling products through our acquisition of <mark type="ph" /> Apco (14:45) during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Overall, our outlook is bright. NOV will continue to play a critical role in the massive industrial transformations at work in the world's oil and gas industry. The retooling of a land rig fleet with modern technologies to develop new shale plays, the replacement of an aging jackup fleet, the build-out of a fleet of floating rigs to develop deepwater resources, and the supply of a myriad of technologies and products to enable horizontal directional drilling and hydraulic fracture stimulation in a safe, efficient manner.</p>
          <p>With unequaled worldwide scale and scope, strong cash flow and financial resources, and most importantly, the best and the most professional workforce in the industry, National Oilwell Varco is exceedingly well-positioned to drive transformation.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to our operating segment results.</p>
          <p>NOV's Rig Technology segment generated revenues of $1.894 billion in the second quarter, up 18% sequentially and up 13% compared to the second quarter of 2010. Operating profit was $517 million yielding an operating margin of 27.3%, up from 26.2% in the first quarter and down from 30.4% in Q2 of last year. We had previously forecasted margins to move down in the second quarter. However, the period benefited from lower costs than we expected specifically on drilling risers we are building for the many offshore rigs the group is constructing.</p>
          <p>Late last year we began to transfer drilling riser fabrication operations to our Ho Chang operations in South Korea in order to improve proximity to the shipyards and reduce manufacturing expense. Our analysis this quarter based on actual results so far showed much better cost improvements than we had anticipated.</p>
          <p>Since most of our large reconstruction projects are booked on a percentage of completion revenue recognition model, we adjust our estimates of future costs periodically and continuously reconcile to expect future margins on all projects. This quarter's adjustment resulted in a margin pickup and higher revenue as we reconcile to slightly higher expected margins in the projects overall.</p>
          <p>Excluding this catch-up effect, Rig Technology margins would have declined slightly from the first quarter. We are pleased that future drilling riser production and future margins are expected to benefit from these operational cost reductions. But nevertheless, we continue to face modestly declining margins over the next couple of quarters due to winding up of the many high margin offshore newbuild projects won during the order ramp-up from 2005 to 2008, and the comparatively low levels of orders in lower margins seen during 2009 and 2010.</p>
          <p>This mix effect is seen in our year-over-year second quarter comparisons which showed a 310 basis point margin decline and only 4% operating leverage or flow-through on a 13% sales gain. This mix effect was less pronounced in going from the first quarter to the second quarter of 2011 and helped by the riser margin pickup. The group's sequential flow-throughs were 33% as a result.</p>
          <p>Record orders for this quarter are rapidly replenishing our backlog with solid projects which we expect to begin to increase margins of 2012 after they drift down for the next couple of quarters.</p>
          <p>Most importantly, these projects will be executed by the best rig equipment manufacturing team in the business, who routinely innovate new ways of building equipment efficiently and profitably <mark type="audio gap" /> (17:58), to continually seek low-cost, high-quality sources of products across our expansive network of facilities and post-manufacturing margins rarely matched in our industry.</p>
          <p>Solid operational performance prompted revenue out of backlog to jump 24% sequentially to $1.390 billion. During the quarter, we delivered six floating rigs and commissioned one jackup, and the commissioning operations continue on 28 rigs in 14 different shipyards. Non-backlog revenue of which 82% this quarter was aftermarket spares and services, improved 4%.</p>
          <p>Organic expansions along the Gulf Coast, Brazil, Dubai and the North Sea, acquisitions in Singapore and India and the growing installed base of NOV rigs should position NOV's ascending service infrastructure for our own-made BOPs to underpin rising aftermarket revenues in future periods.</p>
          <p>Looking into the third quarter of 2011, we expect Rig Technology revenues to be flat or up slightly with operating margins in the mid 20s.</p>
          <p>The Petroleum Services &amp; Supplies segment generated total sales of $1.359 billion in the second quarter of 2011, up 7% sequentially and up 32% year-over-year. Operating profit was $249 million and operating margins were 18.3%.</p>
          <p>Compared to the second quarter of last year, operating leverage or flow-through was a solid 34%. Revenues improved $94 million from the first quarter, but operating profit was up only $3 million sequentially, and margins declined 110 basis points from very strong first quarter levels. The sequential performance represented only 3% flow-through due to a number of factors.</p>
          <p>First, the impact of the seasonal breakup in Canada reduced revenues compared to the first quarter and high detrimentals, mostly affecting our downhole tools and wellsite services product lines. The non-recurrence of high first quarter solid control equipment sales into North Africa and the Middle East and continuing unrest affecting all operations in that region further pressured Q2 results. These sales declines were offset by, first, higher revenues from recent acquisitions at lower margins; second, modestly lower margins on increased sales in Mission, drill pipe and XL Systems owing to mix; and third, lower margins on higher wellsite services revenues due to startup costs for new locations and flooding in the Bakken region. Finally, Tuboscope posted a very strong quarter with sharply higher coating and pipe inspection revenues and strong flow-throughs.</p>
          <p>Domestic mix of revenues for the group increased from 50% in the first quarter to 54% in the second quarter, due to strong demand from the liquids-rich shale plays, while Canada declined from 10% to 7% of the mix, as expected due to seasonal breakup. International grew slightly but the international mix declined from 40% to 39% during the quarter. The group continues to battle inflationary forces for steel, polymers, epoxy, labor, and rent, particularly in the emerging shale areas, and several product lines are <mark type="ph" /> trimming (21:00) start-up costs for new operations across these. But, most are also reporting increasing traction on pricing, typically in the mid single digit range to offset creeping costs.</p>
          <p>Our outlook remains very positive for the segment. We expect revenues and margins to improve both in the third quarter as we emerge from the breakup in Canada, strong activity across the shale plays in the U.S. and offshore markets in the North Sea and the Gulf of Mexico slowly improve. Mission is seeing steady adoption of premium ceramic liners by drillers and strong demand for its growing offering to pressure pumpers and for positive displacement pumps. Sales and rentals of downhole drilling motors should continue to grow with the opening of our new motor reline facility in Houston and some amazing test runs for our new Helios cutter, PDC bits underpin our improving outlook for downhole tools for the second half of the year. Several other units are expected to benefit from new facility startups later in the year and into 2012 including Tuboscope, Fiberglass Systems, Quality Tubing and XL Systems.</p>
          <p>Turning to Distribution Services; second quarter revenues were $423 million, up 3% from the first quarter and up 16% from the second quarter of 2010. Operating profit was $26 million or 6.1% of sales, down from $28 million or 6.8% of sales in the first quarter of 2011. Compared to second quarter of 2010, operating profit doubled, and operating leverage was a solid 22%. Regional mix swung sharply for the group with Canada down 28% sequentially and accounting for only 14% of the segment second quarter mix, compared to 22% in the first quarter. Nevertheless, the Canadian operation was able to maintain good profitability despite the large breakup effect. U.S. and international sales both grew nicely sequentially, with international operations helped by our acquisition of Capital Valves in the U.K. and accounted for 52% and 34% of the segment's mix respectively. U.S. margins were down slightly with new DSC start-up costs in South Texas, Pennsylvania and the Mid-Continent. Mono Industrial sales margins were down in Argentina and Europe but the group foresees improving results later this year as international sales of artificial lift products began to grow significantly later in the quarter. As a result, we expect Distribution Services revenues in the third quarter to move up nicely on higher artificial lift sales, recovering Canada, and continued rig activity driven growth across the U.S. We expect margins to move back up into the high 6% range.</p>
          <p>Turning to National Oilwell Varco's consolidated second quarter income statement; SG&amp;A increased $9 million sequentially, due to higher incentive compensation accruals but declined as a percentage of sales to 10.7% as compared to 11.6% in the first quarter and 11.5% in the second quarter of last year. Operating profit excluding transaction charges grew $84 million sequentially and $118 million year-over-year. Interest expense declined $5 million sequentially, due to our second quarter $200 million venture repayment. Other expenses improved $12 million sequentially due to improvements in foreign currency exchange expenses. Equity income in our Voestalpine joint venture was $10 million for the quarter, down $3 million from the first quarter, due to lower volumes and unfavorable mix as less OCTG and more line pipe was sold. We expect equity income to decline slightly in the third quarter due to our annual summer maintenance shutdown in August.</p>
          <p>The tax rate for the second quarter was 32%, about flat with the first quarter, and we expect the tax rate for the remainder of the year to be in the 32% range. Unallocated expenses and eliminations on our supplemental schedule was $80 million in the second quarter, up $12 million from the first quarter due to higher tax consulting expenses, legal costs associated with acquisition, and intersegment eliminations. Depreciation and amortization was $138 million, up $3 million from the first quarter. EBITDA excluding transaction charges and Libyan asset write-downs was up $94 million sequentially to $858 million or 24.4% of sales.</p>
          <p>National Oilwell Varco's June 30, 2011, balance sheet employed working capital excluding cash and debt of $3.5 billion or 25.2% of annualized sales, down $211 million from the first quarter. This is due primarily to rising orders in our Rig Technology group. Total customer financing on projects in the form of pre-payments and down payments, billings in excess of costs, less costs and excess of billings was $876 million at June 30. Accounts receivable increased $92 million, and inventory rose $186 million sequentially on higher revenues and acquisitions, largely offset by higher accounts payable and accrued liabilities. Cash flow from operations was $912 million for the second quarter, a sharp improvement from the first quarter due to the working capital items I mentioned and strong levered cash flow of $618 million. CapEx increased $34 million sequentially to $113 million due to high expenditures on new facilities, primarily within Rig Technology and Petroleum Services &amp; Supplies. We expect CapEx for the full year 2011 to be a little over $400 million as we pursue a number of expansion opportunities.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we spent $208 million on two acquisitions and acquired two more businesses within the past few weeks, bringing our total to six so far in 2011. This does not yet include the announced acquisition of Ameron, which we hope to close in the fourth quarter, which will push our acquisitions to over $1 billion in 2011.</p>
          <p>We filed for regulatory approval last week and are enthusiastic about the new products Ameron will bring are fiberglass and composite fluid corrosion control solutions and FPSO offering within our PS&amp;S group and new infrastructure and industrial products to our Distribution Services group. We look forward to welcoming Ameron's very talented team to our organization soon.</p>
          <p>Finally, to wrap up our balance sheet discussion, NOV's cash balance was $3.4 billion at June 30, 2011.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn it back to Pete.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Clay. I just want to make a couple of more brief comments and as I was thinking about things that I wanted to say today, really a lot of it is just an instant replay from what we've talked about the last couple of quarters. Needless to say, the big theme in the United States continues to be the shales and even though the gas &#x2013; natural gas is lower priced today, the rigs that are coming off the gas wells are moving to the oil wells, so we're seeing a very nice consistency in the rig count right now. So, I feel very, very good about what we're doing in the shales. And, obviously, all the products that we have out there lend themselves quite well to shales, whether you're talking of our downhole tools or bits or rigs or drill pipe and everything that we have in there. So, I'm very encouraged that this going to continue on.</p>
          <p>The other thing we've talked a lot about is the rig bifurcation. No question that the best rigs are getting to work, and there's also no question you're going to continue to see rigs being built. You saw the bump in land rigs that came out this quarter for us. We're very pleased with that. And, you continue to see the very high activity in both the jack-ups and the high-end drillships and we think this is going to continue for a period of time. There are a lot of options that are still out there. We feel very good about our position in the market and we like what's going on. The reason we feel very good about it, and here's what I think the real theme is that's important for us over the next couple of years, and that's technology. When you start to take a look at the technology that we're putting out there, the interesting thing too is you really have to compress the timeframe with which you're introducing this new technology. I'll give you an example.</p>
          <p>We needed to have a much bigger, stronger top drive, and we were able to develop our TDX-1250 in less than a year and this allowed us to have redundancy, much higher torque, did a lot of different things to it. Today, we have sold and have on order &#x2013; delivered already 12 and have another 34 on order and continue to sell these. We can press at it for less than a year. That's really what our goal is when you talk about technology. We're doing a lot of things today about remote monitoring, our eHawk System, our BlackBox. Probably the biggest push we have going on is in control systems. We're the logical producer of control systems. We have everything on the surface. We have everything downhole, so we're the people that we think are going to really be able to come to market with the primo control system that's very important for everybody.</p>
          <p>We're doing a lot in APL today. Clay mentioned what we're doing there with the integration of that acquisition and we're very excited about some of the things that we can do now with LNG vessels that are coming into the marketplace. When we take a look at some of our PSNS businesses, we're looking at some modular fracing systems.</p>
          <p>We're coming out with some new frac pumps in our Mission Group. We're doing an awful lot of downhole with new bits, we have new downhole motor designs, we have a vertical drilling tool that we think is going to be very well received in the marketplace. So, a lot of neat things going on in technology, and we really think that's going to be a driver as we look to the future.</p>
          <p>Finally, I believe our investments are paying off. As we take a look at we did the last few years, Clay mentioned it earlier, we put an awful lot in the infrastructure growth. We put a lot of things in places like reline facilities for downhole motors.</p>
          <p>We basically doubled our capacity and the capability of doing that. We look at our new fiberglass pipe plants. We look at the things that we're doing and other areas in pipe coating and the like. And we think these investments that we were able to make because of our strong balance sheet in '09 and '10 are really going to be paying off as we look to the future.</p>
          <p>Our M&amp;A, Clay mentioned the operations and the companies that we've closed on this quarter, we feel very, very good about it. We think there's still a lot of good opportunities out there and with the balance sheet that we have, we're going to have the opportunity to do things that other companies cannot do.</p>
          <p>So, all-in-all, we like where we are right now. We think it was a very good quarter. For those employees at NOV that are listening in, I'd like to thank you very much for everything that you've done and the hard work. And we'll continue on with this, and we like what we're seeing for the remainder of this year and as we go into 2012.</p>
          <p>So, at this point, Dawn, I'd like to open it up for any questions that our listeners might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Jim Crandell from Dahlman Rose. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great quarter, Pete. Congratulations to you and the management team at NOV.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim. We appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Clay, could you go into a little bit more detail on the revenue and margin forward outlook at the capital equipment business? I think I understood what you said about the riser business but from here is the outlook for the next, let's just say, two to four quarters or two to three quarters, one of slight margin erosion?</p>
          <p>And on the revenue side, I guess it was my understanding that in the early stages of booking revenue that you book mainly the engineering revenue and that that comes on very slowly while you're running all backlog and equipment deliveries. And so, I was expecting that to sort of unfold fairly slowly for the next two to three quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the revenue picture, Jim, the second quarter benefited from more quick return items and higher completed projects or completed contracts items that helped drive that. So, a lot of smaller well servicing equipment and the like. The margin surprise that I referenced on my comments at the beginning really came out of this reshuffling of our drilling riser production infrastructure when we moved much of that over into the Eastern Hemisphere to &#x2013; in this very large facility that we acquired a couple a years ago in Korea.</p>
          <p>And the way it works, that impacted mostly our percentage in solution projects in a way that the accounting of that works is that we will continually book towards our expected total cost of the project. And a lot of these big offshore rigs that we're working on have riser as part of their cost, part of the products that labor <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:38).</p>
          <p>As we discovered the magnitude of cost savings, which is much larger than expected, what we had to do this quarter then is reconcile towards a little lower margin across those projects. So, what that does in the quarter is have a pretty good lift in margins in Rig Technology that you saw, which was a bit of a surprise.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, in future periods, we do expect better margins in Rig Technology from kind of where we were previously. We're still going to trace the path that drops us, I think, down into the lower 20% range. But not quite as deep a downturn as we were looking at last quarter based upon these efficiency gains. And so, that's our expectations for the next couple of quarters.</p>
          <p>And then in 2012, getting further out, as these new projects flow in, I think that'll improve the margin picture and we'll start to see margins go back to that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Clay, what did you say about the ramp in revenue from here? Would you expect a more modest ramp over the next two to three quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next couple of quarters, I think we're expecting a total of $2.8 billion in revenue out of backlog, which is in line. We have the possibility, Jim, of adding some additional revenue with new orders coming in in the second half of the year. They might push Q4 up a little bit more. But as we're getting deeper into 2011, the opportunity to materially push up our revenue guidance on -- revenue out of backlog becomes more and more limited. So, most of the orders that we're taking in now are going to impact 2012, 2013 revenues much more significantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my second question, Pete, this one is for you. How do you feel about additional deepwater newbuilds besides what already has letters of intent and what's already in your backlog? And I was wondering if you could address three separate categories; one, your traditional customers; two, Norwegian customers; and three, Brazil, and particularly in light of maybe Samsung and Hyundai sort of filling up for the next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Jim, I think that really almost all levels that you just mentioned are really fairly positive right now. I think the &#x2013; you've got the traditional Western contractors which have kind of led at this  most recent order intake surge and I think those guys, a lot of them are continuing to talk about as soon as they get a contract for one, they're going put another one in the queue. So, I think you're going to continue to see that happen.</p>
          <p>You're seeing a re-emergence of some of the Norwegian players. I think that's going to continue to be a very positive deal. And then of course you mentioned Brazil, and I think Brazil while it's been a long and arduous journey, that is one that I think will probably come to fruition here pretty soon.</p>
          <p>The reality is when people think about it, they look at the number of those people on the rigs that are being built and they see this historically big number. But the reality is, when you look at the world that's covered by 60% deepwater, it's really kind of no pun intended, just a drop in the ocean. And you really are going to need a lot more of these rigs. So, we feel very good about it.</p>
          <p>Now, let me also talk about when you talk about Hyundai and Samsung and capacity, remember when we were building these back in '06, '07, '08, they had a lot more tankers in those shipyards. So, they still have the same quay size, but now they have a lot fewer tankers. So, I think the capability of them taking on more is probably a little bit more than people realize at this point. So, all in all, kind of a long-winded way to say we're still very bullish on the opportunities out there on newbuilds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One more quick question, if I could, Pete, do you see a broadening out of the ordering of new land rigs in the U.S. from the traditional Helmerich &amp; Payne, Nabors, Patterson, Precision to other companies in terms of spec newbuilds or just newbuilds from other customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a little bit, Jim. I think that you're starting to see some new entrants into it and I think that's being driven probably by operators going out there and saying, hey, we'd like to get some more people out here doing this, and we'll put these rigs on contract. So, we are &#x2013; we're seeing a little bit of that. I don't think it's huge at this point but it is something that we're experiencing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, Pete.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Robin Shoemaker from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and congratulations guys. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Robin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Clay, in terms of the nearly $3 billion of new orders, could you give us any color on number of drillships and jack-ups that are in that mix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We booked eight drillship packages and six jack-ups in the quarter, and we also had a pretty good sized production platform rig in there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's see, so, it was a pretty big step-up, I guess it was six drillships in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then eight. But that still leaves- I mean, do you &#x2013; your current count of ships that have been ordered if we go back to that October of 2010 start date ...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We booked, in addition in the fourth quarter of last year, I think two drillship packages. So that gets us to 16 drillship packages that we booked since that start date, Robin. So, given that there were &#x2013; the number of ships ordered is in the high 20s, and then there is a lots of options beyond that, I think there's still quite a bit of work out there.</p>
          <p>Also, too, I'll reiterate the second quarter's orders did not include any orders for any of the drillships for Brazil. And so, that's still out there in the mix and we're working hard hopefully to land some of those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. That actually was my second question was on Brazil, where they've clearly designated a shipyard. They've got the financing in place for the first seven rigs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think you're expecting possibly a third quarter award for those rig packages?.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I learned a long time ago not to get too specific on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...the timing of signing contracts in Brazil. It's been an arduous lengthy process, but there have been a lot of good developments. Petrobras did set up Sete, the entity to own and finance these rigs. Sete has executed a contract with EAS on the next seven drillships. And I think a day or two ago, the revised five-year CapEx plan for Petrobras was approved. And so, I think it looks like things are moving ahead there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now that you gave us the figures on drillships, it looks to me like what you must have gotten is really like the full amount that you would potentially get from the drillships and jackups to add up to that nearly $3 billion. So is that correct that you kind of got the full...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd say the level of participation on both was very high and very good. And just as a reminder, NOV, if we sell everything we can into sophisticated drillship; we can exceed $200 million in orders. In the prior cycle, we were up over $250 million. And then in jackups, $50 million is kind of a good &#x2013; the harsh environment, highly capable jackup rig. But, actually, what we've seen here lately is big jackup rigs where we've exceeded the $50 million package in a couple of instances.</p>
          <p>So, overall, I think again the marketplace is seeing the value that NOV adds to these new rig construction projects and I think our participation thus far, has been very, very strong and we need that to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Robin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Kurt Hallead from RBC Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to follow up first on the commentary about the guide points on PSS as you go into the quarter. Some of those maybe around semantics but when you talk about an increase and going out into the third quarter, we've had a few of the other players in the business so far suggest that the revenue growth vis-&#xE0;-vis rig count in the North American market or U.S. market could be two times that of rig count.</p>
          <p>I know that your businesses are not quite as service-intensive so there may be some differential. But if we think about rig count growth being up double-digits on a sequential basis, you would have to think that PSS would at least match that. But is there any other things that we need to consider to think that revenues could grow faster than rig count?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the good part about our business is we do participate in sort of higher growth areas, things like coiled tubing technologies and some pretty high performance drilling motors, bits, and so I think we have a good mix of businesses within PS&amp;S to participate in whatever rig count movement we have happen. Some of the specific things, Kurt, that I referred to my comment had to do with seasonal issues in Canada, a much more magnified breakup, I think, this year given the strong levels of activity in Q1.</p>
          <p>And then that fell off pretty sharply, we lost 400 rigs this year in Canada. And last year, I think, the rig count only went down about 300 rigs. And so much bigger impact this year, and exacerbated by flooding in the Bakken region which have affected both the Saskatchewan and North Dakota. So, going into Q3, we expect all of that to turn around and that was really kind of the basis for our guidance for PS&amp;S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, I guess just coming back to it. So the view for NOV would be, you're not quite at the same two times rig count growth as your serviced companies, but you could do better than that &#x2013; you could do better than rig count growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Kurt, we've never been quite that specific on quantifying our forward-looking guidance. I'll say that the things that are positively influencing our outlook for Q3 or our rising level of activity, the turnaround and seasonal breakup in Canada and the fact that we are getting traction on pricing, which is improving our outlook.</p>
          <p>Some of the other, like pressure pumpers and other service companies that you maybe referring to may be getting a little more pricing leverage or certain segments particularly than pressure pumping are experiencing a little more pricing leverage that we've been able to get. Nevertheless, our outlook remains pretty strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just the prior question there, you've referenced kind of what the potential ticket could be for NOV on a deepwater drillship, for example, in a high-end jackup, you mentioned that the peak for a drillship was somewhere around $250 million. Now, I guess it's still under that. And then, I guess, land rigs are still, what, $15 million to $20 million for the U.S., and if you go internationally, it could be maybe $40 million to $50 million depending on the requirements on the land rigs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's pretty accurate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. That's it for me. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from David Anderson from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, gentlemen. Good morning. A question on drill pipe for the newbuilds, looks like you've got about 21 floaters, 10 jackups coming in the second half of the year, another 14 floaters and 15 jackups in '12. How many of those have ordered drill pipe? And kind of what are some of the trends you're seeing in the timing orders? Clay, I think you and I talked about that some of these guys are &#x2013; because they don't have contracts, you're pushing out further towards delivery days, can you talk about that? And as I come through, I would expect those margins to be incremental to PS&amp;S, am I kind of in the ballpark in my thinking here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We're keeping an eye on that world very, very closely and know that there are a lot of premium landing strings and drill pipe strings to be ordered by that fleet of new rigs, and it'll be delivered here over the next few years. That's something our sales group within drill pipe pays very close attention to.</p>
          <p>And what we're witnessing is some hesitancies &#x2013; not hesitancies, quite not the right word, but I think they're seeking the oil and gas companies, and drilling contractors to seeing a little more clarity on the specific programs those rigs were going to go out and drill.</p>
          <p>The blossoming of all these different size, weights and grade and technologies within drill pipe means that you probably need to be a little bit more thoughtful about the selection of the type of drill pipe. And so, what we think maybe gaining some of these orders is our drilling contractors and their E&amp;P customers waiting to get a little closer to the spudding of the wells and thereby seeking to optimize the selection of the pipe that's going to go on to these rigs.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, you look at &#x2013; the rig fleet that's coming on line, they're going to have to order &#x2013; those rigs don't work without drill pipe, and so we foresee a lot of drill pipe to be ordered and that will be favorable to the mix. That's some of the best margin pipe we sell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was what I thought, I mean, could this potentially be kind of a 4Q upside surprise event, or is this more like a first half '12?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd guess '12.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>'12? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On a different subject, it sounds like you guys are kind of calming people down about the &#x2013; a little about the FPSO market, in terms of how this all kind of playing out, but you mentioned about APL integration, can you just kind of tell us where you stand? I know you're talking about shifting some of the manufacturing, the cost control, the overall strategy. I assume this is still going to be the transition year for APL and then next year, we should start seeing the orders.</p>
          <p>So could you comment on that, and also you had mentioned kind of an offering from NOV in terms of the FPSO package. Is there other things around the turrets that we're not familiar with or is the turret separate from, say, kind of your more traditional packages you'd have on like, I guess, cranes and the other metal bending things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me take the last part of that question first and that really is the NOV offerings on that. What we've got that the turret is something totally absolutely new to us and that came with the APL acquisition. And APL is really a creative organization that's able to do things, and in particular you've got the submersible turret, which allows you to kind of drop the turret, and you kind of sail the FPSO out of harm's way if you're in harsh environments or in the Gulf of Mexico, things like that when a hurricane comes in.</p>
          <p>But we also recently purchased a company called Merpro. And Merpro does a lot of things that are additive to what we do there and then plus with our Norwegian operations and a lot of our cranage and our chain-handling and anchor-handling and things like that, we offer a pretty wide array of things. It's our intent to continue to do that.</p>
          <p>But also as I kind of mentioned earlier on my comments about technology, we're also looking at LNG vessels and APL has offerings for those as well. So we're very excited about where this is going. And I think that as we look at the technology that we have out there, we're positioning ourselves very, very well as the independent supplier of that to a lot of the FPSO owners. And I'll let Clay kind of touch on the integration process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this is &#x2013; and to reiterate, this is a very long-term strategy. We bought APL not for what we're going to do in FPSO orders this year but rather for where we see this industry going over the next 10 years. And it's really underpinned by a very high number of deepwater offshore discoveries and the need of the oil and gas community to plumb those discoveries in, and we think FPSOs offer a pretty elegant way to move in to more remote locations and produce those fields.</p>
          <p>We'll tell you that when it comes to sanctioning the development of discoveries and moving forward on spending big CapEx dollars, meaning buying an FPSO, it also carries along with it a commitment to engage in much bigger drilling programs and buy a lot more other and hardware and services to develop these fields.</p>
          <p>And so, we think that's kind of gating the FPSO orders here in the short run. But given the strong outlook for crude prices, the number of discoveries that are out there, we're absolutely confident these projects are going to go forward as Pete mentioned is probably much more of a 2012 event.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next call &#x2013; question comes from Bill Herbert from Simmons &amp; Company. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Clay, with regard to the margin roadmap for Rig Tech, just a couple of questions and trying to correlate that with your view on margins. You did mention that you had recently implemented a 6% to 8% pricing increase for Rig Tech.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And when does that begin to head to P&amp;L? Is that sometime late this year or is it next year or when?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's more of a 2012 event and actually &#x2013; well, that has a lot to do with our guidance for 2012 margins kind of starting to go the other way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And so &#x2013; and then also the comment that we made with regard to shipyards, delivery times compressing about 10 months on cycle for a high-end drillship, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's sounds good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So basically, your revenue conversion out of backlog cycle-on-cycle should accelerate, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, absolutely. Yeah. What you're looking at, Bill, is much &#x2013; an accelerated delivery which obviously leads right into coming out of backlog quicker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So your mix is going to be improving, price is going to be up and your absorption is probably going to be better. When does an inflection really begin to take place? Is it at the end of this year or do we begin to see that happening second half of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Bill, we've &#x2013; it's out there. We said a couple of quarters away. I don't want to call that precisely into this year versus 2012, but, let's say, a couple of quarters away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, that's all I have. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Mr. Miller, I'm turning the call back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Dawn, and thanks everybody for calling in. And we look forward to talking to you on our next conference call when we discuss third quarter results. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>