<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1165700" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-17</date>
    <companies>
      <company>666</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Daniel Vasella, M.D., Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John Gilardi, Novartis Global Media Relations</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Raymund Breu, Ph.D., Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Joseph Jimenez, Chief Executive Officer, Pharmaceuticals</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Andreas Rummelt, Ph.D., Chief Executive Officer, Sandoz</participant>
      <participant id="6">John Murphy</participant>
      <participant id="7">Raymund Breu</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ludwig Hantson</participant>
      <participant id="9">Tim Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="10">Andreas Rummelt</participant>
      <participant id="11">Joseph Jimenez</participant>
      <participant id="12">Michael Leuchten</participant>
      <participant id="13">Marietta Miemietz</participant>
      <participant id="14">Tim Franklin</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon. This is the Chorus Call conference operator. Welcome and thank you for joining the Novartis Half Year Second Quarter 2008 Sales and Results Conference Call. As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity for you to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Daniel Vasella. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. It is my pleasure to start with our call, and let me first introduce my colleagues who are with me today. We have Thomas Ebeling, Andreas Rummelt, Raymund Breu, Joe Jimenez, Pierre Landolt, Andrin Oswald, and Elv&#xE9; Oppenhau is heading &#x2013; Chief Operating Officer of our Oncology business. And then we have the IR team and several other colleagues from finance with us, if you have any specific questions the speakers couldn't answer.</p>
          <p>And speaking today after my introduction is Raymund Breu, then Joe Jimenez, and Andreas Rummelt, and then we will be open to any questions or comments you have.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn to my first slide, slide number four. If we look at the first half, it's clear that looking at the second quarter &#x2013; we have the &#x2013; first, the Safe Harbor statement by John Gilardi. Before I say anything I think it's prudent to have that. John, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The information presented in this conference call contains forward-looking statements that involve known and unknown risks, uncertainties and other factors. It may cause actual results to be materially different from any future results, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such statements.</p>
          <p>Please refer to our Form 20-F on file with the SEC for a description of some of these factors. We do not assume any obligation to update any forward-looking statements presented in this call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. With that I'm turning to my first slide, giving the year overview. And it's very clear that in the first half after last year, we have started to gain momentum especially in the second quarter. And then we also see that our project Forward has had a positive effect on the productivity and also the simplification and efficiency of the organization.</p>
          <p>From a pipeline point of view we had positive news, more positive than we expected for Afinitor and as expected for Menveo, so two important products going forward. And Afinitor obviously has not just renal cancer indication we are pursuing, but a whole array of additional cancers.</p>
          <p>We also did complete the first step of the Alcon acquisition with the acquisition of 25% of their shares and acquired a majority in Speedel, the company with whom we had developed Tekturna/Rasilez. And finally also, we had a smaller acquisition of Protez, which is a Phase II broad-spectrum antibiotic.</p>
          <p>A few days ago, we announced that we would start a strategic collaboration with Lonza in order to accelerate the progress of our biologics pipeline, which has gained in importance over the last year. And I think overall, we are on track with our forecast.</p>
          <p>If we turn to slide number five, you will see the numbers for the first half. I don't want to insist on that.</p>
          <p>And on slide number six, you will see the comparison between the first half and the second quarter, and clearly with a topline growth of 14% in dollars and 5% in local currencies, and a net income growth and operating income growth of 17%, we are in a significantly more dynamic phase now. And I think the outlook also is promising from that point of view.</p>
          <p>The biggest change on slide seven is obviously in Pharmaceuticals for the positive. There we can see a return to growth even more rapidly than we had forecasted. We had forecasted a negative growth in the first quarter, a zero growth in the second quarter and we are ahead of these projections.</p>
          <p>On the other side, there's some disappointment with Sandoz in the second quarter, which is due to a slow momentum in the U.S. market and a slightly contracting market in Germany despite the fact that we are gaining market share, that Andreas will go into more detail, because we also have very positive news in some other geographies.</p>
          <p>Consumer Health, doing according to the target here. I would like just to mention that CIBA Vision is on track and that will clearly have a turnaround, and they are moving in the right direction and Vaccines and Diagnostics, a very dynamic topline growth.</p>
          <p>If you look at the geographies in the next two slides, then one can see that despite the slow growth in the U.S., which is still impacted by pharmaceuticals and also negatively impacted by generics, we are doing well and especially in so-called the emerging growth markets, the growth is extremely dynamic.</p>
          <p>Looking at our priorities for 2008, as we had mentioned in the past we have continued to selectively strengthen our business portfolio; to step up the investment in innovation focusing really on differentiated products and expanding the high-growth markets. So we absolutely want to invest in certain markets, where we see a lot of opportunity. And last but not least, we have to continue to improve the efficiency and productivity of our organization.</p>
          <p>In slide number 11, you will see one or two more details on these four points. Slide 12 also gives you a little bit more insight, but I think I gave you the summary. Maybe just on project Forward, where do we stand? We are on track to deliver the targeted savings, which obviously also allow us to offset some of the higher costs due to inflation, but we are well here on target to achieve the 670 million savings, which we have targeted for this year and 1.6 billion we have targeted for 2010.</p>
          <p>In the Lonza deal, that's slide number 13; the point, which I want to make is that we did not just simply want a tall manufacturer. We wanted to have a partner with whom we could work intimately and could learn also. And so, we're co-developing a number of the projects that we will do in collaboration. And I think that's the give-and-take for both companies, which will be very fruitful.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to pass to Raymund.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel. I am on slide 15, and I would like to briefly comment on the changes in the margin, in the operating margin and the net income margin. You see in the six months numbers, we had a slight increase in operating income margin of 0.1% and 0.3% in net income.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, you can see that this improvement was accelerating in the second quarter because in the second quarter the operating income margin improved 0.6 percentage point and the net income margin 0.4 percentage point.</p>
          <p>Then on the next slide, we can see where it's coming from. We have improvements in other revenues, mostly royalty from out-licensed product, which adds 0.5 percentage point. And then we have productivity gains, in particular in marketing and selling, 0.4 of a percentage point and in G&amp;A, 0.2 of a percentage point. Obviously these productivity gains are related to the project Forward and part of it has been reinvested in particular in research and development, which has increased 0.3 of a percentage point compared to sales.</p>
          <p>The net income margin on the next slide, you will see that in addition we have improvements coming from associated income and from net financial income, which I'll comment on later on.</p>
          <p>On slide 19, we list all the exceptional items and the amortization on intangible assets. We had relatively few exceptional items in the first half and in the second quarter. The most important relate to restructuring, where in the first half in Pharma we had 47 million, in the second quarter 8 million. Then major product divestments, where in the half-year we had 140 million gain, in the second quarter 26 million. And then the release of pre-launch inventories, which was all, recorded in the first quarter of 45 million. And finally, the biggest item on a net basis here is the release in the U.S. of a provision relating to agency rebates, where based on an updated assessment we felt compelled or advised to release this provision. And that's 104 million, which obviously benefited sales and operating income in Pharmaceuticals directly.</p>
          <p>And the only other exceptional items, which we have, are in Vaccines and Diagnostics, where we had exceptional settlements from legal disputes of 49 million, that is all &#x2013; these are all booked in the first quarter, so we have no additional ones in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>On slide 20, you'll see the overview of the non-operating items. Income from associated companies went up 33% entirely linked to our share in Roche. Financial income, again up 72%, the main reason being higher average liquidity that we had from the divestiture of our Nutrition businesses last year. The average liquidity was 5.9 billion compared to just 0.4 billion in the comparable period.</p>
          <p>The tax rate in the half year is 14%, the same rate as a year ago. This is lower than what we had in the first quarter. We could reduce the rate to 14% for one reason in particular, a reduction in the bars and safety tax of 1 percentage point, which obviously is all the catch-up on the balance sheet items as a significant impact.</p>
          <p>Then on the next slide, you will see the overview of the free cash flow for the six months in the year-ago period, that's 111 million. In this period, it's a negative 771 million. The biggest contributor here is the increase in dividends because we always show the free cash flow after dividends. Apart from this, you can see that the higher needs for working capital to a large extent increased by a lower spending on capital expenditure and on intangible and financial asset acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Finally on slides 22 and 23, we give you the breakdown of the project Forward savings and where we stand. In mid-year, 63% of the 670 million have been achieved already. You can see that all divisions contribute to this. All divisions, a fact that I should say, contribute to this.</p>
          <p>And then in terms of reduction of head count, we are already at 74% of what we had forecasted for this year, so you can see that the personnel reductions moved as fast as we can, and that obviously is a good predict of all the achievements of the savings in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>With this, I hand over to Joe Jimenez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Raymund. I'm pleased to say that the Pharma division is gaining momentum as we move through 2008. We said at the beginning of the year that we could expect sequential sales growth as we moved through the quarters and that is what's being delivered. If you look at the second quarter, our sales were up 14% or 5% in local currency, due largely to the new product launches as well as strength on our base business. So operating income was up nicely at 18% due to that sales growth in the first half of the year and also due to productivity savings.</p>
          <p>If you look on slide 26, you can see some of the key metrics. Sales in the first of the year, 13.2 billion. You can also see the impact of our head count reduction, total associates down 4% versus year ago.</p>
          <p>Slide 27, we're experiencing continued strength in both the Cardiovascular franchise as well as Oncology. If you look at Diovan, EXFORGE and Tekturna together, that franchise is up 20% versus year ago in local currency to over 3 billion, and Oncology up 14% to just about $4 billion in total sales.</p>
          <p>Slide 28 shows the new launches. They've contributed 1.3 billion in sales for the first half of the year. And encouragingly, they continue to build led by LUCENTIS. But I have to say that also Aclasta and EXELON PATCH are doing extremely well. Aclasta in the U.S., behind some direct-to-consumer advertising has driven total Aclasta to over $100 million in sales year-to-date.</p>
          <p>So flipping to 29, you can see that Oncology now accounts for just about 30% of total Pharma sales, and we see this as a big opportunity to invest for further growth as we address the 2012 patent expiry issue of Diovan.</p>
          <p>And on slide 30, specifically you can see Afinitor, our mTOR inhibitor. The Phase III as we recorded earlier in renal cell cancer was stopped early with excellent results. So that will result in an accelerated filing in the U.S. and Europe this year and we'll begin selling Afinitor next year, also very promising for other indications &#x2013; other cancer indications.</p>
          <p>Slide 31 shows ZOMETA, and at ASCO [American Society of Clinical Oncology] this year we reported that ZOMETA was shown to significantly improve disease-free survival in breast cancer. ZOMETA was up in the second quarter and that was actually ahead of this news. So we expect ZOMETA to improve significantly in the back half of the year.</p>
          <p>Slide 32 shows other regulatory and development news. We're very pleased that LUCENTIS received positive NICE [National Institute for Clinical Excellence] endorsement in the U.K. for reimbursement. Regarding development, we announced a few weeks ago the two opportunistic infections that were reported in the FTY trials. I'll tell you that since then we have had discussions with every major health authority around the world, and the Phase III trials continue uninterrupted. As Dan mentioned, we acquired Protez, which is a small U.S. company, which adds PZ-601 to our pipeline, a broad-spectrum antibiotic.</p>
          <p>Slide 33 shows that our productivity measures are on track, so we delivered 382 million year-to-date against the target of 632. This is a combination of head count, right-sizing the field force and sourcing. We still have a huge opportunity I believe in sourcing to push greater and greater percentage of our indirect spend through e-sourcing and e-procurement, which will help us achieve the productivity target.</p>
          <p>Slide 34 shows an update on the new commercial model pilots that we're doing in the U.S. We reported previously that in January we started three pilots in some highly restricted markets. And so far those pilots are doing very well. Sales are strong. Profit is up significantly versus year ago. And importantly, employee satisfaction is up. So you're in these markets and the sales reps will tell you that in a restricted market they spend a lot of time in the physician's office, not seeing the physician, they might get 15 seconds with him in the hall. And by forming these cross-functional teams up against the headquarter of a payor or of a healthcare provider we're able to unlock some of that access. So that's showing some good progress.</p>
          <p>35 shows that we completed our acquisition &#x2013; sorry, we announced our intention to acquire Speedel. Obviously, this is reinforcement of our belief that renin inhibition is going to be a major therapy for cardiovascular disease going forward. And this acquisition will allow us to capture the full economics of the investment that we're making in Tekturna.</p>
          <p>Tekturna we have announced a very extensive post marketing clinical trial program that will result in good news flow over the next five years. So I will tell you that we're still not happy with where we are on Tekturna, but there are some positive lead indicators that suggest that together with the clinical program we're going to drive this thing to where we expect it to be. This is a key part of our 2012 strategy but it is not the only part.</p>
          <p>So to summarize on slide 36, our priorities are clear for the back half of the year. They are all focused on execution and as well though we will be finalizing our plan to drive growth through the 2012 period.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn it over to Andreas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Joe. I'm starting on slide 38. Sandoz sales were up in the first half of the year, 13% in U.S. dollar, 2% in local currencies. Sales growths mainly fueled through continued good growth in emerging markets, especially in Central and Eastern Europe, up 14% in local currencies.</p>
          <p>We also had a slight increase of plus 1% in local currencies in Germany, although Germany currency is at the shrinking market. We've significantly increased our market share, nearly 5 percentage point versus previous year. The market is currently showing strong momentum. In quarter two, performance contributed substantially. So here sales went up 8% in local currencies.</p>
          <p>However, in U.S. we have a further slow-down in sales of minus 7%, for the same reasons as in the first quarter. So with launch timing &#x2013; delayed launches and higher than expected price erosion for some key products.</p>
          <p>On slide 39, I want to focus on the operating income, which was up 5% versus first half of 2007. Giving some details here, we increased the gross margin by 2% versus the same period last year, which was more than offset by R&amp;D, higher R&amp;D spending, and higher marketing and sales expenses especially in Eastern Europe and ramping up our activities for biopharmaceuticals.</p>
          <p>On slide 41, you can see some details on how we are doing in the different markets with continued very strong performance in Eastern Europe, so here just an example, Russia, Poland and Romania. We also see good performance in South America, up 61% in Brazil and a 58% up in Turkey. And even in the established markets like Canada and Switzerland we showed good performance in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Some details on Germany on slide 42. So as I already mentioned, we increased market share by 5 percentage points until May of this year in a shrinking market. So I think despite all the difficulties with the healthcare reform and comparability of data, we estimate the net market growth rate of minus 1 to minus 2% and here we are doing well with a good momentum in second quarter of this year and the expectation that this will continue positively for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>Slide 43 shows the details in the U.S, so here minus 7% in local currencies, of course, influenced also by some of the 2007 launches which lost exclusivity, the price erosion for some products here mainly Cefdinar and Ondansetron, which we have already mentioned in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Enoxaparin, which we have discussed in the first quarter call here, we still don't have a final decision on the patent &#x2013; invalidity of the sanofi patent, although the appellate court has ruled &#x2013; at the District Court, the final mandate which need to be issued is still not available and this final mandate would trigger the 180-day exclusivity clock for   Ampostad.</p>
          <p>FDA approval is also pending here. We will try to <mark type="inaudible" /> later in this quarter and we have two similar situations in Enoxaparin still pending. So basically the exclusive possibility of this can be launched in 2008 will go into 2009. Otherwise we are continuing to prepare for the Enoxaparin launch and we have 108 pending ANDAs in the U.S., so further products to come.</p>
          <p>44 shows the split of sales in the mature generic market, where sales are up only 5%, so this is a continuing trend versus very strong 28% in the emerging generics market.</p>
          <p>So given all this and despite the uncertainties in U.S., we expect a stronger sales growth in the second half of 2008, mainly a continued strong momentum in Germany and some U.S. launches to come in the third and fourth quarter. We expect to have continued strong growth in the emerging generic market and continue also our strong portfolio, with the difficult-to-make technology and growth in biosimilars.</p>
          <p>So given all these facts and the fact that we have increased the proportion of difficult-to-make products in the U.S. and here we have also an increasing number of citizen petitions on these products. So currently we have six citizen petitions pending on products, which await launch in the U.S. And here it's hard to predict when these citizen petitions will be resolved, so the full year outlook is now that we would grow sales at mid-single digit numbers.</p>
          <p>And with this, I turn it back to Daniel Vasella.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andreas. So barring unforeseen events, we are confident that group sales for continuing operations should reach mid-single digit growth rate in local currencies by year-end and that we will achieve a group operating and net income growth for continuing operations at a new record level.</p>
          <p>With that, I close our presentation. And I would like to open it for Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the Chorus Call operator. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First question from Mr. John Murphy, Goldman Sachs, please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much indeed. Good afternoon. First to Raymund, Raymund, you very kindly provided us with a number of currency sheets, so we can work how currency impact going forward. I wonder if to make it simpler still to help us reconcile it, you could maybe give us what the local currency operating income growth was either for the first half or the second quarter?</p>
          <p>And second, the 104 million rebate reversal, can we make any major attribution to any key brands there? And then finally for Joe, you put out on slide 34, you talked about the new customer models leading to significantly improved profitability. Can you tell us a little bit more about this? Is it increased sales, is it lower cost? What's going on, because obviously a lot of companies are talking about pilot models and I guess what we want to understand is how transferable these sort of things might be and on what sort of speed you might see them being taken up as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. John, regarding the currency impact, I think we should start from the impact on sales, which is 9 percentage points on the growth. This will be a mistake to assume that it is the same number on operating income. On operating income, it's less since we have a natural hedge as a larger share of our cost is in this banking model.</p>
          <p>So the net impact on the operating income is lowered by a couple of percentage points. And regarding the rebate of 104 million, around 80% of these reversals is really to the benefit of our matured product, not the key brands, or the mature products in particular Closaring and Takelittle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the new customer models, we went into very restrictive markets. So you could argue that from a resource allocation standpoint, we were probably over-resourcing these markets with sales resources.</p>
          <p>So when we built the cross-functional teams and realigned the sales resources from rep to cross-functional team, there was a total net reduction in total resource against the pilots. And so as we have seen both sales improve versus control so &#x2013; and control being other restrictive markets where we didn't have this model, as well as lower costs in terms of the way that we're running those markets, that's what led to the nicely improved profitability.</p>
          <p>In terms of where we see this going forward, well right now we're still in the piloting state. So for example, we believe that there are &#x2013; there is some tinkering that we have to do in terms of ensuring that we have the right resources at the headquarter level and that we have the right training and development at the headquarter level. And once we feel comfortable in that, then we would be able to look at expanding to other restricted markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can I just ask as follow-up to that, is the key issue on getting the appropriate resources at your end or understanding what those appropriate resources are? Or is it understanding what the requirements at the other end are? In other words, who the key decision makers are in this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, maybe Ludwig Hantson who runs our U.S. operation could address that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, it's both. I think we should look at things both external as well as internal. So it's fully understanding the needs of the customer as well as making sure that we align ourselves with what those needs are. So in addition to what John mentioned on rising productivity through FTE reduction. It also allows us to optimize the marketing and sales mix. And that basically goes through in the first place understanding what the customer needs. So I see this exercise as both a top line as well as a productivity exercise with a focus on driving a customer-centric organization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Tim Anderson, Sanford Bernstein [Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co.]. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A few questions. On generic Lovenox in the U.S., do you expect this to be a fully substitutable AB-rated product? And can you comment on whether you expect to have the only generic available in 2009 or do you think you will be one of many? Also on Generics, do you expect that other major pharmaceutical companies will go down a path similar to yours and get into this and to the drug business? Ranbaxy said that there were other major pharma bidders at the table as it was discussing its sale to Daiichi [Daiichi Sankyo]. And on FTY 720, hoping you can talk about how your confidence in this product may have changed over time. So for example, are you more comfortable or less comfortable today than you were, let's say, a year ago? Because over that timeframe of course, there has been some new safety issues that have arisen and I'm wondering if that's tempered your outlook on this pipeline product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Andreas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well first on Lovenox, ex Lovenox's file there's an ANDA on the 505 day route. We are expected to &#x2013; this ANDA being approved. And then the product would be fully substitutable. In terms of competitors, I think due to the patent dispute with sanofi-aventis, we know about Amphastar and Teva, otherwise I cannot comment. And in terms of other companies moving into the same strategy as Novartis well you have seen some of the recent moves. So obviously, there are some more players who believe that this strategy is right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may add here one word. I think it's a big difference if you do this kind of portfolio strategy from a defensive or an offensive point of view. So in our case, we have been &#x2013; since now decades in the generic business, and the buildup has, in my view, an offensive character. We want to capture growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>I'm not sure that's equally true for some of the other players if you look at their pipelines and what they have in the pharmaceutical core business, where we have a very good position. I'm not so sure about the motivations others have to enter into the segment. If you think back about what, 15 years? We had seen a similar kind of development, then followed by exits, because people did manage the businesses like they used to manage the pharmaceutical business. And that obviously didn't work. It's a different dynamic. But anyway, I think we'll see how it evolves and we're happy to compete with additional players. That doesn't bother us at all.</p>
          <p>Trevor, do you want to comment about FTY?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, indeed. So I'm certainly not comfortable in a circumstance where I don't understand what I'm dealing with. And in a situation where you're developing a drug with a novel mechanism, particularly an exciting and positive mechanism like FTY, I would say a year ago or two years ago, that certainly was the case that we had some idea of how this drug works. But not the complete picture on safety that I would like.</p>
          <p>And understanding that that gap needed to be filled, I think we introduced this intensive safety monitoring in our Phase II, III program. And also behind that, which is probably not as apparent, an extensive mechanistic program to understand how this drug impacts the immune system.</p>
          <p>In terms of the two infection cases that Joe spoke to you about, I think that's a good case in point whereby when we actually looked at those cases and they were highly confounded, it was precisely our ability and the fact that we understood the impact on the immune system in detail, could go to the safety monitoring board and the regulators and explain what had happened, that enabled us to proceed with the study as is. But I have to say that compared to a year or two ago, I'm now much more comfortable with where the FTY program stands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from <mark type="inaudible" />, UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and good afternoon. I have three questions. First of all for Raymund. Just a question that's not so relevant for your free cash flows, but more for your valuation comps relative to peers. I imagine there's a debate internally on whether to focus consensus on pre-intangibles, pre-impairments, pre-exceptionals reporting as your peers have done. Now where does that stand?</p>
          <p>Secondly, for Andreas, what's your understanding of the Lovenox appeals decision finality timelines and when first-to-file status might expire? And then lastly for Joe, on Tekturna, can you yet comment on what programs are ongoing for possible triple or quadruple fixed dose combinations? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Mr. Bala, regarding the question, which earnings per share to use for evaluation. We intend to switch our earnings picture to core earnings, then we would exercise the two of the outgoing transactions. That would be at the earliest in 2010 or at the latest in 2011. At that time, we clearly would switch to this because by then, the impact of the intangible amortization would be huge and would clearly justify that we adopt what other Pharma companies are already doing.</p>
          <p>To prepare that step, we give you since I think last year the numbers already, how they would look like if you would switch, these are &#x2013; the slides or the pages 29 and 30 in this press release, where you see both the half-year and the quarter, the adjusted earnings, how they would look like all the way down through to net income so that you can see how we defined it. Because definition is an important issue here too. And then by the time we switch over, obviously we have a comparable base with the historical record so that you know what is coming.</p>
          <p>Obviously, I should add here Mr. Bala, we are monitoring development. And if the wish from our investor base would be that we should switch over earlier, then we certainly well may consider this plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And in terms of the Lovenox growth situation in the U.S., so &#x2013; as already mentioned, the Appellate Court has confirmed the decision of the District Court that the respected patent is invalid. I think here now there are several possibilities how sanofi can react. They can ask for a re-hearing. And these discussions are ongoing with the Appellate Court.</p>
          <p>So basically, only once this is finished, then the Appellate Court will issue its mandate, and this would trigger the 180-day exclusivity for Amphastar. It's very difficult to predict how long these legal proceedings will take, and this is the main reason why currently I don't believe that a 2008 launch is still possible. It will certainly go into 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there a theoretical bound on how long sanofi could sort of delay the finality of the decision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think this is basically between the Appellate Court and sanofi. And the Appellate Court has to decide how many days the different parties have in order to give their justifications and answer additional questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But certainly this expiry shouldn't &#x2013; of the 180 day &#x2013; shouldn't go beyond 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think the 180 day basically started when the Appellate Court issued its mandate. And here as I said, it's very difficult to predict how long this is going on back and forth between the parties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Regarding Tekturna, we have several fixed dose combinations under development. Some are doubles, some are triples. We are targeting one launch per year for the next few years. And as you know we've launched Tekturna HCT this year in the first half of the year. So you can expect our next filing to be by the end of this calendar year. And for competitive reasons, we have not disclosed which one that is. But you can assume that we are going to have a pretty aggressive launch program for the next few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you say whether the triple involves Tekturna and Diovan, both?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it would be very logical and not very logical not to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and &#x2013; yeah, that's right. I think that's a good answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Joe. Okay, next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ms. Alexandra Hauber, JPMorgan. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon gentlemen. Just three quick questions. To clarify, when you talk about synergies and headcounts achieved so far, on the FTE reduction, is that a gross figure as in &#x2013; do you plan to &#x2013; 2,500 less head count by the end of the year or is that &#x2013; sorry, is that a net figure or is that a gross figure? When you talk about realized cost savings, is that the year-to-date impact or is that an annualized impact if everything what you have achieved already would have a twelve months' impact?</p>
          <p>The second question is on Afinitor. You were alluding to some next steps in breast cancer that was still open at ASCO. Could just tell us whether you have decided whether <mark type="inaudible" /> you go straight into a pivotal study, or whether you need to do a more slow development as you're doing it in Phase II and then moving it into a pivotal setting?</p>
          <p>And then the third question is for Andreas. Can you comment on these delayed U.S. launches? I mean, you know the time is obviously one thing but it seems to affect several products, is there any pattern to this? As in slower approval time or is this merely a case by case situation which just happens to affect several products now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Alexandra. The FTE reductions are gross. These are the reductions related to the project Forward, we are investing or expanding at the same time in various areas, for example in marketing and sales in the emerging gross markets, or we are expanding in development and so, net net our head count for the year is expected to be approximately the same as last year. So no growth, but you can see that the reductions in the overhead areas are offset by investments in targeted growth areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then the impact of the cost saving, the 422 million is the impact on the profit and loss in the first half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's what has already been seen in the profit and loss in the first half, and we expect that by year-end then the full impact on the profit and loss would be 670 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on Afinitor <mark type="inaudible" /> twelve out of thirteen patients responded to Afinitor in combination with Herceptin and Paxil  after failed previous treatment. So we certainly are planning to initiate new studies in 2009 with Afinitor in breast cancer. We don't know yet what the design of this study would be <mark type="inaudible" /> as we speak, so we cannot give you yet the design on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; but do we know whether it &#x2013; is there still a possibility you can get it straight into a pivotal study in a refractory setting or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the options. We don't know yet how we are going to go to the next step, if it's going to be a pivotal study or if it's going to be another study as a Phase II study.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of FDA approvals, we have currently 108 pending ANDAs. And also the other generic play I have a number sitting at the FDA. So the overall number is increasing. And therefore we will see a trend, a general trend to longer approval timelines at the FDA. In the end, it's a case-by-case decision for each and every file.</p>
          <p>I think what is hurting us most during this year is that we have a number of files, six very important files, where we have at least one citizen petition on it. And these citizen petitions, although they have clear timelines to be resolved are in terms of when the FDA starts to address these citizen petitions and how long it takes to respond and resolve the cases, getting more and more unpredictable. And this is the issue we are currently facing. But in general &#x2013; so longer approval timelines and case-by-case are our issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what would you say is right now the average ANDA approval timeline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's now getting again close to 18 months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Michael Leuchten, Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Just three questions. One for Raymund. Just in terms of the tax rate, I know you guided for 15% for 2008. Clearly, that seems to be lower now for this year. What does it mean for the coming year, given that your share of revenues coming out of the U.S. is lower and the local tax rate is coming down? The second question, maybe for Joe. If I look at the marketing and sales line within the Pharma division, even if I take out what I assume just the cost savings are and then take tranches into consideration, that line still seems to be declining even ex-cost savings. And it seems to be a lot given that you're only running pilot projects in the U.S. So could you just A, comment on whether that observation is right? And B, what else is going on in that line? And then one for Trevor on FTY 720, just going back to your confidence. Given that you now know more about the safety and the background information on that product, how confident are you with the lower dose in that program? What can you tell us about the minimal effect of dose?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The expectation for the tax rate for the full year is 14% also. So the same as in the first half. I mentioned that approximately one percentage point reduction is one-time related to this reduction in the tax rate in the city of Barton. So if you go forward yourself, you would have to take that out again. Apart from that, we cannot give a very good guidance going forward. The range that we have communicated to you earlier was a rate in the range of 16 to 18%, I think is our best guidance for the future years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And regarding marketing and sales -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> sorry, Joe. I think we also have to take into consideration the fact that we don't know how the U.S. tax rate will evolve within certain political environments. So in all likelihood, with the huge deficit, I think taxes are rather probably going to go up than down or flat. So I think that is something that one has to keep in mind too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding marketing and sales in Pharma, it is a correct observation that it is declining as a percent of sales. You will see in the back half, slightly higher as a percent of sales than the first half, because of the additional launches, the country product launches that occur across Europe. But if you look at the &#x2013; we're getting a significant amount of cost savings out of sourcing. So really thinking about how to improve the efficiency of sales materials, a lot of things that we buy in marketing and sales, there's &#x2013; there really is a very large opportunity there to not reduce the potency of marketing and sales, but to do it in a more efficient way. So you're going to see a continued effort in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the efficacy of the 0.5 milligram dose, I can just go back to the data which allowed us to select that dose in the first place. So from our Phase II study with 1.25 and the five essentially at equal efficacy indicating to us that we were on total of the dose response; and in the 1.25 showing continued three year efficacy in the recent data from the continuation of that Phase II study; taking into account as well the tenfold accumulation in the brain of this drug, indicates that of all the modeling and simulation extensive that we've done, 0.5 should be an effective dose.</p>
          <p>But of course in the Phase III program where we have a safety board that is monitoring both benefit and risk, I am encouraged that the study is going &#x2013; all the studies in fact are going on unchanged with that dose included.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm smiling Trevor because I was asking if you really answered the question. Minimally effective dose to be very straight forward, I don't think we know. We are very confident that 0.5 works and we will have an acceptable efficacy / safety balance. But frankly, we don't have studies to show if 0.25 for example, or 0.1 would not still work. So that's an open question to some degree. But nevertheless, we are very confident that we are okay with the 0.5 milligram, is this fair Trevor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that's a fair judgment. Certainly the 0.5 has got very observable, measurable effects on the immune system, as would 0.125. But it looks like the 0.5 has got a good benefit / risk profile. So we'll see what comes out of that. As you indicate, even a lower dose might still be effective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Marietta Miemietz, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. A few questions please. The first one on Zometa. You were saying you expect an acceleration in the second half. And I was just wondering whether you were actually looking for increased uptake in the adjuvant setting and whether that is dependent on the AVA results? Or whether you think that the data we saw at ASCO in the adjuvant setting will actually reduce the concerns that physicians seem to be having right now in the on-label indications?</p>
          <p>The second question on generic Plavix. I was just wondering if you can elaborate a little bit on the situation in Germany, why the marketing authorization was suspended and how long you expect authorities to take to reinstate marketing authorization? And also whether you will actually be launching Witriceahol in other European countries and what the timelines on that would be? And my final question is just on the Alcon acquisition accounting, whether you can just run that by us for the first half in particular, what the expected amortization charge will be? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On Zometa, the numbers in the first hand have no effect on what would be the effect. What they're reflecting is a comp indication. We have been able in fact to stabilize the sales in most of the countries or grow again versus last year in many of them and what we anticipate is that the second half of the year in the current indication going to show some growth versus last year on that trend. And this is mostly because we have been able to manage and prevent most of these events of ONJ that had been previously published elsewhere suddenly presenting some views . Now the new data on Asreo we did present it in this last December in San Antonio and will not have any impact on the second half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on generic Plavix, the reason why the marketing authorization which was given by the D-Pharm, the German authority that suspended us sanofi-aventis has taken legal action against this marketing authorization. Issues as we know it are that there are questions around whether the data which are on the file could be used or it couldn't be used. It is very difficult to predict how long this would take to be resolved. I think this is now between the D-Pharm and sanofi-aventis. For us it means that we have to wait until this is finally concluded. It is European approval. So we had a focus on Germany for this year, but we are certainly also planning to launch in other European countries thereafter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, can I just clarify, how does the German situation then affect the other European countries? Because I thought you were filing in each country individually and presumably you can now re-file it any way you like anyway because the exclusivity period has expired. So would you say that's right for Hall's guidance for a 2009 launch in other European countries is realistic? Or do you think that that isn't in any way dependent on the outcome of the German litigation, so to speak?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our understanding is that it's dependent on the German litigation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of Alcon accounting, now that we own just below 25% of outcome, we will treat it as an associated income. So our share of the outcome / income and the intangible amortization will be shown in this line. We expect that approximately 50% of the price that we pay will be allocated to intangibles and those intangibles will be written off of over a period of &#x2013; currently estimated to be 10 to 12 years.</p>
          <p>So on a full-year basis, we expect that on the first step, the intangible amortization will be 500 to $600 million. Obviously, we will then more or less offset our share in their net income. So as a net peak, we expect that the reported EPS will be slightly diluted to 3% and the core EPS will be slightly accretive of again 2 to 3%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Let's come to the last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question from Tim Franklin, Dresdner Kleinwort. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. Good afternoon. In Q2, we're seeing a very strong growth of Pharma in the ex-U.S. markets. And it's driven the ex-U.S. proportion of Pharma sales up to about 60% of Pharma sales. We've got very strong growth in those markets. We see an EBIT margin of about 31.4%. Can you provide some guide on how the Pharma margins compare between the U.S. and ex-U.S.? And maybe some sense of what the Pharma margins are like in energy markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a good observation that we are growing of our business ex-U.S. And really we expect that trend to continue as you look at the slowing growth that is going to occur in the U.S. It makes it much more important for us to drive emerging markets top line as well as European and Asian top line. So from a margin standpoint, we are managing total Pharma in terms of looking at region by region, what do we need from the region.</p>
          <p>So do we need top line growth? Do we need <mark type="inaudible" /> growth based on the dynamics of that region. And we don't get into disclosing whether we make more in certain markets or not. But I think you can assume that if we're driving top line in a particular region, it might be slightly lower than Pharma average. If we're not driving top line at or about the Pharma average, then my expectation is that that unit will drive disproportionate profit growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. With that I would like to close our call and thank you for your questions and your interest and of course support. Bye, ladies and gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference call is now over and you may disconnect your telephone. Thank you very much for joining, goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>