<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1174373" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3044</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen, Executive Vice President and Chief Science Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jesper Brandgaard, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Peter Hugreffe</participant>
      <participant id="5">Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen</participant>
      <participant id="6">Henrik Simonsen</participant>
      <participant id="7">Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jesper Brandgaard</participant>
      <participant id="9">Carsten L&#xF8;nborg Madsen</participant>
      <participant id="10">Richard Vosser</participant>
      <participant id="11">Paol La Cour</participant>
      <participant id="12">Michael Novod</participant>
      <participant id="13">Martin Parkh&#xF8;i</participant>
      <participant id="14">Sachin Jain</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the Novo Nordisk Q2 2008 Earnings Conference Call. For your information, today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to your host, President and CEO, Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and ladies and gentlemen welcome. As mentioned to the Novo Nordisk conference call regarding our first six months' release, which was announced earlier today for 2008. I am Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen, the CEO of Novo Nordisk, with me I have our Chief Financial Officer Jesper Brandgaard, Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen our Chief Science Officer, and present are also our Investor Relations Officers.</p>
          <p>Today's earnings release is available on our home page novonordisk.com, along with a slides that we'll be using for this conference call. The conference call is scheduled to last as usual approximately 1 hour and we will start with a presentation as outlined on slide number 1. The Q&amp;A session will begin in about 30 minutes.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 2. So as I need to advise you that, this call will contain forward-looking statements. Such forward-looking statements are subjects to risks and uncertainties that could cause the actual result to differ materially from expectations. For further information on the risk factors, please see the earnings release and the slides prepared for the presentation. Also note, as mentioned, the conference is being webcast live, and a replay will be made available on our home page after the conference call.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 3. We're pleased with the performance of the first six months of 2008 with robust sales development for our key products and solid progress in the pipeline, including the filing of Liraglutide for regulatory approval in the United States, Europe and Japan.</p>
          <p>Our portfolio of modern insulins continues to show strong sales growth in all key markets. In the first six months of 2008 sales of modern insulins increased by 30% in local currencies, thereby maintaining the robust momentum of our insulin franchise.</p>
          <p>In biopharmaceuticals area, NovoSeven sales increased 14% in local currencies and Norditropin also continued a growth pattern with 15% sales growth in local currencies. Geographically, the sales increase is driven by North America, with sales growth in local currencies of 19% and international operations with 23% local currencies.</p>
          <p>In June, Novo Nordisk received marketing approval by the FDA of PrandiMet six dose combination of Prandin and metformin for the treatment of Type II diabetes. Furthermore, Liraglutide was submitted for regulatory approval in May in the U.S. as well as Europe. The filing in the triad markets were completed in July with the filing in Japan. In addition, Liraglutide has now been submitted for regulatory approval in Australia, New Zealand, Canada and Turkey.</p>
          <p>In June headline results, from the head-to-head study comparing Liraglutide and Exenatide were announced, the study reinforced the competitive profile of Liraglutide with a significant difference in HP1Ac reduction of more than 0.3 percentage points after 26 weeks treatment for a once daily injection of Liraglutide versus twice daily injection of Exenatide.</p>
          <p>Turning to the financial performance in the first six months of 2008. It has been driven by robust sales growth, 13% local currencies corresponding to 7% as reported. Solid improvement in our productivity and manufacturing have continued throughout the first six months of 2008 and contributed to an increase in the underlying gross margin of 130 basis points. This improvement is mainly related to increased productivity in insulin bulk manufacturing and insulin filling activities.</p>
          <p>In reported terms this corresponds to an increase in ten basis points as the underlying improvement is countered by a significant negative currency impact of around 120 basis points. The expectations for reported operating profit for 2008 is now increased to the range of 22 to 25%, and the expectations for growth in underlying operating profit, adjusted for the impact of currencies in non-recurring items, is likewise increased to around 25%.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 4. In the first six months of 2008, the diabetes care segment grew 14% measured in local currencies, contributing 74% of Novo Nordisk's growth. The portfolio of modern insulins were the main growth drivers accounting for more than 70% of total sales growth.</p>
          <p>Our pharmaceuticals grew 13% in local currencies, and sales of NovoSeven increased 14% while growth hormone franchise grew 15%, all measured in local currencies. Sales of both products are impacted positively by timing of tender sales to the tune of DKK 150 million in total in certain of our markets. Sales of HRT franchise products increased 3% measured at local currencies despite generic competition for Activella in the United States.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 5 for an update on our modern insulin franchise. In the first six months of 2008, sales of modern insulin products grew 30% measured in local currencies. The growth was driven by underlying market growth, market share gains for the entire portfolio of modern insulins, NovoRapid, NovoMix and Levemir. Market share continues to increase for all three products. The market performance for all Novo Nordisk's three modern insulins exceeded a steady and durable penetration of various insulin segments.</p>
          <p>On a regional perspective, growth was driven primarily by North America followed by international operations. In the first six months, modern insulins made up more than 57% of total insulin sales compared to 51% in the first six months of 2007, emphasizing the momentum of the ongoing conversion from human insulins to modern insulins. NovoRapid is the single largest modern insulin product for Novo Nordisk with sales of DKK 3.6 billion in the first six months of 2008. The similar figure for NovoMix is DKK 2.6 billion and Levemir continues to gain momentum with sales increasing from below 1.1 billion in the first six months of 2007 to above 1.7 billion in the first six months of 2008.</p>
          <p>Levemir is contributing the highest share growth and increasing by more than 70% in local currencies compared to the first six months of 2007. In June, NovoMix reached more than US$1 billion in sales during the past 12 months, making NovoMix the second Novo Nordisk modern insulin to reach blockbuster sales level. The sales growth of NovoMix in the first six months of 2008 is driven by European markets as well as markets in international operations, where the premix segment accounts for approximately 50% of the insulin market in many countries.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number six for some further insights into the dynamics of the modern insulin market. Around 55% of the global insulin market measured by volume has now been converted to modern insulins, compared to 50% same time last year. And we expect this conversion trend to continue within all segments of the market. This drives value growth for the insulin market along with ongoing conversion to prefilled devices. Novo Nordisk continues to gain market share within the modern insulin market, Novo's market share in modern insulins are now 44% measured in volume compared to 43% 12 months ago. Novo Nordisk continues to be the only company that markets a full range of modern insulins with short acting premix and long acting modern insulin and the most advanced and user friendly delivery system, such as the easy to use disposable FlexPen.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number seven for an update on NovoSeven sales development. NovoSeven sales increased 14% in local currencies and 6% reported in the first six months of 2008. NovoSeven sales growth was primarily realized in North America and international operations partly due to timing of tender sales in certain international operations countries. The sales growth of NovoSeven reflected increased sales within congenital and acquired hemophilia segment, where Novo Nordisk is the global leader. Treatment of spontaneous bleeds for congenital inhibitor patients remains the largest area of use.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 8 for an update on the sales of Norditropin. Norditropin sales increased 15% in local currencies and 9% reported in the first six months of 2008, thereby continuing again the solid growth momentum in the growth hormone franchise. Norditropin sales growth was primarily realized in North America, followed by international operations. However, all regions contributed to growth measured in local currencies. Novo Nordisk's global market share is now 24% measured by volume and 19% is in the United States.</p>
          <p>Norditropin is a liquid, ready-to-use heat stable growth hormone and increasingly sold in our pre-filled delivery device NordiFlex. It continues to be the most advanced offering on the market characterized by significant convenience benefits for patients and their families.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number nine for an update on sales by region. From a regional perspective, North America and international operations are the main growth drivers for the company. In the first six months of 2008 North America and international operations contributed 46% and 31% respectively to the overall growth of Novo Nordisk.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we continue to see solid growth rates for our portfolio of modern insulins, due to market share gains and underlying market growth. Levemir contributed around 50% of the growth. Sales in international operations in the first six months of 2008 grew 33% in local currencies. Sales of modern insulins continues to be a significant contributor to growth in the region led by China, Turkey and Algeria.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, sales of human insulins continue to add to overall growth in the region driven by China. The key contributor to growth in the region is China, accounting for more than 30% of total sales growth measured in local currencies. Sales in Japan and Oceania increased by 3% in local currencies. The sales development reflects sales growth in all three modern insulins NovoRapid, NovoRapid 30 Mix, and Levemir.</p>
          <p>Novo Nordisk has a leading market share in insulin market in Japan, holding 73% of the total market and 64% of the modern insulin market, both measured by volume. Levemir was launched in Japan in December 2007, and has already reached a solid penetration with a current volume market share above 15% of the long-acting insulin market in Japan and around 35% of the long-acting modern insulin market.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 10, which provides you with an update on the development of our modern insulin market shares in Europe including the roll out of Levemir. Novo Nordisk holds a clear leadership position within modern insulin segment in Europe, with a volume market share around 51%, a solid leadership position is reinforced by continued market share gains of Levemir, which now holds 27% of total European market for long-acting modern insulins. And around two-thirds of the Levemir sales volume in Europe is in pre-filled devices and around a third in durable devices.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 11 for the update on the U.S. insulin market. Total diabetes care sales in North America increased 21% in local currencies in the first six months of 2008 and by 6% recorded, reflecting a solid penetration of the modern insulin portfolio, Levemir, NovoLog, and NovoLog Mix. Novo Nordisk continues to consolidate the leadership position in the U.S. insulin market with 42% of total insulin market and 31% of the modern insulin market, both measured by volume.</p>
          <p>According to the latest monthly market share data covering June 2008, Levemir has now obtained 11% of the total long-acting modern insulin segment, measured by volume.</p>
          <p>With this, I would like to hand over to Mads, who will give you an update on the development within our pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars. Please turn to Slide 12 for an update on our Diabetes Care pipeline. As previously announced, Novo Nordisk has now filed for regulatory approval of Liraglutide, the once daily human GLP-1 analogue in the U.S. and EU in May of this year and in Japan in July, with only 53 days having lapsed between the submissions in all triad markets.</p>
          <p>In addition, Liraglutide has been filed for regulatory approval in Turkey, Canada, New Zealand and Australia. The applications contain documentation from an extensive clinical development program designed to obtain the indication for use of Liraglutide to treat Type 2 diabetes as an adjunct to diet and exercise, both as monotherapy and in combination with commonly used antidiabetic medications.</p>
          <p>The competitive profile of Liraglutide was further reinforced in a Phase IIIb clinical study known as V-6 in which Liraglutide provided statistically significantly better blood glucose control than Exenatide, a twice-daily GLP-1 analogue. The 26-week study includes 464 people with Type 2 diabetes who will randomize the treatment with either Liraglutide once daily or Exenatide twice daily as add-on to their existing treatment consisting of metformin, sulfonylurea or a combination of both.</p>
          <p>From an average HbA1c level at the beginning of the study of slightly above 8%, patients treated with Liraglutide achieved a reduction in A1c of more than 1.1 percentage point compare to a reduction in A1c of less than 0.8 percentage point in the Exenatide group, a difference which was statistically significant. Both patients treated with Liraglutide and patients treated with Exenatide lost an average around 3 kilograms during the course of the study with a trend towards more weight loss in the Liraglutide group.</p>
          <p>In the Liraglutide group, the percentage of patients reporting nausea in each week fell to low single-digit numbers after 8 to 10 weeks similar to the level observed in the background population. In the Exenatide group the level after 8 to 10 weeks of treatment remained at the level of 10%. As expected, the overall rate of hypoglycemia in the study was low.</p>
          <p>In July, Novo Nordisk initiated a 26-week Phase IIIb study comparing the effect of Liraglutide with Sitagliptin, a DPP-IV inhibitor in people with Type 2 diabetes inadequately controlled with metformin alone. Two doses of Liraglutide in combination with metformin will be compared individually to 100 mg of Sitagliptin in combination with metformin. The planned recruitment is 651 Type II diabetic subjects and the study is expected to be completed in the second quarter of next year.</p>
          <p>Significant sustained weight loss was reported after 52-weeks in a 32-week open-label extension of the 20-week Phase 2 obesity study for Liraglutide, in which treatment with Liraglutide was tested in obese people without diabetes. Around 400 participants continued into the 32-week extension. After 52-weeks, Liraglutide given once daily at the highest dose lead to a mean weight loss from baseline of around 7.5 to 8 kilograms and a placebo adjusted weight loss of around 5.5 to 6 kilograms. Around 75% of the people treated with the highest dose achieved a weight loss larger than 5% compared to around 25% of the people in the placebo group achieving a weight loss larger than 5%.</p>
          <p>Of all patients participating in the extension study, approximately 30% showed signs of pre-diabetes at randomization. After one year of being treated around 80% of this pre-diabetes subgroup of patients treated with the highest dose of Liraglutide no longer showed any signs of pre-diabetes. The proportion of people that withdrew due to side effects was below 15%.</p>
          <p>On another note, but still related to Liraglutide, let me provide a few comments about Novo Nordisk's perspective on the discussions that are taking place after the FDA Advisory Committee on cardiovascular risk for diabetes drugs, which took place on the first and second of July earlier this summer. As a leader within diabetes care, Novo Nordisk welcomes the discussion on cardiovascular risk and we have included a wide variety of cardiovascular end points in the lead clinical development program as well as in another programs.</p>
          <p>Liraglutide may, when compared to many other classes of diabetes drugs, differ from these when it comes to cardiovascular risk. This relates to the notion that Liraglutide induces statistically significant weight loss as well as in several studies, a statistically significant lowering of systolic blood pressure. Such lowering of body weight and blood pressure is widely accepted as contributing to cardiovascular health. In the LEAD [Liraglutide Effect and Action in Diabetes] program, we also looked at several other cardiovascular risk markers such as PAI-1, triglycerides, LDL and HDL cholesterol. Generally, Liraglutide treatment has lead to an improvement in most of these end points, although these are not in each case necessarily statistically significant.</p>
          <p>Of greatest relevance to the path towards approval of Liraglutide is however interactions between ourselves and the regulatory agencies. In this regard, I can mention that our dialog with the FDA has revealed that the regulatory dossier for Liraglutide is considered to be adequate for full a review, implying that the agency will be able to assess the approvability of Liraglutide on PDUFA action date, which is March 23 next year. In the period from now until the PDUFA action date, we expect many issues, big and small, to be discussed with the FDA. Specifically as regards effects of Liraglutide that may relate to the cardiovascular system it is our clear belief that agreed upon actions such as the potential conduct of clinical studies, will be elements of our post-approval commitments.</p>
          <p>Also within the GLP-1 area, Novo Nordisk has initiated a Phase II clinical study with a longer acting human GLP-1 analog known as in NN9535 and designed for once weekly treatment. The Phase II clinical study encompasses 362 patients and would evaluate the efficacy and safety of NN9535. The trial is expected to be completed in the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to PrandiMet. As communicated in June, Novo Nordisk has received approval by the U.S. FDA of PrandiMet, a fixed dose combination of the fast acting insulin secretagogue repaglinide and metformin for the treatment of Type II diabetes. PrandiMet was approved as an adjunct to diet and exercise to improve glycemic control in adults with Type II diabetes, who are already treated with both meglitinides such as Prandin and metformin or where inadequate glycemic control on meglitinide alone or metformin alone.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide for an update on our hemostasis portfolio. As communicated in June, Novo Nordisk has decided to discontinue the Phase III clinical study with NovoSeven for the treatment of bleeding in patients with severe trauma. The decision was made based on the results of an analysis for futility, conducted by the independent Data Monitoring Committee. The primary efficacy endpoint of the study was mortality and severe mobility. To assess the likelihood of reaching a successful outcome on the primary end point, a pre-planned futility analysis was conducted due to an observed lower mortality than anticipated in the overall study group.</p>
          <p>Thus, mortality was around 10% in the Phase III study compared to more than 25% in the Phase II study. The analysis predicted a low likelihood of obtaining a positive trial outcome with a plan size of the study population. And as a consequence Novo Nordisk decided to discontinue the study. The decision was not due to safety concerns. As soon as the last 90 day follow-up has been finalized for all patients in the trauma study, Novo Nordisk will analyze the results and we expect to present headline results from the study before the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Going forward and given the challenges experienced in expanding the NovoSeven franchise into general hemostasis, Novo Nordisk's research in the field will now focus exclusively and broadly on new treatments for hemophilia A and B. Research activities outside the hemophilia area, which involves 25 employees at the company's research site in New Brunswick, New Jersey, will be terminated and as a consequence, the site will be closed down.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide for an update on other biopharmaceuticals. Novo Nordisk has initiated a Phase II clinical study with a long-acting human growth hormone analogue designed for once weekly treatment. The Phase II clinical study will evaluate efficacy based on surrogate endpoints and safety and tolerability in type-2 adult patients. The study is expected to report in the first half of next year. As previously communicated, Novo Nordisk will increase and focus its activities on inflammatory disorders. An integral part of this new focus will be the establishment of the U.S. research site in Seattle, Washington with a focus on research within inflammatory diseases. Novo Nordisk expects to employ approximately 80 scientists at the research site by 2010.</p>
          <p>With that, over to Jesper for an update on the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Mads. Please turn to slide 15 providing you with details on the financial results. We are satisfied with the overall growth in the first six month of 2008 of 13% measured in local currencies and 7% as reported. The underlying improvement in gross margin was 1.3 percentage point in the first six months of 2008, primarily reflecting improved production efficiency in both upstream and downstream manufacturing within diabetes and higher average prices in the U.S.</p>
          <p>However, as reported, the improvement was 0.1 percentage point, reflecting that these improvements are countered by a significant negative currency impact of around 1.2 percentage points, primarily the lower value of U.S. dollars and British pounds versus Danish kroner compared to 2007.</p>
          <p>In the first six month of 2008, total non-production related cost increased by 4% to 11.244 billion compared to the same period last year. Sales and distribution costs were largely unchanged reflecting the combined effect of a provision related to an anti-dumping case in Brazil recorded in the first quarter of 2007, and higher costs in the first half of 2008 related to the expanded sales force in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Research and development cost increased by 13%, reflecting an increased level of activity in late stage clinical development, as well as the non-recurring cost related to the discontinuation of AERx and other pulmonary diabetes projects. Operating profit increased by 11% to 5.675 billion. Adjusted for the approximately 14% impact from currencies, underlying operating profit increased by around 25%.</p>
          <p>Net financial showed a net income of 444 million in the first six months of 2008, compared to a net income of 1.634 billion in the same period last year where a non-recurring and tax exempt income of 1.4 billion from the divestment of the ownership of Dako's business activities was recorded.</p>
          <p>The foreign exchange result was an income of 474 million compared to an income of 458 million in the same period last year. This development reflects gains on foreign exchange hedging activities due to the lower value of especially U.S. dollar versus Danish kroner.</p>
          <p>Effective tax rate, the first six months of 2008 was 24%. An increase from last year where the tax rate was impacted by the tax-exempt income from the divestment of the ownership of Dako's business activities as just mentioned, as well as a non-recurring effect linked to the reevaluation of the company's deferred tax liabilities as a consequence of the reduction in the Danish corporation tax rate implemented in 2007.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide for an update on our currency exposure. The depreciating trends for Novo Nordisk's most important invoicing currencies including the U.S. dollar and British pound versus Euro and Danish kroner has continued during 2008. With the decline of the U.S. dollar and British pound the hedging gain arising from our hedging activities have increased. The expected currency impact on operating profit, as a consequence of a 5% depreciation, is in line with the previously given estimate. With an annual impact of 470 million of a 5% movement in the U.S. dollar, as well an impact from the Chinese yuan and Canadian dollar included in the U.S. dollar-related line of DDK 100 million, the total annual U.S. dollar sensitivity is estimated to be 570 million from a 5% movement in the U.S. dollar.</p>
          <p>Currently, Novo Nordisk has hedged future expected cash flow related to the U.S. dollar 16 months ahead, the Japanese yen 14 months ahead, and the British pound is hedged 12 months ahead. Foreign exchange hedging gains of around 900 million have been deferred for future income recognition hereof, approximately 500 million for income recognition in the second half of 2008.</p>
          <p>Please turn to slide 17 for an outlook for 2008. Novo Nordisk now expects between 11 to 13% growth in sales measured in local currencies compared to the previous expectation of a growth in the range of 10 to 13%. This is based on the expectations of continued market penetration for Novo Nordisk's key strategic products within Diabetes Care and Biopharmaceuticals, but also expectations of increased competition in both the Diabetes Care area and in Biopharmaceuticals during 2008. Given the current level of exchange rate versus Danish kroner, the reported sales growth in 2008 is still expected to be around 6 percentage points lower than the growth rate measured in local currencies.</p>
          <p>The expectation for growth in reported operating profit for 2008 is now within the range 22 to 25% compared to the previous expectation of slightly more than 20%. This primarily reflects that expectations for the non-recurring costs in relation to the discontinuation of all pulmonary diabetes projects have been reduced from previously 500 million to now DDK 400 million, but also the revised outlook for sales growth. Adjusted for the impact from currencies and the non-recurring costs relating to the discontinuation of all pulmonary diabetes projects in 2007 and '08, underlying operating profits is now expected to grow by around 25% compared to the previous expectation of the growth only being close to 25%.</p>
          <p>In this connection, please note that the underlying operating profit growth for the first six months of 2008 solely is adjusted for the impact from currencies as the R&amp;D cost for pulmonary diabetes activities in the first half of 2007 is at the same level as the total costs, including the discontinuation costs in the first half of 2008.</p>
          <p>However, the expectations for full year underlying operating profit growth is adjusted for the impact from currencies as well as the nonrecurring cost related to the discontinuation of all pulmonary diabetes projects in order to match these expenses in 2007 and 2008. This includes the nonrecurring costs in the fourth quarter of 2007 as well as the cost in the first six months of 2008.</p>
          <p>For 2008, Novo Nordisk now expects a net financial income of 800 million reflecting significant foreign exchange hedging gains primarily related to the U.S. dollar. The expectations for the effective tax rate for 2008 is still 24%. Capital expenditure is now expected to be lower than 2 billion in 2008. Expectations for depreciation, amortization, and impairment losses are still around DDK 2.5 billion, whereas free cash flow is now expected to be around 8.5 billion. All expectations are provided that currency exchange rates, especially the U.S. dollar-related currencies, remain at the current level versus the Danish kroner for the rest of 2008.</p>
          <p>Please turn to slide 18. In 2008, under the Safe Harbor rules Novo Nordisk repurchased 6.3 million B shares equal to a cash value of DDK 2 billion. Based on the sustainable lower level for tangible asset investments of around 6% of sales annually, the board of directors have approved an increase by 1 billion in the ongoing 16.5 billion share repurchase program bringing the total value of the share repurchase program to 17.5 billion. The program is still expected to be finalized before the end of 2009. As a consequence of the increase in the share repurchase program, Novo Nordisk now expects to repurchase B shares equal to a cash value of around 4.7 billion in 2008 and around 5 billion in 2009. In 2006 and 2007, Novo Nordisk repurchased B shares equal to a total cash value of 7.8 billion.</p>
          <p>This concludes our presentation of the financial results. Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen will now moderate the Q&amp;A session. Please note that there will be a maximum limit of two questions per individual with the objective of allowing as many conference participants as possible to have the opportunity to ask questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much to Mads and to Jesper. Please note that this conference is being taped and the replay will be made available on our website. And, operator, we are now ready to take the first question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question today comes from Peter Hugreffe of ABG. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi Peter Hugreffe from ABG. Thank you for taking my questions. I have one question related to the Liraglutide launch, could you give some kind of insight to the upcoming launch in terms of ramp up of sales reps and should we expect any kind of P&amp;L impact for 2008? And then in addition to the NovoSeven and the discontinuation of the trauma study, have you seen any impact yet and should we still expect the same kind of off-label use on NovoSeven? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much; this is Lars Rebien, I think I will give a shot at both the questions. In regard to Liraglutide launch, it is clearly a very interesting subject, which is something that we focus on every day, facing the competitive situation in the marketplace. It is clear to us that the marketing efforts in the diabetes base has increased significantly. And, so, it is most likely that we will undertake an expansion of our marketing activities to be able to successfully launch Liraglutide.</p>
          <p>We will communicate the exact timing and size of this later this year when we announce also our guidance for 2009. It would be our assessment at the moment that cost in 2008 for any such activities would be rather limited. But we will give you more visibility. It's clear that from a competitive perspective, we would like to keep specific information about this as close to our chest as possible.</p>
          <p>Obviously the biggest potential for Liraglutide is in United States, and therefore it is likely that you'll see us announce an expansion of our U.S. sales force. There is, however, also the possibility that we will be announcing adjustments to our sales force in certain European markets and as well &#x2013; continued expansion of our sales force in overseas markets to launch Liraglutide in certain countries, but also to continue to focus on modern insulins.</p>
          <p>With regard to NovoSeven, we have not seen immediate impact on the results from the trauma study on NovoSeven. As you can see, we announced relatively buoyant and strong sales in the second quarter of NovoSeven. So it is not our anticipation that there will be a major impact as we have not seen any safety issues emerging from the trauma studies on those already established, so to speak, investigational usages of NovoSeven.</p>
          <p>And so, if we look at the overall growth expectations for current year, we announced in the beginning of the year that that we would see high single-digit growth. Right now we are above that. It's our expectation when we analyze month-by-month sales that we've had a couple of very good months especially in the second quarter. And on an annualized basis, we usually have only a couple of very, very good months like that.</p>
          <p>So, we still maintain our guidance at the high single-digit growth rates for NovoSeven hence a very modest growth in the second half of NovoSeven. But we would like to be positively surprised of course. Thank you very much. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now take our next question from Henrik Simonsen of SEB Enskilda. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good afternoon, gentlemen. Sorry to go back to the subject of Liraglutide in the United States, but I wanted to raise a question which I think is on many peoples' mind regarding what FDA has said to you. Has FDA given you any exact assurance that they will not require a cardiovascular outcome study during the communication you had so far with FDA? And do they still have up to the 90-day timeline to come back to you with any additional requirements for the acceptance of the filing?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, in terms of the cost structure, I was wondering if Jesper could provide us with the guidance, if that has changed in terms of the various cost structures you are guiding for 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Henrik. I will ask Mads to address the very central question, which is that of the recent concern on part of the FDA on cardiovascular effects of diabetes instruction. And then Jesper will give a run down on the P&amp;L and cost structure issues as you see them right now? Mads?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Henrik, very briefly and very importantly the dialogue with the agency in the U.S., the FDA has really shown that they feel we have provided a so-called full and substantive regulatory dossier that allows for a standard review with the PDUFA action date, which is on March 23 next year, which is the 10 month, as you know, period that has elapsed from the formal check-in of Liraglutide. And, hence that we have the data package that is needed for them to make the decision hopefully to approve the drug on March 23 next year.</p>
          <p>That being said, we are also aware that we, of course, will entertain with them a lot of discussions about both future risk management plans and post approval commitments of other kinds and they may well on their part include of course elements of future cardiovascular studies which we then would expect to be post approval. So that is the dialogue we are having, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, Mads, have they directly said to you, we will not require a cardiovascular outcome study prior to approval? That is kind of the, can you give us kind of the short answer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are saying that we have provided a regulatory dossier that provides full and substantive information on what they need for giving a standard review of our product aiming for a decision on its approvability on the PDUFA action date which is March 23.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that is as close as you can get. I mean, quite frankly, as I also alluded to, drugs are different. And I think you've heard the agency in a very, I think, intelligent way say that also going forward there will, of course, be &#x2013; and based on intelligence and insight, a case-by-case evaluation of drugs as we proceed going forward.  And what we have with Liraglutide is, fortunately, a compound that either has significant, statistically speaking, benefits on cardiovascular risk markers such as systolic blood pressure and body weight or strong trends in the positive direction. So yes, it's our very clear belief that we have what is needed on the cardiovascular side for approval of this agent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; and, Henrik, this is Lars Rebien here. So, as we heard from Mads, we feel quite comfortable that, seen from our side, but as you can also see from the wording and &#x2013; which is very customary from the FDA, FDA wants to keep and maintain their flexibility in terms of demanding whatever they think is needed to protect the American public for any risks. So that's gives of course a certain uncertainty. But so far we have, as Mads stated, not any reason to believe that it will be pre-approval. And then on to Jesper to give a rundown on the cost structures as they see &#x2013; they look right now, six months, seven months into the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lars. If we start with the cost of goods sold and relate it to gross margin, we continue to see an improvement in our gross margin for the full year, which will be at least 100 basis points. We've seen 130 basis points so far and the negative impact of 120 basis points, I would expect that currency impact to be slightly lower in the second half of the year. So, we'll still see an improvement in also reported gross margin for the full year if currencies stay where they are.</p>
          <p>In terms of selling and distribution cost we would anticipate that that would be in the ballpark of 29%. As the ratio in terms of R&amp;D, I would anticipate that the R&amp;D cost would be in the ballpark between 17 to 18% of sales. And this guidance includes the now expected 400 million it would cost us to close down the pulmonary projects within diabetes.</p>
          <p>And then, within the admin cost, we are guiding towards a level of around 6%, maybe slightly below 6%, and ideally growing at lower rate than our top line. And then finally, just to complement the picture within other operating profit income, no sorry, other operating income, we would anticipate an income level in the ballpark of 300 million. And this is also unchanged.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, Jesper, and thank you, Henrik. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will take our next question from Carsten Madsen of Carnegie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much for taking my question. I just have one question, actually, related to your modern insulin franchise. Where growth rates this quarter year-over-year was up, was 18%, which is down from 25% in Q1. Is there any particular reason for this sudden drop in the growth rates? And could you maybe also provide us with some sort of outlook for the full year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. This is Lars Rebien here. When we &#x2013; we have to caution people reading too much into &#x2013; to quarterly numbers. When we usually try to analyze whether there are any changes in trends we are referring to look at MAT data or market share information. And we can see &#x2013; there's absolutely no change in trends in the progression of our modern insulin franchise.</p>
          <p>So, what we rather would like to interpret this as being a certain purchasing pattern timing issues, specifically in United States where there has been some changes in distribution for certain wholesalers and some large purchasing groups which have typically put their purchase in major lumps. And whether these fall in one quarter or the other, it can have a significant impact when you compare one quarter against another. So no major changes.</p>
          <p>And of course then there is the specific issue relating to diabetes that there has been a price reduction in Japan which is kicking in April, taking a little bit of the growth up. But not to the magnitude that you are suggesting with the numbers here; so no changes.</p>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will take our next question from Richard Vosser of JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Richard Vosser from JPMorgan. Two quick questions, the first question on the one-time effects of stocking. I think you quantified them as 150 million. Could you just confirm whether that was just on the overall antidiabetics and whether it included the quantification of the stocking in NovoSeven for this quarter? If you could give an idea of that level, that would be great.</p>
          <p>And then a quick question on the changes in the hemophilia development; could you confirm what those changes are likely to &#x2013; how those changes are likely to affect the development, especially of the factor 13 cardiac surgery compound? Is that likely to be discontinued? And how do you see the new factor VII analogs and their positioning? Is that therefore just only for hemophilia now? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Richard, this is Lars Rebien. If I take care of the first comment, that's the once-off, you can, will respond to the changes perspective in hemophilia. As ones-off we have quantified it as approximately DDK 150 million, of which 100 million is ones-off purchases of NovoSeven, and 50 is purchases of growth hormone. So, we didn't make any comments on '08. It was NovoSeven and growth hormone and 150 was correct. Mads?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So what we hitherto have done has been to focus on the so-called inhibitor segment, i.e. look at the roll of NovoSeven in patients with antibodies again specs eight and nine. With that focus, we now broadening out into looking potentially at all relevant clotting factors in the general hemophilia space. One of the repercussions of this, plus the notion that we haven't had success on the expansion outside of hemophilia, obviously, is that we are stopping pre-clinical research outside of hemophilia and focusing the entirety of our research force on hemophilia-related products.</p>
          <p>Now, that does not mean to say, though, that our factor 13 asset and that the 1731, which we have previously announced, are being tested. As you know, factor 13  not only in cardiac surgery, where phase 1 has been completed, but also in congenital deficiency, which is the one where we are kind of waiting to proceed to the next step. Those will continue on a project-by-project basis. These are clinical activities and not pre-clinical research activities. So they are not affected.</p>
          <p>The same goes for the NN1731 cardiac surgery study, which is something, which is being discussed with the regulators at the present point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the the research activities are discontinued and in the future only focusing on hemophilia A and B, certain development activities including also using the factor VII analog within cardiac surgery will be considered going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question today is from Paol La Cour of Kaupthing. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, this is Paol La Cour from Kaupthing. First question is on CapEx, how much below the 2 billion will you go, I am thinking that in the first half you only spent 542 million and, as far as I am concerned, you haven't started building the Chinese factory and so I am having a hard time seeing that it can get close to two? That was the first part. The second one is on the free cash flow guidance increase that you gave this quarter, you are mentioning that part of this is a change in your U.S. distribution system. Can you give us some more color on this and also tell us if there will be further positive effect from this change in the second half of '08? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Paol, this is Lars Rebien here. Jesper I think both of these would be to you, the CapEx, where do you see it in the short-term and if there anything if you have any comments as to the longer-term perspective on this compared to prices to the level of deprecations and the impact of that cost on to cash flow and the specifics about the U.S. distribution system, which has been alluded to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Paol of course below 2 billion is the broad range to give. The way we typically give guidance on these matters would be within the ballpark of 500 million. So from this you can anticipate that we would expect it to be somewhere in the, let's say, 1.7 to 1.8, 1.9 billion Danish kroner. And that would of course anticipate that we would have a higher investment level in the second half and that's also what we're anticipating including initiation of the Chinese facility and also cost involved, cost in relation to operating of our PIN production platform including potentially new devices and that has a cost indication.</p>
          <p>So that's what's goes in to the guidance, but when we look at our longer term investment levels, as Lars was alluding to, we are now looking at investment levels in the ballpark of 6% of sales and hence there is a very close correlation between the current levels of deprecation and the anticipated level of investments going forward and as a background for &#x2013; and that you should see as the background for the increased share repurchase program that we announced.</p>
          <p>And then, secondly, in terms of the U.S. distribution system, the comment is just made there that the only impact there has been was an impact on cash flow, which was to the tune of 300 million. So, we didn't want our investors to, kind of, over emphasize on the cash flow realized in the first half of this year as there was a positive benefit from this change in distribution system. There was no impact on the recorded sales between first and second half in the U.S from this change in distribution system. What has happened in fact is that Novo Nordisk has now taken full control of the distribution channel in the U.S. where we previously was relying on distribution services conducted skillfully by Bristol-Myers Squibb. Now we have reached a size where we can safely and financially viably handle this ourselves and that transition took place 1st of July, and we now handle the entire distribution process also, and we have no problems in that respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Jesper and thank you Paol. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question will be from Michael Novod of Handelsbanken. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes hello gentlemen. Just a couple of questions, as a follow-up to the guidelines question, that's the last one, do you have any intelligence into the timing of these guidelines because when talking to the FDA it's very clear that it could take a very long time at least? They seem like that on the FDA. So maybe you have some timing guidance. And then secondly, could you give an update to the SoloSTAR litigations, both in the U.S. now we have the appeal over and done and what is the timing of a full verdict, and also in Germany?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Michael. Mads, are you aware of any commitments the FDA has given in terms of timelines for when they would be more firm on these discussions that we have just elaborated on? And Jesper would you comment on the status of the SoloSTAR litigation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well first of all Michael I think the FDA have themselves explicitly said that they are not giving guidance on the timelines that they have set for themselves to conclude upon this advisory committee that take took place, meeting that took place on July 1 and 2. Second of all, even if I did know the timing I would probably not be in a position to say it. But fact of the matter is that we are in a good dialogue with the agency and I can refer you to a remark made by Division Director Dr. Mary Parks during an interview in one of the journals not so long ago, that she has both been talking about the need for the FDA to take a case by case approach and also the notion that companies should be aware, and this also goes from Novo Nordisk, that there is obviously a difference between whether they are in a regulatory phase, as we are for Liraglutide or whether they are doing Phase II, III slash II, or III stage development for other compounds such as is the case for other Novo Nordisk pipeline compounds. They seem, in the FDA minds, considered differently from that perspective, but I think it's fair to say that it is not typical that the agency issues guidelines very shortly after having an advisory committee. We have had obesity drop guidelines, kind of, that de facto functioned but that never were formalized, so I think the agency themselves decide completely at their discretion if and when to conclude on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lars here, and before we just hand over to Jesper, it's also clear that this puts political pressure on the FDA. So which will prompt the FDA to be of course implementing new procedures, new practices along those conclusions, which was drawn at the committee meeting otherwise of course they draw up for themselves a larger responsibility. So, there will be some changes going forward and then we're looking forward to see how that transpires also for our own pipeline. Jesper, SoloSTAR?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the SoloSTAR litigation, the status is that Novo Nordisk has not in U.S or in Germany been able to convince the lower level courts that the SoloSTAR device infringes both U.S and EU patents that Novo Nordisk holds. We are now our waiting for both the U.S and the court in D&#xFC;sseldorf in Germany, we are waiting the written ruling from the court. We'll then study that written ruling and based on that we will decide on the future process. We would expect to get back to the market with our future strategy in that respect in connection with the Q3 release.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please and thank you Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Martin Parkh&#xF8;i of Danske Bank has our next question. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello Martin Parkh&#xF8;i, Danske Bank. Also the two questions, firstly respect to U.S insulin growth, which there was quite a deceleration to the insulin growth in the second quarter versus the first quarter, taking the half-year growth down to 21%. What kind of levels should we expect for U.S insulin growth for the full year and going forward as this has been one of the absolute key growth drivers for you and of course still is. And then secondly respect to long-term guidance, this year your adjusted operating margin will surpass the 25% target. When should we expect you to revise your long-term targets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Martin. Why don't we start with the last question first on the long-term guidance, when we will give you more visibility on this and then I will return on the U.S. insulin growth projections for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's right, Martin, that we now exceeded the 25% operating margin target and we probably would have exceeded significantly earlier, if we not had the decline in the U.S. dollar. That said, we put off those targets for giving guidance on a full-year basis and I think it is, with the current levels of exchange rate it seems likely that we will be able to achieve the long-term financial targets that we set out at the start of 2006 already at the end of 2008. And, based on that, you should expect us in our communication in connection with the full-year results, where it would be clear whether we have achieved those long-term targets, for us to provide new guidance going forward on another, say, around five year horizon, so that would be the timing for that.</p>
          <p>And then going back to the growth in the U.S., I just would like to highlight first that when you look at our reported numbers in terms of U.S. bear in mind that we last year had a non-recurring adjustment to our U.S. rebates regarding the Medicare set up with around 100 million, which was recorded in Q2 last year. So, you have to take that out when you look at the growth in the U.S. in particular, and then Lars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And then the comment I made before, Martin, about one-offs were primarily relating to the situation in the U.S. We see no shift change in market share developments for our products. But it is also clear that the competitive pressures have increased the share for us, or the demand for us in the marketplace with the launch of PPB for us, with continued effort behind LANTUS where they refocus on their insulin business has meant their market share gains are more difficult to come by than they were earlier. And that has implications of course immediately for our ability to continue to gain share, which is going to be more hard to come by, but also for the longer-term the ramp-up of our sales force in the U.S. prior to the launch of Liraglutide. So the numbers that you have seen in terms of growth in the U.S. in Q2 are not the growth targets that we are seeing. We are seeing 20% plus growth targets for the U.S. insulin market going forward, but so don't take any one quarter isolated. Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen let's have one last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question today comes from Sachin Jain of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sachin Jain from Merrill Lynch. Just back to, actually guidance, if I could Mads. And just firstly you got the Phase II once-weekly GLP-1 analogue coming in the first half of next year, how you are thinking about a potential Phase III study for that in terms of where we are with guidelines? And then maybe a little bit premature but just wonder if you had any thoughts there? And then just back to Liraglutide, again just some clarification. You said in your comments that many issues big and small remain. I just wonder if you could clarify what you view as big issues and where they are largely post approval. I think that's what you are suggesting and there is no discussion of any additional data. You're very clear on CV outcomes but no safety data from extension studies et cetera would be required? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Sachin, Mads, first off back to FDA  and one-offs and then finally big and small, what's big and what's small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well first of all Sachin, I didn't say we had many small and big issues, I said we expect many issues big and small to be discussed with the FDA. So I cannot state at this point that there are many issues big and small to be quite frank, fortunately you can say. But that being said this is the case for any regulatory dossier, there will be many issues and they will be big and they will be small.</p>
          <p>It is my belief that, based on what I know from our product, from the regulatory dossier and from our interactions, that the PDUFA action date, which is on March 23 last year is the one we are heading for and also hence planning for to get approval for the product. There will be many discussions and there will probably also, as for all drugs, be post-approval commitments. They can relate to the cardiovascular system and they can relate to other aspects that the agency finds relevant for us to risk mitigate via either clinical post-approval commitments or registries or other kinds of activities.</p>
          <p>So that's on the record side. On the once weekly, obviously it will be very interesting to see because there was absolutely no kind of, let's say, harmonization of views as to which things should be done pre-approval and which should be done post-approval at this advisory committee meeting. That's one of the big dilemmas for the agency, to work out will they continue down the line, as they did in their growth guidance document from February, stating that having a pre-approval commitment to do cardiovascular studies is done on a case-by-case basis when there is a safety cycle, or will they do it more broadly for so called type II diabetes drugs. In the latter case it could have implications for once we detail to one compound. In the former case, I would still argue that even for that compound cardiovascular assessment in the large scale should be done post-approval if and when we see the same cardiovascular features as we do for Liraglutide, but that is too early to speculate on, at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Mads. Thank you very much ladies and gentlemen, for listening in on this first half 2008 release, which, again, was in the focus of Liraglutide and I am sure that's going to be a main focus area for quite a number of quarters going forward, you will be able to revisit the conference call at our website. And we will be meeting with individuals in the extra couple of days. So and then in addition to that we have send out an invitation for our Capital Market Day for those of you that have the interest on the 26th of September, which is going to take place at Hiller&#xF8;d, which is our Biopharmaceutical and Device manufacturing site North Copenhagen. Thank you very much for listening in. Bye, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you ladies and gentlemen. That would conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>