<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1515352" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3044</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Science Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Jesper Brandgaard</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nordea Bank AB (Denmark)">Michael Novod</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Tim M. Race</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Richard B. Vosser</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Danske Bank A/S (Broker)">Martin Parkh&#xF8;i</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Amit Roy</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Sachin Jain</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Luisa C. Hector</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and welcome to Novo-Nordisk Conference Call regarding our performance in the first nine months of 2012 and an outlook for 2013.</p>
          <p>I'm Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen, the CEO of Novo-Nordisk. With me are Chief Financial Officer, Jesper Brandgaard; and Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen, our Chief Science Officer. Present are also our Investor Relations officers.</p>
          <p>Today's earnings release and the slides for the call are made available on our web page novonordisk.com. The conference is scheduled to last approximately one hour as usual. We'll start today, with the agenda outlined on slide number two. The Q&amp;A session will begin in about 25 minutes.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide number three. As always, I need to advise you that this call will contain forward-looking statements. Such forward-looking statements are subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause the actual result to differ materially from expectations. For further information on the risk factors, please see the earnings release and the slides prepared for this presentation. Please note that this conference call is being webcast live and a replay will be made available on our website.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number four. We're satisfied with the performance for the first nine months of this year. Sales increased 11% in local currencies compared to the same period in 2011. Sales growth was predominantly driven by the strong performance in North America and international operations. The key sales drivers have been our modern insulins and Victoza.</p>
          <p>Among the modern insulins in particular, NovoRapid and Levemir drives the growth. The regulatory review of Tresiba and Ryzodeg continue to progress in the major markets. In Japan, the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare approved Tresiba on September 28. We're currently in the process of negotiating price with the Japanese authorities. We expect to launch Tresiba once these negotiations have been concluded.</p>
          <p>In Europe, the Committee for Medicinal Products for Human Use [CHMP] issued a positive opinion on Tresiba and Ryzodeg on the 18th of October A formal marketing authorization from the European Committee is expected within a couple of months, after which, Tresiba will be launched in the first European markets.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. the FDA has confirmed that the Advisory Committee meeting for Tresiba and Ryzodeg will take place on November 8 this year. Further, the FDA has disclosed that the Advisory Committee meeting will focus on the benefits associated with lower risk of hypoglycemia and the cardiovascular risk profiles of the two products.</p>
          <p>Turning to financials, reported operating profit grew 34% and diluted earnings per share grew 31% in the first nine months. Reflecting the strong sales performance in the first nine months, we have increased our expectations to sales growth for the full-year to the range of 10% to 12% in local currencies compared growth expectations of 9% to 12% when we released the second quarter results on August 9.</p>
          <p>We have also increased our expectations for operating profit growth as we now expect growth of 16% to 18% measured in local currencies. Previously our expectations were around 15%.</p>
          <p>The preliminary outlook for 2013 indicates high single-digit growth in both sales and operating profit as measured in local currencies. The outlook reflects an expected positive contribution from Tresiba primarily the United States, EU and Japan countered by impact from the challenging operating environment in major markets. In addition, the outlook for operating profit reflects significant costs related to the expected launch of Tresiba.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number five, in the first nine months of this year, North America accounted for 64% of growth followed by international operations accounting for 20% growth both measured in local currencies. Sales growth in North America was 19% in local currencies reflecting the continued robust market penetration of our modern insulins, in particular, NovoLog and Levemir. Victoza also continues to perform well despite the launch of a competing product. Sales growth in Europe in the first nine months was 2%, measured both in local and reported currencies.</p>
          <p>Sales development reflects continued solid performance of Victoza and progress for the portfolio of modern insulins. Sales growth remains negatively impacted by declining sales of human insulin, low insulin volume growth as well as healthcare pricing reforms.</p>
          <p>Sales within international operations grew 16% in local currencies driven by continued penetration of all three modern insulins, robust human insulin sales growth, and continued expansion of the GLP-1 market. Sales in Japan and Korea were unchanged in local currencies when compared to the first nine months of 2011. Sales development in Japan and Korea reflects a negative impact from lack of insulin volume growth and a continued challenging competitive environment.</p>
          <p>Sales in the Region China increased 17% in local currencies in the first nine months, growth was driven by our modern insulins, especially NovoLog mix, while sales growth of NovoNorm, our tablet based treatment for Type 2 diabetes also contributed significantly to growth in China.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number six, the modern insulins continue to see a double-digit growth rate and Victoza continues also a steady growth trajectory. First nine months, the diabetes care franchise grew 15% while the biopharmaceutical franchise grew 1% both measured in local currencies. Modern insulins were the primary growth drivers accounting for 54% of growth while Victoza accounted for 45% of growth in local currencies. Sales of NovoSeven decreased 1% compared to the same period last year when measured in local currencies. The market for NovoSeven remains negatively impacted by stricter budgetary controls and the increase in inhibitor patients participating in clinical trials.</p>
          <p>Sales of Norditropin increased 8% measured in local currencies. The sales growth is mainly driven by North America and international operations. Novo Nordisk remains the second largest company in the global growth hormone market with a volume of market share of 24%.</p>
          <p>Turn to the next slide, in the last five years the insulin market has grown more than 15% in value on annual basis. The growth in value has been driven by an annual 7% underlying volume growth and the gradual shift from human to modern insulins as well as increased penetration of devices.</p>
          <p>In the growing insulin market, Novo Nordisk has successfully been able to sustain its strong position. Today, the company holds around 46% of the modern insulin market, measured in volume.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 8 for an update on Victoza. Sales of Victoza reached DKK 6.8 billion in the first nine months, this reflects steady sales performance across all regions. Victoza continues to exhibit solid sales growth rates with an average quarterly increase of approximately DKK 200 million.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. Victoza continues to be encouraging, despite the launch of a competitor product. Victoza is gradually increasing its market share and now accounting for 59% of the GLP-1s current in the U.S. Victoza's capture rate for new GLP-1 patient has also gradually increasing now also 59%. In Europe, we continue to see strong uptake for Victoza across all the key markets and Victoza remains the leading GLP-1 product with a market share of 75%.</p>
          <p>Then, I'd like to hand it over to Mads, who'll give you an update on research and development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide. Let me start with an update on the insulin degludec products. The regulatory reviews for Tresiba, the intended brand name for insulin degludec, and Ryzodeg, the intended brand name for the insulin degludec/insulin aspart combination, continue to progress well.</p>
          <p>In Japan, Tresiba was, as mentioned, approved in September and launch is expected as soon as price negotiations have been completed. On October 18, the Japanese agency, PMDA published their assessment report for Tresiba, representing the first extensive data review of the global regulatory dossier for Tresiba.</p>
          <p>In Europe, the Committee for Medicinal Products for Human Use under the European Medicines Agency, EMA, adopted positive opinions for Tresiba and Ryzodeg in the treatment of diabetes on October 18. Novo Nordisk expects to receive final marketing authorization from the European Commission late this year.</p>
          <p>The expected EU label for Tresiba will reflect that the very long and predictable pharmacological action profile of insulin degludec is associated with a reduction in the occurrence of overall and nocturnal hypoglycemia versus insulin glargine across a pool of Type 1 and Type 2 diabetes trials. It will also reflect the enhanced patient convenience associated with the ability to vary the time of injection between days, as well as the ability to administer doses of up to 160 units in one single injection.</p>
          <p>Recently, the Federal Commission for the Protection against Sanitary Risk, i.e., the regulatory agency COFEPRIS in Mexico, approved Tresiba and Ryzodeg for the treatment of diabetes. Novo Nordisk expects to launch Tresiba in Mexico following pricing and reimbursement negotiations.</p>
          <p>In the United States, the FDA has confirmed that the Advisory Committee meeting to discuss the safety and efficacy of the NDAs for Tresiba and Ryzodeg will take place on November 8. On October 25, the FDA further disclosed that the focus of discussion at the meeting would be an assessment of the benefits associated with the low risk of hypoglycemia and the cardiovascular risk profile of the two products.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide. Novo-Nordisk has previously demonstrated significant clinical benefits of combining the use of long-acting GLP-1 and insulin analogues in Type 2 diabetes patients and were adequately controlled on all anti-diabetic agents as well as in the population in need of intensification of GLP-1 therapy.</p>
          <p>Now Novo Nordisk has completed a 26-week treat-to-target extension to the "Once long" placebo study for 3579 in patients with Type 2 diabetes. The extension study evaluated the efficacy and safety of adding one daily injection of Victoza or NovoRapid to patients above an HBA1c of 7% on placebo treatment at the start of the extension as well as assessing the durability of Tresiba plus metformin treatment in patients being below an HBA1c of 7% at the start of the trial extension.</p>
          <p>Patients in the extension trial were, in fact, in their third year of treatment since they had previously participated in the one-year comparative study investigating insulin degludec and glargine as well as the one-year extension of this insulin comparison. From a baseline HBA1c of 7.7% in both randomized treatment arms, the group randomized to Victoza treatment achieved a significantly lower end of trial HBA1c of 7% compared to 7.3% for patients treated with once daily NovoRapid at the main meal. Furthermore, patients treated with Victoza experienced a significantly lower rate of both overall and nocturnal hypoglycemia compared to patients treated with NovoRapid.</p>
          <p>With regard to body weight, patients treated with Victoza achieved a weight loss of 2 kilograms whereas the patients treated with NovoRapid experienced a slight weight increase.</p>
          <p>From an HBA1c of 6.4% at the start of the trial extension, the non-randomized patients continuing Tresiba treatment in combination with metformin experienced a stable HBA1c throughout the treatment period, ending with an A1c of 6.5%. Rates of overall and nocturnal hypoglycemia were low and indeed comparable to rates previously observed for Tresiba. Moreover, the Tresiba patients experienced no weight gain during the extension trial.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, the excellent clinical results from treatment with Tresiba in the BEGIN program are confirmed. And furthermore patients that needed intensification experienced clear and significant benefits following the addition of Victoza therapy for six months.</p>
          <p>In general, the safety and tolerability profiles of Tresiba, Victoza and NovoRapid were confirmed in this extension trial.</p>
          <p>In October, Novo Nordisk initiated the first Phase I trial for OG987SC, the fourth oral GLP-1 project brought into clinical development. The Phase I trial will investigate safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics of single oral doses of the long-acting GLP-1 analog in healthy volunteers.</p>
          <p>Let's now move to biopharmaceuticals R&amp;D. During the last two months, both the European Commission and the Swiss Agency for Therapeutic Products, Swissmedic, have approved NovoThirteen, a recombinant factor XIII product. The product was approved for once-monthly prophylactic treatment of congenital factor XIII A-subunit deficiency in patients above the age of six years.</p>
          <p>NovoThirteen will be the only recombinant treatment option for this rare disease. Novo Nordisk expects to launch NovoThirteen in the first European countries towards the end of the year.</p>
          <p>In October, Novo Nordisk submitted a regulatory application for turoctocog alfa to the EMA and FDA. Turoctocog alfa is a novel recombinant coagulation Factor VIII molecule intended for prevention and treatment of bleeding in people with hemophilia A.</p>
          <p>In September, Novo-Nordisk announced the decision to discontinue the development of vatreptacog alfa for hemophilia patients with inhibitors. The decision follows analysis of the data from the Phase III trial in which a few patients developed anti-drug antibodies to the vatreptacog alfa. None of the antibodies were clinically inhibitory, and the patients responded well to treatment during the course of the trial.</p>
          <p>In October, Novo-Nordisk initiated a Phase IIa trial for recombinant Factor XIII for the treatment of ulcerative colitis. The rationale for investigating factor XIII in this indication is on the one hand that factor XIII has exhibited tissue regenerative potential in models of the disease, and on the other hand, that ulcerative colitis is associated with reduced levels of circulating Factor XIII.</p>
          <p>In this Phase II trial, Factor XIII treatment will take place in patients with mild to moderate disease, and Factor XIII is approved for congenital factor XIII A-subunit deficiency now in EU, Canada and Switzerland.</p>
          <p>In September, Novo-Nordisk initiated the first Phase IIa trial with Anti-Interleukin-21 for the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis. The trial will evaluate the effect of Anti-IL-21 compared to placebo in patients with active rheumatoid arthritis on a background of methotrexate therapy.</p>
          <p>Finally, in October, Novo-Nordisk initiated the first Phase I trial with Anti-IL-21 for the treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. The trial will evaluate the safety and tolerability of Anti-IL-21 in patients with this disease.</p>
          <p>With that, over to you, Jesper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mads.</p>
          <p>Please turn to slide 11. In the first nine months of 2012, sales increased by 18% measured in Danish kroner to DKK 57.1 billion and by 11% in local currencies compared to the first nine months of 2011. The reported gross margin improved by 150 basis point to 81.9% in the first nine months of 2012.</p>
          <p>The improvement is mainly due to a favorable price development in North America more than offsetting the price pressure experienced in markets like Europe. We also see a positive impact on product mix due to increased sales of modern insulin and Victoza. The improvement in the gross margin is further supported by a positive impact from currencies of 80 basis points.</p>
          <p>Total non-production related costs increased by 11% in Danish kroner to DKK 25.4 billion and by 7% in local currencies. S&amp;D costs increased by 13% to DKK 15.4 billion and by 7% in local currencies. Growth in local currencies is primarily driven by the expansion of the U.S. sales force and other costs to prepare for the global launch of Tresiba.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, costs increased due to sales and marketing investments in selected countries in <mark type="ph" /> IO (16:50) as well as the Chinese sales force expansion that was completed mid-2011. Growth in selling and distribution cost is partially offset by a reversal of provisions made for legal disputes.</p>
          <p>Research and development costs increase by 12% to DKK 7.7 billion and by 9% in local currencies mainly driven by development costs related to the ongoing Phase III trials for liraglutide on obesity and the Phase IIIA trial for IDegLira. Within biopharmaceuticals R&amp;D costs are primarily related to the continued progress of the portfolio of development projects within hemophilia and the Phase II trial for Anti-IL-20 in rheumatoid arthritis.</p>
          <p>Operating profit increased by 34% in the first nine months of 2012 to DKK 22 billion. In local currencies, the growth was 21%.</p>
          <p>Net financial showed an expense of DKK 1.543 billion in the first nine months of 2012 compared to an expense of DKK 179 million in the first nine months of 2011. In line with Novo-Nordisk treasury policy, the most significant foreign exchange risk for the group has been hedged primarily through foreign currency contracts.</p>
          <p>Reflecting the portfolio of foreign currency exchange hedging contracts, the foreign exchange results was an expense of DKK 1.455 million compared to an expense of DKK 109 million during the same period of 2011. This development reflects losses on foreign exchange hedging involving especially the U.S. dollar and the Japanese yen due to their appreciation versus Danish kroner compared to the exchange rate level prevailing in 2011. The effective tax rate for the first nine months of 2012 was 23%.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide. The two graphs illustrate the development of the U.S. dollar and the Japanese yen versus the Danish kroner. The tables on the right show the annual impact on operating profit of a 5% movement in each of our key invoicing currencies and the current exchange of hedging for the same currencies.</p>
          <p>During the first nine months of 2012, the average exchange rate for the U.S. dollar versus the Danish kroner was approximately 8% above the level prevailing in 2011. The Japanese yen likewise was approximately 9% above the level in 2011. At present, the value of the U.S. dollar and the Japanese yen is in line with the average 2012 year-to-date levels.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide. Novo-Nordisk now expects sales growth in 2012 of 10% to 12% measured in local currencies. This is based on the expectation of continued market penetration of Novo Nordisk's key products, as well as expectations for continued intense competition and impact from the implementation of healthcare and pricing reforms. Given the current level of exchange rate versus Danish kroner, the reported sales growth is now expected to be around 6 percentage points higher than the growth measured in local currencies.</p>
          <p>For 2012, expectation for operating profit growth is increased to 16% to 18% growth measured in local currencies. The expectation for a high level of operating profit growth reflects the increased expectations for sales growth.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, the outlook for operating profit growth reflects a significant increase in costs in the fourth quarter of 2012 driven by launch preparations for Tresiba, the expanded U.S. sales force as well as sales and marketing investments in China and a selected number of countries in international operations.</p>
          <p>Given the current level of exchange rates versus Danish kroner, the reported operating profit growth is now expected to be around 11 percentage points higher than the growth measured in local currencies.</p>
          <p>For 2012, Novo Nordisk now expects a net financial expense of around DKK 1.7 billion reflecting a net loss on the foreign exchange hedging contracts following the appreciation of the U.S. dollar and the Japanese yen versus the Danish kroner compared to the exchange rates prevailing in 2011.</p>
          <p>The expectations for losses related to currency hedging contracts is more than offset by the expected significant positive impact on reported operating profit from the appreciation of invoicing currencies versus Danish kroner. The effective tax rate for 2012 is still expected to be around 23%.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures are also still expected to be around DKK 3.5 billion in 2012 primarily related to investments in filling capacity and prefilled device production facility in Denmark. Expectations for depreciation, amortization and impairment losses are still around DKK 2.9 billion and free cash flow is still expected to be around DKK 19 billion reflecting significant tax payments expected in the fourth quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>With regard to the financial outlook for 2013, Novo-Nordisk expects to provide detailed guidance on expectations in connection with the release of the full year financial results for 2012 on January 31, 2013. At present, the preliminary plans for 2013 indicate high single-digit percentage point growth in sales and operating profit both measured in local currencies.</p>
          <p>The outlook reflects expectations for continued penetration of the portfolio of modern insulins, continued growth for the Victoza franchise and a positive sales contribution from Tresiba primarily in the U.S., EU and Japan. These sales drivers will be partly countered by the impact from a challenging pricing environment in major markets, generic competition to oral anti-diabetic products, intensifying competition within both diabetes care and biopharmaceuticals as well as the macroeconomic conditions in a number of markets in international operations.</p>
          <p>In addition, the outlook for operating profit reflects significant costs related to the expected global launch of Tresiba. At the current exchange rate, reported growth in sales and operating profit is expected to be in line with the growth measured in local currencies.</p>
          <p>All of the above expectations are based on the assumption that the global economic environment will not significantly change business conditions for Novo-Nordisk during the remaining part of 2012 and into 2013 and that currency exchange rates, especially the U.S. dollar will remain at the current level versus the Danish kroner.</p>
          <p>This concludes the financial update. Now, back to you, Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jesper.</p>
          <p>We're now moving to the Q&amp;A part. Operator, we are ready to take the first question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will now take our first question from Michael Novod from Nordea. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. It's Michael Novod from Nordea Markets in Copenhagen. Just two questions.</p>
          <p>Can you elaborate a bit on how you expect the GLP-1 competition to pan out going forward? What kind of impact you do see now, if you see any, from the, say, complete sales force of AstraZeneca and Bristol-Myers on Bydureon and how you see the landscape going forward?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, to the cost levels, I know there is a reversal of a provision in Q3 but still, if you look at other cost lines like admin, they are very, very low. Is that a reasonable level going forward i.e. around the 4%? Maybe you can comment on that and also the remaining part of the cost lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Michael. This is Lars Rebien here. I'll take the question about GLP-1 competition and then Jesper, if you would care to comment on the peculiarities in Q3 and the slightly low development in admin cost and how that goes going forward.</p>
          <p>With regards to GLP-1 competition, it is basically panning out much the way in which we predicted it would be panning out. I believe we said actually a couple of years ago that we anticipate that we get 60% and competition would get 40%. And the fact that these two companies have now bought out Amylin and taken over, in our view, does not materially change that competitive situation as the competitive situation is determined by the perception of the active ingredient, the molecule where we have repeatedly demonstrated that our Victoza is a more efficacious product and given then their current formulation and administration regime we find it difficult to foresee that they should radically change the current trend.</p>
          <p>So for now &#x2013; and also because we have expanded our sales force in United States and so we have significant firing power, so to speak, in the U.S., it's our anticipation that the development in market share will continue much like we see it right now in spite of BMS and AstraZeneca joining forces. It would require for them to either come up with a significant improved administration system or better for them, a complete reformulation to bring them out of the current situation and we believe that is going to be some time in the making.</p>
          <p>So no change on current trends in the next 12 months, perhaps even longer.</p>
          <p>Jesper?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lars. If I take the individual lines of cost and just give some flavor to the guidance for 2012 on how the development is going to be in individual cost line. And if we start with the cost of goods sold, we stick to the guidance we had given for 2012 which is 50 to 100 basis points improvement in underlying cost margins and we now see with the current rates, approximately 60 basis points in positive currency impact hitting the &#x2013; or the gross margin level.</p>
          <p>On the S&amp;D line, it is correct that we have had a positive development on the selling group costs this year from reversals of prior made provisions relating legal disputes. One of these legal disputes were known to the market which was related to the case we had on compensation of U.S. sales forces for overtime where luckily the U.S. supreme court ruled in June, in a case very similar to Novo Nordisk, that such liabilities didn't exist for people employed under medical rep-like conditions and as a consequence of that, during Q2 and Q3, the provisions we have made for these cases have been reversed following the dismissal of those cases at court level.</p>
          <p>So if we look at 2012 up until now, we've had a reversal of legal provisions in the magnitude of $60 million to $70 million, and I've just mentioned the most significant one, just to give you a feel for what is it that makes these provisions move and this is actually actual rulings in specific cases that made this reversal.</p>
          <p>Then on the R&amp;D line, you can anticipate an R&amp;D ratio for the full year around 14%. It's correct that the growth this year so far has been slightly lower than the underlying growth in sales. We've seen a growth in the ballpark of 9% whereas the sales in local currency have been growing 11%. Of course when we do the plan, we cannot do the plan in local currencies and we are clearly benefiting on the R&amp;D ratio from this very significant currency effect as we have a higher proportion of our R&amp;D costs in the Eurozone.</p>
          <p>So we did in 2011 have some non-recurring costs included in our R&amp;D partly related to the discontinuation of our insulin <mark type="ph" /> test comb (30:19) project. And if you adjust for those non-recurring items a year before, the growth in our underlying R&amp;D cost has been very close to the level of growth in sales at around 11%. So that matches pretty well.</p>
          <p>Then the final line, the R&amp;D line &#x2013; sorry, the admin line, it is unusually low in the first three quarters of this year and that really has to do with some adjustments between the individual cost line and the admin line is very small, so small adjustments there actually do make a meaningful change to the totality. If you adjust for that and a non-recurring item regarding a repayment of a fine paid some five years ago, then you are looking at an underlying growth level in our admin cost at the level of around 2%.</p>
          <p>So ascribe the other factors this year to be of a non-recurring nature and hence, I would more see our admin costs in the ballpark of probably around 4.5%, which I do feel is a very positive development. And I should also just note for the admin cost that going into next year, we are anticipating a slightly higher growth in admin cost as we, in 2013, will have non-recurring costs relating to a relocation both in the U.S. to a new office facility and also towards the end of the year a relocation of the headquarter here in Bagsvaerd.</p>
          <p>So that will bring admin cost side to be up next year not to the level in sales but slightly higher percentage point than what we've been used to in the last few years. So that was quite elaborate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Jesper for that detailed picture. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Tim Race from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, guys. Tim Race of Deutsche Bank.</p>
          <p>First question is just on the 2013 outlook. Could you just sort of detail out what you're expecting in terms of Prandin for 2013? Also what you're pricing in for Tresiba sales launch costs as well as, is there anything included in there in terms of extra studies in R&amp;D? I presume you can't tell us about that at the moment.</p>
          <p>Then just over questions from Mads on the GLP-1s, you've now got four orals in development, could you just talk through the differences between them? And what does this all say about your confidence in any one strategy? I saw there was some other data from Merrion this morning. So any comment on that as well?</p>
          <p>And just a question on China, I see Newswire comments suggesting that you're seeing pricing challenges in the EU and it mentioned China as well. You grew 42% in China in the third quarter so is there something on the horizon here? Or is this just a misquote? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Jesper, you deal with the outlook for 2013 and how we have included &#x2013; to what extent we have included Prandin and Tresiba, what kind of cost have we included and if any sales, and I don't know whether Mads wants to comment on potential studies for Tresiba. Then Mads, if you can comment on the GLP-1 and any competitive developments in the oral space then I'm going to comment on situation in China.</p>
          <p>Jesper?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lars. We've delivered the chosen, as for the top line growth in local currency to go with &#x2013; judged in historic terms, slightly cautious growth level of a high single-digit. Of course, high single-digit can cover a wide variety of percentages, but included in there is an assumption that we will see generic competition occurring to Prandin in the U.S. and it's approximately DKK 1 billion that is potentially exposed to generic competition in the U.S. a little bit depending on when that occurs later in 2012 or into 2013.</p>
          <p>In terms of Tresiba, I don't think Tresiba on operating profit will have a significant impact. We'd certainly expect it to have a positive impact on sales and it is expected that we will certainly launch in Japan and Europe, and we'll also assume that we'll get on to the market in the U.S. but clearly we will have more clarity on that. But the range implied in the high single-digit percentage point to account for various outcomes of the advisory panel in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Of course, as we are only predicting for 2013 that we are growing costs in line with sales, we are assuming that we will be able to handle the launch of Tresiba within the guidance we have provided here, but there will be a clear correlation between the cost level and whether &#x2013; and for a point in time the launch in the U.S. occurs of Tresiba.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much, Jesper and then on to GLP-1 and potentially all version for that, Mads.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And before I do so, Lars, just a quick comment, I mean, you have to imagine that for Tresiba and Ryzodeg, the company is dedicated to do a large number of Phase IIIB trials. Some of them we have already concluded clinically, but a whole range that are in the works, so to speak. They include studies that seek to further expand the label into more combination therapeutic modalities. Studies that will look at specific populations, studies that will add to the therapeutic guidance that we can already give the patients as to how to simplify titration and so on and so forth and ultimately we could also be looking into conducting outcome studies, that is all within the realm of what Novo-Nordisk is looking into for Tresiba.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the oral GLP-1 analogues and their carriers, it is true that our collaborator Michael Donnelly, Chairman of Merrion has announced the successful outcome of the Phase I trial using the GIPET Technology. And as you know, what Novo-Nordisk is doing is working with Merrion and working with another company, Elsevier, and working with our own technology to actually provide carrier systems that facilitate the transfer across the gut barrier into the circulation of GLP-1 molecules that have been designed to be resistant towards acid and enzymatic degradation in the GI tract.</p>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; now that we have no less than four oral GLP-1 Phase I projects, it is not because the other ones are failing, so to speak, because the one that has just been announced by Merrion was indeed a successful one. It is more because we seek to constantly optimize the use, for instance, of the GIPET Technology. The GIPET Technology can be used with a very full coating of the tablet and with a smaller coating of the tablet and so on and so forth. And before Novo-Nordisk were to decide hopefully next year to make the decision to enter into Phase II trials with such an agent we, of course, seek to optimize based on human studies, the pharmaceutical characteristics of those tablets then we will take into Phase II. Indeed, I would have to say that we're actually encouraged by the data we've seen so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mads. Then on to the situation in China, yes, we had a stellar performance in the third quarter in China. And this is of course to some extent because we had such a poor third quarter in 2011 due to the healthcare reforms which were enacted in the summer time of 2011. In fact, our sales slightly declined in China in the third quarter of 2011 and on that background, we are back to growth trajectory in China.</p>
          <p>If we look overall on the situation in China, it sort of resembles in some way &#x2013; the price inflation resembles Europe. We had a negative drag on pricing in China due to competition in particular human insulins and going forward, the main potential negative overhang we have in China is an expected review of pricing and reimbursement on modern insulin which could have a future negative impact on our business. But I mean let's enjoy it while lasts. We had a good quarter and we believe that our business is going to come up for the year approximately, we indicated about 15% growth and that's where we're trending at the moment.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Richard Vosser from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Richard Vosser from JPMorgan. Two questions on Tresiba please.</p>
          <p>Just wondering, now you've seen the label for Japan, obviously, and have a very good idea of the labeling in Europe. Just your thoughts on pricing and the premiums in these markets and what sort of premium you will get and how that could have &#x2013; how you were thinking about that affecting the speed of launch?</p>
          <p>And then connected to that, just in terms of the volume versus price dynamics in the emerging markets particularly, you've mentioned that we could see a price or negative price in China, just how you are thinking about that with respect to Tresiba when that comes to market in the emerging markets? Is there a risk that by maximizing price that you're going to miss out on a significant amount of volume and, hence, the launch in emerging markets could be relatively slow? That's it. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. First of all, let me allow Mads Krogsgaard to talk a little bit about the Japanese label, Health Technology Assessment and the like and then we're going to give you some comments on the overall pricing strategy, of course, within the competitive realms, as it is possible, given that we're just standing in front of the launch. So Mads first and then over to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, Richard, it is indeed true that we know in great detail about the European and the Japanese label for these products. We cannot announce it in great detail until the Commission officially has stamped it, of course, and approved it. But what we have included in the Phase III trials is very extensive health economic outcome research measures both pertaining to efficacy, hypoglycemia and quality of life and other elements, you can say qualities, such as included in the SF-36 analysis that has been, as you know, adopted across a range of these trials.</p>
          <p>Also, assessments of the cost of blood glucose measurement and the ability to decrease that based on, you can say, the simplicity of the treatment. All of this has been put in together and based on the data in Phase III, we actually can justify a premium based on the merits and the calculations that are done and some have been submitted already to agencies in Europe that allow for, you can say, pre-launch submissions of regulatory or health technology dossiers. The price premium that we feel can be justified we cannot disclose at this point, but they are, of course, clearly relevant based on the data and that will be much more be subject to &#x2013; you could see negotiation between us and the agencies and the subsequent reimbursement discussions. But that is ongoing in Japan right now, by the way and in Europe the first countries have received their health technology dossiers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and this is Lars here so what you should be &#x2013; our anticipation is that we would be able to conclude the price negotiations in Japan within the next couple of months allowing us to get on the market in Japan.</p>
          <p>In regard to Europe the pricing situation in Europe is far more challenging, as we have seen historically over the quarters. And therefore the anticipation is that it's going to be more difficult for us in Europe.</p>
          <p>In Europe on the other hand we also, we have a very, very strong label suggesting the benefits of the product. So it is not completely far-fetched that we &#x2013; especially also when you consider daily treatment cost for people on chronic disease like diabetes &#x2013; really for us, we're talking about a couple of euros. So it is not like a cancer therapy or MS drugs or anything in that order of magnitude. But the premium itself in Europe will be causing some concerns on the part of some of the authorities.</p>
          <p>And you're then mentioning emerging markets, and to what extent is that, and of course, it's going to exacerbate the difficulties of getting products penetrating into emerging markets. And first of all, let me say that in China we've not gotten approval yet because it's just in Phase III clinical study in China now, so there's still going to be a few years before we will be able to enter into China.</p>
          <p>Other emerging markets, it's typically such that there are private markets; there are public markets. In the public markets, even if we were to go with the relatively low price, we wouldn't be selling Tresiba anyway.</p>
          <p>So Tresiba initially will be addressed towards patients in the private markets that have either the ability to afford it or the ability through insurance to buy this. So it's much more going to resemble the marketing of Victoza, which is starting to become meaningful also in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>And then hopefully, as the product gets more well known, there will be increasing tendency that also public insurance schemes will be offering this. But then we would be looking probably more at countries like Northern Africa, like Mexico and like Turkey, like Brazil, and whereas the Southeast Asian markets, we have to assume that's going to be years before we see any major penetration there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just a slight clarification, in terms of China, we would intend to use the final approval in Europe to file for approval of the Phase III trials in China to start the regulatory process there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you Jesper and Mads. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Martin Parkh&#xF8;i from Danske Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Martin Parkh&#xF8;i from Danske Bank. Just two questions.</p>
          <p>First, in respect to your high single digit sales guidance for 2013, if you look at your growth numbers on a regional level in the third quarter, it's basically all over the place, very big volatility from market to market.</p>
          <p>Could you go into a little bit more &#x2013; what have you assumed for markets, which markets are that actually will decelerate compared to 2011? Of course, I know &#x2013; sorry, 2012. Of course, I know with U.S. and Prandin. And how much have you included from a healthcare impact in your top-line guidance for 2013?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, with respect Victoza in Q4 last year, we saw a reversal of rebate in the fourth quarter. Could something similar or to a smaller extent happen in the fourth quarter of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Jesper, if you'd prepare to answer the &#x2013; as well as you can, because we're not giving already non-regional guidance on 2013 sales. But clearly, the main growth markets are North America and emerging markets and China. So you comment on that.</p>
          <p>With regard to Victoza, no, we're not anticipating reversals to the same extent as we saw them last year in the fourth quarter in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My reply, Lars, is going to be almost exactly what you said. This is a preliminary guidance at this point in time.</p>
          <p>It's clear that the growth in local currencies, same currency is going to be very modest in both Japan, Korea, and Europe. The growth will be driven by markets like China, international operations growing in the ballpark of 15% and North America getting closer to that.</p>
          <p>And North America having benefited in 2012 from a low level of impact from healthcare reform. And also benefiting especially from winning of contracts in relation to institutions like CVS Caremark, et cetera. We don't have any knowledge of such significant contract wins for the New Year so that should, everything else in same currencies, bring North America a bit down. So that would be factors.</p>
          <p>And then you mentioned Prandin yourself and then let's get the full year numbers and we'll give some more details to the guidance on the individual markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. This is Lars here. I would say that in my assessment the biggest <mark type="ph" /> productivity (47:26) is in the U.S. where we have both the uncertainty around the launch of Tresiba. We have Prandin on/off, as we've had in previous years, and then we have a competitive situation, which is quite volatile in the sense that we have gained this year and who knows what's going to happen going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually I forgot to mention, he also talked &#x2013; Martin asked about the impact from pricing and healthcare reforms, and we've been going at a running rate of around 1.5 percentage points on total sales in 2012, and my anticipation is that it's not going to be lower in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jesper. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Amit Roy from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Thank you. Amit Roy from Nomura. A couple of questions around the hypoglycemic claim of Tresiba.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> We noticed (48:20) in the Phase III study, on the type 1 patients, the baseline characteristics of the patients who haven't have drug yet but are on the Lantus arm is quite different in shape and time compared to the baseline characteristics of the patients in the degludec arm. So their actual blood sugar levels. When you look at the type 2 study, they're perfectly matched and you get a nice result.</p>
          <p>So I'm just trying to understand, is there any reason or any answer to why the baseline shape, the shape of the glucose profile is so completely different between the Lantus and degludec arm before they start treatment. That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And second question, just around the Victoza sales. And I appreciate that you've given so much geographical information that you have kindly let us know there's about 63% from the U.S. When we look at the IMS sales figures, which are obviously only an estimate, for yourself, for Victoza, you see good growth in the U.S. But if I sort of back out the rest of the world sales &#x2013; I appreciate there is also currency involved in that estimation &#x2013; the European or I should say the rest of the world sales number seems to be not be growing as strongly.</p>
          <p>Is that a fair thing to say? Or could we at least get a feel as to how the non-U.S. growth of Victoza is going? Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much. We had a little bit of a poor reception here. So we may not completely have gotten all your question but we'll start with Mads who's going to try to address the issue of Type 1 and the baseline characteristics of those on degludec versus Lantus, and then the Type 2 patients, which were a better match in your assessment. And then we'll get back to Victoza, if we want to give any comments on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, first of all, the biggest study in the studies that was published in the last 3583 base of bolus-type 1 diabetes study, it was actually a big study in almost 700 patients that was, quite frankly, well-matched in terms of the baseline characteristics.</p>
          <p>Obviously you can never get a total match in terms of A1C, BMI, duration of disease, passing plasma glucose. There were no major differences.</p>
          <p>You can actually argue &#x2013; the thing that Novo Nordisk could probably have done even more pertinent would actually have been to ensure that the patients who came in on prior therapy that had been split on a twice daily basal dosing, which we know occurs in about 1 in 4 to 1 in 5 patients with type 1 diabetes, that they should have had a 20% reduction in their degludec dose as they did for Lantus.</p>
          <p>This would have given less hypoglycemia in the running phase and is something that we have learned for future trials that when patients are on a twice-daily previous regimen of basal insulin, they should de facto have a dose reduction, and this is also being recommended in the way that we will reposition for Type 1 diabetes.</p>
          <p>Other than that, when you look into the maintenance period where you see &#x2013; you can say that the true benefits of the products, you do see there's a 25% risk reduction for the nocturnal hypoglycemia that is actually increased in the steady-state period.</p>
          <p>And moreover in Type 1 diabetes, we have to realize that the vast majority, between 80% and 90% of the overall 24-hour hypoglycemic episodes are related to the bolus component. And here it's important to mention that the bolus insulin was given at approximately the same unit amounts in both the glargine and the degludec arms, and henceforth, even in terms of insulin dosing, the arms were pretty well-matched.</p>
          <p>So I would argue that what you should look at in the Type 1 study is nocturnal hypoglycemia because this is where you could wash out the effect of the three-day bolus insulins, and you should do so in well-matched groups, and we actually believe that the groups are well matched here.</p>
          <p>Obviously we will consider doing studies where we &#x2013; just like Lantus was titrated down with 20% in patients who came from a previous therapy, that we would do the same for degludec such that we got even less hypoglycemia in the running period.</p>
          <p>That will be my comment at this point. Overall, well-matched studies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mads. Then on to Victoza sales, without giving you sort of a complete accurate numbers, U.S. is of course still constituting the majority of the share with about probably 60% of the sales coming from the U.S.</p>
          <p>And the growth rate in non-U.S. sales, if you look outside of Europe, is of course, quite significant. Japan, the takeoff is slightly less than what we see in other markets. And you know the reason for this. We had a very unfortunate situation in the initial launch of our product in Japan where, due to some erroneous medical advice, some patients got hurt in switching from insulin to Victoza, whereas in other emerging markets, sales have been growing strongly &#x2013; more than 100%, in fact, in recent quarters.</p>
          <p>So they're becoming noticeable and sizeable.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Sachin Jain from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Sachin Jain from Bank of America. A couple of question please.</p>
          <p>Firstly, as we think about next week, I wonder if you could remind us when you plan the Tresiba BEGIN and <mark type="ph" /> BOOST (53:57) studies, could you recount what discussions you had with FDA around degludec being outside of the diabetes CV guidelines? Any perspective that you might have through discussions of that might be changing in their thought process?</p>
          <p>Secondly on a hemophilia Factor VIII long-acting that you have, Biogen has just put out headline data for its product, and the average dosing for its drug was dosing through 3.5 days. I wonder if you could just remind us, Mad, what dosing interval you were planning to achieve within your Phase III study? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Sachin. Mads, I guess it's you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And surprisingly, AdCom [Advisory Committee] next week.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So Sachin, if I drove back in time to the point where we were at in the Phase II meetings and discussions with the FDA vis-&#xE0;-vis Phase III design and adherence on non-adherence to the CV guidelines from the ATT so on and so forth, it was a clear discussions and also conclusion between FDA and Novo Nordisk that this was an insulin, and being an injectable insulin, it should not, per se, adhere to the CV guidelines.</p>
          <p>When that was said &#x2013; and that also means that the classical confidence levels with the upper and lower 95% bounds being &#x2013; not exceeding 1.8 pre-approval and also 1.3 post-approval <mark type="ph" /> since restrict to, (55:19) were not to be adhered to.</p>
          <p>When that was said, it was also a clear agreement that we should do an adjudication of all the MACEs that were reported by a blinded committee, such that we did as professionally as possible the study even though it was designed for glycemic purposes and not for cardiovascular outcomes purposes.</p>
          <p>So that was the discussion then, and that is also the circumstance under which of course that you will be looking at this whole cardiovascular discussion we expect on next Thursday. And there haven't been any changes since then, other than the fact of course that we are now discussing with the agency based on the briefing books and so on and so forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Mads. Some announced data on Biogen's long-acting Factor VIII suggesting a 3.5-day interval and injection regimen. What are we looking for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so it is true that Biogen Idec with the FC chimeric factor VIII protein have just today announced the headline results from the A-LONG trial, and that one did actually reveal what I would call positive data in low-inhibitor patients.</p>
          <p>Novo-Nordisk for the N8-GP that has provided a half-life prolongation that is very reminiscent of what the Biogen Idec FC construct has done of 1.8-fold to 2-fold, over and above the native Factor VIII. It's being studied on a every fourth day basis in our Phase III program.</p>
          <p>So they are ahead of us and congratulations with the &#x2013; at least, the top-line results that are looking favorable and we will hope to generate equally good results for our product even though that is too early to predict.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Mads and ladies and gentlemen, time flies. We should take the last question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our last question from Luisa Hector from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I wonder if we can just go back to the 2013 challenging operating environment and specifically on two of the points you raised.</p>
          <p>The tough pricing in major markets, would that include the U.S.? Because I believe Lilly was flagging a slightly tougher pricing environment with negotiations getting a bit tougher with the big payers, so just any color on the U.S. pricing specifically there. And you did make the comment on the contracts for the U.S. that there's no, I think, no new ones for 2013 to be aware of. So should we assume in terms of covered lives for insulin for 2013 in the U.S. that it is a relatively stable picture as we go into next year?</p>
          <p>And the second part of your challenging operating environment was the intensifying competition in diabetes and biopharma and your earlier comments on GLP suggested that you don't see a major change there in dynamics. And then in insulin, you're the one potentially launching the new products there. So I'm just wondering what else is causing this intensifying competition?</p>
          <p>And then second question on the FDA panel, just could you tell us how &#x2013; whether you were surprised by the focus on the cardiovascular and to what extent this came up with the European regulator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. This is Lars Rebien here. First of all, 2013 and onwards U.S. competitive situation and then I'll try to answer the second part of the question which is what do we see different in the GLP-1 segment versus the insulin segment? I mean, it is almost, I would say, illegal for me to talk about the future competitive situation in insulin in the United States because it's Lilly and ourselves that are bidding against each other and I don't want to disclose what we intend to do about the price.</p>
          <p>But it is correct that Lilly tried a price war in 2010 into 2011 by being very aggressive on certain managed care accounts in the U.S. and we have then sharpened our pencils and became competitive in 2012. You see the result of that, and then clearly that gives Lilly a very negative picture on the pricing scenario. And what that's going to be going forward, I mean, I'm not going to speculate on that. We'll have to see the results. I don't want to comment on it, but clearly it is a very competitive figure but it's between Lilly and ourselves.</p>
          <p>When we talk about GLP-1, that's a situation where it's only also two companies. It used to be Lilly and Amylin against Novo-Nordisk. In the future it's BMS, AstraZeneca against Novo-Nordisk, two entries into the market that have clear sales profiles and so that gives a completely different pricing environment compared to the general picture in insulins where there are different treatment choices.</p>
          <p>We see it in Europe where increasingly human insulins are being advocated as first choice for patients even though they are old-fashioned products and that has implications for the competitive situation between human insulin suppliers in Europe and there are several human insulin suppliers in Europe, and it also has implications for future pricing of modern insulins and the next generation that we are planning to introduce. So &#x2013; but it's primarily &#x2013; us and Lilly in United States, that are determining the price picture as it relates to insulins and with regards to GLP-1, it's us and BMS, AstraZeneca going forward.</p>
          <p>Mads, FDA panel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so the final round of this one, obviously we'll all be much wiser after November 8. But what I can say is that ever since the FDA Amendment Act [FDAAA] of 2007, it has been the default setting new molecular entities do, by default, undergo an Advisory Committee hearing unless there's something that speaks against one happening. And do bear in mind that previous insulins are prior to 2007 FDAAA. So we're not surprised as such to have an AdCom, then the focus on CV, well, do bear in mind that over the last several years, most of the agency hearings have at least had an element of cardiovascular risk assessment, and in that regard, you can say the FDA, the EMA and the PMDA in U.S., Europe and Japan, respectively, have all seen the same data and we know today that we are on track with EU Commission approval in Europe and we have an approval for Tresiba in Japan.</p>
          <p>We also hope to be able to convince the panel on November 8 that we have a very favorable benefit risk profile for this insulin analogue in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So with that, ladies and gentlemen, I hope you share good wishes with us for next week for the AdCom meeting in United States. I know that you will all be tuned in and I'm sure we will be talking to many of you following that AdCom meeting. So thanks for listening in on this one and we'll be back very shortly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>