<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1266961" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3044</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen, Executive Vice President and Chief Science Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jesper Brandgaard, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Michael Novod</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Sachin Jain</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Henrik Simonsen</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Andrew Baum</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Peter Hugreffe</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Gavin MacGregor</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Sam Fazeli</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Jack Scannell</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Carsten L&#xF8;nborg Madsen</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome to the Novo Nordisk Q3 2009 Earnings Conference Call. For your information, today's conference is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen, CEO. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and ladies and gentlemen, welcome to this Nordisk conference call regarding our results for the first nine months of 2009 released earlier today.</p>
          <p>I'm Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen, the CEO of Novo Nordisk; and with me, I have our Chief Financial Officer, Jesper Brandgaard; Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen, our Chief Science Officer; and present are our investor relations officers.</p>
          <p>Today's earnings release is available on our home page, novonordisk.com, along with the slides that we'll be using for this conference call. The conference call is scheduled to last approximately one hour. And as usual, we'll start the presentation with an outline on slide number two. The Q&amp;A session will begin in approximately 25 minutes.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number three. As always, I need to advise you that this call will contain forward-looking statements. Such forward-looking statements are subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause the actual results differ materially from expectations. For further information on the risk factors, please see the earnings release and the slides prepared for this presentation.</p>
          <p>Also note, as mentioned, the conference call is being webcast live, and a replay will be made available on Novo Nordisk's Web site after the call.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number four. We're satisfied with the sales performance in the first nine months of this year, with a growth of 15% reported and 11% in local currencies. The performance is driven by continued penetration of our modern insulins in all key markets.</p>
          <p>North America continues to expand its position as the largest sales region for Novo Nordisk, with the sales growth of 29% in the first nine month of this year report. In local currencies, this corresponds to 17%.</p>
          <p>While the launch of Victoza(r) in Europe progresses well with an encouraging uptake so far, we're still awaiting a formal response from the FDA for liraglutide in the United States.</p>
          <p>In September, we announced a feedback from the FDA is expected in this quarter and this is still the case. The Phase 3 program for a new generation of insulins SIAC and SIBA are recruiting according to plans. Recruitment for the first trial is now completed.</p>
          <p>In Japan, NovoRapid(r) Mix 50 and NovoRapid(r) Mix 70 has recently been approved by the Ministry of Health, Labor and Welfare. Novo Nordisk expects to launch these products in 2010 in Japan when reimbursement discussions have been finalized.</p>
          <p>Turning to financial, where we once again realized a solid improvement in gross margin. Operating profit grew 30% reported in the first nine months or about 15% adjusted for impact from currencies and nonrecurring cost in 2008 relate to the closure of our pulmonary diabetes project.</p>
          <p>For 2009, we have today raised our guidance for growth of operating profit measured in local currencies from previously between 12 and 14% to now around 15%. Measured in reported terms, the growth of operating profit is expected to be around three percentage points higher than the growth in local currencies. Later in this call, Jesper will give some more details on our guidance for 2009 as well as our preliminary plans for 2010.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number five. Before I read you the sales performance, I'd to draw your attention to the news projections from the International Diabetes Federation on the number of people with diabetes in the world. In 2000 IDF published the first Diabetes Atlas assessing the human and economic challenge associated with diabetes. At the time there were an estimated 150 million people with diabetes worldwide. And now they're expected to grow to 300 million by 2025. Subsequently, as the Diabetes Atlas was revised in the second edition in 2003 and the third edition in 2006, both current and projected future number of people with diabetes were significantly increased.</p>
          <p>Lastly, in connection with the IDF World Congress held in Montreal in Canada, the release of the fourth edition of the world Diabetes Atlas represented a third consecutive time that IDF increases their estimates for the number of people with diabetes, highlighting the growing burden of the disease.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide six. The current estimation predicts that there are 285 million people with diabetes in the world in 2010, and this will increase to 438 million people by 2030. In line with previous analysis, the majority of the increase will come from the Asian countries, especially China and India.</p>
          <p>The economic consequences of diabetes are substantiated by an updated estimate of diabetes healthcare costs. Diabetes is estimated to account for 12% of total global healthcare expenditures in 2010. In coming years, IDF expect this to increase significantly.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number seven for an update on our sales performance. Our portfolio of modern insulins continues to show strong performance overall. In the first nine months of 2009 the portfolio of modern insulins were the main growth driver accounting for more than 80% of total sales growth in local currencies.</p>
          <p>Our pharmaceuticals grew 15% reported and 10% in local currencies. Contributing the most of the sales on NovoSeven(r), which increased 15% in Danish kroner or by 11% in local currencies.</p>
          <p>Sales growth for NovoSeven(r) was primarily realized in Europe and international operations. Also our growth among franchise exhibited solid performance, with 15% sales growth measured in Danish kroner and 9% in local currencies. Novo Nordisk remains the second largest company in the global growth hormone market with 23% market share measured by volume.</p>
          <p>Turn to the next slide for an update on the regional sales split. The first nine months of this year, sales growth was realized in all regions. North America is the main contributor with more than 50% share of growth measured in currencies, and our North American sales region continues to expand its leadership position.</p>
          <p>National operations in Europe contributed 29 and 19%, respectively, of the total sales growth. European sales growth is impacted by currently low volume growth of the insulin market assumed to be temporary in nature and linked to the launch of the incretin mimetics in Europe. In addition to this we have experienced slower growth rate in Eastern Europe primarily due to healthcare reforms.</p>
          <p>Sales growth in Japan during the first three quarters of this year has been around 2% measured in local currencies. The growth of sales is impacted by change in the underlying insulin market dynamics where growth of the basal segment -- in particular, modern insulins -- has accelerated at the expense of premix segment where Novo Nordisk has the strongest position.</p>
          <p>Turn to the next slide, giving you update on insulin market dynamics. Around 59% of the global insulin market measured in volume has now been converted to modern insulins, compared to 54% same time last year. The conversion trend is stable and looks set to continue in all markets globally. Of the major markets, the U.S. is still leading the conversion with almost 70% of insulins market being converted. In Europe the modern insulin market which have sent more than 60% of all insulins, whereas in markets like Chinese -- the Chinese market a significant opportunity remains in converting patients with today only around 20% are using modern insulins.</p>
          <p>The conversion is driving the value growth in the insulin market along with the ongoing conversion to prefilled devices. Novo Nordisk continues to gain market share within the modern insulin market and Novo Nordisk market share of the modern insulin segment is now 45% measured in volume, compared to 44% 12 months ago.</p>
          <p>Novo Nordisk continues to be the only company that markets the full range of modern insulins with short-acting, premixed, and long-acting modern insulins in advanced and user-friendly delivery system such as the easy-to-use disposable FlexPen(r).</p>
          <p>Turn to the next slide to review the performance of the modern insulin business. In the first nine months of 2009 sales of modern insulin grew 28% reported and 24% in local currencies. The modern insulins made up 65% of our total insulin sales, compared to 59% first nine months of 2008, and this emphasizes the momentum in the ongoing conversion from human insulins to modern insulins.</p>
          <p>The growth is driven by underlying market growth and market share gains for the entire portfolio of modern insulins, NovoRapid(r), NovoMix(r), and Levemir(r). Global market share continues to increase for all three products. From a regional perspective, growth is driven primarily by North America, followed by Europe and international operations.</p>
          <p>NovoRapid(r) is the single largest modern insulin product for Novo Nordisk, with sales of 7.2 billion in the first nine months of 2009. A similar figure for NovoMix(r) is 4.8 billion and Levemir(r) kr3.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Turn to slide number 11, which provides you an update on our European launch performance for Victoza(r). Key area for many investors currently is the Victoza(r) performance in Europe. By now the product is available in Germany, UK, Denmark and soon to follow other European markets. In Europe, Victoza(r) is indicated for broad combination use with commonly used OADs and the label is backed by solid efficacy data on blood glucose reductions, sustained weight loss, as well as decrease in systolic blood pressure.</p>
          <p>We're very satisfied with the launch performance so far. According to the latest market share data, Victoza(r) has already captured more than 1% value market share of the diabetes care market in Germany. As a percentage of the GLP-1 market, this corresponds to more than 40%. And in Denmark we now hold the market share around 40% of the GLP-1 market.</p>
          <p>In the UK launch is also progressing well, and we have captured more than 10% of the GLP-1 market. We are continuously expanding the primary care thrust formulary access for Victoza(r) which is a key focus in connection with the launch and attempts to establish broader market access.</p>
          <p>With this, I'd like to hand over to Mads who will give you an update on the development within our clinical pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Lars. Before I direct your attention to slide 12, I'd like to make a few comments on external events, including the recently published 4-T study presented at the IDF conference in Montreal in October this year. The results of this treating to target in type 2 diabetes -- or simply 4-T study -- conducted by the Diabetes Trials unit at Oxford University are also published in this week's edition of the New England Journal of Medicine. The 4-T study investigated three different insulin initiation and intensification regimens, all with insulin analogues over the longest randomized free-to-target comparison yet published in type 2 diabetes.</p>
          <p>The study, which was supported by Novo Nordisk and Diabetes UK, was a three-year randomized controlled multicenter trial in which 708 patients with the suboptimal HbA1c levels on Metformin and Sulfonylurea therapy were assigned to initiate insulin therapy with NovoMix (r) 30 twice daily, mealtime NovoRapid (r), or Levemir(r) (r) once daily.</p>
          <p>Among the outcome measures after three years were mean HbA1c, the proportion of patients with an A1c level of seven or less, the rate of hypoglycemia, and weight gain.</p>
          <p>The 4-T study showed that after three years the dropout rate was below 20% and the mean HbA1c level did not differ between groups.</p>
          <p>The proportion of patients achieving an A1c level of 7% or less was high, about 60% in NovoRapid (r) and Levemir(r) initiation groups, and a bit lower in the NovoMix initiation group. In the NovoMix group, however, fewer patients received intensification during the three-year treatment period.</p>
          <p>The median numbers of hypoglycemic events per patient per year were low, i.e., between two and three episodes for the Levemir(r) and NovoMix initiation groups, but somewhat higher for the NovoRapid initiation group.</p>
          <p>Intriguingly, these low levels of hypoglycemia were also observed among the subgroups that achieved an Hb1c below 6.5%. With regard to weight, the group initiated on once-daily Levemir(r) therapy statistically significantly experienced the lowest weight gain despite being intensified to basal bolus therapy with NovoRapid.</p>
          <p>Overall the 4-T study in type 2 diabetes has over a three-year period shown that initiation of insulin treatment with once-daily Levemir(r) or twice-daily NovoMix 30, followed by simple intensification with NovoRapid when needed, is well tolerated and associated with ease of use and equivalent degrees of A1c lowering in the presence of low levels of hypoglycemia.</p>
          <p>Even more recently, the American Academy of Clinical Endocrinology and American College of Endocrinology released their consensus statement on the approach to type 2 diabetes treatment. They state that, while meta-analysis suppression diabetes outcome studies shows micro- and macrovascular improvements with excellent glucose control, the risk of hypoglycemia in these patients may be causative of the paradoxical increase in mortality at low levels of A1c.</p>
          <p>Consequently, in order to achieve safe but effective glucose lowering the AACE and ACE organizations on the one hand recommend inclusive therapy, in particular GLP-1 avenues due to the high efficacy; and on the other hand use of insulin analogues. Specifically it's mentioned in the consensus document that once-daily Levemir(r) is associated with a weight benefit and a low degree of variability. We consider these guidelines to be a clear positive for our portfolio of efficacious products with low hypoglycemic risk.</p>
          <p>And now to slide 12. As Lars also mentioned, we're pleased to report that NovoRapid Mix 50 and 70 have recently been approved by the authorities in Japan. Both products have been approved for the treatment of adult type 1 and 2 diabetes. Novo Nordisk expects to launch both products in 2010 in Japan when reimbursement discussions are finalized.</p>
          <p>With regards to the regulatory process in the U.S. for liraglutide, our once-daily human GLP-1 analogue, Novo Nordisk continues the constructive dialogue with the FDA. As mentioned by Lars in his opening remarks, we still expect formal feedback from the agency on the liraglutide NDA this quarter.</p>
          <p>As for the new generation insulins SIBA and SIAC, these have now both entered phase 3a clinical development with the trial programs named BEGIN(tm) and BOOST(tm), respectively. This4 huge phase 3a trial program with around 10,000 patients in total is executed in sequence of four waves. The first wave has been initiated, and the first trials have now completed recruitment. The second wave is expected to be initiated during the fourth quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>In the BEGIN(tm) program, the second wave consists of one trial comparing the use of two different regimens of once-daily SIBA to insulin glargine in insulin-naive type 2 diabetes patients.</p>
          <p>In the BOOST(tm) program, the trial in the second wave will investigate intensified use of SIAC compared to treatment with NovoMix 30 in people with type 2 diabetes previously treated with premixed insulins.</p>
          <p>Based on the SIBA-SIAC characteristics, the objective of the program is to demonstrate a superior profile as evidenced by the products bringing more patients to target in the absence of hypoglycemia. The final two phase 3a waves are expected to be initiated during the first half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide on our update on our pipeline within hemophilia. In the area of hemophilia and in line with previous communication, Novo Nordisk has initiated a phase 1 study with a long-acting factor-nine derivative. A Phase 1 study with a long-acting factor seven-A derivative for subcutaneous administration as well as a Phase 2 study with a long-acting factor seven-A derivative for intravenous administration.</p>
          <p>As regards the ongoing Phase 2 trial with NN1731, Novo Nordisk now expects to complete this in the second quarter of next year. NN1731 is a recombinant factor seven-A analogue designed to provide even faster and more effective hemostasis in hemophilia patients with inhibitors. The extended duration of the trial is due to a lower than anticipated number of bleeding events among patients in the trial.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide. While Novo Nordisk has several projects in clinical development within inflammatory diseases, the early-stage research pipeline will be bolstered through the establishment of the new inflammation research center that is based in Seattle on the U.S. West Coast and was inaugurated last month. The U.S. research center will leverage Novo Nordisk's strong knowledge within the field of therapeutic proteins in order to further build the company's pipeline with emphasis on cytokine-based projects.</p>
          <p>With that, over to Jesper for an update on the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mads. Please turn to the next slide. We are satisfied with the financial results for the first nine months of 2009. Total sales growth for this period was 15% as reported and 11% in local currencies. Growth was realized within both Diabetes Care and Biopharmaceuticals and the primary growth contribution originated from the modern insulins.</p>
          <p>The growth margin increased to 79.5%, compared to 77% in the same period of 2008. This improvement primarily reflects improved production efficiency, higher average selling prices in the U.S., and a slight positive product mix effect. The gross margin was positively impacted by around one percentage point from the development in currencies, primarily the higher value of the U.S. dollar and the Japanese yen versus the Danish krone in the first nine month of 2009, compared to the same period in 2008.</p>
          <p>In the first nine month of 2009, total non-production-related costs increased by 13% to 18.7 billion. Around one-third of the increase in non-production related costs reflects the higher value of key currencies versus the Danish krone in the first nine month of 2009 compared to the same period of 2008. The underlying development in non-production-related costs relates to the expanded sales force in especially U.S., UK, Japan, Germany and China, countered by limited growth in research and development costs.</p>
          <p>The development in research and development costs primarily reflects the timing of Phase 3 clinical trial programs as well as the nonrecurring costs of 325 million in the first nine month of 2008 related to discontinuation of pulmonary diabetes projects.</p>
          <p>In the first nine month of 2009, operating profit increased by 30% to kr11.7 billion. Underlying operating profit increased by around 15%. Underlying operating profit is adjusted for the impact from currencies and nonrecurring costs in 2008 related to the discontinuation of all pulmonary delivery projects.</p>
          <p>Net financials showed a net expense of 718 million in the first nine month of 2009, compared with a net income of 626 million in the same period of 2008. For the first nine month of 2009, the foreign exchange result was an expense of 617 million compared with an income of 671 million in the same period last year. This development reflects losses on foreign exchange hedging of especially U.S. dollar and Japanese yen due to the appreciation of these currencies versus Danish krone in the first part of 2009, compared to the exchange rate prevailing in 2008. The effective tax rate in the first nine month of 2009 was 23%.</p>
          <p>Net profit increased by 15% to 8.445 billion.</p>
          <p>The number of full-time employees increased by 8% to 28,500. This development reflects international expansion of sales forces in key markets such as the U.S., the UK, Germany and China as well as manning for international expansion of manufacturing sites.</p>
          <p>Please turn to slide 16, providing an overview of the currency exposure. During the third quarter of 2009, the U.S. dollar has continued to depreciate compared to the Danish krone, whereas the Japanese yen has remained largely at the same level as noted in the second quarter of 2009. The expected annual impact on operating profit of the 5% movement in the currencies as stated on this slide has been updated to now reflect the expected impact in 2010. For 2010, the annual impact of a 5% movement in the U.S. dollar is around 580 million, and for the Chinese yuan the annual impact is around 100 million on operating profit. Therefore, the total effect of a 5% movement in the U.S. dollar amounts to a currency impact of in total around 680 million on operating profit.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide for the financial outlook for 2009. Novo Nordisk still expects sales growth in 2009 at the level of 10% measured in local currencies. This is based on the expectations of continued market penetration for Novo Nordisk key strategic products within Diabetes Care and Biopharmaceuticals as well as the expectations of continued intense competition during the remaining part of 2009.</p>
          <p>Given the current level of exchange rates versus Danish krone, the reported sales growth is now expected to be around 1.5 percentage points higher than the growth rate measured in local currencies.</p>
          <p>For 2009, growth in operating profit is now expected to be around 15% measured in local currencies. The marginally increased expectations primarily reflect further improvement of the gross margin and a slightly lower expected research and development cost for 2009 due to timing of the three clinical trial programs.</p>
          <p>Given the current level of exchange rate versus Danish krone, the reported operating profit growth is now expected to be around three percentage point higher than the growth rate measured in local currencies.</p>
          <p>For 2009, Novo Nordisk now expects a net financial expense of 750 million. The expectation reflects significant foreign exchange hedging losses, primarily related to the U.S. dollar and Japanese yen.</p>
          <p>The effective tax rate for 2009 is still expected to be around 23%.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures is now expected to be around 2.5 billion in 2009, primarily reflecting a slightly later timing of activities in relation to the new insulin formulation and filling plant in Tien Giang, China.</p>
          <p>Expectations for depreciation, amortization and impairment losses of around 2.6 billion are unchanged. And the free cash flow is now expected to be at least 11 billion, primarily reflecting the lower level of capital expenditure.</p>
          <p>With regard to the financial outlook for 2010, it is Novo Nordisk intention to provide detailed guidance on expectations in connection with the full-year release of financial results for 2009 scheduled for the 2nd of February 2010. At present, the preliminary plans for 2010 indicate a 5 to 10% sales growth and more than 5% growth in operating profit, both measured in local currencies. Due to an expected negative currency impact following the recent significant depreciation of Novo Nordisk main invoicing currencies, the reported sale growth for 2010 is expected to be around 3.5 percentage point lower than the growth measured in local currencies, whereas the reported operating profit growth is expected to be around seven percentage point lower than the growth measured in local currency.</p>
          <p>Please also note that the expected significant negative currency impact on operating profit from the development in Novo Nordisk main invoicing currencies is expected to be offset by a significant level of hedging gains of approximately kr1 billion in 2010. The income will be included in the financials.</p>
          <p>The preliminary plans for 2010 that we have provided today reflect an outlook with more uncertainties that we have seen in previous years. The outlook for modern insulins NovoSeven and Norditropin(r) Simplex remain robust and we are increasing our market presence for these products.</p>
          <p>However, as mentioned above, the key uncertainties relates to the U.S. regulatory process for the liraglutide, generic competition for all anti-diabetics in both U.S. and EU, and the potential healthcare reform in the U.S. The outcome of the U.S. regulatory process for liraglutide is expected to have limited impact on operating profit in 2010, since the income related to the expected sales of liraglutide in the U.S. is expected to be offset by launch costs for this product in the U.S. market in 2010.</p>
          <p>With regard to generic competition for all anti-diabetics, Novo Nordisk expects generic competition in Europe in 2010, but the situation in the U.S. market is still depending on the outcome of the ongoing trend in litigation.</p>
          <p>Lastly, the current proposal for U.S. healthcare reform point to a great degree of uncertainty with regard to scope and timing for the implementation of a U.S. healthcare reform.</p>
          <p>All of the above expectations are based on the assumption that the global economic downturn will not significantly change the business environment for Novo Nordisk during the remaining part of 2009 and into 2010. In addition, all of the above expectations are provided that currency exchange rate, especially in the U.S. dollar, remain at the current level versus Danish krone for the remainder of 2009 and throughout 2010.</p>
          <p>This concludes our presentation of the financial results. Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen will now moderate the Q&amp;A session. Please note that there will be a maximum limit of two questions per individual, with the objective of allowing as many conference participants as possible to have the opportunity to ask questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jesper and Mads, and please note that this conference is being taped and a reply will be made available on our Web site. And operator, we are now ready to take the first question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will take the first question from Michael Novod from Handelsbanken. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. It's Michael Novod from Handelsbanken. Two questions. One is to your guidance for 2010. Can you try to perhaps quantify a bit for us the U.S. healthcare reform. What do you count in? Do you count in changes to Medicare and Medicaid or only what we see so far proposed about Medicaid? And then also in terms of the impact on Prandin(r), what kind of levels should we expect for Prandin(r) sales that you account for in your 2010 guidance?</p>
          <p>Second question is I saw Jesper comment on newswires that you expect feedback from the FDA within the next coming weeks on Victoza(r). Can you confirm that or was that just a misinterpretation by the journalists?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Jesper, why don't you start with the guidance 2010? What elements we so far believe might have an impact on our business, a few comments on Prandin(r) if you can, and clarify your comment if so regarding the FDA approval?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lars. In terms of the healthcare reform, I think it's quite deliberate that we have chosen to provide a range for the expected growth in our turnover. And that range of course allows for different outcomes of the healthcare reform process. There are a number of elements that I expected to have a impact on our turnover. One is that we are assuming that the current Medicaid type of pricing is going to be extended into more hospitals. We are also seeing that there will be pricing just to the Medicaid mandatory rebate, and we are also expecting that Novo Nordisk with the rest of the Pharma industry will be assisting in covering of the part of the payment scheme on the Medicare Part D which is currently not reimbursed, popularly referred to as the doughnut hole.</p>
          <p>And then depending on the timing and the precise implementation of these, you can have various outcomes and implications for Novo Nordisk for both in '10 and onwards. The broad-based assumption currently is that it could have a implication to the tune of one to two percentage point of our total turnover effect on the top line in 2010. And as we're talking about rebates and lower prices in general, this will have a immediate effect on the operating profit levels as well.</p>
          <p>As for Prandin(r), if you look at our turnover, Prandin(r), then almost kr2 billion is related to sales in U.S. and in Europe, and a little bit depending on -- and it's roughly equally split, slightly better in the U.S. than Europe -- a little bit depending on how the legal process develops in the U.S., then there could be an implication there. The European situation you could say is a bit more muddy as its local country patterns that are being disputed and there is a legal process ongoing in number of countries. And hence it is hard to predict exactly how that will develop. But of course, if there will be generic competition in countries, then you should expect an element of our turnover this year to drop away in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then perhaps any comments to the referred quotation from you that we're talking weeks and -- as opposed to what is in the announcement, the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want Mads to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we are talking about the same thing essentially, Michael, because we are in the fourth quarter now. We actually approaching November, so the fourth quarter can't be counted in the weeks regardless, so essentially it is a matter of us expecting formal action from the agency during this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; okay. That's fine. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was a reference to the fact that when we had the advisory committee meeting we mentioned that we're talking months and not years to an approval, and now we are -- sorry; that's a little cutely -- saying we are talking weeks and not months. But -- so I guess that's the clarification, Michael. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Sachin Jain from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi; thanks for taking my questions. Just two just on the third element of your guidance for Victoza(r). Just wondering whether you're willing to just talk about launch costs next year, affecting about SG&amp;A growth next year broadly in line with sales and is it reasonable think about the first year of U.S. Victoza(r) as a small drag on EBIT growth?</p>
          <p>And then the second question which is to follow up on your comments on European insulin market growth. Just if you could provide some more color on how growth has changed there and how much of the declining growth you think is due to the launch of the GLP-1 analogues, and how much is due to the recessionary impact in Eastern Europe that you referred to. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Jesper, would you care to comment on your expectations for the SG&amp;A development, and as correctly was stated here that basically the U.S. -- a potential U.S. launch is probably going to be neutral to our P&amp;L in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's got to be crucial what timing we actually get in this approval process, because of course the earlier we get in the year, the more full-year effect of sales we're going to have. The later we get in, we may only get a pipeline fill and then a significant launch cost thereafter. So it's a little bit hard for us and I think premature at this stage for us to give more precise guidance on the EBITDA effect of Victoza(r) in the U.S. as it is so dependent on the specific timing, but I would be surprised if Victoza(r) in 2010 for the U.S. would be a positive impact on operating profit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And then there with regard to the European insulin market, just perhaps a slightly bigger picture before we jump into the European market. We have seen significant swings of the growth of insulin volume in the regional markets over the last five, six years. And we have seen a situation where growth rates in the insulin market in Japan and in Europe have been coming down. And in recent quarters we have seen growth rates in mid America actually coming up so that we in the total global market are looking at growth rates of around 6%.</p>
          <p>In Europe we are seeing a slower growth than what we have done historically, and we attribute this primarily to the increased penetration of the incretin mimetics across Europe and then some impact, although relatively modest, of the economic adversities that we are seeing in countries such as Romania and Bulgaria, which are forcing these countries to implement quite tough healthcare reforms and thereby aging pipelines, etcetera, etcetera, which risks the market.</p>
          <p>It's our anticipation that we should be seeing normalizations of the insulin volume growth going forward. We don't see any changes in the demographics. And as you referred to the IDF statistics we just gave you, on the contrary, there should be in the future growth -- a significant support for growing insulin requirement, but we have in the past as you probably recall with introduction of new oral anti-diabetics see temporary slowdown in insulin growth until such time that these products find their niche and we start to see the underlying demographic come in again. So in fact when we look at the insulin volume growth in Europe we have seen a stabilization over recent months which kind of supports that we are approaching the time when we will start to see a wash-out of the incretin mimetic effect.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Henrik Simonsen from SEB Enskilda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello gentlemen. Henrik Simonsen from Enskilda. One question relating to insulin competition in the U.S. which is I guess you skipped, Lars. If I look at the growth rate in IMS for NovoLog (r) or Aspart in second, third and the first months of the fourth quarter, it seems like growth has come down from around 20% year-over-year down to, say, 16, 17 in the third quarter and then 13% in the fourth quarter. So wonder -- could you speak a little bit about the competitive environment in the U.S. and your take on the U.S. insulin competition, mainly related to the short-acting and premix market?</p>
          <p>Secondly, a question to Mads, I guess. What is your take on taspoglutide Phase 3 results we saw this morning, although there was much of an HPA reduction mentioned in the release. Could I your take on that one as, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Mads, why don't you just comment on what you so far have been able to dig out related to taspoglutide? And then I'll revert with the U.S. comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, first of all a couple of comments on the trial as such. It's a big trial; we're talking a thousand patients or so, so it's like a deep program-like trial in terms of size. You can say -- I must have missed it -- what has been released is very little. On the one hand, it's not surprising that a GLP-1 avenue such as taspoglutide when given in this kind of sustained release formulation is able to act 24/7 just like liraglutide does. And this essentially means that you have full occupancy of the receptors and hence you get superiority over a twice-daily exenatide regimen. So these figures is not surprising.</p>
          <p>I would be eager to learn what difference was there in HP1C and from which baseline. And also I'd like to learn more about what side effect profile in terms of rates of nausea, how persistent was the nausea, were there any antibody reactions, and if so were they neutralizing, what about local tolerability, and so forth.</p>
          <p>So I must say, Henrik, I'm happy on behalf of Roche that they completed that first half, but I'm not much more wise in terms of truly understanding the exact profile of taspoglutide. But I think it can be for reasons of course protecting their ability to publish these data at next year's conferences, that they've been a little bit cautious in how much release all results they have --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Probably so. Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mads. And then on to the U.S. insulin market. When we review on a monthly basis our market share development for the fast-acting product, NovoLog (r) in the U.S., we have seen a strong development of our market share. We have in the last 12 months grown, if we take monthly data, from 38 to a little bit more than 40% of the market. And so there is no -- and no major impact from gluracine and we see a slight decline for Eli Lilly's lispro. And we continue to gain actually quite nicely in this segment.</p>
          <p>The premix segment is declining somewhat in relative importance. Novo Nordisk holds a quite nice position on this and we are not losing any market share there. We are actually gaining somewhat. So we actually see that -- a complete continuation of previous quarters' performance of our business in the U.S., and it's enormous that you may be referring to a quarter-to-quarter basis are, quarterly records and we cannot see this in the any underlying stats the numbers that we are analyzing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So actually you're not worried about, let's say, Lilly's efforts in intensifying its backing of insulins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we look at the share voice and compare the share voice, which we of course monitor very, very closely, we can see that Sanofi Aventis and Novo Nordisk clearly have a leading share voice inside these market in the U.S. Eli Lilly is significantly lower share voice. And actually in fact what has happened in recent months is that Sanofi Aventis has moved some of their activities and marketing push to the Asian countries, so that Novo Nordisk is increasingly having the dominating share voice position in the U.S., whereas Lilly is mainly keeping at a relatively low level. And they are not able to change the pattern, which is one where they are declining their market share, perhaps a slight stabilization in recent quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Andrew Baum from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. One question. When you're -- let's assume that you get mid-term approval in the U.S. of Victoza(r). What's the risk to your existing market share as you transfer your detailing resources towards Victoza(r) and away from your insulin franchise? Do you have a concern or you're confident that you're going to be able to maintain share despite the growing competition as you've previously outlined?</p>
          <p>And then just one second question. Could I just confirm you haven't filed any data in relation with Victoza(r) formally with the FDA since you last addressed this at the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This is Lars Rebien here. With regards -- of course I cannot completely disclose the details of our launch strategy in the United States. But we are quite confident that we have build a plan which gives us maximum flexibility but also the opportunity of giving maximum push behind Victoza(r). And we're not excluding, of course, given successful launch of Victoza(r) in the U.S. that we might need to expand our market presence in the U.S. yet again, as we have done early this year. So right now all forces are on modern insulins. When we're launching, the main focus will of course by Victoza(r). And then you can expect if we have -- if and when we have a successful launch of Victoza(r) that we might even boost our sales force further.</p>
          <p>Mads, your comment on whether or not we have filed data to the FDA up until now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, Andrew, very briefly, just to recapitulate we are albeit the PDUFA action date as long overdue as we're all pretty much aware of, we are in the first cycle of the FDA regulatory process, and it is absolutely true that we have not submitted new data since we last discussed with the market. What we have done, though, is we have responded to queries and questions from the agency, but we have not filed new data as such but rather responded to specifics.</p>
          <p>And as to what Jesper has been telling earlier today, talking about the weeks and the remnants of this quarter, basically implies obviously that we are in the very latest stages of this process in the first cycle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Mads, thanks for that clarification. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Peter Hugreffe from ABG.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi; it's Peter Hugreffe from ABG. First of all a question regarding the launch of Victoza(r) in Europe. Could you give some kind of comparison with Levemir(r)? Is it on par or is it slightly lower or how should we see that? I know it's early days, but nevertheless.</p>
          <p>And then secondly on your upcoming trials both semaglutide and liraglutide in obesity. And also of course the post-marketing study. How fast will you initiate these studies when an approval comes or a conclusion comes from the FDA? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Mads, would you care to comment on your expectations for the upstart of the semaglutide, the lira or Victoza(r), of these three studies and the CD studies that we are committed to upon an approval in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So the one that we're truly committed to as a global enterprise or interaction is of course the leader program, as we call our calculation outcome study. That is one when essentially I can say we have received feedback from the FDA and essentially we are in the situation where we believe that pending of course that we receive a verdict from the agency this quarter, we should actually be able to kick off that trial during 2010, and basically live up to the timeline estimates and requirements that both the EMEA have already given us and that we would expect the FDA to give us upon approval.</p>
          <p>As you are aware the agencies are no longer accepting the situation as it used to be where the industry was not always extremely diligent in getting patient support in post-approval trial commitments. This is really reversing and Novo Nordisk is very much committed to this trial, and we look forward to conducting it</p>
          <p>When it comes to semaglutide, you must understand and appreciate, due to the nature and the length of the our intentions with the agency on Victoza(r) for diabetics mellitus treatment, we have not seen it appropriate to overburden the agency with discussions about semaglutide up until the point where the Victoza(r) is kind of hopefully out of the tube, enabling us to then have the end of Phase II discussions, preparations, for Phase 3 and so on. And I have to add that of course we'd like to see the completion of our non-clinical activities before we press the trigger on that Phase 3 program.</p>
          <p>Then finally on obesity, the situation is very briefly that we have recruited completely the first of the three trials and the remaining two, of which one is a very big one comprising more than 3,000 patients without diabetes but with obesity. They will be contingent upon of course having a benefit-risk balance in the Victoza(r) diabetes label that justifies us moving forward for the obesity indication in the two remaining Phase 3 trials in a dialogue with the agency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Mads.</p>
          <p>And then on to the question about whether one can compare Victoza(r) and Levemir(r) launch in Europe. Of course one can make the comparison but it does not make that much sense in that it's two complete different market or complete different sizes. There's also complete price ratio -- different price ratio between Victoza(r) and Levemir(r).</p>
          <p>We are very satisfied with what we have seen of Victoza so far and we mentioned that we have 40%-plus already now in Germany of the GLP-1 market. And it is not our ambition just to beat Viata in the European market, but rather to grow the whole GLP-1 segment. So we are confident and we are very optimistic based on these initial data. We have similar situation in Denmark, albeit a small market, around 40% of the GLP-1 market. But when we compare that to the total diabetes market, it's &#x2013; we're still talking low single-digit percentages of the total diabetes market.</p>
          <p>So thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Gavin MacGregor from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Thanks very much. Just following on from the R&amp;D questions, can I just confirm or get some clarity on what is included in the 2010 guidance in terms of these studies that you may or may not progress given the FDA decision on Victoza(r) in diabetes?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just get a bit of a sense of how the Japanese market is progressing. I know you highlighted it as an area where you were finding it difficult to gain market share from Sanofi Aventis. And update there'd be very useful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Jesper, the guidance 2010, what have we included so far for R&amp;D going forward and the swing factors that are related to the approval of Victoza(r) and hence the start of the program that Mads was just talking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, again I need to remind you that we have provided a range for the top line and a minimum level from the operating profit. And that minimum level is of course assuming that we will conduct the clinical studies that we need to do including the cardiovascular studies and also progressing with semaglutide, all assuming that we give a satisfactory outcome of the regulatory process with Victoza(r) in the U.S. So we're certainly assuming that.</p>
          <p>The precise level of R&amp;D ratio for 2010, I would revert to that in January, but it's clear to say that it's got to be higher and at least a percentage point higher than the around 15% we are now looking at, which is for Novo Nordisk an unusually low level of R&amp;D percentage in 2009. So we're certain it will go up, and at least a percentage point higher, but I think detailed guidance would be more meaningful to provide when we get to 2nd of February.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and then with regard to the Japanese market, we mentioned that sales force in Japan in the first nine months have been around two percentage points. But what we're seeing there is we're seeing a strong penetration of the basal analogue segment at the expense of the premix segment and also at the expense of the human insulin segment. And those are those particular segments where Novo Nordisk is holding a very strong market position, and in fact Lantus is gaining larger share of the patients when they're converting to basal modern insulins than Levemir(r). Hence Novo Nordisk is losing a market share in Japan.</p>
          <p>However, we are seeing a stabilization of that downward trend and we have further taken initiatives to mitigate the market situation in Japan by expanding our sales force, which is an activity which is outgoing at the moment.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Sam Fazeli from Piper Jaffray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi; good afternoon, gentlemen. Thank you very much for taking my question. There's two here. I just wanted to reconcile your commentary with regards to the impact of the incretin launches in Europe on the growth of insulin in the one hand, and your expectation that this will stabilize and resume despite the fact that you yourselves have just launched Victoza(r) in Europe. Just trying to understand how you think those market dynamics will work together with regards to the commentary you made.</p>
          <p>And also just to get a feel for where we might be with regards to Victoza(r), your line that used to be, I think, previously used to be called insulin-related sales or whatever is now and perhaps has been the case, protein-related sales, is Victoza(r) European sales recorded in that line? That's it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. This is Lars Rebien here. With regards to incretin impact, it seems to us that there are some patients which might have been transferred to insulin which have for a period of time have been temporarily put on incretin mimetics. We -- it's our understanding that patients will enable to control their blood sugar for a short period of time on these product before they eventually will have to transition to insulin. This is why we are mentioning the fact that we are anticipating that we will see a wash-out of the incretin mimetic effect over time.</p>
          <p>We are positioning GLP-1 and now Victoza(r) against other oral anti-diabetics. And so the ideal position for GLP-1 treatment is actually when the patients are as early in their type 2 development as possible where they have still endogenous capabilities of producing insulin. So our anticipation for growth of Victoza(r) is not necessarily at the expense of insulins, although there might be some concomitant use eventually where some patients are benefiting from an appointment time actually using both insulins and GLP-1. In our case you could foresee to have combinations of Levemir(r) and Victoza(r) in the future, but that is still too early because we still have to give the clinical evidence of such.</p>
          <p>So basically we think that the impact right now is a transient one as it relates to incretin mimetics. We think Victoza(r) will largely out-compete oral anti-diabetics and not necessarily change the long-term trend. Unfortunately you might say because there were speculations that there would be a disease modifying effect of GLP-1s that has not been demonstrated in human data so far.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Jack Scannell from Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>At the EAST and the subsequently in Diverplasia, you've published a very interesting meta-analysis suggesting based on your trial data that the instance of cancer is lower with Levemir(r) than NPH. Skeptics, however, will point to the fact that it's your metro-analysis based on your data done by you. If it's true, it seems to be incredibly important. Why don't you do a proper trial to try and demonstrate it? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is you've shown some receptor binding data for Levemir(r) Lantus and other insulins which looks relatively positive for Levemir(r). How do your new insulins, SIBA and SIAC, stack up on those metrics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Before we take this question, perhaps it'll be admitted one question from the previous inquiry and that was the protein-related sales, whether or not Victoza(r) is recorded as protein within sales, and it is. I can confirm that.</p>
          <p>And then on to Mads. Of course some intriguing observations in relationship to our meta-analysis and the fact that achieving these based on those limited data that Levemir(r) has a lower micogenic potential than NPH. Does that warrant some additional single trial work and how are we faring on those components of receptor binding, IGF-1 receptor binding and insulin receptor binding for SIAC and SIBA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, a couple of comments. What we did when we selected all those trials, they were essentially all trials out of the more than 90 randomized control trials that included non-pregnant women and adults, and had a duration of more than 12 weeks and compared Levemir(r) with one or more other insulins. That gave us 21 trials that showed a high degree of statistical homo-- and population-based homogeneity. So both the Higgins factor and other assessments of heterogeneity showed that there was a high degree of homogeneity. And essentially that means that the data we have showing 0.32 events per 100 patient years for detemir and 0.92 for NPH insulin were actually achieving statistical significance in favor of Levemir(r) in spite of the relatively small size of this meta-analysis, a total of 9,000 patients, of which 8,000 received either Levemir(r) or NPH insulin. So we actually consider this a very properly conducted meta-analysis, and we're happy that it has been published online after peer review in Divisalogia.</p>
          <p>Now the sheer notion that the numbers of events were down to 0.32 per 100 patient years for Levemir(r) tells us that to do a prospective trial with a primary end point being cancer diagnosis is not feasible within the next decade or so. So what can we do to further establish the absolute molecular safety and maybe even superiority of Detemir as an insulin in this regard? Well, that has to do with maybe looking more into the in-vivo situation in animal models of accelerated cosmogenesis and so on, so forth.</p>
          <p>I have to say, though, that we have, based on our molecular safety demonstration at the EAST and previously, trust the meta-analysis. We have not received any request from any agencies suggesting that Novo Nordisk do any further analysis. However, academicians all over the world are starting to find a renewed interest in the field of the very weak mitogenic potential of insulin in the in-vivo situation, and in this regard, of course we will be a trustworthy collaborator in terms of investigating different insulins in such scenarios.</p>
          <p>It is also true that the mitogenicity of diverse insulins has been really published by Peter Corsath et al in year 2000 and it has been questioned what was the reproducibility of these assays. And to that extent, in that regard we have repeated in numerous assay systems and highly reproducibly found -- and will also very soon publish -- the notion that in all cell lines that express the good factor receptor IGF-1, there is indeed a neutral, compared to human insulin, or 50% reduced self-proliferation potential of insulin Detemir, which contrasts with that of certain other analogues which actually exhibits increased proliferated potential.</p>
          <p>And finally your question as regards the SIBA and SIAC projects, we have a situation where they have been selected with molecular safety as a prerequisite, i.e., we essentially have not advanced such molecules unless they upfront showed a molecular safety. So I can confirm this is the case for them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So after this, ladies and gentlemen, Novo Nordisk have time for one additional questions and then we'll have to excuse ourselves. The last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question comes from Carsten Madsen from Carnegie Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. That I'll take a just one question here. In Vienna you were talking about in -- with regards to Levemir(r) -- sorry -- that you were seeing a pickup in prescriptions in the area called neutrabrand.. Could you give us some -- a little bit more color on how this has developed since the EAST for Levemir(r) versus Lantus in the U.S. of course? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is Lars Rebien here. The overall picture is that we are not seeing any significant impact on our business. It is correct that we saw initially increase a neutrabrand after the announcement, and the limited discussion that has taken place in recent months. But we do not see any significant long-term impact on our business. So I don't think that's anything that you should be speculating on, for now at least.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, all of you. And again, you are welcome to contact our investor relations officers; they are standing by to answer any questions you have. We would like to wish you a happy New Year and merry holidays. We will be back on the 2nd of February with our full-year result for 2009 and the final outlook for 2010. Stay tune.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That will conclude this conference call. Thank you for your participation. Ladies and gentlemen, you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>