<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1496772" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call - London</title>
    <date>2012-08-13</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3044</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Lars Rebien S&#xF8;rensen</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">K&#xE5;re Schultz</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Science Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Mads Krogsgaard Thomsen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Jesper Brandgaard</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Brian J. Bourdot</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="AKO Capital LLP">Patrick P. Hargreaves</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Lars, thank you very much, and the investor team. It's my pleasure, as I said, thank you to all of you. Without much further ado, I'm going to hand over the mic here to Lars S&#xF8;rensen to make some opening comments on the quarter and also what results we get over the second half of this year. Lars, all yours, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. How do I move? So thank you very much and thanks for the invitation. We've been dreading coming over here a little bit, not because of the results but because of the Olympics. As it turned out, it was very quiet this morning and almost sort of silent, so we have prepared ourselves to fight through the city, but that didn't occur. And the weather's been nice. So thank you very much for that. I'm just going to say a few words of introduction and then we will get on with the program.</p>
          <p>We will get a little bit more extensive sales update by K&#xE5;re Schultz, Chief Operating Officer, sitting over there. Mads Krogsgaard will be giving you an update for R&amp;D; and Jesper Brandgaard is here. He's just out for the moment. And then we will end up with the Q&amp;A, which we'll take seated at the table and hope that it works out.</p>
          <p>As usual, things may turn out completely different than what we predict, usually not the case, I have to say, at least when we speak about diabetes. But there are certain uncertainties associated with making predictions, and please study this slide to know what the risk factors are.</p>
          <p>This is the highlight, in fact, from the front page of the press release that was sent out. Due to a very strong second quarter, we managed to come out the first half with a 12% local currency growth and because of the weakening of the Eurozone, that is translated into 17% growth in the first half in Danish kroner terms. The growth drivers are North America, international operations with 19% and 17%. In terms of products, it's Victoza and the modern insulins. They made up for the total growth. The rest is sort of a wash up and down.</p>
          <p>In the regulatory field, there are quite a few new things here. The regulatory process for Tresiba and Ryzodeg is moving along in all major market. We have gotten a tentative AdCom date, November 8 in the U.S. And the process in Europe and Japan is moving along quite smoothly also.</p>
          <p>We just announced combination trial results where we combined a GLP-1 and an insulin. And as you could see from the data and from the release, they are actually doing what we had anticipated plus some, meaning, that this may present itself as a very attractive treatment option for a variety of different patient categories. And I'm sure we will be discussing the positioning and the potential of this type of combination drug during the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Then we have one news which is perhaps not so good. We saw in the last parts of the trial with vatreptacog alfa, a new Factor VIIa analogue, a neutral &#x2013; potentially neutralizing antibodies formation in one patient. And this needs to be started further, the way this is being assessed is in vitro. So we still need to see the efficacy data of whether any truly neutralizing effect clinically has taken place. We don't believe it has, but it's something we need to investigate further, but clearly, not good news. It just basically shows that when you toyed around with biologics, if you go too far, you actually run the risk of eliciting antibody formation. And so this is an example of the associated risk with biopharmaceuticals.</p>
          <p>When we look at the financials, a very strong operating profit growth, 31%; diluted 26%. And we were able to lift our guidance for the year to 9% to 12% and 15% operating profit growth in local currencies.</p>
          <p>And with this, K&#xE5;re Schultz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars. And I'm going to give brief comment on the sales. And as Lars already alluded to, if you look at the sales from a geographical point of view, then there are two &#x2013; actually three key drivers: North America, international operations and China. And the background is the same as in previous years, so it's quite different from region to region.</p>
          <p>In North America, we have a situation where we have actually a positive pricing environment. We have a positive market share environment where we are taking market shares steadily in both the GLP-1 segment and in the insulin segment. And in total, that gives us a very healthy growth also compared to what happens to all the pharmaceutical companies in North America.</p>
          <p>In international operations, it's a case of demographics. We have basically something like 6 billion people living in what we call international operations or the emerging markets. This, as you all know, strong increase in the occurrence of diabetes, strong urbanization, and that drives a very high level of organic growth in international operations for all the products both the high end and the low end.</p>
          <p>And in China, we have a relatively lower number here than what we've been seeing in the past. There's been some healthcare reforms on the pricing on human insulin which have affected us last year and we will be seeing this number to come up a little more towards the 15% level once we get to the end of the year due to the sort of pipeline changes we saw in China. But basically, three regions, strong  growth. Europe and Japan, pretty much you could say saturated markets with low economic growth, a lot of pricing pressure and no real positive dynamics for us there.</p>
          <p>If we take a look at the products that Lars already alluded to that there are two key drivers of roughly equal size. That's Victoza in the GLP-1 segment, and it's our three modern insulins in the basal, premix, and fast-acting segment. And the dynamics are basically unchanged in the sense that we are taking share very nicely in GLP-1 segment, and the segment is growing very strongly, and I'll get briefly back to that. And then in the space of modern insulins, you could say we are back at a normal growth track. There have been some changes within the last couple years, and I'll comment a little bit on that.</p>
          <p>On the other product areas, we are very happy about the growth of Norditropin. That's basically the result of our ongoing life cycle management of a very old product where we continuously try to make the best formulation, the best device for the injection, the best education material and so on. And as a consequence of that, in a flat market, we are still taking market shares.</p>
          <p>On NovoSeven, we basically have a situation where the market is pretty much saturated. There are not much more patients to be found in the industrialized world. So we have a little bit of growth in some markets but basically a pretty flat situation.</p>
          <p>The insulin market, long term, I think we've said for the last 20 years at least, there's a 5% volume growth worldwide in the demand for insulin. And there's typically a 5% value on top of that through upgrading to better insulin therapies worldwide. So a 10%-plus growth of the insulin market in value totally is what we've been seeing for the past five, ten, twenty, thirty years, and it's what we predict for the future.</p>
          <p>Then there was a little blip for us &#x2013; and I'll just show it here &#x2013; there's a little blip for us if you look at the numbers in 2011, you can see that Q1, Q2 2011, the actual quarterly growth came down. That was basically result of some of the effects of the U.S. healthcare reform which changed dynamics on rebating in pricing on some of the U.S. products and some of the healthcare reforms in Europe.</p>
          <p>And then we had a funny dynamic, which we also commented on about a year ago, where Lilly went in with some very aggressive price bidding on some contracts. We came back and commented in the marketplace that we didn't really see the point of doing it, but we had to, of course, answer back, being equally aggressive. We've done that. It looks like the pricing environment is more stable now and we have got our volume share back up. And that's why we can see on a quarterly basis, the last two quarters, we are back to this 10% worldwide growth. And so a lot of details about the other markets around the world, but the basic picture is we're back to the long-term growth pattern of roughly 10% value growth.</p>
          <p>In terms of Victoza, we also had a very steady development. We had a small blip that I think we have commented on that was in the fourth quarter. That was due to rebating also in the U.S. &#x2013; in healthcare reform in the U.S. We didn't know exactly how this donut hole rebate &#x2013; this whole calculation of the new additional rebates in the U.S. would pan out. It was very hard to get full visibility on it. So therefore, when we did those end-year adjustments of rebates in the U.S., we had to take down the accrued rebates, that's why you get this blip on the Q4 number. That's artificial in a way, it's not volume related. It's related to adjustments of rebates in the U.S. So you can see a steady track there with roughly DKK 200 million being added each quarter to the quarterly sales.</p>
          <p>What's nice to see on the right-hand side is that we are getting some of the other world markets in here. It's not just U.S. and Europe, but we have had a launch in China. It's a very small number still. But if we compare the numbers for the first period in China with all our launches in the diabetes space, it looks very promising. And as you know, in China, you start launching totally unreimbursed, and then after some years, you gradually gain reimbursement. So it's a very good sign that Victoza will also have a great future in China. The same thing goes for international operations where we have also been launching in a long range of countries and where we start to see some meaningful numbers from areas like Latin America, Middle East and so on. So very positive on Victoza and, overall, 73% growth in local currencies. So that's very nice.</p>
          <p>If we just take a &#x2013; and I promise to take a little look at this for the U.S. GLP-1 market, then roughly in the last two years, you can see we have expanded the market from being 4% to being 6% in value of the diabetes market. So this is, of course, very important because as we said when we launched Victoza, it's not going to be a success if we take the market share by area and nothing happens to the segment. Then it's going to be way too small. And it's way too small compared to what the drug deserves due to superior efficacy on glucose and weight. So what we see here is what's been happening, and you can see a steady expansion on the marketplace and steady expansion of the Victoza market share and a steady decline of exenatide, BYETTA, share.</p>
          <p>I'm sure all of you have been following, as I have, very closely, the tracking of BYDUREON and how that's been going since launch. And I think it's fair to say that overall, it has turned out to be a wash for Amylin. Everything they've gained on BYDUREON, they have lost on BYETTA. So a launch where you cannibalize 100% of your gains on your existing product, at least financially, is not very attractive. So that's something we're very happy about, the tracking of Victoza, also very short term, up against BYDUREON.</p>
          <p>If we then take a look at Europe, then we have some different situations, and that's been the case since early days of the launch that's linked to the different reimbursement systems in different healthcare systems that we have in Europe. But roughly speaking, we can say we have a situation in Germany where we have been expanding the market, and we've come to sort of 4%, 5%. But the German healthcare system is relatively restrictive on the sort of allowing doctors to prescribe new therapies because they are very sort of stringent on trying to keep down healthcare cost.</p>
          <p>UK, we had a slower penetration because you need all the PCTs to go in and improve the drug. That took some time. You need to get your nice recommendation, that took some time, but you can see how it's been going very nice and steady and how we are sort of approaching 10% of value for the GLP-1 segment in UK, very positive.</p>
          <p>And then of course in France, we got the best of both worlds because we negotiated full reimbursement for the product. And we got the market convinced faster than in the other countries that Victoza was the superior alternative in the GLP-1 segment, superior to BYETTA. So there, we both sort of managed to bring down BYETTA fast and grow Victoza strongly up to this 10% level in value.</p>
          <p>Now you have to remember that 10% in value is significantly losing volume, so it's significantly fewer than 10% of the patients in volume terms that are using Victoza. What that means is also that it's still unknown for us what the long-term potential is. We have seen markets where significantly more than 10% of the market in value has been turning over to GLP-1 therapy. And in the U.S., for instance, it's only like 1.2% right now of the patients that are on Victoza, so a good tracking there and a good long-term prospect.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll turn over to Mads Krogsgaard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, K&#xE5;re. And from GLP-1, actually for a minute, Lars mentioned a pre-status on the new drug applications worldwide for insulin degludec and DegludecPlus, nowadays known as Tresiba and Ryzodeg. And I think to put it in one sense and to essentially say that the European process has been exactly as we would have expected in terms of timelines and so on and so forth, a very rigorous iterative process with these various day 150, 180, day 210 reports and so on, where you actually have a process of questions and answers ongoing until you have resolved all issues. And we're at the point where we're about to submit the last input; i.e., responses to the list of outstanding issues that will then trigger the final, you can say, route towards an opinion this autumn.</p>
          <p>In Japan, things have been moving faster than expected and I think that's part of the PMDA wish and desire to revamp their regulatory process and show that they can be competitive on new innovative medicines and their offering to the Japanese population, whereas &#x2013; and that means that we believe we are on track towards a positive action also here in the second half.</p>
          <p>In terms of U.S., things have been slower than we would have hoped for. As you know, we got first the extension of three months on the PDUFA, and lastly, the notification of an AdCom tentatively scheduled for November 8. Obviously, we are preparing ourselves with the utmost vigor for that event on November 8 such that we hopefully are able to get a positive action and a launch in the first half of next year.</p>
          <p>Other countries outside of China, I would have to say, are also in a good regulatory process towards, hopefully, approval. China is the odd one out in that we are still negotiating with the SFDA as to when we can start Phase III trials, the sooner the better because obviously China is a very important strategic market.</p>
          <p>Now moving that back to, you can say, at least, in part, the GLP-1 segment in that we have, as you know, combined what we believe is the best of two worlds, namely the best basal insulin, Tresiba; the best GLP-1 analogue, Victoza, into one fixed ratio combination product called IDegLira. And the first and most significant of the two Phase III trials, the one called DUAL I, has now been completed in a very good way, such that the 1,660 patients that were randomized into this trial were failing on one or two oral anti-diabetics; BMI around 31; duration of diabetes, six to seven years; HBA1c at baseline 8.3% across all the groups, were randomized 2:1:1 to either IDegLira, Tresiba or Victoza. So we were up against ourselves, so to speak. And as Lars already alluded to, the data were good.</p>
          <p>And just to attach a couple of comments. It is highly unusual that you have at end of trial A1c that's actually below the ADA cutoff for defining of the Type 2 diabetes, so we are very pleased with the data. But do bear in mind that Tresiba and Victoza took more than half the population to the target with a very benign side-effect profile in terms of hypoglycemia, et cetera, so strong, strong performance from Tresiba and Victoza, but even stronger performance for the combination of the two products.</p>
          <p>Now why on Earth did we get such good data? And let me make quickly an analogy. I think combining Tresiba and Victoza is like having a hybrid car. A hybrid car has combustion engine and an electric motor. The combustion engine is what you use in a highway. So comparing to Tresiba, when you're running on a highway, you would use your combustion engine. And that will actually recharge the batteries, the electric motor. What is happening here is that Tresiba is actually hammering away, making sure that you're in control at nighttime and between the meals, allowing the electric motor, which is the pancreas, to replenish its insulin granules, its insulin stores. This allows, just like an electric motor when you use it in the cities in the hybrid cars, to be charged and ready for use. The same goes for the pancreas. Under the cover of Tresiba, you have replenishment of beta-cell granules containing insulin, and here comes liraglutide and releases glucose-dependent in the insulin at the meals, giving a high significant decrease in the postprandial glucose excursions at all meals; so much surprising but very powerful finding that accounts for the statistical significant difference between IDegLira and the two other products, weight loss and a very low confirmed hypoglycemia rate.</p>
          <p>As Lars has already said, it's now up to management, also pending the outcome of the DUAL II trial, to be able to actually, with this portfolio of many, many products that are all very new, very good, very patent-protected, to find out which ones to use in which segments. And they are at least three places you can do it for such a product. And we'll get back to that once we have come closer to completion of the Phase III program.</p>
          <p>Semaglutide is our, what we call, best-in-class once-weekly candidate. It is actually only a minor change from the liraglutide molecule, such that it has been rendered even more DPP-IV stable and even stronger albumin bound such that kidney filtration and enzymatic degradation will not take place. And that means that rather than an action profile of 30 hours, you get an action profile of ten days or so. Essentially, it's still used in a prefilled injector with a very rock-solid pharmacokinetic property.</p>
          <p>What we are seeing is dose dependency on both weight reduction and shown here, the primary endpoint, A1c reduction, to the extent that we, for the first time, have actually seen numerically higher, you can say, blood glucose decreases than actually on 1.8 milligram liraglutide. As you know, liraglutide or Victoza will normally be superior towards BYETTA, towards BYDUREON and towards Syncria, albiglutide. In this case, the higher dose range of semaglutide is actually able to even numerically show stronger results.</p>
          <p>So we will entertain a huge program called SUSTAIN. It will be initiated with two different doses in the first half of next year. The first study being a cardiovascular risk study, and that will be the supplementary Novo Nordisk offering, we hope, in the once-weekly segment as it hopefully comes to a successful conclusion.</p>
          <p>And my final slide, other topics within R&amp;D outside of the &#x2013; within the diabetes space, we've taken yet another orally-stabilized basal insulin analogue into Phase I development. We've had label upgrade for Levemir. We've had NovoMet approved in China. We've had the next generation durable pen, NovoPen 5, with a built-in memory function showing timing and size of the preceding dose approved for adults in Europe, launched in Denmark.</p>
          <p>And in the biopharma space, we've had the, you can say, unfortunate data on vatreptacog alfa as already mentioned by Lars, where we have to say now we need to see the big picture but it's obviously not looking good that you have a potential in neutralizing in-vitro activity in one vatreptacog patient.</p>
          <p>Tretten, which is actually the Canadian name for Novo XIII where the Novo XIII is the A-subunit version of recombinant Factor XIII has been approved, the first country. Also, we have initiated a Phase IIb trial, the first of two for Anti-Interleukin-20, a human monoclonal antibody for rheumatoid arthritis. And finally, a C5a receptor antibody has also entered the clinic.</p>
          <p>That was all from R&amp;D, and over to you, Jesper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. In terms of sales and distribution costs, quite a low ratio at the half year in the short term for <mark type="indiscernible" /> (22:26) and low prices terms growing around 8%. We expect the ratio to be better in the second half, as we see the effect of the expansion of the U.S. sales force, which are being completed as we speak. And that will hopefully also be impacted by some additional pre-launch and launch cost in Europe and Japan for Tresiba of pre-launch cost for Japan.</p>
          <p>In terms of research and development costs, 10% growth reported, 8% local currency. Hopefully, that will speed back up to a level between 14% to 15% for the full year as we initiate the semaglutide trial, as Mads alluded to, and as we continue with the obesity trials, hopefully to make this <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:21).</p>
          <p>We've had a non-recurring event here in the ballpark of &#x20AC;4 million in non-recurring costs, so it is artificially lower. The admin cost probably will be around &#x20AC;4.5 million for full year. License and other operating income has done pretty well first half year, and it's broadly reflecting recurring income in this line and we're expecting something like DKK 650 million for the full year.</p>
          <p>Operating profit, 31%, a 10% impact here. So again, constant 5% currency impact here, we have to be 10% here. Another quarter we continue to get an effect from the buyback program, and note that we also did a large buyback program this year from Novo A/S. and we did that actually in April, whereas in prior years, it was done in August. So there's a bit more effect at half year compared to how it had looked historically. The number of employees growing at 4%, and I think we'll be at a full 5% for the full year.</p>
          <p>In terms of currency tailwind, you can basically see this here. We have used DKK 601 to buy, and that's of course significantly above the average for last year. So we do expect a tailwind as we move further into the year, and likewise with the Japanese yen. Also, do note that we have updated the sensitivity we have on currency. That's updated in this slide. So slight higher, especially U.S. dollar impact, and we continue to be at around 12 months forward primarily through straight forwards.</p>
          <p>The guidance was operated 1% on the top line, 3% more currency effect on the top line, so 4% in totality, and we are now assuming around 15% local currency growth. Of course, that is in line with the long-term target we have for operating profit of being able to grow around 15%. And that also leads to the deferral of our potential launch of Tresiba in the U.S. so that those costs will now come more heavy into 2013, and then we hope to deliver the long-term target growth level of 15% in local currency terms in 2012.</p>
          <p>The tailwind on currencies will, of course, also significantly impact the reported operating profit. On the other hand, there's a negative impact from the hedging. So when we look at 2013, it is a predominant part of what we think for impairments at attractive levels for Eurozone and all of Novo Nordisk will impact also reported net profit. We only have something like DKK 500 million in hedging losses that are carried forward to 2013 that affect the going rate. Tax rate, this is assumed to be stable around 23%. Over time, they're also stable. We've upped the free cash flow with DKK 1 billion, reflecting a slightly higher operating profit guidance.</p>
          <p>So this is basically it. We continue to see that we can derive at least 10% growth from our diabetes care franchise. We have a 25% market share and it's gradually expanding. We have 50% share in the insulin space and 46% on modern insulin and 65% of the GLP-1 market. We have two new insulins submitted for approval. We have a GLP-1 portfolio that can further offer opportunities not only in Type 2 but also in Type 1. And in liraglutide, we will also illustrate that we will have more than one GLP-1 affecting these opportunities.</p>
          <p>And then I think there's the big news in this quarter, the very convincing data that we were able to produce on Phase III in terms of combination products as we demonstrate the ability to do <mark type="ph" /> like we've done for the sectors <mark type="indiscernible" /> (27:34) two insulin molecules <mark type="indiscernible" /> (27:37) the convenience of just one injection instead of two and getting a very high proportion of patients into the control. Obesity is still in the making. It looks positive in the regulatory mandates in the U.S. since we had first quarter release of the two products approved. We'll also continue to pursue the very challenging end of the obesity market with the severe obese patient where your therapies would be bariatric surgery. And then finally, we continue to work with our pipeline within hemophilia.</p>
          <p>And with those comments, I'll go to Lars, and then we'll take the Q&amp;A just at the table.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much, my colleagues. And the presentation is now open for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start. And it's been a phenomenal kind of last  decade for Novo Nordisk so that as we look at the next 10 years, can you give us your thoughts on how do you see the diabetes market developing globally on one end? And secondly, Novo Nordisk as a company is starting to see some progress on areas beyond diabetes. So how do you see Novo in a 10-year perspective as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At least I can give you the perspective that we do every year. In fact, we do update our 10-year plan and submit that to our Board of Directors. And we've done so again this year. And I would say the net end result looks remarkably the same from year to year, in that the diabetes business is the predominant business of ours. We are &#x2013; with all the uncertainties that we can forecast, healthcare reforms, biosimilar competition, competition from generic players, growth in the economies or lack thereof and thereby price pressures and all the rest of it, we still forecast that our diabetes business should be growing at around 10% per year in the next 10 years. In our planning when we forecast, we do not include speculations. That means we do not include things which have not had proof of concept. Of course, we do have projects that are earlier than proof-of-concept stage, and they hopefully pan out positively in the 10-year period but we do not include that.</p>
          <p>So I think given the demographics of diabetes, given Novo Nordisk's position, given the importance of insulins and the increasing importance of the GLP-1 segment, where we have dominating positions in both areas, we believe that you will see more the same for Novo Nordisk for the next 10 years. Of course, with all the uncertainties that we cannot predict, the regulatory environment has become more difficult. So we have to anticipate that the regulatory costs are going to go up in terms of assessing new drugs more thoroughly than we have done in the past. We may also have to add clinical evidence for utility so as to get decent pricing with the payers and the clinical institutes that we typically see in Europe. But all of that, we factored into the picture. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. It's Brian Bourdot from Barclays. Thank you for coming to London after the Olympics. I didn't see you in the 100 meters last week, but you've done pretty well in the marathon so far. I'd like to ask you about two things, please. First is shifting to the haemostasis franchise. I'd like to ask &#x2013; it doesn't seem to be growing at the moment, NovoSeven. You described the potential as being roughly stagnant. Despite high unmet need, particularly in emerging markets, can I ask you why you're not getting growth from that source and why is that unmet need in those markets not driving high utilization, whether it's just simply unaffordable for those markets, please?</p>
          <p>And the second thing I'd like to ask you about is oral insulin. It is technically challenging. You've described this before. But what has given you the confidence now to move this molecule into clinical testing and what are your aspirations, I suppose, for what you really hope &#x2013; what patients do you hope for it to address? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I'd like K&#xE5;re Schultz, Chief Operating Officer, to comment on the hemophilia market, the current growth rates and expectations going forward, and the seeming lack of growth in emerging markets that relates to NovoSeven. And then Mads Krogsgaard will talk a little bit about oral insulin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to NovoSeven, we have a situation where the market is basically saturated in the industrialized world because basically all patients that are in a situation where they need NovoSeven, so they have inhibitors, the Factor VIII or Factor IX, they are getting therapy, and we have roughly a 70% market share up against Pfizer. In emerging markets, you have two categories of markets. You have some markets that are so poor that nobody really gets treated with Factor VIII or Factor IX. That means nobody develops inhibitors and there is no market. That is maybe the LDC countries, the poorest 50 countries of the world.</p>
          <p>Then you have a big middle category of markets where we actually do see increasing demand and where we do see increasing sales. However, that is, this year for instance, being offset by the fact that NovoSeven has run out of patent in basically all these markets, and we've seen a generic product, a biosimilar product come up in Russia without any real good clinical data or anything. But anyway, it's come, it's pretty similar to NovoSeven, and it has taken over the Russian market. So it's that dynamic that results in flat sales. So we actually do have volume increase in the treatment of people with Factor VIIa in emerging markets, but we've been losing out in Russia, and so that's the balance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Mads Krogsgaard, oral insulin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One thing that has been pretty important to us is that once we realized that prandial oral insulin; i.e., attempted at a meal, is not the way to go because there will inevitably be so much food-drug interaction in the absorption process that it's a no-go. We focused decisively and with great enthusiasm on oral basal insulin. Now realizing that taking a bioavailability from 0.05%, which it is for insulin if you give it in a standard tablet, all the way up to maybe 100 times higher, you will still have the vast majority of the insulin not ever getting absorbed. And that will create some variability in the day-to-day absorption and hence, bioavailability.</p>
          <p>Now the way to mitigate against that is to build in a longer and longer and longer and longer half-life in the circulation half-life of the molecule. So if you can cheat the normal pharmacokinetic clearance mechanisms of the organism such that they don't get rid of the bad molecule as soon it enters the circulation but allows it to circulate for potentially more than 100 hours or so, that will buffer against the day-to-day variability. And what you are seeing in these last molecules, the one that has just entered, for instance, is a longer and longer circulation half-life, hopefully also in humans. But so far, we have been able to do what we call allometric scaling. But you have to prove it and show that in humans, both bioavailabilities can be predicted, which is, for sure, not always the case, but also and just as importantly, the half-life. So I think we're making progress both on the molecule and, to some extent, also on the carrier systems and the coating and so on. So you'll hear much more, I guess, next year as some of these trials come to an end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is a very, very difficult area, and we've had spectacular incompatibility between the animal models and the human real testing. And so this has made it very, very difficult for us. We actually thought that meal-related absorption would be the most readily feasible, but that proved not to be the case. And so we had to go to the other route. So thank you very much. Other questions, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why do you think that BYDUREON has had such a relatively limited impact on your market share? It seems to have been a recently non-event.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We actually anticipated, and our assessment was, in the way it has panned out that it is not going to fail. The molecule itself works, but the administration is probably so onerous that it has been difficult to attract new customers. And therefore, in our assessment, it's probably primarily doctors that have prescribed BYETTA that is upgrading BYETTA patients to BYDUREON. This is pure speculation on me. I can't really say that that's a fact. But what we can see when we look at the new-to-brand scripts that they're split 60:40, which is also something that we predicted if we add up, say, something prior to launch. And so that's where it's coming out, so they're not expanding their share. They're helping us expand the market, which is good for everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have you seen any changes in the discount that you're offering on Victoza post-launch?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>K&#xE5;re, discounts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we launched Victoza, we only launched with a very low standard discount. And then not related to BYDUREON, I would say a year after launch we started negotiations with the Medicare Part D plans. And in connection with that, you give slightly higher discount. So in that connection &#x2013; that process went along with managed care, we did increase the discount to Medicare Part D, but we have not in general changed our discounting policy on Victoza and certainly not in connection with the launch of BYDUREON.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think that the fortunes that we've had here in Europe for BYDUREON has been much more modest than probably related to their margin set up with Lilly who has a Germany duration to it, so that's very modest. We've only seen a little bit of impact in Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just following up on that, Bristol and Astra are obviously coming in behind BYDUREON. Do you see any change to the competitive nature from that, or do you think that they will need the pre-filled pen to change that in a couple of years or months? At least, would you increase your sales force, let's say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First about the product itself, we believe that it's going to take some change to the product, either formulation or device or something else, to have a different penetration rate than what we see currently. So I think no matter who was put on it, we wouldn't be able to change the trajection at this point in time. But as we understand it, they are working on a different device and a different formulation, so that could change things around. It's going to be some time into the future.</p>
          <p>Our own situation in terms of marketing, with the deferral of the launch in the U.S. of Tresiba, obviously, we have a good sales force that we put even more pressure on Victoza, as it is right now, so that's playing in our favor. So we think we are ready also for Astra and BMS. But they're, of course, formidable players in the GP territory. And BMS has a history in diabetes some years ago with GLUCOPHAGE. So they're to be reckoned with, and they apparently have made it a strategic intent to go into the diabetes area so we should look forward to meet them. Mads, do you have anything additional?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Only I think one issue. Specialists, they can handle complicated devices. They can also handle like if there are some &#x2013; not health disturbing but still frustrating skin nodules and so and so forth. It's distinctly more difficult for a GP who only see a patient for a very few minutes both to educate on the device and also tell the story about what would you expect to see with this product. So it's not necessarily so that even the biggest GP sales force will radically change the picture if the product lends itself better to the specialists.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's also, of course, why the DPP-IV inhibitors have been so successful. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you maybe just remind us when IDegLira is supposed to commercialize? What do you have to do IP-wise in terms of <mark type="ph" /> doing essential paths (40:40)? And on Victoza, Mads, just your thoughts post <mark type="ph" /> developing in arrhythmia (40:46) in terms of your confidence of approvability of Victoza and how that has played out with FDA? And then specifically on Victoza for obesity, how many patients and how much drugs <mark type="ph" /> you've used (41:01), we have <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:03)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mads, could you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Patent-wise, obviously...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>IDegLira.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's the first time that it's been possible to incorporate a insulin analogue or any insulin into a GLP-1 preparation. And the way that we've been able to get degludec and liraglutide, and the excipients and constituents of that formulation that has enabled it to take place has been patented, I think robustly until the end of the next decade, not this one but the next. So yes, it is of course, this is not why we're doing it but it is also a nice way to extend, of course, the effective patent life of lira.</p>
          <p>Obesity. Well, first of all, I think the two orals that have come through the FDA process, it must be good news for patients, good news for society because there hasn't, for much more than a decade, been any agent in there &#x2013; actually, agents being pulled out of there. And there's a desperate need for medications as the U.S. political system knows, and that has probably also helped a little bit giving some tailwind to those two products.</p>
          <p>We like them being out there because as Jesper, I think, mentioned in his statement, we foresee that liraglutide premix is actually more for those who are really seriously obese, i.e., above 35 BMI, and with a &#x2013; in particular, a pre-diabetic co-morbidity, such that liraglutide can do something that the others can't, point one; and point two, something that is of societal value in health economic terms. And it is to postpone or avoid a pre-diabetic going to diabetes, as opposed to normal glycemia, is clearly valuable to society.</p>
          <p>So our positioning, as such, will not be right on top of the other guys, meaning, that there's &#x2013; and if you look at hypertension, the lipid market, when you have a big market, there's really umpteen opportunities to position individual products. And we'll, of course, do that in a way that's meaningful.</p>
          <p>In terms of CV data, it is true that most of the data we have on CV, obviously, at 1.8 milligram, and this is also things we've been discussing now two times with the agency. Obviously, the exposure difference per kilogram body weight is not like 60% to 1.8 milligram, it is rather like in the 13 to 30-year range because these are BMIs of late 30s as opposed to BMI around 30. And of course, we'll have in-market data from all the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:29) Ingenix data base systems that we are following according to the PMR we have with the FDA. We will &#x2013; potentially, you will have interim data from the leader, albeit at 1.8 milligrams. A lot of women in there for whom 1.8 milligrams actually corresponds to premix for big meal, obese person and so on. So we have a hierarchy of suggestions that we will follow with the agency until we fulfill the need, hopefully not ending up with the preapproval CV trial. That's a theoretical outcome but that's basically by no means where we are coming for, and I hope also not the agency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question and please state your name and affiliation for those that are listening in on the call. Sorry, I shouldn't have forgotten &#x2013; it's over now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> It's Daniel at First State (44:12). Just with the upcoming FDA meeting, are you aware of the questions &#x2013; or the kind of questions that the FDA wants you to answer? And how comfortable are you that you have all the basics covered in terms of being able to answer those questions?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just in terms of a neutralizing antibody, do you think it's specific to just your molecule? I know it has only been in a one patient probability or more or do you think it may be a question of the fact that the molecule itself is not a whole version but I think a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (44:46)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mads, I think both the questions relate to you. But to be very, very clear, no, we don't know the questions that we have to answer. So that's very clear. So I can't really speculate because whether they can come up with questions that we can't answer, we tend to think that the drug is provable. We've analyzed it from A to Z, back and forth, in all different ways and directions, and we believe the drug is very efficacious, has a very good profile and a benign side effect profile, but maybe you can add color to that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, not so much, Lars. I think you said it. And we'll have to wait until the Briefing Book comes up from the agency. Obviously, we would seek a close to our logs so that we &#x2013; the sooner we can learn more, the better. But the lines of attack, so to speak, or discussion, so to speak, that we are envisioning could happen at the AdCom are all being pursued by our folks such that we, together with external experts, are looking into each and every avenue of the benefit side and the risk side to profile in a honest but also proactive manner as positively as possible this wonderful molecule. So I think we are preparing ourselves in the right way. And we hope to get that to you around Q3, which is close to the AdCom, of course, with some more flavor as to the topics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that one, one small correction. Vatreptacog, the B-domain truncated, that's the turoctocog, for the old cogs somehow. That's the factor VIII. This one is essentially a 99% homologous molecule. It's only got three immunized substitutions around the catalytic cleft, which is not even on the surface of the molecule but inside the molecule. So it's slightly surprising, to put it mildly, that you actually have immunity lift going on here. I think, and that's my personal view, that the clotting factors are so big and have so complex primary, secondary, tertiary, and sometimes even quaternary structures that they seem to be a little bit prone to triggering the immune system.</p>
          <p>You have to be aware that all of us who are developing these molecules, whenever it's said in a 80% and 90% in turoctocog, they have no amino acid substitutions. And <mark type="ph" /> figuration (46:56) as a protraction <mark type="ph" /> molecule (47:00) is not known to be immunogenic. So I think there's no &#x2013; if you are worried about spillovers into our own portfolio, there should basically not be any based on this other than the notion that the immune system doesn't always like coagulation factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Other questions, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick Hargreaves from AKO Capital. Could you just talk about what's causing your market share loss in Europe, please, in insulin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>K&#xE5;re?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the market share loss in Europe...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's your fault.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...is directly linked to the perception in the marketplace of Lantus versus Levemir. So it goes back to the &#x2013; goes all the way to the clinical development of Levemir where we had to adjust the strength of the product because we basically didn't get the dose right in the first go, and that created a wrongful perception in the marketplace that was used by our competition that Levemir was a not a true once-daily, which it clearly is. And the reason why we still see good growth on Levemir is actually that, of course, we again followed it up with a lot of clinical data and we keep pushing the message, and that's why Levemir grew 22% last quarter. But the real reason is that in the basal segment, we are still losing share in Europe and in Japan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then we had last year this discontinuation here in the UK where we pulled out generic human insulin product in the anticipation that we would capture a significant portion of the new patients on our modern insulins. But Lilly lowered the price on their human generic and captured the market instead of us. So that was a little mess up on our own part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> I'm Bill Redroom, Harper Sanders (48:47). You expect to get 80% of share of new prescription <mark type="ph" /> degludec (48:53). That's certainly effective. I'm wondering whether you feel that you've <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:56) on that target. And secondly, I probably don't want to ask this, but insulin (48:04) that doesn't come to market with the high expectations that you'd hoped <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:11).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I've been on the record for stating that I think we'd get seven out of ten patients, so that would be 70%. And I still believe that to be the case. And the possibility for us going forward, I'd hate to think about hypothetical scenarios. Our current dialogue seems to indicate that it is possible for us to get the regulatory authorities to understand the significance of the hypo reduction. It is possible for us to communicate the long profile, and it is possible for us to communicate the flexible dosing. So I'd hate to speculate on a plan B until we have to. We'll do that in the meantime but privately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it looks more like it's going to be a slightly later launch than what we hoped for; that it is not going to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If we look out four, five years, you're going to have what is essentially a two-player market in basal insulin. It could they end up being a three, four-player market with some sort of biosimilar competition. Can you give us your perspective on how do you see market share evolving, a monopoly in the U.S.? Is it in the industrialized nations, and the rest of the world is going to be how the situation might get skewed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think there are going to be three players. It's going to be the current players. Lilly is out of basal insulins now. They're coming back in with a biosimilar, Lantus, and some innovative play as well, which is a little bit further out. So I think it's going to be the three players that we know of. And we are planning on coming to market with innovation. And with innovation, you can still capture the dominating market share. So it's our anticipation that we should grow our share in the basal segment gradually over time with the introduction of Tresiba. We should be able to hang on to and perhaps even further expand our niche share. We have a very high share in the niche market. The mix segment is declining, though, because of the increased tendency to stop on basals.</p>
          <p>With regards to the short-acting segment, the segment which is, first, going to approach patent expiration, Humalog is already off that. And so we are hoping there that we will be able to come up with some innovations before 2017 when our formulating patents are running out. So I hope that we'll be in a situation where we can stop the decline in the markets where we've been declining. Japan is a question. Europe has question marks. How far we can take the market share is a little bit uncertain. It's three-dimensional. Obviously, we don't know the true competitive situation. But it seems like it's going to be the same three innovative players. And we don't believe there's going to be any of the smaller biosimilar players that are going to have any importance in the industrialized world. K&#xE5;re, I don't know whether you want to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just one more comment on the biosimilar situation. You have to remember that we have human insulin which is total off-patent everywhere, where we have tough biosimilar competition. And this has not led to any significant increase in the market share of the biosimilars or the generics. And insulin is not really a product that lends itself very positively to biosimilar or generic competition for a long list of reasons I won't repeat now but that we've been talking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think seen from our perspective, having a generic human insulin is good because we would like to be able to offer this to societies where cost is very important. I mean we hope that we don't get into that situation in Europe where cost is so important that we have to go back to old-fashioned product. So we can offer this to the big public markets in the emerging countries and will, at the same time, in the same markets, have the modern insulin range in the private market. And then people will be trading up as they go along and as they become affluent enough to be able to do that. And so it plays out well for us. And if you will look at it from a competitive perspective, then of course, it also has the effect that none of the similar manufacturers &#x2013; generic manufacturers becomes big because we completely dominate the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So what do you think somebody like Merck or somebody like Astra or BMS do within a 10-year frame because they have a half developed portfolio of diabetes drugs, they obviously want to get broader at some point of time. How do they solve their problems?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. In relationship to insulins, I think it's going to be very difficult. They can try other avenues. They are obviously trying avenues with DPP-IV inhibitors, SGLT2s and with BYDUREON, in the case of BMS and Astra, we happen to think they're not going to be very successful, I mean &#x2013; but obviously, we are biased.</p>
          <p>In terms of insulins, whether it's Merck or whether it's Pfizer, or whoever it is, there's nobody that can compete with us in generic insulins. You can see that every year when the auction is on for the Brazilian tender. Who can sit around the table longest? That will give you a good benchmark for where the competition is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I constantly couldn't sit around for very long.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, one or two questions more, just so that you're prepared, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian Bourdot from Barclays again. Can I ask you a follow-on question to that? How important do you think it is to offer as broad a range of solutions in diabetes care as possible? I mean, clearly, one of your major competitors, Lilly, has taken a different approach doing a deal with Boehringer to bring some orals as well, you focused on proteins. Are you of the view that focusing on proteins is going to give you the best return on capital and you don't necessarily need to be there in the non-protein space as well? Is that possible?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's clear to us. We have been in the non-protein business for quite a number of years. Together with Boehringer Ingelheim, in fact, for instance, repaglinide was co-developed by our two companies and marketed as such. But what we have realized is, number one, it's very difficult with synthetic chemistry to come up with new medications for Type 2 diabetes without it being toxic. Number two, it's very difficult to differentiate. So you can &#x2013; you will end up having eight DPP-IV inhibitors that are slightly different doing about the same thing on HBA1c, but have a different toxicity profile. And then it becomes a mass marketing game of who can convince most doctors which product is the best.</p>
          <p>In proteins, it's a different thing. So that's why we made the decision when we had our own headwind in insulin sensitizers back when we had a collaboration with Dr. Reddy's, to say we get out of small molecules, we are only in proteins. That's what we understand the best. And as it has turned out, protein therapy for diabetes is expanding with the GLP-1 segment. And with the understanding that insulins are safe, there was a cloud hanging over insulin some years ago about cardiovascular issues associated with insulins, this has now been demonstrated that that's not the case. And it's been increasingly understood in the medical community that you should treat diabetes as early and as aggressively as possible and that lends itself to the downstream active ingredients that we are selling, namely the GLP-1s and the insulin. So no, we're not going to be in small molecules. Small molecules are for the big boys with the big sales forces and the big marketing budgets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we would like to be in orals as long as there's some GLP-1 or insulin in there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there are proteins in them. Yes. Okay, so we'll take one last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Given the trajectory and level that you're seeing in a more developed market like France and the UK, is 10% now just too conservative an estimate where GLP-1s can take as an overall share of the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was a pretty good bet when we started without having any indication of where we could take it. But we can see &#x2013; I mean in my own country, Denmark, it's far beyond, I think it's more close to 20%. And so it depends on willingness to prescribe and willingness to pay for modern medication. And the current financial and economic situation is pushing that ability and willingness back somewhat. So I don't think that if we could &#x2013; we'd be content if we could develop it to 10% of the diabetes market sales because you got to remember, there are many markets we have not penetrated to any great extent, U.S. is 5%, 6%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the missing element we also have in that puzzle is what is going to be the long-term average stay time for patients. It looks to us currently in the market like the U.S. that we have a stay time of at least two years on average for the patients. But of course, we've only been just about two years. And what the average data and how that's going to develop over time will also have a big indication for what's decided at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry, just a follow-up, in the U.S., do you think there needs to be a pricing cut in GLPs for you to hit that higher level of market share? Do you think that's important?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think that's the key issue. It's more an estimate of what actual volume share of patients would be in an insurance scheme and in the situation where they would be able to obtain coverage. And since the coverage is already very high of the U.S. population, more than 70% without any problems, then I think it's more a gradual process. And if you look at the current trends then, of course, obviously, it will go beyond 10% at some point in time; but that remains to be seen, of course. It's important for you to understand the difference between the patient volume share and the sales value share. There's a big gap there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as you know well, I mean if you take the total pharmaceutical market, it's projected to be in decline of 1% or 2%. That means that society is not paying less for drugs, even though they are consuming more. So when we had the political discussion with the treasury and the politicians, it's not correct when they say that drugs are getting too more expensive and we're paying too much for the drug. It is the hospital drugs, very specialized drugs, a new introduced drug, but there is so huge patent run-off that on the governmental budget, that is not expanding. We just should remember that. So there's room for a little bit more diabetes drugs and a little bit more innovative diabetes drugs because society will save a lot of money on that because there's lesser amputations and heart disease and blindness.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for joining us this afternoon. We will be coming back again shortly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>