<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1326478" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8920</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Martin Primus, Head of Financial Communication/Financial Analysis</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Peter Schwarzenbauer, Member of the Board of Management of AUDI AG Marketing and Sales</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Axel Strotbek, Member of the Board of Management of AUDI AG Finance and Organization</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Audi's audio webcast and live talk for the first six months of 2010. My name is Martin Primus, and I'm Head of the Financial Communication and Analysis Department of Audi AG. Today, I'm joined by Peter Schwarzenbauer, Member of the Board of Management of Audi AG responsible for Marketing and Sales. And I'm also joined by Axel Strotbek, Member of the Board of Management of Audi AG responsible for Finance and Organization.</p>
          <p>First, Mr. Schwarzenbauer will discuss the company's results concerning deliveries for the first six months of 2010. Following, Mr. Strotbek will discuss the respective company's financial results for the first half of 2010. Before we start, I would like to mention that you have the opportunity to send your questions for the Q&amp;A session or during the presentation by using the text box on our webpage.</p>
          <p>I would now like to pass on to Mr. Schwarzenbauer. Mr. Schwarzenbauer, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome here to the presentation of our numbers for the first six months. And I can tell you already it's a real pleasure to present those numbers.</p>
          <p>And as you can see on the first chart, we can present you today that we had the best six months in the history of our company. We sold 555,000 units, which is an increase of 19.1% compared to 2009 &#x2013; to the same period of 2009. I also have to tell you that internally we measure ourselves more against the record year and this was for us, as you probably know, 2008, and even against our historic record year, we are up 7.6% against 2008, which you can see is 555,000 units against the 516,000 units.</p>
          <p>If you go a little bit more into detail, you see here the three big areas, Europe, China and the U.S. In Europe, you can see that we sold 337,000 units. We are up 6.3%. And here maybe specifically, I can tell you that we are expecting in Europe, in U.K., this year that we are going to sell over 100,000 units again. That means matching our record of 2008. And I also can tell you that in Germany, we are going to sell more cars in 2010 than we have done so in 2009.</p>
          <p>If we come to China, China, we sold almost 110,000 units. You can see here, we are up 64%. And here also in China, we are forecasting an absolute new record. For the first time ever we are expecting to sell more than 200,000 units in 2010.</p>
          <p>U.S., next big area, 48,000 units; here we are up 28%. We are now the fastest-growing premium brand in the market. And I can also tell you here, forecasting for 2010, we are going to sell, and this will be for the first time in our history, over 100,000 units in the U.S. in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at the environment in which we are operating in. You can see here now the market development, and this gives you also a little bit of indication of how strong we are performing. If you start in Europe, market is up 0.1%. I just showed you that our growth is 6.3%. China, total market up 54%, and our sales performance is up 64%.</p>
          <p>U.S., market is up 16.7%. And as I just showed you, our performance is up 28%. That means on a worldwide basis, the market is now around about at 29 million units, which is an increase of 15% and this compares to our increase of 19%.</p>
          <p>This shows you that we increased market share around the world, and I think what I would like to specifically point out here -- you know, the growth doesn't come only from China. Because sometimes if you look around now, what you read about the automotive industry, it seems that everybody is concentrating only on China. You can see here that we managed to grow around the world.</p>
          <p>Let me, when we talk about the market, give you also a little bit about an outlook on the premium sector, because here also publicly we see some discussions that there might not be a bright future for premium.</p>
          <p>I give you here some long-term prediction. Premium markets 2010 worldwide, we are expecting that we will see 4.1 million cars sold in this segment. And by 2020, we are expecting to see a premium market over 7 million cars. And this means that the premium sector is increasing over proportionally compared to the volume market. That means that we strongly believe that premium is an important part of the car market also in the future.</p>
          <p>We are going to take advantage of this strong growth outlook in the premium segment. We, in the next couple of years, are focusing extremely on increasing our share in the C and D segment. We currently, this year in 2010, roughly are selling 250,000 units in the C and D segment, and by 2015 we are increase this roughly to about 400,000 units. That's mean an increase of 60% in the next five years in the C and D segments.</p>
          <p>If you look now to the outlook worldwide, so far we have been saying that we are going to achieve roughly the record level of 2008 of 1,003,000 units. You can see here now that we think we can continue to keep the great pace of our first six months into the second half, and this is why we are forecasting that we are going to achieve a number a little bit over 1,080,000 units. That means roughly an increase of 8% compared to our record year in 2008.</p>
          <p>I would like to get now into a little bit more detail. And as I said before, we choose not China because everybody is talking about China and you saw how great our figures are, but we would like to give a little bit more details on the U.S. market.</p>
          <p>Here in the U.S., I think all the relevant KPIs are at record levels for Audi. We see it as a clear confirmation that we have the right strategy in this market and it is even more important our business model is working. Audi is profitable in U.S. and our plans are clearly to keep it this way. Today's demand shows us that we are in the position now to get higher lease prices from most of our models than our competitors. I think this is a clear proof of how strong our brand is in this market, and at the same time, we spent less incentives than all our European competitors.</p>
          <p>Our residual values are the best-in-class right now, and again, this is a huge proof, as you know, the U.S. market is heavily on leasing. So residual value plays a big role and we improved here dramatically over the last two years and are now at the top of these European competitors.</p>
          <p>Our brand image, as I mentioned before, is on record level and despite that we reduced incentive spending and despite that we are charging higher prices on leasing than our competitors, you saw the development in the market. To repeat it quickly, market is up 16.7% in the U.S., Audi is up 28%, and we are seeing clearly what we are heading to a new sales record in the U.S. in 2010 selling for the first time ever more than 100,000 units.</p>
          <p>So you see us quite optimistically looking into the future. We think we are going to have an absolutely outstanding 2010 and we are going to keep the high pace, which we have seen in the first six months for the rest of the year in 2010.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. And I'm looking forward to your questions later on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Schwarzenbauer, thank you very much for the detailed information concerning the developments in deliveries in the first half of this year. I would now like to pass over to Mr. Strotbek. Please, Mr. Strotbek.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. Primus and Mr. Schwarzenbauer. Ladies and gentlemen, I would also like to welcome you to our webcast for the first half of this year. And as Mr. Schwarzenbauer just mentioned, during the first six months of the current fiscal year, the Audi brand delivered a new record number of vehicles. This extremely satisfying development is also reflected in our Group's key financial figures.</p>
          <p>Let me describe these for you in greater detail now. I'd like to begin with the major items in the income statement. During the first half of 2010, we increased our revenue by 21% to around &#x20AC;17.6 billion, which you can see on the first slide. That was mainly driven by higher vehicle deliveries of the Audi brand in particular, demand for the higher positioned vehicles from the Audi A5, A6, Q5 and Q7 model lines increased.</p>
          <p>Moreover, the market launch of the new Audi A8 in the first half of the year had a stimulating effect. As a result of the expansion of our business volume, the cost of sales also rose to &#x20AC;14.9 billion. The less than proportional rise of the cost of sales compared with the revenue confirms our company's healthy cost structure. It's the direct result of our ongoing process improvements and further optimization of our product costs.</p>
          <p>After deduction of the cost of sales from revenue, we achieved an excellent gross profit of around &#x20AC;2.7 billion, which corresponds to a gross profit margin of 15.3% and thus exceeds the high level of previous years. Despite the sharp increase in our sales volume, we kept distribution costs nearly in the previous year's levels at &#x20AC;1.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Administrative expenses increased to around &#x20AC;160 million during the reporting period. This is mainly a consequence of first-time consolidations, which are described on Page 21 of our interim financial report, which you can download. The slight decline in our operating result is primarily due to lower earnings from the settlement of hedging transactions even though they were still clearly positive.</p>
          <p>In total, the Audi Group's operating profit increased in the first six months of 2010 by around 62% to more than &#x20AC;1.3 billion. The significantly above-average growth in relation to revenue is a result of our corporate strategies focused on sustained growth. This great success of our strategy of continuous profitable growth is shown especially by the trend in our operating margin over time.</p>
          <p>Over the last years, we have recorded an average operating margin of 7.1%, a very competitive figure in the industry. Even as crisis hit 2009, we achieved an impressive operating margin of 5.4%. And thanks to our strong second quarter, we posted a record operating margin for the first six months of 2010 of 7.6%, beating our previous best from the first half of 2008.</p>
          <p>The Audi Group's financial result reached &#x20AC;83 million. Taking this into account, we therefore recorded profit before tax of more than &#x20AC;1.4 billion for the first half of 2010. The Audi Group's sustained high profitability is also reflected in its key financial ratios. As just mentioned, we improved the operating margin in the period to 7.6% and we increased the return on sales before tax to 8.0%, meaning that we reached our target ahead of schedule.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, I'd now like to briefly explain the main cash flow ratios and net liquidity. During the reporting period, we increased cash flow from operating activities to more than &#x20AC;2.6 billion. The main driver of this development was a significant increase in profit before tax. In order to achieve our ambitious growth target, we continued to invest heavily in the first half of the year, not including the change in investments in security and loans, cash used in investment activities totaled &#x20AC;750 million. And we increased our research and development expenditure during the same period by more than 10% to &#x20AC;1.3 billion.</p>
          <p>The focus of our development activities here is, on the one hand, seamlessly continuing our product initiative and enlarging our product range. On the other hand, we will further optimize conventional drive concepts, including systematic efficiency measures for the overall vehicle, and we will push the development of new mobility concepts such as electric and hybrid models.</p>
          <p>As in previous years, we not only managed to finance all these investments entirely from our own resources, we've also generated a high surplus. We thus increased net cash flow by around &#x20AC;0.5 billion to nearly &#x20AC;1.9 billion. The significant increase in net liquidity offers yet more impressive evidence of our company's financial strength. At &#x20AC;11.8 billion, we increased net liquidity in the first six months by more than &#x20AC;1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the key figures for the first half of 2010 proved that we successfully returned to our pattern of growth from previous years. This had been interrupted by the global economic crisis last year. We have profited from our ongoing investments in new products, viable technologies and in our growth markets.</p>
          <p>In addition, our continuous efforts with regard to costs have paid off, thanks to technical optimizations and consistent implementation of our modular strategy in both product and production costs. We have once again been able to generate considerable cost benefits. All in all, we have therefore effectively enhanced our overall competitive strength.</p>
          <p>For the whole of 2010, as Mr. Schwarzenbauer already mentioned, we plan to deliver well more than 1,080,000 Audi vehicles to customers, clearly above our delivery record from the year 2008.</p>
          <p>As for the Audi's financial development, we are also confident that we will carry the momentum of the first six months into the second half of the year. We, therefore, will achieve an outstanding profit this year. This means that we plan to reach an operating margin in the second half of the year, which will be as good as that of the first half. For us, this means qualitative and profitable growth.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your attention and we're ready for your questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. Strotbek. We will now continue with the Q&amp;A session. Of course, you still have the possibility to enter your questions in the respective text box on our webpage and send them to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question reached us from Michael Punzet of DZ Bank who asks about the main drivers of the strong margin development from 5.8% in Q1 to 9.2% in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, our deliveries in the second quarter were clearly above those ones of the first quarter, and we also had a clearly better mix contribution in the second quarter. Further impact and positive impact were, of course, the market introduction of the RX by then the A8, and there were no significant one-time effects. In addition to that, there were also no releases of risk provisions because we are quite, as in the past, quite consistent and quite conservative with all our provision. In the total, our operating result of more than 1.3 billion is a very solid statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Strotbek. The second question reached us by Nico Schmidt from Dow Jones. He refers to the announcement that we are going to provide further guidance on deliveries &#x2013; development in 2010, and his question is, how many Audi vehicles are you going to deliver in 2010, which, I think, we already answered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we answered it. As we showed, over 1,080,000 units, which will be a new record for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question, which basically has been answered already during the presentations. Michael Punzet would like to know more about the financial development in the second half of the year. Mr. Strotbek?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I mentioned, we will have an outstanding result for the second half, and the margin will be as good on the operating side as in the first half, but more than that, will be released later on or reported later on. We, of course, have some impact from the worldwide economies and the exchange rate patterns. So I think we're on the safe side announcing that we keep the same speed on operating margin in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have another two questions from Nico Schmidt of Dow Jones. First of all, he would like to know about the deliveries development in July of this year, and the second question refers to the development in China and U.S. market and if we have further statement on the outlook of the total year development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me answer, first, the July numbers. What we can see so far in July is that we continue on the same trend, which we have seen in the first six months. And this, I think, confirms what we said before that we expect that the second half of 2010 will run at least at the same pace we have seen in the first six months. So July looks really promising for us as well, expect numbers we are going to announce on August 6th, Friday, in a week.</p>
          <p>The second part of the question was, what do we expect in China and in the U.S.? I think I also covered this in the presentation. China, first time ever, we're expecting to sell over 200,000 units in 2010. And in the U.S., we also are aiming for a new record. For the first time, we are going to sell more than 100,000 units in the U.S. market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have another question asked by Nico Schmidt of Dow Jones. He calculated that the Audi results constituted 47.3% to the Volkswagen Group result in the first half of 2010 and he would like to know whether this will also apply to the full year. Maybe you would like to answer, Mr. Strotbek?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope you understand that we cannot comment any further development of the VW Group's profit outlook. This has been done yesterday by Mr. Pi&#xEB;ch, but I can confirm what we have written and what we have said so far for the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we have a question which was asked by Adam Hull from WestLB; refers to the new 2010 unit sales guidance and he would like to know more about the breakdown as how to how many unit we expect to sell in China and how many of these will be exported cars from Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Roughly, we can say that between 15% and 20% are exported, and the rest is produced and sold locally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have another question from Adam Hull from WestLB. You had a 9% margin in Q1. And the question is whether we will be able to achieve a double-digit fiscal year margin within the next two to three years based on all the new models that are shortly due.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me say, first of all, we are coming from the major crisis of 2009 and Audi was lead company in the previous segment, which was hit only just a little bit with 5.4 decreases last year in our sales to customers. We came back with the fastest acceleration this year. Yes, it's valid. We had a very strong first half year, and especially the second quarter. But in general, we also must admit that the turnaround of the worldwide global markets was very strong; in some areas it was a bit faster than expected by us.</p>
          <p>And I think it's also &#x2013; it has to be considered that those effects on the growth patterns and exchange rate patterns cannot be forecasted for the next years on all those positive trends. So we have rather some conservative assumptions for the future and that would stick to our commitment of having 8% margin for the future. And I would like -- be happy to have more, but this we will announce when we get closer to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Strotbek. Then we have another question from Cristoph Rowbot of Dow Jones. He would like to know whether Audi reaches 1.1 million cars deliveries &#x2013; delivery volume in 2010? The question for Mr. Schwarzenbauer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I have said before that 1,080,000, which we are forecasting for 2010 is an extremely strong result already. And with all the positive development, and as a positive trend, we should not underestimate it, but we still have some markets around the world where the crisis is probably not completely over.</p>
          <p>And you can take even here in Europe. We have markets like Greece, Spain, Portugal where there are certain doubts in the markets. So it would be not very professional to say now, the world is totally clean of crisis. I think we should watch this carefully, and therefore we are quite convinced that we are okay with the 1,080,000.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Schwarzenbauer. Then we have a couple of questions on China, which are again asked from Adam Hull. He would like to know how we see the pricing environment for premium cars in China at the moment and if there has been a slight deterioration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we can see is that some competitors are starting to be a little bit more aggressive in the Chinese market, but nothing compared to what we see in the rest of the world. So it's still an environment where we can operate at a price level what we expect. And so far, things are looking quite positive for us there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have another question on China from Andreas Cremer of Bloomberg, who would like to know about our long-term objectives in China and when we will surpass the 200,000 and the 300,000 thresholds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so far we have been obviously saying that our goal for 2012 is roughly 250,000 units. Now that we've seen 2010 that the development is even more positive than we forecasted, that means we are selling over 200,000 already in 2010, we could say that we are aiming now in 2012 for a number around about 300,000 units.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question on China asked by Adam Hull from WestLB. You are expanding local production in China and recently restarted the production of the Q5 locally, but, yes, if we are missing, Adam, profits by giving the &#x2013; or having given the joint venture or if we are still making good margins from selling parts to China and earning license fee money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To understand our China business, you have to know there are three pillars on that. One of course is the export of our cars into China where we increased this year and then we have a considerable ratio, as Mr. Schwarzenbauer just mentioned. So this is one area where our profits come from. Another one, of course, is from the parts we deliver to our joint venture. And the third one, of course, is the profits we generate out of our joint venture in China. And all in all, I'm satisfied with the development and we're satisfied with our profitability in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question on profitability in the Chinese market asked by Adam Hull. He would like to have some indication of the Audi &#x2013; of the revenue Audi gets from exporting cars into China, selling parts to China and license fee, more detailed numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our turnover into China will be roughly more than &#x20AC;3 billion in total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question on the Chinese market. Would you address, Mr. Schwarzenbauer, with the new A8 and the A7 entering China shortly, would it be reasonable to assume a sharp rise in the export of cars to China in 2011 and 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what I mentioned before, already, but in general, and this is not only true for China, we are focusing a lot from this C and D segments in the upcoming years and you can see it. This is based on the products we're just launching now. We just launched the new A8. Last Monday, we had the world premiere of the A7. A6 is coming up, so we are extremely well prepared to really tackle the C and D segments.</p>
          <p>So this is also true for China. To give you here an idea, maybe, we are currently selling roughly 120,000 units in the C and D segments in 2010. And this will increase until 2015, up to 200,000 units, so an increase of 67% within five years only in the C and D segments. So you see that &#x2013; what I mean with when I say we are focusing on these two segments specifically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have, again, a question on our volume expectations for China. I thought we were already answering this question, but obviously, it was not answered. So we'll just do it once again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Outlook for China. In 2010, again, for the first time ever, over 200,000 units and we are forecasting for 2012 volume around 300,000 units.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there's a question from Andreas Cremer from Bloomberg. The Bangkok Post is reporting that Audi has signaled interest to set up a car plant in Thailand. Is there substance in it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is not something which we have done any decision on it. We obviously are always looking around in this market &#x2013; in these areas to see if there are opportunities, but nothing has been decided into this direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there's another question from Andreas Cremer from Bloomberg. Volkswagen has announced to sell 1 million cars in the U.S. by 2018, including 200,000 units from Audi. He would like to know about our plans to beef up our U.S. operations and when or if we will take advantage of the Chattanooga factory to produce cars in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I mentioned before specifically that all current KPIs in the U.S. are at record level. So, we really think that we are, what I would call, at a tipping point in U.S. We are crossing the 100,000 line for the first time ever in 2010. We are preparing to introduce even more new models to the market. You probably saw that we started focusing also on diesel engines quite successfully. The Q7 clean diesel currently had an order intake above 40%. The A3 TDI clean diesel, which was the Green Car of the Year in 2010 in the U.S., has 50% order intake on the diesel side. So it seems to be that also our diesel strategy is starting to work out.</p>
          <p>And as you know, we have some more engines which we could offer in the upcoming years in the U.S., plus new models which we are extending to the U.S. market as well. So that means that with the current product portfolio, which is planned for the U.S. market, we see a clear potential until 2015, which is our strategic outlook of roundabout 160,000 units. And then later on towards the 2018, we'll see what will be possible on top of it.</p>
          <p>The second part of the question was different mixes. Maybe here also it's true what I said before on a worldwide basis that we are focusing dramatically on C and D shift. Currently in the U.S., 15% of our cars sold are C and D cars. This will double to 30% within the next few years. So, also here we are taking advantage of our great models, the new A8, A7 and A6 in this market.</p>
          <p>Chattanooga factory, it's something that strategically is of course an interesting option for us in the future, but no time pressure on any decision on this. And we are still looking into this possibility, exploring all kinds of different opportunities, and Chattanooga is one of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now we have another question which was asked by a journalist. And he would like to know whether the Audi AG can be separated from Volkswagen. Mr. Strotbek, do you have an answer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me clearly say, there are no plans at all, and please understand that we don't make any further comments on this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another journalist question, which refers to the pricing in the U.S. market, and if you could quantify approximately the better leasing rates and residual values in the U.S. versus our European competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably the best example is the hottest product in the market in U.S. right now is the Q5. Actually we are understocked. Dealers are asking for more production, so there's a very high demand on it. And I can tell you that to the direct competitors here, Q5 is 15% above X3 and about 10% above GLK on the leasing front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now we have a question from John Buckland of MF Global. He would like to know about the FX benefit on the second quarter earnings, and he further more asked about the introduction of the A1 and what sense the mix will be impacted and what it will have as an impact on our margin development, can 9% margin be also reported for half two and for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, let me clearly state that the A1 will definitely have a positive contribution to the overall profitability of the Audi brand. And as I mentioned earlier, we will have an operating margin in the second half of the year, which we had seen in the first half, so this means 7.6 plus/minus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have two questions on Porsche. The first one &#x2013; the first question is asked by Frank Biller from LBBW [Landesbank Baden W&#xFC;rttemberg]. And he asked whether there are any news about the cooperation with Porsche and which project are already running and what is planned for the next years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there has been a strong &#x2013; large number of projects between the partners and within the VW Group, but please understand that we will not release any future projects today. This will be done at a specific point of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Another question asked by Sebastian Lab from DPA. He would like to know if there are any plans for a more intense cooperation, for example, like forming a sports car group within Volkswagen similar to the trucks group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, as I've just mentioned in the previous question, we have seen a lot of joint projects and of course we will further look for new opportunities. And once those projects are ready to announce, we will do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question on, let's say, Porsche, I would say. It's asked by Michael Punzet from DZ Bank. And he asked for the case that Audi will get the leadership regarding the sporting car toolbox in the Volkswagen Group, what would be the effect on CapEx and R&amp;D for Audi?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry that third question regarding to future projects in Porsche, we will not release any further details on that topic today. And what I can clearly say that we will strengthen our product portfolio and that there will be, of course, successors of existing cars. And I think this will mainly contribute to the success of Audi in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have a question for Mr. Schwarzenbauer asked by John Buckland from MF Global. Will Audi make cars in the U.S. and when?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I covered it before. It is, of course, a strategic option for us. We are investigating several different possibilities and the Chattanooga plant is one of them</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Mr. Schwarzenbauer. Another question from John Buckland was that during the presentation, that &#x2013; you do not just want to talk about China, but most questions taken seems to be about China, what about our competition mix, margins, pricing et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think about China, what we can say, we currently have a market share on the premium side, I mean this is where we measure ourselves, of 38%. So we are clear, clear market leaders since many, many years. We have a strong presence in the country that we have been the first one to produce locally cars that are specifically targets to the Chinese customers. You know that we have the A4 and the A6 as a long version in the Chinese market and we just started to produce the Q5. So we think we are extremely well-positioned in this market and pricing is very competitive towards the European &#x2013; our European competitors, so we are more or less at the same level as our friends here from BMW and Mercedes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Mr. Schwarzenbauer just answered another question or the question asked by Christian Breitsprecher from Macquarie. He's also asking about the pricing competition in the Chinese market.</p>
          <p>Then we have a question from Christiaan Hetzner from Reuters. Usually VolksWagen calculates net cash flow by subtracting investments from operating cash flow and I assume Audi did as well, but the cash flow statement does not indicate a positive net cash flow of &#x20AC;1.9 billion in the first half, but a substantially negative one. Can you please explain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, our total net cash flow mix was about &#x20AC;1.9 billion is clearly positive, about 500 million against previous years &#x2013; against the previous year. There has been changes in our portfolio where we had our money at -- it's rather a shift between where we put our money into what kind of accounts and into what kind of period of times we left the money in accounts. So this is more an internal shift on the balance sheet and has no impact on the net cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have another question on net cash flow asked by Christiaan Hetzner. Having seen a slide on net cash flow, I see that the &#x20AC;4.84 billion change in securities and loans were stripped out. What does this represent and why did the figure increased from 2.3 billion a year ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we changed our strategy within the last 24 months. So, therefore we are coming back now to put our money on a horizon of more than three months regularly on about six-month horizons. And that's the main reason in the change in our liquidity statement. And maybe let me add. This is due to IFRS standards that we have to show this in our cash flow statement and that's the main reason those questions arise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question by Christiaan Hetzner on net cash flow. Net cash flow or net cash forecast implies the possibility, perhaps even likelihood, that net cash could decline by &#x20AC;1 billion in half two. Is there any reason why you would need to decrease your cash pile, do you see a need to make acquisitions after Italdesign Giugiaro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we are very confident that we will have, also, definitely, clearly positive net cash flow in second half and as a consequence our net liquidity will further rise. And the main objective, of course, is that we can finance all our investments out of our own pockets and not being reliant on external sources. Any further investments such as Italdesign is not planned in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then there's another question from John Buckland of MF Global. Renault has talked about lower mix within segments today. Customers are buying cheaper cars, but this does not seem to be seen by Audi. Does this mean much stronger polarization that we mass-market and premium-market? Can you please explain this development, Mr. Schwarzenbauer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I cannot comment on Renault, but I can tell you that we don't see any of these trends. On a contrary, our transaction prices are going up in average, and specifically what we also can see is that the option content on the cars we are selling is also going upwards. So, we think that this is the sign that the premium market is quite strong and the Audi brand operating within this premium market is extremely attractive. I also think that it helped us a lot on our strategy of increasing our derivates in the different segment.</p>
          <p>Let me give you just one example here. In 2010, we had in the B segment two models basically, the A4 Limo and the A4 Avant. Now we added over the years the A5 Coup&#xE9;, the A5 Cab, the Q5, the A4 Limo and Avant are still here. And now we are selling over &#x2013; and back then in 2010 those two cars, we sold 200,000 units. Now with adding different derivates, we are selling in the B segment first in this year over 550,000 units.</p>
          <p>So you see that the strategy of making our offer much broader in the different segments is working out very well. And at the same time, we are increasing transaction prices. And so, we can't see the trend you are mentioning out of your Renault information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Schwarzenbauer. Ladies and gentlemen, we will soon come to the end of today's live talk, and we will now answer the last questions asked. The next question we have is from Luta Lubineski from Mindfirst. He would like to know more about the quarter-on-quarter comparison and if you can explain the driving forces behind the earnings development, the EBIT quarter-on-quarter increase from &#x20AC;478 million in the first quarter to 853 million in the second quarter. That's a change of &#x20AC;375 million or almost 80%. Retail sales quarter-on-quarter, excluding China, increased by 10% from 212,000 to 232,000 units. How was Audi able to almost double the EBIT and impressively increase its EBIT margin by 50% quarter-on-quarter when deliveries, excluding China, only rose by 10%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, let me mention that we're not looking for the quarterly results only. We are looking for the lasting sustainable growth and profitability of our brand, but there are of course some major items in the two quarters to talk about that differentiate themselves. Number one is, we had a definitely higher volume in quarter two than in quarter one, which of course boosts our profitability.</p>
          <p>Number two, we had the launch of the A1 and the A8 and the R85 and others. So we had a higher amount of start-up costs for our new cars in quarter one. And last but not least, the exchange rate patterns definitely changed after April, so the positive effect of exchange rate volatility came into our books in April, May and June mainly, which was in quarter two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have a question from Christiaan Hetzner of Reuters on the financial results. Pre-tax profit once again surpassed operating profit, can you discuss how much this was impacted by the way we account for earnings from Audi's Chinese joint venture?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The financial result was driven basically by two major items in the first half. One, of course, is the decrease in interest rates, which had a slightly negative impact on the financial results. Clearly positive, of course, hence the increase of our earnings out of our joint venture in China, which more than doubled in the first half compared to last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question which is pretty similar and refers also to a question we had before from Christoph Remyer, DAPD. He would like to have an indication on how much our profit in the first and second quarter came from China and from impact of the dollar/euro ratio in the first half in the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I gave an explanation to that answer already. Once again, we have three major pillars of our China business. This is exporting cost produced in Europe, number one; number two, selling parts into China; and number three, the activity in China in our joint venture and the dividends we receive out of this &#x2013; and the profit we receive out of the joint venture.</p>
          <p>Please understand I don't disclose any further figures, but I can also say that the overall impact on our foreign exchange patterns and the changes in those over the last six months had a slightly positive impact, of course, but it was not an extraordinary effect in our income statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Strotbek. Michael Punzet of DZ Bank has a question for Mr. Schwarzenbauer. If we see any chance that corporate customers or fleets intend to buy smaller cars with less content in Germany or Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we see in the corporate customer area is that companies are focusing more on CO2 emissions. And I think here we are perfectly prepared. We have currently 45 models below 140 grams of CO2. No other premium manufacturer can offer this variety of models below 140 gram. We cannot see a trend that cars are sold with less content, so clear trend towards CO2 emission, yes, but we cannot see any trend towards less content.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Schwarzenbauer. We have another question from a Spanish journalist. He would like to know the overall penetration rate of financing currently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I mentioned earlier, we have a very, very positive net cash flow and we finance all our investments out of our net cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we have a question from Thomas Chad (sic) [Chad Thomas], Bloomberg News. Would Audi consider building completely new models, not as a direct derivative of a current model, specifically for the Chinese market given its growing importance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I strongly believe that as a premium manufacturer, you have to have, what we always call, blood cost, so the same offer around the world. This specific adoptions to local needs, what we did in China as I've mentioned before was the A4 and the A6 as long version, so I can see specific adoptions for different markets, including the Chinese market, but I cannot see specific model developments just for one market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Schwarzenbauer. Now we have another question from Adam Hull, WestLB. Our Group CFO, Mr. Rupert said yesterday on their conference call that at current exchange rates, the second half 2010 EBIT will see further foreign exchange benefits, with the full impact in 2011 to 2012. Does this also apply to the Audi Group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Hull, this fully can be confirmed on the Audi brand as well. If the dollar and all other currencies remain in the level as we have seen in June, we definitely will see the same and have the same impact on the Audi brand. Of course, we &#x2013; nobody of us knows for sure how this will develop, but to be sure and to make things sure we also use the time when the dollar was more attractive for us to increase our future hedging. So I'm pretty confident that we have a good balance on our hedging for the next years to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then we have a last question, which I think was answered during the call, but I think it's an important message, so we answer it for the final &#x2013; for closing our conference call.</p>
          <p>The question from Irene Preisinger at Reuters is on, if we can precise our outlook concerning revenues and operating profit for the total year of 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I have mentioned, Ms. Preisinger, and I will confirm what I have said that we will have an outstanding operating result with the same margin you have seen in the first six months for the second half. And this means, the momentum, the quality, the sustainability of our profit will follow our patterns what we see on the markets. And the next financial figures we will deliver will be due in late October for the third quarter and I'm happy to tell you more by then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Strotbek and Mr. Schwarzenbauer. Ladies and gentlemen, time for today's live talk is up. We would like to thank you in participating in today's webcast and live talk. Enjoy the weekend and your holiday. Thank you and goodbye from Investors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>