<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1353759" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>44121</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Oleg Maximov, Analyst, Troika Dialog Group</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mark A. Gyetvay, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Vadim Mitroshin</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Lev Snykov</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Igor Kurinnyy</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Maxim Moshkov</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Nadia Kazakova</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Mark Anthony</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome to the NOVATEK's Third Quarter Financial Results Conference Call. For information, this call is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Oleg Maximov. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and welcome. I am Oleg Maximov from Troika Dialog and this is NOVATEK's third quarter 2010 IFRS results conference call. Here today is Mark Gyetvay, Chief Financial Officer and Member of the Board of Directors of NOVATEK.</p>
          <p>Mark please start with your presentation. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Oleg. Ladies and gentlemen, shareholders and colleagues, good evening and welcome to our third quarter 2010 earnings conference call. I would like to thank everyone for joining us this evening and again extend our sincere gratitude to Troika Dialog for organizing and hosting this important conference call.</p>
          <p>As customary, before we begin with the specific conference call details I would like to refer you to our disclaimer statement. During this conference call, we may make references to forward-looking statements by using words such as "plans", "objectives", "goals", "strategies" and other similar words, which are other than statements of historical facts. Actual results may differ materially from those implied by such forward-looking statements due to known and unknown risks and uncertainties and reflects our views as of the date of this presentation. We undertake no obligation to revise or publicly release the result of any revisions to these forward-looking statements in light of new information or future events.</p>
          <p>Please refer to our regulatory filings included in our annual review for the year ended the 31st of December, 2009, as well as any of our earnings press releases for more description of the risks that may influence our results.</p>
          <p>First of all, we are very pleased to report record financial and operational results during the past quarter. Our quarterly results continue to demonstrate the robustness of our operations and the successes, we have achieved with our commercial activities. We continue to invest capital in our development projects as planned and remained free cash flow positive during the reporting period. Financial and operational results, we have achieved are consistent with our stated guidance and we have emerged from the recent economic crisis and a stronger financial position without incurring any negative consequences to our liquidity position and/or our business operation.</p>
          <p>However, before we begin discussing the specific quarter-on-quarter and year-on-year financial information, I would like to provide our shareholders with an update of our recent activities. So to begin today's conference call, I would like to briefly discuss the strategic transactions that were recently approved by the Board of Directors and broadly outline how these transactions fit into our asset portfolio and complement our strategic objectives.</p>
          <p>We are very excited about the recent announcements and the accretive value of these transactions to our market capitalization. I have enumerated many times in the past that NOVATEK's corporate strategy is centered on growing our resource base, increasing our natural gas and gas condensate production, expanding our processing capabilities, maintaining our low cost position, optimizing our market and channels and enhancing our net back margins. We have not deviated from our strategic objectives and by undertaking the series of announced acquisitions combined with our ongoing capital expenditure programs. We believe we have continued to enhance as well as supplement our existing asset portfolio with value accretive transactions.</p>
          <p>Speaking about our existing core asset portfolio, it is important that we maintain an inventory of exploration and development projects covering the short, mid and long-term production horizons. With the recent completion of stage three of the second phase development activities at Yurkharovskoye field, it became imperative that we assessed our existing asset portfolio to determine potential opportunity sets both organic and inorganic to complement our core producing fields as well as to maintain our desired growth targets.</p>
          <p>Essentially, this is nothing more than a standard process of high grading our existing asset portfolio. Based on this exercise, we can make prudent capital investment decisions to optimize hydrocarbon reserve movements and production profiles and if necessary acquire or disclose of assets with the ultimate aim of achieving our stated objectives and goals as well as enhancing the net &#x2013; present value of our asset base.</p>
          <p>From a capital investment perspective, we are essentially completing the major capital spending at Yurkharovskoye field and as a result, we expect with regard to spending maintenance capital at the field by the end of next year. If we combine this large producing field, currently representing 72% of our gas production and 58% of our stable gas condensate with our two other producing assets the East-Tarkosalinskoye and Khancheyskoye fields, which are already in maintenance capital mode, all three of our core producing assets will be generating significant free cash flow.</p>
          <p>I have mentioned this fact on a few other occasions and specifically highlighted this point in my last conference call by explaining the expected number of wells needed to grow to complete the field development. Furthermore, it is evident by reviewing the combined capital spend on the East-Tarkosalinskoye and Khancheyskoye fields over the second and third quarters of 2010 representing 206 million and RUB243 million respectively that these two fields generate free cash flow, which is available to redeploy to other development projects or distributed as dividends. It is reasonable to expect that the Yurkharovskoye field will follow the same pattern of free cash flow generation.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet and liquidity position remained strong during the reporting period as evident by the reduction of our net debt quarter-on-quarter by RUB5.4 billion and our ability to fund our capital expenditure program from internally generated cash flows. Our ratio of net operating cash flow to capital expenditures increased from 1.1 times to 1.7 times between the second and third quarters of 2010, clearly demonstrating our ability to fund capital projects and service our existing debt.</p>
          <p>As a result of these developments both the stage of our core asset development and our ability to generate free cash flow, we have now approached key decision point on how best to recycle our free cash flow into future exploration and development projects to continue our growth as outlined in the corporate strategy. The Board of Directors has chosen a path to supplement our current asset portfolio with strategic acquisitions.</p>
          <p>I will now briefly discuss the Tambeyneftegaz acquisition. As previously discussed, in July 2010, we formed a 50-50 joint venture with Gazprom Neft called Yamal Development with the primary aim of developing jointly hydrocarbon assets in Yamal-Nenets Autonomous Region. Yamal Development will acquire a 51% participation interest and limited liability company Tambeyneftegaz from Gazprom for total cash consideration of approximately $1.55 billion excluding the assumption of debt totaling approximately 245 million implying a transaction value per barrel of oil equivalent approximate $0.30/bbl as calculated according to the Russian reserves ABC1+C2.</p>
          <p>Our pro-rata share of this purchase price will represent 50% of the cash consideration and our pro-rata assumption of the debt for total transaction price of approximately U.S. $900 million. The remaining 49% is held by Arctic Russia BD, a 60:40 joint venture of Eni and Enel respectively.</p>
          <p>Tambeyneftegaz through it subsidiaries or licensees to exploit and develop oil and gas licenses in the Yamal-Nenets Autonomous Region which are in close proximity to our existing transportation and process and infrastructure and the Purovsky processing plant. There is no meaningful commercial production at any of the acquired fields as of yet and accordingly we are presently studying the existing development plans.</p>
          <p>Based on our extensive understanding as a subsurface geology in this area, combined with the successful development program we have implemented at the current fields we have formed a very definitive deal on how best to exploit the resources in a cost effective manner consistent with the development cost at our other field locations. As a result, we together with our partners may supplement or amend the current development plans.</p>
          <p>Tambeyneftegaz is comprised with three entities, Arctic Gas hold for a two exploration and development license areas, oil and well one license area and Neftegaz Tecnologia also the one license area. The Samborski field owned by Artigas is the most advanced in terms of its development stage. As of the 31st of October, 2010, the Samborski field had drilled 15 development wells, built facilities including the gas separation plant, fire station and rotational field camp and began construction of a gas and gas condensate pipeline infrastructure although the pipeline infrastructure is not completed at this time.</p>
          <p>All of the remaining license areas are in the early stage of development, plus we would generally characterize this acquisition as primarily being Greenfield development although as mentioned the Samborski is in advanced stage of development. We anticipate the commencement of initial production at this field by the end of 2011.</p>
          <p>As at the 1 of January 2009, total reserves under the Russian reserve classification ABC1 and C2 totaled 1.3 trillion cubic meters of natural gas, 154 million tons of gas condensate and 568 million tons of crude oil according to the Russian Federation's State Balance of the Reserves for a combined total of approximate 13.3 billion barrels of oil equivalent. We expect to have our petroleum engineers DeGolyer and MacNaughton appraise the reserves in accordance to SEC and PRMS reserve methodologies as part of the annual reserve appraisal.</p>
          <p>We believe this transaction provides immediate synergy benefits to NOVATEK due to the close proximity to license areas to our recently launched gas condensate pipeline from the Yurkharovskoye field to Purovsky processing plant, best optimize and utilization of our existing pipeline and processing infrastructure. It is anticipated that gas produced from this field will be purchased directly by Gazprom. We will count for this acquisition under the equity method.</p>
          <p>I will briefly discuss our announced transaction of the 51% equity stake in Surgutneftegaz which holds four exploration license, and product license excuse me, in the Yamal-Nenets region and is also located in close proximity to our existing infrastructure in fields. We will acquire the 51% equity stake from Gazprombank for total cash consideration of approximately $865 million excluding the assumption of our pro rata share of debt of approximately RUB11 billion. And applying the transaction value of approximately $1.26 per Boe as calculated based on the latest PRMS proved reserves appraised by DeGolyer &amp; MacNaughton. Under the ABC1+C2 reserve the implied transaction value that's approximately $0.91 per Boe and the remaining 41% interest in Surgutneftegaz is held by Itera.</p>
          <p>The largest in our four field areas, it is a very good oil field, which presently has 63 developments wells producing mainly dry gas from the Cenomanian layers and is already connected to the UGS pipeline structure via a 32 kilometer pipeline. Natural gas produced from this particular horizon does not require significant further processing for commercial suitability.</p>
          <p>It is important to highlight that a significant portion of capital expenditures has already been invested into veritable refills development stage. Plus there is no need currently to develop infrastructure making the sale for the Purovsky processing plant or expend significant sums of cash into sale development. Surgutneftegaz also produces small quantities of natural gas from the <mark type="inaudible" /> field which has completed 12 development wells, some treatment facilities and is also presently connected to the UGS system via a 36 kilometer pipeline.</p>
          <p>There are ongoing exploration activities and some limited development activities on the two other licensed areas, but as of today there is really nothing of significance to report. For your information the existent infrastructure at Sibneftegaz sales in licensed areas have been constructed over the past three years. After the 31 of December 2009 the PRMS proved reserves as appraised by D&amp;M totaled 290 billion cubic meters of natural gas and 2 million tons of condensate for a combined total of approximately 1.9 billion barrels of oil equivalent.</p>
          <p>The total proved but probable reserves as defined under the PRMS reserve methodology totaled 344 billion cubic meters of natural gas and 3.8 million tons of condensate for a combined total of approximately 2.3 billion barrels of oil equivalent. We will account for our 51% equity stake in Sibneftegaz under the equity method because the voting rights in respect of Sibneftegaz will be split 50-50 with Itera.</p>
          <p>Total production in both producing fields is estimated to be approximately 10.2 billion cubic meters in 2010 and as of the 30th of September Sibneftegaz's production totaled approximately 7.3 billion cubic meters. We will separately market our pro-rata share of natural gas from the fields beginning the 1st of January 2011 and equally important our pro-rata share production is already considered into NOVATEK's Russian gas balance.</p>
          <p>I will briefly discuss how we plan to finance these two acquisitions. We have arranged for bridge financing facility with a group of banks. We will draw down the entire amount of the bridge facility as well as utilize additional credit facility for our pro-rata share of the total consideration paid by Yamal Development to acquire SeverEnergia.</p>
          <p>The Board of Directors have approved the placement of a Euro bond up to the maximum amount of $1.5 billion for a maximum period of up to 10 years. The maximum amount and periods were stipulated by the Board to provide sufficient flexibility based on prevailing market conditions at the time of placement. The proceeds from the placement will repay the bridge facility and any remaining acquisition cost.</p>
          <p>For the Sibneftegaz acquisition we will finance this acquisition with an initial cash payment of approximately $150 million of their purchase price at closing with the remaining balance of approximately 715 million due to be paid by the end of the fourth quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>A portion of the final purchase price will obviously will be paid from the cash generated from our pro-rata share of natural gas production from this particular field inclusive of other internally generated cash flows and the use of existing debt facilities.</p>
          <p>During the period we completed the divestiture of our non-core Polymer business to Joint Stock Company SIBUR Holding for RUB2.4 billion payable throughout September 2013. Under international accounting, we recognized the loss on this disposal by applying a discount of 8% to the deferred payment.</p>
          <p>With the disposal of this entity which accounted for less than 2% of our revenues, we will free up the requirement to invest significant capital over the next few years to modernize and mature the plants product output. In light of this consideration, a discussion was made to dispose of this non-core business to focus our capital investments in our core gas and gas condensate business.</p>
          <p>I would like to now move on to the next area of my discussion and say a few words on Yamal LNG. Recently Prime Minister Putin was present to launch the third stage production facilities at our Yurkharovskoye field. During this event it was mentioned that the Russian Government will propose a series of tax concessions specific to our LNG project.</p>
          <p>Subsequent to this event a formal Executive Order was issued by the Prime Minster to relevant ministries to prepare the necessary framework for a signature into law. This Executive Order is posted on official Russian Government website.</p>
          <p>Essentially the Executive Order stipulates zero MET for the first 250 billion cubic meters of LNG or for a period not exceeding 12 years. Zero MET for the first 20 million tons of gas condensate or for a period not extending 12 years in request that development ministries develop a plan whereby the LNG and stable gas condensate from this particular project will be subject to zero export duties. We expect the fulfillment of the Executive Order to be finalized shortly. This Executive Order provides clarity to the expected fiscal terms for this project.</p>
          <p>Another important step in the process is the completion of the pre-feed study which as of this date is almost complete and based on the work conducted during this feasibility study we now have a better understanding of the technical aspects of the project.</p>
          <p>Based on this latest information we have restarted negotiation dialogues for potential strategic partners. This process is now ongoing and we will provide additional update once we have concrete items to discuss. We expect that the financial investment decision on the Yamal LNG project will be made in 2012.</p>
          <p>I would also like to make a few comments regarding some of our commercial marketing activities before we proceeding with our financial operation results for the third quarter of 2010. We've recently completed the sign-in of a new five-year gas contract with ITERA for approximately 4 billion cubic meters per annum effective the 1st of January 2011 based on the FTS price at this FERC lost region. This agreement is not related in any way to our planned acquisition of Sibneftegaz and will be characterized as sales to wholesale traders.</p>
          <p>I know there have been questions about our ability to market our forecasted productions; this contract is just one recent example. During the quarter, we also made a small acquisition for the amount of $5 million to purchase 100% of the outstanding shares of Intergaz-System, one of the largest LPG traders in Southeast Poland. Intergaz is a holder of the discharging and transshipment facilities at the point where the rail links between Russia and European are different mainly a point where the wide and narrow tracks meet. We believe this acquisition will facilitate commercial development activities within Poland and other European countries. And that extensively concludes my update comments during the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Our production growth for both natural gas and liquids during the third quarter and the nine months ended September 30, 2010 continue to be driven by the successful development of Yurkharovskoye field over the past couple of years. Since 2008, we managed to complete three stages of the fields Phase II development with the most recent launch of another 7 billion cubic meters of capacity availability in October 2010. With the successful launches of these three stages, we have managed to increase the fields productive capacity to approximately 33 billion cubic meters per annum and NOVATEK's total productive capacity to approximately 52 billion cubic meters.</p>
          <p>We anticipate that the field gross natural gas and unstable gas production will more than double from 11.5 &#x2013; 11.7 billion cubic meters in 2008 to approximately 24.6 billion cubic meters by year end 2010 and from 895,000 tons to approximately 2.1 million tons over the same corresponding period. If we combined the infrastructure project that are to be completed and commissioned, during this respective time period, the operational compliments achieved at the Yurkharovskoye field have been stellar. The Yurkharovskoye field will be the cornerstone of NOVATEK's production profile for many years and a significant source of present and future cash flow generation.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter 2010, we managed to increase our natural gas production by 604 million cubic meters or by 7.8% over the prior year-on-year period, supporting continued growth in our production profile from ongoing development activities. We also managed to marginally increase our gas production by 84 million cubic meters quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>For the nine months ended September 30, 2010 we averaged 98 million cubic meters per day or approximately 3.5 billion cubic feet per day representing an 8.9% increase over the full year 2009 average daily gas production. We have subsequently increased our daily average production to approximately 124 million cubic meters per day or the equivalent 4.4 Bcf per day effective the 1st of November, 2010 thus reconfirming our production guidance for 2010 assuming normal weather patterns rather the remainder of this calendar year.</p>
          <p>Presently the weather has been as a more, as more than normal over the past few weeks or so this year which may put some downside pressure on total Russian gas consumption. During the third quarter 2010, we increased our total production of liquid hydrocarbons year-on-year by a 146,000 tons or by 19.8% and marginally quarter-on-quarter driven again by continued strong production growth of 44.1% and 4.1% respectively at Yurkharovskoye field.</p>
          <p>The increase on our year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter liquids productions was mainly derived from production increases of unstable gas condensate offset by slight reductions include oil production.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned in my last conference call, we dispatched the first high ton tanker. The Aframax tanker Baltica on the port of Murmansk to navigate the Northern sea route, carrying a consignment of approximately 70,000 tons of stable gas condensate destined to the Asia-Pacific region.</p>
          <p>The tanker landed at the port of Ningbo on the east coast of China in September and by utilizing the sea route, we were able to significantly reduce the nautical miles of this voyage from approximately 12,900 to approximately 7,700. The cargo traveled in approximately half the time it would have taken us to deliver this cargo using a traditional shipment route through the Suez Canal. We are planning to ship additional cargos utilizing this new route when navigational conditions permit.</p>
          <p>We have highlighted many times before the seasonal variations on our natural gas production and sales by stating that repeat during the first and fourth quarters and we dropped during the second and third quarters. These seasonal trading patterns held during this particular quarter, however, as you're probably be well aware, we experienced the brutally hot summer in this past year, especially, during the months of July and August where average temperatures exceeded the corresponding prior year by roughly seven to eight degree celsius. This meant our overall consumption in Russia was quite robust during this period with strong demand coming from the power sector.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter 2010, we increased our year-on-year sales of natural gas and consumers by approximately 280 million cubic meters or by 3.7%. We also had a notable shift in sales volumes to end customers quarter-on-quarter by approximately 881 million cubic meters or by 17% reflecting the increased consumption by a main consumer base during the hot summer months. As a result, we shifted our quarter-on-quarter sales mix by roughly 9% achieving a 75/25 split in incomes in consumers the wholesale traders as compared to a 66/34 split in the second quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>If we return back to the year-on-year comparison, we changed the composition of our end customer sales year-on-year with a cessation of sales to traders at remote points effective the 1st of January 2010, which meant that we significantly increased our direct sales to consumers as well as enhanced the average net back we received during this period relative to the corresponding period.</p>
          <p>If you recall, our average net back for total end customer sales in the third quarter of 2009 was approximately RUB994 per 1,000 cubic meters inclusive of sales to traders in remote points. During the current reporting period, we managed to increase our average net back by 19.2% or by RUB191 per 1,000 cubic meters by eliminating that category of sales even though our average transport cost increased as a result of transport tariff hike and an increase in the average distance to market.</p>
          <p>Our average transport distance increased year-on-year from 1,952 kilometers for 2,052 kilometers largely attributable to regional shifts and sales with significant increases in sales to come Orenburg, Sverdlovsk in the Moscow regions, which will offset by reduce sales to this Chelyabinsk region and Bashkortostan Republic.</p>
          <p>If we look at the same comparison quarter-on-quarter, the main difference in our end customer sales volumes essentially represents a geographical shift to more distant regions in the current quarter most notably an increase of deliveries to the Moscow region by 355 million cubic meters which represented 40% of the quarter-on-quarter increase. In other words, our average distance increased by approximately 180 kilometers or by 6% explaining the quarter-on-quarter increase in our transport expense and the marginal reduction of approximately RUB30 per thousand cubic meters in our average net back.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter of 2010, we injected approximately 229 million cubic meters of natural gas into the underground storage system to meet future production obligations. Our balance in our underground storage at the 30th of September stood at approximately 1.1 billion cubic meters as compared to 829 million cubic meters after the 30th of June 2010 and 503 million cubic meters as of 30th of September 2009.</p>
          <p>Overall, we're very pleased with the strong financial results we achieved for our natural gas business in the reporting period. The average realized price we received for end customer sales was consistent what our price expectation vis-&#xE0;-vis the general tariff increased and a relative geographical mix of our primary customer base during the quarter. Moreover, we combined our net average, net back price increase year-on-year by 17.6% but it was slightly lower by less than 1% quarter-on-quarter as explained by the increase in our average transport distance.</p>
          <p>Our total volume sold through liquids increased by 37.6% or by approximately 266,000 tons as compared to the prior year. Specifically we increased the volume of stable gas condensate sold year-on-year from 467,000 tons to 722,000 tons or by 54.6% including the recognition of approximately 126,000 tons of stable gas condensate or two tankers that were previously reported as in transit.</p>
          <p>We also managed to increase our volume sold for LPG by 17,000 tons and marginally decreased our volume sold for crude oil by 6,000 tons. In comparison to the second quarter 2010, we increased our total volume of liquids sold by 152,000 tons due to the reduction in stable gas condensate volumes in transit essentially representing a quarter-on-quarter reversal of approximately 181,000 tons.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter 2010, we reduced the volume of stable gas condensate in transit and storage by approximately 126,000 tons culminating in a period ending inventory balance of 206,000 tons as of 30th September as compared to 332,000 tons at the end of the second quarter and 202,000 tons at the end of the 30th September, 2009.</p>
          <p>We dispatched 10 tankers carrying approximately 601,000 tons from the Vitino Sea Port Terminal of which six tankers or approximately 58.6% of the volumes dispatched were destined to the U.S. markets as compared to four tankers or 40.2% in the second period 2010. Of the remaining four tankers dispatched, one was sent to Singapore and three were sent to China. This was the second consecutive quarter whereby we had no tanker sales to the European markets.</p>
          <p>Our Purovsky Processing Plant operated at 67% of its rated capacity with a total output reaching 807,000 tons comprised of 597,000 tons of stable gas condensate, 207,000 tons of LPG and approximately 3,000 tons of methanol. During the third quarter 2010, we completed line fill requirements for the new unstable gas condensate pipeline by allocating approximately 30,000 tons of unstable gas condensate produced at the Yurkharovskoye field to the capitalized cost of the project as well as allocating approximately 6,000 tons of unstable gas condensate to the newly constructed de-ethanization plant.</p>
          <p>Our average export netbacks on a U.S. Dollar basis for stable gas condensate and LPG volume sold during the period increased year-on-year by approximately 6% and 33.9% respectively despite the increases in both export duties and average transportation expenses. In comparison to the second quarter 2010 our average export netback for stable gas condensate and LPGs increased by 3.3% and 29.2% respectively, largely attributable to reductions in transport and export duties for both projects.</p>
          <p>For stable gas condensate we sold 722,000 tons, realized an average netback per ton of approximately U.S. $301 for the third quarter 2010 as compared to $292 per ton in the second quarter 2010 and $284 in the third quarter of the prior year. Our quarter-on-quarter netbacks increased by approximately $9 per ton which resulted from an 8.1% decrease in export duties, a 10.6% decrease in transport charge and a 2.6% decrease in the average contractual price period-on-period. The positive effect of the changes in both export duties and transport charges largely negated the decrease in average contract price.</p>
          <p>For LPG sales we managed to significantly increase our year-on-year average export netback by U.S. $123 per ton on sales volume of 103,000 tons whereas our quarter-on-quarter comparative showed an increase in our average export netback by U.S. $110 per ton although on reduced sales volumes.</p>
          <p>This quarter-on-quarter increase in our average netback was largely due to the higher average contractual price we received which was partially offset by the application of the real and export duty concessions. Domestically we had a reduction in both volumes sold and average netback received by 16.9% and 14% respectively. There were no sales of LPG to the CIS countries during the reporting period.</p>
          <p>We had a quarter-on-quarter reduction in our LPG sales volumes due to the commission in our new gas condensate pipeline and deethinization unit connecting the Yurkharovskoye field with the Purovsky plant. By eliminating the need to use third party facilities, we retained a higher quality of unstable gas condensate before processing to our wholly owned facilities, which ultimately reduced the output volumes of LPG we received at the Purovsky processing plant.</p>
          <p>Overall, we are pleased with the strength of our liquid business and the financial results we achieved during the third quarter 2010. We manage to increase our year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter stable gas condensate sales by 68.6% and 37.7% respectively based on stronger benchmark prices and reduction in inventory volumes and our LPG sales by 27.2% year-on-year. The quarter-on-quarter increase was marginal. As a percentage of total revenues, our liquid business accounted for 41.6% during the reporting period, as compared to 36.6% year-on-year, and 38.3% quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>Our total operating expenses increased year-on-year in absolute terms from RR 13.6 billion to RR 17.6 billion, but decreased as a percentage of total revenues from 62.1% to 59.7%. However, for the remaining discussions on operating cost during this conference call, I will focus my attention primarily between the quarter-on-quarter comparators, unless something needs to be specifically highlighted to better understand the year-on-year numbers.</p>
          <p>Total operating expenses increased by approximately RR 1.9 billion between the second and third quarters, but decreased as a percentage of total revenues from 61.1% to 59.7% largely due to increase in total revenues and our ability to manage controllable cost.</p>
          <p>Transportation expenses and our depreciation -- depletion and amortization charge accounted for approximately 1.3 billion or 68.4%, and 234 million or 12.3% respectively are the change between the periods. The main difference between our operating expenses quarter-on-quarter, or the overall impact on total operating expenses due to volumetric changes, which increased our variable rate expenses as one would expect.</p>
          <p>As previously explained, our total volume sold to end customers increased by 881 million cubic meters or by 17%, which meant that we had a corresponding increase in transportation expenses as our percentage of end customer sales quarter-on-quarter increased from 66% to 75%. Furthermore, we also increased our average transport distance by roughly a 108 kilometers, which partially accounted for the increase in transport expenses during the quarter. The transportation of liquid products contributed 218 million to the overall increase in third quarter transport expenses as more volumes were sold during the quarter.</p>
          <p>In addition, 222 million was charged to operating expenses for the recognition of stable gas condensate revenues that reached its intended destination. The change in inventory was partially offset by the injection of natural gas into underground storage amongst other minor items.</p>
          <p>The same sort of volumetric analysis can be applied to the variable nature of our taxes other than income, but since the overall volumes produced for both natural gas and liquids were reasonably constant period-on-period, the changes in our expense line items were not significant. The only notable change quarter-on-quarter related to their movement in excise and fuel taxes for deliveries of LPG into Poland through our wholly-owned subsidiary, NOVATEK Polska, which increased from 56 million in the second quarter to 82 million in the third quarter. All other changes in tax balances were considered immaterial.</p>
          <p>Former discussions relating to general and administrative expenses and material services and others, I will briefly highlight some of the more significant changes year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter, although we believe we have done an excellent job in managing our controllable expenses throughout these respective periods. The year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter changes in materials, services and other operating expenses was not considered to be material. However, there are certain component costs that tend to fluctuate period-on-period or have been eliminated through the subsequent consolidation of entities previously accounted for as associates, such as operator service expenses.</p>
          <p>The main reason for the year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter increase in materials and supplies related to the purchases of the raw material for the production of polymer products. This trend has been relatively consistent period-on-period, depending on the increase and/or decrease in polymer sales activities. During both reporting periods the increases in polymer sales resulted in correspondent increases in the purchases of raw material feedstock. The divestiture of our polymer business in September of 2010, as noted earlier, renders this issue moved going forward.</p>
          <p>I mentioned on my last earnings conference call that effective the 1st of July we were planning to introduce a companywide inflationary wage adjustment of 10%. I would like to report that this wage adjustment was implemented as planned. Within the material services and other operating expenses, we recorded payroll related expenses for employees who are physically located at our sales operations and charged as part of our operating cost. During the third quarter 2010, we increased the number of employees charged to OpEx by 84 individuals.</p>
          <p>However, despite the increase in our employee head count and a 10% wage adjustment, our quarter-on-quarter employee compensation expense by roughly RUB26 million due to reduction in miscellaneous payroll benefits. The change year-on-year related mostly for the wage indexation and the increase in salaries for the increase in personnel. One added benefit that we expected to achieve with the construction and launch of our own process and transport facilities was a correspondent reduction in these similar types of payments to third-parties.</p>
          <p>With the launch of the deethinization unit at the Yurkharovskoye field in August 2010, we managed to reduce our year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter processing fees paid to third-parties by RUB30 million and RUB91 million respectively. We will continue to monitor these particular cost savings over the next several quarters and report them accordingly. In respect of general and administrative expenses, I will explain some of the more significant changes, such as the 10% companywide adjustment, movements in head count and other items, which I believe is relevant to the readers of our financial statements.</p>
          <p>We consider this important expense category to be well-controlled by senior management and as our historical financial results, our G&amp;A expenses do not fluctuate dramatically period-on-period as a percent of revenues.</p>
          <p>We increased our total G&amp;A expenses by approximately RUB348 million or 22.4% as compared with the prior year, but this expense item decreased marginally quarter-on-quarter. The main components representing the year-on-year increase was the changes in employee compensation and an increase in our charitable contributions.</p>
          <p>Our employee compensation expense increased year-on-year by approximately RUB158 million due to the salary indexation as already mentioned and a corresponding increase in employee head count by 33 employees. The combination of these two factors accounted for approximately RUB100 million of the increase.</p>
          <p>Another main factor contributed to the increase was the initiation of our share-based compensation program in the second quarter 2010 as part of our long-term employee motivation program which excludes members of the management board.</p>
          <p>We expensed 86 million and RUB99 million to employee compensation as part of the share-based program during the second and third quarters respectively. No share-based compensation was expensed in the prior year.</p>
          <p>Our employee compensation expenses decreased quarter-on-quarter by approximately RUB138 million largely due to the reduction in bonus payments between the two periods. Even though our employee head count increased by 33 individuals between the second and third quarters of 2010, the affect of the head count increase was largely offset by the reduction in bonus payments.</p>
          <p>During the last conference call, I mentioned that we do not consider employee compensation to be an area warranted excess of scrutiny because the actual expenses relative to our total revenues was reasonably consistent over the past couple of years, and that same changes were made to employee compensation were implemented to better align employee compensation to shareholder value creation.</p>
          <p>I would like again to reiterate that employee compensation as recorded in our G&amp;A expense category has averaged as a percent of revenues approximately 3% to 3.3% over the past six quarters, again confirming my point. As of the end of the third quarter our total G&amp;A head count totaled 1,059 employees.</p>
          <p>We continue to increase our capital asset base with ongoing worker activities during the respective periods. Our depreciation, depletion and amortization increased year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter by 316 million or by 21.5% and by 234 million, or by 15.1% respectively, largely due to the commission of a series of capital projects at the Yurkharovskoye field.</p>
          <p>Our DD&amp;A unit charge as calculated under the units-of-production method continues to fluctuate period-on-period and was RUB23.9 per barrel of oil equivalent, largely due to the capitalization of approximately 7.1 billion to the cost depletion base in the third quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>We fully expect that the depletion cost base will continue to increase over the remaining course of the year as we capitalize cost to oil and gas producing properties, each respective period and only adjust our reserves on an annual basis which is fully explained in our MD&amp;A.</p>
          <p>As a result of the factors enumerated above our EBITDA and net profit margins have remained healthy and consistent with out financial guidance and we have increased relative to the financial results we have achieved in the second quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>If you exclude the positive and/or negative effects from finance income of expenses, our quarter-on-quarter profits from operations increased approximately RUB10 billion to RUB12 billion or by approximately 20% largely due to increases in our natural gas and liquid sales. Our net profit between period continues to be affected by fluctuations in exchange rate of Russian ruble relative to U.S. dollar and the application of those foreign exchange movements to the portion of our debt positioned denominated in U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter the Russian ruble depreciated against the U.S. dollar by roughly 6.2% resulting in a non-cash foreign exchange loss of RUB1.1 billion, whereas our third quarter net profits were positively aided by a 571 million non-cash foreign exchange gain due to the appreciation of Russian ruble against the U.S. dollar by approximately 2.6%.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet and liquidity position continue to remain strong throughout the third quarter as we decreased our total debt position relative to our year-end and second quarter balances largely due to the payment of debt as scheduled.</p>
          <p>We will continue to serve as our syndicate term loan facility and another debt facility as they mature and finally, we continued to remain free cash flow positive throughout the nine months of 2010.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, we have delivered another solid quarter of financial and operational results completely in line with our expectations for the period. During 2010 we have continued to demonstrate our ability to grow our production of natural gas as domestic demand recovers as well as optimize our sales mix to minimize the effects of seasonal patterns.</p>
          <p>We have also continued to demonstrate our ability to deliver our liquid products to our main consumable markets and we are very proud of the distinction that we were the first company to deliver a large tanker of hydrocarbons through the Northern Sea Route.</p>
          <p>Tonight I briefly touched on our recently announced acquisition and the rationale for investing our expected free cash flow generation. We're very excited about the two announced acquisitions because we know the asset base and the subsurface geology in the region very well and we believe we can accrete value to these acquisitions based on our proven track record of optimizing field development.</p>
          <p>Equally important the Sibneftegaz acquisition will provide incremental volumes to our gas marketing efforts and immediately generate cash flows. Both of these acquisitions will have the minimum contribution to our reserve base and in short continued growth and stabilization of our production profile.</p>
          <p>Our proven operating track record for optimizing field development, our low finding and developing cost and our commitment to cost control will continue to be the hallmark of our operating philosophy.</p>
          <p>Our goal is to create sustainable shareholder value. We remain confident in NOVATEK's growth strategy and we look forward to integrating these value accretive transactions as part of our asset portfolio.</p>
          <p>I will like to end this portion of the conference call and open the season to Q&amp;A. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We take the first question from Oleg Maximov from Troika-Dialog. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Mark. Thank you for the presentation updates. Three questions for me, if you could please discuss the operational upside, do you see at Sibneftegaz. What is the production growth upside from the turn 10 billion cubic meters per year? Is there any cost upside that you see in the company?</p>
          <p>And second question on the Ust-Luga, if you could educate me on the project given that, it will be the new cost, capital cost item for NOVATEK starting next year basically I'm trying to understand what are you're trying to achieve there? And third question, there's new contract with Itera, would you be willing to update your production guidance for next year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Oleg. On the first one, Sibneftegaz I mean, essentially what we have today is what we've reported. We're only going to report production expected for the remainder of this particular year as I mentioned 10.3 &#x2013; 10.2, 10.3 and current production as of September of 7.3 for the field.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned, we have &#x2013; there are all licenses in the particular field and the trend I feel is still in its early state of development. So I don't want to speculate at this particular point on any upside. I believe that it should be able to influence the cost side of the business, due to our understanding the field et cetera.</p>
          <p>But I think it's too premature to really go into that at this particular juncture. On your second question Ust-Luga, for those who don't know what Ust-Luga is about, Ust-Luga is going to be 6 million ton fractionation unit built on a new, I guess product export port about a 170 kilometers South of St. Petersburg region on the Baltic Sea.</p>
          <p>The Ust-Luga project for us will be constructed over the next couple of years and we're going to do it similar to what we did with the Purovsky processing plant is constructed in essentially two phases.</p>
          <p>The first phase we expect to be 3 million tons and that will be completed probably some time in the fourth quarter of 2010 as planned. The objective of Ust-Luga is essentially to take the stable gas condensate that was produced and processed at the Purovsky processing plant and fractionated further down into a constituent of different products such as light naphtha, heavy naphtha, diesel fuel, jet fuel et cetera. And based on that particular constituent products we now have a broader market to sell our products than we presently have say with stable gas condensate.</p>
          <p>So if you look at the stable gas condensate market essentially today, we probably have about 20 or so firm buyers or stable condensate globally. With the fractionation of these constituent parts, product parts we then open up our market in to a significantly higher level of consumers in excess of 100 or so which provides us a little more flexibility to deliver products into the product market.</p>
          <p>And also the other thing too, is that as you know, traditionally our stable gas condensate was priced on a benchmark crude, WTI brands where it went into Asia, Japan, Naphtha and Dubai, Dubai light, and then it had a formula, which some times had premiums, sometimes had a discount. With the product market, we have a defined benchmark prices. So it kind of puts a little more clarity to the product stream.</p>
          <p>What we &#x2013; if you look at where we are today essentially, we have recently &#x2013; our plan to recently finish the next few days I believe are project documents and these documents are essentially technical documents, project definition, engineering components et cetera and we need to finish this before they can really begin construction in earnest. So we'll have this done, submit it to the relevant ministries et cetera who are responsible for that and then start to &#x2013; we can &#x2013; are able to start with the construction side.</p>
          <p>Also I think we're just in about, we're looking to complete the same type of project document for the subcontractors, so that we can essentially decide through a tender process, what contractors will be selected for this particular project and I think we're looking at probably within the first half, probably closer to May, June of 2011 to complete that side of the documentation and contracting phase.</p>
          <p>However, with that said, we've already completed a series of work at Yurkharovskoye, essentially about a 100% almost I would say &#x2013; our total almost 100%. We completed the dredging and the land reclamation of &#x2013; around the field and essentially what we did, we built &#x2013; we dredged sand out of the bay, out of the sea &#x2013; excuse me and rebuilt a new wall and extended the land section and as a result of that we're constructing a 540 meter jetty, which I believe as of today &#x2013; reasonably say we completed just slightly under 50% of the sea wall and this jetty will be able to accommodate two Aframax type class tankers of about 75,000 tons each.</p>
          <p>Next year I think we'll continue again sort of in more earnest the actual construction whereby we start to begin in the actual delivery of equipment to the site building and completing some of the reservoir pipelines, sort of communication electricity, motor lines et cetera and then as I mentioned complete Phase I, 3 million tons per annum by approximately the fourth quarter of 2012. So essentially what it is, it's a project that we've been considering for the last couple of years as a way to facilitate further our marketing of our products at the same time ultimately enhancing the overall netback we received or optimize the netback we received for the finished products.</p>
          <p>I think it's also important to note too, is that when this particular facility is completed it will essentially mean that we probably will stop deliveries of stable gas condensate to the port of Vitino. We will then essentially use the Yurkharovskoye, facility, both where the exports of products and the export of our stable gas condensate. So going forward we probably once this is completed we will stop using the port of Vitino.</p>
          <p>And your third question, in terms of providing any additional guidance going forward, as I mentioned in our last conference call, we expected at least 12% over next year. I don't think we have deviated dramatically from that, but now we have to add on top of that the acquired assets that we expect to produce in 2011. But the Itera, the new Itera contract does not imply that we anticipate to increase or provide additional guidance for our production. What it does and I just wanted to demonstrate that we have now, we're increasing the market for the increased production that we planned to produce, because that was raised by several people and I read in several of the analyst comments from time-to-time that they question our ability to market this gas and that was just one example of the new contract we signed. It's not the only contract that we plan to sign, but it's one of the ones that we've already signed and it will be effective as of 1st of January 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much Mark, very detailed. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Vadim Mitroshin from OTKRITIE. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes hello, good afternoon Mark. It's Vadim Mitroshin from OTKRITIE Bank. I guess I want to return to your acquisitions and I just wanted to verify that I understood it correctly the fact that you provided earlier during your presentation, you said that you will pay 865 million for 51% stake in Sibneftegaz plus assumption of debt of RUB11 billion, which is roughly 355, do we understand correctly that the total cost for you acquisition price will be roughly 1.2 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say, yes. The numbers that you basically have remunerated are the numbers that we planned as I mentioned, yeah. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The numbers that you are generating essentially yeah, that's the total consideration if we assumed the debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Just to verify, I think you also mentioned that despite the fact that you will be buying 51% of stake, you intend to reflect this company in your accounts on a negative basis, because your split in the Board of Directors will be 50-50 with Itera. I wonder if it's true then what are the conditions for you to potentially receiving control over this the subsidiary, and if there is any plan to do so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't say it was the Board. I basically said a charted document basically, the Board invites a 50-50 and that's what it is right now. I really can't comment on anything else in relation to whether or not that will change or not. But that that's where it is right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally, if you could give us any guidance at all regarding next year, regarding CapEx, because my understanding that once the Yurkharovskoye facility modernization and upgrade are finished, my question is essentially how much CapEx do you plan to allocate to your core assets next year, and how much should we anticipate you will allocate to Sibneftegaz gas developments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, CapEx right now, I want to revert from providing any numbers on CapEx as obviously until such time if we close these transactions and get final approval from our Board of Directors on a capital expenditure program for 2011, we will then disclose those numbers. So I think we should wait on that until such time as this process is done and we decide exactly what we're going to do in terms of development activities by the Board in terms of what needs to be spend for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Lev Snykov from VTB Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening. Mark, basically an extension of the previous question, do I understand right that the shareholder agreement, which doesn't allow you to consolidate Sibneftegaz is the legacy from the previous shareholders? Basically the agreement the initial agreement between Gazprom and Itera on the split of control?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's correct. I mean the charter document; we're talking about the charter document right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now if you look at it where it it's essentially 11 Member Board, okay? We will have six people on the Board based on our 51%. But all decisions, all decisions that will be made relative to this field or activity will be approved by, this would be, nine people or ten, by nine people as defined by the charter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So would you say that the right way to model it going forward is an equity method or we should just simply wait until we finalize the deal and maybe sort out the issues with Itera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, presently now we're planning to account for equity, equity accounting and I would probably wait to see if there's any further news flow coming from this particular transaction then, they may or may not change their relationship. But right now we're planning to account for our 51% under the equity method.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And when would you expect all the details to be sorted out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean I really can't comment on that. I mean it's ongoing, let us get into the project first, as long as, there is undergoing discussions let us get into the asset first, close the transaction and then we'll provide some additional information probably either at the annual update or some time earlier. But right now I just really can't comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll now take our next question from Igor Kurinnyy from ING Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone, its Igor Kurinnyy, also a good afternoon. I have three questions; one is on level of maintenance CapEx, which Mark you mentioned that it seemed it will basically move to the maintenance model Yurkharovskoye field. So, I was wondering if you could comment of what the maintenance CapEx would be and in case that your CapEx does grow significant to say in 2011 or 2012, would you consider paying a higher dividends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of Yurkharov, Igor, I prefer that -- what I'm telling you now, yes, we have additional capital need to be spent. Although it's discretionary since we've already achieved capacity today at 33 billion cubic meters, all the infrastructures in place.</p>
          <p>Now, we have the flexibility to alter that CapEx as we see fit. So I would refrain from providing you the exact number on the maintenance capital at this particular time, until such time as we get to that point, and we decide exactly what we're going to do over the next -- beyond the next 12 to 18 months on a particular field.</p>
          <p>I will tell you though however that the majority of the CapEx has been already spent on the field, since we're already at the capacity. In my annual conference call, you can revert back to that and you can see that I provided detail number of how many wells we expect to drill. And I gave you sort of the average cost per well, and if you calculate that you would see that going forward the amount of capital we need to spend at the Yurkharovskoye field to maintain current levels of productions were quite low.</p>
          <p>I can tell you if we look at fields that are already in sort of maintenance mode such as the East-Tarkosalinskoye and Khancheyskoye field that if we look at the capital spent on these two fields over the last two or three quarters, you would see that in the first quarter we spent approximately 204 million at East-Tarkosalinskoye, approximately 5 million at Khancheyskoye, 186 million at East-Tarkosalinskoye in the second quarter, 23 million at Khancheyskoye and 221 million in the third quarter and 21 million at Khancheyskoye. And if you look at the contribution of revenues you would see that the field essentially contributed about, roughly I want to say it was about, I would say about 350 -- $300 million to $350 million of revenues for capital spent of about $8 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, that's the maintenance capital level at the existing fields. Now, what happens to Yurkharovskoye field going over, let us get into maintenance capital mode first and then I'd be glad to provide that information to you, but we're getting pretty close as I mentioned tonight on the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Thank you. And about dividends, because the reference of question was that if you end up being significantly more cash generative going forward would you consider reviewing dividend and basically increasing dividend pay outs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean we look at dividends, we have a policy in place that we disclose on our website that basically says that we will pay at least 30% of the net profit under the Russian accounting standards. We have paid slightly higher the pay out rate has been slightly higher over the last couple of dividend payments. But it also caveats based on what our capital expenditure program looks like, what our cash flow needs and our ability to service debt. So we have spelled out what our dividend payment and what our dividend policy has been like.</p>
          <p>What we look at as what we're trying to accomplish with these acquisitions, we're trying to look at ways to redeploy capital back into accretive projects. So we have these particular projects that we will inherit through the acquisition. We have other projects that we will eventually undertake, such as stage three, expansion of the Purovsky processing plant, the Yamal LNG project et cetera, we'll also take a portion of this capital that we will generate this from the free cash flow.</p>
          <p>So if we do not have projects that are value accretive, if we do not have projects that return similar rates of return that we've experienced then we will consider the option of whether or not we want to issue dividends or increase our dividend pay out in any respective period. But right now, the dividend policy is being established. We have projects that we know we want to invest in and we plan to use a portion of that funds to utilize the development and then as a result of that enhanced or increased further the cash flow generation from the new fields coming on stream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Understood. And also two more questions if I may, one on your gas price negotiations with Gazprom for Sibneftegaz I understand you probably cannot comment on that too much. But if you can give us any color so that &#x2013; in terms of I mean who did the negotiation of this price every year, would it be based on formula. I mean, would it sort of reflect domestic gas prices in Russia over then anything say how to model it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I really not going to make any comment at this point, but you can see relatively speaking what our gas prices are. We don't &#x2013; we basically sell either at the wellhead or based on FDS prices depend on who we sell through a customer or we sell as a wellhead. So I don't believe that's going to deviate dramatically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. And final question on if you can give us any sort of idea about production growth at Sibneftegaz. And also if you see any challenges marketing of that gas considering that you already have significant spare capacity at Yurkharovskoye field. And I mean would you try so as to &#x2013; so the region spare capacity and then ramp up production at the Sibneftegaz. I mean, would it be, would it make it more challenging for you to sort of region the maximum production at Yurkharovskoye the fact that you can't market this additional gas from Sibneftegaz as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At Sibneftegaz &#x2013; has its own production profile et cetera, right now as I mentioned it is expected that gas from off take to gas from that particular field.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And going forward, we may decide at some point in time to change that, but right now that is basically the plan for that particular field. Yurkharovskoye -- we are essentially we have our own marketing structure. We have our ability and as I mentioned earlier, the skepticism that people have on our ability to market our gas all we do is keep showing you that we have new contracts, new ability, we grow our production and we market our gas. We expect to do the same going forward in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Maxim Moshkov from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good evening. Hello, Mark, thank you for the presentation and your detailed comments. I have question also on the acquisitions front. Let me start with Sibneftegaz. Despite they have talked to you currently from the equity basis of Sibneftegaz, but the development you will here for production presumably is unstable gas condensate pipeline and postpone to gas condensate. What incremental revenue you're expecting to realize to book from servicing Yamal Development? And on Sibneftegaz gas, I understand that it will be also on a equity basis, but how you will be returning cash from this particular <mark type="inaudible" /> and what's the dividend policy should be applied for Sibneftegaz recently? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maxim, on your first question, I mean theoretically, you're absolutely correct and your comments about the synergistic benefits of using our pipeline structure and our processing facilities and at this point in time right now, we have supplied our partners with our sort of projected rates for the particular usage of facilities and as -- at such time as we agree them. I'm kind of reluctant to be able to provide any revenue numbers at this point, because we're still in negotiations of these relative tariffs. But they will provide additional revenue streams to NOVATEK for the use of the pipeline and the processing facility.</p>
          <p>On your second question, in terms of -- the second question was on the Sibneftegaz -- well, can you repeat your second question please Maxim, was it on Sibneftegaz?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, how you'll be returning cash flow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The cash on the dividends, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dividends, what will be yield reports of Sibneftegaz actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean -- I think first of all I think, we look at it just like as any other -- we have -- we'll determine a price for gas. We expect since we're taking gas and market ourselves there, NOVATEK will be the profit center. So absent in providing specific details on what the shareholder agreements et cetera, you should just assume that the profit center for any marketing will be from our --at least our proportion of share of gas will be at NOVATEK level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess my question that you are deferring the payment for the asset till the next year. I'm sure you will be expecting that some of this deferral payment for the Sibneftegaz would be financed from the changing rated by Sibneftegaz?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>After I said in my prepared text, we basically said that we expect the cash flow generated from this particular field will be partially used to finance the acquisition along with other cash flow generated from other field as well as debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Nadia Kazakova from JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello I have a couple of questions please, first one referring but quickly to <mark type="inaudible" /> and can you verify the timing please for the first drilling stage of the refinery because you've given us two different dates fourth quarter of '11 or fourth quarter of '12? And what are the CapEx number please for <mark type="inaudible" /> for 2011 and 2012?</p>
          <p>And second question is on Sibneftegaz basically from the P&amp;L perspective I would see NOVATEK projects and Gazprom Sibneftegaz at what cost and then I has Gazprom come to the contribution from significant space and do you like, is it roughly how I would see that other company expecting accounts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about the first one, the first one we expect to launch in the fourth quarter 2012. That's the plan target for the first 3 million tons launch of <mark type="inaudible" /> facility.</p>
          <p>In terms of capital spent; we're not providing guidance today in terms of what we spent or what we plan to spend on a particular project at this point. As soon as we finalize our capital expenditure program from this year, I'll be able to provide that to you in terms of a breakdown essentially between each of the projects we do and specifically related to this particular project I'll be able to provide you with the update. But right now we're not essentially providing that detail at this particular conference call.</p>
          <p>In terms of Sibneftegaz, again as I mentioned, we expect that NOVATEK will be the profit center for gas deliveries, so there'll be obviously a cost -- recovery, cost recovery, expenses et cetera back to Sibneftegaz, but the actual profit on the marketing the gas will be retained through our marketing arm here at NOVATEK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, we'll take our last question from Vadim Mitroshin from OTKRITIE. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Mark my final question if I may, on Purovsky plant utilization, you mentioned 67% utilization rate, I wonder following the &#x2013; all the upgrades that you have done at the Yurkharov field whether we should expect any uptick in utilization in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all what I said is it was 65% in the third quarter. It was 67% in the second quarter. And as I mentioned part of the change was essentially that some of the condensate produced at the Yurkharovskoye field was used for line field and inventory at the deethinization plant.</p>
          <p>So there is actually volumes that would have generally gone through the plant that did not go through the plant during this particular quarter.</p>
          <p>Yes if we increase if we, it's expected that we should increase, continue to increase in the output of natural gas from the Yurkharov field with the launch of the additional facility in October which obviously is a gas &#x2013; is a wet gas field to enhance our liquid production should increase as part of the step up from approximately 98 million cubic meters per day to 124 million cubic meters per day, most of that is coming from the Yurkharovskoye field. I would say your view of your assessment &#x2013; is that we should expect more volume produced in the fourth quarter and hopefully better utilization of the plant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>As there are no further questions. I would like to hand to call back over to Mr. Gyetvay for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And thank you very much for attending tonight's call. I really don't have much more to say other than, we're very excited about these acquisitions and we hope to complete both of them by the end of this year and once they're completed we'll be able to provide you with some additional update. So please bear with us tonight with what we can provide you, but as soon as we're able to discuss in a little more detail, we'll be glad to do that with everybody. So thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you that will conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation ladies and gentlemen you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>