<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1404660" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-08-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>693</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President-Investor Relations">Reed Nolte</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Keith Rupert Murdoch</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Director &amp; Senior Executive Vice President">David F. DeVoe</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Deputy Chairman, President &amp; COO">Charles G. Carey</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Douglas Mitchelson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Jessica Reif Cohen</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="BTIG LLC">Richard Greenfield</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Evercore Partners (Securities)">Alan S. Gould</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">David Bank</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Jason Boisvert Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Australia) Ltd.">Jolanta Masojada</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Michael Nathanson</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Anthony Joseph DiClemente</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Benjamin Swinburne</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Reuters">Yinka Adegoke</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Financial Times">David Gelles</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="The Hollywood Reporter">Georg Szalai</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Advertising Age">Edmund Lee</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Broadcasting &amp; Cable">Jon Lafayette</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="National Public Radio">David Folkenflik</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by, and welcome to News Corporation's fourth quarter 2011 earnings release. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>Okay, at this time, I'd like to turn the conference over to Reed Nolte, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations of News Corporation. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, operator. Hello, everyone, and welcome to our fourth quarter fiscal 2011 earnings conference call. On the call today are Rupert Murdoch, Chief Executive; Chase Carey, President and Chief Operating Officer; and Dave DeVoe, our Chief Financial Officer. First, we will give some prepared remarks on the most recent quarter and full year. Then we'll be happy to take your questions, first from the financial community, and then from the press. We urge you to please keep to one question so we can accommodate as many folks as possible.</p>
          <p>This call may include certain forward-looking information with respect to News Corporation's business and strategy. Actual results could differ materially from what is said. News Corporation's Form 10-K for the 12 months ended June 30, 2011, identifies risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ, and these statements are qualified by the cautionary statements contained in such filings.</p>
          <p>Additionally, this call will include certain non-GAAP financial measurements. The definition of and a reconciliation of such measures can be found in our earnings release and our 10-K filing.</p>
          <p>Finally, please note that certain financial measures used in this call such as adjusted segment operating income are expressed on a non-GAAP basis. The GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation of adjusted segment operating income is included in our earnings release.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn it over to Rupert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Reed, and good afternoon, everyone.</p>
          <p>As Dave will say very shortly, our company's operating and financial performance this quarter was exceptional, and our full-year results are very solid overall. We are continuing to generate strong cash flow. We have the most robust balance sheet in our history. And just as important, we have effective strategies to further expand our content into even more markets and onto more platforms. I'm very proud of our management team and our people around the world and all our businesses. Their contributions are the reason for our strong performance.</p>
          <p>Of course, while it has been a good quarter from a financial point of view, our company has faced challenges in recent weeks stemming from issues relating to the News of the World. Let me be very clear about where I stand. I've run this company for more than 50 years. The kind of behavior that occurred in that newsroom has no place at News Corporation. It does not protect the actions of our more than 50,000 professional employees. The Board and I believe I should continue in my current role as Chairman and CEO, but make no mistake. Chase Carey and I run this company as a team. And the strength of that partnership is reflected in our improved results.</p>
          <p>I'm personally determined to put things right when it comes to the News of the World. Likewise, our Board of Directors and senior management are acting decisively to get to the bottom of what happened. As has been widely reported, Joel Klein is leading our efforts on this issue reporting directly to Viet Dinh on behalf of the independent directors. The Board, and the company have retained independent outside counsel. In addition, our nominating Corporate Governance Committee has engaged <mark type="indiscernible" /> (3:59) to advise on our corporate governance practices.</p>
          <p>We are all committed to doing the right thing. We have taken decisive actions to hold people accountable, and we will continue to do whatever is necessary to prevent something like this from ever occurring again. There can be no doubt about our commitment to ethics and integrity.</p>
          <p>As we work through this matter, it's important to note there has been no material impact on our operations outside of closure of the News of the World. Our broad and diverse global business is extremely robust today, performing well across the markets where we compete.</p>
          <p>As Dave and Chase will discuss, we continue to produce content that is loved increasingly by viewers, readers, audiences, and fans throughout the world. In short, the drivers of our business are intact and our position is strong and our future is promising.</p>
          <p>Another outcome of recent events was our decision not to pursue our offer for the remaining BSkyB shares we do not already own. I'm disappointed about that because it's clear this was no longer feasible under the circumstances. BSkyB remains an important element for us, and we are very excited about its opportunities to continue growth.</p>
          <p>The recent turn of events is an opportunity to carefully reassess our capital allocation priorities. Our first step is the $5 billion share repurchase program we announced last month. I want to give you all my personal assurance that we will be executing that program aggressively.</p>
          <p>We will also be examining our near and long-term priorities. Be assured that in addition to presenting compelling opportunities for further investment in our businesses, we are always rigorously assessing a broad range of avenues to deploy capital to drive value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our fundamental goals at News Corp. are to produce sustained meaningful value for shareholders, to provide outstanding content and services to customers and consumers, and we do it all with integrity. All these goals are interrelated and all are critically important, and we will deliver on them.</p>
          <p>Thank you all, now let me turn the call over to Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Rupert, thank you, and good afternoon, everybody.</p>
          <p>As Rupert just mentioned and as you have seen in today's earnings release, News Corporation closed out fiscal 2011 with very solid financial results. Let's take a look at the highlights of some of our full-year results.</p>
          <p>Adjusted total segment operating income was $4.98 billion, as compared to $4.46 billion recorded a year ago. This 12% growth is right in line with the expectations we provided you a year ago and reconfirmed on our last earnings call three months ago. This growth was driven by more than 20% operating profit growth at our cable networks and a tripling of contributions from our television segments. This growth was partially offset by lower results in film, owing to the success of Avatar and Ice Age in fiscal 2010, and increased losses from MySpace.</p>
          <p>Net income this year was $2.7 billion, or $1.04 per share, which included a $0.10 per share loss from the sale of MySpace, resulting in earnings per share from continuing operations of $1.14. This result also includes a $125 million pre-tax or $0.03 per share charge net of tax at the company's integrated marketing service business related to a settlement of litigation.</p>
          <p>Results for the quarter, segment operating income of $1.35 billion was up 45% over last year's fourth quarter, reflecting either double-digit or triple-digit percentage increases at every business segment. Income from continuing operations was $0.35 per share.</p>
          <p>Let's just take a look at some of the businesses that drove that growth. Let's start with the cable networks. Double-digit growth in our Cable Networks segment continued, with fourth quarter revenues up 15% and operating income contributions up 12%. Overall affiliate fee increased 11%, driven by strong growth at our international channels. And overall advertising revenues were up 22%, reflecting strength across all of our major channels, led by FX and STAR. Offsetting a portion of these revenue gains were one-time costs of over $50 million, primarily resulting from shutting down two underperforming European channels and program write-downs at FX related to canceled shows.</p>
          <p>Our Cable Networks, which delivered $2.8 billion of operating income for the year, now represents over 55% of the company's total adjusted segment operating income. We expect this business to continue to lead our overall growth for the foreseeable future.</p>
          <p>The Filmed Entertainment segment reported fourth quarter segment operating income of $210 million, up 53% from the $137 million recorded a year ago. Higher film studio contributions were driven by the very successful worldwide theatrical results of Rio that generated over $475 million in worldwide box office receipts, as well as worldwide home entertainment contributions from Narnia: Voyage of the Dawn Treader, and Black Swan. Higher 20th Century Fox Television contributions reflect higher digital distribution revenues and revenues from Glee, including concert tours, music, and digital revenues.</p>
          <p>At our Television segment, operating income in the quarter more than doubled from the fourth quarter a year ago. This growth was driven by 7% revenue increases, including increased retransmission revenues and lower programming expenses at the stations, and also, at the broadcast network.</p>
          <p>The national ad market continues to be buoyant, and we are quite pleased with the low double-digit CPM increases we obtained in this year's upfront for the upcoming broadcast season. The quarter's results reflect reduced spending by foreign auto manufacturers as a result of the Japanese supply chain disruption as a result of the earthquake in Japan and lower political spending. Excluding political, local station ad market spending in the quarter was essentially in line with a year ago.</p>
          <p>At SKY Italia, segment operating income increased 50% to $145 million from last year's reported $97 million. On a local currency basis, operating income grew 32%. This improvement is largely the result of lower programming expenses from the absence of FIFA World Cup costs that were included in the year-ago result. Operationally, this business has demonstrated significant progress over the last 12 months, and we're quite proud of the management there.</p>
          <p>As you may recall, about a year ago SKY Italia's consumer offer was reorganized, more than doubling the number of programming packages and lowering the price point for the soccer package. Additionally, SKY has continued its efforts to increase penetration of additional subscriber services such as HD and DVR, seeing a nearly 30% increase in the number of residential subscribers taking at least one of the above services.</p>
          <p>As anticipated, these changes impacted our short-term financial results, reducing ARPU slightly to &#x20AC;43, and increasing SAC by approximately &#x20AC;30 on average for fiscal 2011. However, these initiatives resulted in a more than 25% increase in gross subscriber additions in the last year and reduced churn to 10% for the year, a significant improvement from last year's 13% level. The net result was an increase of 57,000 subscribers in the fourth quarter and 230,000 net new subscribers for the year. SKY Italia now has just under 5 million subscribers at 4.97 million. We have clearly reenergized our business in what I would characterize as a continued difficult economic climate, and we look forward to continued improvement in financial performance for fiscal 2012.</p>
          <p>In our Publishing segment, fourth quarter segment operating income increased by 38% to $270 million. This improvement reflects higher advertising and circulation revenues at The Wall Street Journal, reduced costs at our Marketing Service division, the contribution from the 53rd week, as well as the strengthening both the Australian dollar, and the pound sterling against the U.S. dollar.</p>
          <p>In our Other segment, we reported a fourth quarter segment operating loss of $137 million, a $37 million improvement from a year ago, reflecting reduced losses at the Digital Media Group, particularly at MySpace. And as you all know, we sold MySpace at the end of June, so we will not be reporting those losses going forward. For the year, MySpace operating losses totaled nearly $230 million.</p>
          <p>Before I turn to our guidance for fiscal 2012, I'd also like to make a few comments related to our cash flow and our balance sheet strength. For fiscal 2011, the company generated a record from operations less CapEx of $3.3 billion, which exceeds last year's previous record of just under $3 billion. At year-end, we had $15.5 billion in gross debt and $12.7 billion in cash, which brings our net debt to $2.8 billion.</p>
          <p>This capital structure largely reflects the fact that we accumulated cash for the potential acquisition of BSkyB. With that deal now off the table, in mid-July our Board approved a stock repurchase program totaling $5 billion, which Rupert just mentioned. We intend to execute this plan aggressively once our blackout period ends next week, and are targeting to complete this program over the next 12 months. Also consistent with these objectives, today we announced that our annual dividend rate will increase 13% to $0.17 per share from the current $0.15. And Chase will comment further on our capital allocation plans in a moment.</p>
          <p>Now let me address our guidance for fiscal 2012. As we measure our guidance, we're starting with fiscal 2011 total segment operating income of $4.85 billion, which we just reported, and exclude from this the $125 million litigation charge, resulting in the base for 2011 of $4.975 billion for comparative purposes.</p>
          <p>And as we look at fiscal 2012, we expect many of our businesses will generate strong year-over-year earnings growth. These include continued robust growth at our Cable Networks led by the further expansion of our international channels, as well as sustained advertising and affiliate increases led by FOX News, the RSNs [Regional Sports Networks], FX, and STAR; higher Television segment earnings, which will benefit from continued growth in retransmission consent revenue; growth in SKY Italia from among many factors, but from principally the 230,000 additional subscribers that we added over the last year at SKY Italia.</p>
          <p>Additionally, while we will benefit from the absence of nearly $230 million in operating losses from MySpace in fiscal 2012, this will be substantially offset by reduced contributions from our Publishing segment, largely due to the elimination of the operating contributions from the News of the World, and lower results in Australia due to the current soft trading conditions there. We are also assuming current economic conditions continue. We are not forecasting a significant upturn or downturn.</p>
          <p>Taking these items into account and based on all of the assumptions inherent in our projections, we anticipate our total segment operating income growth rate for fiscal 2012 to be in the low to mid-teens range above the $4.975 billion fiscal 2011 segment operating income base level.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'd like to now turn the call over to Chase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Dave has given you our guidance for fiscal 2012. So, in the next few minutes I'd like to focus on two things: first, our operating priorities for the next couple of years; and second, our plans and strategy regarding managing our balance sheet and capital allocation.</p>
          <p>Regarding operating priorities I want to identify five key objectives. First, to drive our channel's business to its full potential; we're not even close. Both FOX and FOX News will take subscription fees to a whole new level in the next year and a half. FX is setting ratings records quarter after quarter and we have new leadership to build the untapped potential of National Geographic. The growth story in newer channels like FOX Soccer and Nat Geo Wild is even more dynamic.</p>
          <p>And that being said, our most exciting channel's growth story is outside the U.S., where we see the potential to use our leadership position to more than double the profit from emerging markets in Latin America, India, and Southeast Asia over the coming years.</p>
          <p>Second, we want to continue to build on our content leadership. The explosion of digital distribution is going to make content, particularly hit content, more valuable than ever. We want to own the broadest rights possible to make sure we can exploit that content across the widest set of geographies and emerging platforms.</p>
          <p>Our content businesses have great momentum today. On the film side, the theatrical release of Rise of the Planet of the Apes, and the DVD release of Rio earlier this month are both performing well beyond our expectations. On the TV side, 20th Century Fox TV had four of the top 11 scripted series in adults 18 to 49 in the May sweeps.</p>
          <p>Our third priority is to build our platforms into ever-stronger market leaders. We continue to view growth as our short-term priority. That growth will be driven by great content, technology, and service, and we're confident we have the expertise to execute.</p>
          <p>Fourth, we need to intelligently take advantage of expanding digital platforms that continue to reshape our business. We believe authentication is a core strategy in this regard both to maximize and protect the value of our content. Recently, this has led us to put an eight-day delay on free unauthenticated access to our network content, and it has been a cornerstone for new digital extensions to our franchises, like Big 10 to Go. Between now, and the end of 2011, you will see us launch many more exciting digital extensions to our brands and franchises both here and abroad.</p>
          <p>We also make sure we are vigilant about attacking practices that undervalue our products, like $1 rentals, and building new platforms that fairly value our content. We'll do business with new emerging digital platforms like Netflix, where we established clear rules about what is library product. We're also engaged with other competing digital companies. However, our priority is to make sure we're thoughtful and do not allow a quick buck to jeopardize the longer-term value of our product.</p>
          <p>Fifth and finally, we need to work to restructure the revenues and costs of our Publishing businesses. We've launched digital versions of many franchises, and we'll take steps to enhance our traditional revenue streams. We equally need to address our cost structures and strategy in light of our changing world. Our expected results for this year are clearly problematic, and we'll address them.</p>
          <p>With regard to capital structure and allocation, we fully recognize that our $5 billion buyback only begins to address these issues. On capital structure, we believe we should work toward a balance sheet with 2 to 2.5 times leverage and about $2 billion to $3 billion of available cash for flexibility. We obviously will not get there in 12 months, but we're targeting to do so in two to three years.</p>
          <p>Regarding capital allocation, we expect there will be opportunities for us to make value enhancing investments or key acquisitions in our targeted areas of growth. We are a growth company and believe there are some exciting opportunities for us to add real value to our core businesses. That being said, we will be disciplined both about the arenas where we invest, and the returns expected from these investments. Our priority targets are developing markets, synergistic channels, and unique content. These investments should generate mid-teen returns on capital at a minimum.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, we strongly prefer to build rather than buy businesses. So, we will focus on modest investments, those in the tens or hundreds of millions, not billions.</p>
          <p>With this disciplined approach to investments plus the growing cash flow from our annual operations, we recognize that we will have substantial remaining cash flow on our balance sheet. We plan to use this cash to continue to pursue additional buybacks beyond the $5 billion one recently announced if our stock continues to be undervalued, and today it is woefully undervalued.</p>
          <p>I want to be clear that these are strategies and plans by which we will manage our business. However, these guidelines do not preclude our decision to consider unexpected opportunities or to modify our views based on changes in the broader market or competitive dynamic.</p>
          <p>We are excited about our future. We have a great management team and businesses with great growth potential. We're determined to run our businesses with the discipline and focus that enables us to drive real value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And now Dave, Rupert, and I will be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, will you open it up for questions, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question will come from the line of Doug Mitchelson, Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much, a question for Chase. You mentioned a desire to reprice FOX News, and the Fox Network license fees, and I noted that 4Q domestic affiliate fee growth was 7%. So, the question is as those repricings kick in, should we expect affiliate fee revenue growth in the U.S. to reaccelerate back to double-digits? And I guess as part of that, do you see any hurdles for growth with less pay-TV sub growth in the U.S. than we've enjoyed historically? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. What was the last piece of that question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With pay-TV sub growth in the U.S. being more muted this year and perhaps in the short term than we've enjoyed historically with the lack of sub growth in the U.S., are you worried about your ability to grow affiliate fee revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First on affiliate fee growth, as we look out over the next year, essentially we're looking at in the U.S. pretty much affiliate fee growth in line with what we experienced this year, so we do think there's continued momentum for that. I think we've said before we obviously have a number of negotiations ahead of us as we go through the year. But we do expect to continue to maintain the type of growth in the coming year that we had last year and probably higher growth. We had higher growth internationally probably because it's such &#x2013; the growth is so much higher internationally, probably down a touch, but significantly higher growth internationally and continued significantly higher growth internationally.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of the business, we feel very good about the business. Obviously, at some level it has matured in terms of homes. And you've got economic issues in terms of household formation and some of the economic issues that are putting pressure on it. But I think the value of this bundle, and the demand for this bundle out there in the United States I think continues really to be very strong, in many ways, probably as it has ever been. I think when you have a maturing market that affects to a certain degree how many houses, how many homes will be added to the pot, but it's a business we feel great about.</p>
          <p>Internationally, clearly a different story; I assume you're talking domestic. Internationally, you do have tremendous growth left ahead of you. In many countries that are still <mark type="indiscernible" /> (24:53) , including developed markets, not just developing markets. Certainly in the international marketplace, you've got enormous growth ahead in terms of just households coming into the pay-TV market, but I think you've got a really solid business here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to follow up, I think you implied this and Dave as well in your commentary, but the flat margins in Cable Networks in the fiscal fourth quarter is an anomaly, and we'll be back to normal margin expansion in fiscal 2012 and forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We had some one-time events in the fourth quarter. To be clear, we feel very good about these businesses. I really do feel we've got a bunch of businesses there that have not reached their potential. And if you take channel like at FX it has set rating records this year and it's just getting stronger. FOX News continues to be a juggernaut. We got a lot of &#x2013; probably I think in the next year plus, half the universe of FOX News coming up again, and we're still going through retransmission.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to interrupt you for a second, and our ratings are still improving just about wherever you look.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the main event, the strength of that business, we feel very good about. I think we can do a lot of things. So, it was the one-time events in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our margins are about 35%, or mid-30s% rather, and we would expect to see them continue to grow a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that will come from the line of Jessica Reif Cohen, Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Your advertising in the quarter was unusually strong, like almost double everybody else's. I'm just wondering. Was there anything unusual? And can you give us color on your assumptions or how you're thinking about the year ahead given the disruption we've had in the last few weeks in the economy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think our advertising certainly reflects the strength, in many ways the strength of our channels. If you look at the cable ratings, as I talked about FX, you look at the ratings with FX, the strength of FOX News. American Idol obviously for us got stronger as the year went along. We had a good, healthy ad market; a good, healthy national market and good healthy channels to sell into it.</p>
          <p>As we look out into 2012, certainly right now the national business is great, whether it continues to be with great scatter pricing in the Broadcast business, great scatter pricing in the cable business. I think for the year when we look at ad dollars for the broadcast network, I think we're assuming they're probably about flat. And on the cable business I think it's up, domestically up mid-double-digits and higher than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Higher than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Higher than that, a fairly significant notch above that internationally. Probably the area that is right now, certainly the local business is not as robust as the national business. It looks like it will get a bit better for us in September as we get some things kicking in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're looking at, Chase, low single-digits when you exclude politicals, and the Super Bowl from a year ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you do year-on year-comps, I think it's a couple points up. Obviously, politicals are going create year-on-year negative comps, and we did have the Super Bowl in there. So, I think if you put those things in, it probably puts it down a bit on the actual numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just ask Dave a follow-up? The 2 to 2.5 times leverage, which is great, did you guys actually have a target? Is that gross or net leverage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's gross. That's pretty much what we've always been saying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so it's not a change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that will come from the line of Richard Greenfield, BTIG. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. I just had a quick question for Rupert that I'd love his answer to. When you go back a few years ago, I think it was basically August 2008, you were asked a question about buying back your stock. The stock was substantially below current where it is today, and you really responded in a tone where you weren't really all that interested in buying back the stock. And I'm curious now as you look at where you are now, three years later, you delevered dramatically over that time period. Now, it seems like you have a lot of conviction in buying back the stock. And I would just love to hear from you why you're so interested in buying the stock now, and why it's going to be a fundamental part of your strategy going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a question of relative values. The reason in 2008 that I was coy about it was &#x2013; and I couldn't say it &#x2013; was of course, that we were saving up to bid for BSkyB. That has all changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rupert. Operator, could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that will come from the line of Alan Gould, Evercore Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following up on the buyback, Dave, how much of the $13 billion of cash that you have today is held offshore? And at 2.75 times or 2.5 to three times next year's EBITDA, you get to something like $13 billion of excess cash from here. Do we assume that BSkyB is permanently off the table and that you're not going to start saving up for the possibility of getting that again in the next two to three years when this hopefully blows by?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In answer to the first part of your question, about a third of our cash is held offshore. It's principally in euros and in sterling and in all appropriate banks that are highly rated.</p>
          <p>With respect to BSkyB, I would say BSkyB is just sort of -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not stockpiling. We're focused on running our businesses going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that means, as you said, the $5 billion could increase, depending on where the stock is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alan; next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>It comes from the line David Bank, RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I just had one big-picture question and one small-picture question on the TV business. Could you talk about the pacing right now of the local O&amp;O business from what you could see on the small-picture side?</p>
          <p>And on the big-picture side, you've essentially created a new authentication window online by I think it's in an eight-day delay. Do you have authentication deals in place with the majority of your distributors today? And how long do you think it will &#x2013; if not, how long do you think it will take to get all of those in place? And how does it impact viewership between now, and the time that you have them all in place? You're essentially foregoing some viewership, right, if you don't have them all in place?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess on the first question, pacing local, I think as we look at this quarter, and I think we're probably pacing down I think at mid to high single-digits down in the quarter. Again, it will get better as you get to September as we've got some of the things that are &#x2013; some of the events coming in there. The NFL is selling well. The auto business seems to be coming back in September. I think we feel great about the network lineup that we've got to sell into that. And clearly, part of that pacing is political. If you take out the &#x2013; I think if you exclude political, it's probably certainly low single-digit down. So, excluding political, you probably have a reasonably flat market. With the political in it, it gets to be a more mid to high single-digit type of pacing.</p>
          <p>In terms of the eight-day window, it really ties into retransmission. And I guess our overall view in many ways is that our broadcast network is a channel just like in many ways like our cable channels, a dual revenue stream business with advertising and subscription fees. And if we're going to go out and get paid subscription fees for that product, we think it's appropriate that we manage one of the terms in which consumers access it elsewhere. And if you look at most of the cable original programming, it's available in various delays because that's part and parcel of the demands you're putting into the channel itself. And I think what we look to is authentication being the tool through which consumers can get that midnight-next day experience. But it's in addition to the experience, it's not replacing. And we think that's an important principle.</p>
          <p>I'm not going to get too deep into all our negotiations in terms of our agreements with various parties. They have different terms and conditions to them. Obviously, this becomes part of &#x2013; certainly it's tied into running the Broadcast business. Like the cable channels, it's tied into retransmission, which is really the tool through which we're making it a dual revenue business. I think I've said in the past, we're largely in the next 18 months through the vast majority of our &#x2013; I think we're through both affiliates and broadcast and VPDs will be through the vast majority of our retransmission agreements. It doesn't mean, again, we won't &#x2013; the windows are naturally tied to agreements. I think we recognize we're foregoing some.</p>
          <p>And if authentication, our hope would be, if authentication gets some better traction, it has been disappointing in some ways that authentication hasn't gotten further in terms of concept, in terms of execution the last couple years. There's been a lot of talk, not as much action. And I think in some ways, it's getting overly beaten up by some of the distributors out there. We'd like to see an open, robust authenticating environment where a lot of people can compete with it, and there's a lot of choice for customers. It's not another version of a wall garden experience. And hopefully, that's what we can get to, where it's a rich, easy to use, exciting experience where customers get that experience.</p>
          <p>Almost everybody &#x2013; authentication really isn't going to encumber anybody. Most homes take cable subscriptions today. So, really if you make it easy to use and you create it in an exciting open environment where consumers got a lot of choice in that authenticated world, we think it's a great experience that really can make the whole process of the initial subscription, and the ongoing viewing additive. And I think that's, we believe, an important investment in our long-term health. And to the degree there is viewership we sacrifice in the short term, as I said, up front, I think we're going to be focused on how do you build the right business models and long-term asset value and not how do you squeeze a buck out of this for a quarter or two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that comes from the line of Jason Bazinet with Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much. I just had just a question on one of your cable channels, FOX Business. It seemed like there was quite a bit of excitement about the asset a number of years ago. I think you got carriage in New York, which was a key gating factor. You seem to have hired quite a bit of talent from CNBC. But it doesn't seem to show up on the ratings, and you don't even mention that it's one of the under-monetized assets, at least in your prepared remarks. So, can you just give us an update on where you are in FOX Business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the ratings are in fact, improving. At certain times of the day, we're head to head with CNBC and we're beating them. We do need more distribution; that's true. As regards to performance, it is now at cash breakeven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in fact, it has had great growth. It's a much better channel today than it was 12 months ago. They've done a good job. FOX News didn't grow overnight. FOX Business doesn't grow overnight. I think trends made real headway. And really actually I could have put it on the list, but I was getting selective. It was more an example why it's not all-inclusive. To say the ones I didn't mention by excluding them wasn't saying that we're not excited by them and we really are. FOX Business has made great strides, as Rupert said. We've got a couple of holes in distribution that we've got to fill, one, which we've got a handle on. And we think this channel really is an exciting growth area for us as well, and I think really adds some exciting dimension to an arm of the FOX News business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that comes from the line of Jolanta Masojada, Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Chase, I wondered if you could talk through the cost opportunities you see in the publishing business in the U.K. and Australia given the tough outlook, and if you could maybe be specific on whether there's the opportunity to rationalize printing operations in Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are continuing. Certainly it's an ongoing process and it's really multi-dimensional, and it's not just cost. It is revenue, digital extensions of the product. We're certainly investing in that. We're looking at ways we can deal with the printing side of it. We have real scale there. And I think it's important for us to figure out how do we take advantage of that scale to create real efficiencies. And really, like I said, over time, we're continuing. But the growth side of this is going to be increasingly traditional, and that's a long-term transitional process, but in an area we need to focus on.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., we've actually gone through much more with the closure of the News of the World, a much more jarring change than we needed to. We got new management that has been in place for all of &#x2013; we've got a new CEO in place for a couple of weeks. And so he's at, you take something that looks very different than it did a month ago. And I think in fairness to him, we give him time to get his head around how you deal with a business that has actually created a significant negative year-over-year variance for us this year. We need to prioritize how we address a business that looks very different without News of the World there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to add that there is room certainly for economies in various parts of our situation in Britain, but not in printing. We have the biggest, and the most efficient printing plants in Britain. We print for our opposition, and we would print for more of our opposition if they want to come to us. They are extremely economical. In fact, when you're going to these enormous plants it's alarming because you don't see anybody. But it's probably the most efficient &#x2013; the London plant, and the Liverpool plant are the most efficient plants in Europe.</p>
          <p>In Australia, we have relatively modern, five-year-old plants in each of the big cities. You cannot &#x2013; and they haven't got spare capacity. You cannot print in one city papers for cities 600 miles apart. There is not big room for savings there, and that's part of the business. In fact, there have been savings being made throughout the year or the last 18 months in Australia, and I think that head count is down considerably in all corners of the business. Another way to say it, frankly, is, that advertising business is hitting magazines more than us, but business is just bad. People in Australia are saying that it's going to be 12%, and the retailers are doing very badly. We just have to come through this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Could we go to the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and that comes from the line of Michael Nathanson, Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. I have one for Chase, and then I'll have one for Rupert. Chase, you talked in your prepared remarks about mid-teens, or trying to get mid-teen returns on capital allocations going forward. And I wonder when you look back on the previous decision, do you think the company has done mid-teens return on capital? And then if so or if not, what's going to be different going forward, in terms of a new process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not going to go back and critique things that are in years past. Generally, you make honest judgments rarely. It doesn't mean they're not honest judgments. Rarely does something look the same as you thought it would five years after the fact. So, all I can really do is speak to it prospectively, and that's how I'm going to view it.</p>
          <p>And prospectively, I think it is important. We have discipline. We have goals that we invest in places that we really think fit our core areas of focus and growth and that can really bring something, bring a dimension to our business that we can really capitalize on. And again, that being said, when you talk about acquisitions, and I guess I want to continue to be clear, the way you build or you create real value is to build it. And I've said, and I think within that, what you really probably are looking for mostly is places where, if you're acquiring something it's sort of a foundation to build off of. I think if you're buying mature businesses, it's really pretty tough.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I'll just interrupt for a second. In the businesses, we have really huge returns in, 100%, 200% return on investment. And we have businesses, which are soft. But overall, I think we're averaging well over 15% on what we've done, and we hope to do that in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, Rupert, following up on a question I have for you is, on these past calls when the question about newspaper assets has come up and maybe spinning them off, the answer is no, no, it's part of the company. I wonder in light of what has happened, and the damage caused financially and to the brand, if your tolerance for papers or your support of the assets has changed at all, or maybe even a mix of certain types of newspapers. Can you talk a bit about how you're feeling about those assets within the portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm feeling very confident. I'm shocked and appalled at what happened in one small corner, which is the News of the World, and I'm going to see that never, never happens again. But everything else is fine. The Wall Street Journal, I'm not saying it's making 15%, but it is the only major newspaper with increased advertising revenue in the last year in the United States. So, we are making progress wherever we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Michael. Could we go to the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That comes from the line of Anthony DiClemente with Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thanks for taking the questions, a question for Dave on the quarter first. I wonder if you could help us quantify the write-down and closing of channels that led to higher programming expenses at the Cable Network segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was roughly half of amount I mentioned, which is $50 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To be specific, $25 million related to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any part of that that you would characterize as potentially coming up again next quarter or anything in terms of &#x2013; okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, this was a one-off. There were some programming contracts as well that we've had for a while, which we wrote down as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And then when we try and model moving forward in terms of what's contemplated in your guidance, one of the swing factors that is tough for us to project is film. I'm just wondering if you could help us with what your plan is for film for next year. Is that adjusted OI growth going to be &#x2013; can you say directionally what it would be in relation to what your guidance is for the consolidated results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a very, very dangerous thing to predict the outcome. [Laughter] All I can say is you can see the comparison of the three years, which was the lack of Avatar, which was a total extraordinary event the year before. But this year we've already started very well. Last weekend, we had a huge opening, well ahead of budget, on Planet of the Apes. And we also launched, I think, maybe Monday, the DVD of Rio, and beat our full target in about two days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think inside our expectations, we expect a reasonably flat business. You want to be conservative. This is a business that obviously, as Rupert said, it's tough to predict. And so we believe we've got a great team there that has done a great job. But I think as you try to project out, you beat the service, so we projected a year that's pretty flat with this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are very conservative in our projections there, and I think it's very appropriate. We see other companies and we've had the experience. It's not that difficult to lose $100 million on a film. We haven't had that experience for a long, long time, and we are very careful. And we also, I should say, lay off a lot of the risk in every film we make.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I hear you on that. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anthony &#x2013; I think actually Rich asked this. I just wanted to go back to Rich's question that Rich asked Rupert just to give slightly more perspective on it, because I think we forgot this. But if you go back and you compare where we were in 2008 to where we are today, today the company is much, much stronger financially. The nature of the company has changed. The predictability of our earnings have changed, if you look at where we're going in our Cable business. And in 2008, at one point, we thought that the financial world was coming to an end, so we were extremely conservative. So, I just think we're in a totally different place today from where we were in 2008 with respect to our ability and capacity to buy back stock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can we go to the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>It comes from the line of Ben Swinburne, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have one on the guidance, Dave, if you could just comment possibly on the publishing assumption around severance or one-time costs, either News of the World litigation stuff, or in Australia, anything that you're factoring in that might help us understand if it's one-time and quantify it, if you could?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's nothing in Australia to quantify or to do. And in the U.K., no, we're not <mark type="inaudible" /> (48:37) nor do we know. We're trying very hard to <mark type="inaudible" /> (48:44), as well as we can. But first we have to get to the bottom exactly of what happened. Were there a dozen guilty people or two dozen? We are not only investigating; we are cooperating totally, 100%, with the police in their investigations, and we expect that to go on for some time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to the guidance, we have not provided in the guidance anything out of the ordinary with respect to the cost of that. We obviously have provided for the known litigations that we know about, the expected settlements or fulfillments of those cases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's very helpful. And just on capital allocation, and I think you can tell from the questions everyone is very happy to hear the details there. It looks if I run the math, you guys threw off about $4 billion of free cash flow this year. No reason to think that's going down. So, in three years, you're talking about $12 billion of free cash. You've got $12 billion of cash on the balance sheet. If you take that down to $3 billion, you're basically talking about $20 billion of capacity. It's almost near your market cap. It's over half your market cap. The only other variable I think, Chase, you threw out, was acquisitions and you talked about tens or hundreds of millions. I just want to make sure I'm not missing anything in all that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not saying something won't come along about $1 billion, but we don't see anything, and we certainly don't see any really big things like we saw with BSkyB. We don't have any prospects for anything like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we have time for one more question from the financial community before we go to the press. Also at this time, I'd like to remind members of the press that they should start queuing up for the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> That last question comes from the line of Spencer Wang, Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for squeezing me in. Chase, you mentioned earlier you thought the stock was, I think, woefully undervalued. So, I was wondering if, for you or Rupert, would you guys consider some more structural changes at the company? And I don't mean just getting rid of the newspapers, but maybe just help us understand why you think having a company configured the way it is makes sense in terms of asset mix. And then just a quick housekeeping question for Dave, what's the FX impact in your guidance, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't see &#x2013; I think we've got a very good mix. There are one or two. There's one that I'm not prepared to specify for you I think at the moment unless it's been announced that we would sell, but no, no major restructuring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we tried to do, we've certainly done some streamlining of our businesses. And I think we would continue to try to focus on the core businesses that we think are the heart our growth drivers I mean you saw us, I think just the last month or two sold the Outdoor business, and have taken some other steps. But I think from the core area that we're focused on are the areas we grow and build. I'm not sure you're a great fan of financial engineering things, but we want to be smart. But I think we have tried to clean up some of the things where we got complexities, to focus on businesses that we think make sense. We obviously cleaned up MySpace in Digital area this year. So, I do think we're trying to bring a level of focus and discipline to help deal with the undervaluing of our stock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've learned a tremendous amount in the Digital area. And we have some terrific people now, all which are accounted for here, a cast of them in digitizing not just our entertainment products, but all our information products. If you look at our apps on the London Times, The Sunday Times, News of the World, New York Post, they are as good or better than anybody else's. We intend to keep improving them.</p>
          <p>That will expand, and the money coming from that will expand as more people have tablets. And what is interesting is we're getting tremendous take-up, not just on the iPad, but on the Kindle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great; the other question on FX?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not significant in the guidance. We're using pretty much the exchange rates that exist. There's some <mark type="inaudible" /> (53:30) we don't have the exact number on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:32), but it's not significant. And if it's very important to you, I will get Reed to get back to you on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's perfect, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, now we'd like to go to the press. Also, given the time, we will limit each reporter to one question. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And our first question will come from the line of Yinka Adegoke with Reuters. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of which?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yinka Adegoke from Reuters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mr. Murdoch. You said at the U.K. here the other day that you still hope for one of your children to run the company at some stage. It was good to hear you say you're still running the company with Chase for now. Given what has happened and some of the questions about James' testimony, do you think the Board will support you, will support James being appointed as President at some stage in the near future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope that the job won't be open in the near future. [Laughter] Chase is my partner. If anything happened to me, I'm sure he'll get it immediately if I went under a bus. But Chase and I have full confidence in James. I think that's all we need to say about it. But in the end, succession's a matter for the Board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that will come from the line of David Gelles, Financial Times. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Murdoch. Do you acknowledge critics' claims that many of your Board members are not independent by traditional corporate governance definitions? And if it is so, do you plan any changes to the Board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't acknowledge that. And no, I don't plan changes. It's a very strong Board, very often very critical, and we have a lot of free-ranging discussions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>It comes from the line of Georg Szalai, The Hollywood Reporter. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gentlemen. I was wondering if you can talk a little bit about the status of the Hulu auction. When do you expect it to close, and will it go forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not going to speak too much on it. Hulu is running the process. We're obviously partners. I think probably they're the right ones to speak to it. It is obviously ongoing, and I think progressing largely according to plan. But for us, I think we'll see where it ultimately ends up. But I think for us it's still a decision to see what it looks like at the end, and does it make sense to pursue that path, or does it make sense for us to stay in an ownership position and continue to have it driven by content owners? But I think it's on course and on schedule, but I'll let Hulu speak to it in more detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that comes from the line of Edmund Lee with Advertising Age. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Hi. Thanks for taking the call. Mr. Murdoch, so given that you are concerned about what happened at News of the World, what are you doing to &#x2013; what is the company doing, and what are you doing to look at other areas of News Corp. and potential activities of a similar sort, namely at News America Marketing, and other news operations within News Corp.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're cooperating with all investigations, and indeed, invited in legal firms to help us check through, but we're not going into any more specifics of what they are. I can just tell you that we are totally committed to absolute transparency for the whole company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that comes from the line of Jon Lafayette, B&amp;C. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. What steps are you taking to make sure that any future misdeeds come to your attention much quicker than these ones did in the U.K.? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've obviously had a big alarm call. What happened there was we found out, the police found out, a few people were charged, a few people went to jail. And after further investigations by them, other policemen said there was no further evidence, and they were closing their file. In retrospect, we should have continued investigating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Operator, we have time for one last question from the press, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And that will come from the line of David Folkenflik, National Public Radio. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This question is for Mr. Murdoch. I hope you guys can hear. You mentioned that you, and the Board affirmed it would be right that you would continue on as Chairman and CEO of the corporation. That said, there are a lot of ties, familial, corporate, and financial, between yourself, members of your immediate family, the Board, and those responsible for the internal inquiry. What do you say to those analysts who contend that your company -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not true. The people who are responsible are the independent directors -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Dinh and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Dinh is a completely independent director, a distinguished lawyer. And I can just assure you that we continually evaluate our corporate governance practices and have engaged outside counsel to confirm that we are in compliance with standards of good corporate governance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rupert. I want to thank everybody for joining the call today. If you have any further questions, please give us a call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>