<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1469468" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>693</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President-Investor Relations">Reed Nolte</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Director &amp; Senior Executive Vice President">David F. DeVoe</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Deputy Chairman, President &amp; COO">Charles G. Carey</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Douglas Mitchelson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Jessica Reif Cohen</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="BTIG LLC">Richard Greenfield</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Benjamin Swinburne</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Evercore Partners (Securities)">Alan S. Gould</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">David Bank</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Partners (Australia) Pty Ltd.">Adam Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Jason Boisvert Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Lazard Capital Markets LLC">Barton Crockett</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Standard &amp; Poors Investment Advisory, Inc.">Tuna N. Amobi</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Bloomberg News">Edmund Lee</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="The Wall Street Journal">John Jannarone</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Financial Times">Andrew Edgecliffe-Johnson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the News Corp. third quarter 2012 earnings release. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And as a reminder, today's call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>With that being said, I'll turn the conference over to the Senior Vice President Investor Relations, Mr. Reed Nolte. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, operator. Hello, everyone, and welcome to our third quarter fiscal 2012 earnings conference call. Joining me on today's call are Chase Carey, President and Chief Operating Officer; and Dave DeVoe, our CFO. First, we will give some prepared remarks on the most recent quarter. Then we'll be happy to take your questions, first from the financial community and then from the press.</p>
          <p>This call may include certain forward-looking information with respect to News Corporation's business and strategy. Actual results could differ materially from what is said. News Corporation's Form 10-Q for the three months ended March 31, 2011 identifies risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ, and these statements are qualified by the cautionary statements contained in such filings.</p>
          <p>Additionally, this call will include certain non-GAAP financial measurements. The definition of and a reconciliation of such measures can be found in our earnings release and our 10-Q filing.</p>
          <p>Finally, please note that certain financial measures used in this call such as segment operating income, adjusted earnings per share, and adjusted net income are expressed on a non-GAAP basis. The GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation of segment operating income, EPS, and net income are included in our earnings release.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Reed, and good afternoon, everybody.</p>
          <p>As you will see in today's earnings release, we are pleased with our continued progress in fiscal 2012. We reported third quarter segment operating income of $1.31 billion, a 23% increase over year-ago levels. This improvement was led by very solid results at our Cable Programming and Film segments. The current quarter's operating income results include a $63 million charge related to the ongoing investigations initiated upon the closure of News of the World in the United Kingdom. Also note the year-ago quarter included a $125 million charge related to a litigation settlement involving the company's Integrated Marketing Services business. Excluding these charges from both years, third quarter adjusted total segment operating income of $1.38 billion increased 16% from $1.19 billion in the prior year.</p>
          <p>Our share of reported results from our equity earnings of affiliates were up $93 million in the quarter. And after adjusting for gains associated with BSkyB's share repurchase program and adjustments in the prior year, primarily related to asset dispositions at NDS, associated results improved $67 million. The majority of this improvement reflects revenue driven earnings growth at BSkyB.</p>
          <p>Reported net income in the quarter was $937 million with reported earnings per share of $0.38 as compared to reported earnings per share a year ago, $0.24. Excluding the net income effects in both years of one-time items, primarily consisting of the items I just highlighted, third quarter adjusted earnings per share this year are $0.37 compared with the year-ago adjusted result of $0.26, a 42% earnings per share improvement. Our press release includes a reconciliation of our GAAP results to these amounts.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to provide some additional context on the performance at a few of our businesses, and let's start with the cable networks. This segment continues to drive overall company results, generating nearly 65% of News Corporation's total segment operating income. Third quarter Cable segment operating income contributions increased 15% over year-ago levels to $846 million, with double-digit earnings growth at the RSNs [Regional Sports Networks], FOX News, FX, National Geographic, and the FOX International channels. This growth continues to be top line driven, with segment revenues up 16%.</p>
          <p>Affiliate fees at the cable networks increased 18% over last year's level, with domestic channel affiliate fees up 15%, driven by successful affiliate renewal negotiations in the first half of the fiscal year. International fees were up 31%, with about half of the international affiliate revenue increase driven by organic growth, and the remaining reflecting the consolidation of FOX Pan American Sports upon the buyout of the partners in December.</p>
          <p>Third quarter advertising revenues for the segment were up 9% over last year levels, with domestic ad growth of 10% and international growth of 7%. Although all our major domestic channels delivered year-over-year increases, ad sales increases were particularly strong at the FOX News Channel and National Geographic. On the international side, double-digit advertising growth at the FOX International channels continues to reflect strength in Latin America and Asia. And at STAR, much of the double-digit local currency advertising growth was offset on a U.S. dollar basis due the comparative weaker Indian rupee.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, we saw some slight margin compression in the Cable segment. This primarily reflects increased sports programming costs due to the delay of the NBA season and the resulting increase in televised games this quarter, the launch of the Ultimate Fighting Championships, as well as consolidation of FOX Pan American Sports.</p>
          <p>At our Television segment, operating income in the quarter of $171 million decreased $21 million versus the third quarter a year ago. This decline reflects the absence of advertising revenues and operating profit associated with last year's Super Bowl on FOX. Excluding last year's Super Bowl, advertising revenues at both the network and the stations were in line with a year ago. We continue to have solid gains in retransmission revenue, which more than doubled in the quarter.</p>
          <p>At our Film segment, third quarter operating income was $272 million, 10% higher than a year ago. This improved result includes higher contributions from the motion picture studio, most notably from the worldwide theatrical and domestic home entertainment performance of the most recent Alvin and the Chipmunks release as well as higher television production contributions that include increased syndication and digital distribution revenues. Year to date, we recognized approximately $250 million in total revenues from our Netflix and Amazon deals.</p>
          <p>Turning to SKY Italia, segment operating income in the quarter of $40 million improved $23 million from last year. This improvement primarily reflects higher advertising and subscription revenues resulting from the higher year-on-year subscriber base. ARPU of &#x20AC;42 was in line with the third quarter a year ago and was &#x20AC;1 higher than the most recent December quarter.</p>
          <p>While we are pleased with SKY Italia's financial performance, the challenging economic environment in Italy is directly impacting gross sub additions and churn. As a result, SKY lost a net 86,000 subscribers in the quarter ending, resulting in 4.94 million subs at the quarter end. We continue to have complete confidence in the long-term growth prospects for this business given the relatively low pay-TV penetration in Italy and SKY's strong competitive position there. But we are realistic in that our growth is closely linked to consumer confidence and consumption, which will be challenging given the economic conditions in Italy over near term.</p>
          <p>In our Publishing segment, operating income of $130 million declined $31 million compared to a year ago when we exclude the prior year's $125 million litigation settlement recorded in this segment. This decrease largely reflects lower advertising revenues at the Australian and UK newspapers and involves the impact from the closure of the News of the World. Declines at these groups were partially offset by higher earnings contributions at Dow Jones and Harper Collins.</p>
          <p>In our Other segment, we reported third quarter segment operating loss of $147 million, $18 million lower than a year ago. This improvement primarily reflects the absence of MySpace losses, partially offset by $63 million of costs related to the ongoing investigations initiated upon the closure of the News of the World.</p>
          <p>Before I turn to guidance, I'd like to update you on our original $5 billion buyback program. Through May 8, the company has spent nearly $3.9 billion repurchasing over 220 million shares, reducing News Corporation's total shares outstanding by 8.4%. As I had indicated previously, we're looking to complete this program by the end of this fiscal year. But given current pacing, we may miss this timing by a few weeks. Our objective is to buy back our shares in a disciplined manner without artificially pushing our share price up during periods of low trading volume.</p>
          <p>Also please note that, as stated in today's release, our board has increased our buyback authority by another $5 billion on top of what was authorized last summer. We are targeting to complete the total authorized buybacks by the end of fiscal 2013, but the timing can fluctuate based on market conditions and other factors.</p>
          <p>And finally, let me address our guidance for fiscal 2012. And as a reminder, we measure this guidance excluding from fiscal 2011 the $125 million litigation charge, resulting in a base of $4.975 billion in segment operating income for comparative purposes. In addition, as we discussed last quarter, we are excluding costs of the UK investigations from our guidance for the full year due to their uncertain nature. These costs, which are predominantly fees to outside lawyers and advisors, totaled approximately $167 million through the first nine months of this year.</p>
          <p>After excluding the full-year effect of the UK investigation costs and based on all the assumptions inherent in our projections, we expect our total segment operating income percentage growth rate for fiscal 2012 to continue to be in the low to mid-teens range above the $4.975 billion fiscal 2000 (sic) [2011] segment operating income base level, with a bias towards the lower end of that range.</p>
          <p>I recognize that this growth forecast may appear rather conservative given the strong results generated in our first nine months of fiscal 2012. However, there are a couple of factors that will impact our fourth quarter comparative results. While our Film results have exceeded last year's results every quarter so far this fiscal year, as we've previously mentioned or forecasted, we do expect a significant decline in the upcoming fourth quarter compared to a year ago. This reflects difficult comparisons to last year's very successful release of Rio and X-Men coupled with this year's expensing of the releasing costs for our two big June releases and the early July release of the next Ice Age installment.</p>
          <p>Additionally, the advertising markets at our international newspapers have continued to be soft. And also, as we indicated last year, the Publishing segment included contributions from the 53rd week which does not recur this year. As a result of these factors, we are expecting both our Publishing and Film segments to each be approximately $125 million below last year's fourth quarter result, which will contribute to the reduction on the growth rate from the nine-month growth rate of 20%.</p>
          <p>And with that, I would like to turn the call over to Chase for his comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dave, and welcome, everyone.</p>
          <p>Before I discuss the financial and operational strength reflected in last quarter's results, I want to take a minute to address our issues in the UK. As we said, we take these issues very seriously. And our board of directors and management team remain committed to keeping the company on the right track for the future.</p>
          <p>Lots of work has already been done toward this end. The Select Committee report delivered hard truths, most of which we openly acknowledge. However, I flatly reject the report's notion that Rupert is unfit to run a major media company. That's unjustified and, in many people's opinion, including my own, a purely partisan finding. Rupert is taking great business risks, especially in the UK, where he has led News Corp's heavy investment building SKY, bringing great content and choice to 10 million homes, and creating 19,000 jobs. We invested in at The Times and The Sunday Times, titles that were nearly out of business before Rupert made the decision to save them. He's one of the smartest, most forward-thinking executives of our time. And both the board and I rebuff any notion that he is unfit to run this company.</p>
          <p>With that said, let's focus on the quarter. As Dave said, our overall performance in the third quarter illustrates we're executing on plans to achieve our objective of not just building but really bolstering our global content and channels business. Our channels business is a growth business still in its evolution, and we're committed to investing in content to strengthen our leadership position. We're not merely going to focus on sweetening the margins. We want to truly lead. And to do so, we're going to invest today for big returns tomorrow.</p>
          <p>Examples of this include our investment in the UFC, the Ultimate Fighting Championships, our spend on original productions, and a renewed mission to acquire more movies for our FX franchise, and overseas in India our recent investment in BCCI for the cricket rights. I believe firmly that these rights will add a whole new dimension to STAR's business.</p>
          <p>Other examples of investing in content include the moves we've made at the National Geographic Channel, where the new management team we installed has boosted ratings and profits, with ratings up 40% year on year, driven by a great slate of new programming.</p>
          <p>In August, we're launching our U.S. Spanish language network, mundoFOX, already on target to reach 75% of all U.S. Hispanic homes. The demand is driven by one thing, great programming and stations' belief we fully understand how to use content to attract the highly valued and highly sought after segment of the U.S. population.</p>
          <p>Digitally, we're devoting capital to further boost our TV libraries with such breakout hits as Homeland, New Girl, and American Horror Story.</p>
          <p>Simply put, we have the right content. But we not only maintain the value of the bundle, we can grow it. In today's diversified world of global media choices, we know that having superior programming is a must and that's a cornerstone of our growth strategy and the key to delivering real returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>We're also making progress in addressing our almost $15 billion in off-balance sheet businesses. In some cases like Latin American sports, we're buying out partners to take control. In others, you'll see us divesting, monetizing assets to help support our strategy of growing our content and channels business. NDS is an example of this, where we've agreed to divest our 49% interest. It's a great company but not one that fits into our overall long-term plans.</p>
          <p>I know you're interested in what we're seeing in the ad market. On national broadcast scatter, we're seeing a solid market current pricing of low to mid-teens above last year's upfronts. And June quarter cancellations were in line with historical averages. On the cable front, current scatter is healthy, with entertainment scatter up mid-teens. On the local side, the markets are a bit softer and we're seeing a mixed pacing, with heavy auto spending offset by declines in other categories.</p>
          <p>In closing, before I move to questions, I want to comment on our additional commitment to another $5 billion buyback on top of our previous $5 billion pledge. This buyback is yet another illustration of our deep commitment to our shareholders to maximize value by achieving our capital deployment objectives. We believe that these kinds of commitments along with the growth and success of our core operations will continue to ensure the long-term strength of the company.</p>
          <p>And now we'll take questions, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we would like to go to the questions from the investment community now, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First we'll go to Doug Mitchelson with Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much. Chase, I was hoping you could provide a little more color on the growth potential for Cable Networks. Funny enough, it was your domestic networks that led the growth this quarter. International was only single digit. So it looks like you have some visibility on the FOX News renewal cycle; if you could give us a sense how long that renewal cycle will last? And once it's done, do you see enough growth drivers in domestic to sustain healthy growth? And then on the international side, should investors expect you to grow in line with the marketplace, 10% to 15% subscriber growth internationally, or faster than the marketplace? And if faster, any sense of drivers would be helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess domestically &#x2013; I guess really throughout the world, I think those channels businesses, I said we feel great about them. They're pretty much on track on almost any front you want to look at. I think certainly in the U.S., they're pretty much right on course. I think we've talked FOX News. I think what we said essentially is by the end of this calendar year we're in, probably about half the FOX universe will be up for renewal. Obviously, that's the immediate focus, but that will leave half to come. So clearly, we're working through those cycles. Other channels, again, will continue to come through.</p>
          <p>I thought before and I still continue to believe we've got real room to grow there. Again, just whether based on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (18:30) strength in the case of something like FOX News, which again is a uniquely strong and important channel, and therefore that's what we're capitalizing there. Or channels that I still don't think are competitively getting what they can or should, which would be FX, which I think has really carved itself as a true leader in the entertainment space. And clearly, it has a lot of room to grow when it looks at the peers it competes with. And it's a channel that just gets stronger as it goes. Or a channel like National Geographic that I touched on. And clearly again, when you look at some of the players in that segment, it has a lot of room to grow competitively. So I think for us, actually something like NatGeo, one of the attractions is if we can grow we're not adding, we can certainly drive the affiliate rates to a more competitive place and take advantage of the growth on the advertising side by getting ratings to where they are at NatGeo. We've made some strides. But clearly, on channels like that, I don't even think we're close to where we can be or should be.</p>
          <p>I think the international, the international business, we believe we have a unique position of leadership and we should lead the market. And it is why you see us continue to make investments into that market, whether it's the BCCI in India or sports in Latin America, or just general rights that we've acquired like we did with Touch a couple months ago. And I think we are very excited about the potential of that market, other than I can certainly &#x2013; that other segment of Europe. Clearly they have headwinds. But certainly it's true if you look at those big developing regions of Latin America and Asia, and we think they're truly exciting opportunities. We think we have unique brands, unique strengths, unique challenges, and unique expertise. And we think we're in a position of leadership we should capitalize on. But I'm not going to get into if those turn into rates, but I think clearly we believe we should be a market leader, the market leader in those international markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So again, if I summarize all that, is it fair to say that investors should expect double-digit EBIT growth to continue as far as the eye can see? Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I'm not going to get into projecting specific growth rates in those markets. We feel great. As we said, they're on track. Clearly the market is, we expect to be leading in each market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's from Jessica Reif Cohen with Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question for Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you speak up a little bit, Jessica? I can't hear you very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, is that better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll try to scream. I have a question for Dave on the balance sheet. I think that you've historically said that your goal for the balance sheet is to have two to two and a half times gross leverage, and I think you're at roughly two times now. When you think about your cash position over the next year between free cash flow and the NDS proceeds, cash should be roughly $15 billion before this buyback, which is very welcome. I'm just wondering if you could address what you'll do with those cash proceeds. And do you expect to have more proceeds from BSkyB? Do you think you'll have to sell that down? Can you address any other acquisitions, whether it's education or something else? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just told you what we're going to do with $5 billion of the $15 billion is to buy back our stock, Jessica.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so there's $10 billion left.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you are right with respect &#x2013; I think the gross leverage at two to two and a half times is basically &#x2013; is probably a reasonable leverage for us. And if you were to strip out all the cash we get, I think everything you said is correct. And I think we just opportunistically are going to have to look at how we access our &#x2013; how we utilize our capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you say anything about potential to have to sell down part of SKY?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no expectation nor plans to sell down SKY at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The other part of the question was about possibly making acquisitions in education.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Today we're investing &#x2013; it's more investing and building it. I think at this point that is the focus. We made an acquisition at the foundation, but we are investing in education, but it's investing in building a business, which really means we have essentially, as with any business you're starting, you're building, and you have losses you're taking as you build the business. There may be small acquisitions that you tack on. But again, the primary investment has been in building the business; the primary investment today is in building the business. But I think I touched on the side, as I said last call, I think this year a $75 million to $100 million investment which is really a loss for booking, that is an investment in building the education business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chase; operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to Richard Greenfield with BTIG. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Thanks for taking the question. First on sports networks, there has been a lot of discussion about what you all may be planning to do in terms of broadening out the scope of your sports networks. Could you give us a sense of how you're thinking about that?</p>
          <p>And then just a housekeeping question for Dave; I think you mentioned if you back out the FSI charge from last year that your publishing OI was down about 20% year over year. But within that is obviously the closure year over year for the first time of News of the World. Could you give us a sense of organically within that overall Publishing division, if you left out News of the World, what does the revenue and OI year-over-year rates look like in terms of increases, decreases? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The OI basically if you strip out News of the World, it would have been flat for the quarter. That's really not representative as to where we think the year is going to be, where that segment will be down. I'm not going to give you a number, but it will be down significantly from where it was a year ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there a reason why the Q3 was reasonably flat relative to the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had some offsets in the quarter. You had reasonably good earnings growth from both Dow Jones and Harper Collins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the national sports, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (24:45) with the press, I guess I'd say the press probably was a bit overblown. The rallies, we are in the national sports business today. Examples, we have Speed. We have FOX Soccer. We have Fuel. There are more <mark type="ph" /> single (25:00) sports that we always do. We're looking, and we have the big sports business on the regional side. So we have national franchises, regional franchises. I think, as we always do, we're looking at ways, what are the most intelligent ways to maximize the value and the opportunities inherent in it. I think there are great people connected with ESPN. I think it's probably, again, more of the media having fun. ESPN is a unique business. We like sports rights, and we can do things that make sense to add dimensions to our sports business. I think we're much more focused on the franchises we have and how do we maximize the value and the potential of those businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Has your view of a single sport network changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it has always changed. Give me a couple of years, it has changed a bit. I think there are pros and cons. I think there's still a place for them. But obviously, a sports channel with multiple sports probably has a bit more potential to &#x2013; just because the nature of it, to touch a few more people and bring in more of the marginal fans. Obviously, you have to be able to program it intelligently and be able to build a business that makes sense for that. We don't really have any plans today. I think what I said is we're evaluating things. And if there's something that makes sense, then we do it. If there isn't, we like the businesses we have, so I think this would only be simply we saw if there was something to add, add a dimension to it, we'd certainly explore it. If not, we like the businesses we have and we can certainly take them forward. I think there's a role for both. I wouldn't say there's a dramatic shift, but I think there's a role for both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's from Ben Swinburne with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, two. Just on the guidance first, so we should start with the $4.975 billion, and then that grows low teens excluding the impact of the $167 million charges to date. Is that the right math?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And is there anything else, Dave, in the fourth quarter beyond what you called out, newspapers and Film, or Publishing and Film that impacts the quarter? At least my math suggestions flat to down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those are the two principal items. Obviously, we're a dynamic business, so we've got...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Idol's going to be down year on year against its ratings. You've got some headwinds in the economy and Italy that Dave touched on. Those two items are at a level that is unique. There are enough businesses as you go across it, and there will be other items.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a bias to the low end of the low teens was what he said, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And, Chase, are you sort of &#x2013; is there an explicit strategy to monetize the unconsolidated assets, either buy more or exit? You've done NDS, Hathway. You've got some others, and I'm just curious. One of the clear areas of value that would be good on the stock is on the unconsolidated assets. I'm curious if that's where you guys are explicitly now executing as a strategy, or if it's still individual case by case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, first I think I actually said on prior earnings calls that I think we should be with these off-balance sheet businesses moving to either own and operate or monetize. Now I've always qualified that by saying we don't want to put timeframes to it or create pressures that don't let us maximize value of the business we're in; that we're quite comfortable with where we're at. So I think it is an objective but I'd call it a very &#x2013; it's an objective, a goal without any specific timeframe or target to it. I think particularly for businesses that we feel fit what we do, we like where we are, and we may well be there for a while. But I think we have been more explicitly, we've been more historically of saying we think the right place to be is to own and operate or monetize. So there would be a lot of issues you that you don't execute on in the short term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go to Alan Gould with Evercore Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I've got a question on digital distribution. Dave gave us that the revenue was $250 million for the nine months. I was wondering if you can give us what it was for this quarter versus what it was for the same quarter last year. And, Chase, I was wondering if you can tell us if you've seen any impact on ratings or any pushback from the distributors due to the digital distribution deals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess on the ratings, I would say I wouldn't &#x2013; I guess you've got to take a step back. It's a different type digital distribution. You can take something like Hulu which would be concurrent and there's no question you get some viewership, whether it's DVRs are catch-up, again, there's more viewership and more screenings of an episode than television. So I think there are places people are finding shows. Again, that could be DVRs. Clearly, people are finding viewers and they're finding viewership in other places.</p>
          <p>I think at the core channels <mark type="ph" /> and the way (30:50) you're talking about, I think it would be more the Netflix issue and the like. If it has an impact on channels, I wouldn't say so. In some places, we're looking to buy. When we buy film packages today, traditionally we're essentially buying the digital rights. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:24) to a film, we're trying to capture those. And I think as a channel, you'd probably want to continue to own the broadest set of rights you can so digital rights to exploit. You're exploiting them in some ways at a FOX Network. But again, the shows we have on the FOX network, you can view it on Hulu. They're capturing the ad dollars, so it becomes I think in many ways as you look out over time, you're going to have shows premiere live on the network.</p>
          <p>But in many ways, people somewhere are going to view it live. Other shows on the network, some are going to view it on a DVR. Some are going to view it in various forms of electronic media, whether through TV Everywhere or through a service like Hulu. For us, what we're also trying to do is capture as much of that viewership and the value of the viewership in the right way. So I don't actually view that a solution to viewership. I think it's the reality of people finding it in different places and us making sure we're capturing the value of that content, controlling the rights and capturing that value of that viewership to cut across those strengths, different when you get into probably things that are library sources in terms of what type of rights do you own, and do you own rights that &#x2013; do you own the rights you want? Some people aren't finding alternatives through digital media. But again, that's why on something like FX, we're buying broad-based movie rights and not <mark type="ph" /> create it (32:30). This quarter I think, clearly it's probably difficult to be that precise, but we're probably this year in this quarter we're probably up $25 million to $30 million from a year ago in the digital packages.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go the line of David Bank with RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, two questions. The first one is you indicated, Chase, that retransmission consent dollars were, I think, up year over year double or something like that. Could you give us a sense of where we are with reverse comp? And given that it's probably pretty early for revenue, can you update us on what percentage of the affiliate base is at least contractually locked in to start contributing something?</p>
          <p>And the second question is a difficult thing in that you don't want to negotiate publicly. But can you give us a sense in the context of the FOX broadcast, Idol ratings, what kind of ratings guarantees do you think you make given the performance of Idol, if you could give us a general sense of which way you expect ratings to go, I guess. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll come back to that and answer the first. I'm not sure I followed your Idol question, but I'll come back to it.</p>
          <p>On retrans, I'm not sure that's &#x2013; I guess it is about double this year. The affiliate side of it, which I think the heart of your question on retrans, is where we are affiliates on the side of the retrans are essentially payments for the retrans and the affiliation rights. And that's clearly behind where we are in retrans. It really is something that &#x2013; we have some, but it's going to pick up a lot. I think the vast majority of our &#x2013; we have a significant portion, I think it's probably about half the &#x2013; I think <mark type="ph" /> disk (34:57) by the end of the year. About half the affiliate body will go through an affiliate renewal that enables us to put in place a structure that recognizes the value of our programming. And I think by the end of the following year we get up closer to 70% to 80%.</p>
          <p>So we've had some. It's been small. It's probably that is a bit of a tail behind the core retrans we've done through the O&amp;Os, and it will pick up a lot. So I think between now and year-end, a lot comes through. And then there's another block in the year that follows. So in the next six to twelve to eighteen months, the majority of the affiliate body will roll into agreements that have recognized the value of the programming we've put forth. It will be a pretty sizable chunk that comes in this calendar year. On Idol, I didn't &#x2013; can you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the question is given that ratings have been pretty weak, right, as you enter the upfronts, you're going to have to guarantee &#x2013; you're going to have certain audience guarantee levels. How do you view the prospects for ratings next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, Idol didn't &#x2013; I think as I said last quarter, Idol didn't perform what we hoped this year. But realistically, before <mark type="ph" /> jumping on it, (36:30) I think it is just, even with the Super Bowl &#x2013; it just passed &#x2013; or The Voice and Super Bowl package, Idol just passed The Voice to go back to being the number one show this year. It's a big, profitable number one show. And it was down a little more than we would have liked this year. But it's a big, valuable franchise that makes a lot of money. We certainly think it's got a lot of life left in it, and I think our challenge for next year is to put some fresh energy in it.</p>
          <p>I think we did well a year ago, probably not well enough this past year to <mark type="ph" /> find ways (36:50), and probably learned a bit at that show, clearly it's finishing whatever it is, its 11th year or something. But we probably need to make sure each year we're adding enough to it. So I think there was a year ago with the changes in the judges and the like, and I think some people running the show came back with a lot of freshness and a fresh feel. We probably didn't do enough this year, and that's probably a lesson. So I think we need to try and make sure we next year give that show enough energy and excitement to sustain it. The reality is yes, it's an 11-year-old show. But the reality is it's the number one show on television. It makes a lot of money. And it is certainly &#x2013; we look at it as we go into next year a centerpiece for the network, and we're excited about potential of it. And I think we'll be realistic in negotiating with advertisers about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go to Adam Alexander with Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, just a question on the buyback. So far, you've only focused on buying back the Class A shares. I'm wondering if that's going to continue. And as part of that, what plans do you have in place the reinstate the foreign shareholder vote back to 100%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The current plan is continue to buy back the non-voting Class A shares. And with respect to the foreign ownership, it'll be measured from time to time. And to the extent that we can foot that part of the bill, we will. To the extent that we can't, we won't. It's the plan we have in place to deal with the issue with respect to our television license in the United States.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you think there's a timeframe you can put on that, Dave?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, timeframe with regard to what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Getting the shareholder vote back to 100%. I mean, how long do you think or what processes do you actually have to reduce the foreign ownership back to the level required by the license?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's no timeframe on it. To the extent the shareholding would change, it would be more U.S. shareholders buying the voting stock, and it would allow us to let more of the foreign shareholders vote. But it's a function of that; there's no other plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And changing the buyback to buy back the voting stock, would that have any impact on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It could, but that's not where our focus is at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Adam; next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to Jason Bazinet with Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just had one question for Mr. Carey. It seems like the investment community has gotten comfortable with the litigation expenses, but I was just wondering. As you fast-forward to the next reporting period, presumably you guys give guidance. Is there anything that you see on the horizon that could cause the investigation to spill over into the operating metrics? Specifically, I'm thinking about indications that advertisers are pulling away or anything that you can think of that might be on the horizon that would influence your guidance for next fiscal year. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Really, in all honesty, we see none. I can't imagine &#x2013; I guess I'd be shocked if there was. Certainly, we've seen nothing to date.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's from Barton Crockett with Lazard Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you for taking the question. I was interested in the step up in the domestic affiliate fee growth to 15% from 9%. I was wondering if you could tell us a little bit about how much of that step-up was driven by FOX News versus the RSNs. And as you roll in more renewals over the balance of the year, is there potential for that growth rate to step up even more over the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We feel very good about where we are in affiliations. I guess I have always felt that trying to look at it on a quarterly basis is not a great practice. With renewals, you end up with &#x2013; we're right on track. I'm not trying to detract from it, but I'm not going to break it down channel by channel how does it falls out approximate. Clearly, renewals are affected. I think we've said in the past we've had historically 10%-plus, low double-digit affiliate growth. As we look out over the next few years, we continue to be confident and feel confident about that growth. It's obviously a mix of channels there. But I'm not going to break the channels down. I think I've said there are channels that obviously had bigger growth, I talked about FOX News and the fact that its unique strength and its unique value and we're going to renew half the channels between now and year end, so certainly that's a meaningful part of it, but FX is doing great as well. But I think in general, again, this is one you really ought to look at over a bit longer time period to take some of the bumps that can go in a quarter out of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just follow up, you say you're renewing half the distribution between now and the election.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have some done, but it's not all renewing. Essentially this retrans cycle, we've renewed and will renew about half by the end of the calendar year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so there's more to come. It's not all done yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to Spencer Wang with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the question. I guess for Chase a question on cable programming and the pay television business. Chase, you've sat on both sides of the bargaining table as CEO of DIRECTV and now running a very large cable programming group. You alluded to preserving the bundle. Yet it seems like every cable network group is aggressively trying to raise affiliate fees. So I was wondering if you could just speak about how you strike the right balance in terms of maximizing your affiliate revenue while preserving the bundle.</p>
          <p>And if I could just on the topic of off-balance sheet assets, Hulu, if you could just update us on how that fits in and the strategic direction there, thanks. Hello?</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> (43:15 &#x2013; 46:35)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, one moment. Ladies and gentlemen, please stay connected one moment while we reconnect. Ladies and gentlemen, we appreciate your patience in holding we are having some technical difficulties. Please continue to hold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the operator. Please go ahead, Spencer Wang.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In all honesty, it wasn't that tough a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry I scared you off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the question was on the bundles, Spencer. If not, you can follow up. I assume everybody is on the call too. We apologize. Unfortunately, somebody stepped on the wrong switch on one of those extension cords. I guess two responses to the bundle. First from our perspective, we're going to get competitively what we think is a fair price for our content. And the only way I think we can run this business is to get our fair share. So that's our job and that's what we're going to do. If we do a good job with great channels that have real value, we should get what is a fair, competitive rate for our channels.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of what pressure does that create on the larger bundles, I guess it's our job to subsidize them. I think we keep our eyes &#x2013; we're aware of the discussion, aware of the issue. I do think still to date it is an issue that really you don't see in the core of the business. I think the value of this bundle is second to none, and I think it is still one that is tremendously important to people. I think one thing you also have to not lose sight of; there are two sides to the price of this bundle. There's the content and channel side and the distribution side. I used to sit on that side of it. The one thing I know from sitting on that side of it is there are big profitable businesses over there, so this is not about somehow you've got somebody on one side or the other that can't afford the bundle. I understand people have pressures, and we want this to be healthy for everybody. But this is a good business model for both.</p>
          <p>I think that's one of the reasons we believe TV Everywhere is an important solution. It's one of the ways to deal with the cost and to make sure we keep making the experience better and richer and the customer gets new things. They're able to find content on new devices and the like. And I think it's important that we do enrich that experience and make sure that &#x2013; there are always those who would rather pay less. But it is to the degree that &#x2013; I think one of our challenges is to make sure we continue to make that experience better and better for them by enriching this. And actually, I do feel it's a pretty good value. So we're not immune to it. I think we'll continue to do what we can to address it. I do think TV Everywhere is the primary initiative through which we would try and address it by, again, adding value to it as the cost goes up. But I think the power, the importance, and ultimately really the value of this bundle given the time people spend with it make it a really good and important proposition for consumers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just on Hulu, Chase, in terms of any update on the strategic direction and how it fits in given the off-balance sheet opportunistic strategy there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say you mean the off-balance sheet. I'm not sure the off balance sheet part of it, I'd focus on it. For us, I think the focus is really how do we continue to develop that as a digital franchise that enables us to add dimensions to the content and channel businesses we have. I think it is, as I said before, the reason we didn't move forward with the sale of the business is there's no question these digital platforms are going to be the driving force of our business going forward, real opportunities if we can manage it properly. And I think that's because this is a business we need to make sure we have rules and disciplines about how we deal with it and what we put in there and on what terms. But it can be a real &#x2013; it is a real opportunity to add to the mix of our business and enrich it as a whole on a content and a network perspective. That's where the focus is, not necessarily anything in terms of balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go the line of Tuna Amobi with S&amp;P Capital IQ. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you so much. I appreciate the opportunity to ask a question. So I don't remember the last time SKY Italia lost this many subscribers. I was just trying to get a sense of if anything is structurally changing in that market and who were the &#x2013; what's the competitive situation there and where the subscribers are going, just to get a sense of how that business is shaking out.</p>
          <p>The other question was, if I could, the question on the situation with &#x2013; I'm sorry, I'll take the question after the answer on SKY.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think in Italy, I'm not a historian. But I think what has changed is clearly the Italian economy is going through an incredibly &#x2013; the Italian population is going through an incredibly difficult time that has people nervous and concerned about the future with &#x2013; and I think it's probably unique in decades. Again, I can't say because I'm not an economic historian, but I think this is probably one of the most challenging periods of time the Italian economy has faced in decades. It really started last year, probably really started to manifest itself in our business in the beginning of this year, but there is no question consumers are deeply concerned about the short-term future in Italy. What are these various austerity measures and the like I guess are the issues we all hear and read about that are affecting particularly southern Europe are having an impact, and I think there are people that have a lot of uncertainty about what the future will look like.</p>
          <p>We believe in the long-term future of this business. We're very confident. Actually competitively, probably we're stronger than we've ever been. I think a few years ago, we had a platform from Mediaset that was launched to be with us. I think we've actually done a really good job of competing with that. I think the quality of the service is better than ever, but we're going to have to ride through. It's pretty tough, a very tough economic period as Italy finds its footing. And I think they have to get to a place where the population there has some visibility and understanding of what the future is going to be. I think while you're going through this period of austerity with new leaders and policies being debated and election changes and the like, people are <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:00) and they're trying to, again, a way for some visibility to what's there. But I think competitively, the power of this product we feel good about. I think the strength of this business competitively, we don't have a cable business we compete with. And so I think we feel excited there about the long term, but I think we recognize we have a tough period ahead of us in the short term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Chase, it would be nice to get some reassurance that you can continue to grow your operating income in that market, and a housekeeping question for Dave. I guess first half you got a benefit from NBA lockout which you had expected to reverse. I apologize if I missed that. For Q3, what was the number of the reversal, and what amount do you expect for Q4 on the NBA? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was $40 million in the current quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Is that pretty much done now, or is there more to come?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a bit more to come in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that was helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, I think now would be a good time to switch over to questions from the press.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, and we'll go the line of Edmund Lee with Bloomberg News. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the question. Chase, you had mentioned in an investors conference a few months back there had been some internal discussions about possibly spinning off some of the newspapers. Given there was some weakness in the UK and Australian papers this past quarter, is that another consideration to moving forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, just to clarify what was said, I think I know what you were talking about, I was asked was I aware that there was investor interest in us displayed in us potentially spinning off the Publishing businesses. My answer was yes, I was aware there was investor interest in us doing so is, and my response was we take that seriously, as we should, both as management and the Board. We discuss that and other strategic options. As I said, we still treat that we've got a plan to do. And if we don't have a plan to do that, our focus is on getting these businesses &#x2013; obviously, we still have headwinds, and Dave talked about the challenges in the Publishing business in this quarter getting those businesses in place. We've got new management teams that are going to put plans in place to drive them forward. So our focus is on improving those businesses, but we're aware of the issue and we appropriately discuss and focus of it and other things that we appropriately should discuss as a Board and a management team.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to the line of John Jannarone with The Wall Street Journal. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my question. With regard to BSkyB, when you talk about the way you look at an asset and believing that, if you can, you'd like to be an owner and operator, how long are you willing to wait for that? And by that, I mean is there a point in time when you might consider doing something else with all the cash you have invested like buying back your own stock? It looks like the market is pretty happy with the way you announced this afternoon based on where the stock was trading. Is there a point in time when you might start to think about other options if you're not able to move forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me be clear; we're not reserving an option there today I think I said in the last couple of calls. We're not expecting in the short to medium term to be doing anything other than maintaining our interest in BSkyB. So we're not managing &#x2013; we're going forward assuming we're not doing that. So if it's just the perception that somehow we're taking actions that have that in the planning process, that's not the case.</p>
          <p>In terms of owning it, again, I'll probably tell you this is what I said before. We're not going to put a timeframe to it. We like that investment. We like that business. We tried to buy that business. It's an indication of our commitment to and belief in that business. It's got a great management team that does a great job. We've sat with this stake now for 20 years, so clearly we have sat with it for a long time. We're not going to put timeframes to when we may or may not. I recognize the statement. I'm not backtracking on the statement. We'd rather own and control or monetize. But equally we'll reemphasize the statement I made that there are no timeframes to that. And there are different assets and different businesses. We may end up saying that those are the positions that for other reasons override the desire to modify their own and we'll finally stay the course. We've been comfortable staying the course with BSkyB for a long time, and I think that's where we are today. So our focus on BSkyB is going to be to be to continue to be a shareholder that helps it fulfill its potential. We're proud of what that company has built and we're excited about its future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that helps; just one other thing. Can you tell me if you've given any consideration to James stepping down either from News Corp. or from BSkyB?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we did not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's all for me, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, I think we have time for one last press question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That will be from the line of Andrew Edgecliffe-Johnson with the Financial Times. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chase. Could you just clarify for us the process of renewing your licenses with the FCC and the timeframe there? And also did you get any feedback from them on the fact that your foreign ownership went as high as 36%, which I imagine didn't happen overnight?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. Right now, I don't know whether it's all the stations or a subset of stations. The cycle you go through that is up over multiyear, Dave thinks it's every ten years. I don't actually know what it is, but I know it's not one or two. But you go through a renewal process we went through I guess. And as part of that process we went through, and did the appropriate steps, discovered we had this issue and addressed it. I think from all the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>it got so out of whack; how did you not notice that it had gone up so high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We went through this and we found it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Operator, I think we're all set for today. If you have any more questions, please call us in New York later on. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this conference is available for replay. It starts today at 6:30 PM Eastern Time and will last until May 23 at midnight. You may access replay at any time by dialing 800-475-6701 or 320-365-3844, the access code 244401. Those numbers again, 800-475-6701 or 320-365-3844, the access code 244401.</p>
          <p>That does conclude your conference for today. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>