<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1260522" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7795</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christian Mulliez, Executive Vice-President, Administration and Finance</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jean-Paul Agon, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Celine Pannuti</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Simon Marshall-Lockyer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Pascal Lamy</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. We're a little late, people still have their heads on holiday, usually very punctual. Good morning, everybody. Could we have the houselights down a little, please? We don't want the light shining in our face because this is not a show between Christian and myself, we just want to give you the first half-year results, the real heroes of this morning. So Christian, I think we are ready to roll. We are just going to have a few organizational details first. A bit more light in the room, so that you can take your notes and so that I can see them, please.</p>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Before we start the meeting, let me give you some organizational details. As you came in, you will find the headsets for simultaneous translation, French is on one, English on two. So you may choose the channel of your preference. The Wi-Fi connection in this building means that you can have an Internet connection out of a corner near the lobby bar, the hostesses can take you there, which means that you are kindly asked to turn off your mobiles or put any cellphones on standby so as not to disturb the meeting.</p>
          <p>At the back of the room, there are the financial tables that Mr. Mulliez and Mr. Agon will be talking about. There is also a copy of the press release of the half-year results in the financial community after closure of the stock market yesterday, that is available too. All of this meeting will be broadcast on a dedicated website, lorealfinance.com, all the presentations and a repeat of the meeting will be available as a webcast on the presentations webcast section of our website. And then as you leave this morning, we will give you a brochure with the consolidated half-yearly financial statements in English and French.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much and enjoy your meeting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Over to you, Christian Mulliez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. The presentation of L'Oreal 's financial results for the first year will include information about sales profit, the cash flow and the balance sheet situation.</p>
          <p>Let's talk about consolidated sales, as published on the 12th of July. Consolidated sales amounted to 9.670 billion, up by 6.6% at constant exchange rate. Like-for-like, sales grew by 6.3%. Structural effect had a positive impact of plus 0.3%. This corresponds mainly to the American professional product distributors, Maly's West and Marshall acquired in 2009, and C.B. Sullivan acquired in June 2010. After allowing for foreign exchange effect which was significantly positive at plus 3.6%, the trend based on reported figures came out at plus 10.2%.</p>
          <p>Now, let us look at the figures like-for-like by brand and by division. Professional products recorded growth at 5.3%. Consumer product sales have grown by 5.6%. Luxury products, which have rebounded strongly compared with 2009, have recorded a 9.7% growth. Active cosmetics sales have grown by plus 4.7%, the cosmetics branch has achieved growth of plus 6.4%. The Body Shop has achieved positive growth at plus 0.2%, finally in dermatology, Galderma has achieved another half-year of double-digit growth at plus 14.1%.</p>
          <p>By geographic zone now, in Western Europe, the growth rate was plus 2%. North America has recorded significant growth at around 5%, at almost 5%. The new markets have recorded 13% growth with very significant advances in Asia Pacific, at almost 13%, and Latin America at almost 20%.</p>
          <p>We should note that in Latin America this spectacular combination of strong organic growth, with a significant revaluation of local currencies, has led to growth of more than 35% based on reported figures.</p>
          <p>The relative weight of the new market zone increased once again in the first half and it now accounts for 35.7% of our total sales. It will probably not be long before this zone overtakes Western Europe, after having already overtaken North America a few years ago.</p>
          <p>Currencies and exchange rates, almost all other currencies strengthened against the euro during the first half of 2010. It is worth noting that while the appreciation of the U.S. dollar remains modest at plus 0.4%, the currencies of the major emerging countries, such as Russia, Brazil and Mexico, have strengthened greatly against the euro.</p>
          <p>It is also worth noting that the gradual reduction in the weight of the euro is continuing, 35.4% of sales in 2008, 34.2 in 2009 and 32.5% in the first half of 2010. We have already indicated that if the current exchange rates i.e. &#x20AC;1 equals $1.30, are extrapolated up to the end of the year, the positive impact on our sales for the full year of 2010 should come out at around plus 5.5%, which is a very strong change.</p>
          <p>Let us now look at profit and loss account, where we will start by analyzing gross profit. Gross profit has come out at 71.3% of overall sales, compared with 70.2% in the first half of 2009, representing an improvement of 110 basis points.</p>
          <p>Several factors have had a favorable impact. I would mention the following. The improvement in manufacturing costs, thanks in particular to productivity gains in the factories and gains on purchasing, that is stock management, resulting in a reduction in provisions for obsolete and slow-moving items, the reduction in physical distribution costs and a positive product mix effect.</p>
          <p>Conversely, two factors have had an unfavorable impact on this item. The extra cost generated by the increase in promotional offers to customers, which is slightly higher than in the first half of 2009, and the extra cost linked to exchange rate fluctuations.</p>
          <p>The improvement in gross margin recorded in the first half cannot be extrapolated over the rest of the year. In fact, while the weakening of the euro is favorable in absolute value terms, in euro terms this weakening of the euro will have a negative impact on the ratio of gross profit to sales.</p>
          <p>For example, if we apply the current exchange rates that is &#x20AC;1 equals $1.30, if we apply this current exchange rate to the gross profit of the second half 2009, it would work out to 70% of overall sales, as compared to 70.7% based on reported figures, so it's an effect of 70 basis points for this half.</p>
          <p>In addition, production volumes in the first half benefited from the effect of the reconstitution of our internal inventories, which had reached a very low level. In the second half of 2010, we expect that production volumes will be more in line with sell-out.</p>
          <p>Overall, 2010 gross profit should be slightly higher than in 2009. R&amp;D expenses have increased by almost 8%, but as a proportion of sales they have been reduced slightly from 3.3% to 3.2% of overall sales, because of their strong euro weighting.</p>
          <p>Advertising and promotion expenses represented 30% of sales &#x2013; 30.5% of sales compared to 30% in the first half of 2009. We are, therefore, close to the 2009 levels, as we indicated as of the month of February of this year.</p>
          <p>I would remind you that advertising and promotion expenses reflect very different realities depending on the divisions, and commercial channels concerned. In the Professional Products Division, they correspond to technical training courses for hairdressers and salon merchandising. In the Consumer Products Division, we're talking about media and merchandising expenses and special events at sales outlets. In the Luxury Products Division, mainly media expenses, the cost of beauty advisors, merchandising, and samples. And lastly, at Active Cosmetics, they reflect the cost of medical visits, media expenses, and pharmacy merchandising. We will continue to apply our policy of significant investments in advertising and promotion expenses in the second half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Selling, general and administrative expenses now. Expressed as a percentage of sales, they have been reduced sharply to 20.3% of sales compared with 21.1% in the first half of 2009, representing a fall of less than 100 basis points. Based on a constant structure and constant exchange rate, SG&amp;A expenses were virtually stable at plus 1%, reflecting our continuing efforts to keep costs under control. All the divisions have contributed to this improvement.</p>
          <p>It should be noted that there was a strong performance of the Luxury Products Division, thanks in particular to the synergies from the integration of Yves Saint Laurent Beaut&#xE9;. Efforts on SG&amp;A expenses will continue in the second half of 2010, even though their improvement will be less spectacular. And this is particularly because of a comparison base for the second half of 2009, which already reflected substantial efforts. Overall, operating profits have set a new record for half-year, 17.3% of sales, which is an increase of 21.4% compared with the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Talking now about half-year operating profitability. We have the historical series presented here, and this is merely intended to illustrate a constant feature at L'Or&#xE9;al, i.e. first half profitability can never be extrapolated for the second half of the same year.</p>
          <p>Operating profit by division and by branch now. The profitability of the Professional Products Division has increased significantly from 19.1% of sales to 21.2%. The profitability of the Consumer Products Division was virtually stable during the half year, 20.4% compared with 20.7% last year. The Luxury Products Division achieved a very sharp increase in profitability of plus 600 basis points, rising from 12 to 18% &#x2013; going back to 18%, one might say. Lastly, the profitability of Active Cosmetics was almost stable at an extremely high level of 26.9%.</p>
          <p>Non-allocated costs have once again declined from 2.7 to 2.6%. The profitability of The Body Shop, as you can see here from this table, remains highly concentrated on the second half, because of the seasonal nature of this business.</p>
          <p>But for the first time we can see the impact on the first half &#x2013; the impact on the first half of the strong reductions since last year of the fixed cost of The Body Shop. So it was 0% a few years ago, 1.9% last year, and it's improved even further. Finally, Galderma, our joint venture in dermatology, has seen its profitability reach 12.4% in the half year compared with 11.6% in the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>As for the profitability of the geographic zones, we do not publish them, as you know, on a half-year basis. However, I can tell you that profitability has improved in each of the three zones: Western Europe, North America, and New Markets.</p>
          <p>Second part now of the profit and loss account, from operating profit to net profit, which is the basis for the calculation of our net earnings per share. Finance costs, on the second line, were down very substantially to 18 million, which is one-third of the cost for the first half of 2009. This sharp reduction is the result both of the &#x2013; of fall in our average level of net debt and of the continuing decline in interest rates. For the whole year, we can anticipate finance costs in the region of 35, maybe &#x20AC;40 million. The sanofi dividends amounted to 283 million, an increase of 9%.</p>
          <p>Income tax now. Income tax amounted to 521 million, representing a taxation rate of 27%, which is higher than the rate of the first half of 2009, which was 23.3%. This increase is mainly because allowance has been made for the likely impact of tax audits in progress, and this is also the result of the increase in withholding tax on intra-group dividends. For the full year, we may anticipate a taxation rate in the region of 29%. Net profit, excluding non-recurrent items, amounts to 1.411 billion, which is an increase of 16% &#x2013; 16.5%. Finally, net earnings per share amounted to 2.39, up by 15.3.</p>
          <p>Last part of the profit and loss account, after allowing for non-recurrent items, that is a charge of &#x20AC;97 million net of tax, net profit amounted to &#x20AC;1.314 billion, up by 21%. The non-recurrent items consist firstly of restructuring costs amounting to 12 million net and secondly of provisions for liabilities arising from investigations by competition control authorities and intangible asset impairments.</p>
          <p>Cash flow statement. Gross cash flow amounted to &#x20AC;1.792 billion, an increase of 15.4%. Changes &#x2013; increases in working capital was &#x20AC;289 million. The changes in the working capital item have present by far more than it will increase over the full year as is usually the case. This happened this year at the end of June.</p>
          <p>Over the full year, we may expect an increase in changes in working capital of slightly over &#x20AC;100 million. It should be noted that the trade accounts receivable item naturally increases and this is a good thing as business picks up even though the teams concern or the dedicated teams remained extremely vigilant in controlling this item. Investments have remained well under control at 3.3% of overall sales. For the full year, we can expect investments in the region of 4% of sales. Finally, after a dividend payment and after the buying of stakes, let me remind you of the acquisition of C. B. Sullivan and the distributor of professional products in the USA and of the nail varnish brand Essie, the remaining cash flow amounts to &#x20AC;200 million.</p>
          <p>Talking about the balance sheet, again the balance sheet is extremely robust. Shareholders' equity represents some 58% of total assets. The increase of total assets compared with 2009 is the result of the balance between the following: The positive factor profit for the period and cumulative translation adjustments and a negative factor corresponds to the payment of dividends under valuation of the Sanofi-aventis shares.</p>
          <p>Finally, let's talk about the gearing ratio; lastly, net debt came out at 1.673 billion down by almost &#x20AC;300 million compared with the end of 2009. Gearing, i.e. the debt equity ratio came out at 11.7%. And it may be estimated that the net financial debt at December 31, 2010 could be less than &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christian. Now, as you have seen the results for the first half of this year are extremely positive from every point of view, once again the world cosmetics market is growing and we have returned to strong organic growth with market share gains across all continents, development and reinforcement of our major global brands, together with a strong increase in our results both in value and quality terms.</p>
          <p>Now firstly, the cosmetics market, this has picked up very well, which is good news, despite the economic environment remaining uncertain in the first half, the worldwide market for cosmetics products has indeed returned to growth with an increase that we estimate to be &#x2013; and it really is an estimate and nothing more, but we've estimate it to be around 4%, as we had forecast.</p>
          <p>Western Europe, the market was just positive, plus 0.2% which is actually not that bad in view of this serious economic turbulence which has affected the continent over the first six months. Now, some countries even achieved significantly positive growth rates such as United Kingdom and northern countries. The market trend was positive in North America where we estimate growth of 2%, even though there has not really been any evidence of genuine economic upturn there for the moment.</p>
          <p>Trending in Japan is negative, but the big news once again was the strong revival in cosmetics markets growth in the new countries or new markets, coming at 9.5% with the rates of 10.8% in Asia Pacific, excluding Japan of course, 12.7% in Latin America, 5.8% in Africa Middle East and 5.1 in Eastern Europe. I stress these estimates are probably fairly accurate once.</p>
          <p>The acceleration of cosmetics consumption in the new countries confirms the remarkable appetite of the new middle classes for beauty products. And the resulting historic sea change, I will call it in the worldwide cosmetics' market that I've often referred to. That in the first half of 2010 the new countries accounted for 53% of the world market. And 87% of the organic growth on this market, which is of course almost all that.</p>
          <p>On the full year 2010, we believe that the growth rate of the worldwide cosmetics market should stay around its level of around 4%, meaning that the beauty products market we operate on is confirming its strength and its tonnage. It's strong because I say because remember the market trend remained positive in 2009, despite the harshness of the economic crisis and it shows that our consumers in all the developed countries touch great importance to cosmetic or beauty products. And I insist dynamic, because you can see it started growing strongly ones again right from the start of 2010 driven by the powerful appetites of consumers in these new markets.</p>
          <p>Now L'Oreal returned to organic growth in the first half, pulling out our major strategic choices because the Group returned to strong growth in the first half of 2.2%. Thanks to the combined impact of the clear return to organic growth of 6.3%, a positive exchange rate effects which makes pleasant change of 3.6%.</p>
          <p>I would emphasis that this organic growth has been achieved as of the all four divisions which have all returned to good level of growth, particularly in the luxury products division, which was the one that was hit mostly in 2009.</p>
          <p>And there's been growth in three geographic zones with of course very strong growths in the new markets, which in a near future also become the Group's largest business zone, and now up 13%. And I was saying actually that in August this is really historic, I think, first for L'Oreal, the new markets zone on this particular month will come top in terms of L'Oreal figures, which I think is dates that will mark the group.</p>
          <p>Also we've had good return to growth in North America were as about 4.9%. And this is in particular thanks to market share gains in the consumer division. And actually the 2% growth performance in Western Europe was quite good as well. And it has been &#x2013; actually this is growth across the road in all categories, because as you can see from the screen, we are growing everywhere, but particularly in skin care, make-up and fragrances. Fragrances being a business that was badly hit last year. So this return to organic growth is because of the results of our major strategic choices of the last couple of year, I'll remind you what they were.</p>
          <p>Firstly focus on major global innovations with higher value added, but at accessible prices, such as Inneov. That we've talked all lot about, it's true. But it really is the biggest professional hair color success story of all time. It is now found its way to 60,000 hairs salons. And it's almost all in Europe, so there is a huge amount of headroom now.</p>
          <p>And this launch means that we have been able to win a record number of new salons and you know that in professionals we win markets hair salon by hair salons. So it really is about getting to turn the door, so that you can continue to rollout success in salons one by one. We've now achieved figure of 10,000 which is a record high, but it's also meant that we've been able to stimulate color service consumption in salons.</p>
          <p>In consumer we have products such as Youth Code, Matte Morphose, the biggest mascara success in Maybelline history I think or has a Total Repair 5 for L'Oreal. So these are major global blockbusters, driving our growth in skincare, make-up and hair care.</p>
          <p>In the luxury products division. Genifique and I went to, we need to talk about Genifique because it's continuing its global success. We'll talk about growth of not just one year, but maybe three, five and ten years as Genifique is continuing its global penetration, thanks to spectacular successes, which also are fully deserved in view of the product's remarkable quality.</p>
          <p>So the Hypnose Precious Cells, the first truly regenerative mascara by Lanc&#xF4;me and magnificently represented by Julia Roberts. And there is Rege lift volumetry revolution in anti-aging skincare, also represented by first model Kate Winslet. And then also successes in fragrances such as Parisienne and the re-launch of Opium at Yves Saint Laurent.</p>
          <p>In active cosmetics we have Redermic [+] by La Roche Posay, the first anti-aging skincare lines specifically designed for sensitive skin. And LiftActiv CxP Total by Vichy and finally, at the Body Shop, Nutriganics, the first complete range of certified organic skincare products.</p>
          <p>And we are going to continue because you have to remember that these innovations are really the growth drivers, what's going to enable us to win market shares, motivations around the world. We are going to continue and expand even this policy of major innovations with high value-added and accessible prices in the second half with spectacular and innovative major launches such as Luxury, Teint Miracle by Lanc&#xF4;me, once again a revolutionary technology which creates the aura of sublime skin. So it really is a revolution in foundation.</p>
          <p>Rouge Pur Couture by Yves Saint Laurent to mark the comeback &#x2013; the spectacular major comeback of Yves Saint Laurent into lipsticks and 3 major new fragrances. So firstly we have Belle d'Opium by Yves Saint Laurent which is going to be a new generation Opium for the young girls, the daughters of those who bought Opium 30 years ago.</p>
          <p>Acqua Di Gio by Giorgio Armani, the seductive appeal and freshness of Giorgio Armani, which has made Acqua Di Gio the world's number one male fragrance, which is now available in a version for women. And there has been a spectacular takeoff in all countries by the product.</p>
          <p>And outstanding success by Big Pony Collection of Ralph Lauren, all the modernity of Givenchy and elegance of Ralph Lauren in the collection of 4 scents designed to conquer men's markets around the world. And our launches, the two launches, just had Acqua Di Gio and Big Pony, have been spectacular successes.</p>
          <p>Still in consumer, for example, we have Els&#xE8;ve collagen and the new Fructis by Garnier. Hydraphase Intense by La Roche-Posay and a very substantial cluster of products from The Body Shop with Natrulift, DeoDry and Rainforest.</p>
          <p>So major innovations. Now second major strategic choice which is very important is powerful and successful breakthroughs in new key categories, the aim being to generate new growth. So firstly on men's market.</p>
          <p>The powerful expansion of the L'Or&#xE9;al Men Expert brand with 30% growth in first half and which this year should achieved global sales of around &#x20AC;250 million. So this is now beginning to be important. We've always said that the men's market is one that has huge future potential. We are now getting there and we think that with Men Expert we're going to have the first men's care brand in the world and it will be generating serious sales. But the key area there is Asia where men consumers, a large amount of skincare products, and in fact, China is now number one in that market.</p>
          <p>There's also been breakthrough in the deodorants markets with the outstanding success of Garnier Mineral, which was originally launched in Latin America in 2008 and then in Eastern Europe in 2009; and earlier in this year in Western Europe. And it has achieved very success &#x2013; satisfactory success. And all this means that we now have a foothold on this very important market, perfectly complements our existing market.</p>
          <p>Our third major strategic choice of this last year is the acceleration &#x2013; geographic expansion in the global markets. We've had important and successful breakthroughs in many countries which are crucial for the future, starting with China, of course, which in this first half of the 2010 has become L'Or&#xE9;al's number 3 country and it will remain over the rest of the year. This is historic milestone now, third after France and the U.S.</p>
          <p>Our growth rate in China was 14%. We are the leader in almost all of our business apart from shampoos and are particularly well placed to take advantage of the huge potential of Chinese market.</p>
          <p>Then another interesting market is Brazil, which really is confirming its position as one of the major new markets for cosmetics. The developments there have been really spectacular. We've had huge growth 24% in the first half, then it's Russia up 17%. Russia we are number 1 by very long way, very strong market position, and in fact in September we will be opening our new plant at Kaluga which can cope with the fast growth in units sales.</p>
          <p>India, we're up 32% with this particular success, as you all know, of the Garnier brand, but also the very rapid rollout of Matrix in hair salons where we have now won over 11,000 hair salons. And of course it's not just about the BRIC countries, but there are others that are very important when it comes to winning global markets, crucial for our future. Mexico, for example, up 11%, South Korea up 21%, Argentina up 38%, Ukraine up 28%, Indonesia up 25% and Philippines up 26%, to name just a few.</p>
          <p>And finally to the fourth major strategic choice in this first half, the increase in R&amp;D spend and in business drivers to underpin and accelerate our organic growth. As Christian showed in R&amp;D, we have spent, although you can't really see it in the statements, because most of our expenditure is in euros and therefore it is not visible. But on a like-with-like basis compared against growth, it's very significant and it's our strategic aim to increase resources available for research with 2 aims in mind.</p>
          <p>First objective, obviously being to continue to innovate so that we can really come up with breakthrough formulas in major categories, has been the case in <mark type="inaudible" /> and the various areas there.</p>
          <p>But the second objective is what we call universalization. This means the development on each continent formulations, specifically adapted to the specific needs of local consumers, for example, the formulation of &#x2013; by L'Or&#xE9;al hair products in China that we tested on 40,000 consumers to find the perfect formulation for Chinese hair, which is very different from Caucasian hair.</p>
          <p>We in this quarter have also significantly boosted our advertising promotion spend by 12%. That's an increase of 50 basis points, and as Christian pointed out, you have to realize that these investments cover a wide range of different business drivers depending on the division, businesses and channels. And here we have 2 objectives too to continue increasing these drivers, which as I am sure you understand are crucially important in building the success and leadership of our brands on all markets around the world. At the same time, and there's no contradiction here, we have to constantly rethink, renegotiate, re-engineer these investments so as to continue optimize cost and productivity. And we think that in this way in 2010 we should reach a level of spend investment, which will be comparable with that of 2009.</p>
          <p>So these strategic investments underpin the world development of our major brands, which are now again recording strong growth, sometimes double digit growth, such as Maybelline, the world leader in mass-market make-up, which has been rolled out worldwide. And Lanc&#xF4;me, world's number 1 in luxury segment, is undergoing a major renewal, Yves Saint Laurent that we are delighted to see us enjoying genuine renaissance, La Roche-Posay, which is preferred brand of dermatologists around the world, once again enjoying global growth. Matrix, the accessible brand of hairdressers all over the world, and the growth champion, Kiehl's, which in the first 6 months grew by 51%.</p>
          <p>So overall thanks to the strengths of our brands, the quality of our innovations, the power of our business drivers and the talent of all hugely motivated teams we are winning market share and we are strengthening our positions in all geographic zones.</p>
          <p>So this first half is borne out, our strategic choices, our determination to concentrate on limited number of major brands and key initiatives to ensure the strategy is perfectly implemented.</p>
          <p>Results now, see our financials have improved strongly both in value and quality terms. The decisions we have taken, the efforts we have made over the last 2 years have led in first half to return to a record level of operating profit, even though of course, we're well aware this figure won't be extrapolated to the full year.</p>
          <p>In gross profit terms, I'd say that all the actions taken in terms of centralization and strategization of purchasing, together with the progress made in industrial productivity and supply chain modernization, optimization have enabled a very substantial improvement to be achieved in this first half, 110 basis points. Meanwhile, strict control of our cost restructuring carried out, generated a sharp reduction of SGA costs, 100 basis points. All this management efforts have enabled the financing of the increase of business drivers or 50 basis points and a very substantial improvement of operating by about 160 basis points, taking it back to its all time high of which was the level just before the crisis hit, first half of 2008.</p>
          <p>Financial terms, cash flow has remained excellent, with record first half operating cash flow of &#x20AC;1.182 billion, which has enabled us to reduce financial debt which has also reached a historically low level, 11.7% of shareholder equity. And our balance sheet has been now strengthened.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion, the first half results showed that L'Or&#xE9;al is emerging from the crisis and as we had announced, transformed and strengthened and it's ready to score new victories, we have return to organic growth. We are conquering global markets at a faster pace and a virtuous circle of performance, this very L'Or&#xE9;al idea, virtuous circle of performance is now forming so we approach the second half with confidence even though the &#x2013; we have to be aware the economic environment is still very uncertain.</p>
          <p>Finally, this return to growth in the first half also confirms our confidence about outstanding development prospects and our aim of winning 1 billion new consumers across the world over the next 10 years. Well, I can tell you that all our employees are fully focused on achieving this target, which is the key objective of our company for the coming years here at L'Or&#xE9;al. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign language]. We move on to the Q&amp;A session. We need a bit more light in this room please, so that we can see your faces.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is Celine going to get the ball rolling? That is a want. Yes, go ahead Celine. Very, very dim indeed, switch on the wrong switch, okay. We need more light in this room. Go ahead Celine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I have a question. When you talk about the market, you said that there was a growth of 4% and you are expecting growth of 4% in the second half. Wasn't there a positive impact in the first half because of the fact that the first half of 2009 had been very tough. Aren't we being a little bit too optimistic if we look at what's happened in Western Europe over the last quarters? I mean, that's the first question, aren't we being too optimistic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first question first. You are not completely mistaken. There's a very slight impact. We are &#x2013; been reconstituting our stocks, not restocking so much, because I think that's all distributors and retailers worldwide underwent some problems during the crisis and they now want to reconstitute their stocks which went down during the recession. But there are some pockets where there were some cases of stock reconstitution. But this is a very small impact indeed. We would like to get out of this discussion which is endless. Over the long-term, the effect is smoothed out. So it's true that the market was between 3 and 4. It's very difficult to actually tell you where the difference comes from.</p>
          <p>Now, regarding the second half of the year, we can't really know what the growth rate will be. We are 8 months into the year. We can see that what has happened in the markets in July and August &#x2013; we can see that what has happened in July has confirmed the previous trends. In fact, the trend has not improved, but has not deteriorated in an alarming fashion. So, to be more cautious, we should say that there will be a growth rate between 3 and 4. That was our announcement. We haven't really made a mistake, because that's what we had announced last year.</p>
          <p>A lot of people thought that the market would collapse. We felt that it would remain positive and it remained positive. At the beginning of the year, we said between 3and 4. We consider that it will still be between 3 and 4. So we are fairly confident that the market will be fairing fairly well.</p>
          <p>There's a good reason to this. Experience has shown two things. Number one as I said, we can see that in mature markets, cosmetics consumption has been holding up pretty well. Consumers are not ready to give up on the use of cosmetics, even though the business cycle or the economic situation is becoming tougher, they have shown this in 2009, if it were to become a bit tougher, I think that the same trend would apply.</p>
          <p>And we can see that there is a great deal of appetite for cosmetics elsewhere in the world and this is a trend that won't be stopped, and there are hundreds of millions of customers in the world, in China, in Indonesia, in the Philippines or in Brazil, who really have this natural appetite for beauty products, for cosmetics. For them it is an important product that contributes to their quality &#x2013; the quality of their actual life. So it's not a volatile product.</p>
          <p>We are talking about a very strong sturdy market. Cosmetics market is developing for fundamental essential reasons and it will continue to develop. Obviously, there might be little highs and lows and hitches from half to half or from quarter to quarter, but that's not fundamentally significant. What was your second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a second question, and then I have a third question for Christian Mulliez. But I will go quickly. The first question on the SG&amp;A costs, we have seen a drop of 100 basis points as you've indicated. Now, was it the positive impact of the restructuring announced over the last 18 months or is there a recurrent effect or impact and on the middle-term, would it be 90%, 70%, 20% of overall sales, what exactly would be the impact mid-term? Now, focusing on the third question, we have debt levels, the net debt levels are very low. Can we consider a share buyback possibility in the short-term, would that be an option?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian you start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's true that the debt level has been decreased. We could have net debt level of zero at the end of 2011, that's a definite possibility. You know that our policy is target acquisitions. That's what we want to do. For the time being we have no project to engage in share buyback programs.</p>
          <p>Now regarding the SG&amp;A, here again I'd like to say that there is a two-fold effect or impact. First of all, we had the restructuring that has being going on which has had an impact but the main impact comes from all the measures that we've undertaken to control our costs.</p>
          <p>Now, we have decided that L'Oreal should be able to develop internally. Organic growth should be a positive. So what we want to do, of course, is to keep a cap on our costs and control our costs. So we've been working on larger, better organization, more optimization, keeping down our staffing levels, reducing our costs, travel costs and others. All of this will enable us to keep our costs well under control, and there will be a positive trend in the cost-sales ratio. We certainly hope that we will experience regular improvement in this item over the next two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This lady, please. I think this lady first and then you, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> I am interested to get a little bit more information about the development of the consumer products division, and in particular about the profitability development. Given the huge progress that you have made all over the allover business, it would be really interesting to see what has held back further margin progress on the consumer products division? And obviously these are first half results, so it would be very interesting to hear your view on how that is going to develop for the full year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's a good question. In fact, it's true that you've seen a little dip on the profitability of the consumer division in the first half. It is mostly due or 100% due to the one-time cost of the launch of the deodorants. You know that we have launched a very strong initiative at the beginning of the year in all countries of Western Europe on deodorants. And this has a cost.</p>
          <p>I remember when I launched Fructis in the U.S. six or seven years ago, I mean the first year is definitely an investment because you have to pay for getting in the stores. You have to pay for PP materials. You have to pay for high media without sales. So there is a strong cost at the beginning. And this explains most or more than the difference in the profitability on the first half for the consumer division. And what we believe is that on the total year, the profitability of the consumer division should be very comparable to what it was last year. So there is no real concern here. Okay? <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon Marshall-Lockyer from Jefferies. I have two questions. One on the tax rate and the outstanding tax debt &#x2013; the outstanding taxes with the tax authorities in France, have you taken this item into account? Is this item being entered into the books for the first half? It's the question for you Christian, that would mean that in the middle term, there should be an increase in the taxes to be paid by the group. I certainly hope that there will be an increase in the tax base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know that we've had discussions with tax authorities, not necessarily the French tax authorities but tax authorities in general. Discussions are progressing fairly well and there comes a time where they are mature enough, so that you can include provisions in your accounts and you could &#x2013; should see any more than that. There's a one-off impact on the tax rate of that particular half. I said it would be 29% compared to 27% for the year 2010 compared to 2009. So it's a slightly lower, smoother increase, difficult to forecast what the tax rate will be in 2011 because the states obviously are free to decide what the taxation rate should be in 2011, at the constant tax rates, we should have a slightly lower taxation level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it was a one-off effect, wasn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, indeed. And there is another effect which is also a one-off effect, it's a little bit technical on withholding taxes on inter-group dividends. It's a consequence of good news. Our international subsidiaries are getting more and more profitable. The vast majority of these subsidiaries have consumed &#x2013; their debt has to be carried over. So they are starting to pay out more and more dividends to us, and you know that on flows of this nature, they are withholding taxes that have to be paid. So it is in fact the consequence of the good economic health of our subsidiaries. And it's good, because that way we can pay out your dividends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a second question for Mr. Agon on the INOA product. Could you give us some information? You have launched INOA in North America at the beginning of this year. You told us some detail about the progress achieved, about the market shares gained in Europe in particular for this particular product. Could you also tell us about how INOA is fairing in the United States?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a bit too early. You know, it was launched in April in the United States, so from what we've heard about the last four months, we've heard very good news. INOA has confirmed its position. It's a game-changing product. It completely changes the deal and the nature of the market. From what I've heard, 85% satisfaction rate was expressed by the hair stylists and the 15% that were not satisfied, they are not satisfied because they did not use the product as they should have, so they need to be trained and we're sending trainers to train these hair dressers or hair stylists.</p>
          <p>You know that there are technological breakthroughs and leaps that can't be reversed, and that's one of these products, it's a very resounding success. We are very happy about it and we are rolling out the INOA technology worldwide, but it's a bit early to tell you about how the product is faring in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this lady?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I come from <mark type="inaudible" /> I have questions of a different nature. If I've understood correctly, employees are asking you to tell us about your support to <mark type="inaudible" /> would like to know for how long this contract has been underway? 2011, that's the present contract with Mr. Banier, it should be terminated in 2011. Can't you terminate it a bit earlier to satisfy your employees?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is a meeting on the half-year results of the L'Oreal Company. Of course, I can answer your question, but I can &#x2013; I would rather answer you question at the end. It's not that I want to avoid or dodge the issue, but I think we should concentrate mainly on the half-year results. And if there are questions on other subjects, we'll take them at the end of this meeting.</p>
          <p>Now number one, what I can say is that on this particular business, L'Oreal will explain its position, and we consider that this criticism is ill-founded and not justified. We heard about this in the newspapers. And of course there will be an investigation and I won't make any more comments on this today.</p>
          <p>Now any other question on the half-yearly &#x2013; half-year results? I certainly hope that there are questions, because to be quite honest with you, the company is also a great subject of interest. And I would certainly strongly encourage you to take an interest in the actual extraordinary developments of this company. So rather than looking at the different rumors around the company. Madam?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I have three questions. The first one is on the internal growth trend in July and August. You said that the trend was confirmed, that the comparison base is very different from one half to the other. So are we talking about comparing with the &#x2013; are we talking about the trends for the first half of 2010, second half of 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, listen, we are not going to &#x2013; I mean this not a rough estimate, but it's not that precise either. So roughly speaking, what I can tell you is that &#x2013; first of all, let's talk about the markets. Let's look at the different divisions, first of all, that's very more meaningful.</p>
          <p>And I'm a little bit disappointed to see that the hairstylists, the hair salons, the market has not really picked up that much. And from a psychological standpoint, it is very important for me, not from an economic standpoint, but psychological standpoint. It would have been better if the footfall had been somewhat greater in hair salons. So it picked up some &#x2013; a little bit in the summer, but not enough, we feel. So worldwide, hair salons, I mean the market is fairly flat.</p>
          <p>Regarding consumer products, there are two different situations or environments: the Western World, first of all, Western World and North America, where the markets are flat, completely flat. Sometimes you have zero, zero plus one or zero minus one, plus 0.1, minus 0.1. But we could say that the market is really fairly flat.</p>
          <p>And then we have the growth markets in China, in India, in Brazil and Mexico, where we can see that there is a completely world unfolding in these parts and where consumption is really booming. So all in all, we have a growth rate of between 3 and 4% worldwide in consumer products.</p>
          <p>Luxury division, we went off to a good start, again, going back to what Celine was saying, the sellout, sellout of luxury products has resumed, very strong growth in this first half and has resumed a level which is in fact higher than the level that we reached at the beginning of 2008. So it's a very encouraging positive trend. And for active cosmetic division, we have a slightly positive figure for worldwide growth.</p>
          <p>So I don't know whether we should look month-by-month, week-by-week. And I think this is the big trend and this is what matters. And we certainly hope that growth in new emerging markets will continue or even further strengthen. And we certainly hope that we will have good news to report on in developed markets as well. Which means that you could continue outgrowing the market by 1.0,1.5 times. Well, clearly, this is the objective that we have in-house.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My second question now, there is something that really had struck me in the presentation that you made. Something struck me as being new, talking about market growth. We were used to seeing L'Or&#xE9;al grow twice faster than others in new markets and at a lower rate in developed markets. Now, what we can see in the first half is that it is in these developed markets that you have grown &#x2013; outperformed markets by 2 times.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, when the market is flat, two times zero, three times zero, four times zero, always gives you the same figure, doesn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but compared to &#x2013; if you look at the situation in North America for example, you have outperformed the market by 200%. Generally speaking, we see this in new, emerging markets. In emerging markets you're outperforming by 1.5 times. This is a highly scientific analysis, but if you look at the reality, it seems that you gain market share depending on the initiatives that you launched, depending on the opportunities you seize, what you do, what your competitors do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So if you look at the different geographic zones, because you want a very exhaustive analysis, we are gaining market shares very quickly in Asia. We consider that we are probably outperforming the market by a factor of two. We are winning market shares in Latin America, but Latin America is progressing so fast that it's very difficult to outperform the others very quickly. But we are still outperforming in Western America.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, we are doing well in Russia and Poland and in Ukraine. But the market itself is not so great, plus five, we do more than that. And in the developed market it depends, for example in the United States, we're doing better than our competitors in consumer products, not as well in consumer &#x2013; in luxury products.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we are doing a little better in luxury products than in consumer products. You know that there are 20 brands across 60 countries, four distribution channels. So it's very difficult to really draw major conclusions from that, we are gaining market shares across all of our geographic zones, and that's what we need to remember.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Third question. I don't really know whether it was you or the L'Or&#xE9;al Board, asked Nestl&#xE9; to give thought to its future holding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it wasn't me. I think you misread the AFP press release.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't understand German, and didn't understand what Mr. Brabeck said. I can confirm that. I do not speak German.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Manuel, you seem to be trying to fish for information then. What I can tell you is that Mr. Brabeck, who is the Chairman of Nestl&#xE9; Board, was mandated by his Board to give thought to the future holding of Nestl&#xE9; in L'Or&#xE9;al, which for us is a non-event. This is perfectly normal that the CEO, Chairman of the company holding more than 29% in L'Or&#xE9;al should give thought to that matter. Now, I have to say for the journalists in the room that I haven't seen anything new or groundbreaking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question. The 1 billion new consumers, I forgot about that. So this is doubling the figure in 10 years. This is 7 or 8% growth a year in terms of consumer scores, numbers of consumers. Could you perhaps give us a little bit more info about what this means for the different channels, regions? What exactly does this mean for the way the Group will be ten years down the road, because I'm sure you're working on this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you're right. It's very important. Now how did we reach this figure? We said that today &#x2013; because we're talking about 800 million, a billion consumers there at the moment. But since we don't have all of them, it's a rough guess. But obviously it says that based on the markets where we operate and also because we sell about 5 billion products.</p>
          <p>So we crunch the numbers, and I think it's 5.3, 5.4 billion products, okay, with that figure looking at our markets, we think we probably got between 800 million and a billion consumers. So what we said was that with the sea change on the market, the focus &#x2013; this is shifting to highly populated countries. That's the most important thing, actually. What counts is that in 100 years, L'Oreal has grown to number one and sales of &#x20AC;20 billion, mainly with growth driven by countries with limited population. Europe has 0.5 billion, United States, 300 million.</p>
          <p>And the big switch is that you've got hugely populated countries like China, India, and Brazil that are going to have access to these products. And so the change is that we're going to have a much larger consumer pool. Now, over the next few years, we won't be selling each person as many products as we do to the current 800 million. We're not going to double our sales.</p>
          <p>But this is a major change, and it's a change in focus as well. That is to say, we have to choose products and formulations and offer the brands, have the distribution channels in those countries where our consumers will be waiting for us. So if you're trying to read into that some sort of implication about growth rate, it's going to be tough, because we don't know which products, prices, sizes, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Giles Courviert from Les Echos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nice to see you. You don't often do us the honor of coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Body Shop has grown, it's true, but in terms of profitability, remains anomalous in the group. Is there a problem at the moment with that business? Is there a problem with the way the employees react to the L'Or&#xE9;al method? And what do you think about that as a targeting acquisition now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for asking that question. Thanks for coming, thanks for the question. Let me be perfectly honest. Two answers. Firstly, objective reasons why Body Shop's growth rate is lower than others. First is that they didn't slide in 2009. So going back to what Mr. Laurent says when we talk about bases, it's true, it's not as favorable as in divisions that were worse hit in '09.</p>
          <p>The second reason is for the moment Body Shop is very much absent from the new markets. The Body Shop operates in the U.K., Western Europe, United States, Japan. We haven't calculated numbers, but I think if we did, we would find that 80% of its sales come from developed countries where consumption is flat. So this is a mechanical reason holding back Body Shop's growth compared with other divisions.</p>
          <p>A third factor, to be perfectly honest, is that at the moment we haven't fully transformed, to be honest, we haven't really gone through the transformation process that we have to &#x2013; the brands, the products, the stores, and that will be done. And to answer the underlying question, what do I think about the acquisition now?</p>
          <p>Well, I think we would do the same again, because I think that basically Body Shop as a brand is exactly what consumers are wanting today in 21st century world. When you talk to people and you ask them which is the cosmetics brand they see as being for the new century, they say one with natural products, that is environmentally friendly, that is ethical, and this is bang-on Body Shop, to a tee.</p>
          <p>So we're very confident. We haven't always transformed our brands quickly. Doesn't always work first time round. But we'll be very persevering and we will succeed, I am sure. In terms of profitability, it's moving in the right direction. It's not calculable yet, but going in the right direction and we're working hard on it.</p>
          <p>Yes, another question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> three questions. First on the North American market specifically, what can you tell us about the fears on that market, not overall, but regarding L'Or&#xE9;al's performance there in the first half?</p>
          <p>Second, Brazil, we know how important that market is, you stressed that. And also, with respect to direct selling, have you moved on from that? And other income and expenses, I missed what you said about that. Could you give us a bit more detail about what that item means?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On other income and charges, let's recount, when I said million, it's provisions, restructuring costs and provisions for impairment. And you can extrapolate from that into the second half, because if we were going to book things in the second half they would have to be visible in the first half. So we'll give you the details when we come back in February. Maybe there will be a little more maybe not. I'm sure we'll almost learn that at the same time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>United States. What, I can tell you about that is the latest news from market is that the mass market is flat, luxury market is a bit more positive, things are picking up a bit in the big stores and the hair salon market is very quite too. So I think what we can see from all sources is that there is no real economic recovery at the moment in United States. Now what's going to happen? No idea, any more than anyone else. But we're basically &#x2013; our prospects are not related to others but our focus is winning market share. So we want to win market share, in Consumer, we're doing that. Significant market share wins in makeup, we're doing very well with Walmart, very good cooperation with them, very strong position there, although all sorts of plans relate to the second half.</p>
          <p>In Luxury, we're confident too because all the big initiatives that produced the success of that division in Western Europe are now going to be rolled out in North America. So we expect the performance in terms of growth in the <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>In Professional, we're confident because INOA will be driving growth and Matrix, too, is doing well. So I can't give you our forecast about the U.S. economy, that's up to the U.S.A. and others, but we think we can probably outperform the market.</p>
          <p>As for Brazil, pretty good question, ma'am. Brazil is a huge market for beauty. It's a country that is proving to be one of the big players in cosmetics. Now, two categories that are doing well in direct sales, makeup and skincare. Now, I'm going to be in Brazil a few weeks from now and I can tell you what my program is. I'll be talking about how we can have down sales in this market, because nothing is ever sizing in advance and as Brazilian consumers go to the stores to buy a lot of hair care, Brazil is one of the biggest hair care markets and it was probably the largest one because Brazilians very careful about their hair, the use all kinds of essences and ointments. So if they buy those products, I don't see why we couldn't get them to buy skin care products as well. It's our intention, both in skin care and make-up to take control of that market again, which has been demoted to direct sale. So we think we have the way we are certainly to win back some of that matter.</p>
          <p>Now, it's very hard for me to see whose hand is being raised there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am Pierre <mark type="inaudible" /> from <mark type="inaudible" /> Securities. I have a question about the Consumer division in the first half. I'd like to know because you explained that deodorants were being launched in Europe and that was rather expensive in terms of advertising personal spend, but apart from that was there an increase of such costs over the first half? So basically is this a business that has been giving Group increase of 50 basis points. And what's going to happen later because do you think it will be stable over the second half of the year and given existing competition what is likely to be the difference between first and second half in that respect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I'm not going to give you the breakdown by division, but all I can tell you is that in the first half, apart from deodorants launch, the Consumer division was above its level of profitability in first half '09. And with this launch of deodorants, we expect to have profitability around that of last year, which means that excluding deodorants, there has been no slide in profitability. And I want to stress this so there's no misunderstanding, I don't want to say our deodorants are dragging down profitability in Consumer division. No, this is part of our investment strategy. I remember when we launched Fructis in the U.S., the first year, by definition, your profitability is hit, but it's not a problem, it's an investment. And thanks to that, the outcome here is a 500 million U.S. in sales and we are making money. We're very happy. So this is part of the normal investment strategy of any company on a competitive market.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> and very confident and I'm sure this is a market where we'll make money in the future. It's a very important, very significant market, where technology is increasingly key, and therefore, our R&amp;D people can provide high value-added innovations at accessible prices. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pascal Lamy from Reuters. Could you give us more detail in the figures about expected internal growth? And can you give us a forecast of profitability for Saint Laurent Beaut&#xE9;, in particular against the average for the Luxury division? And I have other questions too, but may be I should wait, because it's not really about the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, let's start with that one. Sales, we don't want to give any guidance &#x2013; well, we do and we don't because &#x2013; well, we don't want to because the business context is very uncertain. If you just read newspapers, you come from &#x2013; one day they say that we have no guarantee of recovery and such as &#x2013; It's very difficult to give any guidance over the year in this uncertain business environment. But when we say for example that we think that the cosmetics markets should reach three and 4% and we hope to outperform the market, you can pretty much draw the conclusions about our intentions.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you wanted to ask about Saint Laurent profitability, well, it's improving, thank you, but it will do so gradually. And to be honest, this is a brand where we are still investing. To be absolutely frank, the priority for Saint Laurent is not to drive profitability at all costs. That will be easy, but it wouldn't get us very far. The top priority for Saint Laurent is to turn it into one of the best brands in the world, because we feel, we're convinced that the brand intrinsically has the potential to be one of the best beauty brands in the world.</p>
          <p>So what we are working on, we are investing in fragrances, for example with successful launches in make-up, we are achieving a successful comeback. Next year there will be a new skincare line. It will be very high-tech that will enable Saint Laurent to come back &#x2013; or come, actually, onto the care market and we want to invest into that brand over the next 10 years we will turn it into one of the top 5 luxury global brands and if we do that, if we achieve our target of making YSL a brand that has billions in global sales, that will be our priority.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You talked about men's product in the cosmetics market, that it was a very significant market segment. You said mass-market products should be given priority compared to luxury products, and in Kiehl's, Biotherm or Lanc&#xF4;me you have quite a lot of men's products. Now is that more important for the mass-market segment, number one, and are there possibilities for development for brand such as Garnier for example?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a very relevant question indeed. First of all, for the last 25 years or so we've been trying to launch men's products so &#x2013; and I was disappointed for the last 25 years because every time there were initiatives they were relatively few men buying these products and this was mainly because we were really trying to sell to western men or European men who don't really respond to these kind of initiatives. And the real breakthrough in the male market came from Asia, because Asian men, the Chinese in particular but also Thai men, Indonesian men, Indian men and so on have no taboo in that respect, quite the reverse. They think that they should be taking care of themselves, that it's a normal thing, it's the same as wearing nice clothes and so on. So that's something that's absolutely normal, that is something that happens daily and it's part of their daily routine.</p>
          <p>And that's why we have been speeding up the launches of our male products, and it comes from our Asian experiment, Men Expert became the leading men's brand in China despite the fact that there is harsh competition in that area. We are really in the process of winning the battle and we are going to conquer the world from &#x2013; starting from Asia.</p>
          <p>You were talking about Garnier, there is the launch of Garnier for Men. This will be the Garnier proposal for men, and this product, right, was invented and developed in India. And this is the first time in the history of the Group that a big blockbuster &#x2013; global blockbuster starts from India because it is in India that we find men who have no taboos and who are willing to take care of themselves, so much for the mass-market. Now, quite obviously the biggest potential lies in the mass-market divisions, because there are hundreds, millions of men who really want to take care of their skin, their hair worldwide.</p>
          <p>Now, Luxury Products is the smaller part of the iceberg, but we are doing very well in Luxury Products. We have the leading Luxury Products for men. We also have products in the Lanc&#xF4;me and Kiehl's ranges and we will continue. But we will really speed up and make a lot of progress in the Consumer Products division, regarding products for men, and it could become quite an adventure. I must say that there is a recent shift that gives me a lot of ambition for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have got a follow up question. You were highlighting your very strong growth in Brazil, a market where you arguably are very well established for many years. Now when I compare this growth rate like-for-like to China, also there is a strong 14% in China, it almost pales a little bit against the Latin American market, against Brazil. Is it because Brazil, the strong momentum is particular to this year, particular to this time or unsustainable, or is it that something is holding back growth in China? I am just comparing the 2 numbers and it strikes me that one of the 2 numbers might not continue in the same way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know honestly. I don't know if you can just, again, if you take one number 6-month, 6 months doesn't make a trend for the rest of the life. First, China is much bigger. Our business in China is much bigger than our business in Brazil. It is 2 times or 2.5 times bigger, number 1.</p>
          <p>Number 2, the history of the growth in China has been quite steady, and I have to admit that the history of the growth in Brazil has not been that steady. So maybe I would say that plus 21 or 22 in Brazil on the first 6 months is not something that I can guarantee that we are going to sustain for the next 10 years.</p>
          <p>But it's &#x2013; no, I would say that it's more in Brazil a kind of comeback, comeback, we have a new team, new initiatives, successful initiatives, and the country also is on a roll. Honestly, the Brazil of today has nothing to do with the Brazil of 5 years ago or 10 years ago or 15 years ago. The economy is on a roll. The consumption is on a roll. So we are taking advantage of that. I don't think that you can extrapolate more than this. But it's a positive element.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That growth in China, you know growth in China is still good. It's true that there have been many articles saying that doing business in China is maybe not as easy as it was before, and it's probably true. But what we see is that our brands are well-positioned and that we should take advantage of the potential of the market. What has a little bit, maybe, hindered the development in the China has been that there has been a change in the regulatory, how do you say, measures in the past 6 months and most of the launches has been frozen for us, like for our competition because of the new regulations. And so definitely this is slowing down for a while, the development of our brands in the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. [Foreign Language] I promise you that we will leave you a few minutes for the very fascinating matter that you want to talk about. What &#x2013; when should we close, Christian? When should we close this meeting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At 10.15.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'd rather have a few questions more on the actual business, on the financial figures, interesting in the case of L'Oreal. Please go ahead. Any question on our business would be welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Reuters. This is a question about your investment in sanofi-aventis, and I was wondering if you continue to be happy with that investment. If you have a better timeline on if and when you decide to sell those shares, and what do you think about their bid on Genzyme.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It's going to be an easy answer. I don't want to comment and I cannot comment on their management decisions, number one. We are &#x2013; I think we can say that we are a happy investor, well, at least loyal investor, we would be more happy if the stock price was higher. But we are &#x2013; we have been a loyal investor for a very long time and we still are. And we have no plans whatsoever for the short-term.</p>
          <p>Our position is exactly the same it was one year ago, 2 years ago, 3 years ago. We have said that it is not a strategic investment for the very long future, but that on the other side, we're also a loyal investor and a stable one. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Securities. You talked about the gross margin of gross profit in the first half, there was a strong increase. Do you think it's going to be as stable throughout the entire year, just like you said? Which means that for the second half we'll have somewhat more negative elements fitting into this gross profit. What about your purchases, especially the raw materials, procurements, advertising and promotion items, there have been considerable deflation items over the previous year. Do you see that there is an increase in prices, which means that you are going to be very careful regarding the gross margin in the second half? And more generally speaking, there's the price function; was it significant in the first half? Would it be more relevant in the second half despite the fact that there is very harsh competition from Procter &amp; Gamble? These are rather wide ranging topics, I am sorry, but could you please shed some light on them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would suggest that Christian explain to you, once again, the reason why we feel that the gross margin won't be quite as good in the second half as it was in the first. It's a mechanical reason which has &#x2013; is unrelated to the fact to how good we are and how good our performance is. But it's a bit complicated, so Christian is going to explain to you the currency effect, the change in the consolidation of foreign exchanges on the actual rate of gross profit. It's a mathematical equation, has nothing to do with our actual level of performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, what we've indicated is not that we were expecting gross margin to be stable, we were expecting gross profit to be slightly higher, which is a bit different from what you're saying. Now, the reason is as follows.</p>
          <p>As a company, we only have 32% of our sales in euros, which means by nature we are strongly exposed to the variation of our consolidation currency compared to the other currencies. The vast majority of other currencies, except Venezuela and Argentina, these currencies have improved their position against the euro, which is a very positive for L'Or&#xE9;al in terms of absolute value in terms of sales, in terms of earnings, but it has a slightly negative impact. It dilutes some of our ratios to a certain extent, and the gross margin ratio is one of them.</p>
          <p>And I have given you a figure. In the second half &#x2013; the gross profit for the second half of 2010, if you take the first &#x2013; if you take the gross margin of the second half of 2009, 70.7%, and if you calculate it with the current consolidation rates, $1.30 for &#x20AC;1, we get 70 basis points less. So this is the major effect or impact, which means that we have to be very careful when it comes to establishing our gross profit for the entire year. So conversion effect has nothing to do with how expensive the raw materials are, has nothing to do with the actual productivity of our plans, or actually the specialization level of our plans. It is because of the combination of our gross profits outside of the Euro zone.</p>
          <p>So much for the technical aspects of Mr. Agon, but deep down we are very happy about what we've achieved in terms of actual gross profit. And as you've mentioned, on purchases we've improved, made a lot of improvements on our purchases. We grouped our buying centers, procurement centers. We now have achieved major gains across all these areas because of optimization. It is true that here and there, there are some raw materials that have gotten very expensive, but we are not worried at all regarding the second half.</p>
          <p>Now, as regards the value level, I think that that's what you were referring to, some companies have referred to lower prices. But if I read carefully, these companies are working across several categories which are not ours, they are working in other lines of business. And it's more in the other lines of business that are not competing with ours, that they could see that there were drops in raw materials or prices. In the cosmetics markets we can't say that there is &#x2013; there was no deflationary change in the market in this first &#x2013; during this first half. And we had a positive value effect for the first half, which is not quite as high, granted, as it was last year, but it's still 0.7, and it's a value effect which is still positive, satisfactory. The good news is that volumes have picked up in a big way, which is a source of satisfaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Harold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to everyone. Since we are on the subject, Christian, on the gross profit on the currencies and the fixed impact effect also, can you explain how the hedging strategy will impact the actual margins of the Group? You are hedging the difference in costs between the subsidiaries. So how hard an impact does it have? Just to be sure that I understand correctly. I want to keep things simple.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The hedging strategy of the Group is to hedge a very significant part of the future flows for the year to come, and this is something we've done for the last 15 or 20 years. We don't want to speculate. We don't want to take positions at a time when we consider that the dollar or the pound is doing well, simply because we want to do away with one of the variables which is highly volatile in the P&amp;L of our subsidiaries so that the Directors of subsidiaries can work on volumes, prices, and their actual launching programs, which are the important items.</p>
          <p>From the accounting standpoint, it means that some years we will make more money, other times we'll lose money. To be more precise, at the end of June of 2009, we had an exchange gain of &#x20AC;35 million and at the end of June 2010, we had an exchange loss of &#x20AC;30 million and 95%, pretty much all of this exchange gains and losses are now reflected in the gross margin because it is part of the different flows. And this is something that you requested me to do, you know, to put it in the accounts some three, four years ago. Hopefully this is answering your question.</p>
          <p>Any further questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no more questions on the business side of things. Maybe we'll have to turn to other matters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, are there any questions on anything else? Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, just now...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A bit louder please, otherwise I can't hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you were saying just now that regarding <mark type="inaudible" /> you were waiting before speaking to the judiciary, I mean I want to know what the effects of the case have been so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I can't really say I have to ask team members, I think. My statement on this and I don't say much about it so pay attention to what I have to say now; what I have to say about it is that the Bettencourt affair, whilst very regrettable, does not have an impact on the company's bottom-line and I think if there are any doubts about that the figures that we are now producing corroborate this, that's the first thing.</p>
          <p>Secondly, if you like, once again there is family feud which we find highly regrettable because we're honestly deeply attached to this founding family, don't forget that that's who they are. But there is a company here, &#x20AC;20 billion, a world champion in its business, operating in six countries and 60,000 workforce doing its job, doing its business, working calmly and seriously and fully focused on major corporate mission of winning billion new consumers and focused also on its main objective, which is offering the best cosmetics to men and women around the world. That's it, really. I can't say anything more. And as for the contract, well, I made my comment a little earlier on that. Yes, go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But not the same question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] On this contract, you said that it was an unfounded claim, so we are saying that there is a contract and there is some doubt as to whether it corresponds to any service by Mr. Banier. You're saying the claim is unfounded, so exactly what is the service that is worth 700,000 a year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, listen, I said that I would answer the authorities. I won't give all the reasons here, but if I say that this claim is unfounded, it's because there was a genuine service provided by Mr. Banier. Other questions? From Emmanuel, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we can perhaps take a different approach to this, because obviously we are bothering you with &#x2013; well it's bothering. You have lots of questions about the Bettencourt affair. This question of Nestl&#xE9;'s holding, it's coming up. But, isn't the idea to get rid of the major shareholders, diluting those with an acquisition that will completely transform the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's hard to answer. Maybe I can confirm this. The first thing which is that all the staff members and lot of you know people in L'Or&#xE9;al and you can confirm that first and foremost, they are people who are passionate about their business, excited by their jobs as they have genuine passion for their brands and their assignments and the whole company is fully focused on its corporate objectives. And we don't want to upset that applecart, that's the main thing. And at the end of the day, my job, if you like, it comes down to it, is to ensure that this continues and see that the company continues to prosper. We celebrated our centenary last year. The company has, I think, now got a new lease on life, a new mission, renewed energy and my job is to make sure that all these vital energies in our workforce channeled in the right direction. I think that's what everyone wants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but could this be done, what I was talking about, or is there no point talking about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Emmanuel, I can't give you an answer to that, can I? All done? Shall we leave it at that, then, or is there one -? Yes, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't really have a question, Mr. Agon. Speak up a bit, Mr. Agon. You asked about <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, it's a good and bad news sort of bittersweet, but I think sweeter and bitter. This is the last meeting of Caroline Millot, now probably there are people here for the first time who don't know Caroline. But Caroline is really the jewel in the crown, a monument, although that's perhaps not that flattering. So, his is the last time that Caroline will be at these meetings, and in fact we will go out and toast her a glass of something. Of course, she is going to move on to well-deserved retirement. It's possible that we will replace her and I think you've got something ready in that respect, haven't you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Caroline. This is your last meeting, Caroline, after 13 years which we appreciated your professionality and hard work. We're here to say goodbye and there is nothing better than a little retrospective for that.</p>
          <p>We know that there has been a tradition of visiting subsidiaries, which enables us to get to know them, and New Markets, Brazil, China. Now for the third time [Ends Abruptly].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>