<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1368535" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7795</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Jean-Paul Agon, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jean R&#xE9;gis Carof, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Christian Mulliez, Executive Vice President, Administration and Finance</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Jean-Jacques Lebel, President, Consumer Products Division</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Marc Menesguen, Managing Director, Strategic Marketing</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Nicolas Hieronimus, Managing Director, Luxury Products Division</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Brigitte Liberman, General Manager, Active Cosmetics</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Guillaume Delmas</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Simon Marshall-Lockyer</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Pierre Lamelin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Pablo Zuanic</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Shamina Bhaidjy</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to this meeting for the presentation of the 2010 results. I would like to begin by introducing not only those who are seated with me here but all of the other members of the Steering Committee of the group. I will begin with the people on the podium.</p>
          <p>To my right Jean-Jacques Lebel for Consumer Products; Marc Menesguen for Luxury Products, who is taking on the responsibility of Strategic Marketing, I hope you will have questions to ask him on the scope of this new mission; Brigitte Liberman, who is the Head of the Active Cosmetics Division. To my right Christian Mulliez, whom you know well, in-charge of Finances; and Nicolas Hieronimus, who was the Head of the Professional Products Division, and who since the 1st of January has now taken over from Marc and is the Head of the Luxury Products Division.</p>
          <p>In the room, we have Laurent Attal, who is the new Head of Research and Innovation for the L'Or&#xE9;al group. An Verhulst is the new Head of the Professional Products Division. We did not asked An to present the 2010 results, since she was not really responsible for that but she was the Head of the North American branch, which accounts for about 40% of the profits of the group. And Sara Ravella is the new Head of Communications and our Head of Operations. Beatrice Dautresme is the Head of External Relations and she is with us up until the end of February. And we have the &#x2013; you have Jochen Zaumseil, Head of Asia Pacific, our areas of conquest. And Geoff Skingsley, whom I forgot, is Head of Human Resources and both go together of course. And Alexandre Popoff is the boss for Latin America and Africa and the Middle East. And Frederic Roz&#xE9; is not here today because he is in New York. You know that in the United States you waste no time in doing business, so he is over there.</p>
          <p>So you have the whole team. We're going to begin the meeting. And as usual, I will ask Jean R&#xE9;gis to explain to us about the practical arrangements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies. Good morning, gentlemen. As usual, before beginning the presentations, I would like to remind you of a few practical details regarding the meeting. You'll have found when you entered the room headphones for interpretation. The channels for the two languages available are shown on the middle screen. I suggest that you switch now to the channel of your choice. The entrance hall to this room is equipped with WiFi antennas to enable you, if you wish to connect with the outside world from the entrance hall. So while you are in this auditorium, please make sure now that your cell phones are switched off.</p>
          <p>At the entrance to the room, you were given the booklets with the figures that Mr. Mulliez will be commenting and Mr. Agon's booklet will be &#x2013; with the tables will be distributed during the break. There are many of you attending this meeting and several of you are in the second room, which will be treated absolutely in the same way as this one, especially during the question-and-answer part.</p>
          <p>I would like to ask Suzie <mark type="inaudible" /> who is next door, in the second room, to tell us whether she can hear us well and whether everything is okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we hear you well and everything is okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. So, thank you, Suzie. On your seat, you will also have found a card on which you may ask your questions initially in writing. Do not hesitate to do so. The hostesses will be passing around during the presentations to pick up your question cards. Of course, after the break, you will also be able to ask your questions orally whether you are in room one or two. However, please state your name and company before asking your question.</p>
          <p>The whole of this meeting will be broadcast live or is being broadcast live on your dedicated Web site, loreal-finance.com and will be available again &#x2013; all the presentations will be available later on this afternoon. And finally, light food and drinks will be served as usual in the lounges upstairs. You're invited to go there following the presentations and Mr. Agon and the Vice Presidents will be meeting you there. Thank you for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean R&#xE9;gis. Well, as usual, we are going to begin with Christian who will be presenting the results for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to everyone. This presentation of the 2010 financial results of L'Or&#xE9;al will include information concerning sales, profit, cash flow trend, of course, the balance sheet situation and the dividend growth.</p>
          <p>Consolidated sales amounted to &#x20AC;19.496 billion, an increase of 6% at constant exchange rates. Like-for-like, sales increased by 5.6%. The structural effect is slightly positive at 0.4%. It mainly reflects the acquisition of Professional Products distributors in the United States: Maly's Midwest, Marshall, Sullivan and Peel's.</p>
          <p>After an exchange effect, which was positive, at plus 5.6%, growth based on reported figures came out at plus 11.6%, i.e., the strongest growth rate in the last 10 years. As far as the exchange effect is concerned, it is difficult to forecast what it will be in 2011. I can tell you however that at current exchange rate that is, for example, with &#x20AC;1 at U.S.$1.36, the effect should be close to nil in 2011.</p>
          <p>All the major currencies contributed in 2010 to the positive exchange effect, the U.S. dollar at around 5%, the pound sterling at around 4%, the Chinese yuan at 5.8%, and with a record increase in 2010 the Brazilian real at plus 18.4%. We should note that in 2010 the euro represented 30.7% of overall sales compared with 34.2% of sales in 2009. And five years ago in 2005, the euro represented still almost 40% of overall group sales.</p>
          <p>Let us now look at the like-for-like sales growth by branch and division. Professional Products sales increased by 4.1%; Consumer Products sales grew by 5.5%; Luxury Products sales are at plus 7%, a very strong increase compared with 2009; and Active Cosmetics is at plus 4.7%. The Body Shop comes out at minus 1.1% and dermatology, that is, Galderma posted another year of double-digit growth at plus 16.1%.</p>
          <p>The results by geographic zones now, all the zones achieved sales growth with Western Europe at plus 1.7%, North America at plus 4.1%, and finally, the so-called New Markets, which posted another year of double-digit growth at plus 11.3%. The New Markets accounted for some 37% of cosmetic sales in 2010 compared with 33% in 2009.</p>
          <p>In 2011, the New Markets could become the number one zone for the L'Or&#xE9;al group's cosmetic branch at current exchange rate. Amongst the New Markets, Asia-Pacific recorded strong growth at plus 11.2%, and growth excluding Japan was even stronger at plus 13.2% and the same applies to Latin America at plus 17.5% and it even rose to plus 32.6% based on reported figures. Of course, we're talking here about the exchange impact. Eastern Europe came out at plus 8.1%, with strong growth in Russia and more contrasting trends in Central Europe. And finally, Africa and the Middle East posted growth of plus 4.1%.</p>
          <p>Here is now a close-up of the BRIC countries, which generated a growth rate of around 15%. And three of them have recorded sales of at least &#x20AC;700 million to-date, which means that at L'Or&#xE9;al, they are close to the size of the major European countries and they are now amongst the top 10 subsidiaries of our subsidiaries. Note the speculator growth of India, which is going from strength to strength at plus 32% like-for-like.</p>
          <p>This table is particularly interesting in our view. We're talking here about the sales by business segment. As you can see, L'Or&#xE9;al is concentrated on five major categories. All of them recorded positive growth in 2010, with particularly strong advances for skin care and make-up. On the last line, you can also see the emergence of deodorants, within the hygiene category, showing a growth rate of plus 15.8%.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to the profit and loss account and let us begin by analyzing gross profit. Gross profit increased by 12.1% and came out at 70.8% of sales, compared with 70.5% in 2009. This represents an improvement of 30 basis points, which really corresponds to what we had indicated to you at the end of August, when we said that we were expecting for the full year 2010 a slight improvement of our gross margin.</p>
          <p>There are several factors which had a favorable impact. Amongst which and in decreasing order of importance, we have the significant improvement in the cost of goods achieved in particular from the strong growth in volumes and good performances in raw materials and packaging item purchasing. Second factor, better inventory management, which led to a reduction in provisions for obsolete and slow moving inventories. Third element, the reduction in physical distribution costs.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, two factors had an unfavorable impact on this item and I quote them also here in decreasing order of significance. First one is the impact of changes in monetary parities. To illustrate this point, the negative impact of the conversion effect alone amounted to 50 basis points over the full year.</p>
          <p>To express this more clearly, the 2009 gross profits calculating using the 2010 conversion tables would have come out at 70% and not 70.5% as reported. At constant exchange rates, the improvement in gross profit is therefore very substantial. The second factor which had an unfavorable impact was the moderate increase in customer allowances, which, as you know, are deducted from sales if you apply the IFRS standards. So there is an impact obviously on the gross margin, so much for the gross margin.</p>
          <p>Research and development expenses increased by 9.1% and accounted for 3.4% of overall sales. Like-for-like, the R&amp;D expenses, of which three quarters are allocated in the Euro zone increased by 8.9%, that is, more than the sales, which grew by 5.6% like-for-like. This new advance illustrates why the strategic decision was taken to make significant investment in research.</p>
          <p>Advertising and promotion expenses came out at 30.9% of overall sales, in line with the indications we gave you when the first half results were published. I would remind you that advertising and promotion expenses are not just media costs. They reflect a variety of realities depending on the divisions and commercial channels concerned. In the Professional Products Division, for example, technical training for hair dressers and salon merchandising. In the Consumer Products Division, we have media and merchandising expenses and point-of-sales initiatives.</p>
          <p>In the Luxury Products Division, we have media expenses across the beauty advisers, merchandising and samples. And finally, at Active Cosmetics, it has to do with the cost of medical reps, media expenses and merchandising in pharmacies.</p>
          <p>Selling, general and administrative expenses grew significantly less rapidly than sales, at plus 2.7% based on a comparable structure and identical exchange rate, plus 2.7%, which is an increase of 60 basis points compared with 2009. Overall operating profit came out at &#x20AC;3,057 million, an increase of 18.6% representing a significant improvement in profitability compared with 2009, that is plus 90 basis points.</p>
          <p>Just a few words about the P&amp;L by half year. As you know, at L'Or&#xE9;al, the running of the divisions and zones is based on an annual timeframe, and therefore, it is never possible to extrapolate from half year results. However, we can tell you that in the second half of 2010, currency fluctuations had a more negative impact than in the first half of 2010 on gross profit expressed as a percentage of sales.</p>
          <p>Here again, we are talking about the conversion effect that I mentioned before, which was really focused on the second half of the year. As with SG&amp;As, they were again improving in the second half of 2010 compared with the second half of 2009, even though the improvement was less spectacular than in the first half of 2010 because of the lower comparison base at the end of 2009. Overall, the second half operating profit also grew very substantially at plus 15.3%, following the first half growth rate at plus 21.4%.</p>
          <p>Operating profit of branches and divisions; all the divisions achieved growth in their operating profitability, particularly the Luxury Products Division from 15.1% to 17.5%. Some other points are worth noting, for example, the decline in non-allocated expenses, central costs at 2.8% of sales; the continuing recovery of The Body Shop at 8.7% of overall sales and income, and further improvement in the profitability of Galderma at 19.8%.</p>
          <p>Operating profit per geographic zone; all zones recorded an improvement in profitability. Western Europe at 21.6% of overall sales compared with 21% in 2009. Thanks to better organizational efficiency; North America, following the strong rebound at 16.5% compared with 14.5%; and the new markets, which continued with their growth at 16.9% compared with 16.4% in 2009.</p>
          <p>From operating profit to net profit excluding non-recurrent items, which is the basis for calculation of our net earning per share. Financial costs have been reduced. The net finance costs fell substantially to &#x20AC;35.6 million. This sharp reduction is mainly the result of the very significant decrease in our net debt.</p>
          <p>For 2011, all other things being equal, the finance costs will be close to probably &#x20AC;10 million. Sanofi dividends amounted to &#x20AC;284 million, an increase of 9.1%. Tax amounted to &#x20AC;932 million, representing a rate of 28.2%, slightly above the 2009 rate, which was 27.3%.</p>
          <p>For 2011, we can at this stage of the year even though it's still very early on to say anything about this item, we can anticipate a rate in the order of 28%. Once again, all other things being equal, 28% is figure. Net profit, excluding non-recurrent items, came out at &#x20AC;2,371 million, an increase of 18.7%. Net earnings per share, at &#x20AC;4.01, increased by 17.2%.</p>
          <p>You can see this on the last line. You should note that the number of shares used for the calculation of the net earning per share at 591 million shares was slightly higher than what had been anticipated. This is partly the result of the exercise of stock options in the second half of 2010, but above all, the result of the IFRS method, which consists in allowing for a theoretical, additional number of shares, which could be created in the future as a result of the possible exercise of stock options.</p>
          <p>To illustrate this point, based on the current L'Or&#xE9;al share price, that is &#x20AC;87 or &#x20AC;88 or &#x20AC;89 and all other things being equal, a diluted average number of shares of between 598 million and 600 million should be taken into account for 2011.</p>
          <p>Let us now look at the end of the consolidated profit and loss account after allowing some non-recurrent items, which amounted to a charge, net of tax, of &#x20AC;131 million. Net profit amounted to &#x20AC;2,240 million, an increase of 25%. The non-recurrent items consisted of, first of all, depreciation of intangible assets amounting to &#x20AC;42 million, net. Secondly, provisions, relating to investigations by competition authorities amounting to &#x20AC;79 million. Most of this item was already set aside in the first half of 2010, and finally, some supplementary items for restructuring programs amounting to &#x20AC;8 million net.</p>
          <p>Let us look now at the cash flow statement. Cash flow or gross cash flow amounted to &#x20AC;3,171 million, an increase of 15%. In the depreciation, amortization and provisions item in this statement, depreciation and amortization declined slightly from &#x20AC;781 million in 2009 to &#x20AC;768 million in 2010. Provisions, which amounted to a net charge of &#x20AC;53 million in 2009, amounted to a net reversal of &#x20AC;34 million in 2010. The difference, results mainly from the provisions corresponding to the implementation of restructuring costs and the ongoing process of prudently strengthening the financing of our pension funds. There was a very positive change in working capital, as it was reduced in 2010 for the second consecutive year, by &#x20AC;132 million. Inventories increased slightly as a percentage of overall sales. On the other hand, trade accounts receivable improved, once again, this year.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure continued to be contained, at 3.5% of sales for 2011. A slight increase in this percentage may be expected probably to around 4% of sales. After dividend payment and purchases of acquisitions, which I will remind you correspond to the acquisitions of Professional Products distributors in the United States, and allowing for the exercise of options, the residual cash flow comes out at &#x20AC;1,981 million.</p>
          <p>The balance sheet now. We have here a balance sheet structure as you can see on the screen now, which is very robust. As shareholders' equity represent 61% of total assets there, increased compared with year end 2009 is the result of the balance between on the positive side profit for the period and the cumulative translation adjustments, because of the positive foreign exchange impact, and on the negative side, the valuation of the Sanofi-Aventis shares and the payment of dividends by L'Or&#xE9;al.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the gearing, the year end 2010 net financial debt comes out as a very small amount &#x20AC;41 million, which is lower than what we were expecting even six months ago, and this is partly because of the further improvement in working capital this year. The net gearing is close to zero, as you can see.</p>
          <p>Few words about the dividend, the dividend to be proposed to the Annual General Meeting on the 22nd of April will be &#x20AC;1.80 per share, representing 20% growth compared with 2009. And this increase in the dividend corresponds to a new increase in the pay-out ratio, which comes out now at almost 45% this year, indicating L'Or&#xE9;al's constant concern to implement a balanced and dynamic policy vis-&#xE0;-vis shareholders. Thank you for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations. Christian, thank you very much. Now as usual, we are going to be presenting to you what generates all these numbers because these figures are the result of all of our action in the area of research, product innovation, launches, conquest campaigns around the world. And we are going to begin with the Consumer Products Division and Jean-Jacques will be telling us about the conquest of 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to everyone. The Consumer Products Division achieved growth of 5.5% in 2010, after growing by 3.2% in 2009. In the different parts of the world, on this chart, you can see the split of the growth. In Western Europe, where growth is back plus 1.3%, with &#x20AC;3,665 million; in North America, plus 4.7%, and growth has speeded up nicely over the second semester, and &#x20AC;3,698 million, plus 10.7% in the new markets, the zone which became the number one zone of the division in 2010.</p>
          <p>Within these new markets, we can note that all the BRIMC countries have shown double-digit growth, all of them, Brazil plus 22.5, Russia plus 10.4, India plus 31.3, Mexico plus 11.4, and China plus 12.3.</p>
          <p>And finally, among our top six countries, three are emerging or growth countries, China, Brazil and Russia. In terms of market share, these increases in turnover are translated into market share gains in all regions. You may remember that there was a drop in market share in Western Europe in 2009. In 2010, we stabilized market shares upwards with increases in countries such as the UK, Germany, and Scandinavia, a slight drop in France and in Italy and a more significant drop in Portugal and Greece. With gains on important categories such as make-up, haircare, deodorants, and a slight drop on styling and colourants. So as you see, there are differences across Western Europe, but the overall result is good in a market with the growth rate next to zero.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., in a market estimated at plus 1.2%, our sales have grown by 5.6%, so that is to say more than four times the market, with strong gains in make-up, colourants, and haircare and a slight drop in skincare. In the new markets, our growth is also superior to the market, in particular, in Asia, Latin America, and the Middle East.</p>
          <p>Our three brands show growth; L'Or&#xE9;al Paris plus 2.8%, Garnier plus 5.7%, Maybelline 13.3%. There are two significant highlights for L'Or&#xE9;al Paris, the launch of Youth Code in Europe. The U.S. are launching at the moment and here's the film.</p>
          <p>[Video Presentation]</p>
          <p>And the shampoo Els&#xE8;ve, collagen Elvive hydrated curls collagen for curly hair, for which you can see the press advertising. And Garnier, the extension of deodorants with Mineral for Men in Eastern Europe, and Pure Active, which has allowed us to take first place in Europe in the care for problem with skin markets. Here's the film for the Pure Active Exfo-Brusher.</p>
          <p>[Video Presentation]</p>
          <p>The top prize goes to Maybelline. The growth of 13.2% is probably the largest growth of any Consumer Products brand worldwide and merits a special focus on the brand and the market. The make-up market is one of the markets, which has best resisted the economic crisis. Our broader studies and our psychological experts have shown the anti-luminous effect of make-up and the need to feel good and take care of one's look even in times of crisis. The most dynamic categories over the last two years have been foundation and eye make-up. At the same time, the fashion is for color, the nail polish market is exploding, and lipstick is making a comeback, all of this is shown into the figures.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., the market has grown by 5% versus the total beauty market of 1.2% and in Europe by 3.5% versus the total market showing zero growth. In the new markets, it is one of the most dynamic sectors. Our nail polishes in Latin America are at plus 40% for the year. Maybelline has launched innovations in all categories. Here is the advertising for SuperStay 24 Hr Lip Color, one of the most significant innovations.</p>
          <p>[Video Presentation]</p>
          <p>In Asia, the big phenomenon is the BB Cream, already a star product in Japan and Taiwan and in China. This is the product that does everything, half skincare, half make-up, it protects from the sun, hydrates, tightens up pores, covers imperfections, serves as a base for make-up etcetera. Here is one of the Chinese films.</p>
          <p>[Video Presentation]</p>
          <p>Probably, the most interesting point is that the product introduces new consumers to the use of make-up and allows us to develop the market.</p>
          <p>So to conclude on make-up which I remind you is the number one category for the Consumer Products Division, with the market shares of Maybelline and L'Or&#xE9;al Paris combining to give us closer to 30% of the market worldwide. We are not only undisputedly number one, but also the only company to have worldwide brands which are capable of seizing the opportunities that arise in all corners of the planet. For example, this Lasting Drama gel eyeliner invented in Japan and sold all over the world.</p>
          <p>I will now take a more detailed look at the emerging country. First of all the growth, I have spoken about the growth in the five biggest countries. In the column to the right are five others which are also showing strong growth, where our brands are establishing themselves and which are the growth areas of the future. In the Middle East, we are moving forward with Garnier. In the Philippines and Indonesia, we have launched L'Or&#xE9;al shampoo.</p>
          <p>Now for the product, in order to gain a billion additional customers &#x2013; consumers, we are of course launching our major brands or international ideas, but now we are also inventing products in these countries, which can then be marketed internationally.</p>
          <p>The case of Total Repair 5, which was the key, which allowed us to open the door to L'Or&#xE9;al shampoo in India, and in South East Asia, which was invented in Brazil. The Garnier Mineral deodorants, which were invented for the Russian market and which are now available in India, South Africa and Western Europe.</p>
          <p>And finally Garnier Men, which was invented in India and is now sold into rest of Asia. This will be the case more-and-more often. Thanks to our knowledge of consumer needs and our local development laboratory, which will enable us to create new products.</p>
          <p>Along with this, we now have an industrial savoir-faire that allows us to produce our products in the excessibly priced formats requested across all categories by our consumers in these countries and aiming to gradually reach 1 billion additional consumers.</p>
          <p>Here you can see three sachets that contain between two and five applications of product. Of course we are going to continue along this track in 2011 and do better in several areas.</p>
          <p>Here are our objectives for 2011. Continue to launch innovative products; renew our attack on the markets with L'Or&#xE9;al Paris, we want to more than double growth versus 2010 for L'Or&#xE9;al Paris.</p>
          <p>And you will see in future advertisements, a new breath of creativity, which shows that more than ever the number one beauty brand in the world is desirable and up-to-date.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, we wish to develop our categories across all our target groups, men, seniors, young people.</p>
          <p>Fourthly, gaining market share in Western Europe by successfully executing points one, two and there.</p>
          <p>Five, continue the geographic expansion of our brand. And lastly maintain our stand on business drivers.</p>
          <p>Now as a preview of 2011, L'Or&#xE9;al Paris make-up will launch this fantastic new mascara Lash Architect 4D. The results of our research and development in Japan and the fibres in mascara have allowed us to produce the best mascara that L'Or&#xE9;al Paris has ever made and here's the film.</p>
          <p>[Video Presentation]</p>
          <p>And the Infallible foundation with brush applicator, its gives incomparably uniform coverage. Alongside EverPure and EverStrong in the U.S., L'Or&#xE9;al Paris is launching the EverSleek range.</p>
          <p>I remind you that these products sold at $7 are an important dominization of the haircare market. And everywhere the colorant mousse, Sublime mousse, a very interesting step forward in terms of ease of application.</p>
          <p>For men there is the latest launch from L'Or&#xE9;al Men Expert the <mark type="inaudible" /> Gel. Garnier will have a strong start to 2011 with a new initiative in body care Intensive Seven Day Replenishing Lotion with Bifidus.</p>
          <p>Maybelline will launch a new foundation range FIT ME, and a new Volum' Express One by One mascara for which I want to show you the film.</p>
          <p>[Video Presentation]</p>
          <p>And finally, in order to take advantage of the massive growth of this very profitable market, we're launching on to the mass market, the SE range of professional nail varnishes that we bought in 2010. So we are extremely confident that our innovations, our brand and the strength of our teams will allow us to achieve a very successful year 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Jean-Jacques.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>That sounds &#x2013; that's really fascinating. We're now going to go to a very different world, the world of luxury and I'll hand over to Marc, Marc Menesguen will be telling us about the luxury division in 2010. Over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to everyone. 2010 marked a return to growth for the Luxury Products Division on every continent. The Luxury segment is back. As we had sensed a year ago, the Luxury beauty market bounced back in 2010, with according to our estimates consumer sales up plus 5.5%. In this resurgent market, our division consolidated its global market shares with like-for-like growth of 7% and published growth of 11.5%.</p>
          <p>Broken down into publication regions growth stood at plus 1.9% in Western Europe, with consumer sales in line with the market. We remained the market leader and we have boosted our market share across Europe to almost 20%, way ahead of our nearest competitor. Plus 4.5% in North America, we made the most of the recovery in this part of the world, although our consumer sales are slightly below the market baseline.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we grew by more than 14.9% in the new market. These strategic countries which already account for almost 20% of our turnover are becoming increasingly open to Luxury product. And we have reinforced our position as the number one in these markets.</p>
          <p>In Asia, we are growing one and half times faster than the competition with excellent results in Korea, Hong Kong and China, where we are the market leaders with a 27% market share.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, we are progressing fast in a market that remain very stable. We are now gaining ground on the competition in the region as is the case in the Middle East where sales are &#x2013; have risen steadily.</p>
          <p>Lastly, L'Or&#xE9;al's Luxury product posted strong financial results for 2010. Our operating income gained 250 basis points, plus 25% on the like-for-like basis and reached 17.5% of turnover.</p>
          <p>2010 is also a pivotal year for our brand and a year in which our portfolio strategy was clarified. Our three key brands, Lanc&#xF4;me, Giorgio Armani and Yves Saint Laurent accounted for 60% of our business. These three prestigious global and multi-segment brands are gaining ground and modernizing.</p>
          <p>For Lanc&#xF4;me, the world's number one luxury brand, synonymous with femininity in every country of the world. 2010 was a year of renewal as illustrated by its strong worldwide growth of plus 8%.</p>
          <p>Lanc&#xF4;me found a new spark of magic in 2010. Thanks to the beauty and sensitivity of some exceptional women, three great actresses, Julia Roberts, Kate Winslet and Pen&#xE9;lope Cruz.</p>
          <p>Lanc&#xF4;me has also confirmed its position as an innovation leader with significant progress made in the area of skincare. Thanks to the success of G&#xE9;nifique. The first skincare product based on generic signs, which has doubled its sales in only second year of existence.</p>
          <p>The brand success was also done to increase sales of its key Luxury skincare product Absolue Precious Cells a combination of 20 years of stem cell research; its success has been global.</p>
          <p>Another major event was the launch by Lanc&#xF4;me, the world's number one seductive make-up brand of Teint Miracle, a revolutionary formula that recreates the skin's inner light. Since its launch, Teint Miracle has already become number one in France, Italy and Germany and has recently received the prestigious Marie-Claire Prix d'Excellence award.</p>
          <p>And to celebrate its 20th year, Tr&#xE9;sor is being launched afresh with a new advertising campaign. The irresistible charm of Penelope Cruz pushed sales of our legendary perfume to new levels, capping off a great year for Lanc&#xF4;me.</p>
          <p>Yves Saint Laurent, our haute couture brand epitomizing French audacity and elegance, 2010 marked something of a renaissance with two figure global growth. Thanks mainly to the new found vitality of its women's perfumes. The brand reinvented the legendary Opium perfume to create Belle d'Opium, a modern oriental embodied by a mesmerizing Melanie Thierry. But also thanks to the dramatic return of Saint Laurent's fetish color with the launch of Rouge Pur Couture, the color of heroines, a potent weapon of seduction that joins other iconic stalwarts such as Touche &#xC9;clat and Volume Effet Faux Cils Mascara.</p>
          <p>The global growth potential of Yves Saint Laurent make-up is considerable. The brand is also highly attractive to men as demonstrated by the rise in sales of L'Homme et La Nuit de L'Homme fragrances in 2010. I am convinced that Yves Saint Laurent will one day become one of the five top brands in the world as it already is the case in France.</p>
          <p>Giorgio Armani, our high Luxury brand inspired by Italy's great designer, 2010 was a year of growth driven by a winning strategy. Our main priority was to reinforce investments in the two historical cornerstones of the brand, Acqua di Gio and Code Homme; the number one and number three men's perfumes in the world, respectively. These fragrances seem to have limitless appeal. We also launched the new women's perfume Acqua di Gioia or Essence of Joy, the portrait of a striking and modern women and an initiatory voyage into sublime nature. It is already Armani's bestselling brand perfume and was one of the perfumery sector's great success within 2010.</p>
          <p>Lastly 2010 saw the rapid rise of Giorgio Armani Beauty carried by the success of Rouge d'Armani, a jewel of current sophistication. And the Eyes to Kill mascara as embodied by the stunning Megan Fox, who is now the face of the brand.</p>
          <p>Another asset of the brand's beauty range is skincare with the launch of Regenessence, a highly innovative anti-ageing product, inspired by regenerative medicine. As you can see the Giorgio Armani brand is better equipped than ever to conquer the world.</p>
          <p>2010 was also a crucial year for Kiehl's, the New Year's modern apothecary. Kiehl's has become a major global brand, and it is now present in 37 countries. It experienced tremendous sales growth in 2010 around the world at plus 43%. Kiehl's is driven by strong values when it comes to performance, but also in terms of sustainable development and commitment to social issues as illustrated by the charity campaign run in collaboration with Jeff Koons.</p>
          <p>The success of Kiehl's is done to highly original skincare product, such as the new Midnight Recovery Concentrate, and Night Elixir that is extremely pleasant to apply and very effective, a unique brand experience in stores, unprallelled customer care and first-class service that appeal to men and women from all over the world.</p>
          <p>Also 2010 will be remembered for the dazzling launch of Kiehl's in Asia. In Korea, it's an incredible success. The brand has already number one in its 29 department stores, ahead of all the global brands. And we also hope for in Japan as well as in China, where Kiehl's is already one of the most successful brand at its 11 point-of-sale with wonderful potential for development in this country. Today, Kiehl's is present in just 750 point-of-sale around the world and both exceptional turnover per outlet. So the Kiehl's saga is only just beginning.</p>
          <p>Lastly, I would like to highlight the dynamism of two more of the division's strategic brands. Shu Uemura, first of all the Japanese Art of Beauty, a Tokyo based brand is a major asset in our conquest of Asia, its sales are up by 17% due to the success of pioneering and highly innovative product such as the make-up removal oil and the UV <mark type="inaudible" /> base Foundation Primer but also thanks to its typical Japanese quality of service.</p>
          <p>And Ralph Lauren, the brand started by America's great fashion designer. They also had good momentum in 2010 with the launch of Big Pony, a collection of four men's perfumes that perpetuate the great tradition of the brand and express the Ralph Lauren Lifestyle in its purest form, it's a great success both in the United States but also in Latin America and throughout the world.</p>
          <p>The division's brands are therefore firing on all cylinders and are more aspiration more than ever. Now we also have <mark type="inaudible" />, we transferred the Roger &amp; Gallet in the to the Active Cosmetics division of the group with our 10 biggest brands so representing 95% of our turnover. We have the most beautiful portfolio of brands in the profession and we have wonderful development potential on every continent. 2010 was also a year of the increase in two areas, key for the future of the group.</p>
          <p>First of all, in the digital department, we &#x2013; Lanc&#xF4;me was the first luxury brand at &#x2013; who have a presence on the iAd. The iAd, which is the brand new interactive advertising platform on Apple's mobile application. So another example is on YouTube. Just before Christmas, five of our brands were promoted in spectacular fashion on the homepage. There were 360 million pages viewed in just five days and this indeed demonstrates the power of this medium. Our brand is also very much involved in ecommerce with an increase of 30% of our turnover in 2010.</p>
          <p>In terms of distribution in retail, there are two events that need to be highlighted. First of all we opened some exclusive brand stores, especially Kiehl's stores to have presence of our brands in high traffic areas which are not covered by our partners and distributors.</p>
          <p>We also strengthened our leadership in Travel Retail which is a highly dynamic channel that represented in itself a market the size of United States and serves as a fantastic shop window for luxury products. We are the historic leaders. We are pioneers and we are the historic leaders in this high potential channel which draws high income clients from all over the world. And in 2010, our brands grew by 22% in this segment.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, as you can see, the luxury products division has completely transformed itself and is now well equipped to take full advantage of the tremendous opportunities like Luxury is going to be offering in the coming years all around the world. I am now transferring this division to Nicolas Hieronimus who I am sure will be able to take the division to its new heights. Thank you very much for your attention. Thank you. Thank you very much.</p>
          <p>It is now Nicolas who will be telling us about his former division, the Professional Products division which also had a great year 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes indeed, good morning. For the Professional Products division, 2010 was an excellent year marked by a strong gain in market share on a channel of moderate growth and marked by the conquest of a record number of salons, thanks to our successful initiatives and the complementarity of the our brand portfolio.</p>
          <p>In 2010, the global salon market for professional products grew at an estimated plus 1.3%. It was strong in growth regions like Asia, excluding Japan, Latin America and the Middle East and it was stable or with a slight recovery in mature countries. In this contest, the L'Or&#xE9;al product &#x2013; Professional Products division generated a sales growth of plus 4.1% like-for-like, a performance that is above the market in every region of the world.</p>
          <p>On reported figures, growth was plus 13.8%. So this was a great year of conquest allowing us to increase our estimated market share to 28% and to enhance our worldwide leadership, which is today very significant.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe there are slightly positive global markets, if we exclude Greece. Our annual sales growth was plus 2.2% with significant gains of market shares in Germany, Great Britain, Sweden and France.</p>
          <p>The conquest of more than 4,500 salons such as the <mark type="inaudible" /> going to our market share gain. In North America in a salon market of 2% growth we achieved plus 2.5% with as a highlighting performance of L'Or&#xE9;al professional. The brand become a significant player in the market thanks to Inoa, which was a hit from a &#x2013; among American journalist <mark type="audio gap" /> and she is going to be able to do that in American salons where alongside Inoa, which is off to a great start. Our American brands, Redken and Matrix, which are number one and number two in the market are confirming their leadership.</p>
          <p>Regarding our salon-centric distribution network, we were able to complete an ideal territorial coverage through several acquisitions of regional distributors. Maly's Midwest and Marshall at the very beginning of the year followed by CB Sullivan and Peel's in December.</p>
          <p>In new markets, the division grew by plus 8.6%. The three main regions are dynamic Latin America at plus 13.2% with very strong results in Brazil; Africa, Middle-East at plus 13.3%, and Asia, excluding Japan at 15.6% with India, China, South Korea and Indonesia acting as drivers of growth.</p>
          <p>Overall, it's interesting to note that all &#x2013; of the top ten countries contributing to our growth, there are five mature countries and five new markets. The divisions determination to reaffirm its role as leader and to act as the industry champion has enabled us to again gain one market share point by innovating for hairstylists with &#x2013; hair style and with hairstylists and by taking numerous initiatives to boost the market. Innovation for and with hair style experts, which resulted in a big year for technical products, which is to say those used by professionals for services in their salons. These products are essential to our growth because they consolidate our commercial relations with the salon professionals.</p>
          <p>Hair stylist is one of our typical and remains a loyal customer for a very long time. And of course that's the slide says what we did with Inoa hair color, which was deployed rapidly worldwide basically in Brazil and China. And it's an exclusive salon technology in well over 81,000 salons, 40% of which did not previously use L'Or&#xE9;al products. And they show a very high satisfaction rating. In the hair color, there is also a Matrix and with its new 90ml of SoColor Beauty format that offers hair stylists the most affordable price per application of any leading international brands. There's Redken with color fusion <mark type="inaudible" /> and the strong growth of our hair color applications demonstrate that &#x2013; this is says of this multi-brand strategy.</p>
          <p>Other technical and professional products include products for texture in a worldwide development of the Brazilian hair straightening treatments; include the success of Moisturist, by L'Or&#xE9;al Professional artist trade in India. And last but not least, there is also fiberceutic and its Intra-Cylane by L'Or&#xE9;al professional and Chronologiste by K&#xE9;rastase.</p>
          <p>In 2011, we will continue to innovating products for technical services and real term products with Inoa supreme based on ODS technology dedicated to mature hair Redken <mark type="inaudible" /> to come down hair thinning and hair loss. K&#xE9;rastase' Elixir Ultim&#xE9; launched in November and already a success. And also the first cleansing balm Chroma Sensitive or Matrix with its accessible line of hair care Total Eesults.</p>
          <p>In addition to innovation, a leader must also stimulate its market and help hairstylists to attract more women more often to their salons by talking directly to women by advertising.</p>
          <p>The Inoa multichannel approach with the digital print and TV campaign and reception for a professional product has brought several thousands of women into salons, which have displayed the communication campaign in their windows. So putting this channel also means encouraging hair stylists to reinvent their hair salons. This is what we did with the concept salons presented with the toolbox to be implemented at the inaudible] Beaut&#xE9; event. They have already inspired a lot of salon professionals. Giving hair service, all the keys for success is also what we will do with salonworld.com. This first multi-brand portal will offer professionals other solutions to their needs with inspiration, training and partnership or just simply connection to their community.</p>
          <p>The division has digital at the heart of its strategy of growth. Building our future means of course boosting new markets by educating and inspiring future generations of hair stylists. The L'Or&#xE9;al Professional Institute opened in June in Rio will train this year 1000 students in hairdressing, who will be our future customers. The concept would be deployed in a number of Brazilian cities with a target of 45,000 students per year.</p>
          <p>In March 2011, we will organize an International Symposium of French on Perfume in China attended 3000 Asian hairstylists, and Asian entrepreneurs in search of inspiration. It's a premiere in this country, where expect to reach out to the new generations of salon professionals and thus make a huge step forward with our division. This determination to be beyond just a leader also the champion of the exciting business of professional beauty has helped us win over more than 35,000 additional salons this year and gain one market share point.</p>
          <p>So today, I am very pleased and proud to handover the legacy of a wining division, a division with the portfolio of eight brands well-positioned to cover the entire market through both their inspiration and price level.</p>
          <p>A division with breakthrough innovation and skills that paves the way for the future of hairdressing has become the leader of the profession numerically but also in terms of heart and soul. And I'm convinced that within the health centers heading the division, we will inexorably strengthen our leadership in this market. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nicolas and congratulation. There is a division which is not changing, Brigitte, it was here last year and again this year and you're going to be able to tell us about last year and your vision for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to everyone. We were optimistic last year and we were right. In 2010, we got back on to a growth curve. The Active Cosmetic division increased turnover by 4.7% on a well dermocosmetic market with estimated growth of 2.5 and this was like-for-like. And the good news is that every brand and every zone without any exception is expanding.</p>
          <p>The first satisfaction is that Western Europe is 3.1% up. The main driver is La Roche-Posay which continues its growth. The United States continued upward trend with an increase of 4.5%. A large number of doctors have opened the skinceuticals account and La Roche-Posay increasing present in American drug stores.</p>
          <p>Finally, we are pleased to announce an acceleration in new markets up by 7.7%. The expansion of the dermocosmetic market worldwide will continue over the coming years for three main reasons. Firstly, the whole world is looking for health in beauty. The middle-classes in the emerging countries as well. They are in search of tested and proven formula on sensitive skin. They want reliable products, recommended by dermatologists. They are also increasingly concerned by prevention and global well-being.</p>
          <p>For example in Brazil, more than one woman out of two, claims to have sensitive skin, it's the same proportion as in the United States. In China, 37% of women complain of allergic or intolerant skin and this is same proportion as in France. Second reason, the pharmacy has clearly become the preferred channel for skin, health and beauty concerns and the same applies all over the world.</p>
          <p>In Brazil for example, skincare sold in pharmacies represents more than 50% of the total market and the expansion of modern drug store chains in Asia is a real opportunity for all of us.</p>
          <p>Finally, dermatology is taking shape and evolving towards aesthetics everywhere in the world. Cosmetics are being increasingly used to complement drug prescription.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we confirmed our position as the world leader in dermocosmetics. Here are the four drivers behind this leadership innovation, partnerships with health professionals, adaption to local needs and a unique brand portfolio.</p>
          <p>The first innovation, our policy has given good results with the successful launches of anti-aging skincare Neovadiol and LiftActiv by Vichy as well as Redermic[+], La Roche-Posay. This has reaffirmed our number one position in anti-aging in Western Europe.</p>
          <p>We've also launched a new filter system, some filter system, MEXOPLEX, which represents a major advanced in sun protection.</p>
          <p>Let me give you another example of innovation. The entry price product ranges such as Essentielles and Vichy price at less than &#x20AC;10 or <mark type="inaudible" /> La Roche-Posay.</p>
          <p>Looking back one year, we can confirm that we've recruited new customers, attracted by products which combine the benefits of simplicity and the reliability of the pharmacy, particularly in Europe.</p>
          <p>The second driver behind our leadership is our partnership with pharmacists and dermatologists. We strengthened these links even more in 2010, thanks to increased training of pharmacy staff.</p>
          <p>We have also increased the number of doctors visited by more than 20% in every geographical zone, mainly regarding La Roche-Posay and Inn&#xE9;ov, adapting to local needs. This is the major source of our 19% growth in Latin America.</p>
          <p>We have formulated our products to meet local expectations. The Anthelios sun care product has a fluid texture to correspond to humid climate. With Vichy we've developed Normaderm soap bars for greasy skin, a recurrent problem in this region. And the soap is produces locally.</p>
          <p>This leads us to our fourth driver, our unique and more than ever complementary brand portfolio, which enables us to cover every consumer expectation in health and beauty. The reigning champion in this area is La Roche-Posay. The brand is recommended by more than 25,000 dermatologists across the world and continues its double-digit growth, four times more than market growth, gaining over 9,000 new point of sale in 2010.</p>
          <p>Vichy, the number one dermocosmetic brand has achieved great success in the Anti-Age segment in every zone, particularly in Asia, and in Hygiene in Western Europe. And we also have our other dynamic expanding brands contributing to overall turnover.</p>
          <p>Today, they account for more than 20% of Active Cosmetics growth. They have opened more than 10,000 new pharmacies. They complete our care range from the organic segment with Sanoflore to the super-sophisticated segment with SkinCeuticals by our nutricosmetics through Inn&#xE9;ov or the perfume refreshing models of Roger &amp; Gallet which join our division, as Marc said, last year and is already experiencing more than 20% growth in Western Europe.</p>
          <p>2011 will be rewarding a year in terms of new initiatives for all of these brands. And the pride of place is for Vichy. We are launching LiftActive Derm Source after 10 years of research, seven patterns, six scientific publications and seven clinical trials.</p>
          <p>LiftActive Derm Source is a revolution in anti-aging. It is really wonderful, and we're in the process of launching it now. La Roche-Posay is satisfying the needs of a fast-growing market, ultra-sensitive and allergic skin types. Tol&#xE9;riane Ultra contains an ultra soothing ingredient without any preservatives and presented in the tightly sealed pack.</p>
          <p>It is worth noting that according to the World Health Organization in 2012 in the industrialized countries, one out of two individuals will be affected by allergies. At the end of the year, we'll be launching Inn&#xE9;ov onto the Chinese market, which already represent as much as the whole of Western Europe in nutricosmetics.</p>
          <p>We also intend to reinforce our links with Asia. The L'Or&#xE9;al Group will be the main sponsor of the World Dermatology Congress in Seoul in May 2011 will be an opportunity for our brands to establish even closer links with dermatologists.</p>
          <p>As you can see, we are approaching 2011 with maximum optimism. We have full confidence in our ability to continue to create and develop health and beauty products as the cutting-edge of innovation right across the world. I thank you for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I think that these presentations are very useful or in any case I hope so. They enable you to understand what is behind the numbers, and better understand the job of each of the divisions. L'Or&#xE9;al is beauty, but each division has an expertise and a method which is very complementary and specific. And we are the only beauty group &#x2013; global beauty group which is active in all these four areas.</p>
          <p>I would now like to make some comments about what I considered to be the most important aspects of our sales and our performance in 2010 and share with you, as usual, my vision of our strategic prospects and our major opportunities for the coming years.</p>
          <p>First of all, the markets, I imagine you're interested in that. After proving resilient in 2008 and 2009 during the crises, the world cosmetics market returned to growth in 2010 with an increase that we estimate at 4%, in line with the forecast we made at the same meeting one year ago. The market has thus returned to a growth level, which is close to its historic rate, as you can see.</p>
          <p>As could be expected, there have, however, been short contrast in growth rates between the different geographic zones. In Western Europe, it's slightly positive market at plus 0.7% in a difficult environment, as you know, in North America, a clear upturn in the market with growth in the order of plus 2.4%. And Japan a slightly positive market at plus 1.3%. And once again, it is the very strong growth of the new markets in the order of 8.7% which is driving the global market.</p>
          <p>But there are some fairly considerable differences and situations across the geographic zones this year. Strong growth come back in Latin America at plus 13%, good growth in Asia Pacific at plus 9% and more moderate growth in the two other regions because of difficulties in certain countries, Africa, Middle East with a growth of 5.7%; only in Eastern Europe with a growth of 4.7%.</p>
          <p>Other distribution channels achieved a positive growth and the market was particularly driven by the upturn in Luxury. Over the last three years, the cosmetics market has thus demonstrated its considerable resilience during the crisis and a strong rebound potential after the crisis.</p>
          <p>We believe that the momentum will continue in 2011. And in our estimates the market may once again grow by between 3% and 4%, with a growth rate that is once again high in the new markets. And probably a confirmation of the upturn in North America and we hope a slight growth increase in Western Europe.</p>
          <p>In the medium and long term, we are very confident about the sustainable development potential of the cosmetics market whose growth, global growth, may even accelerate because of the increasingly important weight of the new markets in which the emergence of the middle-class is boosting the consumption of beauty products.</p>
          <p>In 2010, growth at L'Or&#xE9;al also rebounded well, as it amounted to 5.6% like-for-like, reflecting the way the group has outperformed the trend in world markets as a whole. Growth based on reported figures at 11.6% is spectacular because of an extremely positive exchange rate effect reflecting, in particular, the strengthening of the currencies in the new markets, which enabled us to achieve this record sale figure.</p>
          <p>And this performance is both solid and global, because it has been achieved across all divisions and all geographic zones. At division level, the Consumer Products division which is the group's largest last year continued as you have seen to win market shares worldwide, thanks to the power of Express, L'Or&#xE9;al Paris, Garnier and Maybelline and thanks also to the quality of its international and regional adaptations. Obviously, the consumer products division will be the spearhead of our conquest of a further billion new customers over the coming years.</p>
          <p>The Luxury Products division has returned to a good level of growth, at plus 7%. It has reinforced the power of its major brands with Lanc&#xF4;me, of course, and the acceleration of Yves Saint Laurent and Armani and you have seen the extraordinary success of Kiehl's with growth at 43%.</p>
          <p>As for the Professional Products division, its true level of performance goes well beyond the 4% growth recorded in a market which was still depressed. It was the big winner in its industry, thanks to the international success of Inn&#xE9;ov. And thanks also to the record number of new salons recruited and the major advances made in penetrating strategic markets of the future such as China, Brazil and India.</p>
          <p>As Brigitte indicated, Active Cosmetics bolstered its position as the world leader in dermal cosmetics with La Roche-Posay and <mark type="inaudible" /> and Roger <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>The Body Shop had a more difficult year, but we believe it was a year of transition, which enabled it to complete its strategic organization and improve its profitability. It has stepped up its policy of ethically based innovations, accelerated its move into new markets such as in India, where the brand has doubled its store base and extended its distribution to include new channels such as the Internet and travel retail. We believe the brand is now ready to return to like-for-like sales growth as early as 2011.</p>
          <p>Lastly, Galderma had an exceptional year with double-digit growth in amounts invoiced and once again made market share gains.</p>
          <p>In geographical terms, the three zones saw their growth accelerate compared with last year, as you saw in the press release. In Western Europe, the group's growth was in line with the market, slightly above the market, with performances that were good in major countries such as the UK, France and Germany; and less good in Southern countries affected by economic difficulties.</p>
          <p>In North America, L'Or&#xE9;al clearly reinforced its positions in mass market segments with very significant market shares gains. The same applies to professional products where our network of distributors strengthens the power of our brands. In the Luxury segment, our growth was below the market trend.</p>
          <p>Finally in the new countries, the group sales increased quite as fast as the cosmetics market. In Asia, growth amounted to 13.2%, excluding Japan, and spectacular advances in India and also in Indonesia, Philippines and South Korea. And our growth remained strong in China, despite temporary difficulties in registering new products which affected the whole of the industry.</p>
          <p>Latin America had an excellent year at 17.5%, thanks to remarkable performance by Brazil at 21%, and also Argentina, Mexico and Chile going south. The growth rate slowed in Eastern Europe, particularly in the Central European countries which have been hit by a difficult economic situation, as you know. But our growth has remained strong in Russia with market share gains across all divisions.</p>
          <p>Finally, in Africa, Middle East, we have been held back by temporary difficulties in South Africa, but we are growing fast elsewhere and growth in this region should rebound in 2011. Overall, in 2010 the group has strengthened its positions worldwide and made decisive breakthroughs in the new strategic markets for the future.</p>
          <p>So 2010 was a year of conquest during which the group made the most of the new strategic thrusts adopted at the end of 2008, which I would now like to run through. The first was concentrating on major global innovations with high value-added but accessible prices.</p>
          <p>We have successfully continued in 2010 and will continue in 2011 and beyond, our trading right strategy. This strategy of offering innovation without devaluing the products enables us to reach more consumers. INOA, for example, is used in more than 81,000 salons worldwide as Nicolas indicated. Of which 20% were not previously L'Or&#xE9;al professional customers.</p>
          <p>Over more than 5 million units of G&#xE9;nifique have been sold since its launch, it has been an excellent recruitment product for Lanc&#xF4;me. Maybelline has reported double-digit volume growth. And Essentielles and Vichy has also won over new pharmacy customers. We are thus widening our customer base.</p>
          <p>The second major strategic thrust in 2008, which was applied in 2009 and '10, is the extension of our brand to cover new product categories, such as men's skin-care and deodorants in order &#x2013; once again to enlarge our consumer base and generate to growth which is purely additional.</p>
          <p>With the launch of Garnier Men in India and then in most of the Asian countries, our two major consumer products brands now have a men's line. Both are proving highly successful, particularly in Asian countries where there growth is the most spectacular &#x2013; men have no taboo regarding skin care.</p>
          <p>And we have captured first place in this market, which is developing and growing very fast, in particular, in China, where we have become the leaders in men's skin-care. At world levels of sales of the division in this category has grown by 22%.</p>
          <p>As for deodorants, that is a huge market. This is a category in which we are still quite small. We have only just started and in which we have a great deal of development potential over the coming years. 20, 25 years ago, L'Or&#xE9;al had also started new products, skin care or makeup and that carried the group's growth for many, many years.</p>
          <p>The third strategic thrust is the accelerated globalization of our brands. We have strengthened, as you've seen, the penetration of our brands, which were already present to the new markets. Matrix is now present in more than 60,000 salons in the BRIC countries. And we have expanded the distribution of Garnier to more than 400,000 outlets in India.</p>
          <p>We're launching our relay brands in new countries as is the case of Kiehl's, which is moving into India and is proving highly successful in China where it was launched last year. The brand, we've accelerated our rollout in new countries such as Egypt, why not? Pakistan and Kazakhstan.</p>
          <p>And during 2011, we will be opening new subsidiaries in Saudi Arabia and Nigeria and the areas where we do not have a base or &#x2013; very small one. In 2010, we achieved a major milestone with our Chinese subsidiary which passed a &#x20AC;1 billion sales mark and has become our number three market worldwide.</p>
          <p>As Christian indicated in 2011, for the first time, the new markets may be the group's number one zone for sales. Maybe because it depends on the euro and its value and depending on the months and depending on the market, but the new markets zone may become the group's number one zone, ahead of Western Europe and North America.</p>
          <p>For the first months of the year, we made about 40% of our sales there and objective is to make between 50% and 60% of our sales there in the next year depending of course on currency fluctuations. So weight of the zone is advancing inexorably, and this will have a mechanical effect accelerating the group's growth.</p>
          <p>Finally, the fourth strategic thrust was increasing our spending on research and innovation, and on advertising and promotional resources. The research budgets grew by 9.1% in 2010, reflecting clearly our determination to boost our investments in this key sector.</p>
          <p>Although blockbusters from our laboratories are proving to be genuine worldwide success stories. We &#x2013; the cosmetics is essentially technological and we are convinced that it is through research and innovation that we will stand out from the competition, and we will continue to reinforce our global leadership.</p>
          <p>Our advertising and promotional expenses have also grown significantly by 11.9% with gains of share points in strategic markets, such as the U.S. and Brazil. We are going to intensify our efforts to improve the productivity of these advertising and promotional resources, which is one of the first tasks to be tackled by the newly created strategic marketing division to optimize return on investment in this field.</p>
          <p>We've also had a good year as you've seen in terms of results. I am not going to repeat what Christian said in his presentation of course; but I think that these results show that the company is moving forward and adapting to change. All the actions taken in the field of operational excellence over the last two years to improve the company's performance and make it more responsive are continuing to pay-off.</p>
          <p>Just a few examples, 2010 was a record year in terms of industrial productivity. Our global program to improve the efficiency of our facilities has enabled us to gain close to 10 points of productivity in three years, representing a capacity gain of 20% using existing facilities. 2010 was also a record year in purchasing terms.</p>
          <p>The grouping together of purchasing into four sourcing centers and the specialization of lead buyers on a global scale to build coordinated purchasing strategies worldwide are opening up new pathways to progress in conjunction with our suppliers.</p>
          <p>The modernization of the company is also reflected in the improvement in SG&amp;A. As you've seen there has been a significant increase in terms of the percentage. And this is the overall result of the constant process of optimization of our organizational structures and strict cost control.</p>
          <p>It is important to note that all of these advances have been implemented and obtained throughout the company, in other words, in all four divisions and across all geographic zones.</p>
          <p>As you have seen the four divisions have different business segments, but they now produce consistent profitability. And as regards the geographic zone, it is important to point out the increase in the profitability of the new markets, which has risen in five years from 13.5% to 16.9%, even exceeding the figures in North America, the growth that we are generating there is increasingly profitable.</p>
          <p>The good balance between profitability levels, different business segments and regions is one of the group's assets. And it's a major advantage for sustainable and profitable growth.</p>
          <p>Overall, in 2010 we have returned to our virtuous circle model like-for-like sales which grew by 5.6%, gross profit rose by 6.7%, research by 8.9%, advertising and promotional expenses by 6%, selling, general and administrative expenses by 2.7% and operating profit grew by 13.5%.</p>
          <p>As you've also seen this model is also a strong generator of cash flow, which reached a new record level of &#x20AC;2,625 million. A strongly positive operating momentum means that we can look forward to the future with great confidence in the middle and the longer-term. And we're therefore proposing a significant increase in the dividend to the tune of plus 20% at &#x20AC;1.80. And as regards to the future, precisely I would like to share with you our strategic prospects.</p>
          <p>In fact, the world today is facing three major upheavals which are at the same time three significant opportunities for us. The first major upheaval is the economic and demographic change taking place in the world. As we all know now, the emerging countries have become vast reservoirs of new consumers. And this trend is set to become even more pronounced.</p>
          <p>In 2020, the middle classes &#x2013; that the middle classes are at the core of our brands. These middle classes in these countries will total some 2.7 billion people compared with 1 billion in 2010. Today western consumers account for some two-thirds of middle class spending worldwide. In 20 years time, probably 70% of the spending will come from the middle classes of Asia, Latin America or Africa.</p>
          <p>By then, the world's population will probably have increased by 25% and the number of consumers with access to cosmetics products would have grown probably again by around 50%. And this is because one fundamental needs have been met. Per capita consumption grows exponentially. These countries where per capita consumption is still 10 times lower than in developed countries are just taking their first steps in modern cosmetics. This profound transformation of the beauty market offers opportunities on the scale we have never experienced before. And this is the basis for our objective of winning a further billion new consumers.</p>
          <p>Today L'Or&#xE9;al makes the bulk of its sales with less than 15% of the population of our planet. As you can see on this animated map representing the world of L'Or&#xE9;al consumers in the different regions, the center of gravity of our consumers will migrate over the coming years, profoundly transforming the configuration of our customer base.</p>
          <p>In 10 years time, we should have as many customers in Asia Pacific as in Europe and the United States taken together. As you can see on this map, the Asian continent driven by China and India should be the largest contributor of new consumers. But the major developed markets such as the United States, the United Kingdom or Germany, will also be sources of strategic growth. For, even if our market shares there are high, our penetration surprisingly is still limited and this is fairly interesting idea.</p>
          <p>We have identified the fact that our brands for example still only reach one American citizen out of two and one German individual out of three. So we could look for new consumers and we could do this right here, and right now. There's a lot of potential, not compromise. Our penetration of these markets will be increased by expansions into new product categories and the accessible innovation strategy that we have already spoken about.</p>
          <p>In addition to this, we have also, of course, identified 15 major growth markets where our positions are still extremely limited today after the brink, we have the next 15 growth markets that we need to look into, but where there is enormous potential. Everywhere as you can see, our horizon is being enlarged in every direction, setting an objective of 2 billion consumers is a considerable change in scale compared to 1 billion today. Considerable change in the ambition for the group, but it is also a perfectly realistic objective that we can reach.</p>
          <p>Our company is now in a truly new phase of its history. I'm convinced about this. It's a key phase, which is the phase of so called universalization. In accomplishment of the fundamental mission that we set for ourselves, which is as you know, to offer all women and all men the world of best of cosmetics in terms of quality, efficacy and safety, purpose being to meet all their needs and beauty aspirations in their infinite diversity. The major strategic choices made over the last few years and the deep transformations undertaken in 2010 have prepared the group for this new phase of expansion.</p>
          <p>The second major upheaval in today's world is of course the digital revolution. This is a very interesting revolution, because it is profoundly transforming the relationship between our brands and our consumers.</p>
          <p>First, because in cosmetics, as you can imagine, the imaginative dimension is very important and the internet enables communications formats which are practically no limits, which are richer and more effective than the short format of television.</p>
          <p>Secondly, because in our businesses, promoting new rituals involves expert advice and the internet certainly facilitates this approach. Finally, the comfort of service, which is inherent in our business, becomes particularly significant on the internet. Thanks to the possible customization of personalization of contacts and the high-degree of interactivity with consumers. It is therefore an excellent opportunity for our brand &#x2013; for cosmetics in general and for L'Oreal in particular and for our brands to create new richer areas of expression and more direct, closer, and more personalized relationships with consumers. It is of course a new distribution channel, and therefore a major opportunity for additional sales.</p>
          <p>Our brands moved into digital media at a very early stage and we clearly stepped up our efforts in 2010. 2010 was the digital year at L'Oreal, we increased the budgets allocated to these new media, particularly, of course in countries where the internet is already very powerful, such as China, where 8% of &#x2013; all of our advertising spending is already allocated for this purpose, and we also developed expert advice and personal relations with consumers.</p>
          <p>We continue to create e-commerce site for our brands in China, for example we have opened a site which markets all of our luxury brands available in the country. The creation of the new strategic marketing division, again, will accelerate this trend, since the division's mission is to ensure L'Oreal's leadership in the digital media, and to intensify our initiatives and develop our expertise in this field.</p>
          <p>Finally, I would say to be complete that the third major upheaval in the world is the change in societies and citizens expectations about major companies. L'Oreal is the world's leader in the business of beauty, but L'Oreal also intends to be an exemplary corporate citizen in all fields of sustainable development. And sustainable development for example through our pioneering advances in the field of product eco-design, green chemistry and our worldwide leadership in predictive methods and environmental methods through our extremely strong resolve to reduce by half within 10 years our production it CO2, our water consumption and our waste generation.</p>
          <p>In ethical behaviors and diversity through our ambition to be one of the companies most widely recognize around the world by its achievement in these areas. And finally, in terms of similarity by the development of our initiatives to benefit local communities in the areas of which we operate particularly through the L'Or&#xE9;al foundation, after all the actions we have undertaken over recent years. All these efforts meant that L'Or&#xE9;al once again was ranked in 2010 as one of the 100 most sustainable and ethical companies worldwide. And this will make a decisive contribution in the future to the group success and to reinforce in its leadership.</p>
          <p>But as you can see L'Or&#xE9;al is particularly well adapted and prepared to tackle the challenges of the world &#x2013; currently being transformed and indeed to make the most of them as major strategic opportunities. I'm fully convinced personally that these specific and intrinsic strengths of L'Or&#xE9;al give us unique advantages in achieving success in the new world emerging today.</p>
          <p>What are these key assets? Concentration on a single business segment, which is beauty. Passion for research, innovation and creativity, the culture of excellence and quality, a very strong corporate culture and the exceptional degree of commitment of our employees to which maybe added the power of our brands and our totally global reach.</p>
          <p>I wish to, second, pay tribute to Sir Lindsay Owen-Jones, who was both as you know the architect and the builder of this magnificent company which L'Or&#xE9;al has become today. He chaired over the company for 24 years with immense success. As announced yesterday Lindsay Owen-Jones will be stepping down as the Chairman of the Board on the 17th of March, which is the date of his 65th Birthday. As he had always intended and he had announced and he will become Honorary Chairman of the L'Oreal company. From that date onwards, I will therefore have the dual role of Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, and I measure the degree of the honor and the responsibility which will be mine but I put a trust in the future of the company.</p>
          <p>I am convinced that L'Oreal is moving towards the new phase of its history to the phase of universalization of beauty, as I said. And there is this major objective, which is beauty for all. This is indeed a very important objective that we have to win an additional billion of new consumers. This conquest would motivate each of us and drive the group's growth for the long-term.</p>
          <p>This conquest will indeed drive the group's worth. For the next 20 years, it will be solid, sustainable and profitable growth. And as far as 2011 is concerned, which is the beginning of the next two decades and I am sure that you will have questions on that obviously, I could tell you as of now that we are encouraged by very sound beginning of the year. It's very encouraging we feel and we trust in the capacity of the group this year to once again outperform the cosmetics market, strengthen its global positions and deliver yet another year of growth of its sales and profit.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and you deserve a short break, not too longer break if you want us to have time for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, let's go. Who would like to ask the first question? Eva?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions, the first on the market growth. You mentioned 4% since the beginning of last year. I'd like to know whether the growth was balanced during the course of the year or whether it has slowed down. And I'd like to see how you see the consumers developing &#x2013; will it be a consumer pulled by value or innovation for next year?</p>
          <p>And for Mr. Lebel, how do you see the L'Or&#xE9;al brand did outperformed in a dynamic market. Is it a matter of communication or how can you address these problems in the long-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's a nice for a start. Well, first of all, I must say that personally I'm rather pleased with the forecast we made for the market. If I'm not mistaking, these past two to three years, we always announced at the beginning of the year a market forecast which turned out to be correct, with last year that the market would be at around 4% and our most recent estimate is 4%. And frankly speaking, we have not seen &#x2013; we did not see a change in the pace of the markets during the course of the year.</p>
          <p>And regarding invoicing, because I'm sure, your question &#x2013; next question will be why was the fourth quarter lower than the third. It's more related to launches or big American clients that reduce their inventory at a point in time, and this is not due to a significant drop in consumption. So consumption was fairly homogenous during the course of the whole year 2010.</p>
          <p>And it may be a little early to make a commitment. But it would appear that we have the same basic trend for 2011. We believe that 2011 will be a repetition of 2010 for the basic trend. As I indicated earlier, consumption will be fairly flat or slightly positive in Western Europe. One cannot exclude having a good surprise in North America. There could be good news.</p>
          <p>And on a contrary, we are convinced that consumption in all the new markets will be good, and here also there may be some volatility. The economic evolution of the world is not of smooth sailing and doesn't happen equally in all countries. Eastern Europe last year was a little more difficult, some Asian countries progressed more quickly. So, we are confident at the group level that the market will progress in 2011 and we are confident that we can outperform the market.</p>
          <p>So, <mark type="inaudible" /> L'Or&#xE9;al Paris brand. Well it's a good question. The L'Or&#xE9;al Paris brand had a growth at 2.8% and there was a higher growth for Garnier and Maybelline. But last year L'Or&#xE9;al Paris had a growth of 0.7%. So, there is an improvement and we plan to double it this year and increase it from 2.8% to 5.6%.</p>
          <p>Why do we believe in that? We have several reasons to do so. Last year, we got rid of a few obstacles to the growth of the L'Or&#xE9;al Paris brand. We had no entry price products. We now launched the Triple Active product line, which are at an entry price, which the consumers needed. Same for mascaras, we have a cascading to also have a product at an entry price. So, we solved that topic without reducing the prices of the product.</p>
          <p>Now regarding communication, there had been perhaps a bit of where a certain repetitivity of our L'Or&#xE9;al messages, I don't know whether you saw the most recent ads. There is a new breath, a new way of speaking to women and these films are really liked in all the countries where they have been shown and sales have been increasing for L'Or&#xE9;al Paris, for skincare and make-up. So, we are very confident.</p>
          <p>You have also seen that we're launching the L'Or&#xE9;al Paris brand in a country such as India, where we have had Garnier only for 10 years. So we're launching L'Or&#xE9;al Paris in India and it's doing well.</p>
          <p>So, the idea of having the mass premium and the extra quality is very attractive. And more than ever the quality signals which are conveyed by the L'Or&#xE9;al Paris brand and the "You're Worth It" slogan are all part of that.</p>
          <p>And there is also the development of the Men Expert brand. It's the number one brand for men in Eastern Europe and China also. And we hope to develop it a lot. We've added deodorants and coloring products, men's hair coloring products, which have started very well in 2010, and which here I hope for development in the men's customer segment for next year.</p>
          <p>Going back to the first part of your question, we're also very confident on the ability to bring added value. I don't think that the cosmetics market is doomed to having the prices decrease. And the strategic revaluation we did two years ago, affordable or trading right, accessible innovation, trading right is to bring innovation but at the right price, which optimizes both on volume and value. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, <mark type="inaudible" />. I have two questions. You mentioned the digital revolution; could you tell us what your exact plans are? Is it just advertising or will you be selling Luxury products on the internet for instance? Now regarding your shareholder shift, the settling of the dispute within the Bettencourt family, has that given rise to some concern amongst the shareholders? And then there is the problem of Nestl&#xE9;. Are you aware of Nestl&#xE9;'s plans regarding their stake in L'Or&#xE9;al and if yes, that's of course a problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll begin with the second question. I don't have any new news on that. And what I usually answer this question &#x2013; to this question which I hear very often is that during the past 30 years, we've had a stable shareholder shift and that was an excellent thing for everyone, for the company, for the shareholders for Nestl&#xE9; for the Bettencourt family, and all the other shareholders. And at this stage, I have no additional information that would lead me to answer otherwise.</p>
          <p>Regarding the digital revolution, we believe that digital will be a revolution mostly in terms of communication with the consumer in our line of business. It will be a revolution in terms of communication. And on the three aspects, which I mentioned the communication of our image service, counseling and also thirdly the individual element and in a business such as cosmetics, it is a true revolution.</p>
          <p>Last year, with the Heads of Division who are present here, we asked all of the brands to make a determined commitment in the area of this digital revolution to see how each of these lines could best use the digital technology. And there are a lot of projects underway. And Jean-Jacques example for &#x2013; for example in the area of e-commerce.</p>
          <p>Perhaps I can ask the camera to focus on my iPad. Here you go to the Apple Store, here you download the Club des Cr&#xE9;ateurs de Beaut&#xE9; application. And you have their digital catalog, 50% of our Club des Cr&#xE9;ateurs de Beaut&#xE9; orders are done via internet. And so you can turn the pages of the catalog. And you can select your products in this very modern way.</p>
          <p>If I go to my favorite product, which is here the Agn&#xE8;s BB Cream, the first BB Cream to be available in Europe. I can click on that and add it to my shopping cart. So, this has been available for one month on the iPad. And women who access the Club des Cr&#xE9;ateurs de Beaut&#xE9; via the iPad buy more than the average customer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about Luxury?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have some experience of the e-commerce in the Luxury division. We had an online site for Lanc&#xF4;me in the U.S. As I indicated in my presentation, e-commerce and Luxury has progressed by 30%. It accounts for about 2% of our global sales. But in certain countries such as the U.S. it's already about 6%, in Korea over 10%. And for certain brands, young brands, in particular such as Kiehl's, globally we're already at 10%. So, it's an interesting sales channel. And very complementary to our traditional store channel. A question in the second room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Daniela Fernandes da Costa from Valor Econ&#xF4;mico from Brazil. I'd like to know, what process the Brazilian market offers for the near future and the longer-term future? And in which sector of activity will you be strengthening your development in Brazil, and for what reasons or for what in the short term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. Brazil is a very strategic country for L'Or&#xE9;al. As we've indicated earlier, it has become one of the biggest countries for us. We sold for &#x20AC;700 million there and with that pace of growth it will soon be one of the top countries in terms of sales for the country, which is normal since it is the third cosmetic market globally on an equal footing with China.</p>
          <p>So, our strategy is very clear. We wish to maximize. It's the third market on a par with China, well ahead of France and Germany, et cetera. So, our strategy is clear. We wish to maximize our presence. We are very present in Brazil in the hair products and in coloring products and we will continue to develop our presence. We also have an interesting presence in sun protection products and our intention is to increase our presence in the mass market progressively in the skincare products and make-up. And alongside that the Professional Products division is very present also. Nicolas, do you want to say a word there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The progress was achieved by An Verhulst-Santos when she was head of Brazil. Well Brazil is an example for us. It's still in the top two or three contributors of the growth of the division for a few years, is a number six country. I think it will move to fifth position next year. We have 25% market shares in Brazil and the Brazilian consumers very much like the services that we talked about earlier, the hair straightening and coloring. We wish to reach 30% of the market share in Brazil. <mark type="inaudible" /> we have great ambitions for Brazil which should become one of the top countries for the group. We may perhaps go back to the other room?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, my friends. I will ask my question in English. You have been focusing on developing markets, but there are quite a few challenges there and distribution system being one of them. So, my question to you is, what do you identify as key challenges in these markets and how do you intend to overcome them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a very broad question, because there are many, many different situation. No, what we see, in fact is generally speaking, we are able to identify the challenges and find the solutions. I mean and it's true that whether it's truly a question is that all markets are different. You don't conquer China like you do for Brazil or Russia or Indonesia, but we are very pragmatic and in every country in every situation we try to define the right business model, the right strategy, the right approach to find the solutions.</p>
          <p>So we don't see, honestly today especially in terms of distribution, we don't see any major difficulty. The only sometime think that that slowing us down is the fact that in some countries there is not enough stores. For example, if you think about India, we would like to have in India more supermarkets, hypermarkets, department stores, perfumaries, et cetera. That will help, for example, the development of a division like the Luxury Division. But besides that we are very pragmatic and we adjust ourselves to the situation of every country. So we don't see any major hurdle on our development there. I don't hear you anymore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you consider an acquisition to lead you to growth in these markets. I mean, you've been talking about growth in -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know that everybody is very excited about the acquisitions ideas. But to answer precisely, we don't need acquisitions to speed up the growth or the conquest of these markets. I mean, we have today &#x2013; I think it's a very important point to understand is that &#x2013; it's a very interesting idea. In fact, international brands are really extremely appreciated by consumers in the new markets, some time even more than their local brands. So for us today to grow fast in all these new markets, India, China, Brazil, Indonesia, Philippines, everywhere, we don't need a new brand, a local brand. In fact we can really conquer the markets with the international brand that we have. So, if we consider one day an acquisition, it would be for a very specific purpose, but it is not needed for our development there. Okay? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bonjour, <mark type="inaudible" /> Cr&#xE9;dit Mutuel-CIC. I have three questions. First of all, on China, please. Could you give us an update on the position of the Chinese authorities, plus 25% in 2009, plus 11% in 2010, where do you put the cursor for China in 2011? So for consumer products, could you tell us who are the winners and the losers compared with your competitors per major category of product for the year 2010?</p>
          <p>Third question; could you come back to the Luxury products and the fact that in the U.S. your performance was lower than that of the market? You talked about the phasing of some of new launches, but in the end it wasn't exactly what you were expecting. So, what do you plan for 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we will try and answer this quickly. There are many questions. First of all for China, we had said last year that the growth pace would probably be a little lower due to the regulatory problems we encounter as does everyone else in the country. This is what happened. Things are improving progressively, not quite as quickly as we would hope, but things are improving. And in 2011, we do hope to reaccelerate our growth on the Chinese market. You also need to know that we're having good sales, over &#x20AC;1 billion, but our ambition is to continue to reaccelerate our growth on the Chinese market.</p>
          <p>Regarding consumer products, I'll ask for an update from Jean-Jacques, but we will not be telling you about our competitors; that would not be elegant. Jean-Jacques Lebel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for make-up, for instance, we are the winners and in all geographical zones; Eastern Europe, Western Europe, North America, Japan. We also won market shares in Japan with Maybelline. Our position there is very competitive. And so for make-up, we are the great winners, globally. There is another category where we are the great winners in the areas where we have operations is in the hair care. We are the great winners and we are penetrating the Asian market. We're penetrating the market, but we're still very small.</p>
          <p>If you take other categories, we have other competitors who are European competitors, which may have scored some points for hair coloring in Europe in 2010. There's not much more that I should say, because, otherwise, I would have to give names.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In total, consumer products had a good year 2010 and rather better than its competitors. That's the main point.</p>
          <p>And as you have seen, some of our competitors are moving out of some categories, which is a good sign for us. Luxury in the U.S., well, as I said and as Jean-Paul (sic) [Jean-Jacques] indicated, our consumer sales in the U.S. were a little under the market. I'd like to say two things, the growth of our consumer sales increased in the second half compared to the first. We won four growth points during the second half &#x2013; percentage points compared with the previous semester.</p>
          <p>Lanc&#xF4;me is still under the market. But it is true that our Lanc&#xF4;me launch plan in the U.S. was not at the same time as the rest of the world time-wise. And the other relay brands performed well. Saint-Laurent had a year at 12%; Kiehl's at 20%, Ralph Lauren with the success of The Big Pony Collection outperformed its market in fragrances, Acqua di Gioia was very successful in the U.S. So a clear success, so we're very confident for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a question at the back and then we'll go to the second room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Audrey <mark type="inaudible" /> from the Reuters Agency. I have a question. Would L'Or&#xE9;al consider penetrating direct sales market through an acquisition possibly? And I have an add on question. What do you think about the business model of direct sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've already talked about this during the coffee break. So I'll give you the exact same answer as previously. It is not on the agenda, but we have no taboo. So you can conclude from that what you wish to conclude. I am sorry, I can't say more that that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question in the second room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I come from the <mark type="inaudible" /> Herald Tribune. Could you say a few words about the fact that Mr. Owen-Jones is leaving and what about his role, what has he done for the company, especially regarding international sales? Do you know that he was going to leave a long time ago? And is he leaving because of the Bettencourt case? And what exactly is he going to do in the future? What would be his future goal for the company &#x2013; in the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have issued a press release, which was very specific in that regard, yesterday. And it says very specifically, Sir Lindsay Owen-Jones had always indicated and publically indicated during the shareholder's meeting in 2005, that it was his desire, a strong desire to finish &#x2013; to finalize the smooth transition of his position on the 65th birthday. He will turn 65 on March 17th and the board of directors met yesterday. He is sticking to his promise. And this is something that he had always planned to do.</p>
          <p>Now regarding his future role in the company, I think that we all know what kind of role he will play. Over the last 25 years, he played a very significant role, because as I mentioned earlier, he was the great architect and the great builder of international success of the L'Or&#xE9;al company. For the last four years or five years Lindsay Owen-Jones was the Non-Executive Chairman of the Board. And as of the 17th of March, Lindsay Owen-Jones will be the Honorary Chairman of the L'Or&#xE9;al Board, which is a purely honorary role.</p>
          <p>He will not play an operational role. He will not have anything to do with the governance of the company. For quite some time, he will remain the Chairman of the L'Or&#xE9;al Foundation. Can't see you on the screen, so I don't know whether you're satisfied with the answer. He would be board member, obviously, a board director of L'Or&#xE9;al.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just ask a question first of all on gross margin? Perhaps, Christian, you mentioned the FX impact on the gross margin in 2010. Can you give us any indication on what that might be? A number would be great, but directionally would still be helpful for 2011.</p>
          <p>The second thing on the balance sheet, you mentioned that there's very little debt there. And I heard you say this afternoon that acquisitions aren't needed at least in emerging markets. Can you give us some idea, you've got the business back to growth now, after a few years of transition, are you starting to think about how you might be able to use the balance sheet, either through cash returns or are acquisitions still a preference for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as far as the income impact of currency is concerned, it was slightly negative as you know &#x2013; significantly negative I would say in 2010 as a gross margin. The negative impact of the translation effect was minus 50 &#x2013; between 50 and 60 basis points, difficult to predict what it will be in 2011. As I mentioned in my presentation, based on the present currency rates the impact should be zero on the turnover, which means that the impact should be close to zero on the result and on the gross margin. Then we'll see.</p>
          <p>And regarding acquisitions, there are not indispensable, they are not needed. But any acquisition that would help us boosting our development for every brand or in any part of the world would be very good for the company. And that's why we need a very robust balance sheet in order to be ready for any type of acquisition, plus a very dynamic policy in term of dividends as you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think there was a question in the other room. Sorry, this one here. We'll take this one and then we'll go to the other room. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Guillaume Delmas from Nomura. I have two questions. One on the Luxury Division. I was rather surprised to see a shrinking of the margin on the second half, especially because of the good organic growth of the Division and because of the expected synergy from the Yves Saint Laurent business. Could you shed some light on this matter, and can you tell us where you stand with the cost synergy coming from the acquisition of Yves Saint Laurent Beaut&#xE9;? And the second question, just in a nutshell on Maybelline, do you think you will have a double-digit growth figure for 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybelline, first of all, Jean, could you say a few words about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We always celebrate a double-digit growth years. It's something that is exceptional. We haven't recorded one for quite number of years. I think that the makeup market is very buoyant market. We have a lot of range of wonderful innovations in this segment. And as I said previously with our two leading global brands, the only really global brands, reach with the products all over the world. We have a good chance of making it. For L'Or&#xE9;al Paris and Maybelline makeup ranges, I think that we can achieve this double digit growth the next year.</p>
          <p>Yeah, Jean-Jacques is right, there are business segments which face fierce competition, but I think that for makeup, we have a high potential here. This brand together with L'Or&#xE9;al Paris is the only truly global makeup brand, which has a footing in all countries, and the innovation is coming from all over the world and that can be made available to all consumers in the world. I think that this is a strong engine. It is not by chance that Maybelline had a double digit growth last year. And I'm sure that we'll do everything we can to make it happen again this year.</p>
          <p>Marc, not Jean-Jacques, Marc will answer this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, let me answer on the Saint Laurent part. Regarding the acquisition of Saint Laurent, it's all happening very smoothly. We are exactly on track when it comes to our business plans. Saint Laurent was profitable in 2010. The synergy that we recorded following the pooling of the support functions and the industrial reorganization and the synergy that we achieved in purchasing, looking at all the sources of synergy, all of this was beyond our expectations. And as Jean-Paul said from the beginning, we have negotiation to &#x2013; we have a strategy to develop the brand. So, we're ready to invest a lot in our brand, and we're very happy to see that the brand is speeding up and accelerating very strongly, because as you know, as I said, we had a double-digit growth with this brand, with beautiful results in France and Germany and Italy, but also in the United States, for example. So, we are very satisfied with the integration of Yves Saint Laurent from a human organizational standpoint. Also, it's all happening very smoothly. We are doing well. And this is of course very good for the entire portfolio of brands in the division.</p>
          <p>There was a question regarding the margins of the second half compared to the first half. That's not the way we manage our business. That's not the way we do things. We have different margins per division on an annual basis. And of course then you can compare between the two halves, but it all depends on when the launches take place or the time chosen for the investment. So, this is not something that you can extrapolate from.</p>
          <p>As Marc said earlier on, the major element is that the Luxury division has really rebuilt its profitability very significantly in 2010, over an additional 250 basis points this year. And I'd like to point out to you that compare to our competitors this level of profitability is much higher than theirs. So, I don't think we have any problem when it comes to the profitability on the Luxury Products. Any further question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon Marshall-Lockyer from Jefferies in London. I have two questions. The first one is on Inoa in the United States. You launched the range in April of last year. Could you give us an indication regarding the number of salons, the trend, the momentum that you've created for Inoa in the United States at this stage? Second question for Christian Mulliez, regarding the raw materials, maybe you did mention the price of raw materials, but I wasn't around. On raw materials, do you have a target or do you have an estimate for 2011 regarding the cost of raw materials? And could you give us an indication of what kind of impact it will have if we had an oil barrel around $100, could that have a significant impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nicolas, could you tell us about Inoa in the United States, it's a beautiful adventure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nicolas Hieronimus. Yes, there was a national roll-out of Inoa as of the month of April of this year and as you saw, we did very well, we are in 4,000 salons in the United States, 3,800 to be precise that's the latest figure. 40% of these salons did not work with L'Or&#xE9;al Professionnel products before. So, we are really talking about a fully fledged innovation and we have strengthened the presence of L'Or&#xE9;al Professionnel products. It was a challenge around American market and we &#x2013; this was a beautiful adventure and we are only just beginning.</p>
          <p>You're right. It's quite an important turn in history, in the United States. We've managed to acquire the leading brands; Redken and Matrix. So, we are leading the market by far, but the development of L'Or&#xE9;al Professionnel products is fairly difficult and the launching of Inoa is indeed the historic opportunity we were waiting for in order to assert the presence of L'Or&#xE9;al Professionnel brand and we will not miss this opportunity. Regarding raw material, Christian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, regarding the possible increase of input costs, in 2010 as you've rightfully noted, there was a positive impact on our business and this contributed significantly to the improvement in the cost of goods results. For 2011, we have a number of financial assumptions, which we have not made available, but they are fairly cautious. And I think we have a good illustration of this and we could give you an example on the screen. You will see it anytime now. I have to speak slowly while they're looking for the slide.</p>
          <p>Here it is. You can see illustration on the slide, yes, that slide, but there was another one, I was thinking on. You can see for packaging, the basis of 100 in 2005. Then you can see the impact of the increase in raw materials and plastic or derivatives. We should have had 113 in 2010, but now it's a 96, so that's the impact and the same goes for raw materials. We could have shown you another statement under the table, which is the oil content in a bottle. But the oil content is very low. So we are not really sensitive to do these kinds of impacts.</p>
          <p>Jean-Paul Agon talked about this in his presentation. We also have programs for concentrating our purchasing worldwide for centralizing the purchasing. We have a suppliers' panel that has been opened to other geographic areas, including Asia and we are very confident that if there was to be a negative impact on the input cost, it should be limited and well under control. I think it's important we should note this.</p>
          <p>You'd been able to see here and there that some companies were indeed concerned by the increase in raw materials or input costs in 2011, but we are not overly worried, especially because our products are products with very low value added. So, the price of the input costs do not play very major role in our overall prices. And also, we are completely revamping our purchasing strategy, globalization, concentration, re-negotiations are the key words of this strategy. And we should be in a position in 2011 to have a positive effect that would make up for potential increases in input costs. It is our ambition to continue to improve our gross margin. So, we have no major concerns regarding input costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Emmanuel? We need a microphone for this gentleman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Some points of clarification, first, that you need to give us or ask us about, I've a list here. First of all, what about the weight of emerging markets and new markets for Body Shop? You said that the trend was accelerating. Secondly, I saw that Sanofi was offering to pay out its dividends as shares. Now since it is consolidated in your financial statements, I wanted to make sure that you would continue to pay out your dividends in cash. Could you also have the relative weights of the three major brands in the Consumer Products Division? And last technical question. I'd like to check why the margin went down in the Professional Products Division in the second half? Was this due to the acquisition of distributors, which happened during that semester? So, these are the small questions and I've then more basic issues that I would like to ask about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You should have asked with the basic questions to Mr. Agon. Christian, could you take as many questions as you possibly can?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Perfectly normal. For Sanofi you will not be surprised. We will see &#x2013; we will &#x2013; Sanofi announced that in principal they will pay out the dividend as shares, but didn't how they're willing to go about this. We'll look into this. We really have the lot of Sanofi shares in our portfolio, don't we? Regarding what you said about The Body Shop, we're doing this in a rather informal way, but talking about The Body Shop &#x2013; absolutely, we have to give you the results like-for-like. Regarding emerging markets, emerging markets account for 46% &#x2013; 45%, 46% of overall sales for the Body Shop. And it is interesting to note that The Body Shop is only just starting in India with some 20 stores and for the last year or so. So, there will be a lot of expansion planned. The Body Shop at this stage does not exist in China and The Body Shop does not exist in Brazil either. So, we have a lot of potential for The Body Shop, considerable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Between 45%, 46% in emerging markets, is that what you said?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If you take all of the countries, it's 45% to 46% in emerging countries. What was the question to Jean-Jacques and Mr. Agon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The weight of the three brands in Consumer Products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the three major brands which account for 92% of overall sales for the Group. There was another question, what was it? The gross margin increased a lot because of the mix effects and the hair colorant segment regarding variation from one half to the other. It's not significant. It all depends on the balance between the brands and between the different products category, depending on what brands we pushed in the second half. It doesn't mean that there will be any major change. It wasn't linked to the acquisition; they were all concentrated in one half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So fundamental question. Only one to Jean-Paul Agon and to give time for the others. Well, regarding the use of cash, you still have quite a few Sanofi shares. So presumably you are not without cash. You no longer have debt. Now, do you exclude the possibility of a buyback of shares and basically do you feel the need that you build up a stash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll answer that simply, as Christian indicated, our priority in the allocation of cash is for acquisitions, acquisitions, acquisitions and more acquisitions. Number two, there is one interesting concept. The major companies around the world are often companies that are cash rich. So perhaps these days having positive cash situation is not necessarily a problem. And at this stage we have no decision regarding a resumption of share buyback. So, thank you Emmanuel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Pierre Lamelin from Cheuvreux. First question, could you give us the traditional table for the growth between value and volume for makeup &#x2013; sorry, for cosmetics? And secondly, we haven't heard about the Diesel brand for some time. So, how is it doing? And what is the limit for the payout ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was clever on your part. We have never presented the table for volume and value, nice try, as you say. So Christian could tell you about the effect, there is a slight positive value effect. Now while Christian is getting ready, Marc, can you just tell us about the Diesel brand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yes indeed, we did not mention the Diesel brand. In 2010, Diesel grew at a pace which was just under our average growth. But the Diesel brand remains very strategic for the division. It's a recruitment brand. It is a brand for recruitment of men and women to the fragrance market. And the two pillars that we launched during these past years are Only the Brave and Fuel for Life. They have settled well into several markets; France, Germany, the UK. And we plan a very strong launch plan for this year for 2011. And I'm sure that the brand will continue to progress and recruit new customers. What about volume and value, Christian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for sales up 5.6%, the volume effect is just about 5%, so the value effect is 0.5%. A positive volume effect in all the divisions, very positive for Consumer Products, that is no surprise. We're in line with what we had said for the half year results. And for value, a very positive value effect for Professional Products and slightly positive for Luxury and the two other divisions. Consumer Products very slightly negative, and Active Cosmetics is practically at zero, so, so much for volume and value.</p>
          <p>We have a question from the room next door. You sir, you have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Zuanic, Liberum Capital. Just I want to ask a few mathematical questions for Christian, and then if I may follow-up for Jean-Paul. First, Christian, the question was asked before that the growth rate for the market was above 4% for the full year, but the growth rate of L'Or&#xE9;al slowed down as a year progressed. So, does that mean that the company's ability to gain share slowed as the year moved ahead? That's the first question. The second question, last year, if I am not wrong, you did give guidance that EBIT margins would be up for the year. Are you going to give guidance this year? So far you're just saying, sales growth and EBIT growth, but no comments on margins, if you can comment on that? And the third point -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>May I just answer your second question and you will keep the mic for the third question okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, for the second question we are not ready to give precise guidance, but Jean-Paul Agon said that we anticipate the market growth worldwide, which should be between 3% and 4%. And we expect to outperform the market once again this year, because that's what we can say today here in February. We'll see later in the year if we can be more precise. In term of profit, we will not give any precise guidance on our profit, but we can tell you today that we expect an improvement in the EBIT as a percentage of sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the first question maybe, again I said before during the meeting that you should not extrapolate anything of the fourth quarter of 2010. What we have seen in the fourth quarter is that the sell out of our products was generally good. Then the quarters in term of sales of shipments are sometimes volatile. And this should not &#x2013; this should not extrapolate anything on the following quarters. And that's &#x2013; and we believe that the fourth quarter of 2011 will be okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I can just follow-up on one last &#x2013; one mathematical for you Christian and then I will come back to Jean-Paul. I am very much -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, mathematician.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But just one more please, because after that we have other candidates here in the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean, I always think of the 7 &#x2013; the 8% growth rate that you posted in 2007. And if I'm not wrong, your underlying market growth year was about 5%. So you were able to grow about 3 points above the market. Once the market recovered, is that the type of growth rate that L'Or&#xE9;al should aspire to? And I say that because, based on everything you have explained, I'm quite convinced that the company structurally is in much better shape than it was three years ago. So its ability to gain share, should be better.</p>
          <p>Now if I may, just a last follow-up for your Jean-Paul then on the strategic front. <mark type="inaudible" /> Estilo they are, I am sorry to talk about the competition, talks a lot about the high-touch services that they are providing in the department store channel in the U.S. And although I don't necessarily, I'm not a consumer to those products, I don't see necessary L'Or&#xE9;al offering the same type of delivery, if I can use that word, at the department stores that Estilo would be doing.</p>
          <p>And also you know hair care, it's a category that for L'Or&#xE9;al has been, has lagged in terms of growth if I look at your slides, and I'm not talking about color, I am talking about hair care, and obviously Unilever made an acquisition there. So just strategically, what can we expect about hair care going forward, if you can comment in terms of your services or versus high-touch Estilo and department stores in the U.S. And then just last point for Christian on that growth of 2007? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I will take Christian's question, because it's not that mathematical. It's more a question &#x2013; it's more strategic, but first, thank you very much for your comment, because I totally agree with you that we also believe that L'Or&#xE9;al is perfectly equipped in term of brands, products, R&amp;D, innovations and teams to over perform &#x2013; to outperform the market and gain market share and that's absolutely what we intend to do in 2011 and in the years to come. It's &#x2013; some years you can outperform in a major way to market and some other years you outperform maybe a bit less. But our ambition &#x2013; you're perfectly right and I'm totally agree with you is to outperform the market and we think that we have everything in order to do it. That's what we're going to try to do again in 2011.</p>
          <p>Regarding the remarks of Mr. Frieda said for Estilo there, maybe Marc can tell you where.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think these remark of Mr. Frieda is, Luxury is about service is one-to-one and we have been investing a lot also on quality of the service in point of sales in the U.S. One of the key reasons of the &#x2013; the amazing service of Kiehl's, for example, is an amazing quality of service. So it's really very, very high-touch service.</p>
          <p>Also I can underline the very good performances of our brands in Asia and also we know that everywhere in China &#x2013; everywhere in Asia quality of services is paramount importance in the success of brands, and we're doing very well in Asia. So I agree with Mr. Frieda we're doing also a lot to raise the quality of our service in point of sale everywhere in the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we have nothing to be ashamed off. I mean, our Luxury division is very strong. It did well by the way in 2010. The plus 7% was a good number. We grew our market shares in many regions of the world. We are very strong in Europe. We are growing very fast in the rest of the world. So we are very, very committed and very confident about the future success of our Luxury division. Jean-Jacques, hair care.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on hair care, I could not agree with your numbers or the way you view the market. We have a good growth in hair care. Actually it's the category that grows the best after color cosmetics. We had growth in market shares in the U.S. this year and the year where there was a major competitive relaunch by a big competitor. We have a market share growth in Europe and we're penetrating Asian markets like India and China and Indonesia and so gaining share in those parts of the world as well. So both in terms of our sales and in terms of market share hair care is a good category for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, one for Christian</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine for the questions, Shamina, perhaps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Shamina Bhaidjy, Natixis. I have several questions to the two of you. You each get questions. Concerning the working capital requirements, Christian, can you help us a bit for 2011? How do you see that heading evolving, you mentioned a slight increase in the inventory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I thought I was going to help you. Last year when I said that the working capital requirement were decreased by a little over 100 million and a decrease by about 300 million. So this confirms, it's a very difficult line to master. And so I would like to renew for 2011 repeat that the needs will be growing. It will be a need for working capital requirements. Part of the improvement comes from the supplier heading and it is not a deterioration in the quality of payments by L'Or&#xE9;al. It is the pacing of purchases during the course of the year, and it will not be renewed in the same way this year compared with last.</p>
          <p>So, we have if &#x2013; every reason to believe that our working capital requirement will be, well let's say, 100 million to 200 million, so much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question is the operational margin per zone. There was a strong increase in North America in 2010, and the growth was much lower in the new markets. I assume that this is due to the development phase, which is implementing itself. Could you tell us the prospects with the new markets, and what your expectations are for the top line? How do we see things evolving on margins for the other zones apart from Western Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the thing you must look at is, Mr. Agon, is that the profitability in North America has recovered in 2010. It's not so much that it has progressed so much more than the new markets, it has recovered. It had been higher. It had dropped during the crisis. It had strongly impacted North America as you all know. And it's the same thing as for luxury division. It's a great come back. It's a great recovery on the &#x2013; for profitability for North America. So things are not comparable. What is interesting is that the new markets zone has seen its profitability increasing regularly, which is encouraging. It shows &#x2013; it proves that the growth that we are generating there is a profitable growth, and it will continue to grow. We're not going to give you guidance on the profitability per zone this year. But our ambition is to enable it to progress progressively in all three regions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the benchmark of Western Europe, the objective for the other two regions? Can it be reached structurally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's not a good benchmark, because it has this very specific characteristic due to the Group's structure. Maybe, Christian can explain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the margins ex-Europe for Luxury and active cosmetics are integrated in the profitability of Western Europe. Economically, it should be reallocated to the internal client, the North America new market zones. So that part is purely technical. As far as the rest is concerned, there is no reason why China, which has exceeded Germany, Brazil and Russia, could be exceeding other large European countries. There is no reason why they could not reach very high profitabilities. They are today at very high profitability. Otherwise the new market zone would not have profitability at 16.9% which is 80% of, or 90% of what it is in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One very last question. You mentioned a good start for the year 2011. Could you be a little more specific? And my question will be even more specific. Do you see a change in trend per zone? There is a fear of slowing down in the emerging countries. Have you seen a trend per zone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't say some things that I didn't say. I said that the beginning of year was encouraging. I said this because here or there one has read concerns expressed by some people regarding the fact that 2011 would be more difficult than the year 2010 and this is not what we believe.</p>
          <p>We believe that 2011 as far as the market is concerned. It's looking more or less the way that previous year was looking, as far as the possibilities of outperforming the market or we are beginning the year with the same prospects as last year. So there is no reason, why we should do less well.</p>
          <p>And thirdly, we don't see &#x2013; to answer your question, we are not seeing any major change in the consumption patterns, including in the new market zone.</p>
          <p>As I was saying earlier, you must understand that the new market zone is an area, which includes &#x2013; let's say 5 billion inhabitance or something like that. So it's not how much you need. What we are saying is that we are seeing a tremendous boom in Latin America and we are determined to take advantage of that. So Latin America is accelerating compared with its historic pace &#x2013; growth pace of the past.</p>
          <p>We are seeing a good pace in Asia and China is continuing and Africa and the Middle East we are also seeing growth continuing and in Eastern Europe, we are seeing some amount of difficulty. It is no secret that there are number of Central European countries, which are seeing difficulties.</p>
          <p>But all-in-all when you add this all up globally, it remains very dynamic, very positive as is the global economy.</p>
          <p>So we as far as we're concerned are very confident for the year 2011 in terms of market share gains, in terms of growth and growth of our results because our prospects seem good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Capital markets, I have two questions. Do you think that the price mix effect could accelerate this year given the present context? And also you were talking about optimization of the return on investment on your advertising and promotion investments. Could you tell us a little more about that, how can you track the return on investment in that area and what are your objectives in that area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I begin with the return on investment and ask Jean-Jacq, as the Consumer Products division which is the most advanced &#x2013; the monitoring of the return on investment of A&amp;P investments. There are two slides which more or less illustrate what we do. The first is that, we &#x2013; the most important thing is our ability to negotiate good purchasing contracts for our advertising media. So we put into question, media we buy with &#x2013; we reexamine the pitches. We believe that we have the best buying conditions around the world.</p>
          <p>To give you an idea that price of media &#x2013; the price increase in 2010 compared with 2009 and it has gone down a lot then because of the crisis. And I think we were able to gain &#x20AC;50 million in media efficiency compared with a strict comparison with inflation. Now, next thing on the next slide is that in four major European countries, we have setup a modeling system with the best firms consultancy firms and they are able to model from all the sell-through data and the media and promotions. The effect of each Ad campaign in a very precise way and we're going to continue that this year, we're adding a <mark type="inaudible" />. And at the end of the year, we're going to be choosing one or two methods which would &#x2013; which we're going to be working in the future.</p>
          <p>But we are already getting very interesting indications on the way to optimize sales <mark type="inaudible" />. It's not a matter of spending less; it's a matter of spending it in the best way during the course of the year, et cetera. And we've invested in digital as we said, but we're putting ourselves ahead, we're progressing with the encouragement given by Jean-Paul Agon and Marc Menesguen.</p>
          <p>There is one Asian country where we already have evidence that with an exclusively digital campaign, it's a campaign for which there was no other form of advertising, it was only digital advertising, we became number one for a category of product for a specific period. So, we already know how to use digital to gain market shares and increase sales.</p>
          <p>We're very ambitious and confident regarding our ability to optimize these investments, which are very important, says Jean-Paul Agon. We believe that it is an area of improvement for the years to come.</p>
          <p>To answer your first question regarding value, we're not going to give you guidance. We never give guidance on value, thank God. But our ambition just to give you our state of mind is that the value effect should be, we hope, will be better than in 2010. We are not worried about being doomed to have a value effect that would deteriorate over time. On the contrary, in 2011, we have great innovation coming from all divisions, and we believe that it is through innovation that we get the value effect and we believe that we're going to be able to regain some of the value effect in a positive way. And we're going to ask your question from room two. This gentleman has been waiting for an extremely long time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You've already answered, partially the answer that I wanted to ask you. Looking at your operating margin per geographic zone would be interesting because if you look at the overall margin, I mean there is obviously the outcome of the balancing between the gross margins of the three major branches that you've identified. You've already answered on two points.</p>
          <p>You said that the margin for emerging markets should continue increasing, even though it is already higher than the margin that you have in America. And you also said that the European margin should not be used as a benchmark, because it was inflated artificially by some specific conditions. Now I have additional follow-on questions if I may.</p>
          <p>First of all, the margin for emerging markets, should it increase or will it increase in the next five years, will it increase by two or three points as it has done over the last three or four years? And that would mean possibly that the benchmark for all of the regions would probably be to the tune of 20% if we assume that there is an anomaly regarding the present European margin.</p>
          <p>And the second question that I would like to ask is as follows. The American margin which concerns a region that can be compared to the European region in general, the American region is structurally shrinking or reduced by three or four points. Is that a durable and structural phenomenon, is that due to the structure of the product, is that due to the conditions of competition or marketing conditions or phenomenon of the same type, which means that for a long time, we will have a rather big difference between the American margins on the one hand and the European margins on the other that would serve as benchmarks reduced possibly by two or three points as we said for the actual benchmark.</p>
          <p>Regarding the second part of your question, the American margin, if you look at 2010, we see that the American margin can increase &#x2013; profitability can increase. America is a market that I'm very familiar with. It's a highly competitive market. A number of our competitors on the American market, in some sectors, are not very profitable, if you know what I mean.</p>
          <p>But we are firmly convinced as for emerging markets that we can continue increasing regularly our margins in this market. It also depends on how we can establish the right balance between all of our activities. But it is our ambition to increase our margin regularly in the American markets. We are currently doing that. We have Mr. Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Roz&#xE9; in America, and we've urged him to undertake very strong action in order to optimize the industrial facilities, in order to optimize the cost structures of the American operations, and I'm sure that it's going to continue delivering good results in terms of profitability.</p>
          <p>Regarding the emerging markets zone, our objective is to improve margins progressively in all of these countries. As Christian Mulliez was saying, we're no longer at A stage where we have small businesses with high cost and low critical mass. In most countries, we have very large projects with very big critical &#x2013; large critical mass that can give you a very high return on your investment and the new subsidiaries that we're creating are not very costly. We're talking about more &#x2013; bigger countries and we try to establish our presence there gradually. So all of this paves the way, we believe, for regular and sustainable improvements in the profit margin of the Group in general.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have an add-on question here. Can we consider that the European margin is indeed the benchmark and it should be roughly 22% minus, possibly 10% that would correspond to the artificial marketing conditions of your products in this area? So within the next four or five years, an average gross margin of 20% for the United States and emerging countries, could 20% be considered as the benchmark or is that going to happen in the next few years you believe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sure that Christian will give you a very specific answer to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'll give you a very specific and credible answer. It is important to strike the right balance between growth and profitability. Profitability is the outcome of growth. But we don't want to have too high profitability because that would mean that we would take fewer initiatives to support growth and the growth of our markets in emerging markets, and this is not something that we will do. So the growth of profitability in emerging markets will happen in due time at our own rhythm. Yes, but as Jean-Jacques was saying, 20% is not out of the question. It is not impossible in the long run. Was there any other question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian Schubert from the Frankfurt <mark type="inaudible" />. I have two questions. One of the market shares, first of all, do you have figures that indicate the market shares and how do you compare with your competitors Unilever, Procter &amp; Gamble? So maybe sector-by-sector, you could give us an answer or compare to your competitors.</p>
          <p>Now another question, if I've understood well, in the personal care sector, P&amp;G has won quite a lot of market share, so what do you think about the Beiersdorf Company by the way, talking about personal care product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean-Jacques would tell you exactly about the market shares that we have. We don't like to talk about our competitors. The only thing I can tell is that competitors &#x2013; the two competitors that you quoted yourself, our performance in 2010 was better than theirs.</p>
          <p>And that would seem to indicate that we are the ones who won market shares. Jean-Jacques, maybe you can explain where and how we did win these market shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not going to indicate market shares in a very detailed fashion, but in Western Europe, we had indicated the market shares in the past. So we're between 27% and 28%, in total, North America roughly 20%, emerging markets or new markets, roughly 9% market share. And by the way, this shows that there is a lot of margin potential in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Western markets, as I told, 30%, 20% in North America and 9% in emerging markets. Talking about the market shares of our competitors, I don't know, but there are available sources for this kind of information. I mean, I would send you to consult these sources. It depends on which markets you are talking about and how you're looking at these figures. You can look at the different titles, if you don't have these sources, we'll make them available to you and you will see that we are doing quite a bit better than our competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I come from JPMorgan. Productivity gains and cost efficiencies over the past couple of years, can you tell us what are you aiming to achieve and what are you targeting in next year? And second, a small one on the de-stocking comment that you made in the U.S. Has things improved since December or has it got to worse? How intense de-stocking did you see in U.S.? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We didn't say that there was a de-stocking in the U.S. I just said that we should not extrapolate the fact that the growth rate was a bit lower than the quarter before to extrapolate it for the next quarter. So it's not a question of de-stocking, it's a question of phasing, of launches or &#x2013; et cetera. So what we have seen is that the latest news from the U.S. is that the evolution of the consumption was okay, and we expect a good beginning of the year in North America for L'Or&#xE9;al. And so, we are quite positive and optimistic regarding North America in 2011. And your first question was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Productivity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Productivity. Productivity, in fact we had a record year in term of productivity in 2010 and we expect to have another very, very good year in 2011. So we think that we will be able again, and I speak in front of Jean-Philippe Blanpain who is in charge of achieving it. He confirms it that we will have another very good year in term of productivity. In fact that the new &#x2013; the growth of the volume, the units plus the new industrial strategy that we are putting in place is really paying-off in term of productivity and in term of cost of goods. So we are quite ambitious there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just two add-on questions. Regarding Brazil, could you give us the sales per business segment, the enlarged business segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll give you the overall figure unless I don't think that we should indicate this by business segment because this kind of data is confidential. &#x20AC;700 million in Brazil in sales, which is &#x2013; I mean you may guess of course from that, Consumer Products probably account for 65% or 70% of the overall sales &#x2013; of the overall business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry I didn't hear the last bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;700 million with 65% to 70% attributable to Consumer Products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question now on acquisitions. In light of the inflation, increased prices in the Cosmetics sector which is very active, when you say &#x2013; you talk about acquisitions, are you talking about tactical operations here or would the Group be ready to engage in larger scale operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say that tactical is &#x2013; or strategic and significant are two different things. It's very easy to engage in acquisitions. You can buy a company every day. There are companies up for sale in the market every single day at any kind of price. And I can tell you that there is something very clear that I can tell you here. All the acquisitions that were made this year by our competitors are acquisitions that we looked into, all of them. We looked into all of these acquisition projects, and we looked at them in great depth. And obviously, if we didn't engage in these acquisitions, there were good reasons for this, as you can infer from our behavior. So it's not because our competitors are engaging in a lot of acquisitions, but it's necessarily a good thing. Point number one.</p>
          <p>And secondly, as far as we're concerned, the problem is to find so-called strategic acquisitions. Sometimes we have a significant &#x2013; an important or significant acquisition which is the small scale acquisition. Sanoflore, for example, is a bold acquisition, but it's a great brand, a great brand that can become a leading global brand. If you take a small acquisition that we did this year called SE, it's a small nail varnish brand. Our ambition is to turn it into the world leader in nail varnish. It will take as long as it takes, five years, 10 years, 15 years, 20 or 25 years. But it's also strategic importance despite the scale.</p>
          <p>So the issue in terms of acquisition is to target exactly, to pinpoint the complementary products for our portfolio. And we need to engage in acquisitions that will offer the highest middle-term and long-term potential.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It is now 5 past 12, and that was the last question unless there is another one burning, this doesn't seem to be the case. So I'd like to thank you very much for your questions. And we will have a little reception, and you'll be able to meet with all of the members of the Executive Board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>