<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1295660" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>389</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ken Bond, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jeff Epstein, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Safra A. Catz, President</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Lawrence J. Ellison, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Charles E. Phillips, Jr., President</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Adam Holt</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">John DiFucci</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Sarah Friar</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Philip Winslow</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Heather Bellini</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Kash Rangan</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Charles Phillips, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Brent Thill</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everyone, and welcome to today's Oracle Corporation Quarterly Conference Call. Today's call is being recorded. And at this time I'd like to introduce Ken Bond, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kevin. Good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to Oracle's Third Quarter Fiscal Year 2010 Earnings Conference Call. I'm Ken Bond, Vice President, Investor Relations, and with us on the call today are Chief Executive Officer, Larry Ellison; President, Safra Catz; President, Charles Phillips and Chief Financial Officer, Jeff Epstein.</p>
          <p>As reminder, today's discussion will include forward-looking statements including predictions, expectations, estimates or other information that might be considered forward-looking. While these forward-looking statements represent our current judgment on what the future holds, these statements are also subject to risks and uncertainties that may cause actual results to differ materially from statements being made today.</p>
          <p>Throughout today's discussion, we will attempt to present some important factors relating to our business which may potentially affect these forward-looking statements. We encourage you to review our most recent reports on Forms 10-K and 10-Q and any applicable amendments for a complete discussion of these factors and other risks that may affect our future results or the market price of our stock. As a result, we caution you against placing undue reliance on these forward-looking statements, which reflect our opinion only as of today.</p>
          <p>And as a reminder, we are not obligating ourselves to revise our publicly release the results of any revision of these forward-looking statements in light of new information or future results. A copy of the press release and financial table which includes a GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation and other supplemental financial information can be viewed and downloaded from our website at www.oracle.com/investor.</p>
          <p>We'll begin the call with a few prepared remarks before taking questions from the audience. With that, I'd like to turn the call over to Jeff Epstein for his opening remarks. Jeff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ken. Good afternoon, everyone and thank you for joining us. I will review our non-GAAP financial results, focusing on U.S. dollar growth rates unless otherwise stated. But first, a comment about foreign exchange rate movements.</p>
          <p>Excluding Sun, the actual currency benefit we saw this quarter was less than our guidance by approximately 2% for both new license revenue and total revenue. However, even with currency tailwind being less than anticipated, we were able to drive solid results this quarter, as we beat our new license revenue guidance, beat our total revenue guidance and we're at the high end of the EPS range with record Q3 earnings per share. Q3 was a solid quarter.</p>
          <p>Before reviewing our income statement, I'd like to remind everyone that our guidance from last quarter excluded Sun. In discussing revenue, I will provide revenue results as reported, and for some key growth rates I will exclude Sun revenue to align the results to our guidance from last quarter.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, our new software license revenues were $1.7 billion, including $46 million from Sun. New software license revenues were up 13%, and up 10% excluding Sun. This 10% growth beat the high end of our guidance range calling for 9% growth.</p>
          <p>The Americas grew 22%. EMEA was up 3% and Asia was up 12%. Our results continue to underscore the strength, balance and diversity of our business. And the quarter was not dependent on any unusually large deals. Technology new license revenues were $1.2 billion, up 11%, as the Americas grew 20%, EMEA was up 2% and Asia was up 9%. Applications new license revenues were $477 million, up 21% from last year. The Americas grew 26%, EMEA was up 7% and Asia was up 29%.</p>
          <p>Our software license updates and product support revenues were $3.3 billion, including $25 million from Sun, and up 12% from last year. Customer support attachment and renewal rates continue at near record levels.</p>
          <p>Revenues from our hardware systems products were $273 million, while revenues from hardware systems support were $224 million. Our services revenues were $931 million, down 9% as we continue to manage this business to profitable margins.</p>
          <p>Our total revenues were $6.5 billion, including $596 million from Sun. Total revenues for the quarter were up 18%, and up 7% excluding Sun. Total revenues excluding Sun were at the high end of our guidance range, even without the full benefit of currency tailwind included in our guidance. With Sun results now being included in our financial statements, non-GAAP operating income was $2.9 billion, up 13%. The non-GAAP operating margin for the quarter was 45%.</p>
          <p>Our tax rate for the third quarter was 25.9%, as we saw some one-time benefits to our tax rate. Our Q3 non-GAAP earnings per share were $0.38, at the high end of our Oracle-only EPS guidance range of $0.36 to $0.38. Earnings per share were up 9% from last year, and include a $0.01 loss related to the devaluation of the Venezuelan currency.</p>
          <p>In Q3, we repurchased 10.3 million shares at an average price of $24.28 per share for a total of $250 million. As we have previously discussed, the rate of our stock buy-back will fluctuate each quarter, taking into account alternative uses for our cash and our stock price.</p>
          <p>Turning to the balance sheet, we have $17.5 billion in cash and investments. The days sales outstanding, excluding Sun, improved again to 47 days as compared to 49 days last year.</p>
          <p>Finally, we generated $8.0 billion in free cash flow during the last four quarters.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the call over to Safra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff. As you can all see, we had another fantastic quarter. I'd like to first address our performance excluding Sun as this relates directly to the guidance we provided last quarter and then I'll highlight a few points related to Sun.</p>
          <p>For starters, as Jeff mentioned, we exceeded the high points of our new license guidance, with 10% growth in software licenses excluding Sun. This clearly shows substantial strength in the database, middleware and applications business. We also beat the high end of our total revenue guidance with consistent strength in our update and support renewals.</p>
          <p>Results for our application business were nothing short of stunning. We grew 21%, while SAP continues to shrink at a double-digit pace. Our applications business is doing very well in all regions and in all verticals. And it's really no wonder SAP is so unhappy. In addition to our strong top line performance we delivered very strong operating margins. With Sun included, our operating margin was 45%, substantially higher than our peers including IBM. Our operating margin remains much higher than SAP's targets and we are now selling hardware.</p>
          <p>Regarding Sun, as you all know, the transaction closed at the end of January. So our Q3 results for Sun reflect a one-month period, February, which would have been in the middle of their Q3. Sun's revenues for February were 596 million, which was far better than we expected and clearly demonstrates to us that customers are responding well to the acquisition.</p>
          <p>We believe the Oracle/Sun integration is off to a very strong start. We're moving forward quickly to implement the operational changes we described for you on January 27th, and we continue to expect Sun to contribute 1.5 billion in non-GAAP operating income in fiscal year 2011 and 2 billion in fiscal year 2012.</p>
          <p>Now before I turn to guidance, let me just remind everyone that our plans for the Sun business are based on a more profit-aware model. We will no longer be selling products at a loss as Sun did. As we promised in January, we've already ended or modified arrangements where Sun resold other companies' products at a loss. Just this change will immediately mean more profit on lower revenues.</p>
          <p>Second, we're now compensating our sales teams on margin, not just revenue. That has the effect of changing the sales mix from commodity systems, where Sun lost money, to value-added systems where Sun's differentiation is clear to our customers. These two changes will baseline our hardware revenues and profitability at a level from which it will start to grow significantly next year.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to guidance, which will include Sun. We believe that the guidance I'm giving today is conservative. I want to emphasize that our pipelines are very strong in both software and hardware, and the close rates I'm using for software are more conservative than typical Q4 close rates for software.</p>
          <p>For the coming quarter, assuming the exchange rates remain at current levels, we expect there to be almost 3% positive currency effect on license growth rates and almost 4% effect on total revenue growth rates. With that, our guidance for Q4 is as follows: new software license revenue growth is expected to range from 3 to 13% up at current exchange rates and flat to up 10% in constant currency.</p>
          <p>Hardware product revenues are expected to range from 1.2 billion to 1.3 billion at current exchange rates and actually at constant currency. Now these numbers exclude hardware support revenues. These are just the hardware product revenues. Total revenue growth on a non-GAAP basis is expected to range from 36% to 41% at current exchange rates and 32% to 37% in constant currency.</p>
          <p>On a GAAP basis, we expect total revenue growth from 35 to 40% at current exchange rates and 31 to 36% in constant currency. Non-GAAP EPS is expected to be 52 to $0.56 assuming current exchange rates, up from $0.46 last year and from 50 to $0.54 in constant currency. Now GAAP EPS for the fourth quarter is expected to be 37 to $0.41 using current exchange rates and 35 to $0.39 assuming constant currency. This guidance assumes a GAAP and non-GAAP tax rate of 28% for Q4 but may end up lower. Lastly, the board again declared a dividend of $0.05 per share.</p>
          <p>With that I will turn it over to Larry for his comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Safra. I thought I'd review our strategy in two markets where we are not currently the market leader. The first market is high end servers where IBM is our primary competitor and the other is business applications where SAP is our primary competitor.</p>
          <p>Let me start with servers. Since we acquired Sun, we have embarked on putting together clusters of Sun hardware running with our database and middleware software. That is we have a collection of Sun machines, interconnected by a modern InfiniBand network talking to storage also connected to the servers using a modern InfiniBand network. Exedata is the best example of this clustered architecture where we have collections of machines, storage and networks all built together with the software in tune for the software. What we've been able to do with Exadata and there will be other machines like or clusters like Exadata coming out for middleware applications, pretty much all the software that we sell.</p>
          <p>It's not uncommon for an Exadata benchmark when going up against a big IBM pSeries machine to beat them by a factor of ten because they just don't have a clustered architecture. They're stuck with kind of an old-fashioned SMP architecture for transaction processing.</p>
          <p>So we're taking advantage of new technologies, not just InfiniBand, by the way, but Flash, very large scale memory, integrated memories, you'll see. All of that's allowed us to deliver stunning performance using, if you will, commodity parts. And not only do we run much fast than the IBM pSeries but also our architecture because it's clustered there are multiple servers, multiple pieces of storage. It's fault tolerant. There's no single point of failure.</p>
          <p>So it's much more reliable while delivering this fantastic performance and finally it's much lower in cost because the components themselves, if you will, are commodity components that we &#x2013; just disk drives and memory and processors, which we assemble with our software. So we, again, we think we can challenge IBM on the high end of the server market. Better performance, lower cost, and much more reliability.</p>
          <p>In applications, SAP is the leader, but their technology that they use for their applications is a proprietary technology, a German programming language called ABAP where later this year, and that's a 25-year old technology, but it's still the center of their architecture and strategy for applications going forward is ABAP.</p>
          <p>The center of our strategy going forward is Java, and a modern service-oriented architecture. And during this calendar year, we will deliver our Fusion Applications. We've been working on them for a while but we have rewritten, or written in Java all of our accounting software, all of our supply chain software, all of our HR software, our sales automation, our service automation software. It's all been rewritten in Java with a modern service-oriented architecture, and we're going to go compete with SAP's 25-year-old technology. The interesting thing is we're competing quite well against SAP now. We think once we deliver Fusion, we're going to be well positioned to challenge for the number one slot.</p>
          <p>One of the important things about our Fusion Applications is they're designed not simply to run on premise, which of course they do, but they're all on demand or if you prefer cloud ready. So we'll be delivering those applications both by selling the software directly, kind of the old way of doing it, which is still the most popular way, by the way. We'll be selling the Fusion Applications integrated with our hardware, our servers and our storage and our networks and we'll be selling it on the cloud. All modern, service-oriented, 21st century stuff competing against SAP. We think SAP is vulnerable, and we can take them on in a variety of industries.</p>
          <p>The other thing that we're doing that SAP is not doing is we're emphasizing industry functionality. So it's not just technology where we're competing with SAP. We're also competing with them in functionality. So we think we have much more functionality for a telco, a phone company, a large scale retail operation, in insurance and in banking. We have industry specific applications for a variety of industries, Healthcare. I could go on, but &#x2013; so our strategy is to have much better industry focus than SAP in terms of functionality and a much more modern technology underlying all of that functionality.</p>
          <p>Again, it's a company that we think is vulnerable and we think we have an excellent chance of becoming number one in applications.</p>
          <p>With that I'll turn it over to Charles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Larry. The field organization, I thought, did a great job integrating the Sun reps quickly. They executed very well, as you can see, within days and at most weeks we had the accounts and territories and comp plans all assigned. Reps quickly got back in front of customers and that was a key factor in the quarter, and they stayed focused and built pipelines, a great job all the way around the world. All the customer data has been converted over to Oracle systems and pipeline and forecasting processes have been standardized.</p>
          <p>On the customer side, I would say customers are, I still think the best word is, intrigued with our strategy. And a good example is that we had a CIO summit yesterday in Atlanta. It was a day and a half actually. We were expecting about 125 CIOs we invited. We got over 175. 85% of them traveled to get there from surrounding states, and 91% of them were first time attendees to this type of event.</p>
          <p>So we're getting our competitors' customers to come and hear what we have to say. They just want to know what's happening, and I think they sense that there's some sort of transformation in the industry that's possible based on what we're doing. And they want to know exactly what we're planning.</p>
          <p>So we're going to do a lot more of that. We're just getting started. We have four more CIO summits and CFO summit and a CSO summit in the next three months. So get my frequent flyer miles in, but we need to take advantage of this while it's there because we can get an audience with almost anyone right now. So that said, the wind's at our back in that respect.</p>
          <p>By product area, let me start off with database. Exadata, as we've been talking about in recent quarters, the pipeline continues to grow significantly. What's changing now is we're getting multiple orders, multiple machines in a single order, and about 40% of our customers purchased multiple systems in the past quarter. I think Exadata has also generally been responsible partially responsible for generating a lot of the interest in our strategy because it's a good example of what can happen when you synchronize innovation across hardware and software, which is hard to do in this industry.</p>
          <p>Key database wins include Life Technologies. That was a ULA for a Database, Middleware, Apps, kind of wall-to-wall Oracle, and I told him I would mention him because he negotiated the deal at his son's basketball game on a Friday night and still got it done.</p>
          <p>Turkcell, which was a telco in the Middle East. I mention them because this is another ULA for database, Middleware including Exadata, ERP and CRM. They've been also a good customer on the comm side of it. So they're as close to a telco in a box, a strategy that we're embarking on, as you can get. They pretty much do everything on Oracle now.</p>
          <p>And then Buenos Aries city government, and I mention them because they've migrated to Oracle Database 11g for the first time. They were Informix customers. So I just kind of like to remind people; there's still a lot of legacy databases out there like Informix and Sybase and DB2 that we get customers from every quarter. And Buenos Aires city government said they're getting an 80% improvement in performance. They're running that on Oracle Unbreakable Linux. We had some good Linux wins in the quarter including Victoria University, Telkom SA, Reuters and GE Security.</p>
          <p>Switching to Middleware, I'd just kind of like to remind people of the scale that we've achieved in Middleware with 90,000 customers now, and that's not including the 20,000 Apps customers that run Middleware with our Apps and so that's going very well. The upgrade cycle from 11g; I've talked about the 11g launch for the last couple of quarters. On average it's taking customers about 4 to 8 months so that upgrade cycle is continuing as we expected, actually a little better than the last cycle, and there are many customers who are already live on the product.</p>
          <p>There are some components that are yet to ship. As part of 11g over the next 12 months they will be coming out. The ones that are scheduled are Business Process Management, Tuxedo, Enterprise Content Management, Imaging and Process Management and Oracle BI Enterprise Edition. That will generate more upgrades and more uptake of related components.</p>
          <p>Also, in past calls I talked about how important it was to get ISVs to support our Middleware stack. That's driving adoption as well. So in this past Q3 we had 18 key ISV partners, select components, major components of our Middleware to standardize on. That included the North American: Landmark Graphics, SunGard, Intuit, Cerna and EMEA: IFS and LHS.</p>
          <p>So we have a partner technical services organization that's part of development, and they've trained over 11,000 consultants globally and developers on 11g in the last nine months and so that's a key part of getting that adoption. We're starting to see the benefit of that now.</p>
          <p>Key customer wins, Cox Communications, U.S. Department of Transportation selected us over WebCenter to be the portal for their hazardous materials information system. Kaiser Permanente, chose us for BI over Cognos. In the EPM area, we had wins with Carlyle Group and Herbalife and then Identity Management standardized in University of Texas.</p>
          <p>In the applications area, Larry mentioned our competition was SAP. I'm certainly seeing a shift there where I would say two years ago, SAP was considered the safe choice even if the technology was a little bit old and complex to implement and all that. But that seems to be changing as customers appear more nervous about their technology in strategic directions and are more open to discussing things with Oracle, even SAP customers, some of their largest customers. So that's a change that we're seeing.</p>
          <p>And secondly, they don't have anything new to talk about. It's the same product, same technology and basically they're focused on general ledger, and the industry is moving broader than that to include industry applications and entire systems.</p>
          <p>So here are some key wins over SAP in the quarter. IFFCO, a large privately held health food and beverage company in the United Arab Emirates, D&amp;H Distribution, one of the nation's leading technology distributors, a real important one at NBNCo, and this is a new company. We don't get these often but the government of Australia has a national initiative to build a national broadband network from scratch. This is a mandate by the government. It will be the single largest nation building infrastructure project in Australian history. The chief operating officer selected Oracle. He was just actually at headquarters two weeks ago, and he wants to go wall-to-wall Oracle, and he selected us over SAP.</p>
          <p>We beat them at Genuine Parts, Nomura Holdings. We had a good quarter with PeopleSoft. PeopleSoft beat them at the Carlyle Group, Alberta Health Services, UBS, Bank of America, Department of Energy and Ahold. Many more here, too many to list.</p>
          <p>CRM on demand, we had key wins against Salesforce at General Motors, SAIC, Broadcom, Merck, Avis and Starbucks and then important ones for CRM on premise at U.S. Immigration and Northwestern Mutual.</p>
          <p>Vertical applications did well. They actually grew faster than the overall Apps number. And we had a solid rebound in the retail GBU and a big one at Ahold and communications GBU had wins, three each against Amdocs, Comverse and Convergys for building in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Financial Services had wins at Central Bank of UAE, Union Bank of Jordan and National Australia Bank. And an important one in enterprise taxation products; we had the State of Nevada select us for unemployment insurance. The way these deals work, they take one tax at a time. And if we do this one well, which we plan to do, there will be other taxes they migrate to the platform. And then we charge for those as well.</p>
          <p>On the hardware side of it, since we have to start talking about that as well on these calls, we had a good win with Sun RAID. This is their thin client with one of the branches of the armed services which I can't name. But they contracted to deploy a highly-secure multilevel security solution with our thin client device. This is just the beginning. This is going to be scattered across a distributed federal network and they have a planned growth across other commands in the architecture over time.</p>
          <p>We had a win at 101 Internet, the world's number one web hosting company based in Germany and that was 6 M9000 SPARC Enterprise servers. MTN Group in Nigeria has 21 countries, 90 million subscribers so a big telco: Sun SPARC servers Enterprise T5000. And then we had a top 10 U.S. bank that replaced Tandem and HP. That was a replacement there. We had a major financial services company that liked our solid state disk and hybrid arrays, we replaced EMC there. They, in fact, removed EMC from the supplier list when they saw the performance. A lot of good in ones like that on the server side of it and more on the way. The pipeline seems to be there.</p>
          <p>And lastly, I'll mention a large U.S. federal agency which you can probably guess that selected an M8000 and that one will support 5 million pages of handwritten census data that's currently being collected, probably in your mailbox right now, converted into digital format using OCR running on Sun servers.</p>
          <p>So with that, we're pretty excited about the pipeline and what's happening. As you can see, lots more out there. I'll turn it back over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Charles. Operator, we'll take our first question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have our first question from Adam Holt at Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and congratulations on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Adam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned that you're ahead of schedule in terms of the execution on Sun. I was hoping maybe you could drill down a little bit on where you think you're actually ahead of plan. And now that you're a little bit deeper into the integration, where do you see some of the upside opportunities? In particular, what do you think you can do with maintenance revenue in the Sun base? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that really we're ahead on sort of all fronts operationally. Both our business practices are being adopted really as of day one and just operationally, the way we work with our customers has already changed.</p>
          <p>As you know, we've moved to a build-to-order model, versus a build-to-stock model. And we're not encouraging stocking in general even with our resellers. Such that customers can order exactly the box they want, and that way we can optimize for the time it takes to get them exactly that box. And that obviously also reduces any kind of obsolescence or inventory issues for us. That's really in place now for a while and really moving along very, very quickly.</p>
          <p>The regular contractual terms, etcetera, the way we're working with our partners, many of them recognize that the old model really didn't work for either them or for customers and surely not for Sun and are very, very open to readjusting those. And many of those have already been completely adjusted faster than I originally expected.</p>
          <p>As far as maintenance or product support, it turns out that many of our customers are really in need of a higher quality of support that really only Sun can give them, and the Sun Oracle combination. And they are really looking to support that is both hardware and software integrated more and more and so we are really moving ahead both technically and operationally to be able to deliver a more integrated support model for them. And we do expect that customers will be &#x2013; are very happy to purchase their support directly from Sun and not from others simply because the level of support and engineering support that they need really can best, if not only, be done by us at Oracle. So we expect that to be very significant financially ultimately and that's just started of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Terrific. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add one thing to that. When Safra said our business processes are now in place, I think one of the more important ones that is in place is that we look at margin on every transaction and if the margin is not attractive or, worse yet, negative which is often the case by the way in some of the bids we had in flight for high performance computing centers, that we just walked. We chose not to bid those.</p>
          <p>So we said early on we would not engage in transactions where we lost money. We're going to get out of the businesses where we lose money. And again, we look at it transaction by transaction. We do look at the long term and how the importance of the customer. We might lose a little bit of money on a first sale but some of these huge high performance computing transactions, they're &#x2013; adds to our revenue but detracts from our profits and we have &#x2013; our process now identifies those and we walk away from them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from John DiFucci at JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just a question. I just want to make sure my math's right here. You said that the Oracle only software license grew at about 10% constant currency. And it sounds like you had about 5% of a foreign exchange benefit. So you get about 5% constant currency growth from the Oracle only software license. And that was versus the minus 8 to plus 2. Just want to make sure that got that right. Is that correct? Safra or Jeff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's 10% as reported.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you need to take away I think it was 5 points of currency in license. So it would be 5 points of, say, constant currency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then on the guidance, Safra, you said that it assumes lower close rates than you typically see in the fourth quarter. I'm just curious, were the close rates you experienced in the third quarter lower than you typically see? I mean we were hearing sort of mixed messages out there about the macro economy. It still doesn't seem like it's very easy out there. But just curious, what kind of close rates did you see in the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, actually we were flat in &#x2013; in Q3 we were really flat to last year's close rates. We actually are seeing some pretty optimistic customers. Our pipeline is very, very big and the close rates I'm using really are conservative and they're particularly conservative because, as you know, Q4 at Oracle is always a very big quarter because the reps are all motivated by it to close as much as they can for their comp plan. So I just thought, might as well just go with a reasonably conservative close rate, but a realistic one, a potentially realistic one. We are actually quite optimistic about our customers' appetite for our products. Not going to comment on the whole economy. I don't know the whole economy, but we do find a lot of enthusiasm with our customers and deals do look like they're very good size in general.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks. Nice job on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next up is Sarah Friar at Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific. Thanks so much for taking my questions. Two for you. Just on Sun, thanks for splitting out the revenue impact. I know you didn't give the exact cost breakout but can you just give us some sense of whether the costs for Sun ended up more ahead of revenue, just to give us a view of how we think about the full quarter that's coming up when we'll see Sun from both a revenue and a cost perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, Sarah, the reason we didn't give you've a breakout is because we really merged these companies fast. I mean, we just closed them. Any kind of breakout would be really an allocation of a lot of different things and so I'll tell you the best way for you to judge what's going to happen is both to use our guidance and also to really look at what Q4 was.</p>
          <p>This Q3, if you think about it, it was a February. By the time everybody knew where the water fountain was, it was half way through February you would think. So there is &#x2013; there's no way to extrapolate from this Q3 anywhere. Breaking it out is really not possible because you know us, we start integrating right away. Everybody's an Oracle employee as much as possible.</p>
          <p>So obviously, selling hardware has lower gross margins than selling software, regardless. There's just no way to compare it. So our expenses are not a big number in comparison to our revenues. So operating margins, at least for a while, will be lower and you can figure that out from the guidance. So expenses grow quickly. But our revenues are growing quickly also. And you'll be able to really better extrapolate after you see Q4, frankly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then if I could just ask a more product-related question around Exadata. The goal there, is it to replace kind of current data warehousing implementations? Or how do you go beyond kind of big data warehousing implementations into a more broad deployment in someone's IT environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, stage one, Version 1 in Exadata was really aimed at Teradata, Netezza, really the specialist data companies that focused on building custom hardware designed to tackle large scale data warehouses. And that was Exadata Version 1.</p>
          <p>Exadata Version 2 handles not only data warehouses but also handles transaction processing. We added a lot of flash memory into it. And we're going to have new Exadata models. I don't want to preannounce anything. But we're going to get better and better at very large scale transaction processing.</p>
          <p>Our intent is that the Exadata line, challenge the biggest IBM pSeries machines and beats them badly in performance, reliability, and cost. And we think we can do that, where in transaction processing we're twice as fast and in data warehousing we're 10 times as fast. Those are our goals: to be twice as fast as IBM's biggest, best box and again, at a dramatically lower price. And because our architecture is fault tolerant, the answer is all database applications ultimately are better served when they run on an Exadata machine. Everything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on now to Phil Winslow at Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Congrats on the quarter. You all reported impressive return to growth in the application license revenue line. And just wondering if you can gives more of a sense of what you believe is driving that, is the core ERP, CRM, HCM applications? Or what are we seeing in Edge apps? And is there anything across geographies that you see different in the apps space? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to answer and then I'm going to let Charles add to that.</p>
          <p>One is I think our vertical strategy is working extremely well. We're winning large deals in retail, large deals in banking, large deals in telecommunications. And that's dragging a lot of ERP and CRM applications with them. We're doing well in pharma. There are a bunch of industries &#x2013; healthcare in general. There are a bunch of industries where we're very, very strong and we have applications that SAP simply does not have.</p>
          <p>So one of our strategies was to beat SAP in CRM, which we do and then beat SAP in industry specific vertical applications. For example, a telecommunication company has applications to provision &#x2013; you know, you call up AT&amp;T and you turn on your iPhone and you want to turn on interactive TV, well that provisioning software &#x2013; when you provision an application, in a lot of telcos, when you provision an applications, that's the Oracle software that's automatically turning on those services for you. SAP has nothing like that. When you receive your bill, that's an Oracle application that's sending you the bill. SAP has nothing like that. When you deposit money in your savings account, that's an Oracle application that keeps track &#x2013; literally an Oracle banking application that keeps track of it. SAP doesn't have that. And I can go on and on in a variety of industries where we have industry functionality that they don't have. So that gives us opportunities that are simply not available to them.</p>
          <p>We also, we sell these applications a piece at a time rather than a big rip and replace strategy. So when people aren't doing big ERP buys or &#x2013; ERP is a rather mature market. We think we're competing very well in ERP but it is a mature market and SAP is to some degree saturated. And SAP is not a diversified company in terms of their application suite. They don't have a lot of what you're calling edge applications. They don't have a lot of industry specific applications. And their technology is fraying around the edges. And so some of it is our good execution I think and some of it is problems at SAP. We were &#x2013; Safra is sending me &#x2013; we were up 26% in CRM.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean ERP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, couldn't read the slide. We were at 26% in ERP. I suspect that that's a lot better than what SAP is seeing. So we're taking advantage of our strategy that we think is working. We're taking advantage of their weakness. And we think we're going to get stronger while they get weaker.</p>
          <p>I'm sorry to go on for so long but let me say their strategy right now is to try to sell ERP to customers of less than 100 employees. That's their new strategy, business by design, which has been I guess three years late. And by the way, if it's successful, you can't make a lot of money selling ERP to companies with less than 100 people. So we think that's a strategy that goes nowhere. It's a different technology than they currently sell. It's a different sales force. It's different customers than they currently sell to. We think it's a massive distraction for them where our strategy is not to find all new customers. It's to sell more to existing customers so industry specific apps to existing customers, sell technology upgrades to existing customers. We think they've made a fundamental strategic mistake. We think they have lost their way. And if they don't want to be number one, we sure do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. We have a question now from Heather Bellini [ISI Group].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, great. Can you guys hear me okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Congratulations on the quarter, great performance. Safra, I just had a question in terms of you guys shrinking the Sun footprint which you spent some time discussing in your prepared remarks. I'm trying to get a sense for, have we seen the biggest rationalization of the product line at this point? Or are you going to see further partnerships like the Hitachi deal that still haven't kind of worked their way out of the revenue equation yet? I guess I'm trying to get a sense for the pace of the business going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. First of all, I want to make sure you understand that the Sun product line continues in its current form. So there is no cutting back on the Sun product line beyond where we're at. Those products are actually expanding. We've got some incredible products coming up. I mean, the focus of Oracle and the Oracle/Sun combination is on reselling our intellectual property.</p>
          <p>So if you understand that, then you realize that in most places there are certain areas in which obviously we have components from third parties in our equipment and all that, but the real value is in our intellectual property, the way we bring it all together, et cetera. That's the focus of the company.</p>
          <p>Now we do resell some other folks' products. We still are winding down the resale of the Hitachi storage servers. Obviously we're very focused on our customers and for those there will be a very steady wind-down period. And we're managing those together with Hitachi. Hitachi is a very long term partner of Oracle and Sun and things are going very well there. But the big focus of selling other people's &#x2013; those storage servers, that focus is really going to be going onto some of our own products that we've talked about already.</p>
          <p>So that's already in place. There are a few other reselling other people's software and things like that. And, as you know, Heather, that's not what we focus on here at Oracle. So most of it is already disappearing outside of our sales, but again, don't extrapolate anything from a month of February. Really, we'll start to look at this more carefully and really spend some time. You're going get a sense of what our business looks like to &#x2013; you know, after Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add just a little bit to that, which is we didn't add much value selling Hitachi systems. We added no value and we made no money. By the way, it's a fine product and Hitachi should sell it. Anyone who wants to sell it should sell it. Not us. We don't make any money selling that.</p>
          <p>What do we make money selling? Our own storage and we have the ZFS Storage Appliance, also known as a Sun 7000. So we have our own storage server. Sun used to resell VERITAS Backup, terrific product. We make no money reselling that product. We add no value. So we're out of that business.</p>
          <p>The Sun businesses however, we're expanding. We're expanding on the 7000. We're expanding on high-performance high-end servers. So the Sun IP &#x2013; we're expanding and investing in Solaris and Java. The Sun IP and Sun products we're expanding in. Where Sun was simply a distributor of someone else's intellectual property and lost money doing it, we're out of that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. That's what I needed. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on now to a question from Kash Rangan at Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much. One on the Sun channel transition from indirect to direct, how are you guys managing through the transition. And also secondly, a favorite question for you, Larry. How is Fusion turning out to be in terms of code readiness, beta customer feedback? And what is going be the actual breadth of the product when it comes out? Is it going be all the products under the current umbrella? Or is it going be a subset? That's it for me thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to let Charles answer the field or the direct to indirect question or Safra or &#x2013; let's give that, let's throw that to Charles. But let me first answer, how does Fusion look? Well, one thing we did not do, we did not make the mistake of trying to rush this to get this thing out early. I mean, were we late with Fusion? Yes, we were late. I'd much rather be late than deliver a product that isn't extremely high quality.</p>
          <p>[audio interruption] Good morning San Francisco passengers, Clair Main, Clair Main: if you are on board, kindly identify yourself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Stand by. We'll get with that line on our end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. I hope Claire's okay.</p>
          <p>[Laughter].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So customers have been looking at Fusion. Customers &#x2013; we've got a number of large customers lined up to take the product this calendar year. We are &#x2013; again, we've put &#x2013; this is years and years of effort we've put into writing all of this in Java. Modern architecture, modern order orchestration, I can go on and on. But this is 21st century technology. It's really the only application suite. Even Salesforce.com was kind of late 20th century technology.</p>
          <p>So we think we're going to have huge competitive advantage. Customers like it very much because it's &#x2013; because of the fact that it is SOA. So they can use &#x2013; sorry to use so many buzzwords, but they can use BPEL to link the different applications, the different web services together. It isn't a rip and replace strategy. They can take parts of it at a time and gradually adopt Fusion.</p>
          <p>It has a modern Web 2.0 user interface. It's low cost to deploy because everything's written on &#x2013; it's one technology stack, Java technology stack all on our Fusion Middleware. The customers that have seen it see huge value in the built-in Business Intelligence. So BI is not an add-on to Fusion. BI is built into Fusion. The application that you install at your site is the same as the application you run on a cloud, our cloud or someone else's.</p>
          <p>So it's generated a huge amount of enthusiasm. Customers are preparing their own adoption strategies, plans and schedules. And it's all going to happen second half of this year.</p>
          <p>Charles, on the direct versus indirect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the Oracle business &#x2013; core Oracle business pre-Sun, we run about 40% indirect. And that fluctuates actually very little quarter to quarter. It's been pretty consistent for a long time. Sun was definitely higher than that. They ran about 65%.</p>
          <p>We will be shifting that to a more direct strategy especially among the largest customers. We think they want and deserve a direct relationship with Oracle and that's the best way we can provide the level of service that we've been anticipating. So incrementally starting this quarter we'll be more direct. We want the partners to find new business and not show up in the same accounts with us all the time, so fewer four-legged sales calls, as we call them, and shift away from fulfillment and expand the market. So we're going to direct them into the mid-market into the areas where we don't have good coverage.</p>
          <p>We're hiring pretty aggressively right now on the high end to make sure we have our top 1,000 accounts serviced directly by Oracle reps and by Oracle support. And we're also shifting the comp model to pay on net, other words, Sun paid on gross, so the reps were indifferent to whether their partners sold it or we sold it and we've always paid on net, other words, what we get after we pay the partner and that tends to shift things pretty quickly. The partners know that. The VADs know that. We've discussed this with them. They know the strategy and so that will start to happen this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take a question now from Brent Thill at UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. The Americas business did a great job and outpaced Europe. Can you give us a sense in terms of what you're looking at for a recovery in Europe in the second half? Do you expect this to be slower or snap back similar to the pace that we saw in Americas? And I have a follow-up for Charles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'll take stab at it. Europe tends to be more slowly, both on the downturn and on the recovery, so they held up longer. If you recall, that business there, even when the U.S. was turning down, we kept clicking along in Europe for two or three more quarters. So it does tend to take more time. They're more decentralized, a little slower, but the pipelines are growing there. So we expect gradual improvement in EMEA as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, Charles, you mentioned ULAs a number of times. I'm just curious as you see the environment stabilizing, are you seeing more customers coming back to ULAs? And if you could just tie that into Apps business, are you starting to see some of these broader deployments rather than just kind of piecemeal decisions that are being made in divisions? Is that perhaps driving the better than expected growth in Apps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helping. We're also seeing ULAs across multi product categories that includes Middleware and tech and Apps on the same deal and we've learned how to structure those. And the other area is in Europe where the uptake on ULAs wasn't as quick, again because they're so decentralized. We're starting to see them get their act together and see the benefits of doing it all in one contract. And so the ULAs are picking up internationally as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And with that, we will conclude the question-and-answer session. I'll turn things back over to management at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator. A telephonic replay of this conference call will be available for 24 hours. The replay number is 888-203-1112 or 719-457-0820, and the pass code is 784-5753. Also a webcast replay will be available through the close of market on April 1 and can be found on our website at www.Oracle.com/investor. Please call the Investor Relations department with any follow-up questions from this call and we look forward to speaking with you. Thank you all for joining us on today's conference call. And with that, I will turn the call back to the operator for closing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Once again, ladies and gentlemen, that will conclude today's call. We thank you again for joining us. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>