<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1205256" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-01-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>390</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christopher G. Stavros, Vice President Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Ray Irani, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Stephen I. Chazen, President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michael Jacobs</participant>
      <participant id="5">Stephen Chazen</participant>
      <participant id="6">R. Casey Olson</participant>
      <participant id="7">Robert Kessler</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ray Irani</participant>
      <participant id="9">Arjun Murti</participant>
      <participant id="10">Erik Mielke</participant>
      <participant id="11">Paul Sankey</participant>
      <participant id="12">Jason Gammel</participant>
      <participant id="13">Pavel Molchanov</participant>
      <participant id="14">Faisel Khan</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the Occidental Petroleum fourth quarter 2008 earnings release call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you. Mr. Stavros, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Shardae and good morning everyone. I'd like to welcome you to Occidental's fourth quarter 2008 earnings conference call. Joining us on the call from Los Angeles this morning are Dr. Ray Irani, Oxy's Chairman and CEO, Steve Chazen, our President and CFO and Casey Olson, President of our International Oil and Gas Operations.</p>
          <p>In just a moment, I will be passing the call over to Dr. Irani, who will discuss our plans for managing the business in the current challenging economic period, as well as some of our future growth opportunities. Steve will then review our fourth quarter and full year 2008 financial results and provide some additional insight on our capital spending plans for 2009. Our fourth quarter earnings press release, Investor Relation supplemental schedules, and the conference call presentation slides which refer to Steve's remarks, can be downloaded off of our website at www.oxy.com.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Dr. Irani. Dr. Irani, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Last year was an interesting year. Oxy achieved solid results in 2008, including record earnings of $6.9 billion, an increase of 27% from 2007. However, 2008 was in fact three years in one for our industry. Collectively, we experienced solid growth in the first part of the year, followed by unprecedented record-high oil prices, and finally a collapse of those prices as the global economy went into recession.</p>
          <p>Today, I will focus on how we plan to manage and grow the business in the future, even though the current economy and low oil and gas prices make it challenging. First, I want to mention a few developments from 2008 that will be key to Oxy's continued success. Oxy's worldwide production increased 5.4% over 2007, reaching 601,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day. Even more significant was the growth in our oil and gas reserves. We estimate that we replaced approximately 200% of our production in 2008, without taking into account the effect of price changes from 2007 to 2008, with the majority coming through organic growth. Steve will talk more about this later on.</p>
          <p>We ended the year with cash on hand of $1.8 billion and very little net debt. And in the past 12 months, we have capitalized on some key opportunities to strengthen our position and achieve further growth. In the fourth quarter of 2008, we signed an Exploration and Production Sharing Agreement with the government of Oman to develop four medium-sized gas fields and to explore for potential new discoveries. We expect the existing fields to reach production of 10,000 BOE per day, net to Oxy.</p>
          <p>We also continued production growth at the Mukhaizna oil field in south-central Oman, where we have a major steam flood project for enhanced oil recovery, one of Oxy's technological strengths. As of year-end 2008, gross daily production was over six times higher than the production rate in September 2005, when Oxy assumed operation of the field from Shell. In the third quarter we signed a preliminary agreement with the Abu Dhabi National Oil Company to appraise and develop two medium-sized oil and gas fields in Abu Dhabi. Oxy will operate both fields and will hold 100% interest in the concessions. When fully operational, we expect these two projects in Abu Dhabi to produce 20,000 BOE per day.</p>
          <p>Additionally, you may have seen the recent media reports that Bahrain National Oil and Gas Authority has selected Oxy as the winner of the competitive bid to develop oil and gas assets in the Kingdom of Bahrain. Our respective teams are now finalizing the relevant technical and financial agreements. Various Bahrain agencies and government authorities have already approved Oxy as the winning bidder for the project and we hope to have the completed agreement approved by the Bahrain Parliament before year-end.</p>
          <p>Our strong balance sheet has also enabled additional growth of Oxy's reserves in the Permian Basin, Mid-Continent and California in the United States. We intend to continue acquiring additional desirable assets as they become available in the U.S. at more attractive prices.</p>
          <p>In 2008, we spent about $4.7 billion on capital expenditures. This year we plan to spend approximately $3.5 billion on projects that will allow us continued growth while protecting our targeted financial returns. We maintain a firm policy of pursuing only those opportunities which meet our standards for return on capital employed and complement our existing assets and core areas.</p>
          <p>The ongoing turbulence in the global economy only reinforces the logic of our selectivity in considering potential transactions. But even with reduced spending, we are confident that we will grow our production in excess of 5% both this year and next, much of that growth from our international projects, including those I discussed earlier. We are also currently focusing on increasing our operational efficiency throughout the company. We are reducing key cost areas including overhead, external purchasing and outside services. Steve will give you additional details about all of this in a moment.</p>
          <p>The coming months will be challenging for all businesses in all industries. However, in good economic times and bad, Oxy is well-positioned to succeed. Oxy will continue to maintain a low-risk, low-leverage profile and a consistent focus on building stockholder value. With our concentration on core areas, growth in production and reserves, and our efficient operations and strong balance sheet, we are confident in our ability to achieve sustained growth and solid profitability.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call over to Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ray. Net income for the quarter was $443 million, or $0.55 per diluted share, compared to 1.5 billion, or $1.74 per diluted share last year. The 2008 fourth quarter net income includes after-tax non-core charges totaling $514 million. These charges included $390 million for impairment of undeveloped acreage in Argentina and Yemen, $27 million for impairment of U.S. producing oil and gas properties, $37 million for rig contract terminations and $55 million for chemical plant closure and impairments. Core results were $957 million, or $1.18 per diluted share in the fourth quarter of 2008, compared to $1.5 billion, or $1.76 per diluted share last year.</p>
          <p>Here's the segment breakdown for the fourth quarter. Oil and gas fourth quarter 2008 segment earnings were $339 million, compared to $2.5 billion last year. Oil and gas core results for the fourth quarter were $996 million, after excluding the asset impairments and rig termination costs. The following accounted for the decrease in oil and gas earnings between these quarters.</p>
          <p>$1.5 billion decrease in the fourth quarter of 2008 core results was due to $1.4 billion lower crude and natural gas prices, and a benefit of 0.1 billion for higher volumes offset by higher operating expenses, DD&amp;A and exploration expense. Occidental's average realized crude price for the 2008 fourth quarter is $53.52 a barrel, a decrease of 33% from the comparable period last year. Oxy's domestic realized gas price for the quarter was $4.67 per mcf, compared with $6.77 per mcf in the fourth quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Worldwide oil and gas sales volume for the fourth quarter of 2008 were 620,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, an increase of 5% compared to 590,000 BOE in the fourth quarter of last year. The increase includes 22,000 BOE a day from Dolphin, 14,000 BOE a day domestically and 6,000 BOE a day from Oman, offset by 12,000 BOE per day lower production in Libya as a result of the new contract terms. The fourth quarter of 2008 oil and gas sales volumes were 32,000 BOE a day higher than the third quarter of 2008. Exploration expense, excluding non-core items, was $134 million in the quarter. Fourth quarter non-core items included impairments of undeveloped acreage in Argentina and Yemen, impairment of producing oil and gas properties and rig contract terminations.</p>
          <p>Chemical segment earnings for the fourth quarter of 2008 were $127 million. After excluding the plant closure and impairments, the fourth quarter core results were $217 million. The higher earnings were attributable to higher caustic soda margins. Chemicals earned $94 million in last year's fourth quarter. Midstream segment earnings for the fourth quarter of 2008 were $170 million, an increase of $32 million from the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>The improvement in earnings was due to higher margins in crude oil marketing, higher pipeline income from Dolphin and lower NGL margins in the gas processing business. The fourth quarter of 2008 results also included after-tax foreign exchange gains of $88 million, which is, of which $70 million was in oil and gas.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to our 12-month performance. The net income was a record $6.9 billion, or $8.35 per diluted share for the 12 months of 2008, compared to 5.4 billion, or $6.44 per diluted share for the same period last year. Core results for the 12 months of 2008 were 7.3 billion, or $8.95 per diluted share, compared to 4.4 billion, or $5.25 per diluted share for the full year of 2007. Income for the 12 months of 2008 included $491 million of charges, net of tax and 2007 include a $1 billion benefit, net of tax, for the items noted on the schedule attached.</p>
          <p>We have broken out oil and gas production taxes and ad valorem taxes into a separate line called "taxes &#x2013; other than on income" for disclosure purposes to highlight their sensitivity to product price variation. These taxes were $2.62 a barrel in 2008 compared to $1.97 a barrel in 2007. Oil and gas cash production costs were $12.13 a barrel for the 12 months of 2008, compared to last year's costs of $10.37 a barrel. The bulk of the increase related to higher maintenance, workovers and field operating costs.</p>
          <p>We currently estimate that we replaced approximately 200% of our oil and gas production in 2008, without taking into account the effect of price changes from 2007 to 2008. With the effect of price changes, we estimated we replaced about 150% of our production. Slightly over half of the reserve additions, excluding the effect of price changes, came from internal sources resulting in over 100% reserve replacement. Major increases were in the California properties, Permian and the Rockies, and in Oman, which in aggregate constituted more than half of such reserve adds.</p>
          <p>Last year's capital program was about $4.7 billion. Additionally, we spent another 4.7 billion for acquisitions. As a result of these expenditures, we have accumulated a sizeable inventory of projects. The bulk of these projects can be delayed until such time as the industry cost structure is in line with product prices. We believe that the service company cost structure is more reflective of an $80 oil environment than a $40 one. An illustration of our ability to defer drilling is that we have a total of 5 million net acres in the United States. 70% is held by production, about 10% consists of long-term leases, with many years on average to run, with the remainder in mineral acres held in perpetuity.</p>
          <p>This year's capital program of $3.5 billion will focus on ensuring that our returns remain well above our cost of capital given current oil and gas prices and contractor costs. About 80% of the capital will be in oil and gas and the remainder in midstream and chemicals. Gas drilling with less than $5 an mcf gas is generally unattractive. We will continue to fully fund our Middle East operations, our successful exploration programs in California and Utah, and our exploration in Argentina. Formerly "quick payout" wells in the Permian and California will be deferred until they become "quick payout" again. We will also continue to fund our midstream and CO2 programs.</p>
          <p>You should expect that our capital run rate in the first quarter will be greater than the $3.5 billion level and will decline all year unless economic conditions improve. The effect of this program on our production should be fairly modest this year, around 10,000 BOE a day, resulting in a probable production range of 620,000 to 660,000 BOE a day and with about 630 to 650 (sic) [630,000 to 650,000] BOE a day in the first quarter. Year-over-year, Argentina and Oman should show the most growth.</p>
          <p>We are also focusing on internal costs. Some reductions in overhead will be made this year which should improve our overhead levels by at least $1 per BOE. We are renegotiating our supplier contract to further reduce costs and are laying down rigs, including paying cancellation costs when that makes sense. We expect these programs to result in reduction in the cost of executing our capital programs, as well as a reduction of our operating expenses.</p>
          <p>Oxy's focus has been and will continue to be delivering returns well in excess of our cost of capital. When costs and prices are in line, our capital program will be boosted and the project inventory worked down faster. Cash flow from operations for the 12 months was $10.7 billion. We used 4.7 billion of the company's cash flow to fund capital expenditures, 4.7 billion for acquisitions and $940 million to pay dividends. We spent $1.5 billion to repurchase 19.4 million common shares and we borrowed $1 billion in the fourth quarter. These and other net cash outflows decreased our $2 billion cash balance at the end of last year by $200 million to $1.8 billion at December 31.</p>
          <p>The weighted average basic shares outstanding for the 12 months was 817.6 million and the weighted average diluted shares outstanding was 820.8. At December 31, there was approximately 810.4 million basic shares outstanding and the diluted share amount was approximately 813.5 million.</p>
          <p>Our debt to capitalization ratio was 9%. Last year's return on equity was 27%, our return on capital employed was 25%. As we look ahead to the current quarter, we expect exploration expense to be about $60 million. We expect chemical segment earnings for the first quarter to be about $100 million. High caustic soda margins are expected to continue throughout the period offset by continued weakness in the construction and housing market impacting domestic demand.</p>
          <p>Despite the difficult economic conditions, exports are anticipated to show modest improvements over the abysmal demand of the fourth quarter. The worldwide effective tax rate on the core income was 40% for 2008. We expect our combined worldwide tax rate in the first quarter of 2009 to be about 46%. The increase in the rate from the prior year is caused by a higher foreign-sourced income expected in 2009, as a percentage of total income. Our fourth quarter and 12-month U.S. and foreign income tax rates are included in the Investor Relations Supplement.</p>
          <p>Oil &amp; Gas DD&amp;A expense for 2009 should be approximately $11.50 per BOE. Depreciation for the other two segments should total approximately $400 million. We expect to have severance and similar charges in the first quarter of 2009. Copies of the press release announcing our results and the supplements are available on our website or through the SEC's EDGAR system.</p>
          <p>We're now ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Michael Jacobs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for all of the additional guidance on capital spending. Steve, you touched on kind of your return-focused investment philosophy and while you're business model doesn't warrant some of the tougher decisions of trying to live within cash flow. Can you just take a second to discuss what differentiates the Oxy business model and how you think about potentially accelerating cash flows at the cost of returns in the current environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Since we can't predict oil prices, we have to live with what the oil prices are and if we look at each project, especially U.S. projects, which have &#x2013; which are sort of infinitely deferrable. We look at the returns of the current oil situation or gas situation and figure out what the returns are and if the returns are below our cost of capital, we'll defer it. When you get a different cost structure or price structure, whichever or both, we'll reevaluate that and boost the spending or decrease it for that matter. So as long &#x2013; we have a lot of flexibility in deferral; maybe not infinite, but a lot. The contracts outside the United States basically have production sharing contracts, which tend to protect the returns. When things are real good, they don't return as well as you might hope. And when things are bad they cushion the blow. So we've lived this $40 environment and it wasn't that long ago so &#x2013; but all we're doing is bringing our capital spending down to our 2007 levels. We are investing for growth and we're protecting our long-term outlook, but just deferring some things that we could defer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Moving on to reserves and specifically focusing on Oman, we've seen some pretty meaningful production growth in the last few quarters, it seems is clearly penetrating the reservoir in Mukhaizna, can you give us a quick update of what you're seeing operationally and how that factored into reserve adds in 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll let Casey talk about the operational part I think, but on the reserve adds, it was a sizeable reserve add in Oman probably the &#x2013; almost I guess the largest single area of reserve adds last year. So, and also there were some price &#x2013; positive price impact there too because of the production sharing contracts. We're not through with the reserve adds there just so &#x2013; there's still more, as the steam continues to penetrate we'll add additional reserves. Casey?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operationally things are going very well. As we've said, there have been some substantial increases in production. They are right in line and our development plans are turning out right in line with what we anticipated when we won the project a few years ago as we noted in the comments, gross production from the field is up over six times what it was at the end of 2005 when we took over the operations.</p>
          <p>I think we can say that in general the reservoir is in fact performing better than we expected. The steam flood project is doing exactly as we thought it would; but as I've said, performing even better. We had a lot of facility activity during the course of the year, building these huge water treatment facilities that ultimately purified the water and generated the steam. There were some moderate delays during the course of the past year in getting those on stream, by the end of the year we were fully caught up. The remainder of those facilities will be completed as expected and on time this year and so we remain very confident in both the performance of the reservoir and our potential to continue to meet the anticipated schedule for the increase of production to probably 150,000 barrels a day gross by late 2011, early 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you. Just one final question before I hop back into the queue. You mentioned higher workover expenses were partly responsible for the year-over-year increase in LOE, just looking ahead how much of an improvement would you expect in your cost structure, as you reduce your "quick payout" activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Overall for the company probably about 70 or $0.80.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Robert Kessler.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning gentlemen. With respect to reserve replacement last year, it looks like about 50% of your production equivalent was a negative price effect, I guess it's about 110 million barrels equivalent. I was curious if you could perhaps close that up to the positive effects of PSCs and the negative effects of shortening production lives and maybe a little bit more on the geography particularly the shortened production life.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's fairly straightforward on the shortened one, since we're only in effectively three places. So Permian obviously and Hugoton gas reserves, and some in California. So the big, big slog is in the Permian. You know you have a mismatch right now on this price revision. You use the year-end prices, but you effectively -- your costs for cut-off are the old higher costs. So you wind up overstating I think the negative revisions in the domestic properties, because you have a mismatch between your costs and your price and you're not allowed to forecast a decline in your cost of operating, using SEC rules. So I &#x2013; my guess is this number will- if we ran it a year from now on the prices with the same kind of price change, we'd have a much smaller number. So we'll recoup the stuff, but in the production sharing contracts, offset a lot of the big, big gains in Dolphin and in Qatar where, and Oman were the big pieces of that, so, we'll give you more detail when we roll out the exact numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But no guesstimate on the magnitude of the positives for PSCs, in aggregate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I'd just as soon not get into that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It looks like on the cost side, you're certainly doing your part to try and lower the $80 a barrel cost environment down to $40 a barrel with the $58 million termination charge on rig contracts and the like, can you get any more specific on where that is and future contract cancellations? I'm assuming maybe in the Permian -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're about done with the contract cancellations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The &#x2013; we've begun to see some reduction from some of the service companies. But certainly not the order of magnitude we'd like to see. But looking at their results, it looks like they're still making too much money to me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ben Dale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, hi, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just had one question regarding your U.S. gas prices, they came in relatively low versus the benchmark, I wonder if there was any particular reason for that during the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The gas out of the Rockies and the Permian, which basically heads West was crummy, which is why we're reducing the drilling in the Rockies now. It's tightened a little bit, but not very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you look at that going forward, is there any plans to put in any sort of basis hedges to cover that going forward or is that something you've avoided?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've avoided that because of &#x2013; it seems like a way to make the brokers rich and me poor. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I just had one another question there's been some talk obviously in the news recently about Libya, commentary coming out about the potential for re-nationalization, which seems like more noise than anything else. I was wondering if you could just give us your view on that if you have heard anything from the Libyan government.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is noise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's Ray, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Arjun Murti.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. First thanks for breaking out the production taxes, that'll be helpful. The rig contract cancellations, can you say where they are Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually they are scattered. Somewhere here I have it. But they're &#x2013; South America and Mid-Continent are the bulk of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Some Piceance drilling as well I presume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's, yeah, we call it Mid-Continent...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, got you. Got you. If I missed in your remarks, I apologize, I assume the pace of stock buyback slows, you want to preserve balance sheet capacity to keep all options open or am I mistaken of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you're not mistaken. But we're &#x2013; we'd like the business to get some idea of where we're headed here. I keep on reading Wall Street reports and I could get any number I want, so I'm waiting for more consistency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I know those reports are so helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're very helpful, we always listen to them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we'll keep them coming. On the production potential for the Middle East projects can you scale that &#x2013; either of the new ones, Bahrain, the couple from in Abu Dhabi and Oman net or gross production over the next few years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I said in my remarks, Arjun, we expect growth in 2009 even with reduced capital of 5%; the growth for the company would come primarily from the Middle East projects, which I talked about. An additional 5% growth in 2010 and further as you go down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The list is in the remarks, that the individual projects, the Bahrain one because of the &#x2013; it's not a signed contract, we just don't want to talk about that at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. I guess it seems like some of those projects will help offset whatever declines or less growth from the Permian, California and then Rocky --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't expect declines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Erik Mielke.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. My question relates to the chemicals business. Can you give us an update on what you're seeing in 2009, in particular in light of the write down that you've taken in the segment as well? And I have a follow up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The write down are basically PVC plants. It's a relatively small PVC plants and that's &#x2013; it's not material in the total. Basically those plants &#x2013; we added capacity and in one of our large plants and we're basically taking out the capacity in the smaller, less efficient plants. We don't know &#x2013; we had a good fourth quarter, a crummy December and there are some signs of life this quarter. But we've outlooked the earnings for the chemical segment. I wouldn't view that as reflective of necessarily other people's chemical segment. This is pretty narrow a business. The demand for caustic soda has declined some but not as fast as the decline in people's production of it, because there is no place to put the chlorine. So we wouldn't go out and outlook the whole year at this point. We're lucky to get the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the 100 million you've outline for the first quarter therefore is just &#x2013; that's as far you can go at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so the 100 million you've outlined for the first quarter is the size you go in terms of guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's as far I am willing to &#x2013; anything else wouldn't be very reliable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'd be guessing, we're giving you what we think that</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we think we have a feel for &#x2013; beyond that you have to do macroeconomics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And wait on the new President's plan to succeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe he wants to buy a bunch of PVC pipe in the next...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my follow up question is on &#x2013; a follow up to an earlier question on capital cost in the industry. Can you talk a bit about what are the areas in particular that you think costs need to come down and maybe the timeframe in which you envision this happening?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, steel costs have already started to fall, and they're falling fairly sharply but there is more to go there. They look like they fallen maybe a third or so from the peak. The big cost in the business is not so much for us. If you don't have a big offshore drilling. It's really completion costs and the completion costs are the area where I think there is a lot more room for improvement by the service providers. So, I think that's the big area I would look for &#x2013; seismic stuff will probably fall like a rock, right now. But I think the completion costs are the key area. And that's mostly labor and not so much hard goods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That can be quite sticky.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the suppliers want it to be sticky.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of timing, are you optimistic that you might see more of a match towards the middle of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're always optimistic, but who knows. They're coming down. There is no argument that it's coming down. It's just not -whether it's fast enough. And I think like a lot of people, they're hoping that the current environment is temporary and good times will come back, so they won't have to cut so much. And as, we'll see as the year progresses since our crystal ball is no better than anybody else's.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, can I ask about the M&amp;A landscape. You've previously been very willing to talk about the gap between the bid-ask spread on what the sellers were looking for and what the buyers were willing to pay. Are you seeing signs of that is changing, would you consider making, what you can probably term as strategic resource acquisition, such as the Oil Sands or are you keeping your wallet closed at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't &#x2013; there's just not a lot of opportunity right now. The amount of, the material that's up for sale is probably shrinking rather than growing. And there really isn't a lot of opportunity I think. We have the same view as the service people, this temporary and good times will come here soon. So I'm &#x2013; as far as for the short term we don't see anything as far as resource for &#x2013; we're mostly looking for cash flow, and less looking for &#x2013; we got a huge inventory of things to do. And this is an enormous inventory of things to do, once we get the costs in line. And we will &#x2013; so there's no pressure on us to do something that's to build some imaginary resource. So as far Oil Sands are concerned, we'll wait and see how that shakes out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Paul Sankey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that you expect to grow by more than 5% volumes in 2009 and 2010. And you also said that you felt that the lower CapEx wouldn't have a major impact on 2009 volumes. So I was wondering, what the scale of the impact you'd expect to see on 2010 was, in volume terms?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't know &#x2013; we gave you a rough idea for this year, about 10,000 barrels a day, and we just don't know. And I think some of these other projects that Ray has talked about will more than offset whatever effect that is. Remember that the capital we're taking out was largely focused on "quick payout" sort of things rather than the long-term, and so we just don't know. We're hopeful that by year end that the costs will be in line with the product prices. And so, there may not be much effect in 2010. But if it is, it's still not going to be a big number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. And in terms of the split between gas and oil, do we assume that the &#x2013; your previous plan from two quarters ago, you had nat gas growing in '09, I guess we would expect to see more impact on nat gas based your contract.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, more impact on domestic gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have the similar number to the $5 per mcf number that you gave for oil, at which drilling becomes unattractive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, probably under 30.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, if we could just move over <mark type="inaudible" /> to Argentina, can you just talk a little bit more firstly about the impairment, secondly about the contract negotiations, and thirdly about the outlook for growth in the context of both of those? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The impairment was the acreage, not the production. And it's sort of tied to the contract discussions where we've been in discussions with them about extending the contract, but no results yet. And that acreage really depends, exploiting that acreage well depends on the contract extension. So when the &#x2013; without a contract extension in the current environment, that we thought it prudent to expense the acreage at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the prospect there for the extension?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're still talking, but I can't give you a deadline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We just -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>... governments whether it's in Argentina or Libya, it's dangerous to start to give you deadlines on when this might happen. Discussions continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. So we'd expect volumes then to be relatively flat to down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, no, no. We expect good growth in Argentina, and more modest than we would have told you a year ago. But there would be growth in <mark type="inaudible" /> Argentina in 2009, modest, but definitely growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Those are it for me. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jason Gammel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys. My question was, just trying to get pretty exhausted here, but I wanted to come back to the reserve replacement numbers. And you had put that in context to capital spend as well. I've got capital spend roughly 3.8 billion in the upstream in 2008. So, am I kind of in the ballpark in thinking that were it not for price effects, finding and development costs would be have been in the range of about 17.50 a barrel, which is a pretty favorable comparison to what you've done in the last couple of years and the industry, but when we look at the numbers that will actually get reported in the SEC reports, that number will be more like 35 a barrel, does that sound about right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 17 is about right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But if you just wait, in a week or two you'll get the accurate number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the 17 is about right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's all I had, guys. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Pavel with Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Historically you have avoided hedging and certainly it worked very well in first half of '08, are you reevaluating your position in hedging in light of the current commodity environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any circumstances where you would?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I suppose, I just can't come up with it right now. You never say never, I suppose, but the answer to your question is that &#x2013; my view on the counterparty risk is not becoming more comfortable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sounds good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Faisel Khan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much of the 5% growth rate in '09 is coming from the acquisitions that you guys made in '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not very different than the chart we gave you in July.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's &#x2013; you might be a little off on, there's obviously a &#x2013; every time you re-estimate things move around, but in aggregate it's not very different than the chart we gave you in July. A little more probably the growth out in the Middle East, because production sharing contracts have boosted our production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the projects in Oman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That was in the chart there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From &#x2013; in July.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's not a lot different, except again we could re-estimate this every month to come up with slightly different numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. And in the new gas projects in Oman and Abu Dhabi, what kind of gas price should we expect in those projects, is something going to be linked to some GCC oil price or will it be something else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just cover this in total. Just like we told you in Dolphin, the returns on both projects will be attractive and that's all I care to share with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. On your &#x2013; sorry go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean that the projects include liquids and they include gas and so on and so forth, so to get into breaking out what this is and that is, the returns are very attractive even at today's price environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the SandRidge deal that you guys signed last year, how is that project progressing in terms of construction and in terms of drilling on their end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know &#x2013; we don't watch their drilling, but you can ask them about the drilling I think, but the plan itself is on track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And you are pretty confident that they'll deliver the CO2 volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think so. But, it's like any other contract that we believe they will and the CO2 is there. So there isn't a question of whether it's there or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just a matter of drilling the wells and there's no &#x2013; you won't see anything until into next year sometime, 2010. So we don't see &#x2013; we have no reason to believe they won't deliver.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a long-term investment and it's going to happen and it's going to improve our production but to try and guess which months in 2010 or 2009 it's happening would not be useful. So it's here for the longer term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't see any reason to believe that they won't drill the wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. In the last quarter I believe you guys accessed the debt capital markets, do you foresee yourself doing that again this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Given our current program we wouldn't probably. If we buy stuff or something like that then we'd look at it again. Our debt, if you take it to per barrel equivalent, we've got round figures at three billion barrels of reserves and we're pretty much committed to keeping our debt below $2 a barrel. So we've got &#x2013; that would be $6 billion of debt, from my perspective, debt capacity. And so we're a long way from that. So, but we don't foresee a need to just for operations to tap the markets. We have some debt maturities this year about 700 million or so of debt maturities and so we'll just see where we are. But we would only tap it for some sort of opportunity probably.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Thank you for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> You have a follow-up question from the line of Michael Jacobs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just a follow-up, kind of high-level question for Ray. You currently have a lot of international development opportunities in the queue. From a high level have you seen an increase in demand for your capital or technical expertise with respect to any future opportunities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Governments don't react that quickly and the places where we operate are quite different from one country to another. Clearly, when you're dealing with Abu Dhabi, they have plenty of money. They don't need the money, it's the technology and the know-how we have. The other places it's different. But overall, there is no demand for additional investment. Our program has always been long-term and the projects we just announced, we had been working on them for at least three years, some more some less. And we have in the pipeline other projects which down the road will happen, it's not an instant response sort of thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Monroe Helm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Now this is for Steve Chazen. I got on the call late, so apologize, if I'm asking something you've already answered, but I think when I first got on you were discussing your outlook for the potential for domestic acquisitions, and I thought I heard you say that there's still a big gap between what you think the assets are worth and what the sellers think they're worth is that an accurate assessment and do you think given the problems in the banking system that there could be assets for sale later &#x2013; mid to late this year, because of pressure from the banks on people to get more liquid?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean you don't know. It's also &#x2013; there really isn't much out there being offered either. I think most every &#x2013; it isn't just as the bid-ask spread is wide, there's nothing to bid on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That amounts to much. So I think almost everybody is in some belief that by midyear or some other time things are going to get better and all we can do is wait &#x2013; what we just don't know. I think the pressure from the banks doesn't seem to me to at this point to be a lot of pressure on small producers by the banks. Don't really see it even they renegotiate the reserve base, because actually the bank really doesn't want to impair the value of any loans I think right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that your own assessment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>... Impair loans right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So on your own personal assessment though, things will get better by the middle of the year or there is no way...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't know -we've &#x2013; I slept through the economics course in school.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good for you that's why you're a good CFO, or were, now president, <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time. Do you have any closing remarks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you operator. And please feel free to call us in New York, if you have any further questions. Thank you for listening in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's Occidental Petroleum fourth quarter 2008 earnings release call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>