<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1406250" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>390</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Christopher G. Stavros</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">James M. Lienert</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Stephen I. Chazen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor Pickering Holt &amp; Co. Securities, Inc.">David M. Heikkinen</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Paul Sankey</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Ed G. Westlake</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President">William E. Albrecht</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (USA), Inc.">Jason D. Gammel</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Faisel H. Khan</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="IHS Herold, Inc.">Sven Del Pozzo</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Susquehanna Financial Group LLP">Duane Grubert</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Americas Securities LLC">John P. Herrlin</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Katherine Lucas Minyard</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Evan Calio</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Christy, and I will be your conference operator today. At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the Occidental Petroleum Second Quarter 2011 Earnings Release Conference Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Mr. Stavros, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christy. Good morning, everyone and welcome to Occidental Petroleum's second quarter 2011 earnings conference call. Joining us on the call from Los Angeles are Steve Chazen, OXY's President and Chief Executive Officer; Jim Lienert, OXY's Chief Financial Officer; Dr. Ray Irani, OXY's Executive Chairman; and Bill Albrecht, President of our US Oil and Gas Operations. In a moment, I will turn the call over to our CFO Jim Lienert who will review our financial and operating results for the second quarter and first six months of 2011. Steve Chazen will then follow with some guidance and an outlook for the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter earnings press release, relation supplemental schedules and the conference call presentation slides which refer to Jim and Steve's remarks can be downloaded off our website at www.oxy.com. I'll now turn the call over to Jim. Jim, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. I'll discuss the second quarter results for the company and Steve Chazen will follow for guidance for the second half of year. Core income was $1.8 billion or $2.23 per diluted share in the second quarter this year compared to $1.1 billion, or $1.32 per diluted share in the second quarter of last year. Net income was $1.8 billion, or $2.23 per diluted share in the second quarter this year compared to $1.1 billion, or $1.31 per diluted share in the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Here's a segment breakdown for the second quarter. Oil and Gas segment earnings for the second quarter of 2011 were $2.6 billion compared with $1.9 billion in the same period of 2010. The improvement in 2011 was driven mainly by higher commodity prices. The second quarter 2011 realized prices increased on a year-over-year basis by 39% for crude oil, 31% for NGLs and 2% for domestic natural gas.</p>
          <p>Sales volume for the second quarters of 2011 and 2010 were flat at 705,000 BOE per day. Production volumes were 715,000 BOE per day in the second quarter of 2011 compared to 701,000 in the second quarter of 2010. The production guidance assumptions we gave you in last quarter's conference call were at a $95 WTI average price assumption. The actual average second quarter oil price of $102.56 reduced our production volumes by about 5,000 BOE per day. Domestic production volumes were 424,000 BOE per day compared to our guidance of 425,000 BOE per day. The higher crude oil prices reduced Long Beach volumes by about 1,000 BOE per day.</p>
          <p>Latin America volumes were 33,000 BOE per day. In the Middle East region, we recorded no production in Libya, consistent with our guidance. In Iraq, we produced 5,000 BOE per day. The decline from first quarter volume was due to the timing of development spending. The Yemen daily production was 23,000 BOE compared to 33,000 BOE in the first quarter. Civil unrest and operational issues reduced our daily production by 3,000 BOE and higher prices and lower development spending rates reduced daily volumes by 7,000 BOE. The remainder of the Middle East had production of 230,000 BOE per day compared with 235,000 BOE per day in the first quarter. Qatar's production was lower by 7,000 BOE per day, mainly due to planned maintenance and mechanical issues.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter sales volume guidance which assumed a $95 WTI oil price was 725,000 BOE per day, which translates to about 720,000 BOE per day at the higher actual prices for the quarter. Our actual volumes were 705,000 BOE per day. The lower volumes resulted mainly from the lower production in Yemen and Qatar and the timing of liftings in Oman and Qatar.</p>
          <p>Second quarter 2011 realized prices improved for all our products over the first quarter of the year. Our worldwide crude oil price was $103.12 per barrel, an increase of 12%. Worldwide NGLs were $57.67 per barrel, an improvement of 10% and domestic natural gas prices were $4.27 per Mcf, an increase of 1%. The second quarter of 2011 realized oil price represents 101% of the average WTI price for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Oil and Gas production costs were $11, cash production costs were $11.88 a barrel for the first six months of 2011, compared with last year's 12-month cost of $10.19 a barrel. The cost increase reflects more workover and maintenance activity and higher support costs. Taxes, other than on income which are directly related to product prices, were $2.36 per barrel for the first half of 2011 compared to $1.83 per barrel for all of 2010. Total exploration expense was $62 million in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Chemical segment earnings for the second quarter of 2011 were $253 million compared to $219 million in the first quarter of 2011. The second quarter results, one of the highest ever reported for the Chemical segment, reflected higher margins and volumes across most product lines.</p>
          <p>Midstream segment earnings for the second quarter of 2011 were $187 million compared to $114 million in the first quarter of 2011 and $13 million in the second quarter of 2010. The increase from first quarter earnings was mainly due to higher marketing income and improved margins in the gas processing business.</p>
          <p>The worldwide effective tax rate was 38% for the second quarter of 2011. Our higher proportionate domestic income brought us closer to the US statutory rates. Our second quarter US and foreign tax rates are included in the Investor Relations supplemental schedule.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to Occidental's performance during the first six months. Core income was $3.4 billion, or $4.19 per diluted share compared with $2.2 billion or $2.67 per diluted share in 2010. Net income was $3.4 billion, or $4.13 per diluted share for the first six months of 2011 compared with $2.1 billion, or $2.61 per diluted share in 2010.</p>
          <p>Cash flow from operations for the first six months of 2011 was $5.6 billion. We used $3 billion of the company's total cash flow to fund capital expenditures and $1.2 billion on net acquisitions and divestitures. We used $685 million to pay dividends and $1 billion to retire debt. These and other net cash flows resulted in a $2 billion cash balance at June 30. Free cash flow from continuing operations after capital spending and dividends but before acquisition and debt activity was about $1.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Capital spending was $3 billion for the first six months of which $1.6 billion was spent in the second quarter. Year-to-date capital expenditures by segment were 85% in Oil and Gas, 13% in Midstream and the remainder in Chemicals. Our net acquisition expenditures in the first six months were $1.2 billion, which are net of proceeds from the sale of our Argentina operations. The acquisitions included the South Texas purchase, a payment for the costs already incurred for the Shah Field Development Project and properties in California and the Permian.</p>
          <p>The weighted average basic shares outstanding for the first six months of 2011 were 812.5 million and weighted average diluted shares outstanding were 813.3 million. Our debt-to-capitalization ratio declined to 11% compared with 14% at the end of last year. OXY's annualized return on equity for the first half of 2011 was 20%.</p>
          <p>Copies of the press release announcing our second quarter earnings and the investor relations supplemental schedules are available on our website at www.oxy.com or through the SEC's Edgar system. I'll now turn the call over to Steve Chazen to discuss the guidance for the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jim. As we look ahead to the back half of the year at average oil prices of about $95 WTI, we expect the back half of the year in Oil and Gas production to be as follows. Domestic volumes are expected to increase by 3,000 to 4,000 BOE per day per each month compared to the previous month. This should result in average third quarter production of about 430,000 to 432,000 BOE a day. Latin America volumes should remain comparable to the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The Middle East region production is expected as follows. Consistent with the second quarter, we expect no production for Libya. In Iraq, we are still unable to reliably predict spending levels, which have a related impact in cost recovery barrels. In Oman, production is expected to grow from our current gross production of 210,000 BOE a day to a year-end exit rate of 230,000 BOE a day, which should result in about a net of 2,000 BOE per day per quarter growth. In Qatar, we expect to gradually regain the production rate lost due to planned maintenance and mechanical issues resulting in about 3,000 BOE per day growth rate each quarter the second half of the year compared to the second quarter average.</p>
          <p>In Dolphin and Bahrain, production is expected to be similar to second quarter levels. In Yemen forecasting production volumes remains difficult, although currently OXY operated production has been partially restored. We expect the range to be between 23,000 and 27,000 BOE a day. We expect a lifting in Iraq in the third quarter of about 600,000 barrels of oil. Including this lifting, we expect sales volume to be about 725,000 BOE a day at $95 West Texas Intermediate. A $5 increase in West Texas Intermediate would reduce our production sharing contract daily volumes by about 3,500 BOE a day.</p>
          <p>Our total year capital expenditures remains at $6.8 billion, same as the guidance we gave you last quarter.</p>
          <p>With regard to prices, at current market prices a $1 per barrel change in oil prices impacts quarterly earnings before income taxes by about $37 million. Second &#x2013; the average second quarter WTI oil price is $102.56 per barrel. A $1 per barrel change in NGL prices affects quarterly earnings before income taxes by $7 million. A swing of $0.50 per million BTUs in domestic gas prices is a $34 million impact on quarterly earnings before income taxes. The current NYMEX gas price is around $4.40 per Mcf. Additionally, we expect exploration expense to be about $80 million for seismic and drilling for exploration programs in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>The Chemical segment earnings is expect to moderate to about $225 million, mostly due to seasonal factors. The third quarter segment Chemical segment earnings reflect continued strong export demand and overall good supply and demand balances across most products offset by some seasonal factors and turnarounds. Historically, the fourth quarter is typically the weakest quarter and generally earnings are about half of that in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>We expect our worldwide tax rate in the third quarter of 2011 to remain at about 38%.</p>
          <p>As far as our activity is concerned in California, we expect our current drilling program to result in more predictable production growth going forward. The status of permitting is generally unchanged from the prior quarter. We obtained enough permits to allow us to prosecute the program at the current pace until year-end. However, there remains some uncertainty around future permits particularly related to injection wells.</p>
          <p>Our overall rig count in the United States has gone from 38 at the end of 2010 to our current rate of 59 and is expected to grow to 74 at the end of the year. This represents a 25% growth in our total rig count from current levels. The growth will be in the Permian and Williston Basin and South Texas. This program leads to continued growth of production into next year.</p>
          <p>I think we're willing to take your questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from David Heikkinen of Tudor Pickering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just thinking about your production targets and the monthly sequential growth. Can you give us where you were in June domestically by region, just so we can kind of build from there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't report that way. And so what you have to do is use the average because that's the way it will be reported. So if you take the average, which is the 424,000 number and so if you say, okay that was the average, so it will be average to average when the numbers actually come out. So, if it will be up 3,000, up 6,000, up 9,000 if it's 3,000, and then you average that out and you wind up with 6,000 of growth for the average for the quarter. Because if you start at the end of the quarter, you don't actually see the exit rate for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then kind of the regionalization of your domestic, how you see that 3,000 to 4,000 barrels a day of growth, how much of that is California, Permian, Williston? Any idea of that would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we risk these numbers. So the number that we use might be &#x2013; is a risk number as opposed to the maximum number that could come out or the worst number. So it's probably misleading to say exactly where. Clear that there's going to be the bulk of it, the overwhelming majority will come out of California and there will be some growth in the Williston. Williston is small anyway and some in the Permian. So I think if you look at the third quarter, you'll see the bulk of the growth out of California with smaller amounts out of the rest.</p>
          <p>As you go into the fourth quarter, because of the ramp-up in drilling in the Permian, you'll see a little more growth in the Permian, but continued pretty strong growth in California as the wells come on. So that's sort of what it looks like but to actually give you how we figured it out, I'd have to start with unrisked numbers and I don't want to give those kinds of numbers out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on the California permitting side, you talked about injection wells being some uncertainty. If you could just walk us through any color around what that means. Is that just water disposable availability and will you become limited as far as total oil volumes by that injection capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well at some point we will. I don't think we're up against it now. Where it will affect more than anything is actually THUMS more than at Elk Hills and the other places. We probably have enough for a while. But THUMS, they got some &#x2013; that's really a water injection for process. So I think that's probably where you'll see it, but the numbers are real small for this year, certainly within the noise of the rest of the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how do you think about opportunities for additional acreage acquisition and kind of where things are currently in the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I don't know how much more there is in California. I'd probably don't want to buy the land underneath the building here to drill. So I think California will probably, probably not much. Permian, we continue to buy some small parcels of acreage for Wolfberry drilling primarily, and then Williston, there's a lot of acreage for sale. You know, if we were open seven days a week, there would be seven guys here to sell us acreage. So there's a lot in Williston and we're pretty picky about what we do. So there may be a small amount of acreage acquisition there. I don't see a large deal flow in the back half of the year, although I think I said that last year at this time and was shown to be completely wrong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Paul Sankey of Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we just go back to the new disclosure on the rig count? What's the outlook beyond 2011 for those various counts, do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The California one depends on the permitting. I mean, if we had more visibility in the permitting, we'd lay more rigs on to the back half, the fourth quarter. Right now this is the visibility we have and that's why it's showing the way it is. Once we get more visibility, we'd probably raise the count.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be a raised count just for 2011, you mean, exit rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, your exit rate and so you got to get the rigs on before you get into 2012, so we'd start contracting for the rigs. So you'd see a higher exit rate, but right now this is all the visibility we really have. We're looking at the Permian and trying to figure out what the right level is, but more likely than not, it'll go up some more and maybe even sizably more depending on how we can figure it out. I think South Texas is about the same and there will be some growth in the Williston. But I think high probability of the Permian and if we can get the permitting issues worked out the next six months, you'll see significantly higher rig counts in California. Right now, I can't, I just don't have a basis to raise that rig count in California. What we're doing now will generate a fair amount of production growth. So I'm not really concerned that this is going to be bad. But we could do some more, but right now, I just can't &#x2013; I don't have enough confidence in the permitting process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This level of rigs in California would generate growth through 2012 at the kind of pace that you're talking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yes. Oh, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Which seems to be about 2,000 barrels per month?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, somewhere in that. We give you the 3,000 to 4,000. So some of that will be California, maybe in some quarters all of it. So just hard to say exactly what is, again, I used risked numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. If we looked at the year-over-year, you're flat and looking backwards obviously over 2010 to 2011 Q2 to Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's on sales, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. Yes, it's on sales and then obviously net, there's been a negative basically from Libya but all the other movements. From here forward, are we looking again back to the 5% to 8% if we ask you again in a year's time, are we going to be in the 5% to 8% volume growth range that you've talked about in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At least that, because I think the domestic businesses are going to surprise, but I could be wrong. But I think the 3,000 to 4,000 a month for the domestic business is pretty solid for a while, and maybe we'll do a little better, but I think that's a good risked number for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve. If I could ask you about Phibro, the midstream trading business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sort of a surprise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It looked like a good number and we'd been expecting a headwind from Phibro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was a small headwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so Phibro was a net negative. And what I'm thinking about is whether the run rate of your Midstream businesses is just structurally higher now as a function of Permian activity and piping and whether we should think rolling forward of a higher through the cycle or even growing, I guess Midstream profitability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we break it out because it's the most volatile and we have a hard time predicting it. I think the way to think about it is that the volatility and price volatility, oil price volatility and wide differentials between say the Cushing and the world prices generates generally higher numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It might generate lower numbers, too. But it reduces the predictability a lot. So if I were to look at it and I'd say what's the average, I'd average the first and second quarter to get sort of an average number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And again just going back to Phibro, forgive me if I've garbled this number, but I think you said the range historically would be a minus $0.08 to a plus $0.12, was it range of Phibro profitability or loss?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't remember anymore. He was ahead for the year at mid-year, so depending on how you view modest, a modest loss in the second quarter. But for the year, he's ahead and he's well ahead now but again, I think I've told you this before, no sense in watching it. It's like an NBA game. You may as well tune in the last 30 seconds and forget the rest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. And then forgive me if I misheard. This is the last one from me. I kind of missed the Iraq guidance. I think 5,000 of production with no sales in Q2. Is that correct? And then did you say 7,000 a day of production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we said for production in Iraq. You know, the field is doing fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did we say it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The field is doing fine, the gross is really doing fine. You know, our nets may be 6,000-ish, but it really depends on the investment which has slowed up considerably. So I don't really know. We do have a sale of 600,000 barrels this month. So we will have some actual sales this month.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I see even given the spending slowing, that you will, the outlook for next year on Iraq volumes is difficult?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know how to do it because it reacts so quickly to the spending. Because if we spend more, it would, production would go up immediately so I just don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What has been the spending constraint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a lot of issues, I think, with the operator and that sort of thing getting permits approved &#x2013; or not permits but contracts approved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll leave it there, Steve. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ed Westlake of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, Steve. Just on California, you've spoken in the past about trying to get these larger areas permitted because then you can progress it a little bit quicker once you actually get the permits through and that means you get probably more effective capital. Could you talk to us in terms of have you got one of these larger permit areas, two, three, when did you put those permits in and when, given they might take 12 to 18 months, you might get a larger area permitted?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't really know. We could go into that. I don't know how helpful it is. We put a number of them in for large areas, a fair, a sizable number and we just don't know what the process is. It's not exactly transparent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So at this stage, you don't really have a feeling for how long it's going to take for one of those larger areas to actually be permitted?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a nontransparent process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. Maybe then a switch to the increase in rig count. Three to four monthly sequential increase over the second half of this year but obviously your rig count is increasing as you go through the second half. So as you look into 2012, would it be fair to think that that would accelerate a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It should. Let's say we bought a well today, it doesn't make any difference where. Spud a well today, it will have a small effect on the production in the fourth quarter, because it takes say 90 days or so. You hook it up and then you get a partial quarter. So what you're seeing is a wedge of this stuff pushing into next year. So our exit rate going into next year ought to be fairly attractive with a pretty high backlog of production. So it just takes &#x2013; you just lose sight of how long it takes from today, what you spend to drill today to when you actually get a meaningful measurement of production. So I think we're on good track now and I think we'll have an attractive exit rate in the United States as the year ends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then final question is around realizations, maybe any strategies to perhaps, or any changes we should be aware of to try to sort of get away from WTI inland pricing towards more international pricing across the portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not trying to solve the industry's problems in this. We're just trying to solve ours and so I'd just assume not comment on our strategies but to point out that for example, California basically gets world prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm mainly thinking perhaps in the Permian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Permian, some of that could fall into the Midstream rather than into Oil and Gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Doug Leggate of Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning, Steve. Good morning, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, at the beginning of the year, you suggested you may get 107 shale wells drilled this year. What's the latest?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I missed you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>At the start of the year, I believe you suggested that you would drill about 107 wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shale wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Shales, yes. What's the latest estimate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill can answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes Doug, good morning. I think right now we're looking at somewhere between 150 and 175 shale wells to be drilled in California for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how many did you complete, Bill, in the second quarter? You gave us a first quarter number. I think it was 26. How many did you complete in the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was 55.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Completed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not necessarily hooked up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I was going to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So your backlog is building basically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, at dinner about I guess a month or six weeks ago, you suggested your first base target was to get to drill around 300 wells a year. To what extent, I mean, what is it going to take to get there and how engaged are you with the state government in trying to achieve that objective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're engaged with the state. You know, I just should not go into our state relations. I think we're making some &#x2013; we're making physical progress where we can, and I think the state, eventually, I think the state will come around. It just takes longer, that's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess a couple other quick ones, if I may. The production from the shale's obviously what we're all focused on in terms of how quickly that can ramp up. Are you prepared to give us what the current production is from that particular part of the portfolio, and how you would expect given your decline curves and the rate of drilling, how would you expect that to progress let's say over the next 18 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not willing to give you a forecast because again, the forecast, the overall forecast I'd give you is a risked number and the bottoms up numbers are essentially sort of unrisked, but I think Bill can give you some numbers on where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, right now, in terms of current shale production in California, we're running about 45,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and given the pace of the potential hiccups, Bill, where would you expect that to exit the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're not into the forecasting of that again because I think you'll be mixing risked and unrisked numbers on the totals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, all right. The final couple from me are again related to the same thing. Steve, the status of the gas plant place I believe after the maintenance in Q1, I guess we should have been expecting some recovery there and finally the Rosetta acquisition, how much of that was included in Q2? And I guess -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very little because it closed in pieces during the quarter. So it was really a small number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and the plant status?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The plant is ready April, is that what you are thinking, Bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Doug, we're targeting April of 2012 and actually we're currently running a little bit ahead of schedule on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry Bill, I was talking about the existing plant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The existing plant is an old plant that's not terribly reliable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I will leave it at that, guys. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jason Gammel of Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, guys. A few more on California, if I could. Of the 29 rigs that you have running in California, Steve, can you talk about how many of those are actually pursuing the unconventional objectives you have? And then out of that number, how many are looking to derisk further acreage versus drilling in the I believe 200,000 acres that you said you thought you had derisked on the first quarter call?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill can answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, right now of the 29 rigs we have running in California, fully 20 of those are drilling unconventional plays or horizons, and of that 20, roughly 4 to 5 are in the process of derisking additional acreage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the 200,000 acres still a reasonable number for us to be thinking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think <mark type="ph" /> that's now &#x2013; (32:00) plenty for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, agreed. And then one more if I could, it's probably too early to talk about this but I'm going to try it anyway. Anything on type curves, initial production rates, what you expect ultimate recoveries to be, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as we look at this, if we went back to what we said roughly a year ago or a little more than a year ago, I think we're a little more optimistic on the verticals and a little more pessimistic on the horizontals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, can you remind me what you're expecting on the verticals? Is that a 300 barrel a day IP rate, 400?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Jason, it's -- right now we're averaging about 370, and that's BOE, that's equivalent per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just one more if I could. Of that 370 or just on an overall mix of production out of the unconventionals, how much would you expect to be gas versus black oil versus condensate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about 60/40, 60% oil and about 40% gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot, guys, I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Faisel Khan of Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the 3,000 to 4,000 per barrels per month domestic production growth at the end of the year, how much of that is gas and -- gas and oil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because of the way it was computed, there's no particular easy way to tell. I would guess the bulk of it, 75%, 80% would be oil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got you. And then in terms of your -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oil meaning real oil. NGLs isn't oil. Just so we're clear what we're talking about. NGLs are something between oil and gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. And then I'm looking at the overall domestic natural gas, dry gas production portfolio, is that production kind of expected to remain flat through the end of this year, or do you expect declines to take place?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think it will probably grow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. And then lastly -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sometimes especially in California, you drill it and sometimes it's a little misleading because if you drill a shale well, you might take it down to the deeper zone, slightly deeper zone, and the slightly deeper zone tends to be gassy, and you may not have drilled the well for that purpose, but all of a sudden you've got some gas. And so our ability &#x2013; and so as we take what was designed as a shale well down a little bit further, you can wind up with a gas zone and so you get a little more volatility in the number which is not a bad thing, by the way. So predicting this stuff, you might get lucky and find a big gas zone, and so our gas might go up sort of by serendipity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And is that gas able to be produced into the market, or is there infrastructure required to bring -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends on where it is, but the answer is so far we've been able to manage it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. My last question is on the Permian Basin, in terms of your rig count kind of going up in that basin, how much of that is split between the Delaware and the Midland Basin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say -- looking forward, Faisel, is that what you are asking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say probably 70% or so is going to be devoted to &#x2013; of that delta, that incremental rig count is going to be devoted to the Delaware Basin as opposed to the Midland Basin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The delta from where we are today versus where it will be at the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great. Thanks, guys, I appreciate the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sven Del Pozzo of IHS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With that new disclosure on the rigs on the back page, is, gross operated rigs, on a net basis, are the increases similar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a whole bunch of non-operated activity also especially in the Permian, the Permian really. So we don't have any way of sort of predicting that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the overall increase in the rig count in the US going from 38 to 59, are those conventional drilling rigs, or are there workover rigs there included?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That's just strictly drilling rigs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We got a very large number of workover rigs so that would just obscure the numbers, including workover rigs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The IP rig you mentioned, the 370 for the California shale well, that's a 24-hour rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's actually longer than that. It's generally -- a stabilized rate would be over, say a week's time because these wells have to clean up before they stabilize. So it's really over a week or even longer period of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. How did your operations team deal with the flooding in North Dakota? I mean, you're farther away from the river. So I'd assume there was less flooding where you guys are. But I'm not sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It really didn't affect us at all given where we operate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm seeing an increase in NGL production from the US in the second quarter over the first quarter. Is that correct? I mean, a substantial one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>NGL production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I might be wrong. Let me see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't think it went hardly at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, then forget about that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Permian, Apache was mentioning the application of modern drilling and completion techniques, horizontal applications to their CO2 floods and also water floods. I'm assuming whether you guys see similar upside?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have a basis to compare with what Apache is saying. I don't know what that's about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, well that will do it. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Duane Grubert of Susquehanna Financial.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the CO2 theme, we've had others in the sector see CO2 supply as a constraint and I think you guys have been pretty proactive in telling us why it's not a constraint. Can you talk to us about how you think of allocating capital in the Permian to non-CO2 versus CO projects and if CO2 available is a factor in that allocation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have, we supply about half of our own CO2 and we have ways to increase that. So the fact that some smaller operator has a problem getting CO2 doesn't surprise us. The market's fairly snug. It's a very profitable business. We allocated sort of, we have a five-year plan for putting CO2 in the ground and we just go ahead and do it. It's a very profitable business because we spent all the capital really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then jumping over to one of your recent acquisitions, the heavy oil stuff in California, do you have any early read on your enthusiasm for your heavy oil project?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a one-off thing. I don't think we're interested in more heavy oil. This was a pretty good opportunity. It was an undrilled field and five years from now, it'll be pretty good results for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then you have been buying a lot of what appear to be one-off things that could have legs domestically. I'm sure people also pitch to you international assets. Do you have any appetite to be shopping internationally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We always look for opportunities internationally but in places we understand, of course. So, I don't think we'll be drilling much in Antarctica or anything like that. So we're looking for places we understand and where we can make substantial returns. You don't want to go to international just to produce empty barrels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then to follow on to an earlier comment you guys on California. You said unconventional wells, you've got about 20 out of 29 rigs more or less developing and 4 or 5 derisking. Can we really think of that whole program as being in a development stage now, or are there certain aspects of it like infrastructure sizing or maybe where the footprint is that you are still in less of a development stage and more of a figuring out what you want to do stage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're always figuring out what we want to do, I think. I think we always are looking to expand and figure out new opportunities. There's different plays that are around that we haven't talked about publicly. So we're always looking for different things to do, trying to figure out where to build the next gas plant. There are a lot of things we do and so we're trying to figure out what the program will be over the next decade. So that requires a certain amount of &#x2013; it's not high risk exploration, but significant step out activity just to figure out where we're going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then with the current sector environment with the high oil prices and the ability to do a lot of work in domestic areas that didn't frankly exist five or ten years ago, can you remind us of your philosophy of cash use and maybe how the current environment might be influencing or changing that if at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cash use has always been the same. I think I had the same slide for the last 15 years. The number one use is maintenance capital, second use is dividends, third use is growth capital, the fourth is acquisitions and the share repurchases are last.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Herrlin of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, a bunch of quick ones for you, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For your volume growth domestically in the second quarter, was the bulk of that South Texas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll have to &#x2013; maybe somebody will look at the numbers. I don't know whether it was the bulk of it or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next one, California.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With California, you said that the lion's share of the rigs currently running are unconventional. What would it have been a year ago, just to give some perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was more conventional. A year ago, we were probably even 50/50 on it, and we've shifted because we said we were going to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Year-end, should we assume that there's no Yemeni volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think in the case of Yemen, we think that there's a reasonable chance that the government &#x2013; first of all, half the production isn't really covered by that. It's other fields that have longer contracts. And it looks to us that there's at least a reasonable chance that the government will allow us, will allow Nexen to continue to operate the Masila Field while it figures out what it's going to do. So I think there's a reasonable chance that the stuff in Yemen will continue for a while at the full rate. No guarantees of that obviously but about half the production is unrelated to that and is pretty much unaffected by this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. For the properties that Nexen is operating, would you expect then to pay a sizable upfront bonus or some sort?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't know. I think right now, there's really no one to negotiate with. I assume that what will happen is that they'll just let it go for a while until there's clarity in the government there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. That's fine. In terms of the property acquisition marketplace, you're full in California and you said there's a lot for sale in the Williston and there's always drips and drabs in the Permian. Are you considering any sort of new areas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the United States?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really. We tire kick a lot of stuff so we understand what's going on. But I don't see any, certainly not this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay well you're accruing a lot of cash, so would it be reasonable to assume that you would focus on more dividend growth or potentially share buyback, which I know you don't particularly like, but is that a consideration?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We like dividends better than share repurchases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fine. Last ones from me, we're seeing a lot of gratuitous divorces these days in the public marketplace, disintegrations, whatever. Would the board ever consider maybe doing a split of OXY between domestic and international?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You just have to come to conclusion that that actually creates value rather than just some sort of, something to entertain investment bankers. So, you never say never, but I think right now there's a lot of synergies between them. Very difficult for the international business to have anything less than a single A credit rating to get new contracts and so it's just improbable that that would create any value, to split them off that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from David Heikkinen of Tudor Pickering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, just had a follow-up question thinking about the vertical well split, around talking about 60% oil, 40% gas. That's for all the wells drilled including the Elk Hills primary wells, but your guidance is reflecting more oil growth. Can you talk us through kind of what are the current well splits for the wells you're drilling on the vertical unconventional?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, David, most of them are vertical wells in terms of the unconventional wells. Nearly all are drilling vertical wells as opposed to horizontal, just speaking to the unconventional.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm trying to understand the 60% oil, 40% gas and the average of all the wells drilled versus the guidance that most of the drills is oil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I was referring to was the 60/40 split was just solely on unconventional shale wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's an average rather than sort of the outcome. If you look at it, that's what they're sort of doing because when you produce the oil, you get a fair amount of gas with it. The wells are oil wells. They just have associated gas. It's just hard, it's hard &#x2013; most of the growth is out of oil, but I think you asked about really, he answered a very narrow range of wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So out of your total, what is your conventional development program heading forward then and what do those wells look like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those wells are basically oil wells and they're a little less gas. Nothing wrong with the gas. I mean, you get $4 and they have high rates and you get your money back pretty quick. It's just, but we think most of the growth for this year will be oil because we're kind of biased that way. Occasionally, you have this issue with you drill a little bit deeper and you wind up in a gas zone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just was that a &#x2013; the property acquired was 30 million, 35 million cubic feet equivalent a day primarily?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's less than that. We're the largest gas producer in the state, and that's an old field, been around a long time. It's in a different part of the state and I think we would probably market it a little different than maybe the predecessor, but.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Katherine Minyard of JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon or morning. Quick question on your comments on California and permits. You talked about there being some uncertainty around future permits particularly related to the injector wells. I was just curious as to whether there's something about the nature of the injection wells that's holding them up, or is it their location?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's an industry issue not necessarily related to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just in light of that, how much of your growth forecast in California depends on successfully permitting the injection wells and then does that change over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a long-term problem for us rather than a short-term problem. The only place it would affect us in the intermediate term is a little bit under 1,000 barrels a day at THUMS, but other than the rest of it &#x2013; ultimately, you need to dispose of the water. So it's hard to produce oil without producing salt water. So we're going to have to ultimately have more injection wells. And so it's an issue, but it's more an issue for people in the steam flood business, which there's some large players in that here in California that have I think a much bigger issue than we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thanks. And then, can I just switch quickly to Latin America? It just looks like the production that's being reported from Colombia is kind of trending downward. I'm just curious as to whether that's a price related impact or whether it's project delays?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, there's a kicker to the Colombian government on price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thanks very much. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Evan Calio of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. Thanks for taking my call. Hey, if refining keeps on a roll here, it's going to cannibalize the front of your conference call at least for some folks. I will give you a break on the California questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, we thought we'd run out of counties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought so. But on the Permian my question is are wider differentials impacting the way you think about capital allocation, and potentially away from the Permian at least on an operating level, at least until diffs normalize and move into another part of your portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At $100 oil, which is the WTI price, you could drive a truck through the margins, on a cash basis or reported basis or whatever, we historically have viewed $100 as a pretty decent price. And so the fact that somebody says well maybe it should be on some basis $106, yes it's true, but this is still $100. You know, given a very oily portfolio in the Permian, I mean this is enormously profitable. I mean, you say well, you should get some more. Well, I don't know. We should get some more now but I don't know about a year from now. So I think we'll take the money and run.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's I guess the second question and clearly -- respect that that's very profitable. Do you think of changing any kind of hedge position into 2012 if you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not hedgers. We don't know. You know, the Phibro guys are bullish on oil forever so I guess we're not hedgers in that sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay so nothing to protect any TILS exposure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. the reason we keep sort of a debt-free balance sheet is so that we don't have to protect our downside, so we don't have to buy basically insurance for downside. We're not good speculators on product prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fair. Just maybe the last question on Iraq, and I apologize if I missed it earlier. You mentioned your last call you begin liftings in the second half of '11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lifting will be, is this month. First lifting is this month.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your next question comes from Doug Leggate of Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Steve. Sorry for the follow-up. I just wanted to get clarification on a couple of things. You've said in the past that your shale wells were predominantly oil, meaning north of 90%. Has that changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So what's the 60/40 then, I'm confused?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>60/40 is related as to whether it's called oil well or a gas well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So what is the majority of the wells you're drilling? Are they 60% oil or 90% oil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Closer to the 90%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we may occasionally &#x2013; you should understand that sometimes you drill a little deeper and you wind up with a pretty gassy well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, no I understand that, but predominantly if we're talking about completing 150 to 175 wells this year, what proportion of those would you say were in the 90% range than in the other range? Because it makes a heck of a difference to the value obviously.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably not as much as you think because the gas wells will have a lot of liquids with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. The IP rates again, going back to Bill's comments. Previously you've said 350 was a good run rate as an IP rate but you described that as longer than 30 days which is a bit different from Bill saying 7 days. So we can get some clarification on that also? Maybe just reiterate how you see the decline curve as compared to what you gave us a year ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, just to clarify, really what I was talking about 7 days, I was talking about time for the wells to clean up. That 370 BOE a day number really is a 30-day stabilized IP number. That's an average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So how would I think about that in terms of, let's say, a month down the line 30-day average? Is that a good number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good number, Doug, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what he was trying to say as opposed to just a IP rate like a Haynesville well which is sort of 1 day or something, what he's trying to say is it takes him a week or so to clean up the well. It stays at this 370 for a month or so and then the decline would begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, great. And the final one is previously $3 million a well was kind of the number to drill complete and hook up I guess that you'd given us. Can you just talk a bit about what's happening to service costs in the state and whether that was still a good run rate that we should be thinking about in terms of CapEx, and I will leave it at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, I think $3.5 million to $4 million is really a good range. Drill complete and you know, hook up to sales. We are seeing some inflation on pressure pumping obviously just as the whole industry is. But that's still a pretty good number, $3.5 million to $4 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're not fracing these wells, Bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. There's a few that we do fracture stimulate, but the majority are just acidized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great stuff. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your final question comes from Sven Del Pozzo of IHS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry. Just returning to the NGL question from earlier. Yes, in fact it did go up. Just wondering, is that part of the south Texas acquisition? Is that rich gas? Is that why I'm looking at the domestic NGL production, <mark type="ph" /> looks like it's up &#x2013; (56:26)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The additional NGLs from last year, from a year ago come from South Texas and from in the Permian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So are we going to see in the future a similar ramp-up in NGL production sequentially quarter over quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for joining us today on the call and if you have any questions, feel free to call us here in New York. Thanks again and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This does conclude today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>