<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1425615" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>390</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Christopher G. Stavros</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">James M. Lienert</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Stephen I. Chazen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Paul Sankey</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President">William E. Albrecht</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor Pickering Holt &amp; Co. Securities, Inc.">Jessica Chipman</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd.">Jason D. Gammel</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="VP &amp; President-Oxy Oil &amp; Gas-International">Edward A. Lowe</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Arjun Narayana Murti</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Doug T. Terreson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="IHS Herold, Inc.">Sven Del Pozzo</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Americas Securities LLC">John P. Herrlin</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Ed G. Westlake</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James &amp; Associates">Pavel Molchanov</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="CRT Capital Group LLC">Ann L. Kohler</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Simmons &amp; Co. International">Jeff A. Dietert</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Kristy and I will be your conference operator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the Occidental Petroleum Third Quarter 2011 Earnings Release Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> After the speakers' remarks there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you. I would now like to turn the call over to Christopher Stavros. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kristy. Good morning, everyone. Welcome to Occidental Petroleum's Third Quarter 2011 Earnings Conference Call. Joining us on the call this morning from Los Angeles are Steve Chazen, Oxy's President, Chief Executive Officer; Jim Lienert, Oxy's Chief Financial Officer; Bill Albrecht, President of our Domestic Oil and Gas Operations; and Sandy Lowe, President of our International Oil and Gas business.</p>
          <p>In just a moment I'll turn the call over to Jim, our CFO, who will review our financial and operating results for the third quarter and first nine months of 2011. Chazen will then follow with some comments on Oxy's strategy and outlook for the fourth quarter and we'll conclude with a brief Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>Our third quarter earnings press release, Investor Relations supplemental schedules and the conference call presentation slides, which refer to both Jim and Steve's remarks, can be downloaded off of our Web site at www.oxy.com.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call over to Jim Lienert. Jim, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. Core income was $1.8 billion or $2.18 per diluted share in the third quarter this year, compared to $1.2 billion or $1.48 per diluted share in the third quarter of last year. Net income was $1.8 billion or $2.17 per diluted share in the third quarter of 2011 compared to $1.2 billion or $1.46 per diluted share in the third quarter of 2010. The small difference between net and core income is due to discontinued operations.</p>
          <p>Here's the segment breakdown for the third quarter. Oil &amp; Gas segment earnings for the third quarter of 2011 were $2.6 billion, the same as the second quarter of 2011 and compared to $1.8 billion in the third quarter of 2010. Higher volumes this quarter compared to the second quarter of 2011 resulted in flat quarter-to-quarter income despite lower prices. The improvement in 2011 over the same period in 2010 was driven by higher production and liquids prices.</p>
          <p>The third quarter 2011 realized prices increased on a year-over-year basis by 34% for crude oil, 41% for NGLs and remained about flat for domestic natural gas. Sales volumes, which are different than production volumes due to the timing of liftings were 743,000 BOE per day compared to 713,000 BOE per day in the third quarter of 2010. Our production was 739,000 BOE per day compared to 706,000 BOE per day in the third quarter of 2010, which included production from Libya. This represents a greater than 4.5% increase year-over-year, reflecting our continued focus on production growth. The third quarter production was also more than 3% higher than the second quarter 2011 volumes of 715,000 BOE per day.</p>
          <p>Domestically, our production was 436,000 BOE per day, representing the highest ever domestic production volumes for the company, compared to our guidance of 430,000 BOE per day to 432,000 BOE per day. Our production in California rose by 6,000 BOE per day compared to the second quarter and contributed a large portion of the sequential increase in our overall domestic production volumes. Latin America volumes were 30,000 BOE per day. Colombia volumes decreased from the second quarter due to pipeline interruptions caused by insurgent activity.</p>
          <p>In the Middle East region we recorded no production in Libya. In Iraq we produced 4,000 BOE per day. Yemen daily production was 28,000 BOE, slightly ahead of our guidance. In Oman the third quarter production was 79,000 BOE per day, an increase of 3,000 BOE per day over the second-quarter volumes. In Qatar the third quarter production was 73,000 BOE per day, an increase of 5,000 BOE per day over the second quarter volumes.</p>
          <p>The increase reflected the results of the development program as well as maintenance issues that affected the second quarter volumes. In Dolphin and Bahrain combined production increased 3,000 BOE per day from the second quarter volumes. Our third quarter sales volumes were 743,000 BOE per day compared to our guidance of 725,000 BOE per day. The improvement resulted mainly from the higher domestic production and the timing of liftings. Third quarter 2011 realized prices declined for all of our products from the second quarter of the year.</p>
          <p>Our worldwide crude oil realized price was $97.24 per barrel, a decrease of 6%. Worldwide NGLs were $56.06 per barrel, a decline of 3%, and domestic natural gas prices were about flat at $4.23 per Mcf. Differentials improved in the quarter, resulting in realized oil prices representing 108% of the average WTI and 87% of the average Brent price. About 60% of Oxy's oil production tracks world oil prices and 40% is indexed to WTI. For example, in California our realized price was 114% of WTI and 91% of Brent in the third quarter. In Oman our average price was 117% of WTI and 93% of Brent.</p>
          <p>Price changes at current global prices affect our quarterly earnings before income taxes by $38 million for a $1.00 per barrel change in oil prices and $7 million for a $1.00 per barrel change in NGL prices. A swing of $0.50 per million BTUs in domestic gas prices affects quarterly pre-tax earnings by about $34 million.</p>
          <p>Oil &amp; Gas cash production costs were $12.36 a barrel for the first 9 months of 2011, compared with last year's 12-month cost of $10.19 a barrel. The cost increase reflects higher workover and maintenance activity driven by our program to increase production at these higher levels of oil prices. Taxes other than on income, which are directly related to product prices, were $2.29 per barrel for the first 9 months of 2011 compared to $1.83 per barrel for all of 2010. Total exploration expense was $39 million in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Chemical segment earnings for the third quarter of 2011 were $245 million, compared to $253 million in the second quarter of 2011 and $189 million in the third quarter of 2010. The improvement in third quarter results on a year-over-year basis reflects higher margins across most product lines. In addition, during the third quarter of 2011 we temporarily idled certain production in our Texas plants and sold power to the grid during the power shortage, resulting in an increase in the quarter's earnings.</p>
          <p>Midstream segment earnings for the third quarter of 2011 were $77 million compared to $187 million in the second quarter of 2011 and $163 million in the third quarter of 2010. The decreases from the second quarter and prior third quarter earnings were due to losses from our Phibro unit both for the quarter and year-to-date, partially offset by higher pipeline income and increased power sales to the grid during the third quarter. The worldwide effective tax rate was 38% for the third quarter of 2011. Our third quarter U.S. and foreign tax rates are included in the Investor Relations supplemental schedule.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to Occidental's performance during the first nine months. Core income was $5.2 billion or $6.37 per diluted share, compared with $3.4 billion or $4.14 per diluted share in 2010. Net income was $5.1 billion or $6.31 per diluted share for the first 9 months of 2011, compared with $3.3 billion or $4.07 per diluted share in 2010. Cash flow from operations for the first nine months of 2011 was $8.6 billion. We used $5 billion of the company's total cash flow to fund capital expenditures and $1.5 billion on net acquisitions and divestitures. We used $1.1 billion to pay dividends and had a net cash inflow from debt activity of $600 million. These and other net cash flows resulted in a $4 billion cash balance at September 30.</p>
          <p>Capital spending was $5 billion for the first 9 months, of which $2 billion was spent in the third quarter. Year-to-date capital expenditures by segment were 83% in Oil &amp; Gas, 14% in Midstream and the remainder in Chemicals. Our net acquisition expenditures for the first 9 months were $1.5 billion, which are net of proceeds from the sale of our Argentina operations. The acquisitions include the South Texas purchase, properties in California and the Permian and a payment in connection with the signing of the Al Hosn gas project in Abu Dhabi, which is a gas development of the Shah field. This payment was for Occidental's share of development expenditures incurred by the project prior to the date the final agreement was signed.</p>
          <p>The weighted average basic shares outstanding for the first 9 months of 2011 were $812.6 million and the weighted average diluted shares outstanding were $813.3 million. Our debt to capitalization ratio was 14%, the same as the end of last year. During the third quarter of 2011 Oxy issued senior notes of $1.3 billion due in 2017 and $900 million due in 2022 at a weighted average interest rate of 2.3%, which brought the company's average effective borrowing rate down to 3.2%. Our annualized return on equity for the first nine months of the year was 20%. Copies of the press release announcing our third quarter earnings and the Investor Relations supplemental schedules are available on our Web site at www.oxy.com or through the SEC's EDGAR system.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Steve Chazen to discuss Oxy's strategy to maximize total shareholder return and provide guidance for the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jim. This morning I want to spend a few minutes discussing Occidental's overriding goal to maximize total shareholder return. We believe this can be achieved through a combination of: first growing our oil and gas production by 5% to 8% a year on average over the long term; second allocating and deploying capital with a focus on achieving well above cost-to-capital returns; and finally consistent dividend growth.</p>
          <p>I'd like to give you an update of our progress year-to-date. Oil and gas production, the impact of our capital program and increase in drilling activity has started to have a visible impact on our domestic oil and gas production volumes. Compared to the second quarter our domestic production increased about 6,000 BOE per day per month compared to our guidance of 3,000 BOE per day to 4,000 BOE per day.</p>
          <p>This increase resulted in domestic production of 436,000 BOE a day the third quarter compared to 430,000 BOE a day to 432,000 BOE a day guidance we gave you. Third quarter 2011 domestic production is the highest U.S. total production in Oxy's history, reflecting the highest ever volumes for liquids.</p>
          <p>Compared to the prior year total company third quarter production of 739,000 BOE a day was affected by a 7% decline in our international production. This reduction was a result of disruptions in the Middle East and North Africa and the impact of higher prices on our production-sharing contract. On a year-over-year basis, our domestic production volumes increased by 15%.</p>
          <p>In our operations we experienced disruptions affecting our production. Examples of such events in the third quarter of 2011 included the Elk Hill's gas plant shutdown due to mechanical issues, mechanical issues with plants, compressors and pipelines in the Permian and Qatar, and insurgent activity in Colombia that caused a significant portion of our production to be shut in for about 10 days. Without these events, our production would have been 10,000 BOE to 15,000 BOE a day higher, which is more representative of our assets' current theoretical productive capacity.</p>
          <p>Some of these constraints have been removed and we expect others to be removed over time. Others are not within our control and will reoccur. We believe our capital program will yield higher production growth and reliability over time.</p>
          <p>Turning to returns, our return on equity, as Jim pointed out, for the first nine months was 20%. Our return on capital employed, annualized for the first nine months, was 18%. We will continue to manage our capital program and acquisition strategy to yield well above cost of capital returns.</p>
          <p>Dividend growth is an important part of our total return to shareholders. Our ability to pay dividends is indicated by our free-cash-flow generation. Free cash flow after interest, taxes and capital spending but before dividends, acquisitions and debt activity for the first nine months of the year was $3.7 billion. Oxy's annual dividend rate is currently $1.84 per share or about $1.1 billion for the nine months of 2011. Oxy has increased its dividends 10 times in the last nine years, resulting in a compound annual dividend growth rate of 15.6%. Keeping with our philosophy to raise the dividend on a consistent basis, the Board of Directors is expected to consider a dividend increase at the February meeting.</p>
          <p>Turning to a topic which I know is favored among at least some of you, share repurchases. The policy on possible share repurchase remains essentially unchanged. We do not view share repurchases as an alternative to dividends. We believe that dividends are given directly to the shareholders while the effects of share repurchase on the stock price is at best murky. Therefore, you should not expect a program of regular share repurchases, except to offset any shares issued under employee programs. These share issues tend to be very small. If there is continuing excess cash, it will be used to boost the dividend rate. We do consider using the shareholders' capital to buy shares when the stock is trading at a discount to the results we can expect from our capital or acquisition program.</p>
          <p>To assist you in determining this, the analysis we employ is as follows. The value of the Chemical and Midstream assets that are not directly related to our production is determined. This is done on a very conservative basis. The debt and cash levels of the company are netted. The current capital program finding and development costs for each of Oil and of Gas are estimated. We use only proved reserves in the calculation, not probable or possible reserves, and we don't consider the value of acreage. The result of this analysis is not the value of the company but rather the determination of whether the next dollar should be spent on capital or share repurchases.</p>
          <p>Normally this results in a decision to invest in the business rather than a decision to buy in shares. When we do repurchase shares, we will make only the required public announcements in order to minimize what we pay for the stock, thereby enriching the remaining shareholders and not assisting the exiting ones. This approach eliminates our natural bias to think the stock is always undervalued and makes the calculations pretty straightforward.</p>
          <p>We have sufficient authority to purchase a significant number of shares, Form 10-Q filings will show if any shares were purchased, at what price, and how many shares remain authorized. Small repurchases are indicative of employee plan activities. We value the company's financial flexibility, especially in times of stress. It would be a disservice to our shareholders to impair that flexibility to achieve some theoretical short-term advantage.</p>
          <p>As we look ahead to the fourth quarter of the year, we expect oil and gas production to be as follows. Domestic volumes are expected to increase by about 3,000 BOE to 4,000 BOE per day per month from the current quarterly average level of 436,000 BOE per day. This should result in fourth quarter production of about 442,000 BOE to 444,000 BOE per day. This would constitute a year-over-year domestic production growth rate exceeding 10%, and about 6% a year production growth rate going forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of review of our major domestic assets, in California, for the year we expect to drill and complete 154 shale wells outside of Elk Hills, compared to the 107 wells we'd indicated at the beginning of the year. Including Elk Hills, we expect to drill 195 shale wells for the year. We expect to drill and complete a total of 42 shale wells during the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Our experience has been the 30-day initial production rate for these wells, depending on area is between 300 and 400 BOE equivalent per day. With respect to shale wells outside of Elk Hills, about 80% of the BOE production is a combination of black oil and high value condensate. The cost of drilling and completing these wells has been running about $3.5 million per well and we expect this to continue to decline over time. Our conventional drilling program is progressing somewhat better than planned.</p>
          <p>There has been no significant change in the permitting issues in the state from our last call. We expect the current permitting levels to allow us to have our program go forward at these levels and enable us to continue to grow our production volumes in the state. We expect the production rig count to remain at the same 29 rig count, although we're likely to add a thirtieth rig by the end of the year based on the current outlook.</p>
          <p>In the Permian operations our CO2 flood production is progressing according to plan. We expect our rig count to be about 24 in the fourth quarter. Our non-CO2 operations have stepped up their development program. This will not show significant production growth until next year.</p>
          <p>In the Williston we are pursuing a development program with about 13 rigs expected to be running in the fourth quarter. Our production is growing as a result of development program and we expect the growth to continue.</p>
          <p>Natural gas prices in the United States continue to be -- it says here weak, but I think poor. As a result, we are considering cutting back our pure gas drilling in the Midcontinent and possibly elsewhere. Internationally, we believe that once the current uncertainties are behind us, including the resolution of the situation in Libya and achievement of sustained development program in Iraq, we will achieve production growth similar to our domestic operations. We expect that our fourth quarter international production to be about the same as the third quarter production, 4% higher than the second quarter of this year, which represented a low point of volumes following the situation in Libya. Colombia volume should be modestly higher than the third quarter assuming no further pipeline attacks.</p>
          <p>Middle East region is expected to be as follows in the fourth quarter. At this point we expect no significant production from Libya. Our joint-venture partnerships are currently in the process of resuming production. The production ramp up will be hampered in the near term by a lack of vehicles and personnel to address operational problems from the prolonged shut-in. In Iraq, we expect production to be similar to the last quarter. Going forward, we are still unable to reliably predict spending levels, which determine production.</p>
          <p>In the remainder of the middle east we expect production to be comparable to third quarter volumes. At current &#x2013; at quarter end prices, we expect total production to increase to about 745,000 BOE a day as a result of the 3,000 BOE a day to 4,000 BOE a day per month coming from the</p>
          <p>domestic production. We expect sales volumes to be around 740,000 a day due to the timing of liftings. A $5 change in global oil prices would impact our production sharing contract daily volumes by about 3,000 BOE a day. We expect our total year capital expenditures to be about $7 billion. Additionally, we expect exploration expense to be about $100 million for seismic and drilling for exploration programs in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Chemical segment's fourth quarter earnings, which is historically the weakest quarter, are expected to be about $100 million. This reduction in the third quarter is due to the seasonal slowdowns in many markets as construction, consumers' efforts to minimize inventories, and a slowdown in exports. We expect our combined worldwide tax rate in the fourth quarter to remain at about 38%.</p>
          <p>So to summarize, our third quarter income of $2.18 was about 12% higher than the consensus estimate. Our third quarter Oil &amp; Gas earnings of $2.6 billion were essentially unchanged from the second quarter, despite a $6 per barrel decline in our average oil realizations. Our annualized return on equity was 20% for the first nine months of 2011. Our total Oil &amp; Gas production of 739,000 BOE a day during the third quarter grew at more than 3% compared to the second quarter. Domestic Oil &amp; Gas volumes grew to 436,000 BOE a day in the third quarter, a 3% increase from the second quarter, and above our earlier guidance of 430,000 BOE a day to 432,000 BOE a day. Domestic volumes are expected to further increase by about 3,000 BOE a day to 4,000 BOE a day per month in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>I think we're now ready to take your questions, as long as they're brief.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from Paul Sankey of Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, all of you. Steve, one on the Bakken, actually. Your activity levels there seem very aggressive relative to your acreage. Could you just talk more about how you're seeing that play? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, at the end of the year I think we had 171,000 acres, and we may have picked up some more acreage during the year. The wells are actually doing very well. The small piece we had outside of the stuff we bought at the end of last year has yielded some surprisingly positive results. Costs are a little high up there, but they seem to be coming down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you mind putting some numbers around some of those comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the wells vary from where they are. So, maybe Bill can answer the question on the well costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Paul. As Steve said, the costs are coming down. We're somewhere in the $8 million to $8.5 million range, drill and complete, but the trend is down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and the results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We started the year, I think, at 2,500 BOE a day, 3,000 BOE a day, and we're running sort of around 7,000 BOE a day or 8,000 BOE a day currently. With a little luck we'll exit closer to 10,000 BOE a day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And would you be looking to buy more acreage out there, Steve, based on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I told you that every day somebody shows up with some acreage to buy. So if we were open on Saturday and Sunday we could have it seven days a week. So there's really plenty to buy, and we're sort of picky on where we buy it. So if it's additive to what we have and something we understand, we'd probably pick up some acreage. We're not interested in company acquisitions at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Steve, you gave away almost all your Midstream profitability, but you get it back in marketing and trading. One thing that I observe is that that segment seems to perform very poorly when oil equities have a bad quarter, which I would have thought exacerbates your volatility to the down side as a stock. Can you just talk a little bit about how you're seeing that segment now and where we go from here? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The segment is fine. There is certainly volatility in Phibro's results and, just depends on what day you choose to measure it. If you measured it today, he has probably made up all that he lost for the whole year and maybe then some. So it's pretty volatile.  It's not &#x2013; wasn't intended as a hedge. It's really, he's really long oil, and so are we. So I'm not interested in hedging the company's outcome. I'm sort of a long-term, modestly bullish on oil prices. Not as bullish as Phibro, but modestly bullish. So I'm not really bothered by this. It's a, I think over time, a pretty decent return business. If it turned out to be not so decent return, it's pretty easy to exit. So I'm really not bothered by the volatility. I know you might be, but the volatility &#x2013; being long oil is sort of where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, what I don't understand, though, is that you say that you're essentially long oil, but it seems to have the worst quarters when it's the oil equities that go down a lot. I mean, I'm thinking post-Macondo was a bad one, and then it doesn't seem the rate of change in oil was quite as bad as this result would  have suggested unless...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He was investing in some equities, and he's not doing that anymore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so far this quarter if we stopped here things are going well in that segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but again, this is the NBA game problem. No sense in tuning in 'til the last minute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Or a Michigan State/Wisconsin problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I get it. I'll leave it to someone else. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jessica Chipman of Tudor Pickering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two quick questions on the California side. First, just California liquids have grown nicely after bottoming really Q4 of last year. How should we think about splitting growth going forward between conventional and unconventional drilling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we cut back on our conventional so we could think about it some more since it requires a little more thought than the shale drilling. And I think that's had a positive effect on our results. I think we're more thoughtful and we're getting better results. So we'll do the conventional when we &#x2013; it will pick up as we get better results. But the results in the last quarter conventionally were pretty good. I don't have an easy answer for you. It just depends on how things go. So, but basically the base growth comes from the shale drilling. And every so often you'll have a successful conventional, just thing, which will boost &#x2013; you get an unusually high boost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you did have some of that this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It sure looks that way, doesn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The second question just, you expect to drill, I think, and complete 154 shale wells outside of Elk Hills?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How many of those are actually going to be hooked up and turned to sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>By the end, virtually all of them, probably. But the way we count them is they don't count until they're actually flowing into the line. Complete includes hooking them up. Otherwise you get some odd results. We're trying to get the time down between completing and hooking up so we're only &#x2013; for your purpose, all we're doing is counting when they get hooked up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Doug Leggate of Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll try a couple if I may. Updates on the gas plant for 2012, just the timing of commissioning and given your comments on how weak, I think you said, or poor, gas prices are, how is your appetite for getting that thing done as quickly as perhaps...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The plant is really handled by a contractor. He has a date he's got to deal with it by, so it's going to be on roughly May 1, doesn't make any difference what I think about gas prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So should we all think about 2012 as being a lumpy year for production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Every year is lumpy, if you hadn't noticed. It could be lumpier than normal. I'm still concerned about giving away gas at -- even California gas is a little higher, but at $4, even though the conventional wells have a significant amount of condensate in them. But it seems wasteful to sell gas for $4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just a couple on the shale, if I may. Why is the growth of 6,000 barrels per day for month, that obviously beat your prior guidance, why is it going to slow back 3,000 barrels to 4,000 barrels per day?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I actually answered it in the last question. The 3,000 barrels to 4,000 barrels is for the whole domestic business. It turned out that we got it all in California and the rest of the domestic business sort of equaled it. But, I'm using the shale wells to drive the 3,000 barrels to 4,000 barrels. And if I get lucky -- the conventional wells are significantly more profitable than the shale wells. In the case of maybe a shale well, might take you 90 days to get your money back, and a conventional well might take two weeks.</p>
          <p>So, but it's less predictable. So what we're giving you is the predictable number and every so often we'll do a little better, or if there is some mechanical problem, a little worse. But that's really what we're trying to do is give you something you can count on and if we do a little better, we do a little better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Last one for me is I think a few months back I attended a dinner that you were speaking at, obviously, and you said your first base target was to drill about 300 wells a year on the California shale. So I'm curious, where do you stand in terms of pushing forward the permit process and do you think that's still a reasonable first base target? If so when do you expect to get there? I'll leave it at that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I really think at this point, the program we have is all we can really count on from state permitting. Whatever portion of the 30 rigs that we're going to run in California is related to that. And as the permitting process, as we hope, improves, then we'll get there. Predicting what somebody in the state of California might do is way -- it makes predicting oil prices easy. So, I think you got to say that right now this is sort of where we are. And I don't know, I can't really give you a realistic number.</p>
          <p>I think as a practical matter, we could get there if we had the permits. Now the permitting process, the difficulty is, and there's two elements of it: first, it makes it really hard to plan because while you got a visible supply of permits it does depend on getting more and it used to be that you have an infinite supply; second thing is if you find something it makes it really hard to follow up because you might not have a permit for the next lease or something. So it makes the program significantly more inefficient than you might like it to be and makes it hard to plan. The other issue in the permitting, which is probably, has very little really effect on us currently is the injector wells. Most of the production in California, not ours, but generally, result is from either steam or something, some kind of injector program. And the state is studying that more carefully now.</p>
          <p>So that has a significant impact on people who are mostly steam generators in the state, you know steam based oil production. The state is pretty tight on that. The only place it's affected us, I mean, given long enough it might, but, is in Long Beach. And it's a small effect and it really just affects the income the way the contract works, the income of the state, the city and the port of Long Beach. So I guess by not making the injector wells they like the lower level of income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I'll leave it there. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jason Gammel of Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Steve, I just wanted to ask about your Permian operations and I appreciate you said that you don't expect the development program outside the CO2 operations to show production growth until next year. But I just wanted to ask about the rig count of 24. How many of those rigs are actually being devoted to that development program? And are you primarily drilling Wolfberry and Wolfcamp type wells with those rigs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Bill will answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Chazen. We've got &#x2013; expecting a range of somewhere between 14 and 16 of those rigs working the development side of the Permian. And of those rigs we're going to probably run 9 to 10 in the Wolfberry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again these are, remind you that these are our operated, and we have a whole bunch of other activity where somebody else is operating it. So all we're giving you is our operated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Understood. If I can just shift internationally the production in Oman continues to show a nice steady uptick. I assume that is just continued effects from the Mukhaizna steam injection program. How much more do you have to go on Mukhaizna, Steve? Is this something that is still multi-year growth? Or are we starting to near the plateau there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's really caused by two elements and Sandy can cover that. But the old traditional stuff is actually doing very well in the north. And Mukhaizna's doing well. So I'll let Sandy answer your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Mukhaizna today is running 120,000 barrels a day gross. And during 2012 we're adding another 200,000 barrels a day of steam injectability. So that will ramp us up to around 150,000 barrels a day at the end of 2012 or maybe first quarter 2013. As Steve said, the northern Oman is running 99,000 barrels, 100,000 barrels a day gross, which is the highest it's ever sustained in our 25 years. So both looking good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Sandy, would there be any further injection phases after that one? Or is that something you'd still be studying now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're planning to have 600,000 barrels, 625,000 barrels a day of steam. There's a possibility of adding more later, but it's not yet in the plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These plans are approved in stages by the government and other people. So this isn't -- you don't give them a 30-year plan, it's sort of a 30-month plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Arjun Murti of Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, do you have an update on the non-shale California exploration program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was the conventional I was referring to. So I think you can see the &#x2013; again the base guidance roughly, or if you thought about it maybe half of the growth or a little more, that we'd tell you the 3,000 BOE to 4,000 BOE a day a month is from the monotonous shale drilling. The rest of it, if you see an odd number, it comes from that program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think you should view it that way. The other way to view it, just to be honest, when we give you our exploration expense, now it won't &#x2013; it's not worth it <mark type="ph" /> on (37:48) every quarter, but on a cumulative basis for the year, it's basically done by risking each of the wells. So we say, well this is a 15% chance of success, this is a 30%, and we add that up and that's what we give you as the exploration expense. When we continually are lower, you should assume we're having more success than we planned and a lot of that would be in California, some in Colombia and some in Oman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess a few years ago you announced the larger Kern County discovery, presumably you've not had one of that size or we might have heard about it. And...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We might not have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine. A follow up on the Bakken. You've always described it as a science experiment. These slides I think are easily the most positive you've ever been on it, by your standards at least?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well it's like gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it still you need to do a bigger transaction to step up here? The prices are obviously high. There was a recent big transaction. Do you just patiently wait out the next downturn? Or how do you think about scaling your Bakken? Is it patience?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I said earlier, this recent price that some national oil company paid for some stuff is not reflective of what we're paying for acreage with tax bases. And so, I say there is a lot of &#x2013; I mean whatever number of acres you want to have, given a year or two, you can get. So we &#x2013; somebody is here, I'm not kidding, virtually every day with some deal to buy 7,000 or 8,000 or 12,000 or 15,000 acres. If it fits our business model we look to add it. If it doesn't, we don't. But there is no real shortage of opportunity. The leases expire, they roll over. There is really a lot going on. The prices are not &#x2013; I don't think the recent transaction is reflective of the market. I think that was a special deal for national oil companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so the kind of nagging concern some have that we should be braced for some inevitable big transaction...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The purpose of an acquisition is to make the company better, not worse. We have plenty to do in our current portfolio so we're looking for ways to make the company better or stronger. We're not looking for ways to dilute the outcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep. And just a final quick one, Steve, any early thoughts on 2012 CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't really know where I am. We've got a lot of uncertainty about the level in Iraq, the Shah gas field, some uncertainty there. We don't know what we're going to have to spend going into Libya, something I presume, at least for trucks. So there is at least some expenditure in Libya. The U.S. business has a huge opportunity set of high return, relatively high-return projects, in aggregate probably beyond what I would be willing to commit to next year. So we'll push that off a little bit. So really I don't know where I am. We're not going to negative cash flow, that's for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Doug Terreson of ISI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And congratulations on your results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, I have a couple of questions on Bahrain. First, there seems to be some movement over there on the changes to the natural gas price regime in that country and also there seems to be movement on approval for your deep gas exploration plan. So I wanted to see if we could get an update on the status of those two items to the degree possible?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The deep gas, the government's approved the deep gas drilling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So sometime there is a seismic <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:14) seismic and I assume the wells will be drilled as soon as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It might be, probably going to be next year at this point. I don't know anything about gas. Sandy doesn't know anything either, so I don't know what is going on there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's all I had. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sven Del Pozzo of IHS Herold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Late 2010, I think you guys made some comments regarding what point we are in the life cycle of your CO2 floods in Texas. And then I wonder if you could make similar comments this time around and perhaps tie it into the 5% to 8% long-term production growth rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the CO2 floods, normally you have a period of increased gas injection and then it takes two or three years for the results to show up. So the increased injection began, say early this year, maybe middle of this year or so, you'll start to see the effects of it a couple of years from now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So similar kind of question on California shale &#x2013; no just, sorry, total California production as a whole. In the past you guys mentioned it would grow to equal that of Texas by 2013, I believe was the year, correct me if I'm wrong. How does that tie into the 5% to 8% production growth rate long term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It obviously does. It's growing &#x2013; California, the domestic production is growing, if you use the 3,000 BOE a day to 4 BOE a day a month, it's growing 6% a year, so it ties in pretty good, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is there a chance it might -- sounds like things might be getting better. Is there...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You've got to watch this quarterly stuff. You could have a good quarter and a bad quarter, so maybe they're getting better, but -- on the ground it's better, but there's always interruptions and stuff, which make one quarter or some other quarter look good or not so good. So right now on the ground we're doing fine both in the Permian and in California and we're pretty confident about the growth over time. So I don't think there is much problem with the growth per month that we've said. And it could do better I suppose, but over time I think it will, but probably not. It's just not that predictable quarter-to-quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then in the Midstream I did see a pretty big jump year-over-year in terms of Midstream CapEx. What's that related to and if so how much of that relates...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gas plants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...to your E&amp;P business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's gas plants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gas plants. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Herrlin of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, Steve. When you look at your growth going forward, you said you were going to do less gas. So should we assume that it's going to be more like two-thirds liquids, crude and liquids versus half and half, because you're current growth has been kind of split? In the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, where we're going to cut back easily is in the Midcontinent where the gas is real dry. No sense in drilling, so you might see -- if you could see it, you might see a decline in something like the Hugoton or something like that where the gas is dry and the wells are cheap. Just drives you nuts to give it away for $3.50. You might make money at that, but I'd rather defer it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With respect to California, you're split in terms of sequential volume growth, it was also 50/50 liquids versus gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This goes back to the conventional -- if you have a conventional -- the current county-type discovery is a gas condensate reservoir. And if you happen to hit one of those, you're going to get a lot of gas and a lot of condensate. The gas is just gas and the condensate really pays for the whole well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. With respect to your black oil sequential line growth in California, it was 2,000 barrels sequentially. How much was that from your conventional operations versus the new shale type plays?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't really know. But, my guess is the conventional added a fair amount to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Last one from me. You mentioned earlier with exploration expenses that when you miss on the plus side, so to speak, it's because you're having more success.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More success than the risking would have generated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. And essentially you had overestimated by 50% basically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you go back and do the &#x2013; I wouldn't focus on a single quarter because it could be just delays. But if you look at the nine months, I think if you went back and looked at what we said and what we actually did over the nine months, you'll find that we're pretty far below.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then last one for me. You said of the Chemical ops that you opted to sell power. How much net income did you make off that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>$40 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wow. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ed Westlake of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, congrats again on the numbers. A lot of questions have been asked. But just a small one on the shale well costs, the $3.5 million, does that include hook up? I mean what's the total cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We don't do what the small producers do and just give you &#x2013; that includes build out the site, the hookup, the completion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not just some part of the cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thanks for that. And then any update on Yemen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We really don't know anything, I think it's fair to say. There is &#x2013; and so it's hard to negotiate with &#x2013; there, so it's hard to tell what is going on. Sandy, anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only, one of our fields is down for a while, another insurgency, but the production is holding well and our share is well up to what we predicted and we just don't know anything about the Masila block yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Masila is about 8,000 BOE a day, by the way, just so you have a scale for it out of the total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thanks. And then on the overall, what you pick up as you walk around, some people are concerned about CO2 availability and then other people are concerned about competency in shales. I mean these are just things that are, it would be interesting to hear your thoughts on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't &#x2013; a lot of the discussion on the CO2 is about small producers who have different issues. Our competency, well, I think the answer comes from the production. If we make our production and it grows, you'll assume we're competent and if we don't, you'll assume we're incompetent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the question is linked back to Arjun's question earlier on the back end, is that when I'm talking about shales, I'm talking about shales outside your core area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bakken? Yeah, I think we have some &#x2013; we've undergone some learning clearly in the beginning. This isn't exactly a state secret up there. You got all these vendors who are reasonably experienced so I think we've come up the learning curve nicely. We have some more to learn for sure. But I don't think there is any &#x2013; our productivity, because we benchmark ourselves, is the same as other people in the same area, sometimes better, but sometimes a little worse. But I think it's pretty much the same. So we don't have a productivity issue whether we're competent or not up there. We'll know here in the next couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thanks for those clarifications.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from Pavel Molchanov of Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. Just one quick one, if I may. Other than shortage of vehicles and other logistical issues, are there any legal or political hurdles at the moment to you resuming operations in Libya, sanctions or something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sandy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our operations in the fields where we have interest have slowly started coming back on by the operators themselves. We actually have a management team going in there this weekend to visit with all of the government entities that we normally deal with and I would say that we don't expect any surprises but I wouldn't want to really bet on that until after we have some meetings with them. But indications are that they are willing and happy to have us come back in and resume where we left off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think there is any U.S. issues, if that's the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you expect the fiscal terms to be in line with what they were under the previous government?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All indications are that they are going to honor the contracts that are, that were in existence when this war started.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very good. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ann Kohler of CRT Capital Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentleman. Thank you for taking my call. In looking at the Libyan situation, following on to that question, do you think that there are opportunities -- it may be too early, but additional opportunities that the new government might like to expedite additional work? Or is it not, is it too early -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's just too early to talk about that. Just depends on how they want to manage their industry. Right now they have to put up half the capital. Whether they want to do that in the future or not really determines &#x2013; if they want to continue to invest their half the capital &#x2013; if they don't want to, then there will be other opportunities. It's just hard to say because you don't really know what it will look like a year from now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and then just on the acquisition side, if you could just give us sort of an update. A year ago you indicated that you didn't expect that you'd have a lot of action, or acquisition, and then you certainly did step things up at the very end of the year. Could you provide us with a little update and color on the types of opportunities? I would assume that, I guess the last couple of calls you've indicated that you really weren't interested in necessarily just adding acreage in California and it sounds as though you would be selective in looking at opportunities within the Bakken?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know if I would interpret my remarks that way. We always look for stuff in California that fits our business. So I don't think it's like &#x2013; we always add something in California. As far as the Bakken is concerned, we look at a lot of different fairly small opportunities. I'll repeat what I said before, we're not interested in the large corporate-type acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jeff Dietert at Simmons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Sorry to go back on California shale but I wanted to ask, a pretty substantial increase in the number of shale wells expected to be completed, the 154.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you just talk about how that &#x2013; if the pace is accelerating, maybe what that looks like in third quarter and perhaps in fourth quarter as far as number of wells completed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we actually gave you the &#x2013; I gave you the fourth quarter in my remarks. But as the well costs come down, that is basically reflecting the fact that I'm getting more for my money and therefore I'll drill more wells. If we started at the beginning of the year, and we thought the wells were going to cost $4.5 million, we would have said some number of wells, but that's how long it takes, but we're shortening the time. So the costs come down and you drill more wells in the year. So that's what's really going on here, I think right now. This is pretty much what we had planned as far as the breakdown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from Doug Leggate of Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, I wanted to go back to your prepared remarks. You were not by any chance signaling a change of view in share buybacks with your commentary. Can you maybe just give us some clarity as to exactly what you were trying to signal there in terms of where share buybacks rank given how much cash you're throwing off right now? Thanks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll read the relevant portions of the remarks if you'd like, if that's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll edit out the irrelevant portions. We will not have some kind of regular program in lieu of dividends, which is what some companies do. We think dividends are more effective. We've had this discussion over the last decade. So that's what we think. What we are saying here is that when the &#x2013; I'll just make up a number. If we're trading below what I think our F&amp;D is or what I can acquire assets for, which is roughly the same, then we'll shift the money from a capital program or from our free cash or from the acquisition program into share repurchases. And that is actually &#x2013; in recent times, that's happened. So that's what we're saying. So you shouldn't expect every quarter we're going to spend a zillion dollars no matter what the price is. But if the price, if our capital program can't add value compared to buying shares, then the shares will be repurchased.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there an operational limit on your capital program now, in other words what you're capable of actually dealing with relative to the cash flow you're throwing off? Does this become a governor for managing your balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a point of view I could spend a lot of money on share repurchases. We're sitting on $4 billion of cash; I don't know if you missed that. And we don't really have &#x2013; I bought it, I took the cash because it was cheap and provides some insurance for the volatility that's in the market. But we got plenty of flexibility to repurchase the shares if they don't reflect &#x2013; if it reflects essentially below replacement cost of the reserves. So if I think that the price &#x2013; the replacement costs or our finding and development costs, however you want to describe it, is $2 a  barrel and the stock is trading for $1 a barrel, I'll take all the money we have and dump it into the share repurchase because it gives a  better outcome for the shareholders.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, if our finding and development cost is $2 and the stock is trading for $12 a barrel, the shareholders are better off us investing in the business because you got the multiplier. This is a complicated way -- this is exactly what Warren Buffett said, actually, except that he tied it to book value. Book value isn't a very useful measure for us, so I'm tying this to replacement cost. So if the stock is cheap enough, the company will repurchase it because that helps the remaining shareholders. But we're also going to do it in a way that doesn't &#x2013; to kind of reward the remaining shareholders, not assist the exiting ones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. That was very clear. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from John Herrlin of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, one follow up for me, Steve. In terms of your production growth this year, how much of it's been in the U.S. acquisition versus accelerated spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only side &#x2013; in the U.S. &#x2013; the Williston started out, I think,  at 2,000 BOE a day or 3,000 BOE a day. So you can decide yourself. We bought the acreage, obviously. But we didn't buy a lot of production. South Texas was bought, although there has been some growth.  And we bought 20 million a day of gas in California; 10 million showed up in the last quarter and 10 million more in this quarter because it was only a partial quarter. So there really isn't very much of it that's, where we bought production. Now we bought acreage or opportunity and we drill it up, but it just depends on how you want to describe &#x2013; if you want to go back long enough, Elk Hills was bought, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not that far. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions. Are there anything closing remarks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That's fine. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And if there is any further questions, call us here in New York. Thanks for listening, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This does conclude today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>