<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1488489" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>390</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Christopher G. Stavros</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">James M. Lienert</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Stephen I. Chazen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Leo Mariani</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President and President, Americas, Oxy Oil and Gas">William E. Albrecht</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Arjun Narayana Murti</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Doug T. Terreson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd.">Jason D. Gammel</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor Pickering Holt &amp; Co. Securities, Inc.">Matthew Portillo</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Capital One Southcoast, Inc.">Eliot Javanmardi</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Ed G. Westlake</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="IHS Herold, Inc.">Sven Del Pozzo</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President">Edward A. Lowe</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Katherine Lucas Minyard</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James &amp; Associates">Alex Morris</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Americas Securities LLC">John P. Herrlin</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Christy and I will be your conference operator today. At this I time, I would like to welcome everyone to the Occidental Petroleum 2012 Earnings Release Conference call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Christopher Stavros. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Christy. Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Occidental Petroleum's Second Quarter 2012 Earnings Conference Call. Joining us on the call this morning from Los Angeles are Stephen Chazen, OXY's President and Chief Executive Officer, Jim Lienert, OXY's Chief Financial Officer, Bill Albrecht, President of OXY's Oil and Gas business in the Americas, and Sandy Lowe, President of our International Oil and Gas Operations. In just a moment I'll turn the call over to our CFO, Jim Lienert, who will review our financial and operation results for this year's second quarter. Steve Chazen will then follow with comments on our performance, an update on our capital program and production for 2012 and including our outlook for the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter 2012 earnings press release, investor relations supplemental schedules, conference call presentation slides, which refer to both Jim's and Steve's remarks, can be downloaded off our website at, www.oxy.com.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call over to Jim Lienert. Jim, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. Net income was $1.3 billion or $1.64 per diluted share in the second quarter of 2012, compared to $1.8 billion or $2.23 per diluted share in the second quarter of 2011 and $1.6 billion or $1.92 per diluted share in the first quarter of 2012. All the drop in the second quarter earnings compared to the first quarter of 2012 was attributable to the decline in commodity prices. Worldwide oil and domestic gas and NGL prices were significantly lower during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Here's a segment break down for the second quarter. Oil &amp; Gas segment earnings for the second quarter of 2012 were $2 billion compared with $2.5 billion in the first quarter of 2012 and $2.6 billion in the second quarter of 2011. In the Oil &amp; Gas segment, the second quarter 2012 daily production was 766,000 barrels, the highest volume in the company's history for the second consecutive quarter, and was up 7% from the same period of 2011.</p>
          <p>Our total domestic production was 462,000 barrels per day, the seventh consecutive domestic quarterly volume record for the company. Total domestic production was 9% higher than the second quarter of 2011. Latin America volumes were 33,000 barrels per day. Colombia's production of 31,000 barrels per day improved 7,000 barrels a day from the first quarter of 2012 due to significantly lower levels of insurgent activity in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In the Middle East region, volumes were 271,000 barrels per day. In Oman, the second quarter production was 72,000 barrels per day, 2,000 barrels lower than the first quarter volumes. In Qatar, the second quarter production was 74,000 barrels per day, 2,000 barrels higher than the first quarter volumes. For Dolphin and Bahrain combined, daily production increased 7,000 barrels from the first quarter, which includes planned plant shutdowns in Dolphin. The rest of the Middle East/North Africa production decreased by 10,000 barrels per day.</p>
          <p>Oil prices and production sharing and similar contract factors did not significantly impact this quarter's production volumes compared to the previous quarter or the second quarter of 2011. Our second quarter sales volumes were 759,000 barrels per day, slightly lower than our production volumes due to the typing of liftings in the Middle East/North Africa.</p>
          <p>Second quarter 2012 realized prices were lower for our products compared to the first quarter of the year. Our worldwide crude oil realized price was $99.34 per barrel, a decrease of about 8%. Worldwide NGLs were $42.06 per barrel, a decrease of about 20%, and domestic natural gas prices were $2.09 per Mcf, a decline of 26%.</p>
          <p>Second quarter 2012 realized prices were also lower than the second quarter 2011 prices for all our products. On a year-over-year basis, price decreases were 4% for the worldwide crude oil, 27% for worldwide NGLs and 51% for domestic natural gas. Realized oil prices for the quarter represented 106% of the average WTI and 91% of the average Brent price. Realized NGL prices were 45% of WTI and realized domestic gas prices were 92% of the average NYMEX price. Price changes affected our quarterly earnings before income taxes by $38 million for a $1 per barrel change in oil prices and $8 million for a $1 per barrel change in NGL prices. A swing of $0.50 per million BTUs in domestic gas prices affects quarterly pre-tax earnings by about $35 million. These price change sensitivities include the impact of production sharing contract volume changes on income.</p>
          <p>Oil &amp; Gas cash production costs were $14.50 a barrel for the first six months of 2012 compared with last year's twelve-month costs of $12.84 a barrel. The cost increase reflects higher well maintenance activity, in part reflecting our higher well count, higher work over activity and higher support and injection costs. Taxes other than on income, which are directly related to product prices, were $2.46 per barrel for the first six months of 2012, similar to last year's comparable period. Second quarter exploration expense was $96 million.</p>
          <p>Chemical segment earnings for the second quarter of 2012 were $194 million compared to $184 million in the first quarter of 2012 and $253 million for the second quarter of 2011. The sequential quarterly improvement was due to improved PVC and VCM margins, driven primarily by lower ethylene costs. The year-over-year decrease was the result of lower domestic and export caustic volumes, lower VCM export demand and lower PVC and VCM export prices, partially offset by lower natural gas and ethylene costs.</p>
          <p>Midstream segment earnings were $77 million for the second quarter of 2012 compared to $131 million in the first quarter of 2012 and $187 million in the second quarter of 2011. The declining earnings was mostly in the marketing and trading businesses and, to a lesser degree, in the gas plants, reflecting lower NGL prices, partially offset by improvements in the pipeline businesses. The worldwide effective tax rate was 40% for the second quarter of 2012. Our second quarter U.S. and foreign tax rates are included in the investor relations supplemental schedules.</p>
          <p>Cash flow from operations for the first six months of 2012 was $6 billion. We used $5.1 billion of the company's total cash flow to fund capital expenditures and $1 billion for acquisitions. Financial activities, which included dividends paid, stock buybacks and a $.75 billion borrowing during the quarter, provided a net $800 million of cash flow. These and other net cash flows resulted in $4.4 billion cash balance at June 30.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures for the first six months of 2012 were $5.1 billion, of which $2.7 billion was spent in the second quarter. Year-to-date capital expenditures by segment were 82% in Oil &amp; Gas, 15% in Midstream and the remainder in Chemicals. The Al Hosn Shah gas project made up about 11% of the total capital spending for the first six months of 2012. Our acquisitions for the first six months of 2012 were $1 billion, mostly consisting of bolt-on acquisitions in the Williston Basin, south Texas and the Permian.</p>
          <p>The weighted average basic shares outstanding for the first six months of 2012 were 810.4 million and the weighted average diluted shares outstanding were 811.2 million. Fully diluted shares outstanding at the end of the quarter were approximately 810 million. Our debt to capitalization ratio was 16%, and at the end of the second quarter we issued $1.75 billion of senior notes at a weighted average interest rate of 2.4%, which brought the company's average effective borrowing rate down to 3%. Copies of the press release announcing our second quarter earnings in the investor relations supplemental schedules are available on our website or through the SEC's EDGAR system.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Steve Chazen, who will provide guidance for the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jim. Occidental's second quarter 2012 production set an all-time record for the company for the second consecutive quarter, and the domestic Oil &amp; Gas segment produced record volumes for the seventh consecutive quarter. Second quarter domestic production of 462,000 barrel equivalents consisted of 322,000 barrels of liquids and 840 million cubic feet of gas per day. This was an increase of 700,000 barrel equivalents per day compared to the first quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>About 86% of the domestic production growth of the first quarter of 2012 was in liquids, which grew from 316,000 barrels a day to 322,000 barrels a day. Compared the second quarter of 2011, our domestic production grew by 9% or 38,000 barrels a day, of which 25,000 barrels a day was liquids productions growth and 79 million cubic feet a day was gas.</p>
          <p>Our annualized return on equity for the first six months of 2012 was 15% and our return on capital employed was 13%. For our capital program, we are raising our estimate of the total year capital program to $9.2 billion from our previous announced level of $8.3 billion. Of the increase, about $600 million is for the Al Hosn Shah gas project, the remainder of the increase going to the rest of the Oil &amp; Gas segment, primarily to non-operated properties where our forecasting ability is limited. We expect our capital spend rate to slow down modestly from the current levels during the back half of the year and stabilize in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>The Al Hosn gas project is approximately 49% complete and is progressing as planned. This project made up about 11% of our capital program for six months of this year. The spending continuing at current levels, we are increasing our anticipated spending for the remainder of 2012, as I just mentioned. However, total development capital for the project is expected to be in line with previous estimates.</p>
          <p>In our domestic operations, we expect our total average rig count at current levels of about 75 to go down to an average of 70 by the end of the year. However, with the mix of rigs, we'll shift among very different regions related to changes in gas and NGL prices. With our production growth wedged firmly in the place for the back half of the year, we will focus our efforts on improving our profitability. This includes an increased oil program rather than drilling gas NGL wells. We are releasing and will continue to release under-performing rigs and crews. We will also work on improving our operating costs. These things are well within our ability to achieve. We expect to do more with less money in the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>California, we're continuing to see improvement with respect to permitting issues relative to last year. We received improved field level rules and new permits for both injection wells and drilling locations. The regulatory agency continues to be responsive and committed to working through the backlog of permits. The new Elk Hills gas plant, which went into operation early July, will positively affect our operational efficiency and production in the back half of the year.</p>
          <p>Turning to production expectations in the back half of the year. Over the past year, we have generally achieved our 6,000 to 8,000 barrel a day quarter-over-quarter domestic production increase. We expect that we will achieve the high end of this range increase throughout the rest of the year, which would give us an entry rate into the new year of at least 480,000 barrels a day. The increase will be spread among all of the domestic operations.</p>
          <p>Internationally at current prices, we expect production to increase modestly for the rest of the year, depending on spending levels in Iraq. This includes the effect of a drop in production at Dolphin to about 40,000 barrels a day starting in the third quarter resulting from the full cost recovery of the pre-startup capital over the first five years of production which commenced in July 2007.</p>
          <p>We expect international sales volume in the third quarter of 2012 to be similar to the second quarter. A $5 change in global oil prices would impact our daily volumes by about 3,000 barrels a day. The financial impact of this volume change is incorporated in the product price sensitivities that Jim provided you.</p>
          <p>Additionally, we expect exploration expense to be about $85 million for seismic and drilling for our exploration program in the third quarter. The Chemical segment earnings are expected to be about $175 million. Weakness in export demand, conditions in Europe and China, a slowdown in the U.S. demand and rising U.S. natural gas costs will keep some pressure on margins. We expect our combined worldwide tax rate in the third quarter of 2012 to increase to about 42%.</p>
          <p>To summarize, we closed the quarter of our second consecutive all-time company production and the seventh consecutive record domestic Oil &amp; Gas production. We increased our total domestic production by 7,000 barrels a day over the first quarter and by 38,000 barrels a day from the second quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Domestically, where we are the largest onshore liquids producer in the lower 48, our production increased by 9% the second quarter of last year. Our total production increased by 7% in the second quarter and year-over-year basis. We are increasing our estimate of total year capital program to $9.2 billion from our previously announced $8.3 billion. Of the increase, about $600 million is for the Al Hosn Shah gas project, the remainder of the increase going to the rest of the Oil &amp; Gas segment. Our business generated cash flow from operations is $6 billion in the first six months of 2012. We spent about $5.1 billion of our cash flow on our capital program.</p>
          <p>I think at this point, we're ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question comes from Leo Mariani of RBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Just a quick question on your Permian Basin production. It looks like it was down a tiny bit in the second quarter. I just wanted to see if there was anything unusual just in terms of interruptions or maybe just timing of completions there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill can answer that. Bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Leo, really it's all around gas plants. We had several significant gas plant turnarounds in the quarter as well as some third-party gas plant outages. We think most of these turnarounds are behind us for the rest of the year. But it was all attributable strictly to gas plants, both third-party and company operated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And you guys talked about going from 75 rigs to 70 rigs and really de-emphasizing NGLs and gas and adding some crude rigs. Can you give us a little bit more color in terms where the rigs are going to be dropped and where you're going to add some on the crude side and as you reshuffle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. But we talked about reducing our count in the Williston last quarter and that's continuing. There's some quite &#x2013; rigs nationally we have that we have are less than the bottom eight of efficiency. So, we're basically releasing those rigs. We expect that with the higher concentration of better quality rigs and crews we'll do better in the quarter, and I expect we'll drill as many wells in the back half of the year as we did in the first half of the year with fewer rigs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The shift is &#x2013; we're not quite through shifting yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, gotcha. In terms of acquisitions, you guys talked about doing $1 billion dollars kind of in the first half of the year. Are you guys going to continue to be very active on the acquisition side in the second half? And is there any type of certain area that you guys have focused on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It looks pretty slow here in the third quarter. We have very little, if anything, in the hopper in the third quarter. So, I don't expect to see much in the third quarter. There's a fair bit of ask spread between what we would be willing to pay and what somebody would be willing to expect. So, we're not in any hurry. We don't need to do anything. You shouldn't expect to see any large scale M&amp;A from us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Arjun Murti of Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Steve, you did mention some bolt-on acreage acquisitions in the Williston. Can you just talk about where your position is now? I know you dropped some rigs and been have been less enthusiastic. Where are you acreage-wise now in the Williston?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're north of 300,000 acres.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the bolt-on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know exactly, they never tell me this stuff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. So do you have any update on California exploration? It's something you highlighted a couple years ago. I know there's some small stuff and some bigger stuff. But, where is that program now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's actually doing pretty well. We have some moderate successes in some oil and we've got some things that are working. They are a little bit off the mainstream of off the main plan that we had as far as where they're located, and there's still some acreage to be acquired that other people have. So, I just don't want to go into details. But I think it's doing pretty well and we're doing &#x2013; we have some nice adds in the few million barrels a year, maybe 10 million barrel, 12 million barrel adds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. And, then just lastly, I know you've started increasing the drilling in some of the Permian unconventional stuff. Any comments on how that's going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, the gassy NGL stuff, while it may be interesting at some point, not real exciting right now. And a lot of these plays are towards New Mexico and people call them liquids-rich, I call them gas-rich. So they are just not that exciting right now. And &#x2013; but the oil stuff is doing pretty well, and really we're doing just fine.</p>
          <p>And I can't &#x2013; there's another area where there's some poor performing rigs and crews that we're going to upgrade the quality of that. So I &#x2013; my focus, as I said in the back half of the year, I think the production ledge will be fine. Maybe even more than fine in the back half of the year because I think we've got a pretty good-sized backlog. But I'm really focused on improving the efficiency of the rigs and generating &#x2013; lowering the operating costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. And look forward to seeing your new CFO at some point here. Congrats on that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Arjun. She'll be pleased to hear that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Doug Terreson of ISI Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Steve. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Doug. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm doing fine. You guys are obviously a leader in the Permian. And this BridgeTex Pipeline looks likely to debottleneck that area to some extent if it were to materialize. My question is whether or not you could provide us an update on your expectations and any timeline that you feel is reasonable for that situation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think I'd rather defer that and let Magellan talk about it...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...since they're the pipeline company. But you should understand that we could give enough crude to make any pipeline go...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...out of the Basin, perhaps maybe even more than one pipeline go. Not only do we have our net production, but we also have the royalty production and third-party barrels. And so the plan in the Basin is to expand our gathering system, hook it into these pipelines and maybe make one or two lines that go maybe into &#x2013; whether it goes into Houston or Corpus and then into Houston, and put as much of our stuff through there as we can. We're not trying to fix the problem in the Basin, we're just trying to fix our problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. Let me ask you another question. In Abu Dhabi, can you tell us whether or not you guys are still in consideration on the onshore development phase with the SPC. And if not, do you think that you could be brought in at a later date? So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're on &#x2013; we're actively involved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actively involved. Okay, great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Doug Leggate of Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, hi. Good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The gas plants in California, I guess we've been kind of waiting for this for a while. My understanding is you've also gone ahead and ordered a second gas plant. Can you help us understand...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're in the study phase in the second gas plant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Remember, gas isn't such a hot commodity right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. With the new gas plant having started up then, can you walk us through how does that help? Because I think I recall the capacity there was fairly significant. But what should we anticipate in terms of a volume response as a result of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know yet. When we ordered the plant, we thought we would drill more gas wells. And, obviously, we're a little ways away from that yet. So you'll get I think maybe three effects. The most significant one is the increase in reliability. And so, there's a significant loss every quarter due to something that's blamed on some third party. So we'll have to take the blame ourselves now I guess instead of blaming it on somebody else.</p>
          <p>Second, there's a much deeper cut, and so there'll be more NGLs, for whatever they are worth, coming out of the plant. And, finally, there's clearly more capacity. And I'd like to defer the discussion about the capacity response from the rest of the field until we get at least a quarter of actual results rather than just a few weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And my follow-up, if I may, is also on California. So a few &#x2013; I guess a bunch of quarters ago, you kind of laid out the running room you had there, but the Permian seems to have gotten an awful lot better. I guess what I'm curious on what is it going to take for you to get after what you've acknowledged are some of the highest IRR opportunities in the portfolio? Because it seems that with your guidance on rigs, you don't plan to do that any time soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm waiting for them to reduce their cost per well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (24:15).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's simply they can make step changes, sizeable step changes in their cost per well. And my experience over the last however long is giving them more money does not cause that. And so a little diet for a little while will have significant reductions in their cost per well. I'm talking not 10%, not 20%, but a third.</p>
          <p>And once they get to the point where their well costs are in line with what they ought to achieve, then we'll pick up the pace. But if I can reduce the cost, I'll get more wells for the same money. That's really what I'm after. I'm not after volume, per se. I'm actually after money. And right now, they can do a lot better. And they will. But the only way to do it is to ensure that they feel pressed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Forgive me, Steve. You dominate the play. How do you benchmark what's achievable when you're I guess competing with yourself?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Competing with myself. And I know we can tell what's achievable. We've experimented and we know. So it's not a theoretical discussion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We changed some things and we had step changes in it. And this is just the beginning. So they can do better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I'll leave it there. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jason Gammel of Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Steve, I wanted to ask you first of all about your transportation capacity out of the Permian Basin. And really my question is really more around what we've seen as a building differential between Cushing and Midland. I know with the pipeline that you acquired a few years back that you should have the ability to avoid any <mark type="ph" /> glut in (26:25) differentials there, on at least some volumes. I wanted to see how much you're actually covered on transportation there.</p>
          <p>And then my second question is really more housekeeping on the acquisitions. Should we look at the $1 billion of acquisitions year-to-date as incremental to the new CapEx guidance that you've given? And is there any associated production figure with those acquisitions for the second quarter and then for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Starting with the Midland, there was a small problem that somebody had in Midland early sometime this quarter, last quarter, and that's really gone away. I think some of the difference is pretty much gone, so you don't really see that anymore. There was &#x2013; somebody had a problem there, I can't remember who.</p>
          <p>The capital, I've included in the capital additional &#x2013; for the back half of the year, the additional spending on the acquisitions that came in the first half. And then, there was no production effect from the acquisitions in the second quarter because most of them were done late in the quarter. And there might be 1,000 barrels a day or 2,000 barrels a day, all liquids, in the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to follow up on the differential again, Steve. It may have been a relatively temporary issue in the 2Q, but does it indicate that you're starting to experience pretty tight infrastructure in the Permian in general, so it could be another issue that crops up periodically over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think that just take a long view the Basin was &#x2013; the pipeline system was built for a very large amount of oil years ago, and was allowed to degrade because everybody thought it was going to deplete away. And the ownership of the pipelines changed from integrated producers to, generally speaking, cash flow-driven organizations who get paid on increased distributions rather than maintenance.</p>
          <p>And so what has happened is that the system is not in particularly great shape, which is why we bought the pipeline systems. And we're going to invest some money to improve our results in that. But the system is tight right now and it does not take much to create a modest disruption. We're in better shape than most people because we control our own destiny largely. But I think this is something, not just in the Permian but everywhere, where everybody assumed the United States was going out of business in the oil industry.</p>
          <p>Even if you don't buy some of the more ridiculous things that people have put out as far as growth, a modest amount of growth will tax the system nationwide because the infrastructure is basically designed currently for &#x2013; as a cash cow rather than something that you need to keep up. Does that answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's helpful. Thank you, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Matt Portillo of Tudor Pickering Holt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two quick questions from me. Just on the acquisition side for the second quarter, could you give us an idea of the $2.7 billion what approximately was spent on acquisitions?</p>
          <p>And then just a quick second question here. In relation to Colombia, obviously, you guys had a nice uptick back to normalized volumes. There seems to have been continued frequency of pipeline -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think our capital &#x2013; just &#x2013; the acquisition money in the second quarter was like $700 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was $1 billion for the back half &#x2013; for the first half of the year. Capital was $2.7 billion, but the acquisition was I think $700 million or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. That's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so it was $1 billion for the first six months in acquisitions. I got lost in the rest of the question, so if you could repeat it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And just in terms of Colombia, you obviously had a nice uptick in production in the second quarter, I think, as Ca&#xF1;o Lim&#xF3;n pipelines kind of normalized. Are you guys seeing similar levels of production heading into the third quarter? And are there any improvements that you are seeing on the security side down in Colombia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we'll let Bill answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, so far in the third quarter we've had about 1 thousand barrels a day outage is all. You know, we obviously have had more insurgent activity in the third quarter so far. Who know what it's going to be like for the rest of the quarter. But, so far, there has not been a material effect on production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is capable producing 32,000 barrels a day, 33,000 barrels a day. So there was some loss even in the second quarter, so all he's really saying is it's sort of like the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Eliot Javanmardi of Capital One Southcoast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick question for you. Do you still see the Williston basin as a potential longer-term resource play for the company? And the reason I ask that is you obviously get great returns in California in the Permian plays. I'm trying to understand what kind of scenario would you actually be willing to put your dollars at work in the Williston. And I think you addressed some of it on the well cost front, but what scenario would you envision that even if it is the number three play you would invest in, for example, in the U.S., how would you assess that situation as to when you feel good about putting dollars to work there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Definitely number three. It's really a cost issue. I think the service companies are getting as rich as pigs there. And I think until the costs come down and the efficiency improves, we'll continue to focus on the best wells and the most efficient wells and improving our learning curve. We're still on I think a learning curve phase.</p>
          <p>There's that and then there's a differential issue, which I think could be fixed over time. But I'm in no hurry to put capital there. We still continue to put capital there, but not to the level that we were. We're still making 16,000, 17,000 a day there, but it's clearly assets for the future rather than a big driver for today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you for the color.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Edward Westlake of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just a question. You mentioned last quarter when you were looking at the increase in California rig counts, sort of five rigs every six months, that some were going into steamflood as well as I guess the shale <mark type="ph" /> and inverter (33:32) comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us an update in terms of how many rigs are in steamfloods versus other opportunities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually don't know. Three? I think we have three rigs in the steamfloods right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll boost that as the year progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; but still incremental rigs going in against your guidance then into the shale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. Shale and into the steamfloods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And just on &#x2013; this is more of a longer-term question, but obviously in the central part of the San Joaquin Valley, financial geologist that I am, you have a potentially thicker part of the shale, but it's deep and the rock quality may not be as good. But is there any technology that you think could work there to turn that into a repeatable shale play?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe someday. But, right now &#x2013; we try to do easy stuff before hard stuff, and so we're focused on what's easy right now. And what's easiest right now is to drill low-cost shale wells in easy places. We've monkeyed with what you have just said and I think we're still in the early phases of thinking about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it fair to say that you're putting some R&amp;D dollars into that type of monkeying around?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes, we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sven Del Pozzo of IHS Herold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Morning here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you doing? Good morning. Your prospective savings on completion costs in California for your unconventional wells, what kind of timeframe do you think we'll have before we'll start to see some CapEx savings...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is actually happening now. It's happening now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you'll see it as &#x2013; it will be clearer as the year progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And same type of question regarding CapEx for the midstream. When do you think we'll start to see the CapEx deployment in the midstream slow down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, a lot of that is the Al Hosn gas plant and so the domestic capital is not &#x2013; probably not going to slow down for a little while until I get the pipeline system up and running better. But the Al Hosn stuff, that part of it should start to roll off into the fourth and first quarters, but the drilling portion, the part that's close to E&amp;P, will pick up that slack and more into the fourth and first quarter next year. So, all you're seeing &#x2013; so, I wouldn't be too confused about where this midstream capital is going. A fair amount of it except for a little bit right now is going into the Al Hosn project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And your production growth sequentially from the first quarter to the second quarter in the mid-continent region, which also includes the Bakken, if it is not the Bakken where the oil production growth is coming from on the oil side, what region or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of it. The bulk of it is from there. We started, I remember, at 3,000 or 4,000 a day last year, early last year, and we're 17,000 running now, so somewhere in there it's there. There's improvement in south Texas and the rest of the Rockies, but, I mean, fundamentally, that segment is &#x2013; the large increases are Bakken production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Spike in Bahraini gas production. Could you just help me to understand what's going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sandy can probably answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the gas production is paid for on a capacity basis and we've recently installed a lot of equipment that increases the capacity to what the Kingdom thinks they'll need over the next few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is there any way to quantify the profitability change associated with this increase in gas production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty modest. I mean, the profits there will be made off the oil production. And the gas serves as a sort of a base to give us a base return I think is the way to think about the project. So the gas, since it is a recaptive gas market, is basically what pays for the thing. And then the upside, the higher returns will come from improved oil prices, oil production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, lastly, view on Chemicals. Just your announced for sometime after 2015, announcement of 1.1 billion pound ethylene cracker. I don't know if it is an expansion or a brand new plant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there's no &#x2013; I think the announcement is that we're studying it. We're not committed to the cracker. We are going to build a fractionator. But not &#x2013; but we're not committed to a cracker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And for working capital component of your cash flow in first six months of the year, if you'd like to email it to me later that's fine. If you have it right there, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris can deal with that. I don't think you'll find it a big deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Katherine Minyard of JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gentlemen. Thanks for taking my question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just looking at 2Q production for the U.S., how much of that production came from wells that were brought online since the beginning of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's probably a more complicated question than you probably thought. I don't think we &#x2013; you'd have to go basin by basin. We don't know. We'll try to, we'll try to have &#x2013; why don't you contact Chris and maybe we could reconstruct that over the next &#x2013; yeah, we don't have it with us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. And then when you talk about cost reduction of about a third in your drilling, are you looking at...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>California we talked about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So are you looking at achieving that, is it lower drill times? Is it different completion techniques? What would be the main factors driving the bulk of that type of reduction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill can answer that because he's responsible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Katherine, it is really both. Okay? On the drilling side, it's a lot of little things that add up to cost reductions. And then on the completion side, it is primarily reductions in pressure pumping costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Great. Thanks a lot, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from Alex Morris of Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks for taking my question. Following up on the Colombia insurgency question from earlier, could you give an update maybe on Libya and whether production is back at pre-war levels there? And, if not, what needs to happen to get there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sandy can answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we're just about at pre-war levels right now. We've just putting new teams into the country to work on new projects. And we will be doing seismic work later this year. So we're pretty much back to normal in Libya.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Herrlin of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you seeing any discounts to price book by the services companies on the Permian? Some of your peers have been mentioning that. Are you seeing that at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill can answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, we're seeing some modest price reductions off the price book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's that, 10% or less?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's 7% to 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we tend to contract longer term than somebody else who might go to monthly contracts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and so we don't &#x2013; we're not quite as sensitive to the &#x2013; somebody who might be drilling six wells or something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fine, Steve. With the Elk Hills plant, is there just a commissioning start-up phase before you get it fully on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's gone through that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so we're &#x2013; like all plants that are designed by engineers, they always &#x2013; they never seem to work just exactly right the first day. So &#x2013; but we've actually gone through that because we started the process more than a month ago. So right now we're &#x2013; I think we're okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I probably missed this because I got on late. What was your cash position at quarter's end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A little over $4 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I will now turn the floor over to Mr. Stavros for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for joining us today, and if you have further questions on the conference call earnings released today, please call us in New York. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This does conclude today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>