<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1490419" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-08-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2149</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Jeffery H. Boyd</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior VP, Chief Financial &amp; Accounting Officer">Daniel J. Finnegan</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Stephen Ju</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Douglas Anmuth</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Mark Stephen Mahaney</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner &amp; Smith, Inc.">Justin Post</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (USA), Inc.">Tom Cauthorn White</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Piper Jaffray, Inc.">Mike J. Olson</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Millman Research Associates">Michael Millman</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Heath Patrick Terry</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Susquehanna Financial Group LLP">Herman Leung</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Cowen &amp; Co. LLC">Kevin Kopelman</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Evercore Partners (Securities)">Tracy Young</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Priceline Group second quarter 2012 conference call.</p>
          <p>Priceline would like to remind everyone that this call may contain forward-looking statements, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provision of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements are not guarantees of future performance and are subject to certain risks, uncertainties, and assumptions that are difficult to predict. Therefore, actual results may differ materially from those expressed, implied, or forecasted in any such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Expressions of future goals and similar expressions reflecting something other than historical fact are intended to identify forward-looking statements. For a list of factors that could cause Priceline's actual results to differ materially from those described in the forward-looking statements, please refer to the Safe Harbor statements at the end of Priceline's earnings press release as well as Priceline's most recent filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Unless required by law, Priceline undertakes no obligation to update publicly any forward-looking statements, whether as a result of new information, future events, or otherwise.</p>
          <p>A copy of Priceline's earnings press release together with an accompanying financial and statistical supplement is available in the Investor Relations section of Priceline's website, located at www.priceline.com.</p>
          <p>And now I'd like to introduce the Priceline Group speakers for this afternoon, Jeffery Boyd and Daniel Finnegan. Go ahead, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Welcome to Priceline's second quarter conference call. I'm here with Priceline CFO Dan Finnegan. I will make some opening remarks, and Dan will give a detailed financial review. After the prepared portion, we will take questions.</p>
          <p>Priceline reported consolidated gross bookings for the second quarter of approximately $7.3 billion, up 27% year over year or about 36% on a local currency basis. Non-GAAP net income was $405 million or $7.85 per share, up 43% versus prior year. Second quarter results surpassed FactSet's consensus estimates of $7.37 per share and our guidance for the quarter. Worldwide hotel room night reservations were $50.2 million for the quarter, up 39% year over year.</p>
          <p>Our international business recorded 44% gross bookings growth on a local currency basis, down from 58% in Q1. Growth rates were negatively impacted by declines in ADRs; further slowing of growth in Europe, particularly in the UK and Southern Europe where economic conditions seemed weaker; and a difficult comp, with 79% local currency international bookings growth last year. Growth rates benefited from continued high growth rates in APAC and the Americas. International gross bookings also benefited generally from growth in hotel supply and strong results at Rentalcars.com.</p>
          <p>Booking.com's platform now has over 235,000 hotels and other accommodations, up 52% over last year. With the relatively larger concentration of its business in European countries experiencing weak economic conditions, decelerating growth in those markets has impacted overall growth rates. Nevertheless, the absolute transaction and local currency growth rates in Europe and non-euro markets for Q2 were, in our view, impressive and attests to the vitality and potential of the business. That said, deteriorating overall economic trends and headline risks surrounding the euro crisis do cause us to be guarded in our near-term outlook.</p>
          <p>We also announced today that Booking.com signed an agreement with Ctrip.com, China's leading travel service enterprise, under which Ctrip is adding Booking.com's global portfolio of participating hotels to Ctrip's hotel reservations service. We are excited about the opportunity to work with Ctrip and make Booking.com's global collection of hotels available to Ctrip customers. We believe that this will give Booking.com a new way to serve travelers from the Asia-Pacific region.</p>
          <p>Agoda continues to expand its network of hotels and is building distribution as the business scales. They have a significant opportunity in the fast-growing Asia-Pacific market and can also help APAC customers with their travel to other parts of the world with proprietary merchant inventory and access to the worldwide inventory of Booking.com.</p>
          <p>Priceline's domestic gross bookings grew 5% in the second quarter, due primarily to growth in retail hotel room night gross bookings, aided by higher ADRs, and growth in domestic retail rental car reservations. Name-Your-Own-Price services experienced challenges relating to supply for air and rental car. In hotels, Name-Your-Own-Price faced increased competition in the discount space and a more challenging user experience on mobile devices, often used for last-minute bookings.</p>
          <p>We recently launched Express Deals, a published price opaque service that offers great savings to provide greater consumer choice, and we will work towards optimal promotion of that option.</p>
          <p>Merchant gross bookings growth of 23% continues to reflect growth at Agoda and Rentalcars.com. Rentalcars.com was also the primary driver of the group's 29% growth in rental car days.</p>
          <p>We believe the group's businesses performed well in the second quarter given poor economic conditions, particularly in our core European markets. We are pleased with the progress of our brands in growing and improving their platforms. Our aim is to continue building our brands by investing in geographic expansion and supply, product and service innovation, and customer acquisition. I commend my colleagues around the world for their focus and execution.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Dan for the detailed financial review.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff. I'll discuss some of the highlights and operating results and cash flows for the quarter, and then provide guidance for the third quarter of 2012. The growth rates mentioned in my remarks are in relation to the prior-year comparable period unless otherwise indicated.</p>
          <p>Q2 gross bookings grew by 27% or 36% on a local currency basis, led by our worldwide hotel reservation business. Hotel room nights booked grew by 39% in the second quarter, but deceleration compared to the 47% growth rate achieved in Q1. As I said when we gave guidance for Q2 back in May, we expected fairly significant deceleration in unit growth over the back half of the quarter given the size of the business and the difficult year-over-year comp.</p>
          <p>We believe that weak economic conditions and sovereign debt concerns further contributed to the level of deceleration experienced, particularly in our key European market, which represents about 60% of our total booked room nights. We saw softer demand and ADR trends continue in Southern Europe and spread to certain other markets, including the UK in the second quarter. Despite these challenges, our room nights booked grew in Q2 by over 30% in Europe and by over 50% for the rest of the world.</p>
          <p>We are proud of the results delivered for the quarter from a top line and bottom line perspective and believe that Q2 is another in a long string of quarters where we grew our market share of booked room nights both in the U.S. and internationally. We believe that the strong growth rate in markets outside of Europe demonstrates the attractive long-term opportunity as these markets continue to shift to booking online and comprise an increasing share of our business.</p>
          <p>Average daily rates, or ADRs, were down on a local currency basis by approximately 1% for our international hotel service and were up by over 4% for U.S. hotel service for Q2 2012. These results were slightly below our guidance assumption.</p>
          <p>FX rates for the second quarter for the euro and British pound versus the U.S. dollar were unfavorable compared to prior year by about 11% and 3% respectively, and in both cases were about 3% unfavorable to the rates we assumed in our guidance. As a result, currency exchange rates significantly depressed our year-over-year growth rates expressed in U.S. dollars for gross bookings, revenue, and gross profit, and also negatively impacted our actual growth rates for these line items compared to our guidance for the quarter. Our Q2 international gross bookings grew by 33% and by 44% on a local currency basis, in both cases within our guidance range.</p>
          <p>Rental car days booked were up by 24.9%, driven mainly by strong growth for our Rentalcars.com business. Gross bookings growth for our Priceline.com brand business in the U.S. of 5% was at the bottom end of our range of guidance. Strong growth in retail hotel room nights booked and higher ADRs as well as strong growth in retail rental car bookings were key drivers in year-over-year growth.</p>
          <p>However, each of our Name-Your-Own-Price businesses had a challenging quarter, posting decreases in year-over-year units booked. We believe our Name-Your-Own-Price hotel room nights declined likely as a result of the continued presence of competitive discount hotel initiatives and the emphasis on no-bidding offerings in our offline advertising.</p>
          <p>We launched Express Deals during the quarter, which allows customers to enjoy substantial savings with a posted price. We believe that Express Deals will appeal to customers who want to save money but are not comfortable with the bidding process. We're still in early stages and we intend to continue to experiment with various ways to offer Express Deals to customers on Priceline.com in coming quarters.</p>
          <p>Airline tickets booked were down by 2% while average retail ticket prices were up by 7%. Name-Your-Own-Price tickets declined to a greater extent due to limited supply resulting from airline capacity cuts. Name-Your-Own-Price rental car days booked were down significantly due to limited availability of discounted supply and low retail prices that lessened the relative value proposition of our Name-Your-Own-Price offering.</p>
          <p>The decrease in our Name-Your-Own-Price businesses has a more pronounced impact on revenue, and merchant revenue in particular, since these transactions are recorded gross in revenue with supplier costs recorded in cost of revenue, while our other merchant businesses, principally Agoda.com and Rentalcars.com, are recorded in revenue net of supplier cost.</p>
          <p>Gross profit for the quarter was $1 billion and grew 34% as compared to prior year. Our international operations generated gross profit of $859 million, which constituted an increase of 40% as compared to prior year and an increase of 53% on a local currency basis. Gross profit for our U.S. business amounted to $145 million, which represented 6% growth versus prior year.</p>
          <p>Operating leverage improved in the quarter. Non-GAAP operating income as a percentage of gross profit amounted to 48.2% for Q2 2012, expanding by 200 basis points compared to the prior year, as expenses grew at a slower pace than gross profit.</p>
          <p>Advertising efficiency was favorable to our forecast and to prior year, partly due to deceleration in gross bookings, which results in slower growth in advertising. Fundamental advertising efficiency was good, partly offset by the continued mix shift to paid channels. Gross profit decelerated to a lesser degree because strong Q1 gross bookings growth benefits Q2 as gross profit is recognized upon completion of travel.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBITDA for Q2 amounted to $495 million, which exceeded our guidance range of $450 million to $470 million, and represents 42% growth versus prior year. Non-GAAP net income grew by 43%, including a lower year-over-year cash tax rate due to the Innovation Box tax benefit in the Netherlands and a lower statutory rate in the UK.</p>
          <p>In terms of cash flow, we generated approximately $432 million of cash from operations during second quarter 2012, which represents a 93% increase versus prior year. Operating cash flow for the quarter benefits from our decision to prepay in the first quarter $166 million of income taxes for Booking.com in return for an early payment cash discount. These taxes would otherwise have been paid monthly over the year, and so second quarter and subsequent quarters of 2012 have a lower payment burden as a result.</p>
          <p>We spent about $15 million on CapEx in the quarter and spent about $61 million to purchase a portion of the non-controlling interest related to Rentalcars.com. As of June 30, 2012, our cash and investments, totaling $3.9 billion, are available for general corporate purposes, including share repurchases, acquisitions, and debt repayment.</p>
          <p>Now for third quarter 2012 guidance, let me start off with some qualitative comments regarding our approach to the Q3 guidance. Our guidance reflects our expectation for sequentially naturally decelerating growth rates for a very large business comparing against high transaction growth rates in each quarter of 2011. It also reflects the significant drag on growth expressed in U.S. dollars for all lines of our income statement, presented by the strengthening of the U.S. dollar compared to last year, particularly as it relates to the euro.</p>
          <p>Lastly, our forecast reflects our assumptions regarding the impact of worldwide macroeconomic conditions in general and in Europe in particular. For several quarters now, we've noted weaker transaction growth rates and ADR trends for certain southern European countries, and we see evidence of these trends spreading to other markets, including the UK. Our forecast assumes that macroeconomic conditions will deteriorate further as we progress throughout this quarter, and that our unit growth rates will decelerate fairly significantly compared to their current levels as a result.</p>
          <p>We've seen a few quarters now of softening local currency ADR trends for our international hotel business, with ADRs up 2% in Q1 and down 1% in Q2. Our Q3 forecast assumes ADRs for our international hotel service will be down to a greater degree than in the second quarter, and that ADRs for our U.S. hotel service will be up by about 4%. Softer international ADRs and higher cancel rates assumed in our guidance negatively impact unit economics and operating leverage.</p>
          <p>We are forecasting total gross bookings to grow by 10% to 18% and to grow on a local currency basis by approximately 19% to 27%, with U.S. gross bookings growing by about 5%. We expect international gross bookings expressed in U.S. dollars to grow by 12% to 20% and to grow on a local currency basis by approximately 23% to 31%.</p>
          <p>Our Q3 forecast assumes that foreign exchange rates remain at the same $1.24 per euro and $1.56 per British pound as yesterday's closing rates, which would result in average exchange rates that would be weaker by 13% for the euro and by 3% for the British pound as compared to the prior year. We have hedge contracts in place to substantially shield our third quarter EBITDA and net earnings from any fluctuation in the euro or pound versus the dollar between now and end of the quarter, but these hedges do not offset the impact of translation on our gross bookings, revenue, gross profit, and operating income, and do not hedge our earnings beyond the third quarter.</p>
          <p>We expect Q3 revenue to grow year over year by approximately 9% to 15% and gross profit dollars to grow by approximately 15% to 25%. We expect deleverage on non-GAAP operating income as a percent of gross profit.</p>
          <p>We assume that margins in Q3 will be impacted by deleverage in online advertising expense due to business mix and assumed deterioration in unit economics associated with worsening macro conditions.</p>
          <p>Despite economic challenges, we also intend to continue to invest in people, new offices, IT expenses, and increased depreciation expense to support the growth of our business. In addition, our forecast for personnel expense in Q3 includes a $13 million charge related to a purported one-time payroll tax that was imposed in the Netherlands in July. We do not expect the impact of this wage levy to be significant beyond Q3.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBITDA is expected to range between $690 million and $765 million, which at the midpoint represents 13% growth versus prior year.</p>
          <p>We are targeting non-GAAP fully diluted EPS of approximately $11.10 to $12.10 per share, which at the midpoint represent 17% growth over prior year. Our EPS forecast reflects about $4 million of additional year-over-year cash interest expense for Q3 related to the convertible bonds we issued in March and the revolving credit facility we entered in September last year.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP EPS forecast includes an estimated cash income tax rate of approximately 16.4%, comprised of international income taxes and alternative minimum tax and state income taxes in the U.S. This rate reflects the estimated fully phased-in impact of the Innovation Box tax benefit in the Netherlands. We expect our full-year 2012 cash income tax rate to be approximately four to six percentage points lower than what it would have been if we did not have the Innovation Box tax benefit.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP EPS guidance assumes a fully diluted share count of 51.5 million shares based upon yesterday's closing stock price of $665.12.</p>
          <p>We forecast GAAP EPS of $10.21 to $11.21 per share for Q3. The difference between our GAAP and non-GAAP results is driven by non-GAAP adjustments that are detailed in our earnings release.</p>
          <p>Given the uncertainty surrounding worldwide economic conditions, particularly in Europe, where much of our business is concentrated, we believe the variability around our guidance is greater than is usually the case.</p>
          <p>We will now take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Stephen Ju of Credit Suisse. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. So I think in the prepared remarks, you mentioned I guess macro headlines of weakness spreading through the UK and certain other parts of the Europe also out of Southern Europe. Do you think there is any Olympics related impact and there are people just staying home to watch the Olympics as opposed to traveling?</p>
          <p>And I'm also trying to get some context around the guidance for currency neutral gross bookings growth of 23% to 31%. I guess this implies that you're seeing additional pretty steep volume deceleration off I guess an additional ballpark range to 13% to 21%, if I'm doing my math correctly, coming off hotel room might deceleration of about eight percentage points. I'm just trying to figure out what you're seeing in the channel that's making you take off another I guess five to almost another 13 percentage points of volume growth. Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, in terms of the Olympics, Stephen, we've said in previous quarters that we didn't expect to see an impact on our numbers from the Olympics. I think that's still true. These events that take place in one market across our broad, diversified worldwide business don't generally have impacts that we can discern. To the extent that more people are traveling to London or not traveling to London, perhaps they're traveling somewhere else, and so we don't see anything there.</p>
          <p>In terms of the growth assumptions, we've said that our forecast reflects the actual results we've seen to date, and we're assuming fairly significant deceleration in growth rates from here on out over concern about macroeconomic conditions and our worry that conditions will worsen, particularly in Europe, which is such a key market for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from Doug Anmuth of Deutsche Bank (sic) [JPMorgan) (21:25). Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug Anmuth from JPMorgan, so I just wanted to ask you. You talked obviously a lot about the macro pressures here that you saw in 2Q and that you expect to worsen in 3Q. But can you give us a sense of whether you're seeing &#x2013; what you're seeing in Europe in particular from competitive pressures? And I guess should we be thinking about this as primarily macro impact and FX impact, or are you seeing some competitive dynamics here which are getting tougher for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, I think that we look at the markets where our results have weakened most substantially, and those are the same markets where the economic headlines and reports on unemployment, GDP, and headlines around sovereign debt seem to be at their worst. And so that's really what drives us to attribute a portion of the deceleration in this business to economic conditions. And we also see occupancy and ADR trends that are supportive of the deceleration at least in part being tied to macroeconomic conditions. Now we've been guiding investors for a long time to look for deceleration in the business given the size of the business and given the very, very strong comps that we had in the last year. And so we think that that's something that the market should continue to expect, all things being equal, from an economic perspective.</p>
          <p>As far as we can tell as we look at the reported results that our competitors have released and our own results, we continued in the second quarter to gain share against our competition in the major markets in which we operate. I think that the competition has had better results from the last couple of quarters, and I think that's due to good execution on their part. And I think is demonstrative of the opportunity, the substantial opportunity we have in these marketplaces that you can have a couple of businesses of our size growing at impressive rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mark Mahaney of Citigroup. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, two questions please. I think, Jeff, you referred to market share gains for the hotel business in the U.S. Could you be a little bit more specific, or do you mean just against the total market of hotel room nights?</p>
          <p>And then you also mentioned mobile as being a challenge. It sounded like a bit of a change in tone from before. Could you maybe spell that out a little bit more? How is mobile monetization for a travel company, how do you see the challenge in that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Mark. So with respect to the U.S. market share, even though we don't release total group U.S. or North American hotel room nights, we obviously have those numbers and can look at them in comparison to what's released by the competition. And based on that information, we believe we're continuing to gain share in total group hotel room nights sold in North America.</p>
          <p>With respect to the second question, I refer to my remarks to the potential difficultly for a last-minute traveler using a bid process where you may have to go through a couple of iterations to get a completed transaction. And that's something that I think we believe to be the case, notwithstanding the fact that the growth of our Name-Your-Own-Price business in places like the Hotel Negotiator app has been great and it has been quite successful.</p>
          <p>In an absolute sense, we feel there's an opportunity not just in our opaque products but across the board to introduce new products in the mobile channel, try to make them very easy for consumers to complete a commercial transaction. And Express Deals is one way where they can get the kind of savings that they're used to with the bidding process without having to go through that, especially if you're dealing with a small screen and potentially a last-minute transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Justin Post of Bank of America. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff, a couple things. First, when you look at your ADRs, I think they were plus 2% and they went to negative 1%. It seems like when you look at some of the industry data for Europe, it hasn't decelerated like that or some of the other hotels, what they're saying. Is it because people are doing a different type of mix on your platform, or are you seeing something maybe a little different than the industry is?</p>
          <p>And then second, I saw the Ctrip deal. Can you talk about the economics? If someone books a room on their platform is that favorable to you, or can you give us any help with that? And do you have anything for that in your guidance? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Justin. So with respect to our reported and guided ADR trends, our international businesses have a different mix of destinations and types of properties than other businesses. They're all unique, so you can't look at what we report and compare it to Smith Travel or another industry and say they ought to be exactly the same. What we see is impacted by mix, and that's driven by a combination type and it's driven by geography.</p>
          <p>With respect to Ctrip, the terms of that transaction are not disclosed. But you should assume that the transaction will result in a financial benefit to both us and Ctrip if reservations are made by Ctrip customers at Booking.com hotels around the world. And we have an 8-K that was filed at the same time as we announced these other transactions that will say we don't expect the results of the Ctrip transaction to be material, and you should consider that it's included in the guidance that Dan gave you this afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Tom White of Macquarie. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. I just wanted to confirm one thing I thought you guys said in the prepared remarks about unit growth rates by region. Did I hear 30% in Europe and over 50% in the rest of the world? And if so, I guess as we look out over the next couple of quarters, I know you guys have talked about how the seasonality in your newer markets of Asia-Pacific and LatAm is different than your legacy markets of Europe and in the U.S. and that 4Q and 1Q are seasonally bigger travel quarters of those newer regions. With that in mind, can we expect to see maybe some acceleration in your international business later this year and early next as these become a bigger part of the mix? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, we don't guide beyond the current third quarter guidance that we gave, so I can't really comment on that. Your premise that there is the first quarter and fourth quarter better seasonality for the Asia-Pacific businesses and the businesses in the Southern Hemisphere is a correct premise. But that business that we &#x2013; when we talk about outside of Europe for the global business, that includes the United States as well, which is a very big part of that other market, and that has the typical Northern Hemisphere seasonality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And can you just confirm that you said 30% hotel unit growth in Europe in the second quarter and over 50% for the rest of the world? Did I hear that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mike Olson of Piper Jaffray. Your question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just to follow up on that, so you mentioned Europe weakness. But for international bookings expectations outside of Europe, would you &#x2013; I guess just qualitatively, would you characterize the macro headwinds in all the other international geographies as being equally weak as Europe, not as weak as Europe, or not really weak at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think a fair way to answer that would be to say that we have seen decelerating growth trends in most of the markets in which we operate. And again, that's consistent with the guidance that we've given that as the business gets larger, we expect generally to see growth trends decelerate. We pointed out these couple of markets in Europe because of the concentration of our business in those markets and because we believe the deterioration there has been more pronounced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Michael Millman of Millman Associates. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You mentioned U.S. rental car. Could you talk a little bit about why do you think that prices have not risen despite fleets tightening? And also, is it the tertiary brands that are causing this reduction in price and affecting opaque markets, and indeed other tertiary companies are taking share of the rental car business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, I won't comment on share amongst the rental car suppliers, but that is a likely cause is some of these new entrants that are pricing at very aggressive levels, and that's putting pressure on retail prices overall in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Heath Terry of Goldman Sachs, your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. For most of the last few quarters, you've been talking about advertising deleverage. And this quarter we actually saw, at least within the online advertising segment, a little bit of advertising leverage both on a year-over-year and quarter-over-quarter basis. To what extent was the decision made to trade off bookings for EBITDA this quarter, and to the extent that that's a change in strategy from the willingness that you've had in previous quarters to accept that advertising deleverage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To no extent was a decision made to trade off advertising dollars for EBITDA. That's not the way we look at the business or have ever looked at it. We try to drive as much business in all distribution channels subject to ROI requirements, which have not changed in any way in terms of policy for quite a long time. We're prepared to spend additional dollars to drive additional businesses as long as ROIs are acceptable. And we're also prepared to spend at a deficit in new markets and in new distribution channels where we need to build up tenure or a knowledge base in order to make sure that we can be successful in those markets. So we've never driven the business to meet a short-term EBITDA goal and we will not do so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Herman Leung of Susquehanna. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, guys; two quick questions. First, I guess can you talk about your marketing spend efficiencies across the different channels and if anything stood out in terms of the returns on the marketing spend, or was that just largely macro related?</p>
          <p>And then second question I have is regarding the Booking.com piece that is from North America obviously shows up in your international bookings line. I was wondering if you can give us a sense of how that grew during the second quarter timeframe. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Herman, on the first question, we don't comment on our advertising by channel. But I did say in my prepared remarks that fundamental advertising efficiency was good. So you can assume that we had good ROIs during the quarter in comparison to prior year. The overall advertising efficiency when you just look at online advertising as a percentage of gross profit was largely driven, however, by the deceleration in the business, particularly in the back half of the quarter. So you have less gross bookings coming through, you've got the stronger growth rates at the beginning of the quarter and the prior quarter converting into gross profit this quarter. And so anytime you've got deceleration in gross bookings, typically the deceleration in gross profit lags that, and so you get a benefit on that line item in terms of operating leverage.</p>
          <p>In terms of Booking.com in North America, we don't disclose that stat. But we've said for a while now and I'll say it again that North America is one of the faster growing markets for Booking.com. They continue to add properties and perform very well in the market, and we're very pleased with the progress that they've made.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Kevin Kopelman of Cowen &amp; Company. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks a lot. You talked about some of the challenges on mobile for Name-Your-Own-Price. Can you give us any color on what you're seeing in mobile growth outside of Name-Your-Own-Price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I mentioned in response to Mark's question, we've seen very good results in mobile channels for all of our businesses, with Name-Your-Own-Price being no exception, where it's our fastest growing distribution channel here in the United States by far, and so we're very happy with the results there. We want to make sure that we have an opportunity to put products in front of customers that are compelling, whether they want to bid or not. Tonight-Only is a great product that allows customers to save on disclosed hotels. It's not an opaque product. It's pricing available only for tonight. We also offer retail which, in many cases, is what the consumer is looking for.</p>
          <p>So our aim is to promote the most attractive products to the widest group of consumers, and Express Deals would fit nicely into that. We really view mobile as more of an opportunity for the group rather than a challenge. We've got the best hotel inventory, both published price and discounted, of any OTA in the world and a great opportunity with good execution to present that in a way that's compelling to mobile users. So I don't want you to misunderstand the opportunity that we have with Express Deals by thinking that mobile is somehow a challenge. We really view it as a great opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Brian Nowak of Nomura, your question please. Actually, we'll go to our next question from Tracy Young of Evercore. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, two questions. I'm sorry if missed this. But did you give guidance on ADRs U.S. versus international? And also I was just trying to get a sense of your guidance. Certainly, other companies have talked about some deceleration that they're seeing for Q3. Is your guidance based on what you've seen on July or what you expect to see for the quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tracy, we said for ADRs that international was down 1% in Q2, and we're assuming that trend will worsen in Q3. For our U.S. hotel service, we said up about 4% for Q3. And I'm sorry, what was your second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question was in terms of the guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So our guidance reflects the actual results through the end of July and through the first week of August here. And then we are assuming that there will be fairly significant deceleration in unit growth throughout the remainder of the quarter based upon our concerns, particularly in the European market, which is about 60% of our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. At this time, I would like to turn the call back over to our speakers for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all very much for participating in our call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude your program. Thank you for your participation and have a wonderful day. You may disconnect your lines at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>