<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1328362" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2149</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jeffery H. Boyd, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Daniel J. Finnegan, Chief Financial Officer and Chief Accounting Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Ingrid Chun</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Mark Mahaney</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Justin Post</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Ross Sandler</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Douglas Anmuth</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Scott Kessler</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Michael Olson</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Michael Millman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to Priceline's Second Quarter 2010 Conference Call.</p>
          <p>Priceline would like to remind everyone that this call may contain forward-looking statements, which are made pursuant to the Safe Harbor provisions of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These forward-looking statements are not guarantees of future performance and are subject to certain risks, uncertainties and assumptions that are difficult to predict. Therefore, actual results may differ materially from those expressed, implied or forecasted in any such forward-looking statements. Expressions of future goals and similar expressions reflecting something other than historical fact are intended to identify forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>For a list of factors that could cause Priceline's actual results to differ materially from those described in the forward-looking statements, please refer to the Safe Harbor statements at the end of Priceline's earnings press release as well as Priceline's most recent filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Unless required by law, Priceline undertakes no obligation to update publicly any forward-looking statements, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise.</p>
          <p>A copy of Priceline's earnings press release, together with an accompanying financial and statistical supplement is available in the Investor Relations section of Priceline's website, located at www.priceline.com.</p>
          <p>And now, I'd like to introduce Priceline's speakers for this afternoon, Jeff Boyd and Dan Finnegan. Go ahead, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and welcome to the Priceline Group's second quarter conference call. I am here with Priceline's CFO, Dan Finnegan. I will make some opening remarks, Dan will give a detailed financial review, and then I will sum up. After the prepared portion, we will take questions.</p>
          <p>The group, consisting primarily of Booking.com, priceline.com, Agoda.com and now TravelJigsaw, reported consolidated gross bookings for the second quarter of approximately $3.4 billion, up 43% year-over-year. Pro forma net income was $158.2 million or $3.09 per share versus the $2.02 the prior year. Second quarter results surpassed First Call consensus estimates of $2.65 per share and the high end of our guidance for the quarter. Worldwide hotel room night reservations were 23.2 million for the quarter, up 48% year-over-year. We are pleased with the level of growth in room night reservations in the quarter and with the degree of sequential deceleration, as we start to comp against improving performance last year.</p>
          <p>Our international business performed well, with 67% gross bookings growth on a local currency basis, a decrease from 73% in the prior quarter. International gross bookings benefited from strong transaction growth in the back half of the quarter, following the disruption caused by the Iceland volcano and an improvement in average daily rates.</p>
          <p>This strength continues to-date in Q3, and together with the recent strengthening in the euro and pound, results in a solid outlook for Q3. Geographic expansion, growth in hotel inventory, growth in new markets, and adding results from Agoda and partial quarter results from TravelJigsaw also helped drive strong top line growth in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Booking.com continues to build its supply platform worldwide with a hotel count of approximately 96,000 hotels in over 87 countries.</p>
          <p>Agoda continues to build its business in the Asian region and reported its fourth consecutive quarter of triple digit year-over-year growth in gross bookings, contributing to the overall international and merchant growth we are reporting. I am particularly impressed with and grateful for the performance of the Agoda team given the civil unrest in Bangkok, which caused the temporary closure of our office and squelched demand for Thailand, Agoda's most demanded destination.</p>
          <p>TravelJigsaw joined our group in the wake of dealing with the disruption created by the Iceland volcano. Nevertheless, the business delivered solid growth in the quarter and the Group now has a foundation of business in Europe and North America from which to build a global franchise in the rental car business.</p>
          <p>Priceline.com's domestic gross bookings grew 20% in the second quarter aided by strong hotel results and a significant year-over-year increase in airline ticket prices. Merchant gross bookings increased 31% as merchant hotel gross bookings, both at priceline and Agoda, and the addition of Merchant rental car bookings from TravelJigsaw, offset year-over-year decreases in opaque airline tickets and rental car sales, where reduced industry capacity continued to pressure inventory available for opaque discounting.</p>
          <p>For the group, consolidated operating margins improved during the quarter due to improvement in the international business. As in Q1, domestic margins were pressured as airfare increases drove bookings growth but not revenue growth, and marketing spend increased faster than gross profit dollars.</p>
          <p>Global economic uncertainty continues to create volatility in financial markets and currency fluctuation continues to produce volatility in our translated results. The widespread concern that a sovereign debt crisis in the euro zone would lead to falloff in travel demand has not yet materialized and business results to-date are encouraging. That said, we remain concerned that government deficits and consequent austerity measures could impact economic recovery and travel demand in the future.</p>
          <p>In summary, the business performed well in the second quarter and is showing demand and pricing trends consistent with improving economic conditions. I would like to thank my colleagues around the world for their hard work and dedication.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Dan for the detailed financial review.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff. I'll discuss some of the highlights and operating results and cash flows for the quarter and then provide guidance for the third quarter of 2010. Gross booking dollars grew by 43% for Q2 compared to the prior year, driven by strong unit growth and higher average daily rates for our global hotel reservation service.</p>
          <p>Hotel room nights booked grew by 48% in the second quarter versus last year. This represented deceleration from the unit growth rate of 57% that we posted in the first quarter. However, we were pleased with the way the business rebounded after the disruption in the early part of the quarter from the volcano. We saw sustained strength for our international business in the latter half of the quarter, which exceeded the level of room night growth we had assumed for Q2 guidance, and that momentum has continued so far into Q3, as we will see in a moment when we get to Q3 guidance.</p>
          <p>ADRs were also an important driver of our overall performance. ADRs were up by about 2 to 3% for both our international and domestic hotel services for Q2 2010, compared to the prior year second quarter. The prevailing exchange rates when we reported our Q2 guidance on May 10 of $1.28 per euro and $1.48 per British pound formed the basis for our forecast for the remainder of the quarter.  Actual FX rates for the remainder of the second quarter were unfavorable to those rates. FX rates for the second quarter were also unfavorable to prior year rates and therefore adversely impacted our gross bookings growth expressed in U.S. dollars. The average exchange rates for the euro and the pound versus the dollar were down by 7% and 4% respectively in the second quarter of 2010 versus the second quarter of 2009. Our international gross bookings grew by 59% and by 67% on a local currency basis for Q2 2010 compared to the prior year Q2.</p>
          <p>Airline tickets booked were up by 4% in the quarter. Rental car days booked were up by 32% versus second quarter 2009, reflecting the impact of TravelJigsaw. TravelJigsaw, a U.K.-based merchant rental car reservation service, also contributed 43.9 million in gross bookings in Q2 since we acquired it on May 18. We expect to continue to report gross bookings for TravelJigsaw separately for one year from acquisition to highlight the impact of its addition to the consolidated results. Our opaque rental car days and air tickets booked were down year-on-year due to supplier capacity reductions impacting inventory availability.</p>
          <p>In summary, room night growth and ADRs were favorable to the assumptions used for guidance, resulting in performance that exceeded the top end of our range of guidance in all key operating metrics from gross bookings to EPS.</p>
          <p>Gross profit was $445 million and grew 46% as compared to prior year. Our international operations generated gross profit of $322 million and grew by 64% as compared to the prior year. Gross profit for our domestic business amounted to $123 million, which represented a 14% growth versus prior year.</p>
          <p>Total operating expenses were generally in line with guidance. Online advertising expense as a percentage of gross profit was in line with the second quarter of 2009 and came in favorable to our guidance, driven by better than assumed overall advertising efficiency.</p>
          <p>We recorded below the line income in the quarter of about $1.7 million, which was favorable to the expense of $1 million we assumed in our guidance. The variance relates mainly to FX hedging gains resulting from the strengthening of the U.S. dollar versus the euro from the date we gave guidance through the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>In summary, pro forma EBITDA for Q2 amounted to $204 million, which exceeded our guidance range of 170 to $180 million, and represents 62% growth versus prior year. EBITDA leverage, or EBITDA expressed as a percentage of gross profit, expanded by 440 basis points in the quarter versus prior year Q2.</p>
          <p>In terms of cash flow, we generated approximately 187 million of cash from operations during second quarter 2010, which represents a 99% increase versus prior year. We spent about $5 million on CapEx in the quarter and approximately $109 million net of cash acquired for the acquisition of TravelJigsaw.</p>
          <p>Certain members of the TravelJigsaw and Booking.com management teams continue to hold a minority interest in the TravelJigsaw business. The minority shares are subject to put and call provisions that will likely lead to them being purchased by priceline.com over the next three years.</p>
          <p>We spent about $6 million in Q2 to repurchase shares of priceline common stock. We also expended cash in the second quarter of $75 million related to conversions of convertible debt. This amount was comprised of $47 million of cash to repay debt principle and cash delivered of about $28 million in satisfaction of the conversion value in excess of the principal amount.</p>
          <p>Thus far in Q3, we've settled conversion notices with cash of $19 million for principal and elected to use cash of $72 million to settle the conversion value in excess of the principal amount. By settling the conversion premium in cash, we avoid dilution that would otherwise occur upon issuing shares of common stock.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have recently received conversion notices for $30.9 million principal amount of convertible debt, representing substantially the entire remaining outstanding balance of our older convertible bonds. Therefore, at the end of Q3, we are essentially left with only the 575 million of convertible debt issued in March of this year remaining outstanding.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, our cash and investments exceed our outstanding debt balance by about $595 million. We also have our $175 million revolving credit facility that is undrawn and doesn't expire until September 2012. Our pro forma fully diluted share account was 2.3 million shares higher than second quarter 2009, due to a year-over-year increase in our primary outstanding share account, resulting mainly from shares issued due to debt conversions over the past year and also due to the impact of higher share prices on fully diluted shares related to our in-the-money convertible notes. The increase was partly offset by year-to-date repurchases of common stock in the amount of $125 million and the use of cash rather than shares to settle conversion premium on converted bonds that I just discussed.</p>
          <p>Now for third quarter 2010 guidance. Our forecast reflects the strong performance in hotel room nights booked that we have seen thus far through Q3. It also includes a full quarter for TravelJigsaw. Our forecast also assumed that exchange rates remain at the same $1.32 per euro and $1.59 per British pound as Monday's closing rates. At or near these levels, exchange rates will have an adverse impact on our year-over-year financial results as expressed in U.S. dollars. Specifically, euro and pound average FX rates for the third quarter would be down approximately 9% and 4% respectively, as compared to the prior year. We have hedge contracts in place to substantially shield our third quarter net earnings from any further deterioration in the euro or the pound between now and the end of the quarter. But these hedges do not offset the impact of translation on our gross bookings, revenue, and gross profit.</p>
          <p>It's worth highlighting that the exchange rates we're using as the basis for our Q3 guidance are significantly stronger than the FX rates that were in effect when most analysts issued their forecasts that are the basis for the consensus estimate for Q3. FX rates, when most analysts' forecasts were last updated, were in the vicinity of $1.20 per euro and $1.40 per pound. Therefore, the relative strength in our guidance for the quarter versus analyst consensus, while certainly driven by expected continued strength in the fundamental performance of the business, is also driven by the stronger currency trends that have emerged in the past several weeks. This also emphasizes how much of an impact foreign currency exchange rate fluctuations, which are outside our control and not indicative of the core operating results of our business, can have on our results expressed in U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>We are forecasting total gross bookings to grow by 33 to 38%, with domestic gross booking growing by approximately 13%. We expect international gross bookings expressed in U.S. dollars to grow by 46 to 51% as compared to last year, and to grow on a local currency basis by approximately 57.5 to 62.5%. Our third quarter guidance assumes a similar rate of year-over-year increase for international hotel ADRs and further improvement in ADRs for our domestic business, as compared to the year-over-year ADR increases we experienced in Q2. We expect Q3 revenue to grow year-over-year by approximately 29 to 34% and gross profit dollars to grow by approximately 43 to 48%. For Q3 operating expenses, we are targeting consolidated advertising expenses of approximately 174 to $179 million, with about $8 million of that amount being spent for offline advertising.</p>
          <p>Online advertising expense as a percentage of gross profit is essentially in line with prior year Q3. We expect sales and marketing expense of between 31 and $34 million. We expect personnel costs, excluding stock-based compensation, to come in between 56 and $59 million. We expect G&amp;A expenses of approximately 21 to $24 million. We expect information technology costs of about $6 million and depreciation and amortization expense, excluding acquisition amortization, of about $4.5 million. We expect total below-the-line negative impact of approximately $10.5 million, which is comprised primarily of net interest expense, foreign exchange hedging loss, and the charge for pro forma net income allocated to non-controlling interests. We assume that losses will be incurred on our hedge contracts since the FX rates assumed for guidance reflect a stronger euro than the rates that prevailed at the time we entered most of our hedge contracts.</p>
          <p>Pro forma EBITDA is expected to range between 327 and $337 million, which represents 48% growth versus prior year Q3 at the midpoint. We are targeting pro forma fully diluted EPS of approximately $4.78 to $4.98 per share, which represents 41% growth over prior year at the mid point.</p>
          <p>Our pro forma EPS forecast includes an estimated cash income tax of approximately $74 million, comprised of international income taxes and alternative minimum tax in the U.S., where we have a sizable NOL to reduce our cash tax liability. Our pro forma tax rate is increasing as compared to prior year, due to more significant growth in international earnings as compared to domestic earnings.</p>
          <p>We expect TravelJigsaw to be slightly accretive to pro forma EBITDA and EPS for Q3 and the second half of the year. TravelJigsaw recognizes a significant portion of its annual pro forma EBITDA and net income in Q3 as revenue is earned upon completion of high season summer travel. Accretion to second half earnings on a GAAP basis will likely be immaterial due to the impact of amortization expense related to acquired intangible assets.</p>
          <p>Our pro forma EPS guidance is based upon a pro forma diluted share count of approximately 50.9 million shares, which is based on Monday's closing stock price of $227.38 per share. This is higher than our pro forma share count of 50.2 million in Q3 2009, due to a year-over-year increase in our primary outstanding share count, resulting mainly from shares issued due to debt conversions over the past year, partly offset by year-to-date repurchases of common stock and the use of cash rather than shares to settle conversion premium on converted bonds that I discussed a little while ago.</p>
          <p>As a result of those early conversions, the difference between our primary and fully diluted share count has been narrowing, and our fully diluted share count will be less impacted by changes in our stock price going forward. No shares will be included in our fully diluted share count related to our 1.25% convertible debt issued earlier this year, unless our stock price exceeds $303 per share. And these bonds are generally not convertible prior to maturity unless our stock price exceeds $455 per share.</p>
          <p>As for expected GAAP results, we expect to report a GAAP EPS of $4.06 to $4.26 per share. The difference between our GAAP and pro forma results is driven by pro forma adjustments to exclude stock based compensation, acquisition related amortization, including amortization related to the acquisition of TravelJigsaw, non-cash interest expense for amortization of debt discount, non-cash gains or losses related to early debt conversions, certain non-cash income tax expenses, and to include the impact on net income attributable to non-controlling interests of certain of the aforementioned pro forma adjustments, to arrive at pro forma earnings. We also intend to adjust pro forma results to exclude charges or benefits, if any, related to hotel occupancy tax judgments, rulings, or settlements.</p>
          <p>As we've highlighted in recent quarterly earnings releases, the strong results in unit growth rates we've achieved for the past several quarters were to some extent helped by the impact of the global recession on the prior year periods. More difficult comps, in tandem with the sheer size of the business, make it highly likely that the recent pattern we have seen in the first two quarters of 2010 of decelerating unit growth rates will continue. We believe that our comps become progressively more challenging throughout each quarter of 2010 and therefore our unit growth rates will sequentially decelerate in each quarter. Our guidance assumes that macroeconomic conditions in general, and conditions in the consumer travel market in particular, remain relatively unchanged.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call back over to Jeff for some closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dan. We are pleased with our results for the second quarter and the current trajectory of our international hotel business, which continues to take share in a competitive market. Our business has been resilient because of the underlying forces that make the business grow. The growth in global internet usage and the move from offline to online travel bookings, the growth in our hotel supply and geographic expansion, and the efforts of our people to innovate, to improve our content and interfaces and to strengthen our brands.</p>
          <p>We will now take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Ingrid Chun of Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon. So I was wondering if you could tell me about the geographic distribution of the strength in 2Q and as you look into 3Q, which areas &#x2013; which geographic areas are stronger and which ones are weaker, were they your newer markets or more mature markets? And then I was wondering if you could talk to when you think opaque could grow again? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ingrid. Geographic distribution, as I mentioned in the prepared remarks, we saw very strong growth from Agoda in Asian markets and Booking.com is doing very well in Asian markets, too. So new markets continue to, in general, grow at higher rates than the more established markets. But given the size and the concentration of our business in Europe, by definition we had very strong results in Europe as well.</p>
          <p>The other &#x2013; with respect to the opaque business, the opaque hotel business had good growth in the quarter. The air and rental car businesses are impacted by supply and we're starting to see some &#x2013;  enough of an improvement in the broad markets for airline tickets and for rental cars that certainly capacity reductions year-over-year are waning fairly dramatically, and in some cases rental car companies are adding fleet for peak demand periods. So I think that the improving conditions in the economy certainly could mitigate the capacity issues that we've been dealing with to a significant degree over the last couple years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just follow up and ask, in terms of Agoda, do you think you're back to your growth rate pre- all the political turmoil that was going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't really look at it that way, because Agoda has been growing very rapidly and our expectation would be that its growth rates would, just because of the law of numbers getting a little bit bigger, would decelerate. So that's not the way we look at it. One thing I can say, however, is that it certainly remains to be seen whether high season travel in Thailand, which is a very important destination, will come back to the levels that we would expect to see. We just won't know until we get there. Having said that, and as I mentioned in my remarks, we're pretty impressed by the growth in the Asian business in general, given the weak demand in Thailand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As Jeff pointed out in his comments, Ingrid, we still had triple-digit growth in Q2, even with the civil unrest in Thailand, which is one of their biggest markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Imran Khan of JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, thank you so much for taking my questions. A couple of questions. First, it seems like on advertising you've got some leverage on as a percentage of gross profit that are on a year-over-year basis. I was trying to get a better sense like what kind of competition you are seeing for key word trends, as the ADR trends continues to improve, what's dragging the leverage in the advertising side?</p>
          <p>And secondly, trying to better understand some of the synergistic opportunities you see with TravelJigsaw. Are you planning to integrate that with Booking, or you will plan to keep it separate, or are you going to cross sell inventories? Any trend would be very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Imran, with respect to leverage in terms of expenses versus gross profit, I don't want to get into a lot of detail about what the conditions in the market for key words are, but it's a certainty that improving unit economics makes it a little bit easier to meet your ROI targets, and we've been satisfied with the ROIs we've been achieving in the international business in particular. And brand building and repeat business is a very big piece of your overall efficiencies to make sure that you're not having to pay top dollar for every customer that comes into the door.</p>
          <p>With respect to TravelJigsaw, we're going to work with that business in the same way that we've worked with Booking.com and Agoda. They have a fair degree of operational independence. We work with them to figure out specific areas where we might have some business processes or some intellectual property or some knowledge that could help them build their business and generate more growth and be more efficient in things like IT purchasing and that sort of thing. Over time, we will look for opportunities for advertising their product on some of our other websites around the world, but that's not the principal driver of this transaction. The principal driver is for TravelJigsaw to build upon and expand its international franchise in rental cars and to build its own brand and its own direct customer flows. But we'll obviously take advantage of any business that we can move back and forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Imran, just to clarify, on online advertising, there was actually a very slight deleverage. Total advertising expense, we did have leverage and that's because offline, which only supports the U.S. business, didn't grow while we had significant growth in the business, particularly overseas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mark Mahaney of Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. I wanted to just get into the international report a little bit more. You had deceleration, but it was less severe than the toughening comp, and that's how your guide is, too. Given even if you strip out a couple of events like the impact from TravelJigsaw, did not the World Cup or the volcano have the impact you thought it would have? And is there something going on, particularly in terms of the Asia markets? You mentioned Booking.com showing success there. Do you think that you've maybe hit critical mass, both for Agoda and for Booking.com in terms of Asia, and that's what's behind the real lack of significant deceleration? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As Dan and I both mentioned in our remarks, we saw a pretty good bounce back in transaction growth in the aftermath of the volcano. We, in our last quarter earnings, tried to estimate what the impact of the volcano might be and we really haven't readdressed those numbers. So I can't tell you what the overall impact of that was on the quarter, and we certainly don't have any quantification of the impact of the World Cup.</p>
          <p>We &#x2013; I think we're lucky to have a very diverse business, not just a nice business growing in Asia, but also a big business in North America, and I think that having broader geographic distribution and customer diversity would tend to reduce the impact of more localized events like travel disruption from the volcano and maybe even to a degree, the World Cup. I wouldn't say that there is any particular inflection point in Asia. As we've said in prior earnings calls, we've been performing well there for some time. It still represents a pretty small piece of the total puzzle. So we're happy that it's contributing to high new market growth, but I wouldn't take it any further than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Justin Post of Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A couple things. First, a couple of the business-focused hotels have suggested maybe offering less inventory to opaque channels or just online channels. How dependent are you on just a couple of the major U.S. chains, especially in Europe, at all?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, Google is going to be trying to improve their travel search capabilities and just wondering if you think about how much traffic you get from there, is it a significant amount of traffic from Google? And if they do have a better consumer experience, how you would see that affecting your traffic over the long term? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Justin, with respect to hotel inventory for opaque, there's no question that improving conditions, improving occupancy, has an impact on hotel demand for opaque distribution, and I might add that there is more competition in that space right now with Travelocity and Expedia now showing opaque pricing on their principal websites. Having said that, we still have a very solid conversion for our hotel products here in the United States and very good support for that product from the chains, although conversion in hotels is slightly down, and you may have heard some comments to that effect in the Expedia conference call, but still very strong in our case.</p>
          <p>With respect to Europe, the chains are not as important a lever in Europe and in fact, we believe and hope that they represent an opportunity for Booking.com, who built its business over the years without material participation from the major U.S. chains and has been able to, over the last couple of years, sign agreements with the major chains and start to bring their inventory online. It's published price inventory, it's not opaque, we're not offering opaque product on Booking.com. But I think the chain participation internationally is growing, not shrinking, and represents an opportunity for us over the next year or so.</p>
          <p>With respect to Google Travel Search, they've been experimenting with vertical search in non-travel products and more recently in travel products with an experiment they're doing in hotels, and obviously their proposed purchase of ITA shows what their intention is in airline tickets. If you look at the statements that Google has made in connection with the ITA announcement, they &#x2013; and other public statements on their behalf, they characterize the effort as a way to improve the user experience and potentially deliver a more qualified customer to their advertising partners. And in the travel space, the online travel agents like ourselves, are some of their principal customers. So at least by their words, they intend to build a better user experience, so that they can deliver a more qualified customer to OTAs and suppliers.</p>
          <p>So if that's how things shake out, I think it could be a win for Google as well as a win for the online travel agents. You've heard a lot of other people in the space express a concern that Google might someday sell tickets on their own, or that they might start to not renew ITA's agreements with some other third parties out there. Google has expressed &#x2013; has denied that that's their intention, and we take them at their word. I think that over time, it could possibly represent a competitive threat, but that's not how they're characterizing it at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to add on, access to hotel inventory internationally, in addition to the fact that we're not looking for opaque inventory internationally, we also believe that we're one of the lower cost distribution alternatives for hotels. And therefore, even in an improving occupancy environment, we would be less likely to have inventory pulled away from us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Ross Sandler of RBC Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys, nice quarter. Just two quick questions. Can we drill down a little bit further on Europe hotels? You talked about Asia versus Europe. What about, can you talk about the growth you're seeing in your top ten European markets versus the second tier markets?</p>
          <p>And then a second follow-up question for Dan on the online marketing expense as a percent of gross profit. You've now seen basically flat, no deleverage in the second quarter, and you've guided the same for the third quarter. This is a bit of a departure from the past couple quarter trend, so is it &#x2013; should we continue to assume some deleverage in the future, or is the stronger unit economics from the ADR growth why you're seeing a lack of deleverage? Any color there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dan, why don't you take the second one first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, on the online marketing, you're right that as our international business continues to grow at a faster pace, it's likely that we would, all else being equal, see some deleverage when looking at online advertising as a percentage of gross profit. And it's also right to say that the extent that we have improvements in ADRs, that's an offsetting factor. So we've given you what we see for Q3 and we don't forecast beyond that, but your assumptions are reasonable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Ross, with respect to market-by-market, as you know, we don't break out growth rates in our various markets. But as I mentioned in response to a previous question, we continue to see faster growth in general in some of our newer markets, such as Asia, but we also continue to see solid growth in our core Western European markets. And I think part of the reason for that is that we're continuing to add hotels, not only in new markets but in existing markets, and we're also starting to see some benefits from customers that are booking hotels in &#x2013; the bookers are located in new markets and they're booking in some of our core markets. And then finally, as I mentioned in my prepared remarks, we &#x2013; the team is just doing a great job in innovating and improving the website and improving content and conversion, and that tends to promote growth in all your destinations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Doug Anmuth of Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks for taking the question. Two things, first on the air tickets, you saw some modest reacceleration, I think, on an easier comp in 2Q. Can you talk about whether you're seeing any impact from higher airfares on leisure travel? And then secondly, can you give us some more color on Agoda's partnership with Universal Travel Group and how you're thinking about this strategically going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dan, why don't you hit the airfare and I'll do Universal Travel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, we are seeing some softness in airline ticket demand, given the increase in air fares, and we also see some impact for our domestic business on online advertising expense as a percentage of gross profit. So those higher prices driving more clicks as people shop more and try and look for better prices out there. So we are seeing some impact from that. But again, just to emphasize that airline tickets are a pretty small part of our total gross profit and that is &#x2013; what we're seeing there in terms of softness is built into our forecast for Q3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And with respect to Agoda and Universal Travel, they're building their distribution through other travel websites in the region and I think this just represents their continued progress on that front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Scott Kessler of Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. I'm wondering if you could provide some additional details on Agoda or the Asia focused business. Essentially, I'm curious to know if you could provide some additional metrics related to that particular set of operations. And also, if you could talk a little bit about two key markets within that particular continent, obviously China and India. I know that there has been some discussion on these calls in the past about what you may or may not be trying to do at some point, whether it's now or later, in those particular areas, just wanted potentially an update. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott, with respect to additional metrics on Asia, we are not breaking out our results by geographic location generally with respect to the international hotel business, going beyond domestic results and international results. And while we want to give some color to what we think are pretty good growth rates for the Agoda business in Asia, we're probably not going to give additional metrics until the business gets to be of a size where it's truly material, because there's really no basis for treating that market differently than other markets that we're in, that are much bigger and doing quite well and actually having more of an impact on the business.</p>
          <p>With respect to key markets in Asia, I can say that we have pointed our strategy there more at the markets outside of China and India to-date, and that we believe that the opportunity represented by those markets that represent over 800 million people and very nice economic growth, we think is a great opportunity for us and we think it's a lot of work to do in the near term. The markets that are important to us in Asia, in particular the Thai market is a very important leisure destination, a lot of business in Singapore, Malaysia, Hong Kong, we have some business in Japan. Those are some of the markets that I would mention, and I would also say that we look at Australia and New Zealand as part of the broader APAC, and that's a market that we're focused on. And while the population numbers in Australia and New Zealand are very small compared to Asia, the affluence there and the tendency of the population there to travel widely makes it an attractive market for us as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Jeff, thanks for the detail. If I could just follow up really quickly, do you think that Agoda as a business and as a potential growth that needs to evolve is going to be sufficient from, say, a size and scale perspective to attack these markets and others in Asia, or do you think that potentially additional acquisition activity might be appropriate, given the opportunities that lie there? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think that Agoda is building the capability to be successful independently over the long term and build a leading business in online hotel reservations in Asia. And I can't predict today whether that will translate into broad success in China and India. But I believe that Agoda is building what will be a big business in Asia and they have the ability to do that without further acquisition. And keep in mind that Booking.com is also building its brand in Asia, and so we really have two independent efforts in that market and I think they're both well positioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mike Olson of Piper Jaffray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks, good afternoon. I don't want to beat the new markets piece to death here, but what markets outside of Asia are of interest to you, if any, or is any newer market build-out going to be in Asia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you went down the list of new markets for Booking.com in particular, Asia is an important new market. I think the Middle East and Eastern Europe are both attractive new markets that can drive business. We're just in very early days in South America, and we think that has good potential over time. And North America to a degree is a new market for Booking.com and obviously a very big market and represents an opportunity for Booking.com to build some business here. And as I think people on the call know, we've been working on that through initiatives that primarily aimed at driving European customers to U.S. hotels, but Booking.com is building out its hotel supply here and working on North America as a new market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a real high level one, do you think there's any truth to the idea that given some uncertainty in the economy that Europe consumers are traveling more within Europe versus internationally? Is that possibly having a positive impact on your Europe hotel bookings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have heard one other report of an international travel agency that said their travel from Europe to the United States was down. I haven't seen any other reports on that and I just can't comment on whether that speculation is true or not. One thing I can say is I don't believe that the travel agent that made that comment said, and accordingly our business in Europe looks like it's a little better because Europeans are traveling locally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Michael Millman of Millman Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can you discuss what, if any, incremental your business you're seeing from mobile devices, and if that business is broadly similar to your current business or are there certain focuses on that business? And you mentioned that some of the other OTAs are now putting opaque options; are you seeing any impact from that either in availability of hotels and cars or in business flow or other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With respect to the first question, we are seeing, and I think if you talk to other online players, most who are participating are seeing pretty significant growth in visitation and to some degree business from mobile devices for companies that have put good apps in the app store. I think a lot of them have been reporting a significant growth from obviously a very small base in business that's coming from iPhone applications.</p>
          <p>With respect to the type of business that you're getting from those devices, I think that is very often driven by the functionality that you provide in the application. So if, for example, your application is driven at last minute and geographically targeted business, for example, the way priceline's iPhone app is, then you see a lot more last minute business, you see a lot more local business, and because our app is pointed primarily at our Name Your Own Price product, we see a bigger mix of Name Your Own Price business. So it's turned out to be a useful tool in trying to drive particular businesses if they're, if that's consistent with how people are using the native functionality of the device. I think that that will continue to be a growing part of the business. The Android platform has got very wide distribution and is still in the very early days of really getting the number and the use of its applications out there, but we think that's pretty good.</p>
          <p>With respect to opaque inventory and whether we're seeing an impact of that, I don't &#x2013; first of all, the competitive efforts are principally in the area of hotel and Travelocity's Top Secret Hotel offering is pretty new, and we believe at this point in time, pretty small based on what we're seeing. And Expedia is essentially putting Hotwire on Expedia.com, and they've done that with different types of integration, with links and so forth in the past. And so it's not dramatically apparent to us that, in terms of what we're seeing in the business at this point, that we're losing a lot of business to those, but obviously it's a concern for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And getting back quickly to the mobile devices, is the visitation typically incremental new business or is it some of your current customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have any data to share with you that could prove that it's incremental or not, but one thing that we do believe is that if a particular competitor is very effective in a particular distribution channel, that can be an opportunity for share gain. So these may be customers that would otherwise be in the online marketplace for travel, but the fight for share of that is being played out on a different battlefield, and if you can be more successful, for example, in a mobile channel, you might be able to get a share gain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the extent that it's last minute travel, Michael, and we didn't have an app before and now that gives a customer a good opportunity to find last minute hotel room inventory, you could be getting some new business there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And gentlemen, as there are no further questions in queue, were there any final thoughts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for participating in the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude your program. Thank you for your participation. You may disconnect your lines at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>