<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1475867" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-17</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2063</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Investor Relations Manager, Petrobras">Lucas Mello</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial &amp; Head-Investor Relations">Almir Guilherme Barbassa</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Valores SA Sociedad de Bolsa">Frank McGann</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Exploration &amp; Production">Jos&#xE9; Miranda Formigli Filho</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Paul Cheng</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Downstream Director">Jos&#xE9; Carlos Cosenza</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Marcus Sequeira</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="BTG Pactual CTVM SA">Gustavo Gattass</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Morningstar Research">Allen Good</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor, Pickering, Holt &amp; Co.">Brandon Mei</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Americas Securities LLC">John P. Herrlin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Brasil CCTVM SA">Pedro Medeiros</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by, and welcome to the Petrobras Conference Call to discuss the First Quarter 2012 Results. At this time, all lines are in a listen-only mode. Later, there will be a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>Today with us we have Mr. Almir Guilherme Barbassa, Petrobras CFO and Investor Relations Officer; Mr. Jos&#xE9; Miranda Formigli, Chief Upstream Officer; Mr. Jos&#xE9; Carlos Cosenza, Chief Downstream Officer; and Mr. Jos&#xE9; Alcides Santoro, Chief Gas &amp; Power Officer and their staff.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Lucas Mello, Investor Relations Manager of Petrobras, who has some additional comments. Please go ahead, Mr. Mello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to our conference call to discuss first quarter 2012 results. We have a simultaneous webcast on the Internet that could be accessed at the site petrobras.com.br/ir/english.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, I would like to draw your attention to the slide two. We may have &#x2013; make forward-looking statements which are identified by the use of the words will, expect and similar, that are based on the beliefs and assumptions of Petrobras management and on information currently available to the company.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me mention that we have already released the results both in reais and dollars in accordance with International Financial Reporting Standards, however, at this conference call, we'll discuss Petrobras results in reais only. The conference call will be conducted by our CFO, Mr. Almir Barbassa. He will comment on the company's operating and financial highlights and the main events during the quarter, and he will be available to answer any questions you may have.</p>
          <p>Please, Almir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you for being with us in this conference when we are going to analyze the results of the first quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>To start with the next slides, we have the highlights of the quarter that shows we had a very good quarter with R$9.2 billion of net income and EBITDA which is volume of R$16.5 billion. We have increased over last year our production by 2% and we made during the quarter discoveries in the Campos Basin, Santos Basin, Esp&#xED;rito Santo and Solim&#xF5;es Basin. We increased our oil product output in Brazil by 3% and we sold 10% more during the year, when comparing the first quarter of this year with the last year same quarter.</p>
          <p>We start producing in Gulf of Mexico using the first FPSO installed in the Gulf in the Cascade field. And we did raise R$7.2 billion in the international capital market with record low rates. We did invest as well R$18 billion in all segments with the dominance of E&amp;P. Next please.</p>
          <p>The main indicators of company's sales, we have improved over the last quarter of last year, and the reasons, the main reasons are due to the fact that we sold more Brazilian products to international market. We used less international product to be sold in the domestic market. We had the better price in the domestic market due to international oil price increase and due to the adjustments we had in the fourth quarter in diesel and gasoline. And we had more exceptional cost during this first quarter that has accrued during the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Next, we had an increase in the total production of the company by 2%. While our international production has been stable, we had in the domestic production the same increase with dominance of the gas production that came mainly from two fields; Mexilh&#xE3;o and Urugu&#xE1;. We are working on the target &#x2013; production targets for the current year and this is dependent at this moment of the reevaluation of the production efficiency of the assets, mainly in the Campus Basin, as well as the return to production of the Frade fields. We expect to have this information to be given by the moment we are going to release our five-year business plan that we expect to be done up to August of this year.</p>
          <p>Next please. To increase 22,000 barrels per day in the oil production in this year, we had to add 273,000 barrels per day of production through new systems, but at the same time we had decreased total production of 251,000 due to natural decrease in production and some loss in efficiency on the operation of the assets. The main assets that has contributed to increase our production during the period was P-56, P-57, the pilot of Lula, and Aruan&#xE3; extended test &#x2013; yes, the TLD of Aruan&#xE3;.</p>
          <p>Next please. In pre-salt, I would like to call your attention for two main information that we expect to have 20 rigs operating by the end of this year in that region, and the production we have today in the Lula's pilot that has reached 94,000 barrels per day through four wells only. These are important that to say what is going to be happening in the area and what is the productivity we are finding in there.</p>
          <p>Next please. Next, yes. The oil prices, we have the better performance in terms of spreads when comparing prices of the light crude and heavy crude. In the quarter, we had only $6 spread what made possible to make more profitable our production.</p>
          <p>On the domestic market, we saw a price increase due to the diesel and gasoline price correction we had last November. But international &#x2013; and due to the international oil price that has increased in some oil products, we adjust to be shown in the domestic market. But international prices have increased and these have expanded into as well the spread between the prices we are selling domestically and internationally.</p>
          <p>Next please. In terms of costs, we have observed that due to more interventions in our old assets, we &#x2013; and more maintenance costs, we had a cost increase in our &#x2013; in lifting costs, and the government debt has improved too because of international price.</p>
          <p>Next &#x2013; and refining costs, refining costs returned to the level of the first quarter of last year and this was caused by lower stoppage program &#x2013; the stoppage in refineries that has occurred during this quarter.</p>
          <p>Next, we had &#x2013; in the domestic market, in Brazil, we have &#x2013; we had increased our production of oil products used in our existing refineries by increasing our utilization factor that has reached 94% during the quarter. And we have optimized the mix of products we are producing by increasing the production of diesel and gasoline that have increased as well the sales in the domestic market. As you can see, we have a 24% increase in the gasoline demand and 9% in diesel, largely due to the economic activity at Brazil, the gasoline is related to the ethanol market as well.</p>
          <p>Next, we have the trade balance that shows mainly on the export side, we had increased substantially our sales to international markets of crude oil. And part of this crude oil were in our stocks in our subsidiaries outside Brazil. But we had imported also a little more of oil products and this has happened mostly in the end of the quarter and we also imported aiming to attend demand that we expect to grow, certainly, during the second quarter this year.</p>
          <p>Next, the natural gas, we had sold more for thermoelectric purpose and this gas we have sold more came from domestic production and mainly due to the start-up of that Urugu&#xE1; and Mexilh&#xE3;o fields.</p>
          <p>Next, the operating income of the company has increased by R$4.2 billion &#x2013; almost R$4.3 billion and this increase came from sales. We sold a higher price and a larger volume during the quarter and we had what we had sold outside the country with what we sold in the Brazil, it's more than the previous quarter. Although, we had sold less in Brazil and more outside, that is a good contribution of these sales.</p>
          <p>And cost of good sold has reduced mainly because of the composition of the imported product in the mix of products sold in Brazil. And there were no occurrence of cost that were &#x2013; that has occurred in the first quarter that were not expected to repeat like impairments and other higher exploratory costs and extemporaneous depreciation that were recognized during that quarter.</p>
          <p>Next please. You can see that the net income received all the increase from operational income, because the financial results were very stable during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Next, looking at E&amp;P operating income, we can see that we had received better price for the quarter and had lower cost due to the revision in the proved reserves that has reduced the depletion cost of the company. And they had no recurrence exceptional cost that has occurred in the first quarter of the last year.</p>
          <p>Next, downstream &#x2013; we lost the presentation. Okay. Let's go on. The downstream, we had an increase in revenue due to the price effect. As I said, we sold more in the international market, where the oil price has increased. And we had a correction in the domestic market in the first quarter that applied too for the first quarter, as well as the corrections of prices we do on the some products in the domestic markets, when the oil price internationally moves.</p>
          <p>The volume we sold, in total, we sold more during this quarter. So, this increased our revenue as well. But we paid more for all cost &#x2013; for all products we sold during the quarter, as well as selling more we had to use more products that had increased by volumes the cost of goods sold, then reducing even more our operational results at the downstream.</p>
          <p>Next please. In terms of capital structure, we have performed very well, very stable, our leverage. We maintained our high liquidity of the company, even increasing during the quarter. And we have &#x2013; as I said, we have accessed the international capital market, raising $7.2 billion by one transaction, with tenors from three to 30 years and at record low rates.</p>
          <p>With that, I finish the presentation and invite you to make questions that I'll be answering together with my colleagues that are present here. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The floor is now open for questions from investors and analysts. We remind you that each participant will be allowed to ask two questions only. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Frank McGann of Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Just two questions. One is looking at the first quarter and then comparing it to the fourth quarter, it's clear that in this environment that we're in right now, where international prices for products are fairly volatile as well as currency is very fairly volatile, that a lot of the profit moves have to do with the interplay of currency and inventories and international prices for products. And I was just wondering, as you're looking towards the second and third quarters, how do you see those factors affecting results relative to what you saw in the &#x2013; in both the fourth quarter and the first quarter?</p>
          <p>And then second question, in terms of production and production levels as we're looking out through this year, the maintenance levels that you're expected to have in the second quarter, if you could comment on those and how you think that might affect second quarter production versus first quarter production. Also, how much the Frade field cost in the first quarter in production versus the second? And then, in terms of production on the &#x2013; for the new system that you &#x2013; that added production in the first quarter, will those continue to &#x2013; or there's &#x2013; is there further upside from those units in the second or third quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Frank, I don't know if we can help you much, because you are looking forward and we do not give this kind of guidance. But let's see what we can say here. Regarding the first quarter and this quarter in terms of what we expect to sell internationally, all will depend on how our production will perform on the quarter. And what I can tell you, at this moment, is that when we did build inventories outside the country during the first quarter, as we had said during the analysis of that quarter, this does not &#x2013; did not happen during the first quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>We did not build inventories as in the outside the country of crude oil as we did during the first quarter of last year. Regarding production, I don't know if Formigli can tell you something regarding value and what the expectation on the production of the second quarter we cannot say much. But that's here Formigli, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Frank, we &#x2013; relative to the projection of production, as Almir said, we will be only making this public when we announce the business plan or even for the production of this yearend for the coming years. Currently, we are working hard on the &#x2013; at performance improvement plans for the Campos Basin, specifically on that area, because we consider that we have definitely room to increase back that production to &#x2013; for the growth of efficiency, considering not only platform up-time, but also subsea, equipment, availability and well availability.</p>
          <p>So, considering the whole system, we are working hard at this moment on the projection of the predictive and preventive maintenance, plus &#x2013; or active maintenance and that would support the targets of production that Petrobras will announce with the business plan. I cannot tell you more than that, because as Almir said, we are not at this moment making comments on even the level of preventive maintenance that we are going to do on the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>You have asked about also Frade, today we are loosing 18,000 barrels of oil per day. It's our work interest on the Frade production. As you are aware, this is a Chevron-operated field, where we are partners. There are discussions running between the Chevron and Brazilian Petroleum Agency for the conclusion of what happened in the field led to seepage of oil in some areas. And based on that, we will be able to return production. If you ask us when this will happen? We are following the guidance of Chevron as the operator. And before they give any publicity on that, we are not able to make this public from ourselves, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if &#x2013; just to follow-up, if you &#x2013; when you look at the units that you're still ramping up production that have already been installed, is there additional upside from those units, P-56, P-57 that you might see adding to production, as you go through the rest of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We have a fairly high level of wells to be connected until the end of this year. We &#x2013; currently, we forecast close to 40 wells. I won't give you the exact number, because this change depending on the reservoir performance. I mean, since you're aware, we have that Varredura Project, besides the big projects that you have mentioned like P-57, P-56.</p>
          <p>So, there will be more, I would say, new oil coming. There are two big systems to startup during the second semester, the originally Tiro/Sidon project, which is now called Bauna/Piracaba. And there will be another one called Baleia Azul for &#x2013; the name is Cidade de Anchieta. So, these two FPSOs will be running on the second semester, which will add additional oil for &#x2013; with new facilities, and there are many other wells to be connected to the already established facilities, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Paul Cheng of Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Good morning. I had two questions. One is for the downstream and probably one for the upstream. On the downstream, can you give us an update in terms of the timing of the start-up and are there any revision on the CapEx for the new refinery that you currently have under construction, the one that in the Northeast and also that outside Rio? And also there whether you have start spending any serious money in the Premium I and II refinery?</p>
          <p>For the upstream, Formigli, when I'm looking on page six, you guys showing, look like, a underlined decline curve about 12.8%, because you're saying that from the base operation, it dropped by 251,000 barrel per day year-over-year. If that is a reasonable tie up to highway we could use on a going forward basis or that this is also going to subject to change based on what is your analysis going to look like on the maintenance capital and all that on a going forward basis? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cosenza, would you give us information on the downstream regarding the new refineries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:05) Well, for CapEx levels for new premium refineries, the range that we expect is from $30,000 to $40,000 barrel per &#x2013; per barrels &#x2013; barrels per day of capacity. And the timing and overall CapEx will not be announced now. We'll be announcing those figures in the business plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How about that the two already under construction, the Northeast refinery the 230,000 barrel per day and also that Comperj that 165,000 barrel per day. I think that previously you gave a budget of $13 billion for the Northeast refinery and $9 billion for the second one, and supposed to come on stream in 2013 in both, I just want to see if there is any update on those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, just a moment please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for Northeast refinery and Comperj refinery, we do not &#x2013; well, the numbers are above that, but we do not disclose those figures for each specific project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you tell us that whether the number is higher or much higher now or that it's still roughly about the same? And whether that is still going to be on stream into 2013 or it is being delayed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They will be running on 2013 and 2014 and beyond that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because you did gave a budget on both previously. So, I just want to see if that budget now is going to be much higher or is still roughly about the same?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Around the same that were announced, the public numbers that you already have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And how about in the upstream question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Formigli, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you look at that reduction of production, you will have, of course, both effects, decline of the reservoir and, in this case, we have reduction of efficiency. What we can tell you is that in terms of decline of the reservoir, they are running in accordance of the previous quarters. So, we don't &#x2013; we didn't have any decline, which was accelerated at this moment. So, of course, we keep on working on opportunities to reduce this decline. But they are running in accordance what was projected by the reservoir guys.</p>
          <p>When you look at the efficiency, that's where we have room to improve and we look &#x2013; when we look forward, this is currently our main target to be establishing a program to recover efficiency on &#x2013; especially on Campos Basin. So, after that, we will be able to announce the production target. So, we don't disclose specific numbers for each specific item that contributes for the reduction of our production. But you can consider that for reservoir decline is running accordingly and there is room for improvement on the efficiency. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So, should we interpret that while there is room for improvement in the future, but when looking at the first quarter that's really nothing, say, extraordinary in the quarter that had lead to a higher-than-usual decline rate. So, if we have no new improvement, then that 12.8% year-over-year decline is a reasonable proxy. And then, on top of that, we will base on what we think the improvement is going to be, is that a fair interpretation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you have always to consider which was the amount of new oil that was introduced on that. But okay, you are right. When you look at the, I would say, old oil, you may consider that the forward decline will be running in accordance to what is their historical numbers. Please, we don't project specific numbers at this moment for any of the coming quarters. But as I told you, the historical decline of reservoirs in Campos Basin is the same one that we are forecasting at this moment. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Marcus Sequeira of Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Hello. Good morning, everyone. Two questions, refinery &#x2013; the first one is that if you guys expect any maintenance in the refineries in upcoming quarters? You said that your imports of refined products increased at the end of the quarter. You have now a bigger inventory. That inventory made &#x2013; was made to meet increasing demand or just to make up for, maybe, some maintenance shutdowns in the upcoming months? And second question is regarding to prices, and if there is any plan which is being discussed by the &#x2013; with the company and the government, so that Petrobras will stop subsidizing in cost of gasoline and diesel? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marcus, related to prices, we keep doing our appraisal on what we expect looking at the market and reading as far as we can read in terms of price evolution and on presenting these &#x2013; our conclusions to our Board. And our Board has declared comfortable regarding what is prevailing the market right now.</p>
          <p>Regarding the first part of your question of maintenance and how we expect the market &#x2013; why we did import more oil products? As far as I can say is that we expect seasonally that oil product demand on the second quarter, that's why we did increase our inventories of oil products in Brazil. But regarding maintenance, I will ask Cosenza to share some information on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The level of maintenance in refinery in the second quarter is very low, but we have a very important &#x2013; at this moment, very important maintenance in pipeline, the oil pipeline, the crude pipeline in S&#xE3;o Paulo. These are the reasons for having more crude oils storage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So, we could expect a bit of a lower cessation rates into refineries in &#x2013; because of this maintenance, specifically maintenance in your second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. There is no maintenance in our refineries, not very strong impact in oil refinery fleet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And just going back to the prices, I understand, Barbassa, your policy &#x2013; pricing policy, but now Petrobras has been &#x2013; I think, the main question is on the imports, because as imports have been increasing over the last quarters, last two years, and Petrobras is now in a situation that is really buying expensive and selling cheap in Brazil. So, just you're seeing a lot of questions from investors and maybe I'm just wondering what were your response for your investors, especially the ones that didn't participate in the capital increase, when they asked why is Petrobras really subsidizing imports in the country? So, it is something that is, obviously, not everybody is talking about, but I think it is a very important issue for the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, it is not a matter of subsidize. It is a matter for pricing policy. And we had a moment where we were selling domestically at higher price than internationally. What happens is that there are different moments for considering our pricing policy. And this a moment where we are selling here at a lower price than internationally, but it's not a subsidizing policy established. It's a pricing policy established that happens to keep our domestic price more stable.</p>
          <p>What I can tell you is that we do appraise our &#x2013; as I said, we see how we expect the performance in the volatility of the price. As you saw, there were international oil price reduction in the last days. Today, we are &#x2013; this morning, we were below $110. We saw during the end of the first quarter $125. So there are volatility and we do not transfer the volatility, and we do appraise that and present to the Board. But there is no subsidy-established policy for the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much, Barbassa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Gustavo Gattass of BTG Pactual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Barbassa, there's actually two questions that I want to ask out there. They're a bit of a follow-up on the Brazilian call. The very first one, I just wanted to understand, in the last quarter, you guys did a fairly good job of trying to explain what the extraordinary items were that affected the quarter. I just wondered if we could do something similar for this quarter. And the one number that I was thinking about, which is basically the offset from last quarter, was your oil exports or actually the sale of the inventory that has been built last year.</p>
          <p>I was just wondering, can you guys share with us, I'd say, what you believe was the impact on your EBITDA? And more importantly, even for me, is it possible to say where this was accounted for? If it was accounted for an international refining, international E&amp;P or somewhere else in the numbers? So, that's the first question. Then later on I just wanted to have a brief question about the imported product mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We gave the main information that made the first a good quarter. And this is in line with the information we provide you in the first quarter. In the first quarter, we said that we had exported from Brazil, but not sold from the Petrobras system. So, it kept the value in our inventory that we realized during this quarter. This was an important element to explain the results. The second one was the reduction due to the seasonal demand in Brazil of oil products, mainly diesel and so you use less imported product that reduced &#x2013; often did have an direct impact, both of them has a direct impact on the EBITDA of the company. Maybe --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Barbassa, Let me phrase that differently. In last quarter, you guys said, you had an impact on EBITDA of about R$750 million from the building of inventory. Right? Since oil prices were higher in the first quarter, I just wanted to check, should I think about the impact of having been about R$750 or could it have been larger, because oil prices were higher. That's what I was trying to catch. I'm just trying to understand where it was booked?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gustavo, I don't have this information on mind now. I don't know if, Carlos, do you have this number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean, I don't have any additional information. As you just said, we didn't have the same increase of stocks driving this quarter. We didn't drop numbers that I can &#x2013; I can't give you additional information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then if I just may, let me jump to the second one, it's a very quick one. I just wanted to understand, Almir, when you said during the call that during the fourth quarter, you had 32% of import participation, and then in the first quarter that dropped to 24%. I just really wanted to understand how we should think about those numbers? Because we were doing some math on the total volume sold, so fourth quarter you sold 2,229 (sic) [2,229,000] barrels and 32% of that is roughly 713,000 barrels a day. Is that how I should think about it or is that number something that includes imported oil that goes into the refineries as well. How should I think about that number, because it seems a little bit too high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gustavo, when I gave you that number of 32% and 24%, it refers to oil products only, oil products sold. I don't know if this made clear for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the number that I was looking at was oil product sold as well. But what I'll do is, I'll follow-up with the team, don't worry. I just wanted to understand, because it seems like a little bit too big. But I'll give you guys a call a little bit later. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe you want to know if the oil products we sold &#x2013; the oil products that were produced here took more of imported crude oil or less compared with the former <mark type="ph" /> on the slide (46:20), I don't have this information now to give you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have &#x2013; yeah. I don't expect that this was relevant figure. The most relevant was imported oil products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Allen Good of Morningstar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning. I just had a question to follow-up on some of the operating efficiency that you mentioned, the Campos Basin being issue there. In the third quarter last year you enumerated some issues regarding lift, and in some hydrates and in some other things, I was just wondering are those still issues that are persisting or are you running into different issues on the Campos? And then I have a follow-up as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please, could you repeat which kind of problem? I understood hydrates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm sorry. So, on the third quarter of last year, you mentioned equipment efficiently as well, but problems with lift, hydrates formation, compression failures, et cetera. I'm just wondering are those the same issues that are persisting today on the Campos or are you running into a set of issues, or have you made the progress on some of the issues as well, and are you dealing with different ones? Just trying to get a little more information as far as the exact issues with operating efficiency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will try to describe which problems we are facing. In terms of wells and subsea, we have problems associated with hydrate formation and, in some cases, we have also to make work-over on the wells for sand control and I would say traditional work-over for replacing gas lift valves. So, this is a very traditional work-over that we have to do in oil fields with the mature areas that we have in Campos Basin.</p>
          <p>Beside that, in some areas, we have also some lateral submersible pump replacement work to be done. For example, this affected P-57 production during the first quarter. Of course, we are working hard on these issues in order to not happen, but there is a solid number of wells, which demands a big movement in order to guarantee that they come again with their original operational efficiency.</p>
          <p>Looking to the platforms, there are some issues related to processing plant availability and we are working on these areas with preventive maintenance, especially through what we call UMS, which are similar to floatels where you can put more people involved on the turnover of the unit, so you can do that in a shorter time. So, today, we are working on this scheduling of all these maintenance that we have to do above sea surface and below sea surface and that's the reason that today we're not announcing a production target for this year and we will do that when we announce a business plan. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And just a follow-up on those production targets. I assume the business plan will be later this year, maybe later than typical. And so, that will probably be most of the way through 2012. When we get production targets, will that be just for 2012 or do you think there will be some more clarity as far as beginning of 2013 and maybe even beyond that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we will do it as we do for the business plan. So, there will be not only short-term targets, but also near, medium and long-term targets. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one quick one. Is there &#x2013; can you give an update on the asset sales and has there been any progress made there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please, repeat, because this is really difficult to understand. Could you repeat again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. If I could get an update on any asset sales to date or any anticipated sales for the remainder of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are working our plan. We have announced $13.6 billion,, of assets sales we have done. It's not all asset sales, but there is a good portion of it that is better allocation of working capital, releasing working capital to service our investment plans. And we are, the next quarter, announcing a few of the important sales we are planning out of the asset sale we have announced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just to complement the information of Gustavo in the former question. Regarding the composition of imported crude in the total cost of our oil products sold in Brazil. We had a decrease &#x2013; an increase, sorry, in the first quarter. We had 19.1% of imported crude in the total cost of oil product produced in Brazil. And during the first quarter of 2012, this was 22.8%. Of course, we had 8% of increase in the international oil price, which is factored inside this figure as well. But there were, in fact, an impact on the oil &#x2013; imported oil &#x2013; crude oil in our total cost of oil products produced in Brazil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Brandon Mei of Tudor, Pickering, Holt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. My question is on exploration. It appears you're currently drilling about five wells in the deepwater Sergipe-Alagoas Basin, having both pre and post-salt prospectivity. I just wanted to see if you could provide some color on those wells and any potential analogy to the Gabon blocks in the conjugate basin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me see if I understood, you are asking about the portfolio margin in Brazil and how are things running on the wells that we are drilling there and potential analogy of that with West Africa, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I just wanted to get some color on the wells being drilled in Sergipe-Alagoas Basin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sergipe-Alagoas. Okay. So, yeah, we are drilling an appraisal well on the Barra discovery. And whenever we have something to make public we will do it. So, unfortunately, we cannot tell you that this is right moment. But you're right, we are drilling this well and of course we &#x2013; as in appraisal, we have expectations for the well, but I cannot tell you anything more than that. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any expectation on when well will reach TD?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have this information right now. But probably in the next four, five weeks, we might reach TD and have all the logging of the well reached. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from John Herrlin of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. Two quick ones. How is the ramp going with Cascade? And then, with respect to pre-salt, I believe, you're going to use some horizontal wells rather than just vertical wells. Could you comment on what the status is on your horizontal drilling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me have my colleague from the national department to update us on this information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in Cascade, we're going to have another well until the end of this year and we expect it to achieve <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:03) this year, the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now, commenting on the drilling of horizontal wells versus vertical wells in the pre-salt in Santos Basin. We have finished the drilling of horizontal well. It was a very good success in terms of operational performance. These wells will be starting producing in two or three months. The reason for that is that we have already reached, as Barbassa has said, we are the top with the production in the current follow-up system.</p>
          <p>I would say that confirms our expectation. The vertical integrated wells in the pre-salt considering the thickness of the reservoir and permeability gives to us better economical results than drilling horizontal wells. But at the same time, it was very important to make feasible that we &#x2013; so we know that whenever it's necessary we are able to do that. It will depend, of course, on the reservoir condition. But now, for Lula &#x2013; Lula Iracema area, Sapinho&#xE1; and Carioca, we are still look &#x2013; we are still prioritizing the development using vertical and deviated wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Relative to the question of the Barra appraisal well, the current forecast for total depth will be 60 days. So, it will &#x2013; we still have two months of drilling ahead of us. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Pedro Medeiros of Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Thanks. Particularly, Formigli, I have a question for you. Can you comment a little bit more on the performance of the Marlim Leste field and specifically on the Jabuti formation? I think the last development that you guys said was only for a requirement of dynamic balance rate back at the reservoir and increase the production. Is there any new guidance on how you guys plan to work on that or when should we expect production to bounce back on that specific field?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, let me comment on Marlim Leste. We are producing in the Jabuti area. It's a fractured carbonate, as you are aware. We currently &#x2013; we are &#x2013; we have drilled six wells. They are all producing, fairly good production. And for other wells to be drilled over there, we have identified that we need to go for under balance and we are currently still on the economical analysis of the feasibility to grow that with the potential day rate for a rig to be specified for that. Don't consider that we will have new wells on 2012 it's not what's on our production target for this year. So, that's what I can make public now. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And I do have one other question and it's actually a follow-up to previous question for, Almir. Almir, I think, on the last call, you said on the asset sales program, we could expect the bulk of assets being sold through the first half of this year. How has this guidance or this program changed? And I understand that almost 50% of your original guidance was actually coming from working capital improvement, and as far as first quarter goes, we are actually seeing higher working capital being built relative to your revenues growth. Is there any change to that or how long do you expect this program to effectively mature?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did announce last year this program. I mean, we said that we will be implementing it in two, three years time. It was a program for five years, the five-year program. But we expect to have it done by second &#x2013; end of second or third year. So, we have yet another two years as we did announce firstly. And what I can tell you now is that we are progressing in very good timing and we'll have in the second half of this year good information on this program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, thanks. And maybe one last question, I think on the last price increase announced back in &#x2013; by the end of October or early November last year. Federal Government of Brazil has reduced the CIDE tax and that's specific decree curiously had an expiration date 24 the end of June. Can you comment a little bit of where are the scenarios that Petrobras is working for to the expiration of that decree? Are you considering that the CIDE tax will be &#x2013; will recover to the former level or will continue at the current level or maybe even change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, this will depend on the government. But we expect that &#x2013; this all depends on price. CD &#x2013; CIDE is a buffer for oil prices to that gives to the government the control they would like to have on these prices. So, this all will depend on the evolution of prices. So, I cannot tell you what's going to happen next June.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, the base scenario is basically here to keep it unchanged as of now. Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Eduardo Tellus of Espir&#xED;to Santo Securities (1:03:25).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Going back to the lower efficiency in the Campos Basin, you have mentioned that Campos Basin is a mature field and this is one of the reasons for what is going on. My question is do you believe that the problems that change from time to time are permanent or temporary that makes this field less efficient now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Definitely, they are temporary things. The Campos Basin is still with a part which is mature. And there are many new fields and we have today three &#x2013; as a matter of fact, one and that's considering the Whales Park, but we still have big systems scheduled to be followed in the coming years in Campos Basin like the P-55, P-62. So, we have definitely matured areas that has been producing since the beginning of the 1980s and that's the reason that we have to be taking care of them, in order to recover efficiencies that we believe that are totally achievable. So, the current situation is not applied to whole Campos Basin. It's applied to those more matured areas, and no doubt that we will be able to recover to better level of efficiencies. So, that's our point in relation to your question. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is a follow-up from Frank McGann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. Just wanted to follow-up more or less on the same theme, in terms of the decline rates, I was a little confused by the response. The impression I have is that the decline rates on average for the company, historically, 7% to 10% is the range you've always used, and my understanding was last year was closer to the low end of that range or maybe even a little bit below. I was just &#x2013; was wondering if that's &#x2013; in these first quarter numbers you're seeing that you have the efficiency issue, plus the decline rate issue, the underlying decline rates are still either in the 7% to 10% range or lower in that range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's on that range. That's what you may consider at this moment. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question is a follow-up from Paul Cheng of Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Barbassa, in the first quarter, your CapEx is R$18 billion, your budget for the year is R$87 million. I understand that typically that you spend more in the second half, but should we still, based on this run rate, assume that you &#x2013; more likely than not you're going to under-spend your this year budget by about 10%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, if you did multiply by four the 18, it should be less than the total we are forecasting. But we are in an increasing mood in terms of capital expenditure in the company. And so, it all depends on the performance of many different factors. What we can tell you is that we are going to have more rigs available and this is an important factor. This means that about 50% of the development cost today, or plus, depending on the field, and we are all the time dependent as well on the performance of our suppliers. But I cannot give you more than that in terms of --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I &#x2013; Barbassa, can I ask you in another way that? In the first quarter comparing to your internal budget, if the actual spending is lower? And if it is, by how much, or that is roughly about the same as what in your internal budget?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean looking at your spend R$18 billion, what is your internal budget that you previously assumed you will spend in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have these figures. Someone has the information of the first quarter? Just a moment, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. While you are looking for that, if I can ask my second question? On the upstream, Formigli, is that &#x2013; do you have a unit cost inflation rate assumption or estimate that you can share for this year and next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding what was expected in the first quarter was in that &#x2013; we were &#x2013; the volume we did was in the range of 90%, 95% and the question regarding the downstream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the upstream &#x2013; the second question is that, in the upstream, do you have a cost inflation assumption or estimate you can share for 2012 and 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are meaning cost inflation in relation to the CapEx or you're talking about OpEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>OpEx, I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>OpEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>OpEx, operating cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operating cost. Well, we &#x2013; as was shown previously, there is part of our addition cost this first quarter in relation to the previous one, which is associated not only to the amount of work that we have been doing, but there is some inflation on that, but not so that much. For future, we don't make forecast on this range. So, we cannot anticipate to you if we are going to have inflation on that. Please always remember that Petrobras normally runs with long-term contracts. So, for rigs, for supply boats, for helicopters, most them are done on a long-term contract. Of course, if you have a long-term escalation of prices related to these inputs, there may be inflation. But short-term escalations are not &#x2013; normally do not affect, okay. But we are not making any projection of OpEx at this moment for &#x2013; at least make public at this moment. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. There are no further questions at this time. Mr. Barbassa, please proceed with your closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for being with us during analysis of the first quarter results of 2012. And we expect to have you all with us in the next quarter analysis we expect to be in August. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, your host is making today's conference available for replay starting one hour from now. You may access this replay at the company's IR website at www.petrobras.com.br/ri/english. This concludes Petrobras' conference call for today. Thank you very much for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>