<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1299429" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2063</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Alexandre Quint&#xE3;o Fernandes, Investor Relations Manager</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jos&#xE9; Sergio Gabrielli de Azevedo, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Lilyanna Yang</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Ricardo Cavanagh</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Marcus Sequeira</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Frank McGann</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Eduardo Vieira</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Gustavo Gattass</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Subhojit Daripa</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen thank you for standing by and welcome to the Petrobras Conference Call to discuss the Fourth Quarter and 2009 Results. At this time, all lines are in a listen-only mode. Later, there will be a question and answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>Today with us we have Mr. Jos&#xE9; Sergio Gabrielli, Petrobras CEO, and his staff. At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Alexandre Quint&#xE3;o Fernandes, Investor Relations Manager of Petrobras who has some additional comments. Mr. Alexandre, the floor is yours, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good morning ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to our conference call to discuss fourth quarter and 2009 results. We have a simultaneous webcast on the internet that could be accessed at the website www.petrobras.com.br/ir/ing.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, I would like to draw your attention to the slide two, we will make forward-looking statements which are identified by the use of the words will, expect and similar that are based on the beliefs and assumptions of Petrobras management and on information currently available to the company.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me mention that the conference call will discuss Petrobras' results prepared in accordance with Brazilian GAAP. At this moment, we are unable to discuss any issues related to U.S. GAAP results.</p>
          <p>The conference call will be conducted by our CEO, Mr. Jos&#xE9; Sergio Gabrielli, who will comment on the company's operational and financial highlights and the main events during this quarter and who will be available to answer any questions you may have. Mr. Gabrielli, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. I will begin talking a little bit our results and our reserve replacement rate. We had 110% of reserve replacement, increasing our reserves from 14.09 billion barrels of oil equivalent to 14.17 billion barrels of oil equivalent. We incorporated in our reserves 861 million barrels and we produced during the year 785 million barrels a day. We have a reserve production rate of 18 years, and we are incorporating in those barrels only 182 million barrels from the resources that we have discovered. We are incorporating in our reserves only the Esp&#xED;rito Santo Basin discoveries. All the discoveries in the Santos Basin have not yet incorporated in our proven reserves.</p>
          <p>Now in international reserves, we reduced our international reserves from 992 million barrels to 696 million barrels, as a result of the publication of the Bolivian constitution that required that we could not recognize reserves in Bolivia.</p>
          <p>In terms of production, the next slide please, we increased our production of oil and gas in Brazil and outside of Brazil from 2.4 million barrels a day to 2.526 million barrels a day, a 5% growth rate from 2008-2009. In domestic terms, our production of oil and gas increased by 5% and our production in Brazil of oil increased by 6%.</p>
          <p>The production &#x2013; oil production increased as a result of the ramp-up of the P-52, P-54, P-53 and the start-up of 5 million units that we had in Brazil. Most of our new production in the international production came from the Akpo and Agbami fields in Nigeria that are operated by other companies that we are partners with them. Our natural gas production declined as a result of the reduction in demand in Nigeria.</p>
          <p>For 2010, we plan &#x2013; we have a target of a 2.1 million barrels a day plus and minus 2.5% of uncertainties and variation of our target. This production will come from the current Extended Well Test in Tiro e S&#xED;don that's already, we began this week. We plan to increase our production from the Urugu&#xE1; Tamba&#xFA; the second quarter for this year, producing 10 million cubic meter per day of gas and 35,000 barrels per day of oil.</p>
          <p>In Cachalote and Baleia Franca we are going to be producing 100,000 barrels per day and we are going to begin Extended Well Test in Guar&#xE1; with a 30,000 barrels per day of production. In the third quarter, they should then begin producing 15 million cubic meters per day and in the fourth quarter, and we are trying to anticipate the pilot production in Tupi of 100,000 barrels per day by October and 5 million cubic meters of gas in the fourth quarter of 2010 and we are going to begin the extended well test in Tupi Northeast producing 38,000 barrels per day. This will allow us to see &#x2013; to reach the target of 2.1 million barrels by the end of 2010.</p>
          <p>In downstream, in downstream we invested in 2009 R$17.3 billion, most of the investment was &#x2013; 34% was in fuel quality which is that we are increasing our capacity for reducing sulfur emission in our gas &#x2013; gasoline and diesel, trying to meet the environmental requirements of Brazil. We are starting the production of Diesel S-50 in three of our refineries REDUC, REPLAN, and REGAP and we are complying with this more strict environmental standard.</p>
          <p>It's important to mention that on downstream, we had very &#x2013; two very good results in 2009. First, we increased our production of diesel. We could process our crude oil and get a better production of diesel, reducing the production of fuel oil. This increased the value added of our outputs and increased the results of our products and reduced our imports of diesel but we are short in diesel in the Brazilian market. This had a very good result not only in our trade balance, but also in our final results in the bottom line of our company because we have a better margin when we produce the diesel, rather compared when we import diesel.</p>
          <p>The other thing that was very important was that we could process more acid oil and ultlra-acid oil that we are producing more without requiring metallurgy investment in our hardware. We could improve and optimize our processing systems and we could process acid oil, getting good results with the oil &#x2013; the type of feedstock that we are using.</p>
          <p>We have three new hydro treatment phase HDT units and we are going to have &#x2013; we have a production that will increase by 2% from 1.787 million barrels to 1.823 million barrels per day.</p>
          <p>In terms of sales, we have an increase of 2% of our sales in the last quarter compared to the third quarter, showing that we have a recovery of the Brazilian market in the last quarter. But also we have &#x2013; comparing yearly data from 2008 to 2009, we have an increase in our market sales of 1%. Brazil market behaves a little different from the other international markets, some other international markets, because during the crisis we really didn't have a very big reduction in the demand of oil products in Brazil, in such a way that we could increase our sales in Brazil by 1% year-to-year and by 2% in the last quarter compared to the third quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>In terms of natural gas, we could keep on average below what we had in 2008, but above what we would expect &#x2013; if you have taken into consideration only the dispatch of natural gas power plants based only on the phasing of water reservoirs for electrical generation. We also dispatched our thermoelectric plant Brazil as a result of electrical needs for the electrical systems, power generation system in Brazil in such a way that we could keep dispatch greater than we would have expected otherwise.</p>
          <p>We have also a very important thing that was, as the price of ethanol increased in Brazil and ethanol is 61% of the auto cycle demand in Brazil. As the price of ethanol increased, we have a shift in the demand moving toward the gasoline again and the gasoline became cheaper than the ethanol and the consumers that have the choice in Brazil, they decide to move to the gasoline. And we have a increased demand of gasoline in the last quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>In terms of trade balance, we have very good results. We, volume-wise, we increased our net exports from 102,000 barrels a day in 2008 to 156,000 barrels a day by 2009. But the most important thing is not only that volume-wise we have more oil products and oil being sold from Brazil than by to Brazil, but also on financial volume we have changed completely the situation from a deficit of $907 million in 2008 to a surplus of $2.8 billion by 2009. We &#x2013; our trade surplus was big enough to pay all the liquid oil products that we use but also the natural gas that we import from Bolivia.</p>
          <p>Next, please. In terms of biofuels, we increased by 34% our sales of biofuels. We are selling around 125,000 barrels a day of biofuels, 98,000 barrels a day of ethanol and 27,000 barrels a day of biodiesel. In Brazil we have 5% mandatory biodiesel mix blend with diesel and 25% mandatory ethanol blended with gasoline, plus the pure hydrated gasoline that is sold in the Brazilian gas station to any driver that wants to use ethanol in Brazil.</p>
          <p>We have increased 22% of the megawatt average sold by our power generating companies. We sold 1.4 gigawatts on average in 2008 and this was 1.7 gigawatts by 2009.</p>
          <p>The change in the energy sales and the natural gas was also a result of the completion of several projects that we have on our infrastructure for the distribution and transportation of gas in Brazil. We've finished the Urucu-Coari-Manaus pipeline, we have finished several gaps that we had in the Brazilian national grid of pipelines, we just finished. And we're inaugurating next Friday the Gasene pipeline that connects completely the Northeastern pipeline grids with the Southeastern pipeline that actually the molecules of gas now are transported from Bolivia to anyplace in Brazil, from LNG to anyplace in Brazil from our domestic production to anyplace in Brazil, that we have right now a national grid of pipelines connecting Northeastern to the South of Brazil and the Southeastern part of the Brazil or Western part of Brazil.</p>
          <p>We also have developed a new systems for contract for sale of gas; we are selling gas in the spot market. We are creating a short run market that we can sell the surplus of gas for the near future in such a way that we can get hopefully a new system of flexibility &#x2013; flexible contracts for the demand of gas in Brazil adjusted to the supply that needs flexible &#x2013; needs flexible conditions to meet the specific conditions of the thermoelectric <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>Also we had a very important cost reduction effort. We operate in several areas. We changed our drilling process. We divide the packages in different suppliers in such a way that we could get more competitive bids. We subdivide more of our projects. We are trying to get more shelf type of equipments for our projects and we changed the culture internally to give more consciousness of the need to control costs.</p>
          <p>On the bids we have very good results comparing the first proposal with the final contractual outcome and we have for example R$7 billion CapEx reduction on the negotiation of some of the contract. Finally, we have very good results in the negotiation with the APEC FPSOs in the P-61, P-63. We have also good results in the Campos negotiation and also we are expecting good results in the domestic rig building industry that we are right now underway.</p>
          <p>In terms of rationalizing the projects we got online under contract right now, the assembly line of eight identical pre-salt FPSOs that are going to be produced in the southeastern shipyard in Brazil. We have a P-56, a clone of the P-51 and we have relocation of some of our FPSO to improve and optimize the production of some fields in Brazil.</p>
          <p>In terms of administrative overhead, corporate overhead, we could get a very good savings taking a very strong commitment for cost reduction that saved for the company R$750 million on corporate overhead during the 2009.</p>
          <p>Next. In terms of prices, we see two important things that we would like share with you. First, a reduction of the spread between heavy and light oil; this was very clear in 2009 and this was very good for Petrobras as we produce heavier oil than the average ramp &#x2013; than the average <mark type="inaudible" />, in such a way that we could get good results for our own oil, minimizing the spread that in the past we had to comply with.</p>
          <p>The other thing that was very important is that the long-term pricing policy that we have in Brazil. We don't pass through the Brazilian market all the fluctuations, the short-run fluctuation of the international price of oil products, mainly, specifically on diesel, gasoline and LPG.</p>
          <p>We prefer to keep a long-term relationship between the Brazilian market and the international market. And this sometimes is good, sometimes is bad for the results of the company. In 2008 for example, the average realization price of the oil products weighted by the volumes that we saw in Brazil was R$194.7 per barrel, while in Brazil we were selling those barrels by R$176.4 with a difference between 194 and 176.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we have the opposite. We have a Brazilian price that was 167.7 below the 176 of 2008 but above the 130.06 that was the average in the U.S. that captured much more the reduction in the international price for crude oil that we minimized impact in Brazil.</p>
          <p>Looking at longer run, we see that we have a balanced type of policy that can minimize in this move, the price behavior across the different cycles of the price of oil and the price of the crude oil derivative price of oil products across the cycle.</p>
          <p>Looking at the numbers, the operating income was pretty much the same, we had the 46, around R$46 billion in 2008, around R$46 billion in 2009. The reduction that we had in our net operating revenue, we compensated the reduction of our cost of goods sold in such a way that we could keep around R$46 billion, the operating income, such a way that we could get the same, almost the same type of result even in a environment of a lower oil price and a lower average realization price.</p>
          <p>Next. In terms of net income, we have a reduction of our net income, our reduction is very strongly affected by the exchange rate behavior. The Brazilian exchange rate was depreciated in 2008 by 32% in relation to the U.S. dollar. By 2009, we have an appreciation of the Brazilian real by 26% above the U.S. dollar, in such a way that we had in 2009 financial results strongly affected by the financial behavior of the exchange rate, not only directly towards the results in Petrobras Brazil but also affecting our subsidiaries in our companies that are outside of Brazil when we convert the U.S. numbers into reais in such a way that we have a reduction in our results that were smaller than the other companies because on the operating income, we could keep the results balanced off on level with the 2008 results.</p>
          <p>Next. In terms of capital structure, we have an increase in our leverage ratio and our gearing rate increased from 28% in the last &#x2013; in the third quarter to 31% in the fourth quarter of 2009. This is something that is a important sign for us. However, it's important to mention that we have a 15% short term debt on total debt. Our total debt today is R$100 billion, around R$100 billion, and we have a net debt on EBIT of 1.2 times, our net debt is 1.2 times EBIT.</p>
          <p>We have under our guidelines from our board, we have a ceiling of our net debt to EBITDA ratio of 2.5, we are reaching right now 1.2 times EBITDA as net debt.</p>
          <p>Next please. The other thing that's important is that &#x2013; the maturity of our debt. Even though we increased our debt by R$100 million, $57 billion we could get a very good term structure for our debt. In 2007, 60% of our debt has maturity up to five years. Now, we move this maturity to eight years, we have an average life of 7.5 years, 7.46 years in 2009 in comparison to 4.21 years in 2008. We have a bigger debt, but longer structure of the debt which gives us some more healthier conditions to deal and to manage this debt.</p>
          <p>Only to highlight in focus what happened &#x2013; is happening in 2009, you can see that in 2008, we have net cash flow, negative net cash flow of R$3.5 billion and in 2009, this increased by R$18.4 billion. We have almost three times more net cash flow, negative net cash flow and this is mainly as a result of the increase in our investment. We increased our investment from R$53 billion to R$70.2 billion, average year-to-year.</p>
          <p>If we take the fourth quarter, we are going to see that we are moving up in this direction with an investment in the third quarter for R$19.6 billion. The cash, we finished the fourth quarter of 2009 with R$28.9 billion cash. Our cash balance was R$28.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Next. For 2010, we plan to increase our investments from the R$7.7 billion that we invested in 2009 to R$88.6 billion by 2010. Most of the new investments increased, not the new investment, the increased investment is on the refining, transportation commercialization from 17.4 to R$34 billion. Most of this investment is the completion of several projects that are ongoing right now for improving the quality of our products and also the beginning of the new refineries that we are planning to build in this period, mainly the refinery in the Northeastern of Brazil and the beginning of the works in the Campos refinery.</p>
          <p>Next please. In terms of the long-term, we are finishing our investment plan. We are planning to finish it and release the information to the market but we give &#x2013; our Board of Administration is giving us some guidelines.</p>
          <p>First, the leverage ratio should be between 25 and 35%. We have to keep our net debt around &#x2013; below 2.5 times EBITDA and we must keep the returns from our investment project by project. We are taking some assumptions on the Brent curve of the price of oil, we don't see any real fundamental reason why we would expect a reduction on the current price of &#x2013; a dramatic reduction in the current price of oil. We have an average we are on working on a financial base not for the purpose of proving project but to analyze the financial ability of the portfolio as a whole. We are taking an average price between 64 and $74 per barrel. We &#x2013; this is not our expectation that the price is going to be like that but we are taking those numbers only for simulation purpose of our portfolio, how to see, how it's going to behave our financial numbers in those hypothesis.</p>
          <p>We are taking on the assumption that we are going to have a build capitalization of the company. This year we are going to have issues of new shares this year and this is going to be very important to be happening in the first half of 2010. And the second is that we are going to have a very clear and very short-run sight of the funding needs of the strategic plan, the payout, when we'll use the new numbers of our business plan.</p>
          <p>We have &#x2013; it's important to mention to you these numbers that are CERA numbers, IHS and CERA numbers by March of 2010 is not our own numbers. And those numbers shows very clear that the reduction in the cost of capital, and the reduction of the cost of projects of investments in E&amp;P and downstream are reversing to upward movement right now.</p>
          <p>The small reduction that we had in 2008 and beginning of 2009 is already reversed and we are seeing increasing cost in capital costs for investment projects in upstream and downstream in the oil industry. This reflects the continuity of the investment plans of the companies that are not moving on cycle but moving across the cycles in order to look at longer-run view of the development of resources that they have.</p>
          <p>Taking into consideration those hypothesis, the next please, we consider that Brent price, we are taking two hypothesis, under the assumption that the average Brent price is going to be $64 or the assumption that the average Brent price is going to be $77 per barrel and under the assumption that we are going to get from the shareholders' participation, not controlling shareholders of the company, a contribution of between 15 and $25 billion, this year we are going to have an investment between 200 and $220 billion for the next five years. This is going to lead us or move us or lead us to a leverage ratio of between 27% and 32% which is under the assumptions that we have under the range that we have established by our Board of Administration.</p>
          <p>Our net debt to EBITDA ratio is going to be between 1.6 times and 2.2 times of EBITDA in such a way that we are under the range detailed by our plan.</p>
          <p>For 2009, next slide, for 2010, we have approved R$265 billion which represents probably something between 60 and around two-thirds of the investment that there are some projects for upstream, gas and energy refining, transportation, commercialization and biodiesel, biofuels. This is going to increase our investment in liquid salts; this is going to be very strong investment in modernization and expansion of refining in Brazil.</p>
          <p>We are moving forward new projects in petrochemicals and fertilizers, but basically nitrogenous fertilizers and in ethanol pipelines and infrastructure and production, also in ethanol production. We're finishing this investment cycle in natural gas infrastructure and the investment in LNG plants that are going to be prepared for re-gas plant and LNG and liquefying plant and new power generation project.</p>
          <p>In terms of exploration in the pre-salt area, we have very good &#x2013; everything are going in full speed right now. Yesterday we released the results of our production test in the Northeastern part of Tupi. We have a very high productivity in this well that is up to 30,000 barrels per day of production capacity in the Northeastern part &#x2013; a well drilled in the Northeast at Tupi Northeast.</p>
          <p>Also we have been &#x2013; we have very good results in the production test in Guar&#xE1; and we have right now two wells being drilled in Tupi West and North part of Guar&#xE1;. We are drilling for the National Regulatory Agency well in the Northern part of Iara that's not under construction. It belongs to the Brazilian government.</p>
          <p>We plan to drill 11 new wells in 2010, in the pre-salt cluster, in the Santos Basin and we have bid for the eight FPSO for Guar&#xE1;, the second pilot for the BM-S-11 and the eight hulls for the Santos cluster that are going to be allocated to different areas in the Santos Basin.</p>
          <p>In terms of the capitalization, next please. We have the evaluation, the process of evaluation of the barrels, depends very much on the completion of the drilling that we have in the northern part of Iara. There is another well that's scheduled to be drilled as soon as possible. We are going to have an appraisal and a certification of two certifications &#x2013; independent certification company and we have to define the contracts, the conditions, for the reassessment of the value of the wells. The size of the capitalization depends very strongly on those numbers, in such a way that it's impossible right now to have a clear idea for the size of the capitalization.</p>
          <p>In order to guarantee and assure transparency and fairness, we have created a board committee to represent the minority stockholders and we are going to give full and transparent disclosure of all the relevant information about this transaction.</p>
          <p>In timing terms, we are thinking that we may have this transaction in the first half of 2010. One thing that's under our control is the certification process for that. And this certification we are trying to give &#x2013; to get as much as fast as possible a fair evaluation assessment of the value of the barrels but there is something that we have no complete control and we have no control actually whatsoever that is the timing of the Brazilian Congress.</p>
          <p>Given the regulations, next please, given the regulation and the assumption, not the assumption but the fact is that the government requires fast-track process in the Congress like now in the Senate and all the bills are already approved in lower house, House of Representatives, and it's now in the upper house in the Brazilian Senate. They have 45 days for beginning the voting of the projects. If everything is according to the regulation, by the first week of June we are going to have the projects approved. By the first week of June. And this would mean that we are going to have June and July to prepare the corporate procedures to guarantee the capitalization in the first half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Next please. The market right now, we have at end of 2009, we had recovered the market cap that we had before &#x2013; we had by the end of 2008, we had a very big reduction in our market cap. Today we have increase of 9.6, double the market cap of the company during 2009 in such a way that we are the second biggest market capitalization of the oil companies worldwide.</p>
          <p>In terms of investments, by far we have the largest CapEx comparing to other companies. That's one side gives us some challenges, but on the other hand shows that we have a very good portfolio of opportunities, a good project that can increase the value of the company in the future.</p>
          <p>And we're open to question and I hope that I will have the answers. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. The floor is now open for questions from investors and analysts. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The first question we have comes from Lilyanna Yang of UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Thank you for your presentation. Mr. Gabrielli, you have indicated that you are counting on 15 to 25 billion cash injection from the minority shareholders, so as to be able to carry out the business plan and the spending plan and still keep the leverage below the 0.35 of total capital. So given the high uncertainty of the cash injection coming this year, I'd like to understand, number one, what would be the contractual flexibility you have to cut as opposed to delay part of this R$89 billion CapEx for 2010, for which specific project or which area we could see this spending cuts or postponements?</p>
          <p>And secondly, and more on the refining CapEx, I'd like to understand why for instance the Abreu e Lima refinery, you just committed to have a cost that is twice as much the cost of the refinery of similar complexity in the U.S. or Europe? I might be missing something so I just wanted to understand if maybe it was related to infrastructure or something else? And maybe even the Maua and Araucaria refinery seems to be a bit higher in terms of cost versus the international benchmark. So these are my two questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well first, I &#x2013; we have very little flexibility for 2010 because most of the investment for 2010 is already ongoing investment that we have in the contracts. We have to deal with this reality and which means that we need the capitalization in 2010. That's a very important thing to highlight. We need the capitalization in 2010. If we are going to have a capitalization with the transfer of rights, production rights, or not that's another thing but we need the capitalization for 2010, that's a very important thing.</p>
          <p>We are working right now with the hypothesis that we are going to have the capitalization with the transfer of rights for production from the government. But we have to consider also the possibility of not to have the transfer. That's the first thing. The second thing is on the refinery costs, we are finishing the numbers. If you have the numbers, please tell me because we don't finish it, we don't have them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We got the numbers from <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, if you have them, that's another thing. But we are finishing the numbers and for sure that's something that we have to take into consideration on a qualitative basis. For example, most of the assessment of the cost of refineries is a kind of plug and play refinery in which you go, produce the refinery and plug to the infrastructure. And that's it. This is not our case. We have to develop part of the infrastructure within the project of the refinery. Power generation, power distribution, the utilization of residuals, transportation, some things that are necessary to build, the offsite of our refineries are bigger than the offsite of those international traditional companies.</p>
          <p>These are important things to consider because the choice of a new refinery outside of the infrastructure existing today, have several important reasons. One is the environmental reason. The other is the marketing type of decision because our refineries that have been planned to be built are in the Northeastern of Brazil, north of Brazil, they have a market that we don't have enough capacity today for refining in those markets, and also they have a competitive advantage to be near, closer to the U.S., the Central America and the European markets. And this means that we have to pay to consider this difference.</p>
          <p>But, I'm talking about the qualitative type of numbers, I don't have the quantitative right now to give you, because we are in the finish of our process. And all people that are around me here, they've told me that they don't have &#x2013; haven't finished the numbers. If you have them, I would like to know them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was very helpful. Thank you. And if I may follow up just wanting to understand the answer to the number one, so Petrobras or you would consider a regular capital increase without the 5 billion acquisition or the private equity transaction for this year right? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now we are taking only one possibility, that's the capitalization with the transfer of rights together with the capitalization. If it's not possible then we have to decide and have to take it into consideration with other alternatives.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question we have comes from Ricardo Cavanagh with Raymond James. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes good morning and, Mr. Gabrielli, many thanks for the presentation. I have basically two questions. The first one being a non-Brazilian, my interest would be how factual is the premise that Congress should approve the capitalization in the first half of the year in order to pass it in 2010 and not avoid going into 2011? And the second is assuming the capitalization does not go through this year, do you estimate that debt to capitalization will stay within the 35% maximum level that you target? And if it's surpassed, what would be the company's approach knowing your objective to, well, to stay within investment grade category? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I assume that you are not American too, because the Americans also has a long term for discussion of the health plan in the Congress, the U.S. Congress, not a Brazilian case only.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. I am not American.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But what we think is that the government is requiring a fast-track process in the Brazilian Senate. This is what the government can do, the executive. The Brazilian Congress has its own rituals and its own timing but they cannot commit themselves with the time horizon of 45 days for beginning the evaluation. This is the beginning of the voting process. This doesn't mean that the vote is going to finish in 45 days. And really it's very, it's almost impossible to forecast exactly what's going to happen. But the government is strongly committed to get the voting beginning in 45 days. The result is going to be a public process, then this is the cost of democracy.</p>
          <p>In terms of debt capitalization, right now, in the first quarter of this year we are working with the capitalization process. If we cannot get then we have to decide what to do. Right now we have only the plan to take into consideration the capitalization in the first half of 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough and thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question we have comes from Frank McGann with Bank of America. Please go ahead. Again the next question we have comes from Frank McGann with the Bank of America. Hello Mr. McGann?</p>
          <p>We are proceeding to the next question. [Operation Instructions] The next question we have comes from Marcus Sequeira with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning everyone. Good morning, Mr. Gabrielli. Two questions, first one is that possible that capitalization happening &#x2013; if it happens without the 5 billion barrels, could mean that the government will subscribe with bonds and then receive the barrels only maybe in the second half or when the capitalization is finally approved or you would be considering doing a secondary offering? And second on Tupi, you said that you expect the pilot platform to be up and running in October. And if you give me a bit more clarification on when do you expect the production and how many wells you expect to connect &#x2013; producing wells, you expect to connect this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I cannot talk on behalf of the government. We'll have to decide what to do, if we do something like that, capitalization without the transfer of rights. I can't &#x2013; I'm not comment on that. I am talking &#x2013; we are working with the hypothesis that we are going to have the capitalization with the transfer of rights &#x2013; production rights. That's our main scenario and that's the scenario that we working through the first semester of this year &#x2013; the first half of this year.</p>
          <p>In relation to the Tupi pilot, the production system has 100,000 barrels a day, for sure it's not going to begin with 100,000 barrels a day, but we are going to begin production &#x2013; well that's December, the challenging target is October according to our <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, if I could just follow up on the first question, is &#x2013; in your opinion, is that &#x2013; isn't that too risky to have a CapEx program of that size with little flexibility and counting on assumption that is out of control of the company. And do you see the risk to your balance sheet if situation &#x2013; if things don't happen according to your plan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, risk is part of the business, right? And we are &#x2013; we think that we have a risk assessment that allow us to take the decision, we have announced R$88.6 billion for investment 2010. We don't finish &#x2013; we didn't finish yet our plan for 2010, 2014, we have flexibility in that. And we are saying that this R$88.5 billion for 2010 requires a capitalization between 15 &#x2013; that's cash contribution of capitalization of 15 to $25 billion. That's the number that we are working in the first half of 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question we have comes from Mr. McGann with Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good afternoon. Thank you very much. Just a quick question, the CapEx estimate, I just wanted to confirm that and you mentioned that it's adjusted for the possible capitalization. Does that mean that it does include any expected spending for 2010 to 2014 related to the 5 billion barrels? And then my second question would be in terms of the refined product pricing, granted that you want to keep prices over time in line with international prices, does that mean even though you have a premium today and even that persists, it's unlikely that you would lower prices during the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat, Frank, the second question, because I could not get your question, the second one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeas, yeah, I apologize. Related to the refined product pricing, given that prices have stayed above international prices for quite a long time up until now, is it possible you could rate lower prices and make some adjustment in prices for gasoline and diesel between now and the end of the year or do you think that's unlikely even if the gap remains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What are the forward costs of the gasoline and diesel today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I don't have that right in front of me, right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That will give us the first question and then I go to the second one. No, we are not taking into consideration any investment for the 5 billion barrels in our CapEx right now. The range between 200 and $220 is without taking into consideration the 5 billion barrels. If we get with the capitalization, it's important for &#x2013; in terms of cash generation because we need to increase the capitalization as a source of cash for our investment, but not in terms of investment for total debt.</p>
          <p>For sure, if we're going for the capitalization with the transfer of rights, we have incorporated in our business plan the development and investment necessary for the 5 billion barrels. But right now, in the range of 200 and 220 we don't have any investments for the 5 billion barrels of transfer of rights that are under consideration.</p>
          <p>In terms of the pricing and refining product price, we follow the international price backward and forward, which means that we cannot consider only the short run behavior of the price, we have to have some expectation of what's going to happen in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question we have comes from Alejandro Luciano of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's actually Eduardo Vieira. Can you provide guidance on your expected &#x2013; on financing plan for your five year CapEx coming from bonds, external bonds, how much do you have &#x2013; do you expect to &#x2013; do you plan to issue in external bonds in the next five years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are going to announce this as soon as we finish our investment plan for the next five years. We have right now only big general guidelines that we are going to invest between 200 and $220 billion but we are going to have debt to &#x2013; net debt to equity to EBITDA ratio of maximum 2.5 times. And that we are going to keep our leverage ratio between 25 and 35%. That's a number that we have right now. I don't have the financial plan completely outlined and detailed as you want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Do you have a guidance for 2010 in terms of planned bond issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. For sure, most of our financing in the historical has &#x2013; is through the bond issuance. But we don't know exactly how it's going to be like our needs for the future, because we didn't finish our investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you don't have a range, broad range for financing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not for financing. We have a range for investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question we have comes from Gustavo Gattass of BTG Pactual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gabrielli. I have two quick questions, the first one, just so that I understand and again I know that this may be mixing and matching new and old plans, but when you put in slide 21 the simulation for where your net debt to capital would go, could you just tell us if the assumptions as far as oil production goes are still the ones that you used in the old business plan or have they also been changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's been changing &#x2013; it's not been changed, we are changing this. We are just in the project right now and that's the reason why we don't have a completed picture to tell you right now. We are right now under several people working exactly on those numbers right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But the slide was created with a number that's different than what we used &#x2013; what we have at least. If we try to back calculate it, should we use the old model or is that a different number, that's really where I was trying to get?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's probably going to be a little bit different from the old numbers that you have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. The second question that I have, Gabrielli, when thinking about, I'd say the plans for the future, Frank asked a little bit earlier and the impression I got is we're going to have no change in fuel prices right now. But when you're going for the capital increase, and when you are thinking about the five year plan, are you still going to be thinking about parity between the average realization price and the U.S. realization price in your models or is the approach going to be different now that that you have, I'd say, more upgraded refineries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a seven-year track record already that you can look at that and you can see that in the last seven years we are keeping a kind of parity, not in the short run but in the long run you keep some relation between the Brazilian price and international price. But not in the short run and you have seven years of track record.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Does that &#x2013; if we look at that track record and apologies for extending this, but if we look at that track record, there is a historical spread that your refineries are supposed to be getting. Do you know how much that changes with the upgrades you're doing this year and next? Should we think about $1 more than what you had in the past? Should we think about $2 more or is that not something that's quantifiable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gustavo, you model is very, very good at fine tuning, but remember that we have some I would say structural brakes in the markets that are important. The behavior of the spread of heavy and light has been changing very much. Second, we are changing our structure of our output. For example, we are producing more diesel than we produced before. Third, the demand of, for example, jet fuel has been increasing more than the others. Fourth, we don't have a very clear idea of what's going to happen with ethanol in the market. How can you use only the track record in the past and then the put a one or $2 on that, you have to consider more complex models, I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Will do. Thank you then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question we have comes from Subhojit Daripa with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mr. Gabrielli, I wanted to go back to slide number 21. I just wanted to understand this clearly. If I look at these two scenarios, I see that the CapEx goes up as a function, I think, also related to oil prices 64 to $77. There's going to be cost inflation and that's going to require a higher spending from $220 billion. Now if I take the forward curve, okay, just take that as an example, if assume let's say a $90, 85-$90, I wanted to know if my analysis is correct. Would you have to disburse more &#x2013; maybe 250, 270 whatever it is, that would be fair, right? And therefore the company would have to require more cash coming from minority shareholders just to keep the leverage ratio under 35%. Is that &#x2013; is this analysis accurate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that if I could read the table I would recommend you to read line-by-line and not column by column, because really why don't we are talking about the 15 to 25, this doesn't mean that 15's associated with 200 and 25 is associated with 220. Nor when we are talking about 64 and $74 per barrel, we are not associating to 200 and 220. Each line is independent. We have a range of minority shareholder participation between 15 and 25. We have a range of investment between 200 and 220, that's not strongly related to the average price,  Brent price. Has some connection but it's not strongly related to it. Other reason why we have this 200, 220 and this gives us the leverage ratio between 27 and 32 and between 1.6 and 2.2 is line by line, not column by column.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay fine, fine. Just one last thing, just to be clear here. This is not assuming that any of the cash being injected by minority shareholders is going to the federal government?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, this is to Petrobras.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So this is a net for Petrobras?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Net for Petrobras.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the net, right, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It may assume the possibility of part of this cash going to &#x2013; from minority shareholders being used to let's say pay the federal government for the transfer rights?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no, no, this is cash is to Petrobras and Petrobras is going to invest. The $200 billion or $220 billion, not considering expending any resource for the 5 billion. If we are going to have the 5 billion, then we have to add the investment necessary for the 5 billion barrels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a related question to the 5 billion barrels, Mr. Gabrielli, are you expecting to incorporate the development of the 5 billion barrels in the new strategic plan? That's going to be far off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You are going to incorporate that, so that's likely to be incorporated in the production targets to be unveiled by the company in the strategic plan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I don't know if you can have &#x2013; physically possible to have production 2010 to 2014 that's another thing. In our plan we have to incorporate the investment but I don't know if we can get production because I don't know where we are going to get the 5 billion barrels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, perfect. Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you ladies and gentlemen. There are no further questions at this time. Mr. Gabrielli, please proceed with your closing remarks, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much for everybody. I would like to thank you all attendance here in Rio that had very good questions that I hope that I could give some answer to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir, for your time. Ladies and gentlemen, your host is making today's conference available for replay starting one hour from now. You may access this replay at the company's IR website at www.petrobras.com.br/ri/ing. This concludes Petrobras's conference call for today. We thank you very much for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>