<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1225061" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>405</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jon Moeller, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Teri L. List, Senior Vice President and Treasurer</participant>
      <participant id="3">John Faucher</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jon Moeller</participant>
      <participant id="5">A.G. Lafley</participant>
      <participant id="6">William Schmitz</participant>
      <participant id="7">Bill Pecoriello</participant>
      <participant id="8">Lauren Lieberman</participant>
      <participant id="9">Wendy Nicholson</participant>
      <participant id="10">Joseph Altobello</participant>
      <participant id="11">Christopher Ferrara</participant>
      <participant id="12">Andrew Sawyer</participant>
      <participant id="13">William Chappell</participant>
      <participant id="14">Jason Gere</participant>
      <participant id="15">Linda Weiser</participant>
      <participant id="16">Ali Dibadj</participant>
      <participant id="17">Alice Longley</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to Procter &amp; Gamble's quarter end conference call. Today's discussion will include a number of forward-looking statements. If you will refer to P&amp;G's most recent 10-K, 10-Q, and 8-K reports, you will see a discussion of factors that could cause the company's actual results to differ materially from these projections.</p>
          <p>As required by Regulation G, P&amp;G needs to make you aware that during the call, the company will make a number of references to non-GAAP and other financial measures. Management believes these measures provide investors valuable information on the underlying growth trends of the business. Organic refers to reported results excluding the impacts of acquisitions and divestitures and foreign exchange where applicable. Free cash flow represents operating cash flow less capital expenditures. P&amp;G has posted on its website, www.pg.com, a full reconciliation of non-GAAP and other financial measures.</p>
          <p>Now I will turn the call over to P&amp;G's Chief Financial Officer, Jon Moeller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and good morning everyone. A.G. Lafley, our CEO, and Teri List, our Treasurer, join me this morning. I'll begin with a summary of third quarter results. Teri will cover business highlights by operating segment. I'll then outline our priorities before updating guidance. Following the call Teri, Mark Erceg, John Chevalier, and I will be available to provide additional perspective as needed.</p>
          <p>We had a good third quarter in light of a very difficult macro economic environment. We continued to grow organic sales despite shrinking global GDP and rising unemployment, and importantly maintained global value shares. Organic sales were up 1%. Diluted net earnings per share were $0.84. This was towards the high end of our guidance range of 0.78 to $0.86 per share. Core earnings per share was up 8% versus year ago. Excluding foreign exchange, earnings per share grew strong double digits. Operating margin was up 30 basis points as cost savings, productivity efforts, and price increases more than offset volume deleverage, higher commodity costs, and about 60 basis points of incremental Folgers restructuring charges.</p>
          <p>We had a strong cash quarter, generating $3.5 billion in free cash flow or 136% of earnings. Our free cash flow target for the year remains at or above 90% of earnings excluding the non cash Folgers gain. Earlier this month we increased our quarterly dividend by 10% from $0.40 to $0.44 per share. This is the 119th consecutive year since we have incorporated as a company in 1890 that we have paid a dividend and the 53rd consecutive year the dividend has been raised. This is notable in a year when many companies will fail to increase or even eliminate their dividends.</p>
          <p>We also continue to repurchase shares. Fiscal year to-date we've repurchased $6.3 billion of P&amp;G stock. We've purchased 16.3 billion of stock since the July 2007 inception of our three-year stock repurchase program. Most important, we've continued to invest in innovation, commercialization, capabilities and capacity. We continue to introduce new products and expand into new markets. We continue to focus on bringing value to consumers' lives. We're making decisions today with an eye toward what will make us stronger tomorrow. This is the hallmark of our company, one that has thrived for over 170 years.</p>
          <p>While results are good in this environment they are below our long-term targets of 4 to 6% organic sales and double-digit earnings per share growth. Let me explain why this is and how we think about it. Our long-term financial model is fairly straightforward; most of you know it well. Top-line growth is comprised of three to four points of market growth and one to two points of share growth mix and white space expansion. Combined with operating margin expansion of 50 to 75 basis points this drives double-digit earnings per share growth.</p>
          <p>There are four important assumptions in this long-term model that are causing deviations in the near term. The first is market growth, market growth rates have declined in both developed and developing markets driven by increases in unemployment, reductions in household wealth, consumer credit issues, and fear. Our categories in aggregate are growing but they are growing one to two points below the 3 to 4% assumed in our sustainable growth model. We expect that to continue until a broad-based global economic recovery takes hold.</p>
          <p>The second assumption that is implicit in the model is constant trade inventories. Credit and pricing dynamics drove reduction of inventories at some retailers, distributors and wholesalers. We saw the impact of this in both the October-December and January-March quarters in developed and in developing markets. This had an additional negative short term impact on sales.</p>
          <p>A third assumption is a stable commodity environment. This clearly has not done the case this fiscal year. Year-to-year net commodity impacts remain at about $2 billion. Over time we are able to recover about 75% of higher commodity costs through pricing, but this pricing can lead to near term share volatility when we are the first manufacturer to price across markets and categories.</p>
          <p>The fourth important assumption over a long period of time is stable foreign exchange. As we talked previously we've witnessed dollar strengthening that is unprecedented in amount, breadth and speed. This has had a significant impact on our top and our bottom-line.</p>
          <p>We price to recover the transaction impact of currency which impacts every company in the market. The translation impact which is negative for US-based companies but neutral or even positive for non-US competitors passes through to the bottom-line. Currently these impacts are meaningful. Absent foreign exchange impacts, our third quarter earnings would have been up strong double digits.</p>
          <p>While these short-term macroeconomic fluctuations are important, they don't guide the majority of our actions which are focused on the fundamentals we know are critical to long-term success in our industry, fundamentals like superior consumer value, innovation, cost and cash discipline and productivity improvement. Focusing on these items and funding them will allow us to maximize results in both the mid and long-term and will have a much more enduring impact on our business than short-term trade, commodity or FX volatility. I will talk more about this towards the end of the call.</p>
          <p>The last thing I want to address before turning the presentation over to Teri is volume. Organic volume declined 5% in the quarter. This was driven by retailer destocking, foreign exchange related pricing in developing markets and market contraction in more discretionary categories.</p>
          <p>We've already spend a fair amount of time on FX transaction impacts in past conversations but I want to revisit it one more time because absent a clear understanding of this dynamic it is very hard to put current volume trends in context. Currency markets impact commodity costs because many of the commodities we purchase can only be bought in dollars. So, when local currencies devalue, commodities increase in local currency terms.</p>
          <p>The example I will use is fluff pulp, which is used in Baby and Feminine care products. Recently the dollar cost of fluff pulp has come down 7% versus a year ago. Because fluff pulp is priced primarily in dollars and Latin American currencies in aggregate have devalued by about 25% since July 1st, fluff pulp is up &#x2013; is actually up 18% in these markets in dollar terms. In places like Russia and the Ukraine where currencies have devalued 30 or even 40% the cost of fluff pulp is up even more in local currency terms.</p>
          <p>If not addressed these commodity cost increases can quickly comprise the structural economics of a business. If we don't price to recover the transaction impact of foreign exchange our ability to fund investments, innovation and market growth would be greatly diminished.</p>
          <p>Price increases of this magnitude can have a fairly dramatic short-term impact on volume. Retailers and distributors reduce the volume of the inventory they are carrying to managing overall dollars. Consumers reduce pantry inventory and consumption. Volume decreases in developing markets where currencies have devalued account for over 40% of the volume decline on the quarter. All our years of experience managing through these types of situations across a wide range of emerging markets have taught us that well painful, pricing to protect the structural economics of our business is the right thing to do.</p>
          <p>Market size reductions in more discretionary categories also had a large impact on volume. For us, this includes fragrances, salon hair care and Braun appliances. These three businesses accounted for 20% of the organic volume decline on the quarter. While these discretionary categories may be out of favor in the short-term, we take a longer term view. 25 of the last 100 years in the United States have been characterized by some form of recession. 75 years have been characterized by expansion. Our objective is to design portfolios to win in years that represent 75% of scenarios, not 25.</p>
          <p>I'll make two points in the way of summary. First, the choices we are making on pricing, on portfolio, on investments and innovation, on consumer value and productivity are guided by what will allow us to win sustainably over the long term. Second, we are confident in our long term prospects and are reasonably pleased with our short term results. We are growing, organic sales, earnings per share and cash. We are maintaining value shares and we are making investments in innovation, commercialization, capabilities, and capacity.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the call over to Teri.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jon. Starting with the Beauty segment, organic sales were in line with prior year as the benefits from higher pricing were largely offset by a 5% decline in shipment volume. There are a couple of key factors driving these results. First, there are elements of the segment that are more discretionary compared to the balance of our portfolio. As Jon mentioned, the global economic slowdown caused a significant market contraction in the prestige fragrance category. While we continued to build share in prestige, shipments were down more than 20% due mainly to significant market contraction and trade inventory destocking. The volume decline in prestige accounted for over 40% of the organic volume decline in Beauty.</p>
          <p>Beauty shipments were also negatively affected by retailer and distributor destocking mainly in the Central and Eastern Europe, Middle East and Africa region following price increases taken to offset the impacts of foreign exchange rate movement on our local cost structure.</p>
          <p>Beauty shipments in the CEEMEA region were down high teens versus the same quarter last year and accounted for nearly half of the volume losses for the Beauty segment. Looking across the categories, P&amp;G's global retail hair care business grew value share by nearly a point to about 26% of the global market. In the US, retail hair care all-outlet value share was up about half a point. Value shares for Pantene, Head &amp; Shoulders, Herbal Essences and Aussie were all roughly in line with prior year with the net share gain due to the addition of the Gillette Hair Care brand.</p>
          <p>In US Hair Color, Nice 'n Easy value share is up nearly two share points versus prior year, behind the premium priced Perfect 10 initiative, which is more than offsetting declines in minor hair color brands.</p>
          <p>Skin Care organic volume declined mid-single digits following price increases in the North America and CEEMEA regions, and trade inventory reductions in response to slowing market growth in China. Encouragingly, P&amp;G's global value share of the facial skin care market was up nearly a point to more than 12% behind the continued expansion of Olay in developing markets. Olay all-outlet value share of facial moisturizers in the US also increased about half a point this quarter to over 43% behind the launch of Olay Pro-X. Pro-X which retails for 40 to $50 per item has achieved about 5% value share after only three months in the market. For perspective, this makes Pro-X comparable in size to some of the entire brand franchises we compete with. In addition SK-II, P&amp;G's premium skin care brand, grew shipments high-single digits this quarter behind innovation in facial treatment essences.</p>
          <p>The antiperspirant and deodorants business was particularly strong this quarter with shipments up mid-single digits. Growth on the Secret, Old Spice, and Gillette brands was driven by the continued success of the clinical strength and professional strength initiatives, plus several new product and commercial innovations on Secret they are launched this quarter. Secret all-outlet value share in the US is up half a point to more than 16% of the market.</p>
          <p>In the US Color Cosmetics business our market-leading Cover Girl brand build all-outlet value share on both a unit and value basis in a category that was essentially flat with prior years. However Cover Girl shipments were down high single digits this quarter due to sharp retailer destocking.</p>
          <p>To summarize Beauty, we continue to be pleased with the fundamental health of our beauty brand and their growth prospects over time. We do expect some continued pressure from retailer and distributor destocking. It's also likely that the market for Prestige Fragrances will remain soft given its discretionary nature. On the positive side we continue to see strength in our premium beauty offering such as Olay Pro-X, Secret Clinical Strength, Nice &amp; Easy Perfect 10, and Gucci Fine Fragrance, reinforcing the importance of delivering a continuous stream of leading innovations as well as having brand portfolios that can serve the needs of a wide range of consumers at multiple price points.</p>
          <p>In Grooming, market contractions and inventory reduction significantly impacted shipments resulting in a 4% organic sales decline. These impacts were particularly acute in Braun, where shipments were down more than 20%. These products are considered to be more discretionary in tight economic times particularly in developing markets.</p>
          <p>In Blades and Razors volume declined high single digits, as Fusion shipments increased high single digits were more than offset by double-digit decline in legacy systems. The growth of the flagship Fusion brand was led by Western Europe with shipments up double-digits and in Japan with volume up more than 30%. Fusion value share in the US was up about 3 points versus prior year and is now over 29% of male blades and razors. P&amp;G's past three months value share of all male blades and razors is now over 70%. Fusion is also building share outside the US. In Western Europe, Fusion share is up nearly four points to about 23%.</p>
          <p>In female blades and razors, Venus shipments were down mid-singles globally and in the US however the brand build unit and value share in the US over the past three months. Again retailer destocking and market size contraction on a unit basis reconcile these diverging trends.</p>
          <p>In Health Care, organic sales were down 2% behind soft results in Personal Health Care and lower shipment volume of Oral Care and Fem Care in the CEEMEA region following FX driven price increases.</p>
          <p>As expected, Prilosec OTC continues to be impacted by the loss of market exclusivity in March of 2008. Personal Health Care top line results were also negatively affected by one of the mildest cold and flu seasons in years according to the US Center for Disease Control and Prevention. This led to a significant contraction of the respiratory care market. As a result, Vicks shipments were down 20% in the US for the quarter. However P&amp;G's all-outlet share of the US respiratory care market was inline with prior year on both a unit and value basis.</p>
          <p>Oral Care volume declined low single digits as double-digit growth for Oral-B in Western Europe driven by strong power toothbrush growth was offset by lower shipments in the CEEMEA region following foreign exchange driven price increases. Trade inventory reductions in markets like Russia and Turkey led to a mid-teens reduction in shipments in the region.</p>
          <p>Oral Care volume in North America was down mid singles due mainly to soft power toothbrush shipments and market contractions in the tooth whitening segment. In the US toothpaste market Crest increased its all-outlet value share leadership growing to nearly 38% of the market. Crest Pro-Health continues to be the primary driver of Crest share gains in the US. Additionally initial results of our recent introductions of Oral-B toothpaste into Benelux and Brazil are off to a solid start in the first few months in the market.</p>
          <p>Feminine Care volume declined low single digits due almost entirely to market impacts in CEEMEA following our FX driven price increases. In the US P&amp;G delivered solid market share performance across the Always pads and liners and Tampax tampon segments. P&amp;G's all-outlet value share of the US Fem Care category grew half a point to over 51%. Always Infinity, which launched last fall, is delivering good results in the US pad market with market share of 6%. We are continuing to support the initiative with strong value messages and trial incentives to drive conversion to this revolutionary new product in Feminine Care protection. Repeat rates have exceeded expectations, as consumers who have tried Always Infinity have recognized the value created by this breakthrough technology.</p>
          <p>For the Snacks and Pet Care segment, organic sales grew 2% led by Pet Care with strong growth, which more than offset a modest decline in Snacks. Significant pricing actions in both businesses offset a mid-single digit volume decline in the segment. The decline in Snacks volume is due mainly to a strong base period that included the Rice Infusion initiative in Western Europe and the Extreme Flavors launch in North America. Shipments were also affected by trade inventory adjustments in advance of the Pringles Superstack initiative that launched late in the quarter, which included a double digit price increase.</p>
          <p>Iams US value share was roughly in line with prior year levels at about 8%. Recent Iams innovation such as Proactive Health, Healthy Naturals, and Premium Protection continue to deliver results at or ahead of expectations. Eukanuba volume declined high single digits and market share declined resulting from the price increases implemented last calendar.</p>
          <p>Turning to Fabric and Home Care segment, organic sales grew 3% as the benefits from price increases more than offset volume declines. In the majority of cases, globally price gaps are starting to return to levels similar to those prior to our price increases. We are continuing to monitor the relative consumer value of our brands and we will take targeted actions where necessary to restore consumer value to competitive levels. Fabric Care shipments were down mid-single digits, primarily due to lower shipments of Tide and Ariel. Volume declines in these brands were most pronouncing the CEEMEA region with both brands down double-digits following foreign exchange driven price increases taken during the March quarter.</p>
          <p>Tide volume declined high single-digits in the US and all-outlet value share was down 3 points to 38% due to significantly higher price gaps versus competitive brands compared to prior year. The Gain brand delivered a strong quarter with shipments up mid-singles and all-outlet value share up a point to nearly 16%.</p>
          <p>Home Care shipments declined low single digits due mainly to declines in Dish Care and Hard Surface Cleaning Solutions. Dish Care shipments in the US were down due to unit-based market contraction following significant price increases last year. P&amp;G's leading US Dish Care all-outlet value share was down slightly and remained above 54% with Cascade about 61% in auto dish and Dawn at 43% in hand dish.</p>
          <p>The Swiffer and Febreze brands both grew volume for the quarter, Swiffer volume in the US was up mid singles and all-outlet value share increased a point and half to 16% driven by innovations across all Swiffer items including upgrades to both the dry and wet refill products and packaging and implement design.  Febreze volume was up in Western Europe behind continued geographic expansion.  In the US, Febreze volume was inline with prior year in a category that declined 9% in units.  The resulting all-outlet value share gains in the US included more than a 5 point gain in instant air fresheners and more than a two point gain in candles.</p>
          <p>Battery shipments were down high single digits due to market size and share challenges in both developed and developing markets.  Share for the Duracell brand was impacted by trade downs to value in retailer brands and heavy competitive activity in Western Europe.</p>
          <p>In the US, Duracell's all outlet value share of alkaline batteries declined two points to 44%.  In Western Europe, Duracell's share of general purpose batteries was down three points to 33%.  In developing markets battery shipments were down mid-teens in the CEEMEA and Latin America region due to the soft market following price increases.</p>
          <p>Baby and Family Care delivered solid organic sales growth of 6%.  Volume was inline with prior year and the net benefits from higher pricing accounted for the sales growth in the quarter.  Global Baby Care shipments grew low single digits behind solid growth in North America and Western Europe; developing market shipments were down slightly versus prior year following increases in Latin America &#x2013; following price increases in Latin America.</p>
          <p>In the US, P&amp;G's Baby Care business grew shipments mid-singles, behind low teens growth of Luvs.  The Pampers brand also grew shipments in the US for the quarter.  P&amp;G's overall share of US Diapers increased about a half point over 35% behind the growth of the Luvs brand and Pampers share was inline with prior year.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, Pampers grew low single-digits behind strong consumer response to the UNICEF Vaccine Partnership campaign and the successful launch of Pampers Simply Dry in Germany.  Simply Dry, a tier three version of Pampers, has helped the overall Pampers brand to grow share by four points to 59% in the highly competitive German market.  Pampers value share of the total Western European diaper market is up more than a point to nearly 55%.</p>
          <p>Family Care volume declined low-single digits as growth of Bounty was offset by a decline of Charmin primarily due to a high base period that included the Charmin Ultra Strong initiative.  Bounty added nearly a point to its market leading US all-outlet value share, which is now above 46%.  While Charmin US value share declined about half of a point, Charmin continues to be the clear market leader with all-outlet share of nearly 28%.  That concludes the business segment review and I'll now hand the call back to Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Teri.  During the last earnings call and more recently at CAGNY we discussed in some details the priorities we've established to guide our near-term efforts and decisions.  Broadly speaking these three areas are building consumer value, accelerating investments in the future and driving productivity and simplification even further.</p>
          <p>Before moving to guidance, let me take a few moments to provide more detail on these priorities.  Consumer value is about more than price and is defined differently by different consumers.  Some consumers have a larger price component to their value equation.  For those consumers, we're offering more products in lower price tiers than any point in our history.</p>
          <p>We've talked previously about Gain in Fabric Care, Luvs in Baby Care, and Charmin and Bounty Basic in Family Care, all of which are growing disproportionately in this environment.  But the balance of our product portfolio also has lower price offerings.  For example, Olay offers a very good basic Skin Care product in Olay Complete Ageless for $7. And Crest offers excellent basic toothpaste in Crest Cavity Protection at $2 for a 6.4 ounce tube.</p>
          <p>We remain committed to offering cost conscious consumers a broader range of choices.  As Teri said, last month we introduced a tier three baby diaper into Germany called Pamper Simply Dry.  It is off to a strong start already having achieved a 4% market share, and just this past week we launched Naturella which is a mid-tier Feminine Care product into the Arabian Peninsula, which will further extend our leadership position there.</p>
          <p>Other consumers have a larger performance component to their value equation.  These consumers are delighted by Olay Pro-X, which is priced at about $50.  As we've mentioned Olay Pro-X has achieved with 5% market share after only 12 weeks in market.  Tide Total Care despite being priced at a 30% premium is on pace to deliver 120 to 150 million in year one sales.  Always Infinity is priced at a 60% premium but has already received 6% value share.  Crest Whitestrips Advanced Seal was launched at the end of January at a retail price point of about $40 and is already the number one SKU in the whitening category with over a 20% value share.  We will continue to extend the portfolio at the top and bottom as part of our objective to deliver better value and serve more of the world's consumers.</p>
          <p>As we focus on delivering value that is relevant to specific consumers, we are investing and communicating that value through performance-based value messaging at all touch points.  This helps consumers clearly understand the price and performance trade-offs they are making.</p>
          <p>We routinely assess value versus competitive offerings, via weighted purchase intent and price gap analysis.  There are always situations where adjustments are needed to maintain competitiveness and relative value, but broadly we are pleased with the relative value equation of our brands.  About two thirds of our brands have weighted purchase intent advantages and we continue to hold global value share, which is another important indicator of value competitiveness.</p>
          <p>Investing for the future is another top priority.  Our commitment to innovation as an example has never been stronger. R&amp;D spending is nearly two times that of our closest competitor and more than most competitors combined.  This leadership level of investment is multiplied by our extensive connect and development effort, which leads to an effective spend that far exceeds reported figures.  Olay Pro-X, Dawn Hand Renewal, Pantene Nature Fusions, Tide Total Care and Clairol Perfect 10 are all examples of recent innovations that have benefited from connect and develop.</p>
          <p>In the case of our Perfect 10, P&amp;G collaborated with 12 external partners in the US, the UK, and Russia.  These collaborations led to three separate breakthrough innovations that have directly contributed to Perfect 10 success.  Perfect 10 achieved a 4% value share since launch despite selling at a 70% price premium to base Nice 'n Easy, which is now the leading color brand in the United States.</p>
          <p>We continue to be the innovation leader in our industry not just as measured by spending, but as measured by results.  Each year IRI publishes a New Product Pacesetter report.  This US-based study captures the most successful new CPG products as measured by sales over the past year.</p>
          <p>For 2008, P&amp;G share of the non-food category was 40%, meaning P&amp;G had 10 of the top 25 new product introductions.  By comparison, Unilever, J&amp;J, Kimberly-Clark, Colgate, L'Oreal and Energizer collectively had seven.  Over the past 14 years, P&amp;G has had 114 of the top 25 pacesetters versus 94 for that same combined competitive set.  In fact over this period of time products that were introduced by P&amp;G or Gillette accounted for 50% of all IRI pacesetters.</p>
          <p>Advertising is another area where we are investing at leadership levels.  We see the current economic environment as an opportunity to increase share of voice within our industry, while spending fewer dollars in the absolute.  During the March quarter, while costs were down, global media weights were up 5% versus year ago.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in capital as well.  This year capital spending may slightly exceed our 4% of sales target. We are moving forward with the capacity expansion program we started talking about during last year's back-to-school conference. With almost half of the world 6.8 billion consumers currently using no P&amp;G product, and many of the consumers who do use P&amp;G products being underserved, we believe our long-term growth prospects have never been stronger and are structuring ourselves to support this growth.</p>
          <p>India provides just one example. Just over two years ago we launched Pampers into India. At that time the leading competitor had a 70% value share. Today we are the value share leaders in diapers in India. We are continuing to startup a new diaper line about every three weeks somewhere in the developing world.</p>
          <p>Our most recent new category launch in India was Skin Care, where Olay Total Effects has already gained 6% of the market and doubled the size of the anti-aging category. The potential for P&amp;G in just this one country is astounding. If over time we increased India's per capital consumption just up to the level we currently see in Mexico it would generate an incremental $20 billion in annual sales. These are opportunities we clearly need to support.</p>
          <p>We continue to launch new initiatives in the both developed and developing markets, initiatives that will be future platforms for growth. I've talked about Olay Pro-X and the tier three diaper entry into Germany. We've entered the <mark type="inaudible" /> category behind Oral-B in Holland and Belgium and in the pharmacy channel in Brazil.</p>
          <p>We continue to expand auto dish across Western Europe and Align is off to a great start. After just a couple of weeks in market Align is already the number one probiotic recommended by gastroenterologists for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome.</p>
          <p>The last focus area is a disciplined effort to lower cost, increase productivity and simplify everything we do. This provides fuel to improve consumer value and increase investments in the future. Bob McDonald talked at our analyst meeting in December about the transformational work we are doing to redesign our transportation system. As part of that effort we just executed the single biggest competitive transportation bidding process in P&amp;G's history. This project included over 150 carriers, 7600 freight lanes and over 500 million transportation miles across North America. On an annual basis, road miles will be reduced by more than 10% and intermodal usage will increase by 30%.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, our goal is to increase rail and intermodal transportation from 10 to 30% by 2015 and we're making great progress. Currently, we're on pace to achieve 15% by 2009, one year ahead of schedule. These two transportation transformation activities are generating savings of about $75 million per year, as part of a holistic effort to continue leveraging P&amp;G's supply chain as a competitive advantage for the company.</p>
          <p>Another way we are lowering costs and improving capability is video teleconferencing. We've invested in 50 video collaboration studios around the world, which have already saved over $75 million in travel costs. In addition to saving money, this new capability saves time and builds the business by putting us more in touch with each other, suppliers and retailers. We're now conducting global leadership team meetings with this technology, significantly decreasing travel time and cost.</p>
          <p>I hope this discussion helps you understand with a few concrete examples how we're managing the company and what is guiding our decisions. I hope you'll agree with me that these are the right things to be focused on and the right choices to make, as we work to optimize the long-term prospects of P&amp;G for P&amp;G shareholders.</p>
          <p>Moving to guidance, we expect fiscal '09 organic sales growth between 2 and 3%. Total sales are expected to be down 2 to 4%, driven by a foreign exchange hurt of about 5%. Operating margin including 50 basis points of incremental Folgers restructuring charges should be about flat. We're currently comfortable with consensus GAAP earnings per share of 4.22, as the center point of an earnings per share range of 4.20 to 4.25. This range yields year-on-year core earnings per share growth of 6 to 8%; excluding foreign exchange impacts earnings per share growth will be strong double-digits.</p>
          <p>For the June quarter we expect organic sales growth of between 0 and 3%. Total sales are expected to be down 8 to 12% driven by a foreign exchange hurt of 11 to 12%. Operating margins should be up driven by strong gross margin improvement versus prior year as volume deleveraging is largely offset by the net impact of pricing and commodities. We expect earnings per share to be in the range of 0.74 to $0.79 including the Folgers related restructuring charges.</p>
          <p>In the near term our results will continue to be heavily influenced by external factors discussed previously that are not entirely predictable or within our control, particularly market growth and foreign exchange. We are providing wider guidance ranges to reflect existing volatility. We are committed to do the right things for the business and the shareholders over the mid and long term and will prioritize our choices on this basis.</p>
          <p>We are still engaged in our planning process for 2009-10. We are trying to ensure our plans are built on the most up-to-date relevant assumptions for foreign exchange, commodities and market sizes. We're also spending time on a disciplined look at investment options ensuring that we are investing in the right things for long term.</p>
          <p>Our current priorities, building consumer values, driving productivity and simplification and marking the right investment choices will guide our planning for next year. We will provide full guidance once plans have been finalized.</p>
          <p>A.G., Teri and I would now like to open up the call for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  And your first question comes from the line of John Faucher with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes good morning.  Jon in your last sort of sum up comments there you talked about sort of the algorithm in terms of strong double-digit growth and I guess as you look at a difficult environment out there that means you are capturing a lot of the margin from raw material favorability going forward and the productivity.  And I guess, the issue is why not leave yourselves with a little bit more flexibility, take the lower organic growth and say now is the time to take that extra margin if we're getting it; continue to go after some of the structural issues maybe looking at more rapidly increasing the focus in Latin America and some of the other geographies and categories where you are struggling a little bit.  I understand the commentary about productivity and those things, but is there &#x2013; isn't there an opportunity here given the lower multiple on the stock what have you to really push this aggressively forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a good question John.  Let me just provide a couple of pieces of perspective.  First of all in terms of top-line expectations as we stated for the next quarter we're looking at zero to three, so it's clearly &#x2013; we're accepting growth below our long-term targets.  As I also indicated we are still working on the plans for next year and we'll be back to you with those, but importantly in all of this as I've tried to indicate we are focusing on where we should be investing to bring more value to consumers, to grow the business, to expand the portfolio both up and down and across and geographically.</p>
          <p>So you should assume that we are going to take full advantage, as would be the case in a normal economic environment to expand our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John very quickly good morning.  I mean I think you raised a good point, we had a chance to talk about it briefly, when you were here last time and I am very much looking for the right balance and we worked real hard I think to deliver the right balance this year, where we actually had a couple of big surprises and the biggest surprise of course was currency, which I think we've done a pretty good job of managing, but currency hit us for more than $4 billion in the top-line before the year is out and will hit us for likely well over 1.5 billion on the bottom line. So we have had to manage through all of that.</p>
          <p>But stepping back to the larger question, what we have been doing is stepping up our investment and I think it's really important to understand that.  Our CapEx will likely come in above 4%. We are building 10 new manufacturing plants around the world somewhere, this year including a major new manufacturing plant in Utah to serve our Family Care business.</p>
          <p>Jon took you through the investment in R&amp;D, but if you take out pharma and take out coffee, we have a very solid R&amp;D investment this year and then when you add on top all of the connect and develop investment we get from partners, we are stepping it up on the innovation side. We will bring as bigger portfolio of new products to market as we ever have, over the next year.</p>
          <p>The third one is marketing.  Jon talked about the advertising side of it, we are &#x2013; we have been delivering more GRPs to the market. It's always hard to measure, but we think in a lot of cases we are actually building our shares of voice. And we've also of course had to invest more on the trade side because when you are leading pricing up, there is a lot of price discounting that comes from your competitors in the short term and we have to make sure we manage those value gaps. So, hey step back and generalizing from all of that, the biggest thing in that we're looking at for next year is how much investment and where to make those investments because we have a lot of opportunities for growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bill Schmitz with Deutsche Bank.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey I don't know if I missed it in the prepared comments, but can you just give us the breakdown of growth between developed markets and developing markets?  And then if you could also breakdown the volume, what percentage was from the distributor and retailer inventory destocking and what was just shipment declines or consumption declines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first part of your question, Bill, volume growth was slightly lower in developing markets than developed.  So developed grew just a bit ahead of developing, but not too much difference between the two on the quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of the components of the volume decline versus year ago, as I indicated in my remarks about 40% of that or two points of destocking related to primarily price increases in developing markets.  Another point is related to the market decline in the discretionary categories that we talked about: Fragrance, Hair Salon and Braun and the rest is due to volume as a result of price increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the biggest issue in developing markets was CEEMEA.  And I think that's pretty evident, I mean you just have to look at what's happened to GDP and currencies.  And I think you also know that's our biggest developing market region by far.  I guess the other thing I'd say Bill is we're clearly going to continue to step-up our investments in emerging markets.  We are not scared off by the macroeconomic situation, in fact the ability to create more, better and cheaper products and fill out our portfolios in more of our categories and across more of our leading brands, just gives us the confidence that we can go after more consumers and more households in developing markets and that's where the babies are going to be born, that's where the households are formed, that's where there is sufficient income to begin to buy our household and personal care products on at least a weekly basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bill Pecoriello with Consumer Edge Research.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody.  My question was, you made it clear that there is no broad based value adjustments required in your holding global volume of value share with the 1% organic sales growth, but certain categories where you are losing value share, in certain geographies where you need to make tactical adjustments that you are studying for the investment and with this more couponing, adjusting promotional price points, stepping up the value message, can you talk about some of the categories where your consumer research is showing that you need to step up that value message?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Hey first of all it's all about consumer value and winning the consumer value equation. It all begins in the store at the first moment of truth and frankly every day we are making adjustments in the operating businesses up or down.  Broadly we've made some surgical adjustments on our Family Care business in North America. We are making some tactical adjustments on our Fabric Care business in North America. We led the move to compact detergents in North America and Fabric Care we've led the pricing up in Fabric Care as we reported. We probably lost a little bit more share than we would have liked on Tide and we probably gained a little bit more share than we thought we would on Gain.  So, we are trying -- we'll adjust to get that right.  In developing markets, we have to watch our opening price point, affordability and that's why we've talked about the portfolio. Jon mentioned Naturella, but there are a whole raft of product lines across the categories that we introduce and we have to make sure that opening price point is right.</p>
          <p>So, I mean you are dead right and I tried to make the point, we're not only trying to increase our delivery, ensure a voice in the advertising side, but we've got to stay competitive on the short-term pricing and promotion side.  I mean, in U.S. there has been more couponing, because couponing consumers, they're a segment of consumers that redeem more coupons in recessionary times.  But I view all of that as sort of ongoing value equation management.</p>
          <p>The point I think we're trying to make is that the pricing power and mix power is pretty clear.  And we think we are going to hold on to most of it because what underpins it is innovation. That's really the point.  The six points of pricing and mix this quarter is virtually all underpinned by innovation and to the extent the innovation is resonating with consumers, whether it's more value-based innovation or more performance-based innovation, we'll be able to hold it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lauren Lieberman with Barclays.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.  I was hoping you could talk a little bit about why and for how long you expect the destocking to continue. Because I mean, it seems to me like especially at the distributor level, in inventory adjustments that has to do with the distributor wanting to manage working capital levels as you raised pricing, should sort of be taken care of in the course of one quarter and then from there it really is about consumption and market growth. And everything in the press release and the comments in the call sounded like you are expecting destocking to continue, so a little bit on why and then a little bit on for how long?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  The destocking that we saw in the October-December quarter was largely a developed market dynamic as the price increases hit in the developed market and as we went through the credit crisis in particularly North America, but also Western Europe.  The primary destocking dynamic in the quarter that we just completed was in the developing world and that is driven as we've talked about by very significant price increases, some of which have occurred very recently.</p>
          <p>So as currencies devalue further we've had to price further and some developing markets we've taken two or three rounds of pricing. And that's why we are expecting some level of destocking to continue to work its way through the system.  But you're generally right in that, it should be as a whole of relatively shorter versus a longer term dynamic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if currency stays where it is now or as was at the end of the quarter we'll even say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There would still be a little bit of destocking next quarter, the way the system works in terms of banks notifying distributors that their credit lines are frozen, all that stuff doesn't just follow a nice neat pattern, it takes time to work through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So the assumption is that if currency stays where it was at the end of the quarter, all the pricing is in place even if it went out at the end of the quarter, there should be sort of one quarter left of destocking related to these price increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ceteris parabis, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The world changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well of course.  Okay thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lauren I'd say two quick things, one everybody is trying to operate with less inventory okay.  And I think that's good &#x2013; that's good.  One of the things that I love about the challenges we've had the last year is we're more agile, we're more flexible, we're faster and we're frankly operating better and executing better.  I mean our case fill rates okay, which is what the customers judge our service levels on are running 98.5% for like six months in a row, so we've had to get better on the execution side to make sure we're in stock, even when the retailer and the distributor are pulling down their inventories.</p>
          <p>But the easiest way for them, the easiest way for them to improve in short-term is to pull down their inventory.  It's the distributors that are under real cash and bank line in pressure. In the case of some of our bigger retailers, they pulled it down because it was the end of their fiscal year.  So I think &#x2013; I don't think the inventory destocking is necessarily a bad thing, until you get to the point where you can't maintain shopper service levels and you can't stay in stock.  And we watch that very closely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There will also be, we expect, an ongoing dynamic relative to retailers wanting to have the most efficient assortment on shelves that they can possibly have as another way to manage their cash and maximize their biggest asset, their shelf space.  So you will see that continuing to have an impact for some manufacturers. In fact, we're relatively advantaged in an environment of more efficient assortment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Wendy Nicholson with Citi Investment Research.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi I know you guys care about benchmarking yourself relative to your peers, as much as we do.  And I guess I'm surprised with all your commentary, it sounds like you think you are gaining share in a bunch of big categories and what not, but the declines that you are seeing from a volume growth perspective are a lot worse than we are seeing at any of your competitors, both the US companies and European multinationals or the European HPC guys and I know you think you are a little bit more oriented towards discretionary businesses and so maybe there is more shortfall there, but frankly it sounds like you are doing really well on some of the discretionary business like high-end Skin Care.  So the story of the emerging markets, I just don't know that I get it because some of your competitors have much bigger emerging market businesses and you'd think that destocking would be hurting them more than it would be you.  So it just doesn't kind of hold together from me.  Can you help me with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wendy, you have to do &#x2013; I mean I would be happy to take &#x2013; you have to do industry-by-industry, geography-by-geography, channel and customer by channel and customer.  So why don't &#x2013; it sounds like you have some interest in the discretionary category.  So I will do a couple of those and then if you want to talk about another one I'm happy to go there.</p>
          <p>I mean clearly just one quick comment, clearly it's a good time to have a big business in LA.  We are doing very well in LA.  It's not a good time to have a huge business in Central and Eastern Europe and the Middle-East.  We have the biggest business in Central Eastern Europe and the Middle-East.  So part of this is business and geographic mix.</p>
          <p>But let's do a few of the discretionary categories.  Fine Fragrance is probably the most straightforward one.  It's maybe the most discretionary category that we are in.  We've had double-digit drops in the market and every period we are growing our share. In fact o one of the most successful brands right now in the Fragrance world is Gucci.  So our point of view is we want a very good margin in that business, well above the category.  We have built some very strong brands particularly the Guccis and Dolce Gabbanas to go with the Hugo Bosses and Lacostes and we know it will come back.  So, we're probably looking at the worst period for the Fragrance business and when an industry or when a geography is contracting, what you want to focus on is your value share, right.  So when it starts to grow again, you're growing off a stronger value share base.  So, we have clearly prioritized value share above volume share and we've clearly prioritized net sales growth above volume growth.</p>
          <p>Braun and Salon are slightly different situations and I think there clearly we have something to prove.  We've actually lost a little bit of share in the Salon business.  And we have some ups and downs on our share performance depending on Braun line, but what is frankly enabling us to do is to accelerate and deepen the restructure, so we'll get through with major restructures in those business faster.  We are focusing on where we really want to win in those businesses and we are bringing innovation faster.  So, I think again, it's an opportunity.</p>
          <p>Let me think &#x2013; I was trying to think of a third good example. Clearly, clearly our CEEMEA exposure is showing up on the destocking front.  There have been huge moves in GDP in a lot of those markets and frankly the currency impact has been big.  And the combination of the two, demand softening and the price gaps widening, as we price to cover the transaction cost of FX, means that distributors who run their inventories on a dollar basis or on a local currency basis have to pull those inventories down pretty quickly.  And another point that Jon made in his comments, which I think is really important, you build a distributor network and you build relationships with distributors over time.  So we support these distributors and frankly, we support several of our suppliers and we're willing to help them get their inventories down in the short term, so they can continue to provide the kind of service we want and need.  And then when times get better, which I think inevitably will, we'll move back.</p>
          <p>What we're going through in some of these developing markets is not unlike what we went through in the mid '90s in Asia, when I was there.  You just have big short-term moves in GDP contraction and you have big short-term moves in currency.  And in those environments, you've got to price to cover as much of the transaction as possible and you've got to make sure that you maintain your infrastructure, so when things get better, you'll grow.  But I think it's more our footprint, it's more our mix of categories than it is anything that's really different.</p>
          <p>If you look at what the other best CPG companies are doing, they are doing the same thing.  We're all trying to get five or six points of pricing and mix and we're getting about that every quarter now.  We're all trying to manage the volatility that we're seeing in commodity currency and markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Joe Altobello with Oppenheimer.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks good morning guys.  First question if I could for Jon, let me just go back to your comment you made to Lauren's question on shelf space, it sounds like you've held shelf space pretty stable throughout this whole period here and I was curious are you seeing any changes in categories where retailers are trying to go after market share in terms of private label?  And then secondly for A.G. if I could, the data point you've often talked about in the past for trade down has been unemployment.  Obviously that keeps creeping up and it seems like it's going to continue to creep up for the next six to 12 months, so, in terms of the categories where you've seen the most trade down, how do you sort of combat that in this type of environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will take the first one Joe.  Clearly there are some retailers that are trying to increase their own store brand presence in their stores.  And there are &#x2013; the vast majority of the retailers are working on efficient assortment depending on how they best define it for their shopper.</p>
          <p>In general we have been gaining shelf space, not losing shelf space.  And certain of our brands have actually gained a significant amount of shelf space.  But the question behind the question on private label, I think it is important to address as well.  If you look at markets and chains that are very efficiently assorted and tend to have a higher label &#x2013; a higher presence of store brands. So, for example look at Western Europe paper categories, Baby and Feminine Care which have a very high private label development.  Our market share in those categories and those markets is higher than it is in the US.  If you look at chains like Costco, which have a very strong store brand in Kirklands, or you look at Liedel, a discounter in Western Europe.  Again in those more limited efficient assortment stores, our shares are over-developed.  So, in general the move to more efficient assortment should be a positive thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Joe, I definitely agree with that.  We're as &#x2013; hey here is the key, in every recession back to the 70s, generic or private label brands have grown share.  We know it's going to be happen; it's happening in this recession.  There is some trade down, there is obvious pocketbook pressure and frankly more consumers will try private label brands and retailer brands, than would try them in more normal economic times.  The key is to minimize your losses and ideally continue to hold or continue to grow your share in that environment.</p>
          <p>Where is there the most pressure? Generic drugs. And I think that's likely going to continue. One of the reasons that we are considering an exit from the Pharma businesses, because the Pharma business model, I think has the historical one that's worked so well is in question and frankly that industry is going to be under more pressure from generic drugs.</p>
          <p>Clearly Prilosec, which we built into a phenomenal brand and is still a very strong brand is now going through the phase where the generics are going to be introduced and we know we're going to lose some of that business.  The key is how much of it do we hold on to and how do we sustain it.  And you see it in &#x2013; you see across the OTC drug world. There is a lot of pressure from generics.</p>
          <p>One of the things we like about Beauty, Grooming, and Personal Care is that those all tend to be categories where there is much lower private label development and where for a number of reasons consumers are just not even as interested in trying private labels. In Household, it's a little bit more of a mixed bag, but we tend to have very strong brands in the categories that we are in.  So, if you look at paper towel, Bounty has been growing share and private label has been growing share.</p>
          <p>If you look at Bath Tissue, the strongest brands including Charmin for the most part have been about holding their share and private label has been growing share.  In laundry detergents surprisingly, private labels are more developed in Western Europe, but in the US they're not really that developed. There's been a little bit of growth in this cycle, but there is a still a relatively small part of the market. But stepping back, they will grow during the recession. More consumers will try them because their budget is under pressure. The key is we need to be in a position at the shelf, and then we need to be delivering with our brands and products superior value as Jon described, however the consumer wants that.  And then I hope, if we can at least hold or ideally grow share as we're doing on many of our brands we will come out at the end of the cycle stronger and then we'll build from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Chris Ferrara with Bank of America-Merrill Lynch.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys I understand you're working through this stuff now and I get you building a portfolio for the 75% of the time that economies are expanding and that makes sense but, I guess at the risk of asking you to front-run that investment strategy, as a company and as an investment what's the broader philosophical view on businesses like Prestige, Professional, Braun, the driver of that 20% of the volume decline? I guess are you comfortable with the inevitable trade-off of the faster growth in good times with the greater degree of cyclicality they get you when times are like these? And then I guess also how do you reconcile the idea of the managing that portfolio for the 75% when times are good with the initiative to extend the portfolio at the low end and be more competitive during a terrible global recession that may prove to nearing a close when those value offerings can create I guess a mix drag during the 75% of the time when things are good? I guess it seems like you may get somewhat of a long-term crossroads; maybe that's too dramatic. I just want to see if you could comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me &#x2013; Chris let me, let me take on Beauty because that's probably at least the question behind the question and certainly our biggest business with most of the discretionary categories.</p>
          <p>We still very much like the Beauty and Personal Care business.  It has been the single biggest contributor to our net sales and profit growth this decade so far, okay, to the present.  Beauty has generated over 40% of our top-line growth and 40 to 45% of our bottom-line growth.  The second biggest contributor has been emerging markets, which has sort of been 35 to 40% of our top-line growth and about 30 to 35% of our profit growth.  And in both cases you're going to have to deal with the downs and the ups, okay, and we're quite willing to do it because in both cases we like the demographics that are underpinning Beauty and emerging markets.  That's where consumers are, that's where they're spending, they're buying Beauty Care products younger.  They're using more of them and they're sticking with them longer, okay?</p>
          <p>Even in this quarter, our Gillette Fusion share was up, our Head &amp; Shoulders share was up, our Olay share was up, our Clairol Perfect 10 share was up, our CoverGirl share was up and even Pantene eked out a little bit of share growth and we're still not to the major new initiative launch, which we said would come next year.  So, I guess our point of view is you have to look at the attractiveness of any industry. It's a low CapEx industry; it's a relatively high gross margin industry.  It's a highly fragmented industry.  We still have a relatively modest share, despite the fact that we have a relatively big business.  And I think if you step back and look at it, it's a brand and innovation driven industry that's shifting to our channels.  One of the things that's going on right now that's good for us is big part of the Beauty trade down is out of department stores and out of specialty stores into the array of self select kinds of stores, where we have the meat of our business.</p>
          <p>So I think there are a lot of things that are dead right for this.  And I don't get too excited by a quarter or two or even a year or two, if it's a right &#x2013; if it's a good business for us structurally, if it's a business that fits our strategy and fits our core competencies and strength.</p>
          <p>You asked about a couple of specifics, which are slightly tougher nuts.  We &#x2013; on Braun we have a strategy and we have a plan and it has a time horizon and the time horizon is appropriate.  And we're going to find out what we can do with that business. And we're in the first phase, which is accelerating the restructuring. We'll be moving into second phase, which is we're going to be very focused on where we want to play and where we believe on the Braun brand is leverageable and we'll see.  But you know what? If we double the profit or half the profit, you won't notice it, okay.</p>
          <p>The other one is the Salon business, we're quite pleased with the Fragrance assets we got out of Wella.  We're making good progress on the retail assets that we got out of Wella.  I think we finally demonstrated that we can actually make a difference with retail hair color, and that shows in Clairol Perfect 10 and our Nice 'n Easy shares in the markets where we're established. So we're going to learn this business.</p>
          <p>Now again, because of Gillette, we actually had to put some of the restructuring on Wella on the back burner but Robert Jongstra and his team, we got the right leadership crew in there.  We are going to get it restructured this year and next.  We've got a little bit of encouragement from our Sebastian relaunch.  We are very much focusing that business and you will see us do the kinds of things we did in Fine Fragrance in the Salon world, okay. And again is it worth investing for two or three years, heck yes because a lot of the innovation and lot of the ideas come out of Salon and then go into retail and we want to be on the cutting edge of that.</p>
          <p>But I think again, will Wella make the difference in the company's financial results?  It's a pimple.  Okay, it's a pimple.  And I'll hope it will become more, but right now it's not going to make a big difference.  So step-back; still like Beauty, still like Personal Care for a lot of structural reasons and a lot of strategic fit reasons. There are a couple of questionable businesses that you had asked about.  We are working on them. We think we are working on them in the right way.  And we'll come to an appropriate resolution.  And I hope they will be successful, but we don't know yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Andrew Sawyer with Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, I had a quick one that was very specific to US laundry, it looks like the P&amp;L on that business is coming in pretty nicely, you got the pricing, raw materials and compaction carryover benefits versus maybe I think you said a 300 basis point decline for Tide share offset by some Gain market share gains. So I was wondering if you kind of help us understand, first of all you mentioned some adjustments that are making to help improve the market share performance, but how should we think about your tolerance for market share losses in a tough cyclical environment for Tide versus the very positive numbers we are seeing on a P&amp;L basis for that business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not very tolerant.  Andrew, what we did is &#x2013; it's a classic example of first things first, okay.  And in that business, we wanted to lead the move to compaction, which has been good for consumers, good for retailers, good for the industry and good for P&amp;G and we capture a big share of that, okay.  Two, we've had to deal with over a billion dollars in commodity cost hurt again this year and we wanted to make sure that we had our structural margin and costs right.</p>
          <p>Three, we've had to lead the pricing up, as Jon explained in developing markets to cover the transaction impact of FX and frankly in developed markets to recover the commodities.  So, we've sort of stepped through all the things we need to do to make sure that that industry stays attractive, attractive to retailers, attractive to suppliers and of course attractive to P&amp;G, given our leadership overall share.  You are going to see a lot of innovation out of the Laundry business and I'm just going to leave it at that.  You've seen a fair amount this year. We're going step it up.  And the share will come back. It has always come back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bill Chappell with SunTrust.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, you've mentioned in the comments that the media weighting was up 5% year-over-year, but costs were down. I guess that's a little surprising just in that it seemed like you've been cutting back on some media, do you expect to continue to grow year-over-year for the next few quarters and what's kind of the outlook on costs? I mean what we've heard is that after the May upfronts are done, the media cost should come down a step further, do you see that as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  The media world has been a good world for buyers, okay.  And not just in the US.  Here is a simple way to think about it.  Auto industry, big media buyers, dramatic drawdown. Financial services industry, big media buyers, substantial drawdown and I could name a few other industries that have moved down and even in some cases out of certain media vehicles, so it's been a buyers' market, okay.</p>
          <p>And I don't want to go into all the details because there are a whole bunch of negotiations that are ongoing, but I think you are right in the near-term, it's going to be even a bit &#x2013; could be even a bit more of a buyers' market.  So what we've tried to do is take our market mix modeling and our market ROI analysis and figure out how to spend a little less money and get a lot more delivery.  And there is nothing sophisticated than that. Some of it is buying leverage; we are the biggest advertiser in most markets. Some of it is frankly smarter media plans and some of it is frankly creative ways that we work with the media suppliers to generate value for them and value for us.</p>
          <p>So, I think it's been, it's just been &#x2013; it's been a good time.  And frankly, it's been important that that's been the case because as I've said before, we had to spend a little bit more on couponing here and there, we've had to spend a little bit more with our customers in store in various channels, in various countries.  So, I think it's going to stay a pretty attractive situation and our goal over time and again we don't look at it on a month-to-month, quarter-to-quarter basis necessarily, but our goal over time is to strengthen our brand equities and part of that is delivering a consistent share of media voice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Connie Maneaty with BMO Capital.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi this is actually Zeke Cramer with a question for Connie.  I was wondering, if you guys could comment on the &#x2013; or just give us a little bit more color on the article in the journal yesterday about the restructuring in the Beauty and Grooming business and also as well the timing and any charges?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Well on the last part, no impact.  Hey, listen this is something we've wanted to do for a while.  We think it's the next logical phase in how you organize a Beauty and Personal Care business for even more success.  Here is a simple way to think about it.  We're going to organize by &#x2013; more by consumer and customer or channel than by product category.  And it's the first one of our major sectors that we're going to do this with.</p>
          <p>We really do believe the consumer is the boss, we really do believe in the consumer value equation.  And, we believe that we can accelerate innovation and we believe that we can execute better as we go to market with our customers if we organize around Personal Beauty Care around women and around men, very simple.  And then organize several of our other businesses around the channel, whether it's Salon or whether it's the Specialty Beauty channels, but that's all it is.</p>
          <p>Now on top of that it's a dramatic simplification and reduction in the size of the management structure.  We eliminate a lot of overlapping per category and geographic complexity that we had before.  And thirdly it's an opportunity for our best performing beauty and grooming leaders to get more responsibility and to grow faster.  So, I think it's going to make us more agile.  I know it's going to get us closer to the consumer and the customers with whom we work to serve the consumer and we are pretty sure it's going to accelerate our innovation to market and on top of all of that it's going to save us some money.  So it's a win-win.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jason Gere with RBC Capital.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah thanks good morning.  A.G. you mentioned earlier about possible plans with the pharma business.  But I was just wondering if you could just update us more on your thinking on portfolio optimization especially as retailers are cutting back in inventory and certainly looking to exit some of the smaller non-leading brands, but I'm just wondering if you can give a little of context around your thinking on that right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll continue to prune brands from our portfolio that are either not strategic or underperforming.  And I think you've seen that this quarter.  And frankly you've seen that over the last eight, nine, ten years. We have fairly consistently every year pruned a handful of brands and even more in some years and that will continue.</p>
          <p>On the bigger category or industry side, we are always looking at what businesses we should be in and what businesses we should not be in.  As I said while there has been significant interest in our pharma business and while we've announced that we are open to look at all options, we are truly looking at all strategic options, including &#x2013; okay, including hanging on to the business. We are improving our profit year-on-year in Pharma.  So, we're going to do what's right for the shareholder with the Pharma business.  But over the long-term, it's not a play for us, okay.  Over the short-term, we are going to do what's right for the shareholder.</p>
          <p>There are a couple of other businesses, which I obviously cannot call out, that we're looking at, that may not be good fit for us.  And, I'm not talking about small brands here, I'm talking about categories.  But, I think that's sort of the state of play at any given time and there are a couple of businesses that we'd like to get in or we'd to like to take a bigger position in.  And, I think you have to look at that side of it too. I mean, this should be a good time to acquire.  There is consolidation going on in a number of industries, including some that we operate in, so I'm hopeful that there will be some assets that are available down the road.  And, at the same time I think that we will continue to divest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Linda Bolton Weiser with Caris.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks.  Just a couple of questions on the Beauty business, first in your Professional Hair Care business, do you think Unilever has plans for getting bigger in that area, with their recent acquisition of a brand in that industry.  Do you have any thoughts on that and whether that may change the competitive landscape there?  And then secondly, on Olay, I'm curious if you think that price points at mass retail higher than the Pro-X price points are possible, given the issues they have with staffs etcetera at mass retail.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Linda, I'm smiling on the second question because I remember back in 1998, when we had a huge debate, Susan and I were in the room with the team and we had a huge debate about whether we were going to go through the $10 price point on Olay. We were &#x2013; most of the Olay in the world was sold at 6 to $10 and we were trying to decide, if we could get $15 for &#x2013; 10 to $15 for Olay Daily Facials and 15 bucks as the midpoint for Total Effects. And now we have almost a $2.5 billion brand and we can price it from $5 to $50.</p>
          <p>Who knows, I think the real answer is who knows. When the team came up with the Pro-X idea and they developed the product and we started to get consumer response to the concept and the product, I think some were surprised that it could command the pricing that it did. But when you look at what we're delivering, we're delivering products that are better than 2 and $300 alternatives in department stores.  That's the value equation and it's a hell of a value equation, okay.</p>
          <p>And consumers are smart and I think they are less concerned about where they shop.  We've done a hell of a lot of Pro-X business on Amazon believe it or not.  It was one of the &#x2013; one of the Beauty Care brands and initiatives and innovations they wanted to try and it's been successful.  So who knows, I think it will depend on what the consumer wants and hopefully we'll spot it and give to her.</p>
          <p>Hey on the first question, you've got to ask Unilever, I have no idea.  The only thing I can say is when you enter a new business it takes a certain amount of time to learn it.  I wish I could say we could do these things overnight, but after 32 years it just &#x2013; it takes you a certain amount of time to learn it.  And it's taken us some time to learn the retail coloring business, and to really get our technology and innovation programs geared up so we're delivering products that are delightful for consumers and offer good value. It's going to take us some time to learn the Salon business, but you can ask them about their intentions.  As far as the competitiveness, it's really too small to be a competitive factor right now.  So, we've got far bigger competitive issues to deal with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ali Dibadj with Bernstein.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.  I wanted to talk a little bit about operating margins a little bit, and understand the puts and takes there. As far as we can tell volume deleverage is in the &#x2013; call it 170 basis points range, negative 170 basis points range, plus you worked down inventories nicely, so I'm assuming there is a little bit of downtime &#x2013; downtime as well.  On the flip side obviously you took down some advertising from the base point, it looks like 170 from the press release.  But there is also other moving parts we didn't care about, so cost cutting, foreign exchange multipliers, we've been calling it, all that sort of stuff, so I just want to get a sense of how things kind of plus and minus shake out there?  And in that context maybe an attachment question around the Snacks and Pet business, which I continue to be surprised about how low margins that is, particularly if &#x2013; and disabuse me if this is incorrect.  But I thought the Pringles business was in the kind of 20, 25% EBT margin range, which would suggest Pet is much lower, so two parts to the question, if you could help, that will be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we typically answer one question, we'll go to Pet, you can follow-up with guy who is putting the line on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon is pointing at me.  Ali here is the story on Pet margins, I think we have doubled them since acquisition, so they are definitely improving with single-digit to pretty comfortable double-digit. We are not the highest margin player in the industry, but I think we're running second right now.  So, not surprisingly Hill's Science Diet given their vet focus and profile can generate the highest margin in the industry.  But we are actually running higher margins than &#x2013; than the other big players, Nestl&#xE9;, Mars etcetera.  And there is more margin to come because we are in &#x2013; we are going through a major replatforming and rationalization of our whole product supply operation and manufacturing operation. So I think you will continue to see margin improvement.  That has been a focus of that team the last three years and they have made progress on it and we prioritized margin and structural attractiveness before we started investing in the innovation.  And by the way the innovation is all starting to get traction and you saw that in the top-line.</p>
          <p>Hey without going into the details, the Chips business is a another matter and the only thing I will say there is we're in the early weeks of a major initiative where we've upsized Pringles, supersized Pringles, so far so good, but too soon to tell.  And if it works it will be a margin sweetener.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time we have time for one last question. Your last question comes from the line of Alice Longley with Buckingham Research.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning I'm glad I squeezed in.  I'm trying to separate out some of your volume and pricing numbers that you started to separate out earlier when you said that the volume was down a little bit worse in developing markets than in developed markets.  I'm wondering within developing markets if you can give us some feel for how volume was outside the CEEMEA area?  And similarly, could you break out pricing, kind of what pricing was US or developed versus developing markets, so we can see the differentiation there.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alice, you know we report on a global business unit basis, not on a regional basis.  But, I'll just give you a couple of order of magnitude things.  In developing markets LA is the most robust now, then Asia and obviously the one that's been hit the hardest as I said earlier is Central and Eastern Europe, Russia in particular, okay?  And I think that shouldn't surprise you based on reading any of the business dailies and just looking what's happened with those economies and with currency.  So we're sort of- we will cycle through that, okay.  I forgot the other part of the question, sorry Jon help me out with the main one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>She asked about where we're taking pricing, where we're not effectively follow the currency devaluations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  I mean every place &#x2013; we are committed to covering as much of the transaction impact of currency and that's pretty much the pricing that's left. All of the pricing for commodities is for the most part done and behind us, right.  And in fact, we'll get benefit from that going forward because we haven't anniversaried yet in a lot of businesses, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much everybody and we're obviously available for phone calls on further details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And thank you for your participation in today's conference, this concludes the presentation.  And you may now disconnect and good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>