<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1171115" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>62432</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nicholas Rolli, Vice President, Investor Relations and Financial Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Hermann Waldemer, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">David Adelman</participant>
      <participant id="4">Nicholas Rolli</participant>
      <participant id="5">Hermann Waldemer</participant>
      <participant id="6">Adam Spielman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Christine Farkas</participant>
      <participant id="8">Erik Bloomquist</participant>
      <participant id="9">Judy Hong</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jonathan Fell</participant>
      <participant id="11">Filippe Goossens</participant>
      <participant id="12">Christopher Growe</participant>
      <participant id="13">Jonathan Leinster</participant>
      <participant id="14">Ann Gurkin</participant>
      <participant id="15">Chris Burritt</participant>
      <participant id="16">Thomas Russo</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to Philip Morris International's Second Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. Today's call is scheduled to last about one hour, including remarks by Philip Morris International management and the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. Nicholas M. Rolli, Vice President, Investor Relations and Financial Communications for Philip Morris International. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello and good morning and thank you for joining us. Early this morning, we issued a news release which contains detailed information on Philip Morris International's 2008 second quarter results. If you do not have a copy, you may access one on our website at www.pmintl.com.</p>
          <p>Following the completion of the spin-off, historical basic and diluted earnings per share amounts were recalculated based on the actual number of shares distributed by Altria Group, Inc. on the distribution date. In our first quarter earnings release, we provided a reconciliation of 2007 reported results to 2007 pro forma adjusted results by quarter and for the full year; and for your reference, this document is also available on the website.</p>
          <p>As we take you through our second quarter earnings results today, please note that we will refer to certain results as being after adjustments. This will imply that this data has been adjusted for the impact of currency and acquisitions. Furthermore, to provide you with a pure organic comparison, we will also exclude the impact of the transfer of our U.S. Duty Free business to Philip Morris USA in August last year. This latter adjustment is not included in the numbers in our press release issued today.</p>
          <p>Please also note that unless otherwise stated, we will be talking about results in the second quarter 2008 and comparing them with results in the same period in 2007. References to international tobacco market shares are Philip Morris International estimates based on a number of sources.</p>
          <p>Today's remarks contain forward-looking statements and projections of future results, and I direct your attention to the Safe Harbor statement in today's presentation and news release for review of the various factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from projections.</p>
          <p>And now it's my pleasure to introduce Hermann Waldemer, Chief Financial Officer for Philip Morris International. Hermann?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nick, and hello, everyone. As you have seen from our press release, we have reported excellent second quarter results. These results, combined with our continued strong business momentum, currency favorability, higher pricing in a number of markets such as Italy and Russia, and planned reinvestments in key markets have enabled us to raise our annual guidance.</p>
          <p>Our revised adjusted full-year diluted EPS guidance for 2008 is between 3.32 and $3.38, representing a growth rate of between 19 and 21%. Diluted earnings per share were $0.86, up 22.9% or $0.16 per share. Of this increase, $0.06 or about 40% of the increase reflects the strength of our business and favorable currency accounts for the other $0.10.</p>
          <p>In the first half of the year, reported EPS was up 26% or $0.36 per share, with business growth and currency each accounting for about half.</p>
          <p>Net revenues excluding excise taxes were 15% higher at $6.7 billion, representing an increase of $874 million. After adjustments, net revenues increased by 4.4%, driven by higher prices as well as improved volume and mix in several key markets.</p>
          <p>Reported operating company's income or OCI increased by 23.7% to $2.8 billion. After adjustments, OCI was 9.8% higher. We achieved double digit OCI growth in EMEA, Asia, and Latin America.</p>
          <p>Our Cigarette volume reached 223.2 billion units, an increase of 1%. Organic volume increased by 0.6%.</p>
          <p>Strong growth was achieved notably in Argentina, Egypt, Indonesia, Korea, Mexico, Russia, and Ukraine. This is an improved performance that reinforces our confidence that we can achieve our longer term goal of 1 to 2% volume growth.</p>
          <p>Marlboro shipment volume declined by 2.4% to 79.1 billion units. After taking into account the impact of the trends for last year of our U.S. Duty Free business, Marlboro shipments were up in all geographical regions except the EU. The brand continues to perform strongly in Argentina, Egypt, Indonesia, Korea, Mexico, Romania, Russia, and Ukraine. Our innovative line extensions are helping to strengthen the vitality of the brand and its overall equity.</p>
          <p>Increased shipments of Parliament and Virginia Slims have reinforced PMI's leadership position in the premium segment. Parliament shipments were 28.1% thanks to tremendous momentum in Korea, Russia, Turkey, and Ukraine.</p>
          <p>Virginia Slims shipments increased by 12.2%, reflecting both volume growth in existing key markets such as Japan and Korea as well as the penetration of new markets, such as Greece and Romania.</p>
          <p>Our two key brands in the mid-price segment are L&amp;M and Chesterfield. Outside of the EMEA region, the volume of L&amp;M grew by 3.4% driven by France, Germany, Netherlands, and Poland. L&amp;M is the second largest brand in the cigarette industry in the EU region behind Marlboro and over the last 12 months has been the fastest growing brand in Germany.</p>
          <p>As you know, we have revamped the brand in Russia and Ukraine. While L&amp;M shipments continue to decline in these markets, we were able to more than offset this volume decline through higher shipments of Chesterfield. Chesterfield sells at the premium to L&amp;M and consequently generates higher margins. Globally, we are delighted by the performance of Chesterfield as it maintained its very strong momentum with an increase in shipments of 18%.</p>
          <p>Our key brands are in good shape and we are continuing to strengthen our international brand portfolio leadership through the development of a successful innovation pipeline.</p>
          <p>We've talked to you previously about the success of Marlboro filter plus in a number of markets. Let me share with you some other examples.</p>
          <p>Marlboro Intense is a rich, flavorful, usually shorter cigarette in the red pack. It was launched initially in Turkey and more recently in Belgium and the Netherlands.</p>
          <p>In Italy, a lighter tasting version was launched in March as Marlboro Compact in a silver pack.</p>
          <p>To support our leading position in the growling Menthol segment, we have launched Marlboro Crisp Mint, Marlboro Fresh Mint and Marlboro Ice Mint in a number of markets in Asia and Latin America. These refreshing products are performing well. For example Crisp Mint reached a 1.4% share in Hong Kong; Fresh Mint, 0.4% in Malaysia; and Ice Mint, 0.3% in Japan. I will discuss our latest Menthol innovation, Marlboro Black Menthol, when I talk specifically about Japan later.</p>
          <p>We have successfully developed a number of new products in response to an increasing demand in several markets for cigarettes with a slimmer diameter. Premium-priced Virginia Slims UNO has notably achieved an 0.3% market share in Greece and Romania in May and an 0.2% share in Japan in the quarter. Mid-priced L&amp;M Link has achieved a 1.5% market share in Poland.</p>
          <p>Let me now take you through the results in key business developments in our four regions. Industry volume in the EU region is estimated to have declined by 3.7% during the second quarter, driven by the one-time impact of recent public smoking restrictions, higher prices, and the long-term decline in smoking incidents.</p>
          <p>Our shipment volume decreased by 4.4% to 64.8 billion units and our estimated market share was down slightly to 39.4%. Revenues, net of excise taxes after excluding the very positive currency impact, declined by 1.7% and OCI was essentially stable.</p>
          <p>These results were impacted by the total market declines and the need to temporarily absorb some tax increases in the Czech Republic and Poland, where we had shorter inventory durations of old tax products than our competitors.</p>
          <p>During the first half of the year, revenues net of excise taxes in the region, were essentially stable and OCI increased by 5% net of currency.</p>
          <p>Business fundamentals in our four key EU markets continue to strengthen. In Germany, our adjusted cigarette market share was up 0.3 points to 37%. L&amp;M is growing and Marlboro is sequentially improving its share.</p>
          <p>We also expanded our position in the important German fine cut category with a market share increase of 4.8 points to a record quarterly level of 16.5%, thanks to our innovative tobacco block and the strength of our L&amp;M and Next brands. Our profitability in Germany is up both in the quarter and the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>In Italy and Spain, we continue to improve our profitability during the quarter. Our share is up in the first half in both markets. Chesterfield is performing very well and Marlboro is resilient.</p>
          <p>In France, while share is down on a year-on-year basis by 2.5 points due to the impact of a less favorable price point for Marlboro, our market share of 40.9% has been stable since the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>The outlook for the EU region is improving. We have recently announced price increases in Italy, the Netherlands and Switzerland, and have strengthened our competitive position in the important German market.</p>
          <p>Public smoking bans have now been implemented across most of the EU and we expect a one-time impact on total industry to have been largely absorbed by year end. The very large tax-driven price increases in central Europe related EU accession are moderating. The Czech Republic has now reached the excise tax level of currently required in the EU. Hungary, Poland, and Slovakia should reach it next year.</p>
          <p>In this context, I would like to comment on the update to the tobacco excise directives that the EU Commission is proposing. First, I would like to emphasize that we welcome the review as it is an opportunity to improve the framework for excise taxes in the EU. Second, the proposal is essentially in line with what we had expected following a broad consultation.</p>
          <p>The next step is for the EU Commission to discuss the proposal in detail with the member states, a process that will allow individual countries to convey their views on each element of the proposal. As a unanimous agreement is needed on every proposed change to the current directive amongst the 27 EU member states, we expect that the proposal will be modified prior to its finalization, which is foreseen during the second half of next year.</p>
          <p>We are pleased that EU Commission recognizes that there is little justification for significant differences in the taxation level for cigarettes and fine-cut products. We also welcome the proposed increased flexibility to be given to governments in terms of the excise tax structure and the level of the minimum excise tax.</p>
          <p>We, however, regret that the Commission has not taken this opportunity to propose an abolition of the excise incidence rule and are concerned that tax increases resulting from the proposal could have unintended consequences in certain EU countries if implemented as currently proposed.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter, the EMEA region continued to achieve very strong results with volume up 3.2%, net revenues excluding excise taxes and currency 10.2% higher, and OCI excluding currency increasing by 22.9%.</p>
          <p>We are benefiting from the premium SKU of our portfolio as consumers continue to trade up. The resulting volume growth and improved product mix has been further boosted by price increases, thus driving profitability to record levels.</p>
          <p>Russia is central to these excellent results with PMI shipments increasing by 8.3%. Continued strong consumer up-trading has benefited Chesterfield, Marlboro and Parliament. Revenues net of excise taxes in currency rose by 24%, driven by favorable volume and mix in higher prices. This has enabled us to increase profitability to record levels.</p>
          <p>Our shipments grew by 2.9% in Turkey while our share was essentially stable. We benefited from consumer up-trading with very strong Parliament growth. This more favorable mix, along with higher prices, has been driving profitability.</p>
          <p>In Ukraine, shipments increased by 8.2% driven by Chesterfield, Marlboro, Parliament and Virginia Slims. As a result, our market share reached a record level of 35.2%. Our profitability will be further boosted by the recent retail price increases in this important market.</p>
          <p>Cigarette shipment volume in Asia grew by 1.9% to 56.8 billion units, with growth in Indonesia and Korea more than offsetting decline in Japan.</p>
          <p>Marlboro is performing very well across the Asia region with a volume increase of 1.8%. Marlboro Filter Plus and Marlboro Mix 9 Kretek have reinforced the brand's equity, helping to drive the brand family to record levels in Korea and Indonesia; and Marlboro continues to perform strongly in the Philippines.</p>
          <p>Marlboro's success is complemented by the tremendous performance of Parliament driven by Korea, whose shipments were up over 50% in the region; and Virginia Slims, which experienced double digit growth.</p>
          <p>Revenues that net of excise taxes were up 4.9% excluding currency. We achieved a 15.2% increase in OCI net of currency in Asia as excellent results &#x2013; notably in Australia, Indonesia and Korea &#x2013; more than offset the decline in Japan.</p>
          <p>We are very pleased with our results in Indonesia. Our shipments there were up 14.9%, as our entire portfolio grew with A Mild and Marlboro performing particularly well.</p>
          <p>Let me focus for a moment on Japan. During the second quarter, industry volume was down by 1.6%, helped by trade purchases in advance of the implementation of the new vending age control mechanism.</p>
          <p>PMI shipments meanwhile declined by 7% due to the declining total market and an optimization of stock coverage levels. Our share reached 23.9%, which was 0.3 points below the prior year's level, but stable compared to both the first quarter of this year and the last quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Marlboro share remained stable at 9.8%. We are launching Marlboro Black Menthol during the first week of August to reinforce the brand's performance. This innovative new product has a unique refreshing mint flavor and provides a bold, cooling sensation.</p>
          <p>Lark's share of 6.8% was marginally down from last year, but flatly up compared to the first quarter of 2008. The recently launched Lark Menthol X has achieved a market share of 0.3% and the new Lark Classic is doing well in test markets.</p>
          <p>Virginia Slims has continued to expand to reach a market share of 2.1%, driven by the successful launch last year of Virginia Slims Noire.</p>
          <p>These results show that our increased focus on innovation is starting to have a positive impact and we expect improved results going forward, fueled by additional marketing investments.</p>
          <p>While we are focused on restoring share growth momentum, we are also very conscious of the pressures on profitability from a declining market, which is subject to price controls. While we oppose the recent call for a massive tax and price increase, we believe that this debate may encourage the government to consider revising the tobacco law to allow pricing freedom.</p>
          <p>Latin America had another very strong quarter on all accounts. Our cigarette shipment volume was up 7.9% and 1.3% excluding acquisition, driven by strong results in Argentina and Mexico, partly offset by Columbia. In Argentina, our shipments increased by 8.8% and regained 1.9 points to reach a market share of 70.3% driven by Marlboro and the Philip Morris brands.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, the total market remains stable, while we were able to increase our market share by 3 points to 67.2% driven by Benson &amp; Hedges, Delicados, and Marlboro.</p>
          <p>In Latin America as a whole, our revenues net of excise taxes increased by 8%, excluding currency and acquisitions, while our OCI was 15% higher on the same basis.</p>
          <p>Let me say a few words about our actions to enhance shareholder value. On May 1, we started our two year share repurchase program. Since then, we have spent $2.1 billion out of the $13 billion approved by the Board of Directors. In total, we have so far purchased 41.4 million shares at an average price of $51.48.</p>
          <p>On June 18, we announced our first quarterly dividend as a public company of $0.46 a share. As stated previously, we expect to return a total of $21 billion to shareholders over the next two years, which reflects about 20% of our current market capitalization.</p>
          <p>In order to help finance these and other business requirements, we successfully raised $6 billion in May and a U.S. dollar bond offering at what we believe are attractive rates. During the second half of the year, we intend to continue to access the capital markets, provided financing conditions are suitable.</p>
          <p>To sum up, our business in EMEA, Asia and Latin America are performing very well with strong volume growth and improved mix and higher prices and margins. The outlook for the EU region is improving, with pricing power remaining strong and an enhanced competitive position, notably in Germany.</p>
          <p>Japan remains a challenge due to continuous price controls in a declining market. We have however stabilized our market position and have the strategies in place which we believe will enable us to grow share again.</p>
          <p>Enhanced innovation is driving better organic volume and we are on track with our productivity saving programs and our financial measures to return significant cash to our shareholders. As you can see, we are delivering against the targets that we established and shared with you in March.</p>
          <p>I will now be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question is from David Adelman with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Hermann and Nick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hermann, I wanted to ask you a few a few things. First, with respect to share repurchases, what's the argument against maintaining for the foreseeable future the execution pace in the second quarter? You're basically buying back $1 billion a month. Why not keep that going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the share buyback, I mean, look, we have always been and we'll stay on a steady pace there. We actually did opportunity purchases given the attractiveness of the share prices and we'll continue to do that when appropriate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Hermann, why weren't diluted shares outstanding &#x2013; they were flat sequentially. Why weren't they down, Q2 versus Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we started the share repurchase on May 1. Remember there is the 30 day delay after being quoted, so it starts only on May 1. And then it is going in, in weighted averages so it washes in over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then could you clarify your comment in your prepared remarks with respect to the EU tax proposal about regretting the absence of an abolition of excise tax, the excise tax incidence rule? What specifically are you referring to there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean, the EU article for excise review &#x2013; I mean, the way I would put it is, I see three good elements in there, one, washout, and I would say one overriding remark, which is probably what I should start with.</p>
          <p>The overriding remark is that any change to the existing laws, the existing directive, needs unanimous agreement of all 27 member states. So therefore &#x2013; I mean, that's going to take a while. Except something final, say, the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Then the washout, which is precisely your question, is the proposed incidence increases that you see in the proposal. That could trigger price increases &#x2013; excise tax driven price increases in some markets, which could actually lead to the known undesired side-effects from counterfeits to border sales to all these things that we have seen before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's really what I would call a wash out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But very importantly, let me also say that the good things in there, because it's really three good things, more flexibility on the minimum excise tax, which right now is kept at 100% of the most popular price class. That's a good one, an important one. Proposing to raise the specific element, which today can go up to 55% to 75%, is another very good element in there. And the partial alignment of roll-your-own, make-your-own, a two-third of cigarettes taxation is also a good element.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And than two other things, Hermann. Are you willing or prepared that in Germany to have Marlboro at a per-pack price point above 5 euros alone as you've &#x2013; you're sort of repeating the situation you're suffering through in France?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, look &#x2013; of course, future pricing, you know that I will not comment on that. We will decide once the moment is there. I think that's what I have to say on pricing in Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly, Hermann &#x2013; it's early days, but is there any evidence in the marketplace of any change in the behavior of Altadis / Imperial subsequent to the consummation of that merger?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really. I mean, this is competition. There has been competition before. We will have to see. Certainly, there will be a lot of integration going on in these companies. But look, we focus on our own place here and really everybody around to target increased revenues and increase profitability in our own place. That's what we concentrate on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Adam Spielman with Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Hermann. Hello, Nick. Two questions if I can, please. First of all, have you seen either in the second quarter or in your trading since then any signs at all that a weakening economy, either in the European Union or elsewhere, is causing either weakness in volumes or weakness down trading? I know for example that you've seen some down trading away from Marlboro in France, but we saw that in the first quarter. What I'm interested is whether there has been any incremental worsening really anywhere in the world? That's my first question for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I would say, I mean, starting with the EU region, I mean, the down trading you have seen there in the last couple of years, that was mostly triggered by price re-positionings of previous mid-price and even premium brands by competition to the low end. Well, there's nothing left, I'm afraid, to be priced down there by competition. So that is over. We are rather in a more normal competitive situation going forward.</p>
          <p>If we then expanded rather on a worldwide basis in the light of increasing inflationary pressures, rising food prices and all of that, then actually I must say we can't see that Indonesia would eventually be a market where you could expect to see something like that.</p>
          <p>We don't &#x2013; actually our volume in Indonesia is up 14.9%, the market overall is up in Indonesia and that in an environment with high inflation and reduced fuel subsidies for the people earlier this year. So we can't see it there.</p>
          <p>If I go over to Latin America &#x2013; I mean, there actually we have to see that Latin America is rather a part of the world which is a source of commodities and where actually salary increases are still in most places above inflation. So we don't see that there either. So cigarettes are probably a fairly resistant product to these types of things.</p>
          <p>The only place where I could see a little bit of that would eventually be Colombia where you see it at the lower end of the price spectrum, where you see some impact there, i.e. more stick purchases and less purchases overall. But there is a kind of the lower-bracket income class of population, because in that very same market, by the way, Marlboro is growing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, actually, you've already touched on what was going to be my second question, which is to really focus on Indonesia. Obviously in May, the price of gasoline went up by 30%, I believe. Your volume, as you say, in the second quarter was exceptional. But if we can just look forward, do you think &#x2013; firstly, what do you think volume's going to look like because presumably it's going to have to slow down from 15%? And also just to reiterate, you've seen no signs that the increase in fuel is having any impact on your business even in July in Indonesia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean &#x2013; really, I mean, I cannot exclude that for the future, I mean, that this going to have one impact at a certain point in time. But right now I just do not see that. I agree with you that 14.9% volume growth is, of course, an exceptional number and will not be a number that keeps on going there for the next 10 years.</p>
          <p>But, no, we don't see any of that. I mean, what is of course important in the context probably is as well that whilst you have roughly I would estimate an inflation of 10% in Indonesia, prices &#x2013; cigarette prices were up about 6.5%, so a little bit below inflation.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; and if you go through our portfolio, I mean, Marlboro is up 27%, A Mild is up 20%, and Dji Sam Soe is up 4%. So this is really going very, very nicely and we also express our confidence going forward in that market by putting a green field there, which actually &#x2013; the official opening is going to be on August 20.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And actually one final question. In your earlier remark, do &#x2013; you referred to price increases in Italy, in Holland or the Netherlands and Switzerland. Are those very recent increases or were those ones back in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, these are recent increases. The Italy price increase, for example, if I remember correctly, was the last week of June.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I wasn't aware. Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Christine Farkas with Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning, Hermann and Nick. A couple of questions for you if I...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Christine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. And on the costs savings, you did talk about costs savings being on track. Will you quantify those? Do you plan to give us an update, for example, in dollars or perhaps where you may have allocated these cost savings so far year-to-date?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Look, I mean, on the productivity and cost savings, we are on track. We will meet our productivity and cost savings target over the next three years of $1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>So if I may go through a little bit, the main elements and what are we doing there. In manufacturing, where we said the 850 million in manufacturing productivity, the first big element there is the resourcing of volume from U.S.A. factories to PMI factories. We will be one or two months ahead of schedule with bringing that over. Remember that was almost $180 million by 2009, perfectly on track.</p>
          <p>The clustering, which was all re-grouped into technical functions and procurement functions in about 10 places around the world is progressing, rationalizing non-strategic SKUs, product specifications, simplifications is an ongoing job. We go ahead on the $450 million G&amp;A procurement. The head count reductions in the regional and PMI HQs are essentially done.</p>
          <p>The financial service centers are up and running. The human resource shared service centers are being implemented as we speak and are being rolled out. And we have essentially, by the end of that year, you can say we will have implemented one SAP program around the world as a European backbone system for the Company. And in the EU, the EU cost-cutting program, that is also part of the secret of our profitability increase in that in addition to, of course, the pricing variance in there.</p>
          <p>We keep on going there. We have an early retirement program, for example, in Germany in our one-time charges this quarter, so we keep on going. So we'll stay on track with all of that and we will give a detailed review once a year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. And just a regional &#x2013; a couple of regional questions as housekeeping, you certainly did talk about Indonesia. Can you tell us what your share was in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Indonesia is actually a very difficult place in terms of earnings per share. The shares in Indonesia show us essentially stable shares, given the volume increase that I know for sure because these are simply sales and revenues. I would rather think that those shares for the moment are somewhat understated in Indonesia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I was just curious given you've provided that share in the past but not this quarter. It looks like it's at least stable if not higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The share numbers as I have in front of them, they are stable. They're not high up. But I think that there's always a certain delay in certain flows. It's a big country. It's difficult to measure, I guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then last question then on Poland. I mean, just as a broad statement, I was pleased to see underlying organic volume growth, so that's favorable. And looking at a country like Poland and keeping your comments about trading up across many of your regions, we should be lapping the price increases soon, I believe, or remind us when that is. But there's also some down trading. Can you just put the two in context as to how the outlook is for that market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, with pleasure. I mean, yes, Poland is a very important market and we talk about 65 billion cigarettes marketed and another probably 7 to 8 billion in roll-your-own cigarettes, tobacco.</p>
          <p>Look, I mean in 2007, this market really turned into a much more profitable market. The problem in Poland for the time being is still the missing forestalling regulations, i.e. this huge durations of old price, old tax products that are in the market.</p>
          <p>You had some competitors, some brands in there with durations of up to one year. So when the consumer sees the new price, actually the next price increase has already taken place. So that's a bit unfortunate and it's kind of &#x2013; because we're a big company in that market, it's forced us to do some absorption in the second quarter of excise taxes, which is something we really don't like to do unless we are forced to do, which we were here in Poland and actually also in the Czech Republic.</p>
          <p>Well in Poland, this is the last round that is coming now, the last excise increase in the context of EU accession for January 1, 2009. So we will have one more round of this game. So it's going to normalize in the third, fourth quarter of this year, but it's going to restart then as of January 2009.</p>
          <p>However, the good thing is as well that there are a couple of excise structure improvements eventually considered in Poland, although forestalling regulations will not come for January '09, or are unlikely to come. So going forward, we are soon out of that effect of the EU accession and that then will be the moment when actually there is room for up-trading in that market.</p>
          <p>Today, there is not much up-trading in that sense if you like, because prices are going up already that steeply. Once they stabilize, we will benefit actually from our premium portfolio and what you see now in terms of down trading what you talked about is really rather the very low end of the market, and this is traditional 70 millimeter products.</p>
          <p>At the end of the day, we made a conscious choice there between volume share and profitability for the sake of profitability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's all from me. Thanks so much, Hermann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Erik Bloomquist with JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Hermann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Erik.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question on the outlook for the second half. Implicit in the increased guidance is a slowdown in the second half in terms of the earnings per share. I was wondering if you could talk about the places where we should be thinking that there is not going to be a sequential slowdown in the second half versus what we've seen in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I mean it comes down to the overall guidance development there. I mean what we took into account is the business momentum overall, which is very positive to start with, the currency projections of course and importantly, as I said already in the first quarter, the spending pattern which has skewed any rate towards the second half and the additional investments that we are making into the markets, they will actually also hit the market and be visible to the consumer and therefore will hit the income statement also, principally in the second half.</p>
          <p>So that's our additional investments. And of course, financing costs go up, we have to build up the leverage on our balance sheet. I mean in terms of investments where we go, that's &#x2013; of course Japan is one of the places to go. But I wouldn't want to go into individual markets because that would be too sensitive from a competitive point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, understood. But so is it fair to characterize what you're saying then is that the slowdown in second half EPS is more driven by PMI investments than it is by any anticipated slowdown in your markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. I would say if you look at the growth that you have seen in the first half of the year in the actuals. As we said, it's kind of 50/50 between currency and business. Actually for a second half I see a higher proportion of business than currency of the growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, that's very helpful. Second question was with respect to Japan. And I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about &#x2013; more about the potential for a Japanese large tax increase, and then also expand on your comments that PMI hopes that the discussion on tax could lead to a reform of the Japanese tax structure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean the proposal that is on the table is being discussed now, I mean let's first really properly situate what that is. It is a group of 45 members of parliament that have gotten together and are developing that proposal.</p>
          <p>There are hearings that are bringing that proposal together. But it remains a proposal that then goes to the budget and to the finance ministry, which is the decision body. So therefore also in terms of timing, that goes to that decision body somewhere towards the end of the year and you will not see any impact of whatever the outcome is before sometime like spring next year.</p>
          <p>Then I would say that all around the world, governments have seen that abrupt increases don't work. So I think that the real chance in there is that this can lead to a discussion of kind of the imbalance in the system that they have today.</p>
          <p>You have price control on one hand. You have the wish to reduce consumption from the health side on the other hand. You have government stake in one of the top four cigarettes companies around the world. And then at the end of the day, you have price control in the Japanese home market.</p>
          <p>So over time, I would think and I would hope that this could lead to a more &#x2013; a better discussion about how to bring that forward in terms of eventually moderate, regular excise increases accompanied by pricing freedom in the market. So let's hope that this is a trigger point that can lead to a decent discussion on those points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. My last question is just related to the current EU tax proposal. As you noted in your remarks, one of the things that they're doing is increasing the potential level of minimum excise tax. As I recall from the Spanish experience in 2006, that tended to benefit premium brands. Is that a fair way to characterize one of the outcomes of this tax proposal, is we should see a benefit through the EU as it's implemented over time toward a more premium product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think so. As a government, you don't want to raise your taxes and therefore prices on one hand, and then see the people simply trade down and they actually deliver less taxes and smoke as much as before. Then as a government, you have neither achieved the financial ministry targets, nor the health ministry targets. Spain is a good example there, that of course minimum taxes at an effective level puts limits to down trading and therefore achieve on one hand the government's targets and should help actually then the more decently priced products in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Judy Hong with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Hermann. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Judy. Very well. And you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a few questions. First, a clarification in terms of your guidance. And you talked about some of the drivers. But can you quantify how much is currency driven versus operating performance that's coming in better than expected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay look, I mean, what we took into account are of course also as I said before, the currency projections. I think I will go as far that really, the increase that you will see in the second half, that really the business portion of that is really the more important part than the currency part. But I wouldn't want to split it up in detailed numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then if we look at your EU performance in the second quarter, your operating profit was flat if you take out currency versus the first quarter, where operating profit was actually up 9% and the volume decline really didn't change much from quarter-to-quarter. So I'm wondering sort of why the operating profit actually slowed down in the second quarter versus the first quarter? And secondly in relation to that, you sound actually more optimistic about EU outlook going forward despite the second quarter performance. So if you could just talk a little bit more about what gives you comfort that trends will improve and as you kind of look out for the balance of the year, are we expecting the EU profit to actually see positive trends in the back half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yes, there are two &#x2013; rather I would call them almost short-term effects that you see in the EU. And actually if you look through the markets, about 50% of the EU markets are actually affected by one of the two effects I will describe.</p>
          <p>The first one is that actually smoking bans are now implemented essentially everywhere in the European Union. And then of course as we all know, has a more or less strong one-off impact, and then it goes back to normal trends. So that is of course hurting overall total markets and therefore the volumes of the market participants.</p>
          <p>So take Germany, U.K., France, Portugal together, then the market decline in those in the second quarter is 6.1% and the revenue decline in those markets in the second quarter is 3.8. So that's very much driven by that. But as we all know, this is a one time, one-off impact.</p>
          <p>And then the second short term effect is really the EU tax formalization in the accession countries, which as I before is essentially done by year end. Poland is to come on January 1, 2009, so going into 2009, otherwise it's just Hungary, Slovakia and in 2010 you will have Romania, Bulgaria, Baltics, but all the rest is done, the bigger ones are done.</p>
          <p>On the positive side going forward, the pricing power is intact. So we have realized substantial pricing in the EU, so yet &#x2013; in the quarter $77 million. And that's despite the fact that we absorbed for Czech and Poland together $45 million, again for this forestalling effects that we had in those two markets.</p>
          <p>So that's a one-off. The hit was in Q2. That's what something that comes every quarter. As I said before, we hate doing these things unless we have no choice for competitive reasons, so we did it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the price increases that you've taken in Italy and Netherlands and Switzerland, can you quantify the magnitude of the price increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The price increase in Italy we did is essentially 0.10 euro across the board. Switzerland is essentially 20 Swiss centimes across the board, and Netherlands is if I remember correct, yes, is 0.40 euro, again for example Marlboro going to 4.40.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just sort of a broad question. How do you think about your operating profit growth this year coming in well above sort of your long-term target of 6 to 8%, even with some of the challenges that we've talked about in the EU that should get better going forward? I mean we kind of think about that 6 to 8% long-term growth outlook and we look at this year's performance. Is that number maybe somewhat conservative in your view? And if trends stay relatively stable that it is actually a potential for gross targets to be actually higher than what we are at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No look, our guidance is our mid to long term guidance, and that guidance remains unchanged. So if I look at this year's results, then we are simply pleased to see that our innovation activities really begin to pay off, that we see improved organic volume growth on our way to our mid-term target, we are not there yet. So that's a positive. We see that our productivity cost reduction programs work. We see that we are able to realize pricing around the world. So we are happy about the consolation, but that doesn't change our mid-term guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Hermann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Jonathan Fell with Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. A couple of things, first of all on the EU. I just wanted to clear up this Czech and Poland thing. Is there going to be any effect of you swallowing excise increases in those countries in the third quarter, or has that already unwound as we speak?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of it is done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And the other thing on the EU was &#x2013; I think last quarter when we were speaking about this, there was some prospect in Germany of legislation which could put a minimum pack size of 20 cigarettes in place, where have we got to on that debate now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we continue to support it as I said last time, however we regret that as it looks like now that the 20s pack rule will not be implemented in the short term. That doesn't mean that it cannot come back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any particular reason why &#x2013; what is causing you to think it won't be implemented in the short term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that's the news I have, so that it is not being implemented. So all I can say and repeat and that's what we have also told the German government, that we do support such a change in the law.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the other question was on the dividend of &#x2013; the information you talked about share repurchase, very helpful. If I look at your quarterly rate of dividend now, $0.46 &#x2013; even at the low end of your EPS guidance range for this year, 3.32, the payout ratio would be coming in at 55% against your target of 65. Are you expecting the board to review that dividend rate at the end of August?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, look, I mean the payout ratio is 65% as you correctly say. We are now at $0.46, which is kind of 3.5, 3.6% dividend yield. This is an &#x2013; entirely a decision of the Board. We have regular Board meetings throughout the year. Yes, there is one at the end of August. We will see. This is within the entire discretion of the Board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But they haven't indicated to you yet when they might review that rate because clearly, at most companies, it's not a secret really when they start to review dividends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Board will decide. It is a Board decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll look forward to it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Filippe Goossens with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, Hermann and Nick. Congrats on a good quarter here. A few questions here now...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As well. You talked about pricing in Italy, Switzerland and the Netherlands. But can you maybe just broaden the comments a little bit and talk to us about how the pricing environment or competitive environment more specifically is in the European Union and how you look at potential room for price increases in both Germany and Spain? If my memory serves me right, I think Germany, the last time you took pricing was in October of 2006 whereas Spain I think was early '07?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Filippe, I'm afraid I'm sorry that I will not comment on future pricing. I can only really comment on what we did. And I think our actions speak for themselves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then second question, can you talk a little bit about the ongoing restaging of L&amp;M in the Russian market, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In the Russian market, I mean L&amp;M as you remember that we had revamped L&amp;M both in the Ukraine and in Russia. Yes, L&amp;M is still declining in the Russian market, that's right.</p>
          <p>But you should take then as a comparison also the Ukrainian market, where actually we did the change already before our show first. There is we now can really see improvement. So it is really a declining much less now in the quarter than it did before. So we see a rejuvenation of the brand franchise, a more attractive smoker profile. But I would like to focus there really as well on the portfolio aspect of our franchise in the market.</p>
          <p>We attract ourselves with Chesterfield a number of the smokers that are actually leaving the L&amp;M franchise. And as Chesterfield is priced 2 rubles higher than L&amp;M, this is actually even a much better margin. And if you take L&amp;M and Chesterfield together, then actually the Chesterfield growth outweighs the decline of L&amp;M.</p>
          <p>So we keep on working on L&amp;M. But I urge you to look at it in a portfolio comparison as well and not only for the L&amp;M brand, but on L&amp;M itself we keep ongoing with our programs and we said from the very beginning that this is not going to be a short term fix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And moving on to the Czech Republic, and Hermann when will the inventory adjustment be anniversaried?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it depends. If you talk about our brands, then probably we'll be the ones who bring the new consumer prices to the consumer first. As I said, you had a couple of markets participants in there with durations of up to one year. So we'll have to see when that comes.</p>
          <p>But I would expect in the Czech Republic that the fourth quarter becomes a normal quarter, and then actually 2009 we could come back to a normal, fair environment overall, where there is normal competition in the markets of 2009, it should be a normal market, it's kind of &#x2013; now we're working our way through a messed up market. I think it's important also to mention here that the Deputy Minister of Finance of the Czech Republic, although the final decision comes later in the year, has said that there are no plans to increase tobacco excise tax again as of January 1, 2009.</p>
          <p>So, yes, we should have it behind us, soon I hope.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then the other question I had for you, Hermann is kind of more a broader based price question. In the U.S. historically, people have always kind of assumed that price elasticity of demand is about 0.3. We've never really focused on the European Union in terms of what price elasticity is there. But the question I really have, Hermann, based on how you're seeing things develop, particularly in the European Union given rising inflation across the board &#x2013; do you think that this inflation is starting to perhaps have an impact on price elasticity?</p>
          <p>In other words, it's one thing to raise pricing 5% per annum, let's say, if there is no inflation in the general economy. But with household products companies, personal care companies, you name them, raising pricing anywhere between 5 and 10%, could that ultimately have an impact on the price elasticity of demand for cigarettes? Have you done any work on this so far, Hermann?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is actually something which is almost impossible to answer. Yes, we have done some work. But it's impossible to come to a clear conclusion. You actually can argue the other way around. You can say in a higher inflationary environment, people are more used to price increases because they see it in all products everyday, whilst in a low inflation environment, if your cigarette prices go up only and nobody else's prices go up, it might be even more difficult. So you can turn it around the other way.</p>
          <p>All I can say is what is said earlier that so far, we haven't seen impact of inflationary pressures on our product and overall, I think it is fair to say that cigarettes in general can withstand such an environment better than any or most other consumer products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you so much, Hermann and Nick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Chris Growe with Stifel Nicolaus. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've covered a lot of the questions. But I had a couple of follow ups for you just relative to the prior question. So the first one is that, could you quantify in the quarter or give us a feel for how much your volume was down in Czech Republic? I know that's been a tough market. But what sort of decline would you see in that market this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Looking at &#x2013; the quarter number for Czech Republic I don't have here. But I mean there it is such a screw up at the end of today in that market that you really have to wait until it washes out. I mean at the end of the day, the measures we took on the marketing side, on the pricing side, on the absorption side, we have defended our cake in the market, if you like, and we look forward to a more normal situation next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And am I correct that you've already raised your prices to reflect the new tax level in the Czech Republic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you will see in the third quarter, we will be the first one to pass on really to the consumer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. And then I wanted to ask two more quick ones. The first one again in relation to an earlier question. As you've raised your guidance for the year, have you also reflected perhaps some increases in marketing and a promotion in this higher guidance? So are your spending levels going higher even as your guidance is going higher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have reflected in that guidance that we have a skewing of expenses towards the second half, and we have reflected in that guidance the additional investments that we plan to make in a number of markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the last question I have for you is related to volume. In the quarter, Marlboro was a little weaker than I expected. But you did have a little tougher comparison there too. But given all the new product benefits, a pretty robust R&amp;D pipeline across your portfolio, is the second half of the year when you're closer or on track with kind of getting at least within the range of your volume, your long term volume growth of 1% to 2%? Or the second half being &#x2013; is that a period where you could see that being a little below that long term guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look I mean, we will keep on working as much as we can on our innovation pipeline, on excellence in marketing and sales, out in the market, we are really pleased to see the improvement in the second quarter here. We will do everything to stay on track and to keep on improving and to keep on refilling the innovation pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the second half, could volumes be up closer to 1%? Or should we see consistent progress I guess I should say sequentially in your volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I wouldn't want to change the volume projection that we have given earlier for the year. I would rather prefer that we keep on working as good as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Jon Leinster with UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, Nick and Hermann. A couple of quick ones. First of all, you believe in the number of times the marketing's been down in the second half, as of the sort of percent of net revenues, was there any sort of growth in the first half, or was it essentially sort of flat as a percentage of sales in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Flat in the first half, growth in the second.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Correct. And just secondly, on the &#x2013; clearly the EU proposals to include this idea of a much closer alignment between added tax on factory made cigarettes and roll-your-own, what do you think is the future of roll-your-own, that would raise within the European Union if this proposal is passed in any shape or form?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look &#x2013; first I mean the proposal is not full equalization so therefore there will be always a role for that segment, because even in that proposal there remains a substantial price differential and tax advantage still for this type of products. So there will be always that part of the market. Will there be a in such a constellation, more up-trading to cigarettes? I would hope so, nevertheless, we are also very present in that market and we're increasing as we speak, our presence in that market, take Germany as the best example or take the acquisition of the Interval Trademark as the second example. So there is always some market there even with such a change in the excise system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And do you think its slightly the quarter double digit or significant decline in volumes in some of those markets where the amount is questions on the tax even if the market continues to exist?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it would be very much speculation at this point in time. Let's wait until we have something more final there on what really is going to come out of the EU Commission then you can see what that means, in terms of roll over prices and then we can have a better view of what that can eventually mean. That's too early.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lastly just on Japan I mean you obviously mentioned the, cigarette market is down to 1.6, I've tried but, thought cost implementation of the year. Vending machine age. All right I think realized that the market wrapped enquire. Why is, why was the related a big, trade impact almost, because of the change in vending machine age for verification and also, I determined to this age verification has been done with machines over time &#x2013; implemented over time. And secondly you know, how &#x2013; how successful, how this sort of implementation of this sort tax level they would top be. Is there been a wreckage shift. Is the OTC in Japan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. first in terms of implementation that has been implemented really by region, by area, so now in the Tokyo area was the last area that was being implemented now actually in July. So it's full year rolled out now you kind of in every area you had the load and the de-loading impact of then one de-loaded the next area loaded so it's very hard to read for the moment what the real impact is. We will now in the next two or three months because now it's everywhere.</p>
          <p>The test per card actually where it started as low as 15% or something in the area when it was the first area where it's was rolled out in that very same area the penetration is now about one third of the people. Who have that card so it's improving but it's of course still far away from a 100% of the smokers applying for such a card. So over time it will increase. Will there be a substantial shift in convenient stores, yes. And that's of course what we have prepared in our sales programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So does that means that it might as well be quite a substantial asset write-off for a lot of these vending machine cards, that access both the all of the packet come some of the retailers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now I can of course only speak for ourselves. In our case, we did adapt our vending machine part already somehow before all that came into place. So it's not a surprise for us and therefore there are no surprise write-offs that I would expect in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jonathan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Ann Gurkin with Davenport. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just wanted to ask you about leaf cost that you've highlighted in your presentation I think 550 is that still a number you are using?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, look I mean the leaf situation is has I said before just stays an area of concern. Supply is below demand. But we'll have to focus on that this is manageable just may be best is I give you kind of the proportion simply hot numbers of the first half. We have a leaf inventory sitting on our balance sheet of $4.1 billion. That means duration of our leaf inventory well beyond one year.</p>
          <p>The year-to-date income statement cost expense of leaf in the first half of the year is $1.7 billion. You have to put that in to relation to the net revenues excluding excise tax which is $13 billion and the actual price impact that we've had price increase impact that we've had year-to-date June is some $50 million so it's there its $50 million &#x2013; $50 million and we take it serious and you look at that, how to increase supply but the overall thing is of course manageable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But that 550 number is that still a number you are using through 2010 or is that number going...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are still using correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Still using that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then if I can just get an update also on China. I think you are licensing Marlboro production with the Chinese and by first distributing some of their brands. Can we just get an update on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, China domestic, the licensed production has actually started in two factories, in Changsha and in Longgang. So we are very pleased that a major step forward and the products will be on the Chinese market in the month of August.</p>
          <p>On the international JV side, we're also progressing. RGD, Red Golden Dragon, which has been launched in Czech, is having 0.5% share, 0.4% in Slovak and has just now been launched also in Poland. Dubliss we're doing which is a mid-price trend. Doing test market launches now, in the Ukraine and then Russia. It's launched in Romania, in May this year.</p>
          <p>By the end of the year, you are going to have six market launches out of international JV. So, yes we're making progress, steady progress going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. That's all I have, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, your next question is from Phia O' Rigufta with Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello just follow up on your prepared remarks, if I could. You indicated, at the end of your remarks that you would expect to continue access to capital markets in the second half of the year provided that markets are suitable and how they believed that you had indicated that if you were to come to market again, it would likely be in Europe, wanted to know if that was still the case; and then secondly if you could just highlight your leverage target for the end of the year. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yes, we of course look also at other currencies. Your first question clearly ignores it is not just the U.S dollar but it's also the other major currencies like Euro, Swiss Francs, that's what we look at.</p>
          <p>The leverage for the year, well right now we're at net debt to equity ratio of something like 0.4, so we keep ample flexibility and in that sense nothing has changed in terms of what we had said earlier, what the share repurchase program is and so on so forth but, that's the way we go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Pam Yook with Financial Times. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Hermann. I've just a couple of quick questions. I mean I guess one which is the follow-up to capital market which the analyst before me just asked. I was wondering how much are you looking &#x2013; I mean what are your credit facilities at the moment and what I mean do you have any idea of how much you would access in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well would decided that how much the amounts once we get to the market, so that is something I wouldn't want to reveal already right now. You have seen that we have done a very successful $6 billion bond offering in May. Its really what we believe very attractive rates that's an weighted average of 5.7%.</p>
          <p>That I believe really, really good and we look at the other ones as they come and we look at the moment in &#x2013; what the market gives and then we look also at the right size. So it's nothing you really can say well ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the sums weight, would that be to continuity share buy-back program or are looking perhaps to some acquisitions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look it is for the overall business, these funds provide us the flexibility for all of it, for share buy-backs, for acquisition should that be attractive acquisitions, we always look at them but I will of course not go further than that. So really for the overall business it's nothing year marked us specifically to one or the other activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And this time last year we were discussing a bit wave of consolidation within the tobacco sector, do you think there is still room for further industry reconsolidation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do not expect the large scale industry consolidation that you have seen in the last two years. I would not expect any thing of that size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And given how and &#x2013; how sales and revenue &#x2013; given the sales and revenue performance in your European business, I was just wondering whether you can perhaps elaborate bit more on your strategy for Europe and how you plan &#x2013; I mean when do you think growth will stabilize any time, do you think sales or revenue will stabilize any time soon or are we looking at a kind of a continue decline in the European markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The European market I would say is a market where of course in terms of overall market size, this is going to continue to decline. I think that European markets, EU markets will probably decline on a mid-term basis between 1 and 2% going forward.</p>
          <p>That doesn't necessarily mean that revenues decline because as I said the pricing power is intact, so vast volumes certainly will go down in that part of the world, that does not mean that therefore profitability is going to go down. That's the big difference to say to the emerging markets but both mature and the emerging markets in that sense are good markets, they are just different.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you just see any acquisition opportunities and for as a far as your European business is concerned at the moment. I mean you mentioned earlier that the money rate is not earmarked any specific, but if there are kind of any attractive acquisition opportunities that would be some thing you would consider?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look we always look at acquisition opportunities around the world and if they are strategic fit and if they have attractive financial returns, then we look at that wherever that is around the world.</p>
          <p>At the same time we certainly have the financial flexibility to do them if we want to do them. But otherwise I really have to stop it there, because I cannot go into geographies or potential targets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What should the market PMI would be interested in getting into?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are overall a tobacco company and not just a manufactured cigarette company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, is that yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fine. That's all. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Chris Burritt with Bloomberg News. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hermann, thank you for your time. Could you provide an update on your activities in China and how soon we're going to see the cigarettes company coming and going to and from that country?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, look I mean, it's really our business in China is two-fold as I said on the China domestic side, that we are very pleased that we localized this production for Marlboro in those two Chinese factories have started and on the international JV side, where we are working with our Chinese partners on the commercialization of Chinese heritage products in the international arena.</p>
          <p>That is key to our relationship I believe, that we are today and that has always been our target, that the Philip partner offer CNTC China National Tobacco Cooperation. This is huge company, this is a huge market, and anything there you'll see will take time. This is not for tomorrow, in our guidance we've always said, that we don't expect in the short term substantial impact on our financials, be it volumes or be it dollars. However going forward, this is of course an extremely important business development market.</p>
          <p>And here I close them all that we are all happy that we have made progress again in the last couple of weeks with the start up of the license productions at Marlboro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so would it be accurate to say that Chinese smokers are now able buy Marlboros made in their country or is that still on the production and distribution stage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is being produced now, distribution will start in August however, there would be certainly more demand in China than the supply will be, this is supply driven market not a demand driven market. So it's not that Marlboro is available in any desired quantities around the country, once it start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, you're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your final question is from Thomas Russo with Gardner Russo &amp; Gardner. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pleased to play back up here at the and a terrific conference call on the long run, thank you Hermann. Hermann, in your release you mentioned that one interesting factor was that Marlboro impact of the allocation of duty-free in the U.S. over to all to your firm PMI, and I wonder how as you look out over time and PMI develops a portfolio local markets is how is to look different from Altria's portfolio.</p>
          <p>How will this relation best in PMI's interest when travelers return to their homeland look to buy products and duty free they make their relationship to those products which Marlboro naturally addressees? So how would you guess the proper marketing support and encouragement from for those travelers with this arrangement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, look I mean the split of a trademark between geographies is nothing unusual and you see it in many other trademarks as well. I mean the genes and the origins and the backbone of Marlboro is what Marlboro stands for and nobody on either side of the Atlantic is going to change what really Marlboro stands for.</p>
          <p>That being said, Marlboro has always been adapted to the taste, to the preferences of the consumers around the world and it's actually extremely important, I mean, the best example is probably Marlboro Filter Plus, which has tremendous success in a number of markets. Take one Romania, it's now 1.5% national share and 2.3% in the city of Bucharest. I bet you that Marlboro Filter Plus is a 1 milligram product would not sell much in the U.S. so it's a normal situation, I would think and nothing that concerns me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And think of some more questions about the dividend payout ratio and it raises a broader question about the role of currency and reported results. Assume a year and half from we have a vastly different currency fixture, what steps did PMI take going forward to protect against the possible reversal of the dollar supply on its OCI and its net and accordingly on the dividend that you eventually project from that net interest. What steps do you take to buffer against the OCI impact of currency?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Look I mean we always look at the transactional exposures. I give you one example. It's, for example, the dollar denominated purchases of leaf tobacco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's something we always we look at, but its always transactional hedges. We have not done in the past and its not our policy to do a speculative hedges there going forward, I believe we stick to our business to our underlying business that has always been our philosophy in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And by the way, just as in side, the fact that you are providing in China. And it wasn't really highlighted on the printed there release. I think you've been far too modest, I know that Louie has spent the enormous amount of time getting to this point. And I would have thought that you would have celebrated a little bit, that you actually up and running and producing in China. That's quite a milestone, are there any Virginia blend Marlboros, or said that American blend Marlboro is being produced. Are there any other western manufacturers in such a position today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is an American blended product that is being produced, there it is through Marlboro in there. So I mean to difference, and that will let others speak for themselves. But the difference really is, that we've an agreement with the top of China National Tobacco and not just this affect somewhere in the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That I think is key to future success. And we're happy about it. About the recent achievements in China believe me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think you should be &#x2013; congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I'd like to hand it back over to management for any further or closing remark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well thank you very much for joining us today. I just want let everyone know that the Investor Relations team is available in Lausanne, Switzerland if you have any follow-up questions and you can reach us at the telephone number that's in our press release today.</p>
          <p>Thank you for joining us. And have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This does conclude today's Philip Morris's International second quarter 2008 earnings conference call. You may now disconnect your line and have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>