<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1296107" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1568</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Denita C. Stann, Senior Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">William J. Doyle, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Fai Lee</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">G. David Delaney</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Elaine Yip</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">PJ Juvekar</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Vincent Andrews</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Robert Koort</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Jacob Bout</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Don Carson</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">David Silver</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Garth Moore</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Edlain Rodriguez</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Jeff Zekauskas</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Michael Piken</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep">Wayne Brownlee</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">David Begleiter</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Charles Rentschler</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Mark Gulley</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Hari Sambasivam</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Aleem Ladak</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Potash Corp First Quarter Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the conference over to Denita Stann, Senior Director, Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brock. Good afternoon. Thank you for joining us and welcome to our first quarter earnings call. In the room with us today we have Bill Doyle, our President and CEO; Wayne Brownlee, our Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer; Jim Dietz, Executive Vice President and Chief Operating Officer; Joe Podwika, Senior Vice President and General Counsel; Garth Moore, President of PCS Potash; Tom Regan, President of PCS Nitrogen and Phosphate; and David Delaney, President of PCS Sales.</p>
          <p>I'd like to welcome the media who are listening in and remind people that we are live on our website. I would also like to remind everyone that today's call may include forward-looking statements. Such forward-looking statements are given as of the date of this call and involve risks and uncertainties. A number of factors and assumptions were applied in the formulation of such statements and actual results could differ materially. For additional information with respect to forward-looking statements, factors and assumptions, we direct you to our news release and our most recent Form 10-K.</p>
          <p>Also today's news release, which is posted on our website, includes a reconciliation of certain non-GAAP financial measures to their most directly comparable GAAP measures.</p>
          <p>I'll turn the call over now to Bill Doyle for some comments and then we'll go to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Denita. Thank you. And good afternoon, everyone. And thank you for joining us for Potash Corp's first quarter conference call.</p>
          <p>This quarter marked the beginning of a significant and positive transition for our business. Over the past 18 months we operated in very challenging conditions brought on by the global economic downturn. But as we have often stated, food production and fertilizer are essential industries that will inevitably rise above tough times.</p>
          <p>The simple truth is that people need to eat and to produce enough food for almost 7 billion people, farmers around the world need fertilizer. Nutrients that are essential to human development are drawn from the soil by crop production and must be replaced. This is basic crop science.</p>
          <p>Every crop harvested is equivalent to taking money out of the bank and the record crops of recent years have resulted in large nutrient withdrawals from the soil. Taking out more than you put back is not sustainable and farmers must return to the practice of making deposits to keep their soils productive.</p>
          <p>With crop prices remaining profitable and well above historical levels, farmers are recognizing the opportunity and returning to more normal fertilization practices. Most distributors emptied their bins in 2009 and now are coming back to producers for Potash, phosphate and nitrogen to meet their customers' needs. In this environment, Potash Corp.'s quarterly earnings reached $1.47 per share, the second highest first quarter total in our history. This included $715.1 million in gross margin, with almost three-quarters of that generated by Potash, our core nutrient.</p>
          <p>We benefited from higher sales volumes in all three nutrients, most significantly in Potash. North American farmers were the first to respond to the scientific needs of their soils, and we shipped a record 1.3 million tons of Potash to domestic customers in the first quarter. Our offshore sales volumes also rebounded strongly to 1.2 million tons, more than triple the produced volumes of the same period last year.</p>
          <p>While first quarter global volumes demonstrated that nutrient demand is reemerging, some observers have not fully appreciated that a recovery is underway, creating a drag on fertilizer stock prices in recent weeks. Suggestions of lackluster crop prices have garnered significant attention. Without question, global crop prices are an important factor in our business. However, fertilizer demand and prices do not rise and fall with day-to-day movements in crop commodities markets. When you look at the bigger picture, today's crop prices are well above historical averages. That makes the economics of farming and proper fertilizer use very attractive.</p>
          <p>At current corn prices, a North American farmer is spending less than 4% of projected revenue on Potash, and is capturing historically high returns over input costs. As we saw in the first quarter, farmers in the United States are making that investment in fertilizer and are off to a fast start with spring planting. This has raised the expectation of a bumper crop in the U.S. In reality, a fast start only increases the likelihood of an early harvest. Growing conditions through the summer months will ultimately determine the success of a crop.</p>
          <p>More importantly, the U.S. is only one piece of the puzzle. There is a tendency to view global agriculture through a North American lens. The world needs significant production in every major growing region to keep pace with rising food demand. In Southeast Asia, the El Ni&#xF1;o weather pattern and reduced fertilizer consumption over the past 18 months have impacted crop production, resulting in palm oil and rice prices 60% above the 10-year average, while Brazilian farmers are completing a record soybean harvest and benefiting from strong sugar and soybean prices.</p>
          <p>Monsoon developments will be closely watched in India this summer after the crop production shortfall of last year. In China, extreme drought in the southwest and cold temperatures in the north have muted farmer engagement, the third consecutive year that fertilizer applications, especially for Potash, have been below normal levels. This is expected to impact crop production this growing season and has contributed to higher commodity prices. China continues to import record soybean volumes, and just recently purchased some U.S. corn for the very first time, which is a positive development for the global corn market.</p>
          <p>The Chinese government recognizes its food production challenge and is introducing initiatives to promote balanced fertilization. In late February, China's Ministry of Agriculture announced a soil survey-based fertilization program, which will send 100,000 experts and agronomists into the field to provide training and support to an estimated 160 million farmers. By helping Chinese farmers understand soil surveying and balanced fertilization, the country is hoping to improve the nutrient balance on 180 million acres over time.</p>
          <p>India has similar motivations, as annual food price inflation in that country is continuing at more than 15%. With its growing population and strengthening economy, food security is a major concern, which is why India's government recently implemented a nutrient-based subsidy program to address imbalances in its soils.</p>
          <p>With Potash under applications to be addressed in most developing regions, we believe the long-term demand potential is significant. The key to our business and to the way we operate at Potash Corporation is to look at longer-term patterns and trends. Changing diets, urbanization and growing population are expected to put unprecedented stresses on the food chain. In the next decade alone, global population is forecast to grow by an estimated 800 million people. More than twice the population of North America. Much of that growth will occur in Asia. According to the International Monetary Fund, economic output in emerging Asian nations has already surpassed levels prior to the economic downturn. As we have witnessed in the past, more people with higher incomes drives the desire for more food and healthier diets, which translates into the need for more fertilizer.</p>
          <p>After a sharp decline in 2009, the Potash market is in a period of transition. Demand is returning and the current forecast for 2010 global consumption is approximately 50 million tons. Still below the estimated historical trend line of around 55 million tons. Fertilizer distributors, many of whom experienced losses in 2009, are still motivated to end the season with empty bins.</p>
          <p>In North America we expect this will result in second quarter shipments above last year but below historical levels. With limited inventory in the supply chain this sets up for strong domestic shipments in the second half of the year. In offshore markets we anticipate ongoing strength in Southeast Asia, while demand in Latin America will begin accelerating towards the end of the second quarter. China and India are both expected to require additional tonnage in the back half of the year.</p>
          <p>As purchasing continues to meet immediate needs, global Potash producer inventories are being drawn down. North American producer inventories are now 21% below the 5-year average. We are confident that scientific requirements will return consumption to the historical trend line growth. In addition, as distributors around the world begin to refill the supply chain, and farmers address shortfalls created by mining the soils in 2009, demand could climb higher then trend line consumption. We anticipate a strong multi-year growth period will put pressure on Potash supply in the years ahead providing the opportunity for improved margins.</p>
          <p>Moving forward we are very optimistic about the potential for our company. There is a simple truth about the Potash business and that is you cannot buy time. Building capacity takes years to complete. Whether you're looking at brownfield expansions, or a greenfield operation. The long-term Potash expansion program that we launched in 2003 has continued through the economic downturn, helping us prepare for projected demand growth in the years ahead. By 2015 we expect to have more than 17 million tons of annual operational capability, roughly double the level we had when we started our expansion program 7 years ago. Our projects represent the largest portion of brownfield expansions underway anywhere in the world. We expect this will be increasingly valuable as demand grows.</p>
          <p>While we bore the brunt of weaker market conditions in 2009, in a rising market we will have the capability to capture a greater share of new demand. In this environment we look forward to demonstrating our full Potash potential serving our customers and delivering greater returns to our investors.</p>
          <p>Given current conditions we expect 2010 earnings of $4.50 to $5.25 per diluted share. Including second quarter earnings in the range of $1.00 to $1.30 per diluted share. We view 2010 as an important step forward as we move toward longer-term demand growth. We believe the drivers of our business remain extremely favorable and our company is very well positioned to deliver long term value to all of our stakeholders.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your interest in Potash Corporation. I'm joined today by members of our executive management team and we would be pleased to answer any questions you might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now conduct the question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question today comes from Fai Lee of RBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Bill, just with respect to your guidance for this year I'm just wondering if you can maybe talk about some of the major assumptions behind your Potash, maybe phosphate and nitrogen with respect to pricing going forward, maybe directionally? Also with respect to your Q2 guidance range, I'm just wondering where it would fall if distributors, potash distributors, actually revert to a normal re-stocking pattern, which it appears that's not what you're assuming, but what if that did occur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I'm &#x2013; answer the first part of that question and then pass it on to David for the second part.</p>
          <p>In terms of our guidance, this is a recovery year in the Potash market in the fertilizer world and being such, it's uneven. We do think that the year will be one in which we will build momentum as we go through the year, but we are going to take it as it comes. I said that in the first quarter and I will say it again to you now. We do think that we are going to set ourselves up in 2010 for a very strong 2011. Very good years, 2011, '12, '13, it's just coming at us. You can see the rebound, the re-stocking that's going to be required, which is a multi-year process and this year is so far has worked out the way we thought it was going to work out but our guidance is to take it as it comes. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding &#x2013; Fai, regarding Potash domestically the industry moved 3.1 million tons in Q1. 2.2 million tons in the second half of '09. So we think for a 7 million ton year the industry will move about 1.8 million tons in Q2 and that assumes our customers, distributors, everyone ends the season empty. Now if you go back to previous years when we had a bit of a fell in the second quarter that number would probably grow by another million tons or so, but we're not forecasting that, we're forecasting a very strong second half. Dealer attitudes are terrific, it's been a great spring, we're off to a great start here in April, inventories have been depleted very quickly, people are coming back for resupply. Very optimistic attitude, but I would say 1.8 from an industry standpoint for the second quarter is the right number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Elaine Yip of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, how are you? Can you give us a sense as to whether Canpotex has been successful pushing through some of the price increases they announced in the global market. And then with regard to China and India, do you anticipate that Canpotex will sign for the contracts there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Elaine. Thank you. Canpotex is working on the price increases I would say in Brazil. It's a work in progress still. We have not attained those increases yet but keep in mind Brazil is early in the process, although I would say if you look at Brazil just as an indication of the change, if you look at the first quarter. Brazil in 2009 first quarter imported only 83,000 tons. During the first quarter of 2010 1.133 million; so quite a bit difference. And that's typical of what we're seeing, and this is well before the June to September demand period.</p>
          <p>So as that period comes upon us &#x2013; and I was just down in Brazil a couple weeks ago and I would tell you that the Brazilian customers are very optimistic about what's happening there. And they see with this crop influenced by wonderful weather in Brazil this growing season. A tremendous amount of nutrient removal and where they say that they think there will be 5% up total NPK usage in Brazil. They're saying that that number could be stronger in that potash consumption and potash import requirements could be even stronger. So you're going to see that in that June/September picture and when you get that type of demand, you're going to see prices improve. And we think you'll see prices improve in that spot market of Brazil as we go towards the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other part of the question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China and India</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China and India, I do think both will take additional tonnage. China heavier than India but again we are pursuing quarterly contracts in those markets. We continue to think that that's the proper approach. We think it's the best for the marketplace. We think it's the best approach for both Indian and Chinese farmers, and I've explained why we do that. It's different than the iron ore people. We think that we have to have contracts that are honored, and when you have the obligation only on the suppliers part, that really doesn't work and you hold up the entire global marketplace in doing so. And that doesn't serve farmers anywhere, not Chinese farmers or Indian farmers or Brazilian farmers or North American farmers. It doesn't serve any farmers to have that type of scenario, and we think it's just going to be a lot healthier for the market. We think that will come and be recognized in 2011 as this demand goes back to trend line growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from PJ Juvekar of Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Good afternoon. Your forecast for Chinese demand is about 8.5 to 9 million tons. What do you think is the underlying demand, assuming normal weather? And then secondly what is your intelligence on how fast China is expanding its internal potash capacity at the Qinghai Salt Lake? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. PJ, what I would say in terms of internal production, the Qinghai Salt Lake being the biggest producer. You're looking at about 4.5 million tons. They were 4.4 last year, it would be 4.5 this year. We're really getting up towards the top end in terms of myriad. We've got some SOP production, but that's used for different crops. So if you say that they're going to have 4.5 million tons of domestic production, we think that they are going to import a total of 5 million tons this year. And they've imported a range for imports already this year of about 2.5 million.</p>
          <p>So we think, and keep in mind you've also got some rail, which will be about 1.2 million. So that would leave you with about, according to our calculations, about 1.3 million left to be imported into China, and that's assuming consumption is going to be in the 9, 9.5 million ton range. So you have to have a little bit more inventory than you will actually consume. China, as you will recall, in 2007 consumed 11 million tons, and then in 2008 and 2009 went down to 7 million tons. That is not sustainable. They are getting off to a slow start, because of the weather issues we addressed in our remarks, but you're still sitting here at the end of April and we understand now they're getting going and we think that consumption is going to be pretty strong.</p>
          <p>When you see China import corn, I don't know how many of you have picked up on this, but there's a 115,000 ton corn order from China, which just came out yesterday. There's indications that that is going to, there's going to be more behind this. We have been waiting for China to import corn for a number of years. If you'll recall, China used to be a 15 million ton corn exporter. So for China to go from being a corn exporter to a corn importer has spectacular consequences for the corn market, for the grain markets. I'm not sure that that is totally appreciated, but it speaks to the corn harvest in China last year, which we believe was overestimated, because they wouldn't be importing corn if they had produced as much corn as they said they produced last year, and the proof is in the pudding here.</p>
          <p>I think everyone, you know people have talked there are no catalysts for Potash prices out there. There won't be any catalysts for 3 weeks or 6 weeks. Or some of the outlooks that I've read and some of the reports, this is just one catalyst for fertilizer prices and Potash in particular that can really make a difference and get this market moving in a completely different direction than some people think we're seeing now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Vincent Andrews of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and good afternoon, everyone. My one question I guess is going to be, Bill, can you just talk about the price increase in the United States. In the press release this morning, you talked about it's just beginning to realize at the end of the quarter. So I guess, and the question really is, if the price increase is about to go through, help me reconcile why the distributor doesn't want to be stocking up now ahead of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Vincent. I'm just going to ask David to speak to distributor psychology, but I will tell you that as of today, we had a $30 increase put forth in March, and as of today we've gotten about half of that. So we've gotten about $15 so far. I've also read that we haven't gotten any of that by some people. I don't know how they know that, but we're at about half of that 30. Dave, do you want to talk about psychology of the distributors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the psychology, Vincent, really stems from last year, when there were a lot of write-downs primarily on nitrogen and phosphate. People have been stating all year, they want to end the season empty. That's been the stated motto of every one of our customers. So, as I mentioned to Fai earlier, we've had a terrific season, off take has been great. All of our customers have made money, the farmer is making money, but at the end of the day everyone wants to end the season empty and that's the psychology. So, we're expecting a very strong second half as I mentioned earlier and thus far in the quarter we have received $15 of our stated price increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vincent, you know getting back to this catalyst issue to significant price improvement in Potash. What I'd say is they are many and varied, but anyone of them could kick off a rapid change in the pricing environment. So when you see corn sold from the U.S. to China for the first time, that's a catalyst. When you see China realizing that it's cheaper to import Potash then it is to buy corn, that's also a catalyst. Dave just talked about the psychology in the U.S. but coming out of the spring season empty is going to lead to a strong summer fill in the U.S. at the same time that we're going to see strong demand from Brazil in the June to September time period, that could also be a catalyst.</p>
          <p>We've got this El Nino problem in Malaysia and Indonesia, palm oil prices are escalating, that could also be a catalyst. We've got continued record soybean imports into China, also a potential catalyst. The recognition in the marketplace of tightening supply/demand fundamentals of Potash that will drive the re-stocking of the supply chain. When that light goes on, also a potential catalyst. So, when you hear people say that there are no catalysts for the price of Potash to improve or change, it just shows a fundamental lack of understanding all the nuances that are in this marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Robert Koort of Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Bill, I was wondering if you could talk a little bit, you mentioned your moving to short run contracts in Potash with China. Can you maybe give a little more color on the basis for going long term in phosphates with India. Then secondly, if I could, you talked a little bit about how the producers psychology is changing as you guys think about second half export business, maybe more particularly what your fellow Potash producers, how they may change, how they approach the market with seeing 6 months ago they were negotiating from a point of weakness, and I would suspect you'd believe as we go through the summer they will be negotiating from a point of strength, so a position of strength. What changed the process, the dynamic and then maybe you can talk a little bit about pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's about an hour answer, Robert, I'm going to give you the short one and I'll try to get to you on your most important points. What I'd say when you look at China and India in terms of Potash, and again we're pursuing short-term contracts, cause we think that's the most logical way to go when you have a Potash market that we think is going to be supply challenged, and we think it makes most sense. We're getting an accurate reflection of what demand actually is. So it wouldn't be disguised, and we think that's going to be an overall benefit for farmers. In phosphate you have a totally different dynamic, different supply-demand fundamentals, but India alone as you know is the dominate player in phosphate on a global basis. They are the biggest importer in the world in phosphate. No one is a close second.</p>
          <p>So to take a longer-term position, you're referring to PhosCan, take a longer-term position there, and a 3-year deal makes sense, because it is a base load for the market. It gives a base from which to build price in all other markets, and it underscores bringing phosphate over a 3-year period of time. Keep in mind we've got some new additions to phosphate coming into the marketplace over that 3 years. And that also carries you through that period of time. So phosphate is a completely different situation, and one of the important things I think in managing a company in our business is to understand the differences between the nutrients and the way that you need to manage them. You don't manage them all the same. Some people do, and I think they make a big mistake and they shortchange their shareholders in the process.</p>
          <p>In terms of the psychology of our competitors, that's something that's beyond an hour explanation. It would take maybe a couple of months, because it's very perplexing, but I will say to you that I have noticed, I spoke about nervous suppliers the last conference call, and that's just a fact. We don't only have nervous suppliers in the offshore markets, we have nervous suppliers in the domestic markets. So it's not unique to international players.</p>
          <p>But I will say that once these suppliers get comfortable again, I mean the nervous sellers tend to get comfortable when they get a certain volume of business, and I would say that the most nervous suppliers have taken the biggest pieces of India and China, and now they're becoming more comfortable. I think as the year goes on and the momentum in the spot market continues to grow, that they will become calmer and will see that price long term has to be reflective of costs, which is what we've maintained all along. And they'll understand crop economic prices a little bit better, and the returns and the many facets of determining what is a fair price in the marketplace. So I've always been curious, I could probably write a book on this subject. I've been studying it for years and it still remains a bit of an enigma.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jacob Bout of CIBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I had a question just on offshore pricing. When we take a look at some of the benchmarks here, India being down at 370 a ton CFR. Maybe you can just walk us through what happened in the quarter, when you had the realized price of 286. Was that freight hedging or were you selling at lower pricing? And then maybe you can give us an idea where you're selling into Indonesia and Thailand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well keep in mind, Jacob, that 370 is a deliver price into India, and 286 is an FOB mine price Saskatchewan. So you got to take the ocean freight off. You've got to take the terminal costs off. You've got to take the rail from Saskatchewan to Vancouver off. You've got to take 180 day terms, which are also included in the Indian price, off. So by the time you take all of that off, you get some number that's close to $286. That's how it works. So you can't confuse delivered pricing with FOB mine pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Don Carson of UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Bill question &#x2013; a follow-up on your question about nervous sellers and how they're depressing prices. Are you finding that you're having to once again act as a swing producer and take a little less market share this year? Is that implicit in your volume guidance? And then just a follow-up on Brazil. You've always been under pressure to provide more P and K to that market. We've seen you make a move in phosphate with Bunge, and it appears that they want to build some mines in both Brazil and Argentina, do you see more capacity coming on line over time in South American in Potash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's cover the nervous producers first, and then I'll talk about the second part.</p>
          <p>We've always matched supply to demand, and that's the way we continue to operate. We said in our quarterly release that with our capacity this year over 11 million tons of operational capacity, we're going to initiate shutdowns, because we're not going to sell that much, and so we won't produce that much. That's been &#x2013; over the long term that's proved to be a very successful formula for us.</p>
          <p>Do we take a little less in a weaker market? Yeah. Yeah, we have. If you go back in time, you look at it, we always take the biggest hit when the market is slow, and when the market grows and is dynamic and the levels that we think we're going to see in 2011, '12, and '13, we're going to take a much bigger piece, cause we're the only ones with capacity. It's that simple. Yes. We take a little less when the market is weak.</p>
          <p>In terms of new mines in Brazil and Argentina, the permit for this Carnalita project near Sergipe by Vale, that's a permit, but that project is challenged. Kind of like, as you know, Don, you've been doing this a long time, Carnalita is not exactly the greatest ore body to dig into. It is full of challenges and it's high cost and it's &#x2013; I'll be surprised if they go ahead with that one. The Amazon project, that's been around forever, and also extraordinarily challenged. I'd be surprised if that one will ever reach fruition.</p>
          <p>Argentina, they paid quite a bit for those reserves, but it's an extraordinarily expensive project that has a lot of infrastructure associated with it.  I think right now that's the most expensive greenfield project in the world for the tons that they will get out of it. I don't know whether that one will go ahead.</p>
          <p>You know it's interesting that Vale have changed quite a bit here over the last 6 months. Vale was a minor player in Brazil in fertilizer. All of a sudden they became the major player; buying Bunge's phosphate operations, Fosfertil taking Mosaic and Yara out. They're a big player. They just spent over $5 billion to get that right, and I've always been impressed with Vale as being a company that understands the value of the dollar and understands that you've got to make a return on their investment. I think they've got a very smart CEO, so I don't see him doing anything foolish. And right now I'd put Argentina in the foolish category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Dave Silver of Banc of America- Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Bill I was hoping you could clarify one of your earlier statements in your prepared remarks. You talked about 17 million tons of operational capacity by 2015. And if I recall I think earlier you were targeting I guess 18 million tons by the end of 2012 or so. So is that your difference between mechanically complete and operational, or what would account for maybe the difference between those targets and actual amounts of capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Hi, David. I'm going to ask Garth to respond to that one and explain it to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David. The difference between the two numbers is two-fold actually. The initial numbers we were looking at is 18 million tons of mechanical capacity basically, or capacity. And the 17 million tons that Bill was talking about or 17-plus, is operational capability which is less than 100% of capacity and the timing is basically the original dates that went out or just basic completion of the mechanical and instillation so that's the difference in the two time frames, plus a little bit of a few month slow down in a couple of our projects pushing them out at 3 or 4 months, but other than that, that's the difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David and this might speak to a little bit more to Don's question also. The economics of these projects. And when I say I think Argentina would be in the foolish category, if you look at that first quarter average export price we have at $285. Well, that will work for our brownfield, but in order to get greenfield and a minimum return of 10% on your investment for a 2 million ton mine with 2.8 million Saskatchewan economics just within the plant gate and then you add infrastructure, you get up around $4 billion. You've got to have a return to get that 10% of at least $600. And if you want to take that to a 15% return, which is the way we do it, because keep in mind you've got that money sitting out there for at least a 7-year period with no return whatsoever, 15% return gets you up closer to $900. So you've got a price of 285 FOB and you've got a project in Argentina which is going to require at least $600 FOB mine to justify.</p>
          <p>The Vale people are smart. They're not going to sit there and say well wow, why would we do that? It doesn't make sense. And a lot of these projects and people give so much credence to everybody that says they're going to do something. They're going to drill, spend a couple million bucks to drill some holes. The difference between drilling a couple holes for a couple million dollars and building one of these projects is enormous.</p>
          <p>And any Board of Directors, I can guarantee you, if you go to Vale's Board of Directors, or BHP's Board of Directors or any other one, and the board said OK Mr. so and so what's return on this investment of 5 billion, 4 billion in certain cases, one of the projects is a $10 billion, what's the return? Well you know what we got a negative return on the project today. The board members would look at you like you got a hole in your head, I mean that's just not the way business works and so I would just like to see a little bit more scrutiny and a little bit more discernment when people look and just take all these projects for granted. And again the proof is in the pudding. None of them are underway. So if it was such a hot spit deal, we'd be doing it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Edlain Rodriguez of Broadpoint Gleacher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Bill can you talk about the impact of Russian and Israeli Potash coming into North America that could potentially undermine the current price increase on the table, and do you see those as opportunistic sales or something more sustainable. In the sense that is this a reflection that there is excess supply in the market and if there's excess supply what gives you confidence that you can place the foregone sales to China, why not do it in a contract like other producers to other markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Edlain, I'm going to ask David to respond to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Edlain, we have always, the U.S. has imported Russian Potash for several years. Israeli Potash has been intermittent, there has been a little bit that has arrived this year. Year-to-date imports January through March are 161,000 tons. As I mentioned we sold 3.1 million tons as an industry in Q1. So yes it's there, maybe it's had a minor impact on the river but it doesn't dictate what we do in the marketplace as Potash Corp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it shows any, when you look at those numbers, as David just said, it really doesn't give you a very good indication that there's any excess supply out there. I don't think that's the case. I don't think it's going to make a bit of difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Jeff Zekauskas of J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. BPC and Israel Chemicals have committed to sell Potash to India through March of 2011. Because they've done that at a stipulated price of I guess 370 delivered, does that mean that if Canpotex chooses to sell to India they also would sell at that price? Or does Canpotex have room to negotiate a different price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I'd say to you is we are not going to sign onto any year-long commitment in India or China for that matter. We just think that's a mistake, and we think by the time those contracts are up next March 31, that the market is going to be considerably different than that, so we'll see who's right by that time. But the material that we delivered to the private sector here that we're starting to deliver, we start up in April, that is priced at the 3 70, but that is a quarterly price. So that's as far as we're going to go. So as India comes in the second half of the year for more tonnage, then we'll take a look at it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Michael Piken of Cleveland Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I have a question on the cost side. If you could give a little bit more color behind how many shutdown weeks you're anticipating over the next couple of quarters? And then also if you could provide sort of an update in terms of what type of rate we should expect for the provincial mining taxes? That would be real helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Well, I'm going to split that up. I'm going to have Garth talk about our mining shutdowns, what his thoughts are there. I'm going to ask Wayne to comment on the tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, as far as the shutdowns go, as Bill mentioned about the capacity we're slightly over 11 million tons this year, and their forecast was between, it's considerably less than that. So, we've already announced one shutdown at Rocanville of 5 weeks and all of our plants are having 4-week maintenance vacation shutdowns during the July-August period. Cory has to go down, or we're doing some major modifications there, because of our expansion project. We have to change out our hoisting system and our production shaft, and that's going to take us down to around 13 weeks.</p>
          <p>And the other shutdowns we haven't really planned yet if we're going to tie them in with how the market goes and how the sales move. So that they'll depend a certain amount on what our sales forecast is. There will be certainly some additional shut-downs in the third and fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Wayne, do you want to talk about the tax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The tax that we're paying actually is really the resource surcharge in Saskatchewan, which was for the first quarter was represented almost all the entire amount of the tax that we're paid. That's because of the capital spending that we're doing in Saskatchewan, it is deductible against the profit margin, which basically negates any base payments or profits tax liability. So if you just want a modeling answer, I would be in a 4 to 5% against total gross margin for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from David Begleiter of Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Bill, if the world returns to trend line consumption in 2011, how much of that additional 5 million tons should you guys capture. And just on China, what is the long-term demand potential of that market? Is it above that 11 million tons we did in 2007?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first part of your question, how much of the additional 5 million will we capture? I don't know yet. If this thing gets going, and of course you get up to 56 million tons, and of course then there's an inventory rebuild, you're going to go above trend line here. In that 2011, '12, '13, you're going to go way above trend line to get back to trend, plus growth. People don't take into account growth. The market is growing. People are adding more people as I said in my remarks. This balance, need for balanced nutrition, I mean you see what India's doing with their new nutrient subsidy scheme. You see what China's doing. We're going to have a renewed appreciation for the importance of balanced nutrition, for plants, potash being the nutrient in least supply, that's going to put pressure on the system. So you're going to see quite a bit of growth here.</p>
          <p>To answer your question, I don't know exactly of the additional 5 million. The second, the long-term growth in China, that's pretty simple when you look at the science part of it. Again being so important for everyone to remember that this is a science-based business, but China consumed 11 million tons in 2007. The China Soil Science Academy along with the International Plant Nutrition Institute has said that China needs to be at 26 million tons of Potash consumption to get a balance with nitrogen and phosphate, and do that over the next 15 years. So we know China is going to come back and be a very strong customer. There's a limit to what they can do with domestic production.</p>
          <p>There's so much brine you can take out of the lake before you destroy the balance, so China's going to be as we said before. Minimum 75% dependent on imports, so as the market grows, and by the way when it comes back, if China is the real wild card because when it pops up you're growth is tremendous. We've always held our breath over the years. When China goes on one of its growth spurts it's the dickens for everybody to keep up with it and you'll see that in the next couple year period. China's really going to take off again and we've got to be ready for it, and we will be ready for it. But a lot of growth in China. China will be the biggest Potash market in the World, despite the last couple of years where it's had lower consumption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Charlie Rentschler of Morgan Joseph.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill. Following up on that comment. I was struck by your earlier view of that the Chinese were taking a more businesslike approach to negotiations and remember several conference calls ago that you've spent quite a bit of time talking about their negotiating behavior, you weren't very pleased with it, but to the extent that they are going to short term contracts, maybe on a quarterly basis. Can you give us some insight as to why do you think that they've changed  their approach and what makes you think that this might continue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Charlie, I didn't mean to give you the understanding that they have changed yet. It's our impetus to change it and I would also say to you that I have tremendous respect for the Chinese negotiating capability. They're terrific. I mean, they are really good, tough negotiators and historically, they've kept their work. That's important. Unfortunately, during this last three year period the MOU that we had with China, between Canpotex and China, which ended December 31, 2009. The last year they didn't take anything. That was a very, very poor performance and they know it. They're aware of the fact that they didn't perform and that's not typical Chinese.</p>
          <p>But we do think because of they hold up that, that really caused the rest of the World, because everybody's waiting for China and as I said that doesn't do farmers anywhere any good and that's not good for food production. We just think it makes much more sense to have quarterly pricing that will give us a much better reflection of the actual market. So if the market's slower, we'll know that. If the market is more heated, we'll get a better reading there, too. So it's a work in progress. We do think that we'll have quarterly pricing in 2011 as a practice widespread because it makes sense. In this market, in a transition market, we've been the only ones to get that done, and we're going to stick with it because we think we're going to lead, and we think that it's important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mark Gulley of Soleil Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bill. Most of the discussion this afternoon has been about Potash, but of course you're also in the phosphates business. So can you talk a little bit about the raw material trends you're seeing in phosphates and whether or not you think you're going to be able to pass on some of those raw material increases in the form of higher selling prices? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Mark. I'm going to have David Delaney answer your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Mark. Sulphur was just announced up $145, a $55 increase here in Q2. Ammonia prices have settled at 405 for May, and my guess is they will trend down in the summer months, then bounce back up here as we get into September. Again there's been great off take for ammonia in the pipeline in the Midwest, so they'd have to be recharged, which is likely positive for ammonia throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Sulphur prices in the second half of the year, I think, will likely level off a little bit. Product selling prices have been covering the additional cost with the PhosCan contract to India. That net back is close to $435 per metric ton, which is profitable even with the sulphur price increase. Our LoMag, Poly, or other product lines are doing well. Also with the settlement in India on DAP, acid prices, MGA prices, have gone from 610 CFR to 775. So we look for a better year in our phosphate results here in 2010, even with the higher input cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Hari Sambasivam of National Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Just a couple of quick questions. Again, I had a phosphate related question. As the prices increase from say the November time period to right now, where you're sitting at close to $500 DAP or high 400s DAP, what kind of demand elasticity have you seen in the corn belt or other marketplaces? That was the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question I had is in relation to the rationale for the price increase in the corn belt. The price increase itself was announced multiple months ago, and I'm just curious as to what kind of rationale that you gave growers and wholesalers as to why that price is going to go up and now that the price, the price increase obviously has been resisted how do you go back and reinstitute a price increase down the road I mean, I'm just sort of thinking through the rationale of the explanations or how do you actually position that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Harry. I'm going to have David speak to that one as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Harry, with the phosphate price where it is the contribution margin as we mentioned earlier is still extremely good for both corn and soybeans. It's the fifth year in a row that we've seen really terrific returns for the U.S. farmer, but also if you look at returns around the World for all commodities are significantly up over on a 10 year high basis. If you look at phosphate demand, globally we're MAP, DAP and triple export demand is going to go from 18.9 to probably 21 million tons, so that's a good example.</p>
          <p>We think domestically in the U.S. we're going to produce about 11 million metric tons this year and we think there's demand between the offshore and domestic demand of close to 12 so that inventory number that is already tight will become tighter, but we haven't seen any push back at today's prices and in fact their map has run out throughout the Midwest, and most terminals, there is, so from a demand standpoint it's been extremely good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Brock, we'll have time for just one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The last question today comes from Aleem Ladak of Desjardins Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Most of my questions have been answered but one in particular I wanted to ask was do you think based on the occurrences of last year with regard to the standoff that the power has shifted onto the consumer side as opposed to the producer side where it's been for arguably a very long time, prior to last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, Aleem I don't know about the power thing, I mean that doesn't make any difference to us. We used to think that you've got to have a price that's reflective of reinvestment economics. It's pretty simple if you don't you're destroying value and &#x2013; we love our customers, and we want to do right by our customers, and we want to provide fair value, it just has to be reflective of economics.</p>
          <p>Some people don't think that way. Some people think that you just need to drive the price down whenever you get a chance and some people think you've got to drive it up whenever you get a chance and I would say a middle ground is reasonable but it has to be reflective of the economics of the industry. If it's not you're just going to have much more volatility and that doesn't serve anyone's interest and certainly it doesn't contribute to the important job of producing food for the global populous.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks Bill. Before we finish up today I would just like to remind everybody that we have an upcoming analyst meeting at the New York Stock Exchange on the afternoon of May 19 and registration and details are available on the home page of our Web site so we hope you're able to join us. Thank you for joining us for today's call and if you have any further questions, please don't hesitate to call our offices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call for today. Thank you for participating. Please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>