<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1509823" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>82997</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior VP-Investor Relations &amp; Strategy">Craig Clayton Reasor</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President &amp; Chief Financial Officer">Gregory Gene Maxwell</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive VP-Commercial &amp; Transportation">Timothy Garth Taylor</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Ed G. Westlake</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Doug T. Terreson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Simmons &amp; Co. International">Jeff A. Dietert</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Howard Weil, Inc.">Blake Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Katherine L. Minyard</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Inc. (Broker)">Faisel H. Khan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Paul Cheng</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Evan Calio</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James &amp; Associates">Cory Garcia</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Third Quarter 2012 Phillips 66 Earnings Conference Call. My name is Kim and I will be your operator for today's call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. Please note that this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Mr. Clayton Reasor, Senior Vice President Investor Relations, Strategy, and Corporate Affairs. Mr. Reasor, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kim. Good morning, and welcome to Phillips 66 Third Quarter Conference Call. We appreciate your interest in our company. Before we get started, we wanted to share our concern about those hurt by Hurricane Sandy. Many of our employees, shareholders, customers, and friends were impacted by this devastating storm. And we're supportive of efforts being made to help get lives back to normal. Our thoughts and prayers are with you all.</p>
          <p>Joining me this morning are Tim Taylor, EVP Commercial, Transportation, Business Development and Marketing, as well as Greg Maxwell, Executive Vice President of Finance and our CFO.</p>
          <p>We will give you details about our third quarter financial results, provide some guidance about the fourth quarter, and communicate our plans for growth and enhancing returns, which allow us to increase future distributions to shareholders.</p>
          <p>The presentation material we will use this morning can be found on the Investor Relations section of the Phillips 66 website, along with supplemental financial and operating information.</p>
          <p>Slide 2 contains our Safe Harbor statement. It's a reminder that we'll be making forward-looking statements during the presentation and our question-and-answer session. Actual results may differ materially from today's comments, and factors that could cause our actual results to differ are included here on the second page, as well as in our filings with the SEC.</p>
          <p>So that said, I'll turn the call over to our CFO Greg Maxwell to take you through our third quarter results.</p>
          <p>Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Clayton. Good morning, everyone. I'll start on slide 3 with some highlights for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Our reported earnings were $1.6 billion or $2.51 per share. Excluding approximately $300 million in special items, largely related to impairments, our adjusted earnings were $1.9 billion or $2.97 a share. Excluding special items, our year-to-date annualized return on capital employed is 21%, which is up from 18% in the second quarter, with cash from operations coming in at $1.9 billion. Consistent with our stated intent to return capital to our shareholders, we commenced our share repurchase plan in August, purchasing over $100 million of common stock during the quarter, and we also paid $125 million in dividends.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to slide 4 for a high level look at our third quarter adjusted earnings. Compared to the third quarter of 2011, our adjusted earnings increased by $369 million. Starting from the left side of the slide, Refining and Marketing generated $1.7 billion in earnings, with the majority of the $400 million improvement driven by much stronger refining margins, due largely by improved crack spreads. Midstream earnings were $56 million, which excludes the $133 million special item related to the impairment of our 25% ownership interest in the Rockies Express Pipeline.</p>
          <p>On an adjusted basis, midstream earnings were approximately $60 million lower than last year, and this decline in earnings reflects reduction in equity earnings from DCP midstream, driven primarily by lower NGL prices.</p>
          <p>Chemicals earnings of $275 million, which excludes $122 million of special items primarily associated with CPChem's early retirement of $400 million of debt, along with some asset impairments. Adjusted earnings were approximately $80 million higher than the corresponding quarter of 2011, and this was mainly due to higher margins and lower utility costs. I will cover each of these operating segments in more detail later in the presentation. Excluding $13 million of repositioning costs, corporate and other costs this quarter were $112 million. The negative $65 million variance is largely due to higher interest expense on debt that was not in place last year prior to the spin.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at cash flow for the third quarter as shown on slide 5. During the quarter, we generated $1.9 billion in cash from operations, including $200 million of positive impacts from net working capital changes. As noted on the slide, we funded $300 million for our capital program, primarily refining and marketing related, and returned more than $200 million to the shareholders in the form of share buybacks and dividends. Our cash balance increased by $1.3 billion, resulting in $4.4 billion in cash and cash equivalents at the end of the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to slide 6 for a look at our capital structure and our returns. We ended the third quarter with $21 billion in equity, and $8 billion of debt, resulting in a debt to capital ratio of 28%, which is 2% lower than last quarter. Taking into account our $4.4 billion ending cash balance, our net debt to capital ratio was 15%.</p>
          <p>On an adjusted basis, our year-to-date annualized return on capital employed was 21%. This is up from 14% in 2011. This improvement was driven primarily by higher earnings in our refining and marketing and chemicals segments. We ended the quarter with $29 billion in capital employed, up $2 billion compared to the second quarter. 74% of our capital employed was R&amp;M related, down from 76% in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Next we'll cover each of our operating segments in more detail, starting with Refining and Marketing on slide 7. In R&amp;M, we ran very well in a strong margin environment. Globally, we ran at a 96% utilization rate, despite our Alliance refinery being down for approximately 3 weeks, related to the impact of Hurricane Isaac, and our clean product yield was 83%. As part of our ongoing strategy to enhance returns, we are taking steps to process more North American advantage crudes.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter, 63% of our U.S. crude slate was advantaged, and this is up from an average of 61% for the first three quarters of the year. Marketing margins were lower this quarter, and we'll cover this in more detail later in the webcast. Our refining realized margin was $17.05 per barrel and our year-to-date annualized return on capital employed improved to 22% .</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to slide 8, where we'll cover adjusted earnings for Refining &amp; Marketing. Earnings for R&amp;M were $1.7 billion this quarter. This is up from $1.3 billion a year ago, reflecting significant improvements in our Atlantic Basin/Europe and Central Corridor regions, partially offset by lower earnings from Marketing, Specialties, and Other, or as we refer to it, MSO.</p>
          <p>In the Atlantic Basin region, earnings increased due to improved refining margins and lower controllable costs. Margins improved largely as a result of higher crack spreads, while controllable costs were lower primarily due to the Trainer and Wilhelmshaven refineries no longer being in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Gulf Coast earnings were up slightly due to higher refining margins, as market cracks were partially offset by lower product differentials and lower secondary product realizations. The Central Corridor improved significantly this quarter due to higher refining margins, reflecting our advantaged feedstock position in the region as the WTI/WCS differential widened. And we increased the amount of our sour crude processed at the Wood River and Ponca City refineries.</p>
          <p>The Western Pacific regions earnings were higher this quarter compared to a year ago, primarily due to higher refining margins. U.S. Marketing, Specialties, and Other was down by $95 million &#x2013; this is primarily due to lower margins and the negative impact associated with Hurricane Isaac. And internationally, MSO was down $60 million, mainly as a result of lower margins. The next few slides highlight our performance in Refining and provide more detail on MSO.</p>
          <p>So now turning to slide 9, Refining's adjusted earnings increased over $500 million, compared to a year ago. Improved margins were the key driver, with higher market cracks and higher feedstock advantages being partially offset by less favorable product differentials and secondary products.</p>
          <p>Earnings were up $55 million, as the result of higher volumes, mainly in the Central Corridor where we were able to take advantage of lower cost crudes. And we also had lower operating costs, largely due to no longer having the Trainer and Wilhelmshaven refineries in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Let's now take a look at our market capture shown on slide 10. Here we look at our global market and realized crack spreads. The market crack was very strong this quarter, and we captured nearly 80% of the market crack, up nearly 10% from the second quarter. Our realized margin for the quarter was over $17 per barrel, and we capitalized on these favorable margins by operating well, with a 96% utilization rate.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, our actual clean product yield for the quarter was 83%, which results in the $3.42 adjustment shown on the slide. The $5.39 per barrel reduction related to secondary products reflects the fact that the non-clean products we produced attracted a sales price which, on average, was lower than the cost of our benchmark crudes. The positive $4.82 per barrel for feedstocks stems from running crudes and other feedstocks that are priced lower than our benchmark crudes. Our feedstock advantage this quarter was primarily related to the Canadian heavy and foreign sour crudes that we processed, as well as increased shale and WTI-based crudes on the Gulf Coast.</p>
          <p>Finally, the Other category primarily reflects the impacts of product differentials. You'll see in the appendix that we've also included updated market indicator crack spreads for each of our regions.</p>
          <p>So moving on to slide 11, this slide shows that during the year we've increased advantaged crude runs at our refineries while also improving our clean product yield. Many of our refineries have the complexity to run advantaged Canadian crudes, and we have access to multiple transportation systems to reliably deliver these crudes to our U.S. refineries, resulting in an overall competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>U.S. advantaged crudes increased from 52% last year to 61% year-to-date in 2012, this was primarily driven by an increase in Canadian heavy crudes, as well as domestic WTI price linked streams, including an increase in the amount of shale crudes that we processed.</p>
          <p>Please note that the bar graph on the left has been updated from what we shared with you last quarter, as we are now providing additional detail on the different types of U.S. crude slates that we run.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to slide 12. Marketing, Specialties, and Other generated earnings of $95 million, that's $154 million lower than the same quarter last year. As shown on the slide, lower margins were the main driver for the decrease, accounting for approximately $130 million of the variance.</p>
          <p>We saw large swings quarter versus quarter, as we had gains last year related to inventory management compared with losses this year. Also impacting margins were product prices rising more sharply this year compared to last year, tied mainly to the impact or the impacts from Hurricane Isaac and lower gasoline exports.</p>
          <p>Volumes decreased over $30 million quarter over quarter, primarily due to reduced volumes resulting from a weaker power market, planned maintenance internationally, and from Hurricane Isaac domestically. Other includes favorable foreign exchange impacts. Year-to-date, MSO has generated earnings of over $500 million, which is in line with year-to-date earnings that we showed for 2011.</p>
          <p>Slide 13 shows our per barrel metrics. Refining &amp; Marketing's income per barrel improved this quarter to $6.37 per barrel, with cash contributions of $7.21 per barrel. This now completes our review of the Refining &amp; Marketing business segment.</p>
          <p>Next we move to the Midstream segment beginning on slide 14. Our Midstream segment was impacted this quarter by reduced equity earnings from DCP Midstream, largely driven by depressed NGL prices, as quarter over quarter prices were down 42%. Year-to-date our annualized return on capital employed was 28%, down slightly from the high of 30% in 2011. We ended the quarter with $800 million in capital employed in our Midstream segment. As mentioned earlier, during the quarter, reported earnings were negatively impacted by approximately $133 million associated with the after-tax, non-cash impairment of our equity investment in the Rockies Express Pipeline.</p>
          <p>As we move to slide 15, Midstream's adjusted earnings of $56 million were comprised of $39 million in earnings associated with our interest in DCP Midstream and $17 million from our other Midstream businesses.</p>
          <p>The next slide provides additional variance explanations for both DCP Midstream and other Midstream earnings. As shown on the top portion of this slide, earnings associated with our interest in DCP Midstream decreased by $48 million this quarter, mainly due to DCP's exposure to NGL prices. This was partially offset by a reduction in depreciation expense that is attributable to an overall increase in the remaining useful lives of DCP's assets that was implemented last quarter. Our other Midstream businesses were down $14 million, driven in part due to inventory impacts.</p>
          <p>Shifting now to a discussion of our Chemicals segment, please turn to slide 17. Our Chemicals segment consists of our 50% equity interest in Chevron Phillips Chemical Company or CPChem. CPChem had another great quarter, providing equity earnings of $275 million. CPChem achieved a 97% capacity utilization rate in its Olefins and Polyolefins segment, allowing it to capture the cost advantages in the North American and Middle Eastern ethylene and derivatives markets.</p>
          <p>Year-to-date annualized after-tax return on capital employed for our Chemicals segment increased from [sic] to 31% and this is up from 28% last year, and we ended the quarter with $3.6 billion in capital employed. Special items for the quarter included $122 million for losses associated with CPChem's early debt retirement and impairment of fixed assets, along with an increase in deferred tax liabilities related to the Phillips 66 spin from Conoco Phillips.</p>
          <p>The next couple of slides provide more detail on the Chemicals segment earnings. Turning to slide 18, this quarter adjusted earnings increased by $82 million compared to the same period last year. The increase in earnings was primarily in Olefins and Polyolefins due to stronger chain margins. This was primarily attributed to reduced feedstock costs due to higher industry ethane inventories, as well as continued strong demand for derivatives. Additionally, CPChem's operations continue to benefit from lower utility costs stemming from low natural gas prices.</p>
          <p>Slide 19 provides additional details on CPChem's operating segments. The top part of the chart, Olefins and Polyolefins, generated equity earnings of $225 million in the third quarter. As previously mentioned, the $63 million increase was due primarily from higher Olefins/Polyolefins chain margins and lower utility costs as a result of reduced natural gas prices. Equity earnings from Specialties, Aromatics, and Styrenics increased by $4 million compared to the same period last year. This was mainly due to higher equity earnings from Saudi Chevron Phillips, driven primarily by higher sales volumes and margins.</p>
          <p>This concludes our discussion of the financial and operating results for the quarter. Next I will provide you with some outlook items for the fourth quarter. As shown on slide 20, I want to start by providing an update on our Northeast operations, where we have the Bayway refinery located in Linden, New Jersey, and three storage terminals in the New York/New Jersey area.</p>
          <p>As you know, Hurricane Sandy made landfall in the Northeast on Monday evening. Prior to the storm, we safely idled the refinery and shut down the terminals as a cautionary measure. There was some flooding in low lying areas of the refinery, but floodwaters have since receded, and as of this morning power has been restored at Bayway. We are currently assessing the condition of the assets and a decision on resuming the operations will be made once this assessment is complete.</p>
          <p>So from an outlook perspective for the fourth quarter, in Refining and Marketing, assuming Bayway is running, we expect our global utilization rate to be in the low 90s and our pre-tax turnaround expenses to be approximately $100 million. Scheduled maintenance &#x2013; the scheduled maintenance turnarounds at the Wood River, Borger, and LA Refineries are currently underway and are proceeding as planned, with return to normal operations expected in November.</p>
          <p>In Midstream, as we noted in our earnings release, we expect to acquire an interest in two NGL pipelines currently being constructed by DCP midstream, and Tim will talk about this more later in his remarks. This investment will increase our total capital investments by an estimated $700 million to $800 million over the 2012 and 2013 time periods. Excluding the pipeline expenditures, total capital expense for the year is estimated at $1.2 billion to $1.4 billion.</p>
          <p>In Chemicals, distributions resumed in the fourth quarter after the completion of CPChem's debt repayment program. Corporate and Other is expected to be a cost of about $40 million per month or approximately $120 million for the quarter and this includes after-tax net interest expense of about $50 million. In October, our Board of Directors declared a $0.25 per share dividend payable in the fourth quarter. This 25% dividend increase, along with our $1 billion share repurchase plan, is part of our strategy to return capital to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>We expect to complete the share repurchase program by the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>We can now turn to slide 21 and I'll hand the call over to Tim Taylor to take you through an update on how we are advancing our strategic initiatives. Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Greg. We continue to execute our strategy of enhancing returns, delivering growth, and increasing shareholder distributions. In Refining and Marketing, we're improving margins, enhancing returns by increasing runs of advantaged feedstocks, and increasing refined product export capability. In order to supply higher quality, lower cost crude to our refineries, we're improving our logistics infrastructure and developing new sources of crude supply.</p>
          <p>For example, we're delivering 30,000 to 40,000 barrels per day of advantaged crude to our Bayway refinery by rail. We're also ramping up deliveries of locally produced Mississippian Lime crude into our Ponca City refinery via pipeline and truck. We expect to receive up to an additional 50,000 barrels per day of this high-quality crude into Ponca City by the end of 2013. We've also reached agreement with Kinder Morgan to deliver up to 30,000 barrels per day of Eagle Ford crude via a new pipeline connection to our Sweeny refinery in early 2014.</p>
          <p>All in all, by mid-2014, these actions, along with others that we're taking, are expected to increase our access to advantaged crude by about 165,000 barrels per day across our domestic refining system. This represents about 9% of our U.S. refining capacity. We also continue to increase clean product export capability through low cost capital investments in order to meet growing international demand.</p>
          <p>As part of our ongoing portfolio optimization efforts, we've been evaluating the potential disposition of the 1.2 GW Immingham combined heat and power plant in North Lincolnshire, England, which is adjacent to our Humber refinery. The marketing period could last several months and we'll continue to operate the asset as usual during this period.</p>
          <p>We remain committed to expanding the midstream business as part of our strategy to deliver long-term profitable and valuable growth. We've reached agreement in principle to acquire a one-third ownership interest in DCP's Sand Hills and Southern Hills NGL pipelines, representing a total estimated investment of approximately $700 million to $800 million. This investment will enable DCP to maintain its growth plan throughout the &#x2013; or through the 2015 time period. And these pipelines strategically complement our Midstream and Chemicals businesses. The Sand Hills pipeline is expected to commence deliveries of NGL from the Eagle Ford Shale into Mont Belvieu by year end.</p>
          <p>DCP recently started the South Texas segment of its Sand Hills NGL pipeline, initially delivering 10,000 barrels per day of liquids from the Eagle Ford to the DCP Partners Wilbury's pipeline. The second phase, with service from the Permian Basin, is targeted to be in operation by the second quarter of 2013. The Southern Hills pipeline project, which will extend from the Mid-Continent region to Mont Belvieu, Texas, remains on schedule for completion in mid-2013. In Chemicals, CPChem announced in October that the Saudi Polymers Company world scale petrochemicals facility in Saudi Arabia began commercial production. CPChem's projects in the U.S. Gulf Coast are progressing as planned, including the proposed ethane cracker and related polyethylene facilities, as well as their 1-hexene plant.</p>
          <p>Finally, we'd like to remind you that we'll be hosting our first Phillips 66 Analyst Meeting in New York on December 13. We look forward to seeing you there or having you listen to our webcast.</p>
          <p>This completes our prepared remarks, and we'll now open the line for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And at this time, we have a question from Edward Westlake from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Congratulations on the earnings, and I obviously hope everyone at Bayway is safe. I guess a quick question, firstly, you've got very strong free cash generation, so I guess our thoughts are going to turn to additional opportunities as well as distributions &#x2013; I'm sure you're going to get lots of these questions at the Analyst Day. But can I ask you a question about returns &#x2013; what sort of hurdle rates do you think are appropriate for say, volatile chemical cracking or NGL fractionation versus sort of longer term more stable logistics contracts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when you &#x2013; this is Tim Taylor, Ed. I think when you look at the Midstream and the fee-based kinds of projects, we see returns in the low double-digits to mid-teens. As you think about the Chemicals space, we would plan in the 15% or higher kind of returns for that and similar kinds of thoughts around the NGL expansions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then when I'm talking about the &#x2013; obviously, we can see a lot of logistics growth potential in North America, but I guess I'm less familiar with the potential in Chemicals. I mean, you've talked very clearly about the Gulf Coast ethane cracker, but I'm just wondering, could you give us some &#x2013; any thoughts about other opportunities outside of that big project that you could potentially go for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when you look at the Chemicals business, it's a global business and the investment thesis really for CPChem has been the focus on advantaged feed stocks. And so it's gone for the Middle East in the early 2000s to really now strong positioning in North America. And so they continue to look at where they can have a competitive advantage in terms of project development on a global basis. So I think initially still the Middle East, North America rise to the top, but there's always interest in Asia as well because of the growth in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any opportunities further downstream or just stay pretty much upstream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as downstream from ethylene or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you mean, so I think really the focus has been on the polyolefins and olefin and ethylene derivates chain. And there are other options as you begin to look at other kinds of materials. There's strong presence in the aromatics business as well. But right now the biggest opportunities have been really in the olefins part of the chain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Doug Terreson from ISI. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations on your results, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you guys have been very opportunistic on use of advantaged feedstock, especially in the West Coast, Mid-Continent, and the Gulf Coast, too. On this point, I wanted to see whether or not you consider there to be significant opportunities in the West Coast as well, and how you may be thinking about some of those options. And also on the West Coast, some of your competitors appear to be reconsidering their desire to participate in the California market because of some of the costs that may be associated with the new regulatory plan. So my question regards your strategic view of West Coast market and whether you feel that the positions out there are sufficiently advantaged that they warrant continued participation. And so just kind of a strategic update on the position on the West Coast as a whole as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me take those a little bit in terms of the market opportunity in the West Coast. Clearly, when we look at the West Coast, it's been one of the more challenged markets from a recovery standpoint post-recession. In California specifically it's a tough regulatory environment as well. So costs are higher and there is a lot of potential additional costs as new regulations come into effect. That said, it's still a very significant market and we think it's really important to look at how can we get some of these crudes out of the middle part of the country into the West Coast, particularly California. So we're working hard on that to try and change that, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The comment I'd make in Washington is that, that's got a natural access to the Bakken in North Dakota and Canadian crudes. And so we kind of separate, I think, the Washington piece from the California piece that way, but I think everyone's working hard to look at some crude solutions for the West Coast to improve its competitive position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Jeff Dietert from Simmons. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned the $250 million of feedstock advantages in the press release and I appreciate the comments also in your lead in on 30,000 to 40,000 barrels a day of Bayway rail, but I was hoping you could put that $250 million in perspective, perhaps discuss which regions it's most impactful and what arbitrages you're capturing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We look at that &#x2013; it's a significant advantage this quarter, so we've kind of touched on the East Coast, which is the Bayway, with the ability to bring shale crude into Bayway, it's got a great appetite for it. And the other place that we're really seeing the change is in the Gulf Coast, where we're seeing the HLS/LLS and the Brent relationships change and bringing in more domestic light sweet crudes into that region as well. So access and supply of domestic light into that region has improved its competitive position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that primarily Eagle Ford crude going in to replace LLS/ HLS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's &#x2013; Eagle Ford crude moving in from Texas is doing that as well. There's also going to be increasing amounts of WTI moving into that area as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Via rail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Via rail today, and then obviously the pipeline logistics infrastructure is changing now with the Cushing to Seaway reversal and Cushing connection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very well, thanks for your comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Blake Fernandez from Howard Weil. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Folks, good morning. I had a number of questions on the Sand Hills and Southern Hills, I guess I'll just rattle them off here all together and maybe you could respond. For one, I'm trying to understand the nature of the contract. Can you remind me, are they fee based or POP? I'm trying to understand or just confirm that it is indeed a one-third outright ownership of PSX outside of DCP, and if that is indeed the case, you know, ultimately where do you see that ownership landing? Could it ultimately be moved to DCP? I know you're considering a new MLP potentially, could it be moved there, or do you see it just remaining in the PSX umbrella?</p>
          <p>And then finally, on CapEx, I think I heard $1.2 billion to $1.4 billion. I'm trying to understand, I thought that was roughly in the range of where we had previous guidance. Obviously, this is an incremental investment. So I'm trying to make sure I understand the moving pieces of how CapEx is going to change as a result of this, so &#x2013; thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Blake. Good morning, this is Greg Maxwell. With regard to the nature of the contracts, still in process but they're pushing more DCP Midstream, pushing more towards fee based contracts. The intent for DCP, their stated intent, is to drop their one-third interest into DPM and having fee based contracts obviously is a very positive thing for an MLP. With regard to your &#x2013; I may have spoken too fast with regard to the guidance, the guidance for capital expenditures for the year is in the $1.2 billion to $1.4 billion range, excluding the investment that we would make in Sand Hills and Southern Hills, our one-third share, and we estimate that to be in the $700 million to $800 million dollar range. With regard to the structure, we're still working on the structure. We currently anticipate that that would &#x2013; we would be acquiring a one-third interest in which it would be a JV related structure. And so us, Spectra, as well as DCP at this time would own a one-third interest in a JV structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one more detailed follow up if I could, just on the share count, I noticed it actually increased almost, what, 2.7 million shares or so quarter-to-quarter, despite the buybacks. I'm just trying to make sure I understand if there was anything we should be aware of going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's two &#x2013; sort of twofold really, Blake. We purchased what turns out to be a little bit more ratably over the third quarter. So from a weighted average perspective, you won't see the full impact of those purchased shares until we get into really the fourth quarter. On the flip side, the share issuance side, you saw that we lost a little ground on the weighted average basis but a lot of that was tied to the exercise of options from non &#x2013; primarily from non-PSX or Phillips 66 employees, as well as some additional issuances on our long-term stock savings plan. So it should be more of a one-time event with regard to that. So a very astute question, we think from an actual end of the quarter perspective, we basically, on a basic share perspective, stayed roughly even.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Thanks a lot. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Kate Minyard from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning gentlemen. Thanks for taking my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Kate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I just wanted to ask a few questions on some of the comments that you have around the export capability and increasing that over time. You talk in the press release about increasing export capabilities through some low cost capital investments. And I guess my questions are, first of all, where do you see the opportunity as being the greatest, whether geographically or product wise? And then, what's the time horizon of this opportunity? So in other words, how soon does Phillips 66 want to recover its capital and generate a return in order to justify these investments? And then finally, how much more flexible is your current refining configuration, so what could you do without additional CapEx in the interim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so, we're actually doing a number of projects at our refineries that are located with access to water. And it makes, particularly focused in the Gulf Coast and the West Coast. And so these are typically kinds of pipeline connections, tankage, those kinds of things that can increase the rates or the availability to load export cargos. From an opportunity standpoint, when we look at that, it's really when you look at that it's the Atlantic Basin, specifically Latin America and West Africa, that today have been the primary opportunities that have developed from that standpoint. And based on supply/demand balances going forward, we would expect that to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did we answer all your questions, Kate, there was something else I think you asked....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, is there a particular time horizon, I mean, you indicate that you think the opportunity would continue, but is there sort of a time horizon? Is this kind of a three-year opportunity or do you see it as more extensive or would you like to recover your capital and return a little bit sooner than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So our target would be to go up to 220,000 &#x2013; 230,000 barrels a day of export capability. And we're looking to get that done by the end of next year. So that's, when we talk about low cost, short term those are &#x2013; these are relatively minor projects that we can execute quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh huh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Faisel Khan from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Faisel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm wondering if you could elaborate a little bit more on some of your &#x2013; some of the remarks you made in your strategic initiatives section of your press release. You guys talk about how the PSX has recently entered into several transportation agreements and plans to improve targeted logistics infrastructure. Could you elaborate a little bit more on what these several transportation agreements are and the duration of these agreements? And I have a follow-up after that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Faisel. We did talk about the connection to the Kinder Morgan crude condensate line that runs close to the Sweeny refinery. So that's actually a project or a connector pipeline that's relatively short that will be built by Kinder Morgan, and so that's a throughput pipeline connection agreement that we have specifically for that. Beyond that, we've talked in the last couple of months about our purchase of railcars to have a very flexible method of delivering these crudes in the developing plays into our refining systems.</p>
          <p>So there it's not only an investment in railcars, but it's also an investment in around the infrastructure to unload railcars and to load those, and really when we look at our system, it's the ability to unload the railcars, when we think about infrastructure logistics, that we are looking at &#x2013; at for instance, at Bayway and other refineries as a way to increase the amount of rail that we can take into those various refineries. And so that's the capital side, and then we've got the commitments in terms, from time-to-time, with other third party kinds of logistics providers to make that happen as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Faisel, there are probably some other things that we're working on right now that we just &#x2013; it would be premature for us to disclose because those contracts haven't been finalized or the agreements with our counterparties haven't been flanged up. So there's a lot of work that's going on in this area. You should expect hearing more as time goes forward. Tim, I don't know if you want to..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I &#x2013; there's a lot of pipeline expansion and opportunities there and we're just making sure that we're looking at all those opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, understood. And then can you talk a little bit more about, I believe you said there's major maintenance going on or turnarounds going on at Wood River and I think you said Ponca and Borger, but I was wondering if you can elaborate a little bit more on that in terms of what those turnarounds are and what you guys are doing in your Mid-Continent portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Wood River and Borger are both in turnarounds today &#x2013; we expect those back in operation here in November. And those are major turnarounds &#x2013; Borger is a very significant one. We do have some operations continuing at Wood River today. So those are planned turnarounds that we've had. We've got smaller turnarounds going on at LA that have some minor impacts in terms of its throughput.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we talked about what, $100 million in turnaround expense this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And last question from me, the 30,000 to 40,000 barrels a day of advantaged crude that you guys consumed at Bayway. Is there any way to give us an idea of what the cost of getting that crude into the refinery was? And what was the advantage of bringing in that crude versus, say, taking a West African barrel? Was it a $3 advantage, $5 advantage, what was the real crude advantage you guys realized into Bayway from that strategy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you can appreciate the prices move around, but on average, we would use $2 to $3 a barrel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much. Appreciate the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Doug Leggate from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning, guys. Thanks for taking my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I've got a &#x2013; one strategic I guess and one &#x2013; maybe a couple housekeeping ones. As you look at the Gulf Coast, you talked in your remarks about how you started to see Louisiana Light, I guess, see some benefit relative to imported light sweet crude, like Brent for example. We've obviously been noticing that as well. I'm curious as to whether you could give us your prognosis as to how this is likely to play out? How you react to it in terms of your ability to ramp up your light sweet crude barrels or maybe substitute your light sweet crude barrels. I'll start with that one and I've got a couple of housekeeping ones, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, this is a continuing story and we've seen the imports of offshore light sweet diminished, particularly in the Gulf Coast, and so I think all of us in that area are looking at that. We're very active in this area. So the increasing supply of these light crudes out of the U.S., ultimately we believe that will displace that waterborne barrel into particularly the Gulf Coast. So I think our view is that when that happens that puts additional pressure on the LLS price to be competitive. So I think that we would continue to expect that there could perhaps be some additional widening on the Brent LLS spread.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you think what we're seeing right now is indicative that this this has already started to happen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe it has started to happen, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Have you guys taken any sort of baseline shipping commitments on the Seaway expansion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't &#x2013; I'm not sure we have and if we did, we probably wouldn't want to disclose it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, okay. Fair enough. The housekeeping one, just real quick, the inventory gain, Clayton, I think that's included in the gross margins. Can you break it out by region as to where that gain was realized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on &#x2013; you're talking about the $100 million difference?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Year-over-year. Do we have that, Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as split...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of that was in the Gulf region and in the east Atlantic Basin area, as I recall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, the single largest variance was in the Atlantic Basin/ Europe area, the $100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, that was kind of what I was expecting. And I guess the final one, I don't know if you can give us this or not, but it looks to us following Valero's results yesterday and yours today, it looks like the European side of the Atlantic Basin was very strong, is there any way you could give us some kind of indicative spilt as to how the earnings split between the U.S. and the international piece of that, and I'll leave it at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let's see, we may have something. You got that, Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll have to get that for him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll have &#x2013; we can &#x2013; yeah, I would just say the European refiners, when you look at the third quarter, that was their &#x2013; quarter, the year, I think Whitegate, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:44) and Humber all had good quarters, but Bayway did as well. But I would say most of the change probably comes from an improvement in earnings out of Europe rather than improvement in Bayway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful. All right guys, thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Paul Cheng from Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hopefully there is a number of quick questions. Greg, can you share with us that in general what is your insurance policy in terms of BI and property damage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you're probably talking specifically with the Bayway incident and the terminals, I guess, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a perspective of that, that falls under named windstorm coverage and as a result other than a smaller piece in our participation in O.I.L., we do not have any commercial insurance associated with named windstorm coverage. So as a result we're basically self-funded.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So and do you have any BI, business interruption, insurance or not really?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we do carry BI Insurance, but as you're probably aware, you have to actually take out named windstorm coverage in order to get that associated with any hurricane activity. So as a result, given the pricing, as well as our view of the overall total impact that a hurricane or a named windstorm could have on our operations, we elected not to take out that coverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. A second question, Greg, if we assume that the Saudi Arabia chemical plant, the polymer plant actually was on stream before the third quarter, based on the market condition there, what would the earning contribution to you guys would be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're talking about <mark type="ph" /> SP Co's (48:45) start up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's actually started up in October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, but <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:50).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right at the beginning of October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I was saying that if we assume that there is actually a pro forma, that it actually running in the third quarter, what earning contribution you may have? I mean, do you guys have a number you can share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think it's clearly in the ramp-up phase of their operations today, but I think in a longer term I might say steady-state basis, we kind of look at that to be 10% or so of the &#x2013; of the CPChem contribution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Greg, can I have some quick balance sheet data, what is your working capital market value of inventory in excess of the debt, and of the total debt how much is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:35) in the long-term debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the replacement costs and...<mark type="audio gap" /> (49:45)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...in the third quarter. From the second to third quarter, did we have debt increase or debt that may have already been running at that rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They've increased, Paul. I can't remember the exact increase, but we're increasing that and as you can guess, we are continuing to, so to speak, test the limits and we can go substantially higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think the challenge for us is to continue to work logistics and get more and more of that into the Bayway refinery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have a number then, how much is the increase on the WTI link, including the Eagle Ford crude runs, sequentially from second to third quarter in the Gulf Coast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gulf Coast crude run changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd have to see if I can get back, it did increase, Alliance was down, so the percentages, as a percent of total, it impacted that somewhat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It probably did &#x2013; it probably did &#x2013; did not go up because Alliance was down for two or three weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. And then, in earlier comment you say for Bayway, the up that you realize is about say in the $2 range. Do you have a similar number for the Gulf Coast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So uplift relative to West Africa and our North Sea crudes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it really &#x2013; it's still driven off the LLS/HLS dips, and so it's probably in the same order of magnitude right now, in that area as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Two final one, one of your competitor is voicing concern about the California market, on the long-term future, given the regulatory environment. I want to see that, what is the view of PSX in terms of California, is that still consider as a core market for you guys, or is that you guys also have your own doubts? The second one, I think maybe is for Greg. On dividend, you guys have a nice increase, 25%, but your payout still extremely low, and that your yield is about 2.1%, certainly lower than some of your peers. And just want to understand in terms of the criteria and also the timeline how the Board will determine, in terms of when or by how much that &#x2013; what kind of criteria they need to see in order for them to raise in a more significant way on the regular dividend, given that I think a lot of your long-only account investors may probably quite appreciate a higher dividend yield?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, I'll address the market question. California, as I said a little bit earlier, I think we look at the market and say, demand continues to struggle out there as well post-recession and then I think you look more fundamentally at the operating environment and the costs associated with the, particularly the environmental regulations, and we think that's going to continue to keep pressure on operations and operating costs out there. So yeah, I'd say that from a California perspective that it is one of the more challenged parts of our portfolio in terms of the basic value equation. So that's why we're still looking at the crude side of it and continuing to stay abreast and on top of what it's going to take to comply with things like AB32 to really maintain your operations out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But Tim, do you still view that as a part of your core portfolio or that you may have doubts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the past, California's been a really good in the market at times, but right now it is our lower performing. So I think that if our assessment would become that it's going to be challenged for some period of time, we've either got to find a way to improve that operation or find some other way to deal with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the divided question, Paul, that's something that we always look at and, I think as evidenced by our 25% increase, our objective is to have a dividend that is competitive. We wanted to be also affordable and we also want to grow over time. I think Greg Garland, our Chairman, his view is he wants to look 10 years down the road in the rearview mirror and say every single year he's had a history of Phillips 66 increasing our dividend.</p>
          <p>Having said that, though, we also recognize that we're in a highly cyclical business and as such one of the ways we try complementing returning value back to the shareholders is through our share repurchase program. That gives us an opportunity to basically create a swing &#x2013; a variable swing that in the event that we hit the low point of the cycle then we're able to maybe pull back a bit on that if our cash requirements required it. So I think from a guidance perspective, the intent is for us to look at and get in a pattern of an annual view of our dividend increases and probably take an assessment and raise the dividends, if appropriate, on an annual basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And at this time we have a question from Evan Calio from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys. Great results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Evan. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Quick follow-up and then a different question on utilization levels, but how much LLS are you running today that's not currently considered an advantaged crude in your 63% calculation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's primarily Alliance. So LLS/HLS at Alliance, it's the predominant part of our crude runs at that facility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. And a different question on &#x2013; your aggregate refining utilizations are high, at 96%, with some downtime at Alliance. I mean, I know that various clean fuel regulations have lowered max utilization from historic highs and runs are depending upon a feed slate, yet is that close to your theoretic maximum? Or could you kind walk us through your four regions &#x2013; and tell me where you think they could actually run, if they had the right incentive to run?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think that we're seeing in the Mid-Continent, in the Central Corridor. When I look at that &#x2013; we've actually seen sustained runs now creeping up a bit. I think it does speak to consistency of the crude slate in some of Mid-Continent operations and continuing improvements in our joint venture refinery at Wood River. So we've seen that there. Bayway has run very well with processed inputs. So it's not only crude runs, but additional input as well in terms of loading up the units.</p>
          <p>So the probably &#x2013; I look at the Central Corridor and say we pretty much ran it about as much as we could. We'd like to get more because it's got a great margin today. The California refineries, West Coast, were again close to their capacity as well, I would say that's pretty much it for them. And in the Gulf Coast with Alliance is probably our biggest opportunity after the hurricane and the impacts of that to come back up to full rate. So we look around our system, the Atlantic Basin/Europe, we're right there, the Central Corridor. So about the only place where we didn't run pretty close to capacity would be the Gulf Coast. And I think that's just a matter of getting Alliance line back out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would full be for the Gulf, would it be in the high 90s?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think when we look at that, 95% and above is pretty &#x2013; pretty high capital utilization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And just maybe one last question if I could, I know it's been, look, MLPs have been a real defining element of this cycle, inclusion of more and more cyclical assets have grown in popularity, as well as IRS permissibility and valuation in the market. I mean, can you discuss maybe how your consideration has changed or how you think about the suitability of that structured for either refining assets or in the ethane cracking assets where I know you have a partner that would have equal say, but how do you think about the suitability of the structure for those assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we certainly see the value that can be created from an MLP, as Greg talked about earlier, with fee based kind of assets, so our transportation and logistics assets, we look at that and we say, okay, we see the value creation. It's got some other challenges, so to speak, when you do the MLP structure in terms of dilutive to ROCE, dilutive to earnings. And so that's kind of the contra piece and it can be &#x2013; depending on how you view it, relatively expensive from a financial structure. So that's part of our deliberation and really where we're focused is on that transportation/logistics piece with PSX. The variable MLP is pretty early, we'll wait and see, it's a great time right now to have those with distributions, but clearly they are variable. And I think that we'll &#x2013; it will be interesting to see how that works out with the test of time. And I can say that, in the petrochemical side, we really don't have any plans to look at that from a cracking standpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. At this time, we have a question from Cory Garcia from Raymond James. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning fellows, great quarter. I was just hoping kind of in the petrochem theme, would you guys be able to provide a bit more color into the demand trends you guys are seeing in terms of your polyolefins business? Clearly the U.S. trend seemed a lot stronger than what we're seeing in Europe and elsewhere, but any more color you guys could have in terms of Asia, Latin America and then also refresh me on, I guess, the amount of export you guys actually participate in sort of that market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So let me kind of break that. When we look around the world, I would say a great place to be today is in the United States. The demand has been relatively stable. It's still not what I'd call robust, but clearly with the operating rates you've seen, a great place to be. And I think it's speaks to the advantaged feed stock that we have here, as well as, probably a decent demand from the industrial manufacturing sector.</p>
          <p>Europe is weak, when we look across the globe. Asia has backed off substantially from what you would have thought a year ago, and frankly part of that stems from the weakness in Europe, because they're still heavily dependent on trade for their manufacturing. So I don't think there's anything surprising there except that perhaps we look at the base U.S. and say it's a pretty good market. Latin America is still relatively small, but does okay as well.</p>
          <p>And then when we think about the export piece, that does provide some underpinning, if you will, for the petrochemical business in the U.S. and so I think as an industry I still think about it in the 20%-25% range of petrochemicals being able to be exported or you can do that. So a lot of optionality there that develops when you've got that kind of cost position. The other thing I would say on CPChem is it's important to realize that if you think about their production based in the Middle East and their production based in United States positioned well in &#x2013; two lowest cost areas in the world in petrochemicals and I think that shows up in the strength of their earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, I appreciate the time, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This concludes the time that we have for questions. I'll now turn the call back to Clayton Reasor for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you again for the participation, interest in the company. You can find a copy of the transcript from the call on our website and we look forward to talking with you all soon. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>