<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1185319" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>426</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Gilbert, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Paul E. Jacobs, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steve Mollenkopf, Executive Vice President and President, Qualcomm CDMA Technologies</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">William E. Keitel, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Maynard Um</participant>
      <participant id="6">Donald Rosenberg</participant>
      <participant id="7">Brian Modoff</participant>
      <participant id="8">Tal Liani</participant>
      <participant id="9">Mark McKechnie</participant>
      <participant id="10">T. Michael Walkley</participant>
      <participant id="11">Tim Long</participant>
      <participant id="12">Tim Luke</participant>
      <participant id="13">Simona Jankowski</participant>
      <participant id="14">Derek Aberle</participant>
      <participant id="15">Philip Cusick</participant>
      <participant id="16">Len Lauer</participant>
      <participant id="17">Kulbinder Garcha</participant>
      <participant id="18">Matthew Hoffman</participant>
      <participant id="19">Anil Doradla</participant>
      <participant id="20">James Faucette</participant>
      <participant id="21">Glen Yeung</participant>
      <participant id="22">Adam Benjamin</participant>
      <participant id="23">Stacy Rasgon</participant>
      <participant id="24">Mark Sue</participant>
      <participant id="25">Craig Berger</participant>
      <participant id="26">Tavis McCourt</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Qualcomm third quarter fiscal 2009 conference call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded July 22, 2009. The playback number for today's call is 800-642-1687. International callers please dial 706-645-9291. The playback reservation number is 16320448.</p>
          <p>I would like to turn the call over to John Gilbert, Vice President of Investor Relations. Mr. Gilbert, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon. Today's call will include prepared remarks by Dr. Paul Jacobs, Steve Mollenkopf, and Bill Keitel. In addition, Steve Altman, Len Lauer, Don Rosenberg, and Derek Aberle will join the question-and-answer session. An Internet presentation and audio broadcast accompany this call and you can access it by visiting www.qualcomm.com.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, if we use any non-GAAP financial measures as defined by the SEC and Regulation G, you can find the required reconciliations to GAAP on our website.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to direct you to our 10-Q and earnings release, which were filed and furnished respectively with the SEC today and are available on our website. We have also furnished the SEC our financial statements and related footnotes in the extensible business reporting language XBRL format as required by the SEC.</p>
          <p>We may make forward-looking statements relating to our expectations and other future events that may differ materially from Qualcomm's actual results. Please review our SEC filings for a detailed presentation of each of our businesses and associated risks and other important factors that may cause our actual results to differ from these forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>And now it is my pleasure to introduce Qualcomm's Chairman and CEO, Dr. Paul Jacobs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John, and good afternoon, everyone. I'm very pleased with our strong operating performance in this uncertain economic environment. Revenues were at the high end of our prior guidance. Operating income exceeded our prior guidance, and pro forma combined SG&amp;A and R&amp;D expenses were 5% lower year over year and well below our prior guidance.</p>
          <p>Worldwide demand for 3G remains robust. And despite the global economic uncertainty, we anticipate another strong quarter of demand for our chipsets in fiscal Q4. We are raising our fiscal 2009 revenue and operating income estimates given the strong underlying fundamentals of our business.</p>
          <p>Before commenting further on the business, I would like to welcome Dr. Young Koo Cha as Senior Vice President of Qualcomm and President of Qualcomm Korea. Dr. Cha's extensive experience in the high tech industry, academia, and the Korean government is a great addition to our management team, and we look forward to his leadership in this key region for our business.</p>
          <p>Our business continues to generate strong operating cash flows, which enables us to return capital to our stockholders. As of June 28, we have returned over $10 billion of capital to our shareholders since fiscal 2003. We also recently announced another quarterly cash dividend payable on September 25 of this year.</p>
          <p>While we did record additional impairments on our marketable securities this quarter, those impairments were significantly lower than previous quarters. In addition, recent improvements in financial markets have greatly reduced our net unrealized losses from 898 million at March quarter end to $25 million as of June quarter end.</p>
          <p>Turning to the business, QCT shipped a record number of chipsets this quarter, an increase of approximately 9% year over year. We believe the CDMA inventory channel has largely stabilized yet remains near historically low levels, consistent with our prior forecast. In addition, CDMA-based device shipments by our licensees in the March quarter were at the high end of our prior guidance and increased 4% year over year.</p>
          <p>Worldwide 3G adoption continued to accelerate while GSM shipments continued to decline. According to Wireless Intelligence, 3G subscribers grew 28% year over year to approximately 830 million as of June. In Western Europe, WCDMA subscribers grew 52% year over year compared to an 8% decline in GSM subscribers.</p>
          <p>In addition, according to industry analyst forecasts, 3G handset shipments are expected to eclipse GSM shipments for the first time in 2010. And 3G-enabled handsets are forecast to be over 60% of total handsets shipped in 2012. The 3G ecosystem is vibrant, and consumers have an extensive choice of competitively priced, feature rich devices to keep them connected, informed, and entertained.</p>
          <p>The GSA reports that approximately 94% of WCDMA operators have launched HSPA services, and the number of HSPA devices has grown by over 120% year over year to more than 1,600 devices by over 180 suppliers. In addition, the number of HSPA enabled notebooks has more than tripled in this same period. Also according to the GSA and operator announcements, there are now five HSPA+ commercial networks, and more than 25 additional operators have announced plans of testing, trialing, or deploying HSPA+ technology.</p>
          <p>CDMA2000 continues to be successful in both developed and emerging markets, and according to the CDG is approaching 0.5 billion global subscribers. India reached a significant milestone this past May, surpassing 100 million CDMA2000 subscribers, of which approximately 50 million were added in the past two years.</p>
          <p>Globally, there are over 65 EV-DO Revision A commercial networks with over 30 additional networks in deployment. Revision B is gaining traction as several operators including China Telecom have indicated interest in Revision B to further leverage their 3G investment.</p>
          <p>In China, the broad deployment of 3G CDMA and the world's largest wireless market continues. Since January 2009, China Telecom has added more than 11 million CDMA subscribers, and has announced plans to deploy EV-DO Revision A to 500 cities by the end of this month. In addition, China Unicom announced its HSPA network covers 100 cities today and plans to deploy HSPA in a total of 284 cities by the end of this year.</p>
          <p>As with most new market deployments, ramp up takes some time for networks to be fully deployed and for a broad portfolio of handsets to be made available to consumers. We've always believed that when licenses were issued, infrastructure deployments would occur rapidly, and I'm very pleased to see the pace of these deployments.</p>
          <p>We continue to see growing demand for 3G Broadband services driven by increased consumer desire for mobile Internet access and more personalized user experiences. For example, in North America, multiple operators continue to report strong wireless data growth year over year, driven in part by smartphone competition, including recent launch of multiple new iconic devices. The trend towards connected mobile computing in the U.S. continues as the three top operators now offer subsidized notebooks or netbook computers with embedded 3G capability.</p>
          <p>And the trend towards cloud computing in the mobile environment continues to evolve, and it is a trend that bodes well for us. Recent announcements such as Google's Chrome operating system and Microsoft's plan to offer a free online version of its Office product suite will further enable the shift towards mobility.</p>
          <p>Our continued commitment to innovative research and development puts us in a unique position to benefit from the growing demand for compelling new 3G enabled devices. Our comprehensive chipset portfolio supports multiple operating systems and provides our OEM partners with more choice and flexibility to develop new categories of mobile computing devices that will support an increasingly mobile society.</p>
          <p>We have previously demonstrated advanced interference cancellation techniques in our CDMA2000 infrastructure chipset solutions that further improve system capacity. We also recently announced a collaboration in which ZTE will utilize Qualcomm's advanced uplink interference cancellation technology in their next generation UMTS base station. Using this technology, operators can boost their UMTS data throughput by up to 60% and deliver a user experience that is comparable to LTE in a similar channel bandwidth.</p>
          <p>Turning to FLO TV, the DTV transition is enabling our expansion into key major markets, such as Boston, Houston, Miami, and San Francisco, as well as expanded service in Chicago, Los Angeles, New York and Washington, DC. By the end of 2009, FLO TV will reach more than 100 major markets and more than 200 million potential customers.</p>
          <p>In our display business, we recently announced the opening of our dedicated mirasol color display fabrication facility in Taiwan in partnership with Foxlink. This is an exciting new step towards further commercialization of our innovative mirasol technology that provides a more rewarding mobile experience by enabling extended battery life and superior outdoor viewing.</p>
          <p>You may note that we have disclosed that the Korea Fair Trade Commission [KTFC] is expected to issue a decision on our case shortly. Unless and until an order is issued, it would be inappropriate for us to comment further on the case than what we have provided so far.</p>
          <p>So while the global economic environment remains uncertain, we will continue to invest strategically in key research and development programs to improve our technology leadership, competitive position, and to drive shareholder value while closely managing our SG&amp;A expenses.</p>
          <p>There are many exciting new growth opportunities in wireless today and we're fortunate to have a strong balance sheet and operating cash flow to execute on our strategic objectives. We are well positioned to drive innovation and growth in 3G and next generation wireless technologies.</p>
          <p>That concludes my comments, and I will now turn the call over to Steve Mollenkopf.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Paul. QCT continued our track record of strong execution in the third quarter, and I would like to highlight the results. We shipped approximately 94 million chipsets this quarter, a record shipment level for QCT. This represents a 36% increase quarter over quarter and a 9% increase over the same period last year.</p>
          <p>We generated record revenue of approximately $1.8 billion and delivered record earnings before taxes of $548 million in the third fiscal quarter of 2009. We are encouraged by these strong Q3 results and remain focused on cost reduction efforts within this current economic climate.</p>
          <p>Our average revenue per MSM remained consistent with the previous quarter at approximately $19, driven by a greater than expected mix of chipsets that enable advanced data devices combined with the stabilization of inventory levels in developed markets.</p>
          <p>EV-DO shipments increased 83%, and UMTS shipments increased 54% over the previous quarter. While we expect ASP to trend marginally lower in the fourth quarter, we anticipate a similarly healthy product mix.</p>
          <p>Now turning to product milestones, commercial devices enabled by the QSC6240 and 6270, the industry's first single chip products for UMTS, launched this past quarter as scheduled and are now available in stores. We continue to believe our single chip solutions for cost effective UMTS devices are helping to accelerate the migration of GSM users to 3G.</p>
          <p>Our Snapdragon products are making strong progress as well. In May, Toshiba's TG01, the first commercial device enabled by Snapdragon, launched in several markets across Europe. Consistent with our prior statements, we anticipate that numerous additional commercial Snapdragon enabled devices will be announced throughout the year.</p>
          <p>At the COMPUTEX show in June, we announced an extension of the Snapdragon roadmap with the QSD8650A. The 8650A offers a 1.3 gigahertz core for 30% greater processing capability and enhanced graphics while leveraging 45-nanometer technology for 30% lower power consumption.</p>
          <p>HSPA+ also continues to progress as scheduled with over 25 operators now planning to launch service this year. We have more than eight device manufacturers designing products based on our industry leading MDM8200 chipset solution for HSPA+, with Huawei already having launched their data cards into multiple markets. This technology allows carriers to evolve their network capabilities, making it a very compelling upgrade option, especially in today's challenging economic environment.</p>
          <p>We continue to diversify our product portfolio in order to enable the next generation wireless experience. This past quarter we announced two wireless LAN products that take us into new markets that complement our core cellular business. Our N-Stream WCN1320 chip supports performance up to 600 megabits per second and is designed to enable the wireless distribution of multiple simultaneous streams of high definition video, voice, and data throughout the home. As part of our end-to-end wireless LAN solution, we also announced the WCN1312 chip, an 802.11n solution for handsets and mobile devices supporting data rates of up to 72 megabits per second. Both products are sampling now.</p>
          <p>QCT has continued to execute successfully despite an uncertain economic climate, and the results are evident in our financial performance this past quarter. We remain focused on meeting our customers' needs as well as expanding to win new business in new markets with new partners.</p>
          <p>Thank you, and I will now turn this call over to Bill Keitel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve, and good afternoon, everyone. I'll begin with highlights of our third quarter results. Revenues of $2.8 billion were at the high end of our prior estimate as 3G device shipments grew approximately 4% year over year in the March quarter, and our chipset shipments grew approximately 9% year over year in the June quarter. Pro forma operating income of $1.12 billion also exceeded our prior estimate.</p>
          <p>We continue to see the benefits of our broad initiatives to reduce certain operating expenses. The combination of pro forma R&amp;D and SG&amp;A expenses decreased approximately 5% year over year including a 20% decrease in SG&amp;A expense. R&amp;D expenses grew approximately 6% year over year as we have increased our investment in select key projects.</p>
          <p>Operating cash flow was strong in the third quarter, approximately $1 billion or 39% of revenue. Approximately 111 million new CDMA devices were shipped by our licensees in the March quarter, at the high end of our prior estimates. The average selling price of CDMA devices shipped in the March quarter was approximately $191, consistent with our prior guidance and down 5% sequentially. We shipped a record 94 million MSM chipsets, consistent with our prior guidance and up 36% sequentially as a significant contraction in the CDMA inventory channel has now stabilized.</p>
          <p>Pro forma net investment income was $79 million in the third quarter compared to a net investment loss of $67 million in the second quarter and includes our adoption of the new FSP FAS 115-2 covering debt security impairments. Investment impairments also decreased. For the third fiscal quarter, we recorded $112 million in net other than temporary impairments in unmarketable securities, which equates to approximately 1% of our cash, cash equivalents, and marketable securities. Net unrealized losses on our investment portfolio decreased substantially in the third quarter, down to $25 million at the end of fiscal June as compared to $898 million at the end of last quarter.</p>
          <p>Our total cash and marketable securities grew to approximately $15.7 billion at the end of the third quarter, with approximately $7 billion onshore and $8.7 billion offshore.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter, we paid $282 million of cash dividends or $0.17 per share.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our full year guidance, we are reaffirming the 565 million midpoint of our prior calendar 2009 CDMA device shipment forecast. We estimate that between 540 million and 590 million CDMA devices will be shipped in 2009. The 565 million midpoint represents an 18% year over year increase, and we estimate that approximately 217 million units will be CDMA2000 and approximately 348 million units will be WCDMA.</p>
          <p>We are reaffirming our prior estimate for average selling prices for CDMA2000 and WCDMA devices. We continue to expect average selling prices will decrease approximately 9% year over year to approximately $199 per unit in fiscal 2009.</p>
          <p>We believe that the significant CDMA inventory channel contraction observed in the first and second fiscal quarters has ended. Looking forward and consistent with our prior estimates, we expect the CDMA inventory channel will remain relatively low at approximately 14 to 15 weeks for the remainder of calendar 2009.</p>
          <p>We are raising our revenue and operating income guidance for this fiscal year. We now expect fiscal 2009 revenues to be in the range of approximately 10.25 to $10.45 billion, an increase of approximately 200 to $400 million above our prior estimates. We estimate pro forma operating income for fiscal 2009 to be in the range of 3.3 to $3.4 billion, an increase of approximately 250 to $350 million above our prior estimates. This updated financial guidance reflects continued strength in 3G device shipments around the world as well as a favorable mix of more data capable chipsets for our QCT business.</p>
          <p>We expect the combination of pro forma R&amp;D and SG&amp;A expenses to be flat year over year, reflecting successful SG&amp;A expense reduction combined with thoughtful investment in select R&amp;D projects.</p>
          <p>Our estimated pro forma fiscal 2009 tax rate is approximately 29%. Excluding investment impairments and the litigation settlement charge, our underlying pro forma tax rate is estimated to be approximately 21% for fiscal 2009.</p>
          <p>Turning to the fourth fiscal quarter, we estimate revenues to be in the range of approximately 2.55 to $2.75 billion. We estimate pro forma operating income for the fourth fiscal quarter to be approximately 950 million to $1.05 billion. We anticipate shipments of approximately 88 million to 92 million MSM chipsets during the September quarter. This reflects continued healthy demand, up approximately two to 7% over the same quarter last year.</p>
          <p>We estimate that approximately 127 to 132 million new CDMA based devices shipped in the June quarter, up approximately 14 to 19% sequentially, and reflecting our expectation for strong growth across multiple regions, including WCDMA in developed markets. We estimate the average selling price was approximately $189 per unit.</p>
          <p>And we anticipate fourth fiscal quarter pro forma R&amp;D and SG&amp;A expenses combined will increase sequentially approximately 4%.</p>
          <p>That concludes my comments. I will now turn the call back to John Gilbert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bill. Before we go into our question-and-answer session, I would like to remind our participants that our goal on this call is to address as many questions as possible before we run out of time. I would encourage you to limit your questions to one per caller. Operator, we are ready for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Maynard Um from UBS, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks, just a question on your guidance. Your handset guidance assumes a ramp in the back half of the year, and I would have assumed you would have actually seen an acceleration of chipset units ahead of that given low levels of inventory, but your chip guidance is actually down slightly sequentially. Can you just talk about the disconnect there and if you can market share and those types of things? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maynard, this is Bill. I'll give you my inputs here. The 94 million chips we shipped in the June quarter as compared to the midpoint of our estimate for the September quarter of 90 million, this is very much in line with what we were seeing approximately three months ago. We had a couple major operator launches occurring in the June quarter. We expected there would be a product build in advance of that launch as we have seen so many times in other operator launches. And so seeing a slight decrease here in the June quarter is consistent with our prior estimates.</p>
          <p>And then yes, you're correct. We are expecting a ramp in units in the second half of the calendar year. Obviously, there is a one quarter lag between our royalty units and shipping and the time we recognize the revenue. So we are expecting a ramp in the second half for the year. In terms of our chipsets, we're an important ingredient of the market. We'd like more share but certainly there are other parties shipping into this robust market as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then just quickly, can you offer any feedback with your customers in Korea and the discussions there relative to the KTFC? That's it for me. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Discussions with our customers &#x2013; this is Don Rosenberg. We of course have quite good relationships with our customers in Korea. And we think that largely, they have been supportive of us. But beyond that as we say, as Paul said earlier, we don't want to talk about the deliberations with the KFTC at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Brian Modoff from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Can you hear me all right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. Just following up on that guidance, in a recent discussion with MediaTek, they are looking at 90 million units for Q3, and actually that number may be higher than that. So they are seeing good demand in China. Samsung's numbers are &#x2013; I mean LG's numbers last night were well above the expectations, and Samsung is out tonight and we expect some decent results there.</p>
          <p>Given that you guided to an 89 to 92 or 88 to 92 in the quarter previous and ended up doing above that, looking &#x2013; given we're not seeing a lot of indications of weakened or weaker demand in Asia in particular and WCDMA continues to track well, are you being conservative here with what you're saying on your ASIC shipment forecast relative to the quarter? And are you inferring on Q4 by maintaining your full-year guidance and implying a ramp there in the back half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, this is Steve. I'll just comment very briefly on the MediaTek numbers. I think it's a little difficult to correlate them to our market because we play in such different markets today.</p>
          <p>In terms of our guidance, we're pretty confident in the number that we've given out. As you know, we have in the face of new carriers launching as we've talked, we tend to I think want to observe the ecosystem a little bit before we understand what's going on. So we have pretty good visibility into what's happening over the next quarter. As we've said in June, we've seen the developed markets really respond back to normal levels of inventory, so we have much greater visibility into what I think the majority of the chipsets are going to be now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk a little bit about what you're doing on &#x2013; your R&amp;D continues to be strong relative to your other expenses, and you're doing a lot of work in process technologies in terms of bringing down your diameters. Can you talk a little bit about what you're planning to do going into next year relative to performance and cost on some of your chips, and should we see several new product launches over the next several quarters as you work through as your R&amp;D starts to turn into parts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look, we've been investing in processor technology, both DSP processor and microprocessor technology for the last five years and we're really starting to see the fruits of that in the market. It started very much on the Snapdragon product line. But as you know, we're moving that through the entire product line, that core and that core technology through the entire product line. We have recently announced really two products that meet the theme of what your question was. Number one, we announced dual-core products, which we think is an important differentiator for us moving forward, as well as new geometry. Both of those advancements I think move in a way that helps us.</p>
          <p>The other aspect that I should mention is as we go to the lower geometries, we think that our advantage of having an integrated solution becomes larger. Primarily what happens is that the products become limited by their I/O and not by their die size, so I think we have a fundamental advantage given our strategy moving forward should those things play out the way we think they will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Tal Liani from Banc of America, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I'm afraid I have a question on the same topic and then one more question on Tessera. If you look at chip shipments over the last quarter, it went up from roughly 70 to 95, and we saw that the lot of it is attributed to China. Can you forecast what could happen in China? First of all, just confirm the sources for the growth, the sequential growth we've seen this quarter, and maybe give us some color on how much of it is related to data cards, how much of it is related to China, and give us some more color there.</p>
          <p>And second, you're guiding again to the same neighborhood. If we add conservatism to your guidance, it means that roughly it's going to be flat to slightly down. And the question is wouldn't you think that China is going to start slowing down? This is what we've seen the last quarter or maybe you have a different forecast for China. So just to get some color on chip shipment.</p>
          <p>Second question not related, it seems like &#x2013; Tessera today said that Amkor is not a licensee that is in good standing currently, and I'm just wondering what are the implications on you if at all. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tal, this is Bill Keitel. I'll try and take your first one here. At the outset of this quarter, we had expected a significant portion of this quarter's demand to be targeted at the developing world. And as we progress through the quarter, there was a good ramp there, but some of that demand shifted to developed, shifted from developing to developed. And I think you could see that in our uptick in revenues and kind of what you would calculate as the average selling price of our chipsets. So there was that shift there. We've even seen a bit of that continuing into our demand here for the September quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Don. I'll take the Tessera question. Amkor is a licensee of Tessera. Tessera has acknowledged that on several occasions. We understand that recently Tessera has alleged that Amkor's payments are not appropriate under the terms of their license. Amkor has assured us that they are. In any case as far as we're concerned, this seems to be yet another dispute over their license agreement and what the appropriate level of payment is, which as in the past will be resolved under the terms of that agreement, which we understand have a dispute resolution procedures. But none of that should impact us. We're still purchasing from a licensee, Amkor, and it shouldn't have an impact on us with respect to the limited exclusion order in the ITC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark McKechnie from Broadpoint AmTech, please go ahead with your question. Mr. McKechnie, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh. Thank you. Can you hear me now? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir; please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Okay, sorry about that. First question is how do you account for the Broadcom settlement? Is that a one-time loss I guess in this quarter or how are you going to account for that going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, we took &#x2013; the only accounting for this quarter is fairly modest. In this quarter, it's an amortization of some of the patents that we acquired as well as some imputed interest on the extended payments. So the bulk of the charge occurred last quarter, and this quarter was fairly minimal as it will be going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Okay, thanks. And then second, this is probably for Steve. On Android, for the second half of '09, is that &#x2013; I don't know, maybe you could discuss your expectations for that and let us know. It seems like you have pretty good share on the Android Designs. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, we're pretty optimistic about Android. We've had a number of customers choose Android on our 7000 and 8000 devices, and you've seen a number of them come out sort of in the first half, primarily from HTC. But we're looking forward to that having a bit more broad adoptions. And then as Paul mentioned in his text, I think the cloud-based computing and some of the initiatives that Google has in terms of where the data is going to reside will actually be beneficial to us outside of the handset space and into the smartphone space as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Walkley from Piper Jaffray, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. Bill, just a question for you on the overall ASP, how we should think about that for calculating royalties. Obviously, you've got low end CDMA growing in emerging markets. Then you have a higher mix of smartphones. So do you see any seasonal patterns with the March quarter more slanted towards emerging markets and the back half of the year more towards mature markets, or do we just expect ASPs to steadily decline over time? And then also just a quick clarification question, with a little lower operating income margin in the QTL business, was there any other charge on QTL that was unusual this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Mike. First on the ASPs, you get a little regional variation in the ASP. Although for this year in total, we don't think that's going to be too big of a variable. FX for the full year is a bit of a reduction, probably in about the $5 range. So the bulk of it is just an outright increase in the average selling price. I think that's really driven by WCDMA with this significant volume ramp, volume and time is what has enabled the price to come down effectively. But then we're seeing the benefits of that greatly expanded market, TSM declining at a faster rate and makes the call that it's growing at a faster rate. So I think all in all, that has been healthy. But then you're on to the key point then after that. Demand for data capabilities and data features has been growing nicely. And so that has been an offset to some degree and I expect it will continue to be.</p>
          <p>And the second question, QTL op margin, nothing really significant this quarter. You either get some &#x2013; it tends to get some gyrations from quarter to quarter. It tends to be a function more so of relative infrastructure royalties to handset royalties. And from time to time we complete audits and there can be a recovery there, but nothing noteworthy I think at this point to be drawing out. You'll just see some fluctuations from quarter to quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim Long from BMO Capital Markets, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, two somewhat related questions, if I could. Bill, it looks like the blended royally rate did tick up a little bit in the quarter. Was there anything there other than you had mentioned that there was a little bit of shift in the quarter towards the developed world. Is that what helped it or was there anything else going on there?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just back to the overall unit guidance, we are three months later than your last report and you still have a pretty wide range. So you should have much better visibility now but you chose not to tighten that range. So how should we read into that and what would you say are the big secular issues that are going to move you one way or the other in that range? Is it <mark type="inaudible" /> or are there other drivers there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, on the royalty rate, we did mention, I would just point out we did mention last quarter that we had a very large quarter in terms of shipments of our CSM chips, the infrastructure chips, and we had a fairly good quarter also on infrastructure royalties in the quarter we just reported with all of the network build-out that has been going on in a number of regions. But other than that, the driver tends to be, as I said, it's mix of customers, reporting licensees, and then the mix of the combination of subscriber royalties versus infrastructure royalties versus royalties that end up as a result of our audits.</p>
          <p>On the unit guidance, yes, we had a good discussion on the range that we went through our normal processes, and it was good to see we're still vectored on the midpoint of our estimate. But we decided it's best to leave the range as it was. One, the economic situation although it's improving certainly, there is uncertainty ahead. And then number two is that we're still at &#x2013; we think we're at a very low level of total channel inventory for CDMA product. And so we thought we'd best let that go another quarter or so before we would consider narrowing that range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim Luke from Barclays Capital, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much. Bill, maybe Steve, as you just think about the calendar year for the chip side, could you just remind us how we should think about seasonality as we head into the calendar fourth quarter? As the market ramps, should we usually expect the chip business to see some sequential improvement, or are there factors as you build ahead of a slower March quarter that might mitigate a sequential improvement in the chip number in the calendar fourth quarter?</p>
          <p>And Bill, you were reiterating that your sense that you feel 14 or 15 weeks is the level now for the channel. Did you feel that that's the level that is sustainable going forward, or do you ultimately believe that there will be some further restocking required? Like you just said, Don, maybe you could give us some sense of the EC update if there is any to perhaps coordinate with a Korea update. Thank you so much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, this is Bill. On the first two questions, looking at the chips on the calendar year, I think the most pertinent point here is that we've reiterated our 565 million unit forecast for the calendar year. And so we are expecting good growth in unit shipments of new devices into that market here for the next two quarters, and I think that bodes well for our chipset business. I think overall we've done &#x2013; have been doing steadily well on share, steadily improving on share, so I hope that should bode well for us on the chipset side.</p>
          <p>On the 14 to 15 weeks, we would like to believe that's sustainable, but I would say we're suspect of that. We think at the 14 to 15 weeks, it's a pretty tight level, especially when you consider the wide variety of devices that are out in the market on 3G technology and the range of offerings that operators and consumers can avail themselves of. I think that's pretty tight. I wouldn't be surprised if over the next couple of years we see that uptick a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Simona Jankowski from Goldman Sachs, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you very much. The first one is just if you can give us an update on the license and renegotiations with one of your WCDMA licensees, and if you're still expecting that to be completed by September? And then just secondly, within your overall commentary on inventory in the channel having stabilized, just by region, is that still the case in China, or do you see China still bleeding down, and if you can just give us the context of what percent you think of your end demand comes from China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Derek. Let me go ahead and take the first one. I think really not much more of an update since the last call. Our negotiations are continuing. I think we're making good progress, and I think we still anticipate concluding the extension sort of within the timeframe that we've talked about before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the inventory channel stabilization, when we speak of that inventory channel, we're speaking of it on a worldwide basis. There's are always ebbs and flows on a regional basis. As we mentioned earlier that we think there were a couple of major operator launches in China, and as is typical as we've seen many times in our past, there is a little pre-build for that. It's only logical to see that happen. But I would just add that we're maintaining our 565 million midpoint for the market, and we haven't deviated our regional estimates. So we think thus far, the market is performing pretty much to our expectation. We're monitoring it closely, but we're not really seeing surprises on our end here.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the China specific to our business, we used to disclose that, and we've drawn back from that for a number of reasons. So I don't think we'll be getting back into disclosing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Philip Cusick from Macquarie, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, thanks. I wonder if we can talk first about cost cuts. How much has really come through versus your expectations and versus what we're going to see in the fourth quarter? And then will those be fully baked by the fourth quarter or should we look for some in early next year? And then second of all, if you could just give us an update on what you expect from MediaFLO devices later this year, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the cost cuts, there are some implementation costs we're incurring this year. We've declined to break those out. I know others do so. We prefer not to. We're making select and small adjustments in our work force. I expect on the programs, we'll be largely done going out of this year, but I think some programs will have some momentum that will carry on into some improvements for fiscal '10 as well. So I think the program has gone well. It has been very broad. We're seeing improvements across every organization in every business unit in the company. And so we feel it's been well engrained by our approximately 16,000 employees and largely complete end of this year, but I think still some benefits to show through in fiscal '10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, this is Len Lauer. Your question about MediaFLO devices, we're &#x2013; as we move through the year and really get into the fourth quarter of the calendar year, we're excited on a number of fronts. One is we'll have some new feature phones out to our operator partners but also entering the smartphone marketplace with a smartphone device.</p>
          <p>We also in partner with Audiovox in the fourth quarter will be launching into dealers and going into the rear end displays in cars in the U.S., and that will be aftermarket at the dealers, and also launching accessory capabilities to go out to existing devices that have a FLO capability. So you will see an expansion of the devices both in handsets and also accessories that will really start to I think establish us in being strong with the operators and more distribution channels with the consumers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Kulbinder Garcha from Credit Suisse, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and just a couple questions, first of all for Bill, just a clarification. Did you mention that you could have further OpEx savings into 2010, and can we then assume that OpEx could continue to grow at a slower pace than sales going forward for a few quarters? That's a clarification. And the second question is on the licensee negotiation that was mentioned about six months ago, is Qualcomm expected to accrue that fiscal year? And can you give us any update in terms of how that deal might look in terms of upfront payment or not and any kind of idea on timing really? Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll try and clarify on the cost side. Yes, we do expect some benefits to carry on into next year. And I would say yes, we were definitely planning at this stage that our operating expenses would grow at a slower rate than our revenues would for fiscal '10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the license extension, this is Derek. Again as I said, I think we're still confident that we will conclude this extension in the timeframe that we previously discussed. Again, we've been somewhat cautious in terms of getting too much into the details. We do continue to believe that the agreement will include a lump sum component to it as well as a number of other terms and conditions. So I think that is also consistent with what we've said in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Matthew Hoffman from Cowen and Company, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, a quick review here on the infrastructure side. You mentioned that the royalties were a little bit better on QTL. Can you go through the OEMs where you have &#x2013; are there certain OEMs where you see better royalty rates than others? Is there a mix issue on that front or is it just that the overall infrastructure spending was better in the quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, on our infrastructure royalties over the years, we've described them a couple times as lumpy. It's really more a function of network build-outs and the timing of those. It's just that it has been the nature of our infrastructure royalties for many years here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And as you look into the 4G roadmap here both on the &#x2013; especially on chipset side, I guess as you look at what's going on with LTE, can you update us on the chipset front there, and are you on target to hit all your milestones on LTE chips? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Steve. On LTE, we've announced two products. We announced a product a little bit over a year ago or about year and a half ago which was a data centric product. That came in really three flavors, all of them multimode because we believe that the initial deployments and in fact for some period of time that deployments will require both a backward compatibility mode and a 4G mode as well. That product is on track and doing well.</p>
          <p>We've also augmented our product line this February by announcing a smartphone product as well, which combines the processing power from our Snapdragon product with the modem of the product that I just mentioned, the LTE modem that we just talked about. So we have a fairly robust portfolio of products for LTE, and I would expect us to do a similar thing to what we've done with HSDPA or with DO, which is that we will move that through the portfolio as the market requires it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Anil Doradla from William Blair, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. My question was regarding India and 3G options out there. The second half of '09 as the options get completed, how should we be viewing the impact of that on Qualcomm, especially &#x2013; I mean can we start seeing it blip a quarter or two from now just as we've seen with stronger demand in China, and have you accounted that in your Q4 guidance going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Paul, so there is still little bit of uncertainty about the exact date of the auctions. There are some reports coming out of India talking about whether or not the government is in a hurry to have those auctions, so it's not clear yet exactly when that's going to happen. It's likely that the major impact of that would not be in this calendar year though. With that said, we continue to see good growth in China. As I said &#x2013; I'm sorry, in India. They passed the 100 million mark in CDMA, so that was a nice milestone to pass.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean typically if the auctions are done say on a certain date, typically do the handset vendors start ordering chips a quarter or two before or what is the time difference between the auctions and their ordering chipsets from folks like you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In this case if the operators don't know whether or not they're going to get a spectrum, they won't be pre-building. So it will take them some time, probably the better part of a year, to build their networks out. They may have some early launches, so you'd see that ramp happen.</p>
          <p>And then often what happens in a new market is that multiple vendors will try and/or think that they're going to get the same order, so we have to actually judge what the end demand is. But the ramp &#x2013; you can see what's going on in the ramp with say China Unicom as a good proxy here where we are seeing demand, but it's still a little slower as they continue to roll their network out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>James Faucette from Pacific Crest, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I wanted to quickly touch on chipsets, primarily both from a strategic perspective and also from a current market perspective. From a strategic perspective on Snapdragon, so far we've really only seen that product announced into smartphones. Can you talk just quickly about why you think that is and at what point we'll likely start to see that move more aggressively into other form factors and segments?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is, you talked a little bit about pricing coming down some going forward, and you seem to allude to that being primarily mix driven. Can you talk about what type of pricing or competitive pressures you may be seeing on the different segments of your chip businesses? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On both those questions, the first one on Snapdragon, what we did was we invested in this technology really for two markets or two market segments. The first one is really high end smartphones of which the first ones you've seen with the Toshiba TG01, as well as devices that we think cross over between a smartphone and a laptop, a term that we would refer to as a smartbook. We've talked a number of times about how the first of that second category, meaning smartbook phones, will start to come out in the fourth calendar quarter of this year, and we still remain confident in those launches. We do expect that market to develop over time, paced primarily by how the software gets developed across the various players. There are a number of traditional software providers in the cellular space that are trying to pull that user experience up into this new class of devices, and we're excited about supporting them and I think that will build through next year as well.</p>
          <p>With regards to pricing, which was your second question, what we said was that we would see kind of a marginal downtick in pricing, pretty consistent with what we would see in all cases in cellular, which is that there is an ASP erosion. If you were to think about next quarter versus the quarter we just reported on, a similar type of mix in terms of strong demand for the products that use data. So we feel pretty good about how our ASP is going to hold up given the normal trends that are in cellular. So I think it's more of a strong story than perhaps you're thinking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Glen Yeung from Citi, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. I just wanted to follow actually on the last question with respect to ASPs. I think part of what we're seeing obviously is a mix shift downwards, and that's likely being exacerbated by the economy. And I wonder if you can give us your thoughts on what if any impact there may be on ASPs to the extent the economy is getting better next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on ASPs for next year, it's a little too difficult to tell. And one of the reasons is really what impact and what size will the China market be. We've talked a bit about how difficult it is to predict new market launches, and they tend to be lumpy in terms of demand. But in terms of the developed market, which we're starting to see, as we said, the inventories stabilize, we feel pretty good about how the ASPs are holding up there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one other question. I think the comment was made that the CSM business was actually very strong up until now. Is that being guided down for third quarter, either if it is or isn't? And what's the thought about Q4, calendar Q4?  Is there potential for that business to change course?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Steve again. On the CSMs, we announced last quarter that we had a record shipments, primarily DO Revision A and B capable; a similar type of shipment level this quarter, not at the record level, but still very, very strong. And we expect that to continue consistent with new carriers launching.</p>
          <p>I would say though that from the perspective of our broader business, the CSM business tends not to be as financially significant, but it does indicate mix shift in the future meaning the fact that the carriers are deploying DO Revision B capable infrastructure means that we expect reasonable demand for the handsets in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Adam Benjamin from Jefferies, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I was just interested in asking some follow-up questions on the wireless LAN. You guys introduced a product there after quite some time, out of the Airgo acquisition. Just curious if you can elaborate on the strategy there going forward. You partnered with Atheros, if you can elaborate on that partnership going forward as well as your own solutions, that would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, this is Steve again, really two vectors there. On the very high end, I think we have a vision of a connected home or certainly devices in the home distributing much higher data rates. And I think those devices will tend to be connected more with the cellular network than they have been in the past. So you can envision our Femtocell product and our high data rate wireless LAN product perhaps coming together in a format that may be very easy for the market to take. So on the high end, I think we have a strategy to run that in the connected home.</p>
          <p>In terms of the more standard products and I mentioned the WCN1312, that's really an extension of our existing integration strategy where we think it's important as the attach rate goes up in the handset devices that we start to integrate those more tightly with our solutions. So really both of those vectors we're driving now. And as we've mentioned in previous calls, that really augments our existing Bluetooth capability as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So when do you expect to be shipping your own Wi-Fi solution, either comboed with somebody else's Bluetooth or standalone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've been shipping Bluetooth for the last year, and we expect at the end of this calendar year to start to ship our wireless LAN solution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Stacy Rasgon from Sanford Bernstein, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Thanks for taking my question. I just wanted to revisit again the device guidance for next year. So I know historically typically you have maybe 55% or a little bit more or a little bit less of shipments in the back end. But I mean It's obvious you've got a bit more of a ramp this time. It doesn't sound like it's restocking. I'm just curious if you can give me a little more color on what actually is driving that ramp. Is it demand pickup? Is it something else that's going in the channel, or what is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think it's demand pickup. We expect the channel to be holding in this kind of 14 to 15 week band, so we do think it's a demand pickup. We've seen continued success with demand by the end consumer for advanced data services. We're continuing to see operators doing well with data ARPU. There seems to be a healthy competition out there for enabling good affordable prices for the end user. And you have a large number of network launches and network upgrades. So we think &#x2013; and then a bit &#x2013; a little bit better improving economy as well. So we think the foundation is there and we're hopeful of seeing it come to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give me any color on how much of that might be driven by handset demand versus demand for other devices, I guess non-handset demand that are also 3G?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've indicated in the past that the data device &#x2013; data-only device market has been quite strong. We gave some estimates on that about nine months ago. I would just say that we continue to see that to be a very healthy market growing at a very strong rate, stronger than the market as a whole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark Sue from RBC Capital Markets, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, just the over-asked question in a different way. Is there any share loss going on on the chipset side perhaps at China Telecom? And then separately as it relates to Snapdragon, any rough estimates on smartbook units next year and whether or not we should be worried about cannibalization with smartphones?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As it relates to share, as you probably are aware, we actually don't talk about that in terms of quantitative numbers. But I think as Bill mentioned, we feel pretty good about our share position at the moment and as exiting this fiscal year as well.</p>
          <p>With regards to Snapdragon and how it may cannibalize different markets, I think our view is that it's very much an incremental market relative to the smartphone market. I think you will start to see and it's evidenced in our customer base a lot of customers which will cross over. But from the perspective of a handset person looking at this market, it will look incremental.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do want to just also come back to the point, the question that was asked on data devices. There have been some press reports on various markets, notably some developing world markets. And we just know we've seen this in the past that as some press would tend to report a market, they often &#x2013; they don't count a subscriber who has a voice centric device and a data-only device. They don't count that as two subscribers. Obviously we do. So you can see some &#x2013; you might be seeing some anomalies in terms of how you're picking up numbers from various sources versus what we're seeing here simply because of the data devices and subscribers having multiple subscriptions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig Berger from FBR Capital Markets, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the questions. First just help me understand a little bit more on the mirasol business. Is there meaningful business there and what type of devices? And then a separate issue, for LTE do we see the same type of royalty rate on LTE that you're seeing on the 3G licensing business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to clarify, you're asking about the status on the mirasol business? Your phone line was breaking up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the revenue for 3G &#x2013; size and devices timeframe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't started to project revenues for the mirasol display business yet. We just launched the first fab. It's coming up to speed and we're pleased with the traction that we're getting with customers. Obviously the first customers are going to be relatively small opportunities as we launch the technology into the market. But from a technology standpoint as we look out, we have some nice demonstrations we've done on larger displays, full motion video, and enhanced color gamut. So I think the roadmap looks good for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Derek. Let me take the LTE question. I think as you all know, the multimode devices that have CDMA and WCDMA as well as LTE will continue to be covered under our existing CDMA/WCDMA agreements. We've also now signed eight what we call single mode OFDMA subscriber agreements, meaning ones that do not include CDMA or WCDMA, including with Nokia. And we've stated publicly as well as on our external website that we expect at this time based on our patent position and the standards around LTE that we would expect to charge 3.25% for a license to our essential patent portfolio for the single-mode OFDMA devices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Steve. Derek, I think it's important to know that we believe strongly that as LTE rolls out, it will be rolled out in a multimode fashion. So for a significant period of time, our existing CDMA agreements will cover that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Tavis McCourt from Morgan Keegan, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="26" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question, two of them. First in the QCT business, it looks like operating margins were as good as they've been in quite a while. And I'm just wondering is there a point where it gets more difficult to continue to expand margins in that business and you have to keep on reinvesting, or is this something that we can expect margins to continue to expand as revenues ramp in the chip business?</p>
          <p>And then second, now that it seems like you've got the spectrum, you're ramping products with the FLO TV. Can you explain to us a little bit how financially this will work in terms of added OpEx or CapEx over the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Steve. I'll take the first question. Yes, this quarter we actually did have a very strong profit percentage, driven primarily by the leverage coming from the top line. So I think it's a fact in this business that you have to continue to invest in order to maintain your leadership position, and that will be true moving forward.</p>
          <p>We have seen and we expect this calendar or this fiscal year to exit that year or exit this year in a range that's more consistent with our historical levels. So we're pleased that the business has really returned to the point where we said it was going to be about two quarters ago when we said that when the orders returned that that will restore the leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And this is Len Lauer. On your question about MediaFLO, we're close to finishing the majority of the build-out of the network. A lot it was built out waiting for the DTV transition. We've opened in the key markets that Paul mentioned earlier. And now we're pretty much in implementation mode of going out expanding as we said earlier, the number of devices and also enhancing with our distribution partners. So I'd say it's pretty steady state, we should grow and expecting increases in what we've been doing. And now we're just really looking forward to executing with a strong national network and hopefully having even better service out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And ladies and gentlemen, we have reached the end of the allotted time for questions and answers. Dr. Jacobs, do you have any final or closing comments you'd like to make?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to thank everybody for being on the call today. I was particularly happy to see the chipset shipments back to a record level this quarter. It's nice to see that that followed our projections as we went into the downturn and to come out the way that we projected.</p>
          <p>Also I like seeing the uptick in the treasury portfolio. We didn't spend too much time on that today, but I just wanted to say that our team there did an exceptionally good job this quarter.</p>
          <p>I'm also pleased by the fact that we've been managing the OpEx as well as we have, particularly SG&amp;A, because we've continued to be able to grow R&amp;D, and we think there are a lot of exciting opportunities to address with our research and development. Obviously, we talked a lot about the trends towards smartphones, and we're very excited by the smartbook opportunity with some exciting new partnerships and as well as our strong existing partners.</p>
          <p>And then as we look forward, we discussed these new geographies opening up, and clearly this is a strong 2G to 3G transition which is continuing. It's nice to see. We're really happy after all these years to see that we're going to have the majority of the shipments of the 3G devices going forward.</p>
          <p>So we're very happy with our competitive position. I think we have some great new products and great new technologies coming out over the next year. And hopefully that will continue to show in our performance. So thanks very much everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude today's conference call. We would like to thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>