<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1492453" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7787</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Stephen A. Hester</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrew P. Coombs</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Director &amp; Group Finance Director">Bruce W. van Saun</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Chirantan Barua</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Jason C. Napier</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Rohith Chandra-Rajan</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Chintan Joshi</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Raul Sinha</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Investec Bank Plc (Broker)">Ian D. Gordon</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Autonomous Research LLP">Manus J. Costello</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Michael F. Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Oriel Securities Ltd.">Mike J. Trippitt</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Tom A. Rayner</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Peter H. Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd.">Ed H. Firth</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep" affiliation="Head of Investor Relations, Royal Bank of Scotland Plc">Richard O'Connor</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Santander Investment Bolsa Sociedad de Valores SA">Arturo de Fr&#xED;as</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Today's conference call will be hosted by Stephen Hester, Group Chief Executive of RBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you very much for joining us. With me as usual is Bruce van Saun, our Finance Director, Richard O'Connor, who you also know, Head of Investor Relations. This morning has a slightly different format than other half years because obviously we're not doing a physical presentation. I hope all of you have seen our physical presentation via webcast which was up 7:00 this morning in addition to our releases and in that context, therefore, we're not going to re-go over that ground. We're only going to spend this morning's session answering any questions that you may have which, of course, Richard can do afterwards if we don't get to all of them.</p>
          <p>So let me simply say by way of introduction that I believe RBS is making good progress, albeit, clearly we're doing it in the face of a set of challenging conditions in economic and regulatory terms. We have two jobs as you know. The clean-up job, I think, continues to go well. We're on course for the five year timetable we set out, and on every measure, we're getting stronger and safer, important in these difficult times and it's showing how we can ride through some of the current storms that have been going on in financial markets.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we do have a good ongoing bank that we're building and that is poised to respond even better when economic times allow. The vast majority of our ongoing businesses are already making double-digit ROEs. They're all capable of doing double-digit ROEs, better than the cost of capital as well. And I believe that we'll see the upturn once our customers see the upturn. In the meantime, we're working hard to make them as strong and resilient as they can be given the top line pressures there are. And I think that in many key areas, we're ahead of the game in terms of our restructuring activity, most notably the change of proportion of our wholesale activities to the total that we have effected.</p>
          <p>So with those introductions, let me pass straight over to any questions you may have. And operator, perhaps, you can take us through them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stephen. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll take our first question from Andrew Coombs from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. I have three questions, please. One on the charges you've taken, the technology issues and hedges, one on APS [Asset Protection Scheme] and the B shares and then finally on provisions.</p>
          <p>If I start with the first one, it's interesting to see that you've taken the &#xA3;125 million charge for the June technology issues and a &#xA3;50 million charge on the interest rate hedge products above the line, whereas you've taken the PPI charge below the line. Is there anything we should read in to that in terms if you think the first two potentially are ongoing or recurring costs, whereas the latter is seen to be a non-recurring cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think on -- clearly, on the tech incident, that's an operating pitfall of the businesses that we operate in. We made a conscious decision not to push those back to the affected businesses because, in effect, those businesses secure the technology services from our centralized technology group. So we thought it was appropriate to show those in the core performance, but not attribute those back, so you're able to see the underlying trends in the affected businesses.</p>
          <p>On the interest rate and the selling, that's a little bit of a finer call. I think at this point we left it in core and we could reassess that down the road; but PPI to us was something that was really relating to prior periods. And so therefore it's exceptional in nature, in size, and time period and we thought it was appropriate to leave that one in exceptionals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, and just to move on to the second question. I noticed you've been more firm in your dialogue regarding APS. You talk about more of an announcement once you got formal regulatory clearance, but then you're talking or it seems very certain we're going to hear that in the second half. On that front I mean perhaps you could also update us on the B share and any renegotiations there are on that front, or are they, continue to be viewed as completely separate to the APS exit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think our focus has been on APS exit, that's for the moment. I think the DAS [debt available-for-sale] repurchase and B share simplification is something that's more for down the road; as in over the next 18 months we're very focused on sustaining our capital ratios through the whole period of RWA [risk-weighted asset] inflation with CRD IV [Capital Requirements Directive] and some of the local regulator initiatives. And so, dividend is farther out in the future, and since the DAS relates to the dividend, I think that can wait for another day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Final question was on provisions. I just wanted to highlight the Non-Core provisions, you talk about a large one-off provision there in Portfolio Finance. How big is that one-off provision as a function of the &#xA3;607 million Non-Core provisions you've taken during the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was about &#xA3;125 million. So, it related to an asset in the project finance portfolio and it was something that we thought could go sometime this year, and it happened that we assessed it to take the impairment in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Chira Barua from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Quick three questions. One on Non-Core. Great progress there. What do we see as the block at the end of 2013? Around -- it would be great if you can give us some color around the credit risk and market risk that'll remain up there. The second one is on technology. Are you foreseeing increasing spend in technology given the outage going forward? And third is on the Dutch entity. Are there any implications for capital, tech charges and funding if that collapses? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the first and Bruce the second two. I think at the end of 2013, we've given our balance sheet target for Non-Core, i.e., we think it will be at the point where it is close to irrelevant in balance sheet and funding balance terms, and therefore that the priority for reduction falls. I don't think we will have substantive market risk left at that stage. Obviously, we will have credit risk in the rump of assets there. We give very high disclosure on what's in there and clearly, the stickiest bit will be real estate, especially Irish real estate positions. I hope they will be substantially provided by that stage, although obviously we'd have to see.</p>
          <p>So, I expect Non-Core will make losses beyond 2013, but they should fall sharply. We shouldn't be needing to take big disposal losses post that point, and the rest should be left to run off over whatever period is relevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On your second question about tech spend, I should be clear that over the first three and a half years of the recovery plan, we've increased the tech spend quite dramatically and so we're doing lots of things to both address the infrastructure systems and resilience as well as the fancy new stuff in terms of how you communicate with the bank and mobile apps and things like that.</p>
          <p>This tech incident was a very specific matter in upgrading a piece of software that runs, that's related to the batch running overnight. We are going through a full investigative review to get to root cause and then look at our response and look at what we need to do to make sure that doesn't happen again. I do think that the preliminary findings there are that it will not cost a meaningful amount of money to actually make this right and make this more resilient going forward. So we have to do some things to simplify the batches and to tighten our processes and procedures a bit. But in terms of having a meaningful impact on future spend, I don't think you'll see it.</p>
          <p>Your last question was on the Dutch entity and I think again here, we've been doing this in waves. We moved over a big slug of assets last year in the fall. This is the last big slug to move across. We had it all teed up for July but that was right in the midst of the tech incident. We wanted to keep our focus on that first. We pushed it back out to the September 8, that weekend. All systems are go and we think that'll go off without incident and then we'll really have a fairly much of a rump left in that NV entity that will just run down over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Jason Napier from Deutsche Bank. Please ask you question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, three fairly straightforward ones, I think. Just in terms of the wealth division in Core, there's reference made to it again on disposal as well as reduced cost on the ALICO Enhanced Variable Rate Fund. But would you be able to give us sort of a sense of what the net impact of those is, if you could?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the quarter, those are about a wash, so we had a kind of mid-teens positive impact from the gain on disposal and same as in terms of the redress on the regulatory matter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and from a principal perspective the reason those don't go in strategic disposal gains below the line is because they were, it wasn't in Non-Core or how do you think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It wasn't a separate business. It wasn't a discrete business that we would carve out and sell. It was simply client relationships. So, it was actually a book of business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, okay. Thank you. Secondly, the AFS disclosure seems to suggest that a sort of a better quarter for realizations there, maybe &#xA3;150 million more than last quarter. I'm just wondering whether you sort of think there's anything unusual in sort of run-rate of realizations there, whether that's a repeatable kind of contribution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually that's not accurate Jason. I could see why you could draw that supposition. But there was actually a few things going on in Central Items...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...probably the biggest of which was a swing in IFRS volatility. So, there's a risk management P&amp;L in treasury that bounces around based on &#x2013; it's effectively a hedge portfolio. We don't want to burden the businesses with that, so we keep it in Central Items and it had flipped from a negative last quarter to a positive this quarter; and that flip was quite significant, over &#xA3;150 million. So the actual incremental swing in the AFS gains from quarter-to-quarter was, I'd say, circa &#xA3;50 million. It wasn't that big.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the Note 14, sort of &#xA3;160 million, there's something else going on elsewhere that brings that down to about &#xA3;50 million, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the Visa gain is probably in there as well. So that was reported in the U.S. results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay. And then lastly, potentially a question for Stephen. The commentary around the Funding-for-Lending scheme is extremely clear and the sentiments around passing on the funding gain to customers is one that we've heard from Barclays retail already.</p>
          <p>I just wonder whether &#x2013; you sort of confirmed that the lending will obviously be profitable from a shareholder ROE perspective, and also how it is you think about passing this on. Is this is a cost plus kind of thought process? It's generally not the way that we sort of understand product pricing to work. So I'm just interested in how you thought about the waiving of fees on SME and the like? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, all of our ROE disciplines in our affected business divisions are intact. So in other words, the instructions of our management is to target ROEs better than the cost of capital in the things that they do. But simply, what I did was to say that to the extent that funding cost fell as a result of this government scheme, that we shouldn't treat that as a windfall profit but we should use that to pass it on to customers. And so that's all that's going on now.</p>
          <p>Obviously, every individual pricing decision has got all sorts of different dynamics and is in front book and back book impacts and so on. But the business targets are unchanged, but there is -- I think it would be inappropriate and undesirable to take out any windfall gains from this and it's our job to pass it on to customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Rohith Chandra-Rajan from Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. Thank you. A couple of cap -- on capital, please. Firstly on Basel III, just wondering if you could give us a bit more clarity around the 9% to 9.5% fully-loaded 2013 ratio, both -- if you could sort of just reiterate your capital and RWA adjustments. And then also, just describe what you're thinking in terms of the underlying balance sheet and earnings through 2013 that drive that 9% to 9.5% ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So effectively, we've given you most of the numbers previously in terms of the RWA uplifts that come from the CRD IV and then also from some of the FSA local initiatives like CRE slotting. So we continue to track towards those numbers and as I said, our objective is to manage above 10% at year-ends on a transitional basis, both at the end of 2012 and then at the end of 2013. That 9% to 9.5%, the fully loaded deducts would principally relate to three things. So DTAs is one. The EL in excess of provisions is the other and then some for Direct Line Group. And so I think at this point, you have to recall we're in transition, so we're a recovering bank, we're running down Non-Core. There's a bunch of moving parts here as we project outwards. We're using our own balance sheet projections. We're using consensus earnings, and then we're giving you the uplift that we have for RWA. So, I think it's -- all the breadcrumbs are there for you to do the math. You can call Richard later in the day and he can walk you through that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Just on the direct. Why is there is a direct line deduction still, at the end of 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we still have an inflation to RWAs for the piece, related to the piece that we hold. So, I guess that would be more of an RWA impact than a deduct impact, you're right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And then, secondly, just on Non-Core. The &#xA3;7 billion to &#xA3;12 billion asset reductions for the second half, I'm just wondering about the risk weighting and the capital impact of that. So, risk weighting on the book overall is about 100%. It looks like the reduction in the first half, if you exclude the operational risk, RWA inflation, was mid-60s? So in terms of what you've got targeted for the second half of year, I was wondering what the average risk weighting we should think about would be. And then also in total Non-Core, again, excluding the op risk, it looks pretty much capital neutral in the first half. And again, so I just wonder if that was something we should extrapolate for the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in Q2, aviation capital was a big driver in terms of the types of assets that went out. I think adjusting for that, I'd say closer to 1:1 would probably be the risk weights that go out over the rest of year. What -- your second question was on ops risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Sorry, the second question was just in terms of overall capital impact. So, first half looks pretty much capital neutral. It should look at the RWA reduction and the losses in Non-Core, whether that would also be the expectation for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's safe. When we look out over a longer period of time, it's neutral to slightly accretive. That's still our call on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're still working through regulatory increases in risk weighting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah,</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which are broadly offsetting the asset reduction, at least this year and the beginning...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so there are some headwinds in terms of that you won't be able to do the quick math. We'll probably have to clarify that for you, but there's things like CRE slotting are going to affect the Non-Core RWA. So, there'll be a little bit of gapping there relative to what the underlying trend is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. Thanks very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Chintan Joshi from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, three questions from me please. And the first one is in your prepared comments you mentioned growth in the U.K. R&amp;C divisions. How has the pace of growth for aggregate U.K. lending, as the BoE sees that, has been over the past 6 to 12 months? Do you believe you can grow aggregate lending in the next 18 months including non-core deleveraging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that it is safest for us to assume that lending doesn't expand until economic growth takes place. That would be the pattern of past recessions speaking of the industry as a whole. And, of course, any bank with a non-core will then see if core lending isn't expanding, will then be a reduction in respect to those non-core. Now obviously, if we are able to take market share then that would be an offset. In mortgages in the U.K., we have been able to take market share which is why our mortgage book has been rising. In corporates, we haven't taken much market share which is why the corporate book has been stable to slightly down in terms of draw lending even though gross lending has been quite active.</p>
          <p>So I think that the -- I think, since you're probably working through to net interest income trends, we've made some comments on NIM. But in terms of, if you like, interest earning balances, I don't think that we -- you should assume favorable trends yet a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would say to Stephen's point, in terms of once you see some recovery, I think a number like 4% to 5% loan growth is something that we could see. But, of course, the path from here to then and how quickly that materializes is a hard call at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that 4% to 5% in Core?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not now...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand, recovery, yeah. Just following on from that. I mean, if -- I mean, the Bank of England clearly wants to see growth of lending in the U.K. or the next 18 months. Growth isn't likely to be recovering substantially over the next 18 months. Do you think you would face pressure from the regulator if net lending in the U.K. didn't expand because two big banks are reducing lending in Non-Core?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that the regulator is in fact is insistent that the two banks in question do reduce their Non-Core for risk reasons. And because, of course, a large amount of that Non-Core is commercial real estate which the regulator wants to have reduced and is putting regulatory penalties on holding through slotting. So I don't think there's any dissonance with the regulators in terms of Non-Core.</p>
          <p>And even -- and the authorities, I mean, the authorities want the economy to grow and want lending to be available if it is needed for that. I think the Bank of England understands that in recessions, lots of companies and individuals are trying to manage their balance sheet downwards. So, what they're mostly focused on, is that if lending doesn't grow, it should be because there isn't creditworthy demand, not because there are supply constraints. And also, they're now trying to discover whether there is any price elasticity and the funding-for-lending is all about whether there's price elasticity at low interest rates or not; and of course, we'll see that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. My second question was on Citizens, you've obviously seen the New York Post article. I'm wondering how core is Citizens?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Citizens is core. It was loss-making three years ago, and every single year that we've been managing it, we've improved its performance. So, it is much more valuable to our shareholders today than it was three years ago and I expect it to be more valuable again in three years from now. Now, obviously, we're a shareholder-owned company, we will always try to behave in the interest of shareholders on any of our businesses, but our view is that the most valuable thing we can do for shareholders is to keep the trajectory of Citizens moving upwards as a core part of the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if you get...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it is -- and I should just add, it is a very valuable franchise, so it's not surprising if people think that it is so. But as Stephen said, we're continuing to improve it, and it fits well inside our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the article indicates that you're looking for &#xA3;14 billion to &#xA3;16 billion, which is a premium...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, the article is completely inaccurate. We have not received an offer and we haven't put a price on it. We...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're in no discussions...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You don't have to look very far to see the sort of prices that banks are getting in disposal today. We don't think that would be optimizing, to sell any banking asset, other than our non-core ones, in the current environment and we think we can improve Citizens' performance further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and the third and last question, very quick one. Where do you see the Base III Core Tier 1 fully loaded today? Ex-APS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess that's -- ex-APS, did you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, ex-APS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, look. It's not a number that we published because, again, as I said, in response to an earlier question, we're in transition and so we're targeted to where the future numbers are that we're going to have to print down the road when it really matters. If you'd look at where we are today, I think we're roughly in the pack with the U.K. peers. So it would be mid sevens [mid-7%], but again, that's not a number that we're very much focused on or concerned about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, not least, we've got Direct Line which is about to be sold which is one of the big type of calculations in this thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And indeed our strength in their branches, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Non-Core is not run down to where the point it'll matter. So there's a bunch of things that I think show a clear path to the range that we indicated of 9% to 9.5% by the end of 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bruce, so that mid seven number is actually ex-APS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Raul Sinha from JP Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, gentlemen. Bruce, in the prepared comments and around the LIBOR issue, I think you mentioned that there are some meaningful securities gains positions available to the group to offset any negative capital impact. Could you elaborate on that statement and maybe give us some idea of where these gains are coming from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, sure. In our liquidity buffer, we have various holdings that we have in cash at central banks. We have a bond portfolio. We have other eligible collateral that's posted at the discount window. So that number is &#xA3;155 billion. Within the government bond element of that, we have tried to stay very high quality. So, we have a big portfolio of treasuries, gilts and bunds that as the world have seemed riskier, those assets have become safe havens and have rallied in price.</p>
          <p>And so we have, I think, a meaningful gain that has increased over the half year. And so all we're pointing out is, again, mission critical over the next 18 months is to absorb these regulatory impacts on capital and continue to deliver according to our operating plan. If things hit us that weren't expected we have some balance sheet actions, including realizing securities gains that could generate Core Tier 1 capital and provide some offset. So, that's there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I mean obviously, this doesn't look like you want to quantify it for us right now. But if I put the question differently, the Bank of England has said or the regulators are quite happy for banks to run down their liquidity buffers. Would this be something that you might consider doing more immediately, sort of in the next few quarters, if you don't think that you require the liquidity buffer to be as high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if we're taking down -- I do think there is potential to take down the liquidity buffer but it would be across the different elements. The things that we hold,  the cash at central banks and the government bond holdings, are things that we could adjust down in response to the FSA and the FPC saying that banks have built buffers upon buffers and probably have more liquidity than is appropriate on the balance sheet and we can work that down. So, we'll be doing that with an eye though towards still some of the challenges in the environment. The eurozone situation, I think, we'll be reasonably cautious in terms of the pace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That leads me to my next question on the margin. I mean, obviously, you're indicating the R&amp;C is likely to be up slightly in the second half. But then when we look at the quarter-on-quarter progression in the R&amp;C margin, it looks like Q2 is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:21)...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that's really a Group NIM statement, so the juxtapositioning may not be the best. But I think we're satisfied with how we've been managing the overall NIM. I think the Retail NIM is likely to be stable and I think we can improve the NIM a bit from here, largely around some of these liquidity and funding initiatives that we have centrally. So we've been driving off some higher cost funding as we reduce liquidity. And I think there's more of that to come in the second half, which can certainly solidify and grow slightly the Group NIM.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just lastly, quick follow-up on the NIM again, the interest rate hedge impact that you indicated is weighing on the U.K. Retail margin. What should we expect that in the second half or going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess, it continues to tractor through. We have kind of a five year hedge in place, and so every month we drop something and we pick up something new. So it's a gradual impact, which is probably going to be similar to what we saw in the first half. And I think the challenge for the business is to look at how they're pricing deposits if we're potentially looking to -- we've got this surplus of liquidity &#x2013; we can drive off some of the higher cost deposits potentially and also look for asset pricing opportunities to offset some of that headwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Ian Gordon from Investec. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually apologies. Mine has already been done. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Manus Costello from Autonomous. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, everyone. I had a couple of questions on your capital structure, please. You're confident of leaving the APS in the second half of this year, but the quid pro quo for that is likely to be some kind of change in the trigger point for your outstanding CoCos [contingent convertible bonds]. So, I wondered if we should be modeling for any kind of charge for that. Because the way you booked the original CoCo line was against equity. I wondered if we should be putting anything in for the second half for any change of trigger in Q3 or Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Manus, on that point, that's been speculated in the press. But we have nothing to comment on there and so there's no guidance in terms of modeling any change at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, your 99.5, for example, of Basel III would not -- in 2013 &#x2013; would not include any impact of changes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct. That is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my second question was coming back to something you discussed at the very beginning of the call about the timing of dividends. I noticed that the Treasury recently changed its assumption on when you would start paying a dividend from 2013 to 2015, and you were talking about putting off discussion of attacking the dividend action to another day. When you talk about another day, is the 2015 timeline something that you would recognize or do you think you could do a bit better than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't -- there's been no board discussion about this. I think the observation I've made is that I was -- we expect the FSA to take a dim view of dividends unless it feels that the capital position is ahead of where Vickers needs it to be, i.e. the 10% sort of thing with CRD IV brought in. And so I think we have to look at the situation at the end of 2013, understand whether we've hit our targets and what the margins are, and then decide how quickly to bring back the dividend in the light of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and so again I think the different analysts have it modeled as 2014 or 2015. If that is the kind of realm of possibility, then a conversation around the DAS and B shares could kick off some time in the back half of next year, I would think. But again, we have no direct timeline or anything agreed with UKFI in terms of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Michael Helsby from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, gentlemen. I've just got three questions. On insurance, the revenue trend is clearly still down and revenues were down Q-on-Q. When do we reach the -- when do we reach the bottom of that trend given obviously all the restructuring that you've been doing and repositioning the book? Second -- do you want to do one at a time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's easier for me to remember them if we do them one at a time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, cool.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, yeah, I think of the highlights for the Insurance Group this quarter was that in-force policies across the different lines of business were actually up 2% and the motor policies stabilized in the quarter. So that's a precursor for, I think, seeing the revenues, top line revenues, bottom out and eventually grow. So if you go back and think about the turnaround, we had taken on risky driver pools that we wanted to drive out. We had taken on some broker business that we didn't want to sustain. And so the effort was around refocusing on the customers that we think were -- the good relationships for the longer term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also, meanwhile, getting our act in order, our house in order, in terms of the basics of the business, pricing, underwriting, claims management, the expense base, which once we got those things properly addressed, we'd be in better position to go out and compete on the front foot for business. And so, we're through -- largely through that. We're now seeing that the in-force policies are stabilizing and the objective would be to start that growing again from here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Great. Thank you. Second question, apologies if this is in the document, but you referred to regulatory increases in the RWAs, but I can't find any reference to the sterling amount that's come in, in the half. Is that in the document or if it's not, could you give us an idea of what it is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think we've absorbed about &#xA3;15 million, so we had said that &#xA3;50 million to &#xA3;65 million was going to be the CRD IV and credit model impact. And so we put away about &#xA3;15 million. So we're running hard in terms of deleveraging and asset reduction and some of this we have to absorb CRE slotting and some other model changes which were taking on board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What division is that in, Bruce? Is that in Commercial or is that in Non-Core or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's mixed around a bit, so there is some in MIB, there is some in Non-Core and there'd be a little bit in UKC as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And finally, just more of a broader question, really. Clearly, from the outside, there looks to be a hell of a lot of political pressure on Royal Bank of Scotland. And a lot of the international investors that I speak to think that as a result, you're just pretty much un-investable. What can you say to talk to about how you ensure that you've got independence as a board from the government?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I guess, here's how I would see it. It remains the case, 3 1/2 years on, that not a single significant strategic or operational decision that we have made or not made has been driven externally by political influences. We've been managing the company for all its shareholders in the best way we know how. And therefore, all I know is what's happened so far and I have no reason to believe that will change, but of course, there are risks in the future but that's the position so far.</p>
          <p>The second thing that I'd say is we all have to recognize that the banking industry is quite politicized everywhere in the world today as a result of its role in the financial crisis and the tensions, the political tensions arising from the financial crisis. And so, banks equals politics whether that's in Spain, or Germany, or here, or America, or Ireland or you pick it.</p>
          <p>And in that sense, there are political risks and calculations that have to be made for the banking industry and the regulation that's affected and the other pressures that could be on it. We've seen that in the U.K. away from RBS rather recently. So, I do think that bank investors are right to worry about politics, but it's not clear to me that RBS is particularly distinguished in that regard. But clearly, the best way we can insulate ourselves from this is to do our jobs well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if we fall down on the job, we invite more interference from whatever quarters. If we do our jobs well, we'll be left to get on with doing it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, you're certainly doing that. So, good luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Mike Trippitt from Oriel Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. A couple of quick questions on Non-Core. Short term, first of all, just on the sequential quarterly movement impairments. I wonder if you could just put a bit of color on the spike up in international banking. And although a smaller number, the U.S. Retail and Commercial impairments have doubled Q-on-Q. And then just tied in with that, your sort of -- your revised guidance on the run-off of the Non-Core this year and then going into next year, should we continue to assume that that will be capital neutral going forward or would you see accelerated losses or impairment charges with that accelerated run-off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first off on impairments, we did point out that there was a large project finance write-off that was in the second quarter and that was about &#xA3;125 million. That principally accounts for the spike. Given that there's a lot of tall trees in Non-Core, I don't think you should expect to see discrete trends quarter to quarter. Those numbers can bounce around a bit from quarter to quarter. You have to really look at the trends over time and you can see that impairments have come down dramatically and consistently through time and we would expect that trend to continue. The book is getting smaller and most of the really poor assets such as the Irish Development Land and different assets, we've impaired pretty heavily and reserved against pretty heavily.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was glad you said that. That project finance one-off is in international banking, is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the U.S. is not -- I don't think there's anything worth commenting on there. I think that's just noise from quarter to quarter. The second question was on run-off and I guess in terms of capital accretion or not. And I think again, we do see kind of through the next 18 months, out two years, that this should be neutral to accretive on an underlying basis. However, there is a few headwinds of the CRE slotting that will maybe not make that as apparent, so we'll try to break that out so that you can see that. But again, as Stephen indicated, I think there's probably another year of hard work to get from low 60s down to 40. We'll probably have higher disposal losses next year and lower impairments and the overall loss should come down a bit, but it won't meaningfully drop until 2014, 2015, in which case I think at that point, it steps down pretty significantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Tom Rayner from BNP Paribas. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, chaps. Can I just go backwards to the margin guidance because I think I maybe wrongly assumed that it was referring to Retail &amp; Commercial rather than Group? And, I mean, would you be able to give the same guidance if it was on just Retail &amp; Commercial? And if so, can you say anything additional about Retail versus Corporate because there seems to be a bit of diverging trends within the margin progression within those two sort of key divisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, look, I think it again -- I would call it broadly stable in Retail &amp; Commercial. Maybe slightly up would also apply. So it's somewhere between stable to slightly up there as well. I think we've now seen Retail has been under some pressure, U.K. Corporate has held its own and I think at the margin, that's about right. There's a few things in the first half that are non-repeating items, in U.K. Corporate in the second half. So I think U.K. Corporate, you could see a little bit of erosion there in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and in Retail, deposit the pressure you mentioned and also the hedge. Can you give us a sense of what's the key -- I mean the key driver of the -- because obviously you're trying to reprice the assets as well in Retail I guess. I mean is it the hedge that's really making life more difficult for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that's one thing, but the second thing it's just a mix shift. So if you look over time, we've been trying to get a bigger market share in mortgages and we've been running down our book in personal unsecured. And so, I think that's also had a pretty big impact overall. So we've changed our risk appetite. We're doing more mortgage lending and doing less on the personal side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's coming through the impairment line as well, I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes, you're seeing continued positive moves on impairments and credit loss there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Peter Toeman from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions. First of all, can I just -- looking at the market's performance, at the beginning of the year you talked about &#xA3;70 billion reduction of RWAs at market. Actually, over the last six months, we're down about &#xA3;13 billion. So am I right in thinking that you're still budgeting for reduction in market's RWAs from a reduction sort of inventory and, therefore, the numbers we're looking at here are still not in the sort of status quo. There's still &#x2013; revenue numbers &#x2013; could still be subject to declines in trading volumes as books are -- the size of trading books are reduced.</p>
          <p>And then, I guess, the second question, on your comments about discussions on the DAS and B shares taking place at the end of 2013, I mean, that puts you at the end of your sort of five year time scale. So I wondered will you still be around to navigate RBS back to the private sector?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Interesting question. So on the first one, which I can give a more definitive answer to, in markets, there's a couple of things at work here; so there is advance mitigation taking place of <mark type="inaudible" /> (44:55). There is also, I think, a restricted posture in terms of the market risk we want to be taking in these markets, and so you're probably seeing this benefit somewhat from that, and some of that would not be sustainable if the markets pick up. If you have a view that the second half markets aren't going to be great, then maybe that does sustain through the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Obviously, what's coming is the CRD IV uplift and then various other model adjustments work though with the FSA, and so those are the headwinds. But I think we're on top of the game there. All things considered when you look at the exiting of certain businesses, the adjustments to other businesses, using less balance sheet, using less RWAs, to manage through all of that and still put up 14% ROE in the first half in markets and have a performance in line with peers, I think we're pretty pleased with how that's going.</p>
          <p>The second question on the DAS and B shares, look, I think in terms of the safety and soundness agenda we will have ticked all the boxes by the end of 2013 that we had in the original plan, so non-core getting down to 40 tick, strong capital ratio, 100% loan-to-deposit ratio, much improved position of liquidity relative to short-term wholesale funding, I think we'll be able to say job complete where because of the economy, the core businesses may not be at the level of returns that we had hoped for originally. And so that timeframe may be elongated. I'm not sure that ultimately our shareholders would view that as a blemish given the ultimate backdrop that we're facing, but we'll just see. We'll see if we're still here in 2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Edward Firth from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Just one question. On -- in page 185 of your accounts, you give some excellent disclosure on commercial real estate. And I guess my question is about the defaulted portfolio outside Ulster, which seems to have had this massive increase in average loan-to-value from the year-end. It's gone from 129% to 189%. Could you tell us roughly what's driving that and what the implications are in terms of provisioning going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me get caught up to you, page...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, page 185.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You break out the elements of the defaulted and non-defaulted and what the average loan-to-value are, and you highlighted the rest of the group as about &#xA3;12 billion of, I guess, you call it defaulted or nearly defaulted exposure. And it now has an average loan-to-value of 189% and at the year-end it was 129%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It seems to be a huge swing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I guess I'll have to get back to you. Richard will have to come back to you. I don't want to give you an answer off the top of my head.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's an explanation on page 186, on the first key point, down the bottom, it's one corporate client substantially provided for. So it's a one-case distorted number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it looks to me &#x2013; it looks all related. But it looks to me that it's about &#xA3;3 billion of exposure that has swung which would seem to me a huge exposure for one client.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll come back to you. And clearly, we can't comment on one case any more than that but I'll come back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Okay. Thanks, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your final question comes from Arturo de Fr&#xED;as from Santander. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, good morning. Two quick ones, please. One on Retail, ROE trends, I mean, you have already said relatively clearly that the NIM in Retail should be a bit more stable in the second half after having fallen for a few quarters. But the ROE trend which is what I'm interested in has been quite decent mainly due to lower -- substantially lower impairment losses. So I guess my question is, if and when we see the Retail NIM stabilizing, will that or should that increase the Retail ROE, or do you expect some deterioration on impairments to kind of offset that and we will have a stable or established ROE in Retail?</p>
          <p>And the second question is also on ROEs but on markets. I mean we all know that this division is highly volatile and we all know it's very seasonal and usually Q1 is very strong and then the following quarters are weaker. But I have been a bit surprised to see the substantial decrease in profitability in Q1, or in Q2 versus Q1, and my question would be, do you think this is only seasonal or do you have the impression that because of the downsizing, the underlying ROE potential of this division is falling? So, yeah, that's the question. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Look, on the first one, I think the ROEs have been in a 22% to 24% band for U.K. Retail, and I think the outlook as long as the economy is in the situation that's it's in and we don't see any more vigorous recovery, I think it can land and stay in that territory. So we may see the NIM stabilizing. I think the continued trend of improvements in impairments kind of lose the steam at some point. It's not going to go to zero, but I do think we'll stay reasonably consistent until we see the return of more economic vibrancy.</p>
          <p>In terms of the market ROE, you're right that the 14% number for the half had a very strong -- over 20% Q1 and then a 7% Q2. Having said that, that's certainly in line with peer groups, and so I don't think there's anything from the shrinking that's actually affecting our numbers out of proportion to anyone else. I think what we've seen in the past couple of years is a very strong first quarter, a pretty strong second quarter and then the third and fourth quarters could be even softer than the second quarter.</p>
          <p>I think last year that was particularly exacerbated by spread widening, and so many investment banks including ourselves, lost money on their credit books as spreads widened. At this point, I think that's probably less likely in the second half of the year. So the comparisons, I think, there's a good chance to improve upon where we were in the second half of the last year. Having said that, I do think risk is off at the moment and the market conditions are somewhat challenging and so we'd still maintain a reasonably cautious stance on the second half of the year. Having said that, July was a pretty good month. So we'll see how it goes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Can I have a small follow-on on that one? I happened to think that the whole investment banking industry is going to see lower ROEs in the future because of all the changes we are seeing. So, do you say we are not very different from the industry, but that was not exactly my question. My question was, do you think ROEs are going to be structurally lower going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, I think we did when we announced the restructuring at the annual results and we took you through some of the math there. As you'll recall, last year in the first half of the year we had a 17% ROE and then the second half it was breakeven. And so for the year, we ended up at around 8%, 7% to 8%. And we said that wasn't acceptable and we had to develop a plan to improve that, so that we got markets back at least to delivering a return on equity that exceeded our cost of equity. So, if you call that 10.5%, 11%, 11.5%, somewhere in that postal code, that was the plan that we laid out.</p>
          <p>And so if we're starting at 8%, it's going to still, I think, take some period depending on market conditions to just build our way back and pull through some of the adjustments that we've made in terms of smaller balance sheets, smaller cost base, more focused approach into the areas of real strength. That's what we're focused on and I guess the good news on that is through the first half of the year we're exceeding our own internal targets and we're executing that plan quite well. That doesn't mean &#x2013; it's not guaranteeing success &#x2013; we're watching it closely but at least we're off to a good start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific. Well, thank you very much. We much appreciate all of your questions. Richard is available for any follow-ups you may have. We do think that RBS is making progress. Of course, the progress is bounded by the economic and regulatory headwinds, but we're going to continue to keep plugging along in the direction that we've laid out.</p>
          <p>Thank you, again for listening. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that will conclude today's presentation. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>