<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1492454" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call - Fixed Income</title>
    <date>2012-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7787</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Director &amp; Group Finance Director">Bruce W. van Saun</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Treasurer">John Cummins</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Lee A. Street</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Alan M. Bowe</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Louise Pitt</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Pramerica Investment Management Ltd.">James Hyde</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Today's conference call will be hosted by Bruce van Saun, CFO of RBS, and John Cummins, Group Treasurer of RBS. Please go ahead, Bruce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Good day, everyone, and welcome to our call. You should know we have a pre-recorded slide presentation covering our first half results available on our website. We also have the morning Q&amp;A session is also available for replay. So, I'll keep these opening comments brief. As you know, John Cummins, our Treasurer, is here with me. So, let me start off by looking at the numbers in a little more detail, and then we'll kick it over directly to Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>So, looking at the first half consolidated group financial highlights, our first half operating profit was broadly consistent with a year ago, adjusting for a couple of one-off items in Q2. While our income has shrunk, given our deleveraging strategies in challenging markets, we've seen progress on expenses, claims and impairments provide offsets. The group's Q2 impairment charge was broadly stable on the previous quarter. Core impairments fell nearly &#xA3;100 million, while Non-Core increased by a bit over &#xA3;100 million.</p>
          <p>The performance in Q2 ex the one-offs was about as expected. The sequential decline reflects seasonality in the Markets business.</p>
          <p>So called, below-the-line items increased in the half to &#xA3;3.3 billion, with &#xA3;3 billion of that being a charge for our own credit adjustment, as our credit spreads have tightened markedly since the year-end, as I'm sure you're aware. Carrying that through to the bottom line gives an attributable loss of around &#xA3;2 billion, although without the own credit item we had an attributable profit, in fact, of around &#xA3;300 million in the half.</p>
          <p>Our Core Tier 1 ratio improved to a robust 11.1% during the half, reflecting this profit, some employee share issuance and lower RWAs.</p>
          <p>John, how about the funding and liquidity picture?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bruce. We continued to prioritize the balance sheet strength, reinforcing our funding and liquidity metrics. The group's funded balance sheet declined by a further &#xA3;50 billion during the half, assets of &#xA3;929 billion are now down 24% from the peak. A key driver, this has been a good progress in Non-Core rundown, where the funded assets are now &#xA3;72 billion with a year-to-date decline of &#xA3;22 billion.</p>
          <p>We remain comfortable with our full year 2013 target of &#xA3;40 billion on our pipe that remains filled with many small transactions. Given where we are, we've revised our 2012 year-end funded asset target &#xA3;5 billion lower to &#xA3;60 billion to &#xA3;65 billion.</p>
          <p>In Q2 2012, the group's loan deposit ratio improved further to 104%, while the core loan deposit ratio is now 92%, reflecting an &#xA3;8 billion increase in customer deposits over the first half.</p>
          <p>We continue to manage down our short-term wholesale funding in the last quarter, down a further &#xA3;18 billion to &#xA3;62 billion. The liquidity buffer remains at a highly prudent level, given the Eurozone concerns, at &#xA3;156 billion or 2.5 times our short-term wholesale funding. However, we'll look to gradually bring this down over time, which will boost our net interest margin.</p>
          <p>The cash under buffer is now 115% to the short-term wholesale funding. And the pool of assets eligible at the banking discount window has been increased.</p>
          <p>Please note that the recent Moody's action has had a negligible impact on the group overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, John. On the capital front, as we indicated, the Core Tier 1 was 11.1%. Net of APS relief, our Core Tier 1 ratio is now 10.3% and that's up 50 basis points year-on-year. Our target is to maintain the group's Core Tier 1 ratio above 10% at the 2012 and 2013 year-ends, including the impacts of APS exit and various regulatory changes.</p>
          <p>Mitigation actions are in sharp focus in order to achieve that, including RWA reduction from our Non-Core rundown, our Markets business restructuring, using less balance sheet, and then also future attributable profit generation.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me give you a quick update on a few other key issues. First off, we're working with the FSA to secure agreement on the exit from APS and at this advanced stage in those discussions, we're optimistic. We've made good progress in separating Direct Line Group. The business is performing well. I think that's pretty much on track, assuming the markets are receptive in terms of the IPO.</p>
          <p>The one that's going to slip a bit is the branch sale to Santander. This is proving to be a bit more complex an undertaking than we initially had planned. We're taking great care to ensure a smooth transition for our customers. We're developing a new timetable, planning timetable and we'll update you soon, as soon as we know.</p>
          <p>The Aviation Capital transaction closed in the quarter. It delivered a gain of &#xA3;197 million. This will be the last really big deal from Non-Core. There's lots of smaller stuff from here.</p>
          <p>Both Markets and International Banking are executing their restructuring plans quite well. First half ROE was 14% for Markets and 9% for International Banking. However, we still remain cautious on the operating environment heading into the second half.</p>
          <p>Our last big migration out of the RBS N.V. into the RBS Plc was postponed until early September due to the technology incident, but, however, that remains on track.</p>
          <p>Our peripheral exposure continues to be manageable. We've reduced our net peripheral sovereign holdings to zero, while our lending portfolio, excluding Ireland, is now less than 2% of group loans and advances.</p>
          <p>We didn't take any accrual for potential LIBOR fines at this point. We continue to cooperate with various investigations and that'll unfold as those go further. Note that we do have a meaningful level of securities gains. Our unrealized position on some of our bonds has improved over the half, so we could realize some of those gains to offset any impacts and protect our capital targets.</p>
          <p>So, to wrap up, we continue to make steady and solid progress on our safety and soundness agenda. Our core businesses are showing a stable 10% ROE, although growth is challenging, given the current operating environment, and we're tracking well against the milestones that we set out for ourselves for 2012. With that, let's go right to Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bruce. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will take our first question from Lee Street from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello and good afternoon, and thank you very much for holding the call. I have three questions for you. Firstly, I hear what you're saying in terms of cost, you want to stay about 10% but, obviously, the FPC is continuing to ask the banks to increase capital levels. Based on your discussions with them, <mark type="ph" /> do you know if there's (7:28) any indications on where they actually expect you to get to and when they expect you to get there by? Secondly &#x2013; I don't know should we let's do them one by one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let's do them one by one, it's easier for me to remember them. So, on that one, I don't think there's explicit guidance from the FPC. And so, I think at this point, with lots of uncertainty in the environment and concerns about what's going on in the Eurozone, I think more is better is kind of the broad guidance that we have. But I don't think the FPC or the Bank of England are looking to push the banks to a very super equivalent level in terms of front-running the Basel timeframe. And I think we have a notion that 10% is a good level to be at. And so, that's why I say, at the year-ends, we want to be around that 10% in terms of what we're printing.</p>
          <p>The fully-loaded B3 has become the rage. People want to know kind of what's that number? We put that number out for the first time in the materials today that we're anticipating about a 9% to 9.5% level in December of 2013 on that basis. Although I'd have to say, for a group like us in transition, that's probably a less important figure because we have things that we're running down Non-Core. We have Direct Line Group, which we're going divest. There's a bunch of things in flight that make those &#x2013; that number. We have big DTAs. There's a bunch of things that will be transitional and will go away in the not-too-distant future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Secondly, and one for John, you mentioned that reducing liquid assets to boost the net interest margin, is there any reason you wouldn't also look to do some form of tender for senior unsecured securities? Obviously, and other banks do, and then obviously you have the same purpose and go hand-in-hand with reducing liquid assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, clearly, we've been running a very big liquidity portfolio given some of our concerns about the environment in the Eurozone. I think, initially, some of that was as a hedge against any Moody's impacts, which we said was rather negligible.</p>
          <p>So, we have cash in central banks. We have a big bond portfolio. We have opportunities to take that down and reduce some of our liabilities. In fact, with Non-Core running down and now restructuring the Markets balance sheet to make it smaller, we end up with more upwards pressure on the liquidity portfolio, as opposed to downwards. And so, we have an exercise to try to find expensive liabilities and drive those off the books. That could be a combination of deposits. It could be some term debt.</p>
          <p>You've seen, initially, we've run down short-term wholesale funding in the half. We went from &#x20AC;102 billion down to &#x20AC;62 billion. Some of that used to be term debt, so it was debt issued under the CGS program, which was expensive, which as it comes under less than a year, it moves into short-term wholesale funding. And so, some of the boost you're seeing to NIM is that we paid that off and we didn't replenish that.</p>
          <p>So, effectively, we're kind of working through that. We're trying to figure out what's the best use of our cash, where do we land the liq buffer kind of month by month, quarter by quarter, to try to have, in the end, the best net interest income impact, while sticking to our LDR glide path, et cetera. So, it's a bit of a linear program. But we're out to optimize that over the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That makes sense. That's very helpful. And finally, perhaps, a bit more of a broader question, you give very good disclosure in terms of your commercial real estate exposure. I'm just wondering if you can give us any indication somewhat of, perhaps, your leading indicators are telling you and how things are looking as we look out for the rest of the year, given we both &#x2013; you have some weakness in UK growth and obviously weakness in Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the commercial real estate picture you have to look market by market. And what we have, our biggest exposures are in the UK and we have a decent kind of London and Southeast element to that, which I think has been probably in better shape than the rest of the country. Having said that, we don't see huge land mines, as long as the economy stays about where it is and eventually starts to pick up. It's just the long-term glide path down in kind of getting the exposure we have to commercial real estate back to our risk appetite.</p>
          <p>When we look at what we have in Ireland, there it's a different story that's heavily impaired assets. We had a big development lending portfolio, probably 95% of that's impaired. We have those non-performers covered with 60% provision coverage, which we think is enough. But effectively, that portfolio goes into long-term workout and it's unclear how long that's going to take and whether there's going to be a need &#x2013; whether we get any money back from that level of provisioning or whether we have to add to it. I think it feels about right at this point.</p>
          <p>And then, our stuff in Western Europe, I think most of that's in Northern Europe and I think is in generally decent shape. So, I'd say it's a &#x2013; it feels okay, except for Ireland. But we'll see how it plays out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very helpful. Thank you very much for your answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Alan Bowe from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just have two questions. The first with relates to RBS N.V. and sort of how you're feeling about the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (13:43) you haven't transferred those over and you were going to have trouble doing that? And you mentioned in the earnings call this morning that it was &#x2013; the entity was just going to sort of run down. Are you thinking of just leaving those instruments in there? Or do you have another plan for them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll continue to look at both of those instruments and as we transfer the assets, we'll obviously look at managing that capital because we only have capital or liquidity but it's not something we're giving very clear guidance on right now, but it's obviously &#x2013; as the assets move across we want to make sure we have as much capital effectively used in the entities we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It makes sense. And so, the second question, unrelated, is more in regards to the <mark type="ph" /> plc (14:32) and how you're sort of thinking about that in terms of whether you think that senior debt will also be allowed to count towards the <mark type="ph" /> plc (14:39) or whether that would just be made up of own funds and subordinated debt? And if so, sort of how you plan to obviously get to the 17% ratio, assuming you're starting from what 14.6% now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Look, I think it's still &#x2013; some of the final rules on that are still to be written. And so, I think you'd like to see your total capital ratio over time potentially move closer to that 17%, although I think it's envisioned that the senior unsecured could comprehensively be incorporated into those <mark type="ph" /> plc (15:27) requirements. And so, we're waiting really for the final framework to be decided upon by the UK government on that. And also, I think there's been an increasing appetite to dovetail more with what is taking place with Basel. You saw that the leverage ratio had been proposed differently by the Vickers Commission and then the initial paper that came out about a month ago, aligned it more with Basel. So, there's still more to be written there, but I don't think we're, in effect, that far off if we're still building our capital a bit. I think we'll get close to that just on our total capital ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just an additional follow-up, I guess, on that would be with regards to the FSA's stance on your total capital. Obviously, you've carried out a debt-for-debt exchange earlier in the year. Do you think there's any &#x2013; well, how long do you think it's going to be before the FSA would let you reduce total capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think what we've done consistently is we've tried to look at what our layers are on top of Core Tier 1, both, first, for Tier 1 and then in terms of total capital and make sure that those have been in line with our peer group, and that kind of governed some of the three liability management exercises that we've taken over the past four years was to &#x2013; we certainly had a surplus of those kind of cushioning layers that we reduced and partly to increase our Core Tier 1 in the early going, not knowing for sure, what the Tier 1 and total capital was going to mean in the Basel world. We thought we should hedge ourselves and make sure that that &#x2013; those cushioning layers were roughly in line with peer groups, and I think that's still a safe place to be at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from Louise Pitt from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning, guys. First of all, thanks again for holding the call. It is really helpful to have it in U.S. time zone. So, thanks a lot for that. Second question is &#x2013; well, first question, I guess, is on the recent press speculation about full nationalization. Can you just comment on that a little bit, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. It caught people by surprise a bit because it seemed a bit &#x2013; one faction of the government had floated that out there, and why it hit the front page of the papers has surprised a lot of folks here. In the aftermath of that, I think there was a pretty resounding counter-thrust that a lot of analysts put out short notes saying why that was a pretty, pretty poor idea, and the government later came out and said that there was no serious debate on that topic. So, I think it's not a runner.</p>
          <p>I think what it does show, though, is that people are trying to look for avenues to increase lending in the UK. I think that's probably what's behind it. You've seen this first NLGS scheme to &#x2013; the HMT put out to try and increase lending and then the Bank of England with this Funding for Lending, and I think there's a faction of the government who consistently has thought, hey, if we own 82% of a bank, why don't we use that vehicle as an entity that can extend more credit into the economy to get the economy going?</p>
          <p>I think there's certainly a lot more efficient ways to bolster the supply of credit into the marketplace than nationalizing RBS, the Funding for Lending being one scheme. There could be other targeted programs at small businesses that need start-up capital that the government could back. And so, there's so many negatives in terms of what it would mean to nationalize RBS, it's probably not worth ticking through them all.</p>
          <p>So, I think at this point, our job is to simply focus on recovering the bank. We are available for business in terms of lending. We're actively participating in these government programs. We have the lowest rates right now on offer for SME loans and with fees waived. I think, in the end, you have to recognize that the inability to really &#x2013; to grow the loan book stems more from lack of loan demand and business confidence. And that's something that will take time to recover, just &#x2013; so we're out there trying, but until a small business person thinks that the economy has better prospects and the Eurozone's not going to implode, offering a little bit cheaper financing, it's &#x2013; while it helps, I think it's not going to make a huge difference in terms of that loan appetite.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks. I just have two other very quick questions. One is really for John with respect to the short-term wholesale funding book, how low do you think that that can conceivably get on the balance sheet right now? It's down to &#xA3;62 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't want to get too much lower, given that it is still very cost-effective funding. So, we would have to compare that to other as we're trying to push away more expensive term liabilities as well. So, we wouldn't expect it to get dramatically lower...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks. And then the final question is just on Irish asset quality. There is clearly going to be a change in the bankruptcy laws in Ireland. How do you think that could potentially affect the residential book that you have over there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question. I think that the bankruptcy period has been 12 years in Ireland, which is pretty much off the euro market. It was one of the terms of the Troika was that that be reduced more in line with other peer countries. I think the draft legislation has that at three years. In comparison, the UK here is one year.</p>
          <p>So, I think, in general, landing it there is probably a reasonable outcome overall, whether that creates any downside risk in terms of behavior to us remains to be seen. It think when it was first advanced, I think there may have been some people that thought that maybe this is an opportunity to see how this plays out because I think last quarter, as this was advancing, we saw some uptick in the book that looked like it was behavioral. It wasn't &#x2013; unemployment wasn't changing. Housing prices had started to stabilize a bit. But we still had delinquencies going up, so we couldn't tell if there was a behavioral aspect to that. But I think our people on the ground think that, if anything, it's a mild negative, but it won't have a very drastic impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from James Hyde from Pramerica. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I joined the call a bit late, so I must apologize in advance if any of these matters were covered. I've got two broad areas of questioning, one, to do with the APS exit versus the indication of substantial costs of LIBOR in one shape or another. And I noticed this wasn't really raised at the morning call. So, I'm wondering does the drift of whatever can be identified as a cost of LIBOR not in any way affect the exit from APS, given the initial at least capital hit that that would take? Do these matters at all affect the APS is my first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; James, let me go one at a time here...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'll just answer that, and then you can then carry on with your next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're really not related. So, the APS program was designed for RBS at the initial stages of the recovery, and it's served its purpose. As we've gone along our recovery journey, we've reduced the balance sheet dramatically, and the covered asset pool is down by more than half. And so, we're still paying a very significant premium for an asset plan that has a high threshold before you'd actually be able to claim. And we and the APA have both done plenty of stress testing and even reverse stress tested the scenarios where you'd be able to make a claim and get anything from this program, and it's almost inconceivable that that would happen. So, there's agreement on that.</p>
          <p>We had to pay a minimum of &#xA3;2.5 billion in the program, which was time pro-rated. We come to the end of that at the early part of October of this year. To stay in the program costs us &#xA3;500 million per annum for something that we get minimal benefit from. So, I think there's all parties look at that and they understand that. We still have to work it through the FSA. They have to look at our stress test and look at our capital position broadly. But I think they acknowledge that the APS provides little benefit at this point.</p>
          <p>The LIBOR, if there's any &#x2013; we didn't take any accrual for LIBOR at this point because the investigations aren't far enough along for us to reliably estimate what potential costs could be here. One thing that is paired to that though, we mentioned that we have, in that liquidity portfolio that we keep, we've seen our gains increase. We have a good position in gilts, in treasuries, in bonds, very safe assets that have safe haven status. And as the world has seemed more concerning, the value of those instruments has increased a lot.</p>
          <p>And so, we could realize some gains on that portfolio and use those to protect our capital position against any exceptionals, such as fines. So, our job here really is to make sure that we're managing our capital base, and we keep a strong capital ratio that we're able to absorb the regulatory up-drifts in RWAs that are coming from the CRD IV, the Basel changes here, and also be able to handle anything that's not in our original operating plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Second question is the old chestnut of the ring-fence. Now, the white paper seemed to be generally benign or less benign than it could have been, rather. But then, we have the Lord Turner Bloomberg speech in which one of the things that was quite &#x2013; he was quite insistent on was that he saw the SMEs as being in the ring-fence, which sort of &#x2013; I wonder if that changes your plans a bit? And that wasn't his personal view that was what he said this is the policymakers' view is that SMEs should be in the ring-fence. And so, does that really change any of your plans for the ring-fence, for the potential solutions? Or is there anything you can provide us more now than you have been able to &#x2013; a few months back on where our bonds are likely to end up, or the longer-dated bonds are like to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Look, I mean, that's all quite far out into the future. So, we're working closely with the government in supplying information and discussing some of the nuances of the legislation they want to craft. And obviously, we're running different scenarios and different models as to what do we think is optimal from businesses, go to a narrow ring-fence or go to a broader ring-fence. So, we have more flavors than a Good Humor truck in terms of the varieties that we're looking at of options.</p>
          <p>I do think, in the end, it's clear that the wholesale business, the Markets business will be outside the ring-fence. And some of the steps that we're taking here to shrink the balance sheet in our Markets business is in line with ultimately where the whole Vickers and ring-fencing is pushing the banks in order to minimize the impact. If you have a smaller investment bank, you'll have less overall cost and drag from that whole proposal.</p>
          <p>So, we're keeping an eye on things, but we really haven't determined exactly where to draw it. Part of that is game theory. We have to see what is Barclays going to do? What is HSBC going to do? Where are corporate deposits? Are they on the one side or the other side? And if someone does it a different way than you, can they use that competitively against you? So there's, I think, more to come. It's something that we're engaged on, but frankly it's a bit for down the road.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a follow-up question from the line of Lee Street. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Just a quick follow-up, just in terms of your answer you gave to the APS, if I sort of translate that logic over to the contingent capital line you have in the government, is there any scope or thought of possibly trying to actually give that back early to effectively reduce cost or something, which presumably you think that you'll never need? Has there even been any thought on that? And would that even be permitted? And is that line still needed from an FSA stress-testing perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, that's a good question. And there's been some speculation in the press over here that perhaps the FSA in letting us out of APS may look to have the terms altered on contingent capital because initially when we negotiated that package, the thought was the banks can operate with an 8% Core Tier 1 ratio and then 8% became 10%. But when you were 5% trigger against an 8% Core Tier 1, you were 300 basis points away, and that could be a reasonable stress scenario and you could use that contingent capital as a recovery action. Whereas now if you're up at 11%, where we are, you've got this trigger down at 5%, it's highly unlikely you'll ever use it. And if you do, it's more for bondholder protection, as opposed to a recovery action as you're going on the cusp of resolution.</p>
          <p>So, you could say, if you're the FSA, would it be nice to move it up? If you're us, you say there's two years left on it and it's just going to run out at the end of 2014, can we accelerate the demise or just leave it sit? I'm not going to color anymore on that. It's something that is kind of under review and it's being discussed. But I don't think it's as critical an issue right now as APS. APS is costing us money. There's a lot of compliance cost that goes with it. We clearly don't need it. You could say there's still some value to the contingent capital and so keeping it around in some form, I think, is probably more likely than not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That makes sense. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions at this time. I would now like to hand the call back to Bruce for any closing comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sure. Well, gee, thanks so much for dialing in today and, again, we feel it was a very solid quarter-and-a-half with good progress on our two principal tasks in making the &#x2013; first, making the bank safer and sounder; and second, driving a superior core operation that's sustainable and attractive for our future. And so, we ask &#x2013; we welcome your further questions, if you have any, into the team here and be sure to take advantage of all the information that we put out on our website.</p>
          <p>Thanks again, and good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that will conclude today's presentation. Thank you for your participation. You may now all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>