<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1434510" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call - Fixed Income</title>
    <date>2011-08-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7787</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Treasurer">John Cummins</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head of Debt Investor Relations">Emete Hassan</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Deputy Group Treasurer, Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc">Liam Coleman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Lee A. Street</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Robert Smalley</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="John Hancock Life Insurance Co.">Susan Simi</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Louise Pitt</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and good morning to those who've joined from North America. Welcome to RBS Second Quarter Earnings Call for our fixed income and debt investors. I'm going to provide a brief introduction to quarter results and then I'm going to turn you over to Liam Coleman, our Deputy Group Treasurer, Emete Hassan, our Head of Debt Investor Relations, who will take you through the results in more detail. We'll then offer a few concluding remarks before we open up the call for questions and answers. We've also provided slides on our Web site and we will use the slides to guide you through our presentation.</p>
          <p>So if you move to Slide 1 on business achievements, you see the obvious sort of solid performance in challenging market conditions. Our H1 group operating profit is up &#xA3;0.65 year-on-year to &#xA3;1.9 billion due to reduced non-core losses. The core retail and commercial businesses maintained a steady momentum with UK retail being the strongest contributor. Our non-core funded assets declined a further &#xA3;12 billion in Q2 and we are on track to hit our target of less than 10% of group funded assets by full year 2011. We continue to make very good progress with our funding and liquidity position. The group loan-to-deposit ratio has improved further to 114% while the core loan-to-deposit ratio remains at 96% below our 2013 target. We have a strong core Tier 1 ratio 11.1% and our RWAs are down &#xA3;9 billion in the quarter.</p>
          <p>We continue to work through the sins of the past as previously guided. We've taken a charge of &#xA3;850 million payment protection claims. Additionally, we've taken a prudent provision of &#xA3;733 million for our Greek government available for sale exposure.</p>
          <p>I will now hand over to Emete to go through the bank's performance in more detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John, and hi, everybody. We're on Slide 2 tracking well to planned targets. We're halfway through our five-year plan and as you can see we've made considerable progress against most of our risks and balance sheet metrics.</p>
          <p>As John stated earlier, our loan-to-deposit ratio continues to improve and is quite robust. Our liquidity portfolio is now greater than that of our short term wholesale funding which puts us in a very good position, especially in times like these in the markets. Capital remains strong at 11.1% and we believe that we are in a good position and well capitalized to meet any upcoming regulatory changes.</p>
          <p>The ROE in core was 12% and as we continue along our path to an ROE greater than our cost of capital, we feel that we will be able to meet targets that will be on or around the target price of currently 15%, although we are currently reviewing what these targets will be once we see the full assessment of regulatory changes going forward. Stephen Hester had mentioned this morning that that probably &#x2013; that revision would probably come to you by early next year.</p>
          <p>One area where we feel quite comfortable is our retail and commercial which made further progress in the second quarter from 11% to 12%. Some examples of de-risking are a leverage ratio below our target of 20 times at 17.8 and non-core assets are down 56% from when they started which was the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>On Slide 3, I'd like to look through the financial highlights for the second quarter. You can see that our core operating profit is up 6% and that's driven primarily from the retail and commercial division's continued strong performance and the reduction of impairments that are, however, somewhat offset by some higher costs. The group operating profit is over &#xA3;500 million year-on-year and stands at &#xA3;818 million. This is largely due to the lower non-core losses that we are having in that division. The balance sheet is largely right sized and we anticipate that it will stay around the &#xA3;1 trillion mark even after non-core rundown is completed.</p>
          <p>Turning to the net interest margin, the group NIM was of 6 bps on a headline basis but only 3 basis points adjusting for UK corporate one-time adjustment in Q1. Retail and commercials underlying NIM expanded slightly versus Q1, but it was up considerably, 11 basis points versus a year ago. Group's GBM's NIM declined. Margin effects achieved Q2 subdued money market income and furthermore GBM and non-core also bear the brunt of the cost of strengthening our liquidity and funding profile, which hurt the group NIM by about 2 basis points in the quarter. We've clearly moderated our expansion assumptions at this point given the persistence of low rates and the flattening of the yield curve.</p>
          <p>On Slide 5, we have some information for you on impairments in REILs. At the headline level, second quarter group impairments rose over &#xA3;300 million versus last quarter as current impairments declined modestly. However, non-core impairments increased by about &#xA3;350 million, but year-on-year they've still improved.</p>
          <p>The non-core entries really reflects the targeted provision on Irish land values in the Irish portfolio as well as a few single name corporate impairments. Note that recoveries on equity positions from workouts offset this increase, but our reported and other income rather than netted against impairments. So when we manage our budget for non-core, what we really are looking at is the overall loss and so that is taken into account when we look at the assessments across the board.</p>
          <p>Turning to provisions, our loan impairment provisions increased a further &#xA3;1.5 billion during Q2 to &#xA3;21 billion and this gives the group an REIL or nonperforming loans coverage of 49%. We continue to see a gently positive trend for impairments with Irish impairments declining in H2 for this year.</p>
          <p>On Slide 6, we continue to provide you with the same slide with updates for the quarter and you can see here that our non-core rundown continues to make excellent progress. The &#xA3;12 billion reduction in the quarter to &#xA3;113 billion reflects &#xA3;7 billion of disposals and about &#xA3;4 billion of runoff. At the end of the second quarter, we had pending transactions of &#xA3;2.5 billion as well as a fairly strong pipeline considering the environment. We believe we are on track to meet our &#xA3;96 billion year-end target, which will be less than 10% of the entire balance sheet.</p>
          <p>On Slide 7, we have some metrics for you on reducing risk. Our risk profile remains a key component in achieving a right sized de-risked balance sheet that will underpin future sustainable growth. Good progress continued in the first half and some of the highlights are noted on the slide. Our direct peripheral European sovereign exposure in the banking book beyond Greece is modest relative to our balance sheet and capital. And as John pointed out, we took a &#xA3;733 million impairment charge against the Greek available for sale bond portfolio. I'd like to note here that we have written our entire position to market values after deeming it impaired. If the current planned restructuring of the pre-2020 maturing Greek debt is approved in the second half, we stand to recover about &#xA3;275 million of this provision.</p>
          <p>Separate from direct sovereign exposure, as you'd be well aware, we have indirect Irish exposure through Ulster Bank. I'd like to take a moment here to provide an update on this exposure. The non-performing loans in the non-core portfolio continue to rise and the commercial real estate development non-performers now stand at 87% of loans. However, as we had guided, the coverage ratio has improved 10 percentage points to 56% in the quarter and this is in line with our peers.</p>
          <p>Provisioning levels in the Ulster core book have also strengthened with total coverage at 47%. We're intensively managing our impaired assets, but Ireland will continue to be a long term workout heavily dependent upon the path of the economy from here.</p>
          <p>Q2 Irish impairments across core and non-core were down 4% relative to Q1 and our view at this point is that the second half Irish impairments will fall, particularly in non-core.</p>
          <p>Turning to our sector concentrations which you can find in the middle of the slide, you can see that we have continued to reduce concentration risk across selective sectors. For example, the group's exposure to property has been reduced by 7% over the past 12 months with 3% in the first half.</p>
          <p>We have also continued to make headway with our single name concentrations, which are down 33% versus a year ago. Clearly, there is more work to do, but at the halfway stage of a five-year plan we can see tangible progress and we hope you do as well.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn it over to Liam to go over our funding liquidity and capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon to you all. Good morning to some. And thanks very much, Emete.</p>
          <p>Turning now through to Slide 8, deposits. We continue to make good progress with our funding and liquidity position. In H1, the group loan-to-deposit ratio improved 300 basis points to 114% and our core loan-to-deposit ratio remains below the target level at 96%. Our resilient franchises continues to support the stable customer deposit base. Deposits increased &#xA3;8 billion year-on-year to &#xA3;429 billion. We remain focused on bringing down the level of wholesale funding to actively term it out and continue without deposit growth initiatives. A notable example is our GTS division where deposits increased 17% to &#xA3;73 billion versus a year ago.</p>
          <p>If you turn to Slide 9. At June 30, the wholesale funding greater than one year was stable at 56% and the deposits represented 58% of our funding structure. This number compares favorably with our European and UK peers. As evidence of an improving funding profile, the funding GAAP is broadly halved year-on-year and was close to further &#xA3;5 billion in Q2, so &#xA3;61 billion. Additionally, our net stable funding ratio has improved to 97%.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Slide 10 &#x2013; funding issuance. The continued deleveraging of our balance sheet through the rundown of non-core reduces our market funding requirement going forward. We've revised our target to &#xA3;23 billion of term issuance in 2011, primarily reflecting a strong private placement pipeline and we've made good progress.</p>
          <p>In the first half we issued &#xA3;18 billon which is made up of &#xA3;8 billion private, &#xA3;5 billion secured and &#xA3;5 billion unsecured. Looking forward into H2 we have a relatively limited term funding requirement of &#xA3;5 billion remaining, an issuance there will primarily be private placements and in secured format.</p>
          <p>Turning to Slide 11. Issuance in half one was diversified across a specimen of markets, currencies and term structures. To date, we have issued five transactions for our UK regulations covered bond program and in half one, we issued two covered bonds in three and five-year maturities totaling &#x20AC;3 billion. In Q2, we issued an RMBS transaction in multiple currencies. Offsetting this issuance, we recently called Arran 1 and have announced our intention to call Arran 2, both RMBS transactions and the Arran 2 transaction will the call go through in September. A benchmarked secured and unsecured issuance is complemented by our strong private placement franchise which spans multiple currencies.</p>
          <p>Turning to Slide 12, strong liquidity reserves. We continue to exceed our long term liquidity portfolio target of &#xA3;150 billion. The group increased its liquid asset balances by &#xA3;4 billion during the quarter given unsettled market conditions. The increase was all in FSA eligible government securities which demonstrate our commitment to improve the composition of the portfolio towards high quality government bonds and cash.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Slide 13, gross risk-weighted assets were down &#xA3;9 billion due to a reduction in GBM market risk and the net impact of non-core de-risking. Our core Tier 1 ratio remains strong at 11.1% despite the &#xA3;1.6 billion of one-offs taken during the quarter. Up all three guidance remains unchanged. We will continue to deliver on the mitigation actions and develop further opportunities to optimize the outcome. And at this point in time, we believe the impact is manageable. Clearly, global regulatory issues remain largely unresolved, although we are continuing to gain clarities as quarters roll by.</p>
          <p>The ICB recommendations in September remain at key near term uncertainty and throughout this quarter we've worked with the Commission to raise thoughts and bring perspective. This culminated in our submission that was published in July. Until we gain full clarity on this issue, we cannot accurately assess how the impact to our capital funding, liquidity and cost base.</p>
          <p>We are, as with all banks, a function of the economies in which we operate. As such, we are dependent on continuing global economic growth with gradual rate rises and a sustained turnaround in Ireland. Growth remains subdued and persistent sovereign debt news flow continues to knock confidence.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn back to John who will wrap up with his final comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On looking at the conclusions on the last slide, we can see that in our core franchises we've had good retail and commercial performance. GBM is being disciplined in the weak market environment. The &#xA3;1.6 billion plan revenue figure is a very respectable performance given the environment and binding down the risk that we've done on a prudent and safety installments basis. We've had a very good bounce back from previous underperformers, Citizens and insurance and the lower losses in Ulster.</p>
          <p>On our non-core and risk trends, our non-core balance sheet of &#xA3;113 billion is down 56% from inception and ahead of plan. We've reduced our peripheral sovereign exposures. We took a very prudential view on our Greek exposure. The Ulster impairments appear to have stabilized. On the balance sheet as Liam has said we continue to have very good performance. The LDR continues to improve down 1% at 114%. The funding gap down a further &#xA3;5 billion in Q2. &#xA3;18 billion of term issuance in the first half in a good position to have a modest requirement for the second half as Liam has already mentioned and our provision balance up &#xA3;1.5 billion to &#xA3;20.8 billion gives lending coverage at 49%. Our capital position 11.1%. Core Tier 1 is very robust and we're well positioned to support the business plan and absorb regulatory capital increases.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll hand you over to ask questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We will take our first question from Lee Street from Morgan Stanley. Please ask your question now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello and good afternoon and thank you for hosting a Q2 fixed income investor call. I have two questions. Firstly, you're &#x2013; request on your funding plan for the year and have a &#xA3;155 billion of liquidity for portfolio. I'd just like to understand the extent to which RBS will be comfortable to run down the liquidity portfolio in the event the markets obviously are encouraging and difficult for an extended period of time?</p>
          <p>And my second question is previously RBS has stated that the baseline assumption would be the optional coupons on hybrid securities would be resumed post the EC restriction period. Could you firstly confirm that that is still the case? And secondly, if that were no longer to be case, what would it require for RBS to no longer be resuming paying those coupons after they expired at the bank? Should I be thinking about a specific level of profitability or ROE, for example? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for those questions. On the liquidity questions, I think Steven gave a good answer in the original analyst meeting where basically he confirmed that we will obviously use that liquidity, that's what it's there for. We continue to be monitoring very closely the activity in the money markets and we will obviously manage ourselves in a prudent manner. That's why we have increased our liquidity in this half and obviously we've improved our quality of the cash &#x2013; sorry, quality of the government bond holding. So to answer your question, yes. Obviously, we would use liquidity if required.</p>
          <p>On the point of optional coupons, I mean obviously we are subject to EU restrictions and we would obviously meet those restrictions. Obviously, then we'd be looking to all of these be equal to pay those coupons. If you look at that the quantum of the coupons overall compared to our interest coupons, it is a very modest amount. So I don't think it's worthwhile to give a specific ROE or number in terms of a dependency. We expect it to be about &#x2013; we stop paying those coupons, but obviously that is a future event. And so we'll just have to see when the coupons come off in 2012, but we fully intend to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Richard Thomas from Bank of America (18:19). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello everyone. Three questions if I may. Can you give us an update on RBS NV? And I know that there are plans afoot there, but I think the last release I read was probably a little bit vague about what the intentions. So can you give us some clarity on what will happen there and the timeframe? The second question that relates to funding as well. You talked about the &#xA3;5 billion of funding that you still have yet to do this year for this year, but what about prefunding 2012? What's been your historic policy with respect to prefunding the next year when you get into the third or the fourth quarter? And then finally, perhaps a more generic question. Obviously, there is a lot of regulatory &#x2013; well not so much change. There has been a lot of documents published. CRD 4 obviously just started recently. What's your kind of state-of-the-art thinking about regulatory capital, the existing stock of instruments? How it will fit together come mid-2012 when you're off coupon restrictions and can do other stuff with the securities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It goes through the points on August and the &#x2013; obviously we're working very hard on the project to transfer the assets and the liabilities and the business across to all the SPLC. We have made good progress with the plans. We continue to work that. We continue to be, we are on track without a high engagement with our regulators and as I've said we've seen these ratings actions are being taken obvious and they're comfortable that we are going to progress with that plan. So that is something which is ongoing and this is just the final combination of over the 3.5 years of ABN AMRO integration into the core markets business of GBM and GTS, for example.</p>
          <p>On the outlook for the rest of the year in prefunding. Obviously, last year we took a view that given the uncertainties in the euro peripheral zone, we have only prefunded this year. We have given guidance that we've done &#x2013; we guided &#xA3;23 billion, we've done &#xA3;18 billion, we've got &#xA3;5 billion to do. It would seem perverse to give guidance at &#xA3;23 billion and then in the afternoon say we're going to try and do more than that. So we're sticking to the &#xA3;23 billion and obviously that gives us &#xA3;5 billion. But don't forget as you look at going forward you can see that our requirement to repay some guaranteed paper and our maturities on a reducing scale and as we increase our deposit flows as well we'll continue to have a less demanding amount of term funding to do as the balance sheet continues to improve.</p>
          <p>On CRD 4, we're continuing to monitor developments we wish to. Our Core Tier 1 position is obviously very strong. We're continuing to model what those impacts would be on some of the Tier 2 instruments for example. And we also monitor developments in the CoCo market. Given the environment right now, it would be premature for us to give out guidance as to what we would do with some of our Tier 2 instruments and that's &#x2013; that is consistent with what we've said to investors and to analysts in all the previous meetings I've had with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only thing I did out there is as far as the guidance that we gave at the end of last year of circa &#xA3;100 billion of RWA uplift. We still feel with the initial look through of the CRD 4 that that number won't change, but anything more specific we're still trying through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Robert Smalley from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks very much. And thanks very much for having this call at a time that those of us from the U.S. can join as well. I think we all appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are aware you have bought a lot of our bond money. We have nothing else planned this afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we appreciate the time of the call. Three questions. One on the funding and some of it's been covered but you went up from 20 to 23 and you're saying that the private market seems to be much more accommodative to your issuance. Could you talk a little bit about the cost there and if you're doing anything structured or anything else that makes what you're doing there more attractive than what might be happening in the public market?</p>
          <p>And are you getting some feeling from the public market that investors might be full on your name for a while? That's my first question. Second one is Belgium exposure FSA. Asked for that the other day. Didn't see it on the slides. And the third is that at least in the U.S., we're starting to see a bid for banks &#x2013; bank subsidiaries and comp consolidation is heating up. We've seen non-U.S. bank selling subsidiaries. Same question you always get about Citizens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well the same question gets the same answer to that before. We have no desire to sell. It's core to us. It adds diverting mix. It is self funding. And as you can see from our results, it is improving profitability to top line growth reduction impairments, improvements in its customer service and it's improved its ROE from four to seven, which obviously has still some way to go, but it's obviously showing good, good signs of improvements.</p>
          <p>On the funding side, one of the legacies &#x2013; the positive legacies of ABN AMRO was the very important equity structured finance business we have that has continued to perform and that gives us another distribution arm. So we do private repos and we also do private structured depending on the collateral and then obviously we do private equity structured finance as well. That actually has got a pricing advantage. Those are all behavioralism issues in terms of having &#x2013; there is a constant flow of buybacks there as well compared to just a five-year bullet for example.</p>
          <p>On the public markets we are comfortable that we still got capacity in the market. Obviously, you only had the JPM deal last week. This is not a time to try and be too aggressive on the public term markets with such risk aversion and we're also getting very good &#x2013; continue to get very good feedback on our public secured covered bond program and ABS as well. So we'll be a mixture of both private MTNs, structured MTNs and obviously the secured funding. I mentioned covered bonds and ABS and that is one of the strengths of the whole funding drive by Liam has been to drive that diversity.</p>
          <p>On Belgium, we have government bonds of &#xA3;172 million and lending of &#xA3;2.4 billion and that is actually within the 180 pages which is going to be a great read for you over the weekend. But we are committed to being very transparent on all of these exposures and we have put that stuff out there so it was on the slide because obviously it's a small exposure. On page 149 &#x2013; to save you looking it all the way through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's a nice country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Susan Simi from John Hancock. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking my call. I have two questions. The first one if we're looking on page 2 of your dec. I'm just looking at the liquidity portfolio relative to short term wholesale funding and it's great that the liquidity portfolio of &#xA3;155 billion covers short term wholesale funding. I just wanted to make sure I understand the footnote in terms of excludes derivative collateral in the &#xA3;148 billion and that just basically means that you include some derivative liabilities in your short term wholesale funding...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What that means &#x2013; to give you the clear answer. What that means is obviously we have netting agreements with counterparties because obviously most of the derivatives market is obviously now collateralized. And in terms of accounting when they post collateral to us, that counts in the short term funding. So it's actually not what you'd call pure short term funding but it's characterized as short term funding. So we break it out and that is basically derivative collateral placed with us from other counterparties, professional counterparties. And the short term funding number &#x2013; this short term unsecured number and that's why in previous presentations, if you go back on the Web site, you'll see that number, and the worst point in this presentation shows &#xA3;297 billion.</p>
          <p>In the previous presentation, it was &#xA3;343 billion because that included derivative collateral at that time. So I think the point that was well made by <mark type="ph" /> Bruce (27:39) again in the analyst meeting this morning was that the worst point that he will be comparing the most recent events to 2008. The worst point we had just over &#xA3;350 billion of short-term funding defined less than one year and now we have &#x2013; the number as outlined there, &#xA3;163 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So it's just the &#xA3;140 for '08 is simply net of derivative collateral that you have, that other &#x2013; net of collateral that other counterparties have posted to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay and that collateral is good collateral?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's not stuff we wouldn't accept, so yeah it's good collateral. It's cash or it's stuff which is in agreement from both sides in terms of the CSA. And it's collateral we would &#x2013; and if the thing moves the other way, we have to post collateral to them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just in terms of if I could get an update &#x2013; any color you have in terms of the last few weeks and any &#x2013; in terms of the short term funding markets what you've seen. I'm sure they're tighter. But any type of interesting color that you could give me would be appreciated. And then my second question is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a third question actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's your third question, but we're not counting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I take a third question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can do as many as you want. This is your meeting, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's in terms of impairments in Ireland and I'm focused on the residential book in the core. And it seemed to have gotten better &#x2013; and I haven't gone through the whole &#x2013; your whole release obviously. So maybe this answer is in there. But it seems to have gotten better in the quarter and I know your CFO mentioned that the reason that it got better I think is due to somewhat of an anomaly in the first quarter where you recalibrated your models. So the impairment on the residential spiked up a little bit in 1Q.</p>
          <p>I'm just wondering if that is correct. And then secondly, just an update on the Irish consumer and you're seemingly somewhat stable to positive outlook for impairments going forward. I'm just wondering. I don't know a lot about the Ireland economy, so just any information on unemployment or home prices would be appreciated. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To give you the brief 60-second view of the world and I'd &#x2013; if you can email me afterwards, I can get you put on our distribution. I've done this for quite a few U.S. investors. Ireland economy, obviously unemployment is about 14%, house prices have already gone down about 55% from top to peak. There is actually still immigration. It's sort of reoccurred again. About 39,000 people went but most recent census number, Irish population actually had increased even though you'd seen some of that immigration. Quite a lot of those people were Eastern European workers going back to Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>The savings rate though had gone up to about 14% and GDP figures are actually quite &#x2013; in the context of the world economy &#x2013; were actually quite strong and muted but they're still positive and you've also seen quite good export gains which is as the Irish economy rebalances to more exports that actually this sector doing still quite well. We have the presentation on the Irish economy on the Web site, which we can direct you to and that gives you and which we will give you &#x2013; can send you that. And that's basically &#x2013; it gives you a huge amount more detail on the Irish economy. I'll let Emete over the Irish mortgages in a minute and to finish off with the color on the money market.</p>
          <p>Obviously, there's been the risk aversion now for the past few weeks and that's been driven obviously by some of the 2a-7 U.S. money market fund pulling back because either they've had about &#xA3;70 billion of redemptions or people wanting to move into the front end of the curve. You've obviously heard the news very recently of the color of Bank of New York Mellon potentially charging for above average amounts of deposit. A lot of funds are being latched with custodian banks. We would see that that sort of would be &#x2013; that could be recycled somewhere and obviously people have cut back on.</p>
          <p>And this is not a new phenomenon because a lot of the U.S. investors were actually scaling back the ones anyway structurally. But also scanning back their exposures to European and keeping them to very short ones. So I think the most recent data will be out today sometime in the U.S. which will give you a good indication of how much of the real exposure to European credits has gone. We obviously continue to work with clients and obviously there's been very muted term money markets. I think the positive sign obviously last week was a JPM 10-year deal, but we're not expecting in the dark days of August with this environment we have right now, there'll be much term issuance and that the money market funds will continue to keep everything quite short.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the mortgages, basically in the first quarter we have what was called a latent provision, which is a term over here that's pretty much general provisioning ahead. So we basically topped up our provisioning in the first quarter in anticipation of what we were seeing down the pike and therefore the coverage levels that we have now are suited for what we see going forward and we will see some NPLs kicking up a bit with the economy; however, very much well provisioned for and manageable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what's your coverage level now in the mortgage portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>38%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will get the Irish slides and if anyone else interested, we can have them &#x2013; if you email them, we will get them to you and give you the link to that. We've been quite keen to get this information out to investors. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> James Hyatt from Pramerica Investments (33:27). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes. I have three questions. First of all, beyond the CGS on Slide 10, what can you say about other non-private sector schemes, Central Bank's funding, et cetera? Secondly, on the issue of prefunding, I just wondered what is your view on the possibility of stepping up non-core disposals? I mean not all parts of the market frees up at once and what is the appetite to recognize losses if necessary but how about keep with the plan on the non-core? I note I am aware that one of the answers in the webcast in the morning was that you actually made a profit on disposals in Q2.</p>
          <p>And thirdly and I think Emete knows this one's coming, can you just &#x2013; this may be a silly point, but if you revealed &#x20AC;1.1 billion of fleet exposure with the EBA test and then &#x2013; and now it's &#xA3;1.4 billion that you provide against, does that mean that the GBM was actually increasing Greek exposure sometime in the first half? That's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so on your first question, if you're referring to any of the kind of legacy schemes, we don't really comment on the SLS or give numbers out. We are comfortable. We're on track. We will be out of SLS in this year. On CGS, people can see the maturity profile there. Obviously the &#x2013; you've had the ECB announc the LTRO last week &#x2013; announced they'll bring it in next week. So that's &#x2013; European Central Bank's taking action to assist peripheral banks. We don't give any numbers out on any of the legacy Central Bank supports, SLS for example. So that's where we are. We're very comfortable. It's a very modest amount. So is that question...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Non-core acceleration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The non-core acceleration. Obviously we &#x2013; again it would seem perverse from what we said this morning that we are getting down to &#xA3;96 billion. It will be a good place to be and also I think Bruce did mention that obviously part of it &#x2013; the non-core management has been to not necessarily destroy value. We are very comfortable where we are. So that's kind of the announced plan is what we're going to stick to of &#xA3;96 billon. That's the reason &#x2013; most I can say there. And on the Greek point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically on the Greek point what you have when the EBA stress test came out, which you have different tables with different measures. So you have exposure of default, which can include contingencies. You have some other commitments in there and some tables don't include the AFS bonds and some tables do. So maybe offline, <mark type="ph" /> James (36:42), I can go through that the whole piece with you if that's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But this Greek provision on this Greek amount, this is purely for maybe an Ambrose liquidity books legacy item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Louise Pitt from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. Good morning, guys, and thanks again for holding the call. This is really helpful. Most of my questions have been answered but the last one I just wanted to ask is more of a statement on the APS scheme. Can you just comment on what the view of exiting the APS scheme is and if it's been updated recently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We still plan to exit it in 2012 and we confirmed that this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So in addition &#x2013; basically the color is that we're going to work to a place where &#x2013; the FSA needs to get comfortable and we understand what they need to get comfortable on. And we will make sure that we do everything we can to get them comfortable so that we're out of the APS by November when the &#xA3;2.5 billion fee would amortize to, as we don't want to pay another penny for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very grateful for the fee and for this insurance, but it seemed silly to sort of carry on or try to extend it and so that's where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Letitia Guya from Perry Capital (38.05). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. This is actually <mark type="ph" /> Todd Westus (38:11). Would you mind just clarifying the decision to actually pay the coupons in April of 2012 and just what the process is, how involved the European Commission is? Is it purely RBS's decision or do you have to get approval again after April 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well we would have to &#x2013; the physical ban comes off in April 2012. Then any decisions to pay that which we would expect we would be looking to do would be decisions by GALCO and we would obviously confirm that we are &#x2013; we'd have to be able to see to make sure our regulator <mark type="ph" /> to say (38:50) is comfortable with this decision as well. And we have confirmed this repeatedly to people out here. We are in the business &#x2013; banks take coupons. We're in that business and that's what we'd like to do and we've been stop paying coupons on this and once the EU lifts the restriction in April, we will switch them back on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. There are no further questions at this time. I would now like to hand the call back to John for any closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much for taking the time to dial in. If you have any other follow-up questions, please get in touch through email as we are committed to being transparent with our investors. These are very interesting times. We want to be very open and transparent with you. And for those of you lucky enough to be on vacation, I hope you have a good one and... [Ends Abruptly]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>