<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1247371" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7787</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Philip Hampton, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Stephen Hester, Group Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Guy Whittaker, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="3">Sandy Chen</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jonathan Pierce</participant>
      <participant id="5">Robert Law</participant>
      <participant id="6">Leigh Goodwin</participant>
      <participant id="7">John Hourican</participant>
      <participant id="8">Simon Pilkington</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to RBS' Half-Year Results. Today's presentation will be somewhat fuller than usual. You will recall that in February Stephen Hester set out the initial conclusions of the strategic review which have been launched a couple of months earlier. Essentially that work has been refined and developed in these ensuing months both for the group as a whole and in detail for the constituent parts.</p>
          <p>So today you'll see the shape, size and direction for RBS over the next few years. You'll also, as Stephen indicated in February, see much more disclosure so that performance of the business can be measured and judged by shareholders, both government and private, as this business is put back into shape.</p>
          <p>Although you will have much more clarity today that is of course very different from certainty. Whilst some of the more extreme outcomes for banks generally and RBS in particular appear at least less talked about than they were a few months ago, major uncertainties do of course remain from things that frankly none of us have experienced before, such as the continuing massive activity of central banks in different parts of world notably the Bank of England yesterday, the asset protection scheme which remains in negotiation, and of course more importantly than perhaps anything the shape of the global downturn.</p>
          <p>I'll make one final point in my opening comments. There have been lots of distractions, the likelihood of which I frankly have never seen, to the management team here in recent times, both the management team and indeed all RBS employees. I think they have dealt with these extraordinarily well. We are clearly now moving into a next phase with a focused team with the last appointment &#x2013; last major appointment announced today.</p>
          <p>I think a very clear strategy which has been reinforced over the months and the whole business knuckling down for the long-term job of focusing on our customers. Through that we will reestablish the standalone strength for our shareholders. There is absolutely no doubt that this will be very tough and very challenging, but there is also no doubt that it will get done and Stephen's job today will be to explain to you exactly how.</p>
          <p>And just go on to the next slide. This is what today's program is. Stephen is going to go through the highlights and then perhaps most importantly today, the vision, strategy and performance targets, implementation being an absolutely critical challenge, the APS that you're all generally familiar with. And then challenges and market trends and then Guy of course will take you through what is actually a formidably complex set of half-year results with the core and non-core disclosures made for the first time.</p>
          <p>So with that over to Stephen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Philip. Thank you everyone also for coming. I sympathize with you, I don't apologize but I sympathize with you having to absorb all this information. I'm afraid it will even get more complicated when we actually have an Asset Protection Scheme to overlay, but I hope you will agree notwithstanding the time it's going to take you to wade through this. It will end up helping you and helping investors understand us look to the future and I think that is to the good, particularly for a company which needs to attract more investors as we encourage our government shareholder to sell them.</p>
          <p>And echoing if you like Philip's message the core message from today is that we are optimistic, we are positive for the future of RBS. We are confident and we are putting that confidence into hard targets that we will rebuild value and we will get out of risk and we will serve our customers, but we are also going to remind you in an inconvenient way that this is a marathon and not a sprint.</p>
          <p>So in terms of highlights, obviously, we've done quite a lot in the first half of this year starting clearly in January with the disclosure of RBS' true position which had our share price at 10p per share. Unfortunately, they weren't awarded to me at that price.</p>
          <p>We've obviously changed the Board of Management, comprehensively. Philip referred to our new Finance Director appointment today, which I'm thrilled with both in terms of the individual and to complete the team, but I also want to say as I did in the release that Guy Whittaker here who is with us for two more months has really done a phenomenal job over the last nine months in supporting me, absolutely through thick and thin in producing what I think is a formidable set of disclosures and financial actions.</p>
          <p>The plan we are going to talk about and Asset Protection Scheme and of course were it not for all of that stuff simply business as usual would have kept us pretty busy. And you'll see that the bottom line in terms of our financials is six billion of profits in the core bank, nine billion of losses in non-core because of the one-off liability management gains that sums to zero and underlying that strong income trends but matched by obviously high impairments and write-offs. We've made good progress on the balance sheet and Guy will of course go over those in more detail and I think that all the rest of it is self-evident.</p>
          <p>So let's just talk about the plan. Now clearly what we are announcing today actually is really reconfirmation of what we set out in February, but February was what I described at the time was back of a fag packet, not that I smoke, but back of a fag packet strategy, we've spent a massive amount of time making sure we're confident this is the right strategy. And then cascading it in literally thousands of sub-plans across our organization to make sure it actually adds up. Of course the world will not turn out like this, but it's the best job we can do for now.</p>
          <p>And I think you really need to see our strategy in these three parts. We have a risk and overreach problem, which is what brought us down and we will fix most of that through the wind down of non-core and that's a vital activity. We've got people focusing on doing it exclusively, we've made huge strides so far, but the difficult stuff lies ahead of us.</p>
          <p>Our second job in addition to getting out of our risk and overreach is to recreate shareholder value through customer focus in our remaining core businesses and that is in itself a massive restructuring job. Every single one of our businesses needs retooling, not because they are terrible today, but because they need to be better and the future will look different in some of these markets. And so that is if you like our vehicle for value creation. And then across the whole firm, we need to make RBS different. We need to make it culturally different. We need to make it strategically different. We obviously need to change the management. And of course then we have something like the Asset Protection Scheme which comes across. So these interlocking strengths are really the key to our strategy and what we are trying to do and why we think that it will be successful.</p>
          <p>The vision, of course like all visions, is a bunch of motherhood and apple pie in it, but it is carefully crafted with a lot of thought behind it in terms of what we have to do. We plan to stay a universal bank. We plan to be stable. We believe that these profitability targets are required to achieve that. We believe that the risk profile needs to be in this sort of category and there is a huge amount of extra data on that.</p>
          <p>We believe in blending. We obviously have more volatile businesses in the investment banking. They need to be anchored by a higher percentage of more stable businesses in commercial and retail. And every single one of our businesses is knit together in a thoughtful way, but not just in synergistic sort of cost and revenue terms but in terms of funding, usage funding, production, and so on. And we talked I think a little bit about the management hallmarks that we believe the new RBS needs to have.</p>
          <p>Now, normally I would consider it foolhardy to put out the targets that we are doing today and it probably is, but I think that such was, if you like, the erosion of confidence in RBS and such is going to be the complexity of our financials for a few years that we have to overcome natural reticence and give you a clear roadmap and also give our, if you like, public policy audiences a clear sense of accountability in terms of what we think we can accomplish.</p>
          <p>So, we first of all do that at the corporate level here. Remember our two jobs are get risk down, make us stable, safe and standalone, and get shareholder value up and so I divide our targets into these two categories. We take if you like the worst point in 2008 in our reporting cycle on the left, where we believe we can get in 2013. Of course, these are only targets, the world will work out differently. If we're lucky we'll achieve them both as to time and amount but that is all ahead of us in terms of experience.</p>
          <p>Now, I'm not going to go through these slides because they are mainly for you to read afterwards, but every single one of our ongoing core businesses, as I mentioned, has got a fundamental restructuring plan and we've set out here targets for if you like the three most visible financial return metrics for those businesses, the ROE, the cost income ratio and the loan to deposit ratio, both for three years and for five years time which I think will give you a huge amount of fun in reverse engineering what you think our financial forecasts are.</p>
          <p>Be careful with it because you may over interpret, but anyway I hope that will give you a sense, both of where we think things will be difficult for longer than you might have thought and where we think we can get the businesses. Again, I hope we can do better than this, but these are not either easy targets to do. And so I think as I say I'll leave you to read them as you go through the same for the other businesses in core.</p>
          <p>Now non-core can't be ignored. But of course our non-core targets are fundamentally different and that is to say non-core is something we have to get out of at as fast a pace as is consistent with shareholder value and with the other constraints that are around us. So I have no clue whether that will be what we are presenting here. But this is the best crack we can make at it. And you will see that, actually we made very good progress in the first half of this year. Some of that is flatted by foreign exchange movements but nevertheless we're on our way, the division is up and running. This is roughly the profile that we are aiming for if markets are favorable and if the government gives us the right permissions on the Asset Protection Scheme we might do better and vice versa.</p>
          <p>But importantly on the right hand side of the slide, we've shown you some of the moving parts. Again I'm sure it won't exactly work out like this. First of all, understand that this can get worst because in these there are a whole bunch of committed lines that could get drawn down to make our task harder and there are a whole bunch of people who have got loan maturities, who won't be able to make them where we're going to have to roll over those loans because just putting them into bankruptcy will waste everyone's time and lose value.</p>
          <p>And so the picture will get worst. And at the same time we'll try and make it better through asset sales run-off. And crucial to making this we believe will be the ability to accelerate the run down of those assets covered by the Asset Protection Scheme, probably through either sale of those assets or securitization if the scheme goes through its first loss and it becomes close to AAA now. We would need government approval for that. They haven't given it to us. I believe that they would in the future, but I can't tell you that they will. And so there's a risk factor in there. But I think it's just important for you to start understanding some of the pluses and minuses and ins and outs of this job as we go through it.</p>
          <p>Now across, as I mentioned, the third component core businesses, non-core is then cross-cutting disciplines and rationale for the Group. And you'll see here we could make this a very long essay but four of the most important. Each business we have must be attractive in its own right and I set out at the very beginning last October the tests that for me define that we repeat them here.</p>
          <p>Each of our businesses must have strong linkages across the Group. We must function as one bank and we must maximize synergies of all kinds. Each of our businesses, we believe in the core mix we've selected has complementary strengths. We think it would be a mistake to retreat solely back to the U.K. That would give us an absence of growth and an overconcentration one geography that we think would not be good for shareholder value. But of course the U.K. is a source of enormous strength for us, which we intend to robustly defend and improve. It &#x2013; we don't want every one of our businesses exposed to the same credit cycle and some of our businesses like GTS and the Insurance business give us some protection in that regard.</p>
          <p>Funding, one of the most crucial things that we all get out of the crisis in the last year is how do you fund a bank and how vulnerable is that. And again we have businesses like our Wealth business and our GTS business, that are big providers of funding to some other businesses that are big users of funding and then some like citizens in the U.S. that is well matched already. And certainly you can read the other sorts of issues on complementary.</p>
          <p>But I do want to be clear. By having businesses that are valuable in their own right, that exploit synergies and that are complementary, the Group should be more valuable than the individual businesses on their own. And that's what we believe will be the case once we have reestablished performance and creditability. But there will be no sacred cows. This is not a business mix that we are in anyway religiously or emotionally attached to, and if the world changes or different circumstances present themselves we will of course react rationally with an eye to stability in shareholder value.</p>
          <p>Next two slides basically say that we've done a lot in the last six months whether it be the strategy and plans, setting up the non-core division and beginning to run that down, you have seen this week the first of our Asian disposals successfully announced and congratulations to the team who have been working on that very, very complex activity. The Asset Protection Scheme I am going to talk about a little bit more in a second, so I will skate over that.</p>
          <p>Obviously risk management, a huge amount going on in that area; Nathan Bostock has joined us leading that and obviously some of the progress will take time as we actually get out of risk processes, but in terms of culture, in terms of new kinds of limits and in terms of the macro targets we have set out already a revolution which will bite progressively in the coming years.</p>
          <p>Expense reduction or efficiency remains crucial. The &#xA3;2.5 billion program that we announced is well underway, 600 million of that in the first half. And then human capital, we talked about renewal of management but this is, of course, a massive issue for us. We will not recover successfully if we don't have, attract and retain good people who are well motivated. There are also two reasons why that is difficult. Indeed our turnover &#x2013; the losses of our top performing people doubled in the first half versus the past and it is for exactly that reason that we are very clear we are going to pay our people competitively in a form that leaves the industry in terms of being responsible with deferrals and claw backs, but we must attract and retain good people. I believe we can. We have lost people, but it is damaging as opposed to destructive, and I think we can hold it there but that's of course ahead of us.</p>
          <p>Let me just update on the asset protection scheme. I won't again &#x2013; I won't really read through the slide because what we are really saying is that the essence of what was announced in February remains on track. We present today some refinements of the portfolio around the margin, five or less than 10 percentage has changed, but as we've refined it and there'll probably be a few more refinements in the next few weeks. We're still aiming for autumn in order to get it accomplished in terms of, if you like, some of your accounting issues, we were originally thinking we would amortize the costs over seven years. We probably think five years is more likely. The quicker that it stops distorting our P&amp;L and so on, the better.</p>
          <p>We have increased the estimate of the tax cost. Don't read too much into that because none of you will quite understand how we're moving profits around our internal group and do understand that part of that is that we &#x2013; is that the fees associated with APS and indeed the tax losses are not themselves tax deductible. And so that makes the number bigger than you might interpret. But of course who the hell knows anyway because we can't really predict our results with that fine accuracy.</p>
          <p>We have represented the updated pro forma impact on Core Tier One which assuming the 19.5 billion of B Shares and the scheme roughly in its current dimensions gets you just over 5% addition to Core Tier One which is pretty much the same as we've said at the end of the first quarter. That holds in reserve the 6 billion contingent B Shares, that it doesn't take account of that in that calculation.</p>
          <p>Now as I mentioned, we are aiming for autumn. There are basically three hurdles between us and bringing this over the line. The first is just finishing all the very complex technical stuff that we have to do, an example I give in the shareholder letter is that we have to provide regular reporting on 1 billion data points to the treasury, in relation to the scheme. What they're going to do with that billion? I don't know. But that's what we have to do and that's just taking time to get the systems to do it.</p>
          <p>We need to; the treasury needs to complete its evaluation of our assets, its due diligence which is nearly completed. I am sure we're headed for a bit of an argy-bargy around the margin on terms. I believe it will be around the margin. But I can't prove that we'll find out and so we'll see where we end up on that and then the EU is very important. The EU needs to approve the scheme. They have to look at two things. Basically, they have to look at viability, is our restructuring plan going to do the job. I believe it will, but we need to make sure that they're persuaded of that. And then secondly they look as if they want to take a crack at our domestic market shares as they have done in the other banks, Fortis and Commerzbank and so on. They are particularly focused on our small business market share. We are in the middle of discussions on that, so it's premature for me to know the results and there are some obvious issues around customers' disruption as well as our own disruption that we are trying to minimize.</p>
          <p>So that's basically where we are on asset protection scheme. My take is, although you know you must read all the caveats and so on and so forth, all sort of things go wrong, my take is that it will end up getting done in more or less the same economic power as you are all expecting, but there will be some stuff around the margins. I hope it remains around the margins, there's a risk it isn't but I think it's likely to be around the margins.</p>
          <p>So challenges and opportunities will &#x2013; if we just put five key things here. Implementation, we might do it well or badly, but it's a massive, massive thing that we are undertaking. Wholesale funding risks steadily reducing, actually fast reducing in some respects, but we will remain vulnerable to conditions in the wholesale markets until we get non-core properly wound down.</p>
          <p>Clearly the economic environment might go better than we are expecting. May be we are being &#x2013; may be we are caught in the trap of being too cautious. This is a self help plan. We are not relying on markets bailing us out quickly. So may be things will be better, faster but of course the converse could also be true.</p>
          <p>Non-core again could go better or worse than we think, but will be vital both in terms of balance sheet and if you like book value as we go through and its self-evident that the regulators and governments are going to be crucial to all banks as we go forward. This slide although slightly repetitious of a couple of things, tries to just kind of update on if you like leading indicators on some of the key risk factors.</p>
          <p>Loan losses, I am very nervous about saying anything about loan losses because I know how topical it is for people to be calling the turn or not calling the turn, and look the simple fact is the data set is not complete enough or long enough for any of us to really tell you with confidence, exactly where we are in the turn or even if we, whether or not we've turned what the trajectory of travel from that point is.</p>
          <p>What's clear is that the world has got big problems to overcome and if they are technically overcome quickly, there is a long tail of working through a hangover in any event, and so I just think it's important to have some balance in this process.</p>
          <p>And as a result, if impairments follow the pattern of past recessions, they are likely to stay high overall for two or three years. They may not follow the pattern of past recession, but if they do, look back to the early 90s before you get too carried away about how quickly they will come down even if they start coming down.</p>
          <p>However, all of that said, you will see graphs later on that the flow of bad debt into our recovery units is markedly slowing at the present. The leading economic indicators I don't need to talk to you about, you know what they are currently saying and so that there certainly are some reasons at least as Philip said to think that the stress test scenarios are becoming less likely where we are in the range of central scenarios, I'm not going to make a bold prediction on.</p>
          <p>Wholesale funding, getting materially better. Our reliance on central bank discount windows has halved in the last three and a half months. We've started unguaranteed term funding as have other banks.</p>
          <p>Our liquidity, if you like our day survival on liquidity has markedly gone up over the six months and so all of that's good. But we must still understand that these are fragile, abnormal markets. By reference to history, the funding &#x2013; the spread cost remain high which has obviously margin implications and clearly there are storm clouds out there, around Sovereign ratings in particular, which can impact all banks who are beneficiaries of Sovereign rating halo of one sort or another.</p>
          <p>Interest margins, well obviously what banks do as you know is sit in the middle of people with money versus people who need money and clearly there is a, what we've experienced as a major shift of power away from borrowers who benefited from oodles of money, over the last two decades in favor of people with money that shift of power is disguised by absolute interest rates and banks are sitting in the middle. And so, happily all banks are being able to increase asset margins at faster or slower rates depending on the nature of the product and the markets you are in. That's being offset. Currently more than offset by the combination of lower savings margins, although I think our quarter two run rate should be much more stable on that.</p>
          <p>Clearly there are hedges that run-off on free interest balances. I'm sure Guy will talk about these things, funding liquidity and so on and so forth. Guy will talk about the margins more so, I won't go on about it.</p>
          <p>And then finally regulatory, my view is it's going to be five years before we really know what the new regulatory regime is because every regulator is going to be very cautious about doing things without international consensus and that doesn't happen quickly. So, I think we all know the direction. It's going to be awhile before we really know the end point and we have to see.</p>
          <p>So just before handing over to Guy, I think some of this I said already, but my take on the numbers is firstly a positive and optimistic take. Everywhere in the world our custom franchises are intact. None of our major businesses have lost customers, which is pretty good considering the kicking that we were taking. I think the GBN rebound, even if it is volatile in terms of how it works through as all investment banks are. When you think of the restructuring that GBN has also taken on, is pretty creditable.</p>
          <p>Our Banking businesses of course are being hurt by recession, but we can already see the actions taking hold that will ultimately overcome those trends and the balance sheet and funding issues early days but big strides. But we can't wish away our risk vulnerabilities. They are there. Impairments will stay high for a while. I hope other write-downs, monolines and so on start moderating sharply, but I think you will be able to see very transparently our progress against those issues.</p>
          <p>So with that Guy, perhaps you could take us through the numbers. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Stephen and good morning to all of you. I'd like to take a few minutes now to run through the highlights, financial highlights, the risk highlights and the balance sheet, highlights of this morning's company announcement.</p>
          <p>Income grew 27% to &#xA3;14.8 billion, costs of &#xA3;8.7 billion, up 4% after claims pretty much flat year-over-year. We recorded a profit before impairment losses of &#xA3;4.2 billion, that's up threefold from this time a year ago. Impairment charges were up markedly to &#xA3;7.5 billion, that's five times the first half of 2008 and up 25% from the second half of 2008 resulting in an operating loss of &#xA3;3.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Recorded gains in the first half on extinguishment of own liabilities as well as disposals of the Bank of China stake and the new Director. In total we've raised &#xA3;4.2 billion. After deducting restructuring costs integration charges on the amortization of goodwill and intangibles we recorded a profit before tax of &#xA3;15 million and after paying preference shares, minority interest and a goodwill write-down of &#xA3;300 million related to assets in our non-core division. We recorded a &#xA3;1 billion attributable loss for our shareholders.</p>
          <p> Percent of income up 27% to 14.8 billion really driven in the first half very much by the growth in trading income within GBM, we saw declines in net interest income as funding and liquidity costs rose as well as deposit floors in the low interest rate environment pressuring liability margins. We saw a decline in non-interest income on lower fees, some losses on asset sales as well as in this case for comparative purposes, the absence of prior year gains, you recall the first half of 2008 we took a &#xA3;600 million gain on the sale of Angel Trains.</p>
          <p>Income did benefit from foreign exchange movements to the tune of &#xA3;600 billion, and in other items there's a mixture of big ups and downs recorded, as you recall, &#xA3;5.9 billion worth of write-downs in the first half of 2008. This year I am happy to say was &#xA3;4 billion better than that. But it was offset by adverse movements in CDS hedges and the fair value of own debt.</p>
          <p>On net interest margin, we saw a fall in group margin from 2.08 to 1.69%. The general themes across our businesses were wider. Front book asset margins not yet compensating for the deposit floors for the cost of term funding or for the increase in liquid assets that we're holding.</p>
          <p>GBM numbers rose on a strong money markets performance as well as some benefit from the internal allocation of some of their costs to other divisions. And you can see the non-core net interest margin falling quite markedly as it took up a significant share of the term funding consistent with the nature of the assets in that portfolio. The outlook we put out in the end of the first quarter was for 160 guidance for the full year, and we're sort of reiterating that guidance. We are reiterating that guidance this morning.</p>
          <p>On costs, we saw an increase of &#xA3;300 million to &#xA3;8.7 billion. At a constant FX basis, costs fell 5% or &#xA3;400 million. The cost reduction program of &#xA3;2.5 billion that was announced in the first quarter remains on track and we recorded &#xA3;600 million of benefits in the first half. Group head count is down around 8,400 since the beginning of the year, of which 6,400 relate directly to the cost reduction program. However, the cost of deposit insurance both here and in the United States cost us around &#xA3;200 million over the first half of last year.</p>
          <p>Our cost income ratio improved from 72% to 59%. On an adjusted base if you look at costs divided by income less insurance claims, it came down from 86 to 68%.</p>
          <p>On the credit portfolios, our loans and advances came down from &#xA3;700 million to &#xA3;610 billion, about half of that related to FX movements and around half through de-leveraging of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Non-performing loans rose &#xA3;12 billion in the first half and now stand at 30 billion or roughly 5% of our loans and advances. The impairment charge in the first half of the year was &#xA3;7.5 billion, up 25% from the second half of last year. &#xA3;700 million or so of that related to AFS securities we designated in the third quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Credit charge-off now standing at just over 2.2% of loans and advances. Our provision coverage at 44% was in line with the first quarter, but down around six percentage points from the 2008 year-end levels. And principally due to the higher proportion of our non-performing loans being in the corporate or secured areas, which have driven the increase.</p>
          <p>The bulk of the impairment charge was in non-core, &#xA3;5.3 billion with 2.2 against our core divisions. About 70% of these credit charges and the write-downs would be covered by the Asset Protection Scheme.</p>
          <p>In line with the strategic plan announced at the end of the full year results, we've undergone a major restructuring of the group in the second quarter to divide it into its new operating units. And for the first time in the 200 pages or so, you can see disclosed our new core and non-core divisions. They will show, if you recall from the first line, operating loss of &#xA3;3.3 billion. That really is made up of two parts, our core divisions which contributed a &#xA3;6.3 billion profit and our non-core division with a &#xA3;9.6 billion loss. And I would just like to take a few minutes to go through the highlights of each of those.</p>
          <p>Within the core divisions, income grew 25% to &#xA3;17.8 billion driven by a very strong trading performance in global banking and markets. Reduced margins in fees in retail commercial banking was more than offset by the strong trading performance. If you look down the table you will see central items year-over-year reflect the absence of prior-year gains on the fair value of own debt as well as some IFRS volatility recorded in the centre. We saw foreign exchange benefits to income of the tune of &#xA3;1.2 billion in the first half. On a constant FX basis, core businesses grew income by 16%.</p>
          <p>We have had a couple of couple of questions just on quarter-on-quarter sequencing of that particularly around movements in fair value of own debt. I will just highlight those for you. If you look into the numbers there, page three of appendix two in the announcement, we saw roughly &#xA3;1 billion swing in the fair value between the first quarter and the second quarter. A gain in the first quarter as credit spreads widened and a recovery &#x2013; to give back &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; in the second quarter as credit spreads narrowed. The impact of that on divisions, it added &#xA3;650 million to headline income in GBM in the first quarter and took 500 off in the second quarter and in the Group Centre, it added 350 million to first quarter income and took &#xA3;500 million off the second quarter numbers.</p>
          <p>Steven mentioned GBM performance and what we have tried to do here is give you a slide which illustrates the underlying performance of the business, and out of that we have removed the effect of those fair value adjustments as well as the impact of previously disclosed trading asset write-downs in the 2008 numbers. And you can see really a sort of run rate through 2008 in that sort of &#x2013; between 1.6 and &#xA3;2.3 billion, a very strong first quarter, strong second quarter and I think we're guiding to more normal expectations for the second half of the year. We'll leave you to deduce what those are from this illustration.</p>
          <p>Core impairments rose 18% versus the second half of 2008 and now charge-offs are running at 91 basis points of loans and advances in the core portfolio. We recorded &#xA3;143 million of AFS losses as well. The key drivers of growth here in the U.K. Retail, U.K. Corporate and Ulster portfolios, a function of rising unemployment on the personal unsecured portfolios and the cards portfolios as well as property-related exposure everywhere. The Asset Protection Scheme will cover roughly two-thirds or so of these losses.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding that, the core divisional franchises we think are in strong shape. Profit before impairments, I mentioned earlier, &#xA3;8.5 billion or four times the impairment charge in the first half of the year. Core operating profit of &#xA3;6.3 billion is up 33% to the headline level, 23% to constant FX. Big contributor, obviously, GBM; &#xA3;4.9 billion with contributions: half a billion from GTS, half a billion from our retail and commercial banking businesses around the world and 200 million from RBS Insurance.</p>
          <p>In the newly formed non-core division, we recorded a loss of &#xA3;9.6 billion, a combination of both negative income as well as a significant impairment charge. The negative income of &#xA3;3 billion principally a function of write-downs and provisions against monoline exposure, CDPCs and various elements of the credit and credit trading portfolios are no longer core to the group. We also saw losses recorded in this division on CDS hedges, principally from narrowing of spreads in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Again, just going back to, related to the first quarter numbers, we saw around 2.1 billion of losses recorded in GBM in the first quarter. Those numbers are now in the non-core division. There is an additional &#xA3;1.1 billion worth of write-downs excluding the CDS hedges recorded in this division in Q2, if you are trying to track old GBM to the new non-core division.</p>
          <p>The pro forma donating divisions are shown to be helpful. Clearly, with management now having moved, we would not be planning to continue reporting on the donating divisions on a going-forward basis. This is just to help you in managing the transition.</p>
          <p>Total impairments of &#xA3;5.3 billion are up 30% from the second half of 2008 including &#xA3;600 million of impairments on available for sale of securities. The biggest contributor is from the former GBM portfolios of &#xA3;3 billion. The biggest contributors to growth in impairments come from the UK from Ulster and from the United States, all again as I mentioned in property and property-related exposures. The Asset Protection Scheme covers around 75% of these impairment charges.</p>
          <p>We made good progress, however, in non-core. Running down the balance sheet, as Stephen mentioned, 325 billion to just over &#xA3;230 billion. Just over 40 billion of that was related to revaluation gains on derivatives coming down over the course of the period; about 50 billion was in third-party asset reductions; FX accounted for 14 of that, the balance on write-downs, run-offs, disposals, including the new Director and the Bank of China earlier this week as was mentioned. We saw a partial sale of our Asian businesses that is not included in these numbers.</p>
          <p>From a risk point of view, we saw credit migration in the first half of the year downwards, consistent with the economic cycle, average portfolio quality moving down from 3.9 to 4.5 on this one to ten scale that you have here. Within the core divisions, average credit quality at 4.2 distributed as shown. Around 15% of our credits are under heightened monitoring, predominantly within GBM and about half of those relate to corporate exposures, about half of those relating to financial institutions.</p>
          <p>In the non-core division, not surprisingly, a lower overall average quality at 5.3. Again the distribution is shown for you, and not surprisingly again, a higher proportion of those, 30%, under heightened monitoring of which about a quarter are financial institutions and three-quarters are corporate exposures. Over 10% of this portfolio is our non-performing loan book.</p>
          <p>We gave some disclosure at the full year around single name concentrations, which was deemed to be helpful during the first half of this year. We've revised and refined our approach, in many cases applying tighter limits depending on the individual credit grades of the underlying client exposures and we have restated 2008 results for you. On the same basis, what you will see is the volume of single name concentrations is about the same as we reported with the full-year results, but it does include a greater number of names that we will capture under the revised methodology.</p>
          <p>During the course of the first half, within that we did see a slight reduction both in the volume of outstanding exposure to these concentrations as well as the number of cases involved. We would expect to see continuing, but I think rather slow progress in this area over the coming months and years. And about 90% of the names here are also covered in the Asset Protection Scheme.</p>
          <p>In terms of outlook, we have seen a steady rise in impairments of case load and volume over the course of the last 12 months and reflected in the impairment charges, led by property and property-related sectors. There are signs, certainly in the flow of numbers of cases and volumes, of leveling in Q2. I think it is too early to draw any conclusions about the longer term outlook. We remain very cautious on the outlook for credit and expect impairments to remain at elevated levels in the near future.</p>
          <p>Of &#x2013; just sort of looking out in terms of core and non-core, perhaps looking versus H1 for a slightly higher number coming through in the core divisions as the impact of the real economy on unemployment filters through on the personal books in the UK and also the U.S., as well as continuing pressures in the corporate sector, but perhaps offset a little bit by some lower provisioning numbers in the non-core division on the greater sort of visibility and seasoning of the assets within those portfolios.</p>
          <p>And in terms of balance sheet, we have made I think very good progress during the first half of the year, coming down &#xA3;100 billion or so since the full-year results down importantly, 23% or over &#xA3;300 billion on a funded basis since the peak in 2007 and on the nominal basis including derivatives down over &#xA3;600 billion since &#x2013; in the last 18 months or so. Tier 1 leverage was at 22 times, that's down from 28-fold this time a year ago. If you like your ratios the other way, it is about a 4.3% Tier 1 leverage ratio. Good progress on tangible common equity to tangible assets, up 3% from 2.4 at the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>And on derivatives, quite a substantial drop with narrowing of spreads. Revaluation gains coming down from 980 billion to &#xA3;550 billion, and those assets and liabilities remain substantially balanced.</p>
          <p>On funding and liquidity, along with a reduction in balance sheet size, we saw good measures taken in the first half to strengthen both our funding and our liquidity position. Our loan to deposit ratios came down from 152 to 144%, allowing the funding gap to come down by over &#xA3;50 billion and now stands at 188. With the disposal of Asia announced, that would be around 178 as reported in the company announcement.</p>
          <p>Our wholesale funding with the remaining average life of over one year increased to 47% of outstanding from 45. And our stock have actually helped in that case by &#xA3;5 billion of non-guaranteed, non-government guaranteed, unsecured issuance in the second quarter. Our stock of Central Bank eligible liquid assets rose from &#xA3;90 billion to over &#xA3;120 billion at the half year.</p>
          <p>Headline, RWAs came down by a little over &#xA3;30 billion to stand at 547 billion. Assets in de-leveraging were largely offset by the impact of pro-cyclicality in the downturn reflected largely in our non-core and UK Retail and Corporate portfolios. We did benefit from favorable FX movements to the tune of &#xA3;30 billion which net-net account for the principal amount of the decrease.</p>
          <p>As a result of that, our capital ratios, our Core Tier 1 rose from 5.9 to 6.4% driven on the upside by the preference share conversion earlier this year in January, February time. Gains on redemption of owned liabilities offset by the attributable loss that I reported earlier offset by the loss of minority interests from our co-investors in the Bank of China as that stake was sold down as well as deductions which knocked around 20 basis points off that number. 6.4% Core Tier 1 as at June 30, Tier 1 ratio at 9% and as Stephen mentioned earlier, subject to Her Majesty's Treasury, the European Union and &#xA3;19.5 billion worth of B Shares, we would expect to see an APS benefit in excess of 5% to that. And with that and a few closing remarks before questions, I will hand it back to Stephen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Guy. Well, I guess we set out what we're planning to do. And now fundamentally we have to get on and do it. So I think the agenda facing us, of course, is bringing APS across the line, but then it's basically implementing the plan and serving our customers and dealing with events. And I am sure there will be events to deal with.</p>
          <p>As I said at the very beginning, we are confident that at the end of this marathon, we will have rebuilt RBS to both standalone strength and value.</p>
          <p>Very pleased to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously it is usually &#x2013; if you could sort of, hand up and state name and institution for those of us who don't know. Over there. Philip, do you want to &#x2013; I'm so sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't worry, don't worry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian Teneman from HSBC. I just wondered if you would provide some more guidance on the nine to 11 billion of deferred tax payment associated with the APS scheme because at first sight, it seemed to be suggesting that you were giving us an implied profit forecast for a loss of about 20 billion and I wanted to get your confirmation that isn't the case.</p>
          <p>&lt;A &#x2013; Stephen Hester I think you should see it more as part of our discussions with government and the outside world where we want to demonstrate that APS is not a free lunch, that the taxpayer in our view is unlikely to lose out. And I think that's the main context in which you should see it. Of course, we don't know what the future will bring. As I mentioned earlier on, you also have no ability of knowing where we are going to put losses in our Group, as it were, and where they are going to occur. Although clearly most of them will occur, if you think of where our non-core assets are, the vast majority are in, if you like, the U.K. entities including all the GBM assets and so on. And then finally the amortization of all of the fees and costs of APS is not planned to be tax deductible. Now all of these are subject to change but I suppose I would mainly just say don't overanalyze it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Goldman Sachs. Just a quick question maybe to you, Stephen, about how you see GBM in your 2013 vision. I guess you gave us ROE and cost income targets, but it doesn't give us any idea of the size. You are probably top ten in the world if we sort of look at investment banking revenues year-to-date. Is that where you see it in 2013 as well, or is it a much smaller part of your Group as you allude to? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you for asking the question. I suppose I never want either to have as our goal or to be measured in sort of where we are in a revenue league table or even a size league table. To me, what's important is our competitive strength in the markets in which we compete. And so not just with respect to GBM but with respect to everywhere, you wouldn't have seen a single reference to a size ambition. What our ambition, though, is to be top tier in the markets we compete in.</p>
          <p>And therefore it is a matter of complete indifference to me what size GBM is compared to other people's investment banks. It is a matter of great interest to us as to whether we are top tier in those segments of the investment banking market in which we compete. And the answer to that is in the vast majority, yes, and it will get better but we are of course not competing in M&amp;A and U.S. equities, and so on and so forth as we go through.</p>
          <p>Now at a rough guess, and it's very rough because it depends on all sort of things, I would have thought that GBM is unlikely to be much more than a third of our Group in steady state. And I feel that that sort of two-thirds and one-third balance is roughly desirable given the volatility that investment banking presents given the, if you like, the funding issues that it presents, but on the other hand given the growth and opportunities sophistication, profitability benefits that it brings. So I think that we are going to be able to be very proud of our investment bank, but in the same way as every other part of our Group, we are competing in markets we select and we are not competing based on gross size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Sandy Chen from Panmure Gordon. Just two questions if I may. The first is just a question on the impairment guidance. I know it is difficult to forecast, but looking at the Q2-on-Q1 progression, overall the impairment charge looks like it more than doubled from about 1.3 to 3% for the Group and impaired loans obviously went up as well on a Q2-on-Q1 progression. I mean, should we take Q2 more as our indicator or the trend line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what I said in the outlook, again one would expect quarter-on-quarter volatility. There was some, given the pace of build up, there was some incremental reserving against sort of emerging losses that was taken in Q2. So perhaps you saw an acceleration there which I wouldn't interpret as being reflective if you multiply it by four.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, I think we are making no calls on it being the top, so I think when we said the outlook is for signs of leveling in Q2 but remaining at elevated levels. We would think maybe a sort of half-over-half comparators are a better indicator rather than quarter-to-quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. And then the next question that I had is a more broader question. I was just really looking at the de-risking versus the ROE targets in long term. You talked about bringing the wholesale funding reliance down by about 200 billion, lowering the customer loan deposit ratio from 144% to below, well, say, targeting 100%. I mean that seems to imply a significant degree of balance sheet shrinkage and would that put pressure on the "R" in the ROE target in the long term or how do you want to kind of bridge that gap?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The primary vehicle for balance sheet shrinkage is non-core. So that's roughly the amount &#x2013; in fact, we've got 200 billion of non-core left. So that tells you, that is your 200 billion of wholesale funding when we do that. So what that's telling you is that we believe in our core businesses. We can run pretty flat on balance sheet for a few years which will be balance sheet going up in some areas like fulfilling our U.K. lending commitments, but we think that there are some efficiencies, still more efficiencies we can get in other areas, particularly GBM on balance sheet as we work through in a sort of more careful way where we are deploying our capital.</p>
          <p>So, I don't believe that we will be constraining the core businesses inappropriately as it relates to balance sheet and the concentration will be on fixing the balance sheet through non-core coming out. All of that said, the world needs to get used to safer banks and safer banks means higher asset margins than was once the case, although probably not higher than is now coming in on the front book. And I think the good news is that indeed, those asset margins are being accomplished. They will take a number of years to work through and then the liability margins will probably never get back to where they once were. But an element of them will recover as interest rates rise once the cycle allows that.</p>
          <p>Now in the loan-to-deposit ratio, if you like, one component is the loans coming down through non-core, but the other thing is deposits coming up. Now we, in common I think with many banks, had a business where &#x2013; I'll exaggerate, unfairly so, but to make the point &#x2013; where balance sheet was free, funding was easy and therefore you only did deposits if you made a lot of money out of them.</p>
          <p>And we're moving into a different world where deposits we of course do want to make money out of, but where they are a fundamental component of the safety of our bank. And so every one of our businesses is approaching deposit gathering with a completely different sense of urgency and focus. And I believe that the other bit of this, it making us safer, is having a stronger deposit franchise. Unlike some banks, we are very well placed here. When you think of our franchises, our franchises in the U.K. and the U.S., our GTS and Wealth franchises, I think we have the ability to be strong deposit competitors on business quality, not just punting the marginal price. And indeed, the progress we have made in the first half was on that basis. But that's something that everyone had better get used to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We stay in the same row.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. It's Jonathan Pierce from Credit Suisse. I've got a couple of questions. The first is back on this deferred tax asset issue. Putting aside the fact you obviously have to give up your U.K. deferred tax asset, is it your understanding that the APS fee would not also have been tax deductible anyway? Or is it specific to you that you are not getting tax relief on the APS fee?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was our understanding from...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From the get go, but I am not sure what others have done. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was one other thing. There was a nice little sting in the tail sprung on us, the deferred tax asset of 4.8 billion. We've also been told that as a price of APS, we can't carry back taxes to 2007, which means our starting point is 500 million worse than we thought, 5.3 billion that we give up before we get into the future which was not the agreement in February but is &#x2013; we are being told what is required now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No, see, so that's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The fee is discharged directly to issuance. It would be unusual if that was tax deductible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Steven's point there actually comes on to my subsidiary question within deferred tax. Can you tell us what the deferred tax gave up was as of June, so we can work up to your 9 to 11 in terms of future deferred tax give ups?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We recorded, we actually had a tax credit of around &#xA3;400 million for the first half of the year on the basis that the operating losses, net of, well, the gains were tax free and the operating losses were still deemed tax recoverable. So we took a credit of &#xA3;400 million in the first half on the tax line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. The second question is on the wholesale funding profile. Clearly you're going to have a lot less of it anyway in a few years time. At the moment I think you showed a 47% of the non-bank wholesale funding as one year plus. Would you expect that number to go up or down from here in the process of reaching a normalized balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would expect that to go up, to a slow steady progression.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The percentages to go up and the absolute number down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The percentage to go up and probably absolute number to come down as the non-core business runs off over the next three to five years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our broad ambition is to maturity match subject to treating a bunch of our core deposits as longer term than they technically are, if I can put it that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert Law of Nomura. Two questions please, firstly, could you quantify what the total amount of state backed funding is at present and how it's moved over the half year? I'm aggregating out all the various components to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not allowed to disclose. The central banks and governments get very nervous about disclosing those things. So I don't think we're allowed to give you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's why I'm asking for the total as opposed to in the individual lines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yeah, there was a total at one stage in our release. And then we were told to take it out. But we might be able to give a component of it. I think we can probably give the government guaranteed funding, the term funding, can't we? What was that, 20 -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Government guarantee 27, 23?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>23, 23 billion currently outstanding under the government guarantee programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And secondly unrelated, can you give us some view of how the non-APS impaired assets have moved over the period and where they now stand? So I am looking at your impaired assets on page 107. So how much of that is covered by APS and how much is not? And some view as to how it's moved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, unfortunately, we haven't given detailed disclosures on where APS was at the half year and let's tell you the truth, that's just simply because our finance teams were so completely flat out doing core, non-core, quarterly, blah, blah, blah, that we just didn't have time to get comfortable enough with the data to disclosure levels. So there is no really weird trends. But I'm afraid we just didn't produce it. We will in the future. We just didn't get there over the line, I am afraid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. It's Leigh Goodwin from Fox-Pitt Kelton. Couple of questions please? My first one is on to GBM revenues. And then I have a second question afterwards. My first question is, it seems to me, your guidance, if I'm hearing you, is for a much weaker second half after the first half. I think you're telling us that we shouldn't expect impairments to necessarily be higher based on what you showed this morning. In other words, it's down to revenues. I think you are saying it's down to the core revenues, i.e., flow business revenues and not just due to additional write-downs that are coming through. So first of all, I just want to check that I have understood that correctly? And secondly, why are your core revenue flow businesses do you think weakening in a way that perhaps we are not seeing with some of your peers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think dealing with the first one, you've picked up the general mood. And typically in GBM if you look at the pattern of 2008 on an underlying basis the second half with sort of July, August as well as December tends to be less revenue generating than the first half.</p>
          <p>And so you have to draw your own conclusions on the guidance. But we were trying to strip out the one-offs and give you a sense of what the underlying run rate was. Clearly, it's a business incentive to maximize the opportunities that are there. But I think we would say it was unrealistic to build expectations on what was an extremely strong first quarter and a strong second quarter, and saying that's what we would expect the second half to look like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On comparative performance, this of course is somewhat difficult because everyone gives different levels of disclosure. But as far as we can tell like-for-like business mix across the first half, we were pretty normal for investment banks, which is to say we materially outperformed the pack in the first quarter. We may have slightly underperformed in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>But you have to also understand business mix is important because we are obviously very dominated by fixed income revenues and those with bigger equity revenues. And then there are some people who report their GTS type businesses in the investment bank. And then there are all sorts of swings on fair value of own debt and other things like that that have gone in different directions than us.</p>
          <p>So I think if you work hard as we have done, you find that the competitor differences are not that meaningful. And I would not particularly expect them to be like-for-like business mix going forward. But of course, none of us really know what the next two quarters will be, so each quarter we'll see how we do.</p>
          <p>It would be pretty spectacular if we keep up given the amount of disruption that GBM has had. We've had, we have an ongoing massive restructuring program at GBM. But so far they have been doing a great job.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe if I can just -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the impairment number, we've I guess given all the caveats and uncertainties and difficulties of forecasting it and the potential volatility, but the indication of leveling would, as I said to Sandy's question earlier, half-over-half comparison with 7.5 in the first half, you can draw your own conclusions. Consensus numbers are somewhere between 12 and 17 billion centered around the 15. So I guess you've picked up that one correctly as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Maybe if I could just press you a little bit further on the revenue side, just on these flow businesses. I mean we are expecting maybe slower volumes, seasonal factors and so on in second half. But have you seen much movement in spreads and could you give us some quantification of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, do you want to? This is John Hourican who runs GBM. Do you want to sort of have a crack at it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have absolutely seen spreads contract quarter two on quarter one and if you look at all the various bases that drive the spreads across the flow businesses they have contracted materially Q2-on-Q1. And our planning assumptions is that as the market normalizes, the ex &#x2013; the very high spreads that we saw through the foreign exchange rates businesses in the first quarter, and actually sort of contracting in through the second quarter will not repeat to create the environment in the fixed income space. That would leave revenues at those super normal levels.</p>
          <p>It is also the case that Stephen uttered. I'd sort of reemphasize his point. If you look at our GBM business, we are less levered to the equity and M&amp;A space than some of our competitors. So we are fundamentally &#x2013; you need to look at the fixed income components of our competitors to make a proper comparison. But spreads have tightened. And we are presuming that those spreads will remain tight depending on the economic environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very helpful. Thank you very much. Just and my second question was, I just wanted to follow-up these comments about the EU investigation. I know this is very difficult. But you've sort of thrown this one in today that we may be looking at a break-up essentially of your SME business, very core part of your business and presume there could be some shareholder value implications from that. I mean could you give us any more guidance on how you think that might pan out from a shareholder value perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, of course we do present for you the profitability of our UK Corporate businesses in the pack. The larger amount of that is large corporate business. So only a relatively small amount of that is the SME business. And in balance sheet terms, the SME business is not either a big &#x2013; is not a big balance sheet consumer, comparatively speaking.</p>
          <p>So I think that the issues around it are more likely to be business disruption, customer disruption. And while I think that there will be a negative shareholder effect if the EU continue in what they are asking, I think that that will be smaller than the negative customer effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more? They've obviously all ganged up in the middle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Simon Pilkington from Cazenove. Two things really; first off, on the outlook for net interest margin, I see in the first half your net interest margin came in lower. But it's primarily GBM that drove that. And in fact if we look Q2 and Q1 your retail and commercial banking business has all showed an improvement. Should I expect a similar trend through the second half and also then any sort of thoughts as you go into 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've tried to put a few a little helpful arrows on the slide, which is sort of indicative of where we thought.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Put it different, why don't you expect the Q2-Q1 trend to carry through for the retail banks? What was peculiar that gave you that step up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The U.K. Retail was sort of about steady over the course of 2008. If you look at 2008, it actually went up in the second half and then came down second half to '08 versus first half of '09. U.K. Corporate you can still see tightening margins there, similarly in retail and commercial businesses, Ulster slightly anonymous almost went up, although as the funding mix changes there we'd expect that to trend back down again.</p>
          <p>GBM money markets of course we saw an extraordinary move in rates, which I don't think we would expect to see repeated given where rates have now got to and similarly turning out Non-Core funding.</p>
          <p>And against that, you've got this sort of constant drip to think about which if you look at the non-interest earnings liabilities and the fact that they typically invested out over, say, a rolling five-year program, as they drop off, even if they were put on few years ago and yielding 5.5 plus percent, now would be going on at somewhere 3.5 to 4%. That drips in over time as well as maturing long-term liabilities, which were issued when spreads were 25 basis points and are now being replenished at 200 basis points or so. So there is a sort of constant chipping away, reflecting the current environment that we are in and so we felt it appropriate to reiterate the guidance with a degree of caution.</p>
          <p>Now businesses are taking every opportunity to push out front book margins and over time that will play through, but I think we stick with this guidance for now and probably still pressures into 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean I think it would fair to say that we probably are, feel that we've done a bit better than we first expected on asset margins generally, some of which are immediately apparent and some of which will take time to work through. But certainly, I think you should always ignore GBM when you're doing NIM, frankly for any bank because you get just enormous noise from the particular way that money markets are behaving. But if you look at the commercial banking businesses, the liability side, as Guy said, interest rates didn't really trough until well into the first quarter, so the second quarter is a more normalized rate for deposit margins but free interest balances are winding down. So particularly our GTS business, which has a lot of free interest balances because it's if you like money that's moving around the world, will suffer from hedges running off over a number of years. As Guy mentioned, the term funding peak costs is probably next year before the absolute balances start going down.</p>
          <p>So there're all of these different things going on. On the asset side, our mortgage book re-priced almost immediately in U.K. because we have few trackers; in Ireland, it's all trackers, so it doesn't re-price at all. So that's why you really have to get in the weeds and why hopefully we're being helpful in giving you divisional breakdowns of all of these things so you can follow them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just one second question, more broadly on your outlook. You are clearly cautious. I wonder if you could just share with us what your central GDP scenario is for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that our outlook is based off forecasts that would have been consensus about two months ago. And if you believe the stock market in the newspapers today, maybe there is some upside, as I said earlier on, at the beginning, it's our I think responsibility to plan on a conservative basis and if there's upside to be got then, we'll see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you just move it along?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good morning. Altonio Frias from Evolution. A couple of questions on the APS and then one more on risk-weighted assets growth. On the APS, I think you said that the impairment seen in the Core division in H1 would be around two-thirds covered by the APS and the impairments seen in the Non-Core divisions would be covered by around 75% by the APS. And if I run that quick number, that means around five billion of impairments covered in H1 by the APS. If we kind of assume and this is obviously a big assumption that impairments are going to stay more or less in this cruising speed for the next three halves or whatever, you would get to the end of 2010 without having seen any substantial impact on your P&amp;L because of the APS. You would consume your fresh loss between 2009 and 2010, is that a fair interpretation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Missing the write-downs component as well. So if we look at impairments in the first half of sort of 7.5 billion or so write-downs of three, something of that order of magnitude. And we make comments around 70% of that being covered...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>70% of the total....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>70% of that total then that gets you to a 7 and 7.5 sort of &#x2013; 7 to 8 range would be a better estimate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you would already expect to see some positive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly, we are not going to make any predictions about how fast the first loss is going to be used up. A, because of the uncertainty in the economic outlook; B, because APS is not yet finally agreed. And it's a very political number to speculate on. But I understand your analysis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then continuing with that one. If we think that by 2011, it's very likely that you will see a substantial support from the APS in your P&amp;L, why is it that your ROEs are or your ROE guidance for U.K. Retail and U.K. Corporate seems so low? Because 1% &#x2013; I mean, I know you say more than one and more than five, but it's still, it's very low numbers. Is it because the Core part of your business, what is not passed to the APS you also expect kind of sustained worse than cycle average?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer that. In Retail, actually well in both. In all of our Core businesses new loans by and large are not covered by APS. There may be a small amount of rollovers, you know, that are dealt with but, and clearly there are, there is quite a lot of turnover of loans and particularly the higher loan loss loans, your unsecured lending, credit cards and so on and so forth. So in the Core businesses the coverage levels will start going down as new loans are written.</p>
          <p>So that's one answer in terms of why you might, your impairment counts might be out in later years. We also think that there are continuing headwinds. If we take the Retail business, we think the deposit competition as I've mentioned will stay intense as the market rebounds, whereas most of the asset re-pricing has already happened in Retail land and it happens very quickly so it doesn't flow through over time and so we have a very major restructuring to do.</p>
          <p>There are also some headwinds that we are expecting on certain fee lines, the PPI product has gone away and no doubt there will be changes in the overdraft charging structure, which we can all see ahead of us. So by the way this isn't that different, frankly, than our Retail business in the U.S. Retail businesses as we have said and Mike Gogan said as well, has a big restructuring ahead to retool for a future banking market. So we'll get there, but as you see at the moment we are saying we are going to get there in five years as opposed to in three. Might that be cautious? We'll see.</p>
          <p>On the Corporate book, you've got some of the same, but on the Corporate book the asset re-pricing takes longer to come through because the assets are generally longer although again, new lending is not necessarily covered. I think we are probably being a bit cautious on how long impairments will stay high, but we're looking back at the early 90s, and so we'll see whether that's true or not. And again, I think we expect liability margins to continue to be well competed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very useful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I hesitate to talk about 2011. I very much hope we can beat our ROE targets in 2013, but there is so much that's open there that I think we believe these targets are very responsible and clearly we will try and beat them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The other question was on risk-weighted assets growth. I think from all your Core divisions the one that shows a stronger risk-weighted assets growth is U.K. Retail. Is that new volume driven or maybe there is a big component from PD migration, procyclicality et cetera? And given that you haven't discussed the procyclicality impacts, can you give us your view, your thoughts on what is going to be the impact going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both were contributory. So a balanced growth on particularly mortgage lending as well as some PD migration which increased the risk-weightings associated with those. I think in one of the slides, we highlight around &#xA3;39 billion impact of procyclicality in the first half of the year off an asset base of 550 billion, so whatever that is, 6.5% or so in the first half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That would annualize to 12 or 13, which probably is higher than what other banks are talking of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that reflects if PD migration happens pretty quickly doesn't it, so I gave some indication of the credit migration we've seen in the first half. Again if things start to have leveled-off then maybe the PD migration will be less strong in H2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more, or do I sense holiday is beckoning? Jonathan you're back for a second bite?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Can I just ask a follow-up on this point with regard to APS because I think Stephen raises interesting points on how rollovers are dealt with in APS. And your suggestion is that the APS probably won't cover most of these loans as they come up for refinancing. So effectively the assets in the retail bank that you pointed to, will come out of APS and back on to balance sheet. Should we infer from that that actually risk-weighted asset growth in the non-APS businesses over the next few years will be pretty substantial as the 150 billion RWA benefit from APS rolls off and effectively transfers back to balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I could deal with that this way. Crudely, in Non-Core we don't expect to replace the assets. So hopefully the asset rolls off as APS rolls off. There will be a number of assets where there are maturity extensions because a borrower can't pay back. But that will be involuntary as opposed to voluntary.</p>
          <p>In our Core businesses part of the deal on APS as agreed in February was that there would be a level of rollover allowed in our U.K. Core businesses, not on the other ones, to give us firepower allowed under APS and still covered for the first five years of the period. So that there will be partial rollover, a coverage which basically was giving us extra firepower to make the lending commitments that we made. One of the two areas where the government is so far trying to roll back on what was agreed in February. One was the tax carry back and the other is the extent of rollover and that's still under negotiation.</p>
          <p>But irrespective of that point, our 2013 targets are assuming that the benefit of APS in RWA has gone by 2013. It won't actually have gone but as we get closer to that point, we will start showing you, in a sense; an APS normalized set of numbers because if something is going to go, you'll want to understand what the bank looks like. So our ROE and other targets are what I'll call normalized, i.e., stripping out any remaining benefit on RWAs. And I think that's the way we should manage ourselves. APS you should think of as a temporary scheme to cover us during the period that we can get back to standalone health. Once we are in standalone health, we shouldn't be relying on it any more and it will be anyway toning down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Is that the lot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We thank you all very much for coming and thanks in particular to Guy for being here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>