<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1245416" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>44094</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Peter Voser, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Simon Henry, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Gordon Gray</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michele della Vigna</participant>
      <participant id="5">Alastair Syme</participant>
      <participant id="6">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="8">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
      <participant id="9">Mark Bloomfield</participant>
      <participant id="10">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="11">Kim Fustier</participant>
      <participant id="12">Alexandre Weinberg</participant>
      <participant id="13">Mark Iannotti</participant>
      <participant id="14">David Cline</participant>
      <participant id="15">Lucy Haskins</participant>
      <participant id="16">Iain Reid</participant>
      <participant id="17">Bert van Hoogenhuyze</participant>
      <participant id="18">Colin Smith</participant>
      <participant id="19">Neil McMahon</participant>
      <participant id="20">Jason Kenney</participant>
      <participant id="21">Neill Morton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Royal Dutch Shell Q2 Results Announcement Call. There will be a presentation followed by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would like to introduce our first speaker, Mr. Peter Voser.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, Operator, and welcome to the Royal Dutch Shell Second Quarter '09 Results Presentation. I'm here with Simon, who will take you through the results, before both of us will take questions afterwards. Please take a moment to read the cautionary statement.</p>
          <p>So this is my first time speaking to you as CEO. I've been in this job for 30 days, but I'm just going to make some brief points at this stage and tell you what I want from Shell. Firstly, let me first say this isn't about changing our strategy. Upstream, Shell is set to deliver 2 to 3% growth into 2011 and '12. We have options in the portfolio that can deliver growth to 2020 and we have announced six new discoveries today. Downstream, Shell has leading brands and clear plans to improve our manufacturing base.</p>
          <p>Yes, we are in a recession, and that puts pressure on the financial side. And I don't lose sight of the fact that Shell today is in a very competitive position in the oil and gas industry. However, we need to sharpen our focus on delivery of the strategy and on managing our financial framework, what I call affordability.</p>
          <p>We are facing a challenging environment in '09, and that puts industry earnings under pressure at a time where we have a large capital spending program underway. So what are we going to do about that?</p>
          <p>I want to sharpen up the focus on delivery and affordability. By taking these steps and combining them with Shell's portfolio, we can bridge the company and our shareholders into a period of strong growth in 2011 and '12. Looking longer-term, we have a strong portfolio in Shell and we are working hard to create the best value from all of that for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the energy supply-demand picture and costs. Firstly on the oil market, we expect global oil demand to fall by over 2 million barrels per day in '09. This breaks the trend of average 1 million barrels per day growth since year 2000. This is the steepest demand drop since 1980. Today, OPEC has over 4 million barrels per day of spare oil capacity, which is a 5% overhang on the market. On the refinery side, there is over 2 million barrels per day of new industry refining capacity coming online this year. That's a 15, one-five, million barrels per day overhang on the market, or 15%.</p>
          <p>Looking at the natural gas side, after 30 years of near continuous growth, we expect Europe's natural gas demand to fall by 5% this year. Also, U.S. gas demand is falling. This all comes at a time when global energy supply is increasing by about 10% this year. There is a simple point in all of this. There is ample energy supply and not enough demand. This is quite a turnaround from the picture a year ago.</p>
          <p>Turning to costs, industry-wide cost pressures are easing as activity levels come down, but costs are still high by historical standards. We simply don't know when the global economy will recover, and we have to plan on the basis that this downturn could last quite some time.</p>
          <p>So if I look at the industry landscape today, it's a picture of oversupply in both upstream and downstream and a general slowdown in capital spending. This is all a bit counterintuitive in an industry where you have natural field decline rates of about 5% a year. So we see the best return opportunities in upstream and a more difficult job to find attractive returns in downstream.</p>
          <p>So our long-term thinking hasn't changed, but I want to have more urgency in Shell. We simply have to respond more quickly to the very different near-term conditions that we are now facing. The medium-term fundamentals are positive for Shell, and with a sharper focus on affordability and delivery, we can bridge the company and shareholders into a period of strong growth in 2011 and '12.</p>
          <p>We have announced the reorganization of the company recently. The Transition '09 program is a fundamental change to the way we are running Shell. It simplifies the upstream, that's created a new division for project delivery and technology, activities that were previously dispersed across the company. So by dividing the new upstream into two geographic segments, we have increased the accountability for each part to deliver good operating performance and profitability. We're also improving Shell's representation to governments and other stakeholders. The oil and gas industry is facing a complicated world with increasing service risks to manage and I want our most senior people working on that.</p>
          <p>Projects and Technology division will manage the construction of major projects including the pre-fee design and final investment decision. Project and technology will run Shell's global procurement and technology activities. A series of internal mergers in Projects and Technology is creating new efficiency gains and cost savings in a talent pool of over 10,000 staff.</p>
          <p>We are moving quickly. We have reduced the number of senior management positions by 20%. The top 600 leaders have all been announced and this has allowed us to reduce the number of senior managers by 20%. The full reorganization will be finished by the end of 2009. Overall, I expect that this and other programs will result in significant cost and staff reduction.</p>
          <p>I think this is more than simply about quick wins on costs. We simply have too many people doing business with each other rather than with the outside world. I want to strip away the layers that are not earning value and put much more focus on front line activities. This means changes in businesses and functional areas like corporate affairs, human resources, IT and finance. It means fewer people thinking about strategy and more people actually implementing it. It's more standardization and lower costs in project design and in procurement and even more emphasis on global strategy and capital allocation.</p>
          <p>We spend some $60 billion a year on contracting and procurement. That's 150 million per day. It's over 120,000 suppliers worldwide. There are savings to be had there. So I want to make Shell a simpler company with more accountability for delivering results. Now this will take time and the Transition '09 program is the beginning of the change we are going to make.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to costs. Industry costs have increased in recent years due to strong inflation and increased project complexity. We have seen these pressures in Shell and we have also deliberately chosen to spend more on exploration, feasibility studies, and maintenance programs. We have a series of cost-cutting programs underway at Shell. These cover things like negotiating lower prices from our suppliers and simplifying and standardizing our activities.</p>
          <p>We reduced Shell's operating costs by some 700 million pre-tax in the first half of '09. Now this is the figure which is a good snapshot of what we have achieved. It excludes exchange rate movements which have reduced headline costs by about $2 billion. And it excludes noncash accounting effects.</p>
          <p>Turning to capital spending, looking at the capital cost trends that we see in the market and our plans to launch a new project, we will be reducing spending into '10. 2010 capital spending will be more than 10% lower than '09 levels at around $28 billion. There will still be more flexibility into the spending program and there is scope to cut back further in 2010 if we need to do that. This is all part of managing affordability in the company and in the down cycle</p>
          <p>Turning to downstream. On the downstream side, Shell has good product offerings, strong brands and a low cost base. We do well in marketing and we continue to make selective growth investments. But clearly, we can do more to refocus the portfolio, both in marketing and in refining.</p>
          <p>You can see that in refining, we are looking at &#x2013; to exit from a further 8% of our capacity and to concentrate the portfolio in the world's most valuable sites. These non-core refining assets will be sold if the market is strong enough, or could be converted to oil terminals which can be used as hubs in the supply distribution and trading areas.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to upstream. We have a significant development program on the way in upstream and you can see the key projects on this map. Two new start-ups in '09, Sakhalin II LNG in Russia and BC-10 Deepwater in Brazil. They will add some 140,000 barrels per day of peak production for Shell on a gross basis and these two projects are running well. Looking into the future, we have around 1 million barrels per day of upstream under construction and all these projects are on track for the start-up timings we have previously shown.</p>
          <p>Exploration remains the most attractive way to add new barrels to the portfolio and typically costs us just 2 to $3 per barrel. We are investing about $3 billion this year in exploration and appraisal and we have made six interesting discoveries so far in '09. It's early days in terms of assessing these well results, but we are estimating that year-to-date, exploration and appraisal have added around 0.7 billion barrels for Shell with more wealth to come in the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>Now let me make some comments on Nigeria. As you know, there are three main business &#x2013; Shell businesses in Nigeria; deepwater oil and LNG where we have generally safe and reliable operations, and the HPDC joint venture, where there are some significant security problems. This is a high-tax environment, so that Shell earns low margins on these barrels, typically $2 per barrel.</p>
          <p>HPDC assets are spread over a wide &#x2013; a very wide area, 31,000 square kilometers, about the size of Belgium's, is about 6,000 kilometers of pipeline. This is in the Niger delta with its numerous river channels and creeks and a very difficult setting for the authorities to police.</p>
          <p>Shell's production there has more than halved since '05, with disruptions to gas supply for the LNG plant on Bonny Island. This is all to do with attacks from various armed groups and theft of oil at a very large rate. The Nigerian government is very focused on resolving these issues and new initiatives are underway. In addition to the security situation, there are some significant challenges on financing in a joint venture. The Nigerian government is also planning to reform the industry and tax system overall. It is too early to say what the final outcome will be, but we are going into a very uncertain period here.</p>
          <p>Now before I hand over to Simon, let me make some comments on the production outlook. So we are reconfirming the growth outlook for upstream that will be presented in March. This is a 2 to 3% growth rate in upstream from '09 to '12, a more selective growth in downstream. In upstream, we are seeing pressure on volumes from the demand environment, and the HPDC is a wild card in these forecasts. But the underlying growth strength is clear and this is an attractive outlook for Shell and our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So now let me hand you over to the new CFO, Simon Henry, and Simon will take you through the second quarter figures. Over to you, Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter, good afternoon. The macro conditions remained tough in the second quarter of 2009. This is a very difficult environment overall for the oil industry and we need to be clear about that and the impact on results. The operators basically halved from over $120 a barrel a year ago to just under $60 a barrel in the last quarter.</p>
          <p>The natural gas and LNG prices also fell from year ago levels and declined since the first quarter of 2009, this is a different ascent to the oil prices, which actually increased since the first quarter of this year. Refining margins were under pressure for the whole quarter and conventions remained particularly difficult with increased oil prices and weak demand for products and the chemicals environment remains challenging.</p>
          <p>Demand conditions overall remained weak so far into the third quarter. However, given this background, I am pleased with Shell's operating performance. Excluding identified items, current costs of supply earnings were $3.2 billion and earnings per share decreased by about 60% compared with the comparative quarter in 2008. The quarter was characterized by lower earnings in both upstream and downstream, mainly a result of the lower oil and gas prices and the lower industry refining margins.</p>
          <p>As we indicated with the first quarter results, we made a $3.6 billion cash contribution to the pension fund in the second quarter and that's deducted from the operating cash flow. Excluding this effect and net working capital movements, the cash flow from operations for the quarter was some $7.4 billion.</p>
          <p>So let me talk about the business performance in a bit more detail. First, on upstream. The upstream earnings decreased by 69% to $2.2 billion in quarter two and the fall in oil and gas prices was the main factor behind this decline as well as higher exploration cost. Upstream production fell by around 5% quarter-on-quarter to some 3 million barrels a day. If you set aside the security situation that Peter just described in Nigeria, and exclude the other external impacts such as OPEC, the PSC price effects and disposals, then production in the quarter was broadly similar to the year ago levels. And the driver behind this underlying performance was the new production.</p>
          <p>First half production volumes were boosted by some 210,000 barrels a day versus a year ago from new field start-ups, mainly in Russia and Malaysia, and the ramp-up of other fields around the world. These new barrels more than offset the impact of planned field decline.</p>
          <p>LNG sales volumes decreased by 6% year-on-year, but excluding the Nigeria security impact, the LNG volumes increased by 7%. The upward strength in capacity driven by the new trains in Australia and in Russia is actually ramping up.</p>
          <p>The demand for LNG, especially in Asia, remains under pressure. However, the gas and power earnings were supported by LNG cargo diversions and by natural gas trading activities. And again, the underlying performance is strong, despite the generally weak demand environment for LNG.</p>
          <p>Turning to Downstream, Downstream earnings also declined by about 70% against year ago levels to $0.4 billion. This decline was due to losses in refining and the weak chemicals environment, partially offset by strong earnings from marketing. Refining margins were down in all regions versus year ago levels. Shell's margins were generally better than the industry markers, except on the U.S. Gulf Coast, where the narrowing of the light-heavy spread was a disadvantage in particular for complex refiners.</p>
          <p>Shell's quarter-on-quarter refinery intake fell by 9% as a result of soft demand and some run cuts. Marketing earnings increased versus a year ago with support from retail, trading, lubricants and the business-to-business activities. And overall, the marketing portfolio has been resilient in the face of that very tough economic environment.</p>
          <p>So those are the earnings, the results by business. Turning to the cash flow on the balance sheet, looking at the cash position over the last 12 months, Upstream and Downstream segments' cash inflows have been broadly balanced against the outflows, while clearly, the quarter-by-quarter picture has become tougher over that period.</p>
          <p>Shell has a significant investment program underway, one of the most ambitious programs in the industry today. We kept the conservative balance sheet to make sure we can finance all of this across the cycle. In the last quarter, gearing has risen and stood at 12.5% at the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>This is part of our prudent increase in debt across the downturn. We've been active in the debt markets and issued $13 billion of debt in the year-to-date, average debt terms issued six years. It is our intent to balance our debt maturities out over time and gearing is still well below the 20 to 30% long-term average range that we see as acceptable.</p>
          <p>As we said with the fourth quarter results, we expect the gearing ratio to be in the low 20s at the end of this year, based on Q4 2008 macro conditions. And that guidance and the guidance we've previously given for 2009 CapEx is unchanged.</p>
          <p>Before I hand you back to Peter, just let me update you on disclosure plans. We aim to be transparent and to give the market the numbers you need to understand the company and its results. Following on from the reorganization of the company from the third quarter, we will report on three basic segments, upstream, downstream, and corporate.</p>
          <p>There'll also be more a detailed information supplement for investors, essentially additional data, with an expanded spread on upstream geography and a break-out of integrated gas earnings and the two downstream businesses. Historical information will be available from Investor Relations in good time for the third quarter results.</p>
          <p>Now back to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, Simon. Let me summarize. We are facing a very challenging environment in 2009. There is excess energy supply capacity in the world today and that is both in upstream and downstream. Shell is sharpening up to focus on the cost structure and delivery. By taking these steps, we can bridge the company and our shareholders into a period of significant growth in 2011 and '12.</p>
          <p>So looking further into the future, we have a strong set of further options for growth and we are looking at launching selective projects in the near term. To put it simply, we have a strong portfolio in Shell and we are working hard to create the best value from it for shareholders. So with that, let's take your questions. Please, can I ask you to limit yourself to one or two questions each, so everyone has the opportunity to ask a question?</p>
          <p>So with that, over to the Operator to start the question session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you. The first question comes from Gordon Gray from Collins Stewart. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Just a quick question, a single one about the slide you have on Page 20. You have the slide which you've shown several times. Given your capital under construction as a proportion of the capital employed, if I'm right, you're now up at the highest level you've ever been, give or take a quarter, of entire capital employed. I wonder if you can just give us a feel for what that figure could look like on a one-year and a two-year view? Obviously new FIDs come into play here, but your best idea of how that portion of unproductive capital would change over the next one to two years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gordon. Simon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good question. Total capital employed at the end of the quarter was $165 billion and the amount actually unemployed and that including the non-producing leases was $55 billion. Of that, around just over 40 is under construction and around 40% of that is in Qatar and Athabasca. So you can expect to see that come off over the latter end of 2010 and 2011 and effectively move into production. Those are the two &#x2013; the biggest slugs in the amount. As we go forward, of course we'll be taking new FIDs and that capital as we spend that will help increase at the unemployed demand and therefore we can expect that the amount won't decrease by quite the amount I've just indicated as we take the new FIDs. Hopefully that helps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Michele della Vigna from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I just had a question on your CapEx guidance for next year. So you're indicating about 10% lower CapEx, I was wondering how much of that will be lower activity and how much would be lower costs?  And also in terms of your 2010 CapEx, I was wondering if you could already give an dea of the split between new project and the base and how different that is from 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We are investing 31 to $32 billion this year and we will complete that program as we intended.  That is the largest program in the industry and even with a 10% reduction of 28 billion, we expect to be at the top end of the industry spend level. So this is not a major cut or change in strategy. We'd expect the reductions relative to this year to come partly from activity and partly from a reduction in the unit cost. Of course, we do have projects completing at the moment, Sakhalin no longer spending and Brazil, BC-10 and we expect Perdido in the Gulf of Mexico to come onstream at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>So as projects come off we would expect to take newer FIDs and potentially at lower unit cost than we're currently spending. And that should enable us to be able to deliver the investment program next year without having a significant impact on the growth figures in the medium term. There is no intent to reduce the spend on the big projects that are currently in progress, all of which remain pretty much on target on both schedule and on cost. Does that answer your question?</p>
          <p>Move to the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Alastair Syme from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Peter, I wonder if you could reflect upon the move to restructuring about how you're benchmarking the company against the peers?  What do you see out of line relative to your peers? Is it cash costs, profitability, the way you reinvest, what can we track to help measure your progress over the coming years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks for the question. We have quite a sophisticated benchmarking system actually in the company where we go down to the asset level and we benchmark that in order to actually see that we are keeping track and out-performing our competitors. I think from a more top level point of view, it is clear that we are going into a period where there will be strong growth. So for us, key will be project delivery and you can measure that in a pretty simple way over the next two to three years. That clearly will also bring us more production and as we always said, more cash flow, cash flow per barrel and obviously that's easy to check as well and to follow.</p>
          <p>And the third one, on the cost side, quite clearly with all the programs which we are driving we are moving towards a more competitive cost base both on the upstream and the downstream and you will see this quarter-by-quarter being delivered and our competitive performance on a unit per barrel basis will therefore go up. That's, by the way, what I will use internally, as well as the three, four key performance measures apart from achieving returns, long-term returns on investments and steering the capital allocation according to our internal profitability criteria. So I think that's a kind of a snapshot on how we are or how I am going to track and I will be transparent on this with the market over the next few years on how we are improving here. Thanks for the question. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Irene Himona of Exane BNP Paribas. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I had two questions, please. Firstly, on cost reduction, you referred to the 700 million of pre-tax costs achieved in the first half.  Can you give us a sense of what that is as a percentage of the total and is there any target for the total cost reduction by the end of Transition 2009? And my second question, concerning the expected increase in gearing to 20% by year-end at the Q4 conditions, is there any way you can restate that to say what it would look like in the current environment please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I take one or two and then the last one, Simon will take on the gearing. Maybe I'm going to be a little bit longer on the cost side, but I think it's important to explain how we are driving this or how I'm driving this. So to begin, let me explain that we haven't just started on cost and reorganization. This has been going on for some time and we see this as a normal business at Shell and all the short-term reaction. But I have clearly upped the pace and the scale of it this year.</p>
          <p>So today there are several programs on the way. The Transition 2009 program is the largest one, announced in June and it resets the definition of what is done in each business and how they are linked together. So five businesses going into three, plus projects and technology. Those internal mergers will impact large numbers of staff. There are also other costs in the reorganization programs in hand from earlier initiatives which were within the businesses and the functions, so this is about Shell's service center, globalization of functions, supply chain costs, et cetera.</p>
          <p>There are smaller scales, but we are obviously now linking them together with the '09 Transition project. And I've already said that in the first kind of 30 days we have now announced the top 600 leaders. We have taken 20% out and they got their margin orders in terms of cost targets, et cetera. So cost saving opportunities run into the billions of dollars and I expect the reorganization, as I've said, to be completed by the &#x2013; in 2009 so that we can actually benefit &#x2013; have the benefit flow into 2010.</p>
          <p>So the absolute base for the first half year of the 700 million will be around 20 billion, it's 19.8 to be precise. We have or I have set targets to all the businesses and all the functions for the second half of this year and there will be sharper targets then also for next year. Now I've said earlier today in the press conference as well, I have a strong belief that the leaders now have their marching orders and we are managing the company in a normal way and I don't need external pressure to get internal compliance on the costs. So we will keep the targets setting internally. I will watch this and we will follow it up this way. So these will be my kind of two answers to the two cost questions and the gearing I give to Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter, and thanks for the question, Irene. On the gearing, we set the low 20s based on the Q4 '08 environment. Since then we've seen oil price probably better than that, but actually the gas price and the refinery margins in particular worse. Also you may have picked up at the end of Q2 an increase in working capital around $3 billion, around two-thirds of which was in trading where we are investing in working capital because of the opportunities the market present. If those opportunities are still there, we may still use the working capital in the balance sheet by the year end. So it's difficult to give a precise figure. I still expect it to be in the low 20s and it depends obviously on how the gas refining margins come back, as well as the oil price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Jon Rigby from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Two questions. First, can we visit the corporate and FX lines? Seems to me that ever since the merger of the Royal Dutch and Shell T&amp;T groups, that the corporate in particular has sort of changed its sign. And I just wondered whether something coming out of that merger maybe had changed the way that earnings are being recognized in the income statement. And probably supplemental to that, is there anything unusual in the FX earnings this time around? Because the movement in currencies from one quarter into the next quarter end doesn't seem to explain such a large movement.  The second is just on your downstream, I think you explained some of the strength in marketing as being lubes and business to business and this is somewhat close to the question I asked last quarter is we're in the worst recession since the 1930s and a lot of it's a manufacturing recession. How are you generating good earnings or better earnings from those businesses? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You take the FX and then I go on the downstream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jon. Corporate FX, since RDS was formed, I haven't been tracking it that length of time, so I'll take your word for it, but there is nothing unusual in that figure this particular quarter. What we see in the DIE, the FX in particular in corporate is the movements on the inter-group balances and any other assets or liabilities held in currencies other than U.S. dollar. We have a significant number of companies, particularly in the downstream, that operate in a functional currency other than dollar and it's just a translation difference when we see significant movements in the dollar at particularly the end of a quarter. That's the only thing I would say.</p>
          <p>The other thing I'd guess is in 2004 is the interest income and expense appears in the corporate sector and we have had typically a large cash balance. That is, of course, reversing now as we go forward, so you can expect to see that effect in the sector. Our guidance remains zero plus or minus 150 million third quarter in the corporate sector, excluding the FX impacts which can be more volatile.  As we go forward, of course, we are changing our segmentation as we put the upstream and downstream businesses together and I believe it's incumbent on us to give new guidance on that as we have completed that process. But that guidance will probably apply from the first quarter of next year. Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the downstream side, Jon, let me give you a little bit further insight on this.  Both businesses have actually gone through major restructurings over the last few years. They both were heavily globalized and both actually started to concentrate on very specific business segments where through differentiation of service offering, of product quality offering, of other services we could actually enhance our margin take and some actually got out of the pure volume focus. That actually applies to both.  So that has remained through the additional services and other product offerings which we are giving. We could actually maintain the margin, albeit a little bit at a lower volume, which has carried us through this one, so through the recession so far. So these are generally marks to both.</p>
          <p>Let me take lubricants out just to explain to you.  Lubricants is a business which is exposed to many industries in the world and it really depends on how you have structured your detailed channel management and in our case I give you one number. Our lubricants business is actually only what I call the early cycle industries, like the car manufacturing, et cetera. You're only about roughly speaking 20% exposed from a volume point of view, so we have actually concentrated in other value segments over the last few years. So this explains actually the resistance and resilience of both businesses and retail, I could give you the same story. So very pleased with the marketing side from that point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Theepan Jothilingam from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi good afternoon, Peter, good afternoon, Simon. Just a couple of questions actually. Firstly on, I think Peter you mentioned you wanted more urgency within Shell. I was just wondering how you sort of change or go about changing that culture, are you sort of looking at changing the incentivization program there? And then secondly just on the downstream, you're looking to sort of reduce your exposure to refining by around sort of 8%. How realistic do you think that is in this type of sort of depressed environment? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, Theepan, for the two questions. I think on the first one, this is not about remuneration systems or payment systems. This is about what I call internally walking the talk and demonstrating what you want to do. So this is about speed, this is about de-complexing your organizational structures, this is about pushing the accountability down to where it actually should sit, which means you need to remove layers in the organization that actually decision making can really speed up and the accountabilities are at the right level. From that point of view, over the last few weeks I've been very clear on speed.   We are pushing this reorganization through in a very fast time. The organization is responding very well, the leaders taking this on, taking the accountability, taking also the burdens of delivering with it and I think that's the way they're going to drive this one. This is about getting a better business and be ready for the growth period in the right way.</p>
          <p>On the refining portfolio, undoubtedly the market is tough out there, but I think portfolio management is not something you actually switch on and off. It's something you do on a constant basis, so you are testing the market on a constant basis and you will always normally find buyers in the market. What I've said, if that is not the case and we can't actually get the proceeds which we want to get for these kind of niche refineries, then we are prepared also to actually transform them into terminals, et cetera or even close some of them.  So I think we will go through this and move it as fast as possible and I'm convinced there are enough possibilities in the market and we will not stop portfolio management. Thanks for the question. Next one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mark Bloomfield from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Just wondered if you could offer us some color on how you're viewing the trade-off between sanction and profitability on some of your key growth choices?  I suppose specifically wondering if you can give us a sense of the critical path on Mars B, Carmon Creek and Prelude please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Mark. Yes, I think the way I would do it is we are on track for the growth, as we have shown to 2011 and '12 and no changes to the targets. The PFID portfolio is a good one and it can support growth to 2020. I would say that the 28 billion of spending is, on the one side, lower than '09, but this is still a high figure in the industry and it is an investment for medium term growth. So we don't detail production targets at this stage for you, which will demonstrate the growth for 2012 and later, but I do not expect a fall off in production after 2012 or '13. We will continuously invest and have enough projects there.</p>
          <p>Now on future projects, coming FIDs, as you know, we have slowed down on FIDs in '07 and '08 because actually CapEx or costs were at the highest levels. Now we are seeing some easing on the cost side so we are now looking into the next few projects. What we are looking at, at this stage are a few attractive projects which we have in the books.  The very early ones, I think we see coming is -- we are working together with our partners on Gorgon, which is a Chevron and Exxon.  We would expect that FID to be taken shortly. We have put an FLNG, so a floating LNG scheme into field in July. So that is the first one of FLNG if you take FID and there should be actually quite a few of them afterwards.   And Mars B  in the Gulf of Mexico is also moving forward and we are considering that and then a full scale tie-cast development in North America are also possibilities over the next 12 months. So I think moving forward I do not comment on Prelude or other projects, but these are the kind of next steps which you will see us going through and taking FID.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mark Gilman from the Benchmark Company. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter and Simon, good afternoon. Had one question of a financial nature and then one with respect to LNG. On the finance side, Simon, I'm wondering what particular financial parameter, if any, goes into defining the 28 billion 2010 CapEx guidance number?  Because based on our numbers in 2010 you will be at or through the 30% debt ratio ceiling at that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, your second question, Mark? Give me both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second one relates to LNG and I guess the comment that the LNG sales in the quarter were down in part due to demand, suggests that you're not running certain facilities at capacity, which I guess I find to be somewhat surprising. Could you respond to that and also, provide some color as to realizations and in particular, the benefit which is referenced in the release of contract renegotiation, as well as cargo diversion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Mark. I'll take the first one. What parameter on the 28 billion limit, as I mentioned earlier we expect to be in the low end of the 20 to 30 gearing by the end of this year. We have, we believe, enough levers available to us to take us through 2010 comfortably within that range and those are obviously CapEx, what we choose to divest or dilute out of the portfolio and the cash generation from operations, which will be driven to large part by the macro environment. So 28 billion is a level we're comfortable enough, so gives us enough flexibility and I've indicated if we need it, there is a bit more flexibility there as well. So we are &#x2013; it is a 30% that we look at and the dividend, but all the parameters that help to set the capital for any given period. Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your second question, which was about plant availability or LNG in general first and plant availability and I think cargo diversions was the third element in that. I think if I look at the LNG, mainly obviously in Asia-Pacific, I think what we have seen in the second quarter is quite clearly that long-term customers are listing, let's say, at the lower end of their off-take agreements they have, which gave us actually some spare capacity in some areas which we could actually use for diversions and Sakhalin goes into the same category there.  The first cargos of Sakhalin actually we could use and send them, for example, into India, et cetera where we could actually achieve good prices in a market which was quite clearly no longer a market which we used to see last year.</p>
          <p>So that's the first one. On the capacity side itself, indeed, we had one or two of the plants not running at full. I think it was clearly the case in Malaysia and in Oman where we had not full capacity at this stage. We also, as you know, we obviously had problem areas in Nigeria which with Soku, Soku not operating.  We obviously did not have full capacity in Nigeria itself, but there again, Sakhalin and some others came handy into the whole equation and we could actually use those cargos for that. So all-in-all I think a very good result in LNG and in the second quarter we are very pleased with gas and power, including the marketing and trading, and so that was a good result. Thank you and the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Kim Fustier from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, gentlemen. Just two questions, if I could. Firstly going back to costs, within the $700 million of cost savings achieved in the first half of this year, could you roughly quantify the contribution of self-help programs versus reductions in third party costs? And then secondly, oil sands returned to profitability this quarter.  It looks like your units costs were down something like 6% versus Q1. Can you confirm that this is broadly rights and where do you see breakeven now in oil sands? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Simon takes it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kim. Good question. The 700 million we've achieved year-to-date is roughly half self-help and some energy cost reductions and a small amount of other third party costs. The third party costs, we are actually seeing reductions in negations that we're being involved in over the past six, 12 months. But they will not typically show through into the gulf immediately and quite a lot will be targeted at CapEx more so than OpEx. Overall on deflation we are expecting &#x2013; we published in one of the slides we use, the Cambridge Energy Index, which topped out at around 250, is headed down towards 200. And we would expect it to fall a bit further, maybe around another 10% or so, but not a lot further than that. But that, of course, is for current negotiations. Most of our current spend reflects negotiations held one, two, maybe three years ago.</p>
          <p>On the oil sands unit costs, yes, you're correct. Well first of all, we're back in profit. Secondly, the unit costs have indeed come down. Some of that is in fact energy-cost driven. We did have some down time on the hydrogen manufacturing units. We had a lower up grading yield than we might have hoped for, otherwise results would have been potentially 50 million better. There are some reductions in unit costs being achieved on the site. Not as high as the 15 to 20% that you see quarter-on-quarter, but we are improving our operations there steadily over time. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Alexandre Weinberg from Petercam. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, gentlemen.  Just two questions, so maybe first on the CapEx flexibility for 2010 on the 28 billion. Could you maybe indicate us what are the sources of the additional flexibility and also maybe give us some indication of the part of this CapEx which is for pre-FID project?  And secondly, maybe regarding the refining business and considering that many refineries are current loss making, would a temporary shutdown be an economical alternative for as to consider this as core or non-core. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for the questions. I think Simon could start with the second one, which is the refinery, and I take then the first one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the question, Alexandre. The refineries, if we look around the world, we have made several run cuts for economic reasons, particularly in Asia where over 20% of capacity was not being utilized in the last quarter as a result of the economic situation that we saw. Overall, we're about 3% higher or actually lower through puts, so higher run cuts than we were a year ago for economic reasons only.</p>
          <p>To actually temporarily shut down a plant incurs significant one-off costs in terms of safe mothballing and operational activities that need to be carried out and of course the fixed costs of the refinery don't actually go away. So shutting down even temporarily is a difficult economic option to get to and at the moment we're not looking at that for any of the sites. Other than where Peter mentioned in portfolio terms, not so much temporarily, but if there are assets that we can't sell, then we will consider converting them into terminals and effectively reducing the refining and distillation capacity in that way. Peter, do you want to comment on the 28?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I take the first one, it's on the &#x2013; sorry, but I will not break out further the 28 and split them and also don't give you pre-FID. We are in mid-2009 at the moment, so we'll further update on CapEx in early next year somewhere. I think we wanted to or I wanted to give you an early view on how certain things are transferring into our early views on the CapEx and I think I'll leave it at that. Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mark Iannotti from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Afternoon, gentlemen. Just a quick question on this idea of disposals. I mean, you seem clear that you're prepared to sell assets in refining where others may have a value in those assets higher than your own. But I think realistically it's not going to add much cash to your business because there isn't a great market for these types of assets and it seems to become a portfolio cleaning exercise. In E&amp;P there is a very good market for assets, particularly the Chinese, Indians looking to pay very strong prices. Why wouldn't you consider, particularly in light of a new CapEx that is lower than before and suggests slowing down some FIDs, why don't you consider accelerating the monetization of the E&amp;P portfolio with a more aggressive disposal program in E&amp;P certainly would help your balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. Thanks, Mark for the two-in-one question. Let me start with the refining side again. Quite clearly it is not only that you make a cash in, it is also that you actually operate one or two or three less refineries which allows you to take costs out, but it also allows you actually to use your brainpower for other things in the refining side, that's one. The second one is many times when we look at these things they are refineries of lower scale, that's one, so lower complexity, but it is also, we are always linking refineries to our marketing activities as well. We are always having very careful look at our supply and distribution envelopes. You can have impacts there as well, which makes it necessary that actually certain refineries just don't belong to us anymore because we have major changes on the way with supply or we do marketing. So that's quite clearly one.</p>
          <p>Portfolio management in general is quite clearly high on our agenda and we are looking constantly at both businesses, quite clearly of where we can use assets to either generate cash, what you were mentioning, or you can also generate other opportunities with assets you have. I think time will tell how much we do about all of this and this is always the question is when do you go into the market with these things. Everything needs a little bit of time of preparation as well, so I want to be early and ready in order to actually capture the market at the right time.  But quite clearly upstream is always a possibility as well and we have had good examples in the past, over the last 40 years we saw more than $30 billion of assets and we picked the markets very well both on upstream and on downstream. Thanks for the question. Next one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from David Cline from RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, two questions, if I may on the indications of 2010 capital investment. Firstly, at the level of the divisions do you see the projected decline in capital investment being broadly balanced across each or is capital spending in one or other of the divisions likely to hold up better than in the others?  The second thing, just on a longer term perspective on capital investment, I know it's very early days, but would it be reasonable &#x2013; how should we think about the 10% decline? Is it temporary or is it a new benchmark for future spending beyond 2010 or is it the beginning of a period of declining spending do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.  Two questions, I'll pick them both up. 2010 CapEx, we're actually in the process of ensuring which division gets which amount of CapEx at the moment, so I can't give you any specific figures, but typically we've been an 80/20, 70/30 upstream, downstream split and that split is likely to persist. We will continue the completion of the major projects, of course, so the Singapore cracker project we'll need to complete if we continue with Port Arthur.  But the majority of the CapEx will remain in the upstream.</p>
          <p>We will likely give an indication of Americas versus international as we go into next year. Longer term investment levels, we actually have a portfolio which would enable us to continue to spend at the $30 billion level probably for most of the decade. We will choose the rate at which we spend according to the, both the conditions we see in terms of revenue, but also the balance sheet that we referred to earlier. So we think 28 is the prudent level for next year. We will intend &#x2013; well, our strategic aim is always of course to invest through the cycle and therefore we don't intend to be volatile to a huge extent around the numbers we talk about. But we could go up or down from the 28 depending on the macro environment that we see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Lucy Haskins from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, couple of questions, if I may, Peter and Simon. Firstly on the LNG business, could you give some steer in terms of when you think Soku might be contributing once more and also what element of sort of benefit you got from the trading conditions in the second quarter? And I guess the second question is sort of what if we x out the sort of cash out flows required by the pension contribution this quarter, what kind of level of oil price sort of you felt you had a cash breakeven at during the course of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I gave both to Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Peter. Thank you, Lucy. The security situation in Nigeria remains a bit unpredictable, difficult to call and while we've had encouraging news on Soku, I really can't give you a date at which time it will be back on stream and making a difference at the LNG cargo level. The gas and power results as we reported them did include much better results year-on-year in both North American gas trading and in the European marketing and trading business.  The year-on-year impact was around $200 million, but that was against a relatively low quarter a year ago.</p>
          <p>On the cash breakeven, it's fortunately not something I worry too much about, the cash breakeven in any given quarter. Our aim, clearly our cash breakeven over the year as a whole, investing at the 31, 32 level, ahead of the increase in the cash from operations that we expect in 2011, 2012, is going to be higher than current oil prices. Our aim is certainly by 2011 to bring that breakeven price down to below current oil price levels and we're on that.  The 28 we'll take is on that journey and the breakeven price for this year, though, is clearly above the current level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Iain Reid from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gentlemen. Two questions, please. Firstly, on Nigeria, of the volumes that you've loss due to disruption, is it feasible to think that at least some of that might be recoverable by the time you've got your production growth in 2010 starting and how much of that do you think it's possible to forecast that can contribute to that?  And secondly, returning to costs, you've talked about the 700 million. I wonder if you could break that down into a unit cost reduction, specifically for the upstream, so we get some idea because obviously your volumes are full year-on-year, so it would be interesting to see what unit cost that represents?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for the two questions. On Nigeria, as I've said in my introductory remarks, Nigeria is a little bit of <mark type="inaudible" /> over the next two to three years for the two main reasons, which is really security, but it is also funding, which are unpredictable and then on top of it, the new petroleum bill which we just don't know yet the outcome. That's why we have actually split it out on the production growth chart which we have used during the presentation. We have actually spread it out in Nigeria there because it's just too uncertain at this stage to predict.</p>
          <p>The results are quite clear that over the next two, three years we have also, in our plans, we have slowed down capital investments in Nigeria because of the security issues and we are clearly just doing what we have to invest at this stage to keep going. So there might be growth. We will take it, but I would not bank on it and hence I'm not going to give you a percentage.  Now on the cost side, I do not have the number with me because we haven't broken it out into upstream and into downstream, so let us come back on this one and we'll give you the insides afterwards. Thanks, next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Bert van Hoogenhuyze from Dresdner. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Peter and Simon. Nice to speak to you again. One follow-up on the refineries issue, I assume that utilization rate you mentioned for Asia, 80%, is more or less system-wide and regarding that is it fair to assume that you're trying to go back to about 70% refinery capacity in view of your production capacity?  And the second question, again on Nigeria, I am afraid, of course, one of your peers has evoked either ridicule or admiration by his position to go for a $2 margin in a very large country, oil country with the same security problems.  The justification is that there's still so much opportunity there. Should I think that this is the same justification you have for staying in onshore Nigeria or is it just that it's unthinkable for you to go out of the onshore production and just concentrate on the LNG?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now I start with the second one and Simon will pick up the first one on the refineries, but thanks for the questions. On Nigeria and the comparison to Iraq, et cetera, let me just say a few word around Iraq. We are concentrating on two things quite clearly on this south coast where we have already started both in Baghdad and in Basra. We are moving from the MOU towards a final agreement and the progress there is encouraging.  At the same time, we were involved in three of the bid -- of let's say the fields during the bid round.  On one we came first as an operator and the other one as a partner. The third one we were a little bit further down. I think given the risks in the country we just didn't feel that it was right actually to go at such low levels of returns.  Particularly the risks are around similar things like in Nigeria around security, et cetera, et cetera.  So going into Nigeria, two comments, really. RDS Shell depended a lot on Nigeria in the past in terms of growth.  If you go four, five, six years back, we have successfully over the last few years actually built different growth pipelines, which we are using now, in order to actually build the growth for the next 10 years after 2020.</p>
          <p>We would love to have this growth out of Nigeria. We are just very careful at this stage.  But we have been operating for a long time in Nigeria. We have reduced now our kind of focus on the growth side in the delta, but we want to manage the situation together with the government and I think some of the new initiatives they are taking are positive.  But it's quite clear, as you have seen from the chart, it is very difficult and hence we are slowing down on the investment side and we'll just take stock on an ongoing basis over the next few years to see how we are going to operate in Nigeria. That's as far as I can go at this stage.  Thanks and then to the refinery question, over to Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Peter. Bert, I think the question was about refinery coverage and strategically how we would reduce our coverage of marketing sales. If we go &#x2013; we are at around 80 at the moment. Yes, we would go down into figures that you postulated if we were to divest the refineries that we talked about.  Could I just follow-up a previous question as well about the unit cost?  The impact in the upstream of the 700 million is probably between 40, $0.50 a barrel, pre-tax, it's probably 20, $0.25 post-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Simon. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Colin Smith from ICAP. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. A question for Peter, just on the changes you're putting in place in your organization, obviously there's been a bit of a discussion about personnel and cost savings. But in the context of your discussion of it sharpening up the organization, I wondered if you could just give us a view as to whether you think it's the cost savings are the sort of more important part in terms of driving earnings or whether it's the fact that you expect the business to run better once it's been refocused?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks for the question, Colin, very important one. This is not about costs only, quite clearly. This is about value generating. This is about on the one side bringing the technology together, bringing the EP technology, the global solution, the downstream technology together in order to actually deliver projects better in the future, even better, also cheaper hopefully with our technologies, which are second to none, applying them across the world in the same way in order to deliver value.  On the two geographical upstream businesses, quite clearly there at the beginning a lot of costs will come out because we are clearly bringing EP and GP together and in many areas actually the savings we have in terms of people in the structures are actually higher than the 20% because you're bringing typically an EP and a GP regional office together. And that will give us more savings, but that's the start.</p>
          <p>And the second one is clearly that we have got one face towards the stakeholders, to the customers, to the governments, et cetera, talking about upstream, talking about Shell and that will help us also to generate further value.  The decision time will be faster because there are less people involved in a certain country. Planning will be simpler because there is just less involved. So you will get, I think, a much faster, much less complex, less bureaucratic way on running the two businesses. And they're really front line revenue other than actually what I call back office driven in that sense.  So I think this will give us a much sharper operational and also value generation. So that's really the long-term focus. Short-term there will be a lot of our cost the next two, three, four quarters of even 2010, but at the same time this is about value delivery in the long-term. Thanks for the question.  Next one, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Neil McMahon from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just wanted to get a bit more clarity, when you were talking about LNG plants running at lower capacity, such as Oman and Malaysia, are these structural changes? That we know Oman is suffering from a lack of feedstock gas, but also just wanted to get an update on Malaysia, is that due to the feedstock, declines in the feedstock going into that plant or some other reason?  And then a second question, really on your exploration success in the first half of the year, you commented on 0.7 billion barrels of oil equivalent net to you. What sort of field sizes are we talking about that you're classifying as large discoveries? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Neil. On your first question, Simon will take the exploration one. On the LNG and the plants, let me start more from a macro point of view.  In the Far East, particularly we had roughly 30,000 barrels a day or 5% less demand in our system.  Now I think they are predominantly &#x2013; these are not structural reductions. This is really a reaction to the lower demand in most areas. Quite clearly in Oman there is some structural element in it from a supply, feedstock supply point of view, but the predominant effects which I have explained actually were market demand driven rather than the other way around. That will be the LNG answer. Now I pass on to Simon for exploration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. We don't use a particular indicator for the size of a significant discovery anymore on the grounds that volumes and value are not always directly related. So significant could mean lower volumes, significant value. We added 700 million barrels, six significant new discoveries. We had four good exploration appraisal follow-up successes as well and we didn't actually include the Vito well, which is an announced by the operator Anadarko last night in which we have a 55% stake.</p>
          <p>So overall it's been a very good quarter, a very good half because we actually produced about 600 million barrels and more replaced the production in that sense. They were, in this particular period as well, pretty valuable barrels. They were in the Gulf of Mexico, in Norway and in Australia. So very successful program, very pleased to see the additions.  I mean you can work out if it's only six main discoveries and four appraisals and 700 million barrels, each of them pretty significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a quick follow-up, what are your plans on drilling out in Brazil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We currently have limited activity planned in the rest of this year in terms of drilling in Brazil, but we do have interesting wells still in the portfolio to be drilled.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Jason Kenney from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. I know I missed some of the earlier parts of the call, so apologies if you've already covered some of this. Firstly on Russia, you've been invited back into Sakhalin 3 and 4 and I just wonder if you could give us some color around that opportunity, kind of development timing, resource opportunity, building on the Sakhalin LNG interest you've got across there?  And then the second question on diversions in LNG, I understand that there was some upside in Q2 mainly in Asia.  Do you see the chance for diversions in LNG dissipating going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I take the Russia one as I was in the meeting in Moscow. I think, taking you back a little bit in history, you know when we take the dilution to Gazprom before we finished the Sakhalin project, we also signed actually an AMI that -- which actually covers the Sakhalin Island up for future developments. The partners in Sakhalin 2 would actually try to work together.  Given the successful termination of the Sakhalin construction and the good start up, we are now have been offered by the Russian authorities to work first on Sakhalin 3 I think I would call it, which is additional train, 3 and 4, as Mr. Putin said, and we are now in discussions with our partner Gazprom and others in order to actually take this to the next level or the next step.</p>
          <p>It is too early to say what this is. There are exploration acreage there and there are blocks where we know that there are volumes there, resources there. So we are now going into that and we will quite clearly talk to our Russian partner and others over the coming months.  I think too early to give you more details, but it's an encouraging message back from the Russian authorities that the appreciation of delivering Sakhalin 2, together with our partners, Japanese and the Russian partner Gazprom, was well received.  On the diversion I'll pass over to Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. Yes we were able to divert cargos in the quarter, partly because of either a lack of supply from competitor projects or from Nigeria, definitely benefiting from having the global organization in place that enables us to bring together those cargos and customers, plus the regas terminals that we do have in place. For example, we put cargos into India. We have a deal to provide LNG cargos to Kuwait across the summer and at least one of the Sakhalin cargos was in a chain that included the UK LNG import terminal. So it's important to remember the majority of our volume is long-term contract and marketed through joint ventures which we don't control. But at the margin we have a very efficient method of joining the molecules with customers who are prepared to pay good value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So what is the outlook going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So what is the outlook going forward for the trading side of LNG?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that might be giving away our actual commercial position if I gave too much, but that global position remains a big advantage structurally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, next question, thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The last question comes from Neill Morton from MF Global. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. A couple of questions left, both on the U.S.  On Chemicals, I'm afraid it's the perennial question about your loss making operations there. I know it's the bottom of the cycle, but now that you're in charge, Peter, I just wonder what you think can be done differently about your operations? They seem clearly to have a structural disadvantage, both regionally and with regards to the cost structure.  And just secondly on the upstream business, I'm struggling a little bit to try and reconcile the very sharp recovery from small losses in Q1 to sort of $700 million plus in the second quarter. I know higher oil prices, but lower gas prices, perhaps just help me a little bit there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I take the first one and Simon will cover the second one. On Chemicals, yeah, you put the finger on the right thing that we have some disadvantages with the liquid cracking which you have made in the U.S. We have worked on this one and there is a plan in place which we are going through which would get us in a better competitive positioning over time. We are changing, for example in Deer Park, but also in others we are adding some gas feed into our chemical sites in order to be more competitive from a feedstock point of view. So we have a program to get our loss making Chemicals business more competitive and we are working on this one and you will see improvements over time. I think that's more or less what's going on at this stage. So it's at hand and we are working on it.  The second one to Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Many thanks, Peter. Yes, the U.S. E&amp;P earnings did go from a slight loss in the first quarter to a 500 million profit. There is a one-off item in the operating segment in Q2 related to litigation settlement for a couple of hundred million and we had better oil prices and fundamentally we had stronger performance from that oil price. The gas, realized gas price is a lesser issue for us so we just benefited from a better environment. We I think had some exploration write-offs in the first quarter that were not repeated in the second. Hopefully that covers that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I also assume that the amortization costs in Q1 continued into Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, they did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thanks for the question. This brings us to the end. Thank you very much for all your questions and for joining the call today.</p>
          <p>The third quarter results are on the 29th of October and so I'm going to take to call on that one. So on behalf of Simon and myself, again thanks for calling in and have a nice afternoon.   Cheers, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This concludes the conference call. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>