<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1514116" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>44094</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Director">Simon P. Henry</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Martijn P. Rats</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Michele della Vigna</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Oswald C. Clint</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Iain S. Reid</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd.">Jason D. Gammel</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Kim A. Fustier</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Doug T. Terreson</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Lucas O. Herrmann</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Alastair R. Syme</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor Pickering Holt &amp; Co. Securities, Inc.">Robert Arthur Kessler</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Peter W. Hutton</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Hootan Yazhari</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James Euro Equities SAS">Bertrand Hod&#xE9;e</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="VTB Capital Plc">Colin S. Smith</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Royal Dutch Shell Q3 Results Announcement Call. There will be a presentation followed by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would like to introduce our host, Mr. Simon Henry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Operator. Good afternoon, good morning, wherever you may be, and welcome to the Royal Dutch Shell third quarter 2012 results presentation. I'll give you a summary of the performance of the last three months and then take your questions. First of all, to those on the web, the cautionary statement. Shell is pursuing and delivering on our long-term and consistent strategy against a backdrop of very volatile energy markets. Any one quarter's results are simply a snapshot of the delivery against this long-term strategy.</p>
          <p>Third quarter underlying earnings were $6.6 billion. Earnings per share declined by 6% from the third quarter a year ago. We have announced around $6 billion of asset sales so far this year as part of the overall capital efficiency drive. Our growth projects continue to ramp up well. We've launched a couple of new projects, oil and gas developments in Italy and the United Kingdom, and we've been adding new positions for future growth out towards the back end of the decade.</p>
          <p>So let me give you more details, and I'll start with the macro environment. If you're looking at the macro picture here compared with the third quarter of 2011, liquids and gas realizations both declined from a year ago. But within that mix, I'd highlight the discount of WTI to Brent and the discount of Western Canada Select or WCS to Brent. And that of course is important for our heavy oil business in Canada. All these discounts remained wide by historical standards, a $17 discount of WTI to Brent and a $33 discount of WCS to Brent.</p>
          <p>On the gas side, oil-linked natural gas realizations increased year-over-year, and you can see the uplift in our Integrated Gas results. However, by contrast, the spot gas prices in North America declined sharply from last year by around 38%.</p>
          <p>In the Downstream, industry refining margins increased sharply from year-ago levels in all our regions. And it's been quite a while since we've been able to make such positive comments on the downstream macro. However, I do want to tamper the enthusiasm here. We believe this rally is being driven primarily by capacity outages such as the PDVSA fire in Venezuela and hurricanes on the Gulf Coast rather than by stronger underlying demand conditions. In fact, to the contrary, we're seeing increasing evidence of the weak economy all around in our downstream marketing and our chemicals businesses. So we believe the downstream rally could be short-lived.</p>
          <p>Overall we're seeing a complex macro picture this year, all playing into our cash flow. We have the high headline oil prices, big discounts on North American oil market, weak downstream conditions, and the low gas prices in both North America and in Europe. So for those of you who are modeling our financials, we give guidance that a $10 increase in Brent prices, the sort of stat we've seen in recent years, would in theory add over $3 billion to annual earnings.</p>
          <p>However, in practice, we're seeing about half of that uplift in our numbers because the old price since 2009 has come against the background of that weak downstream, low regional gas prices, and the discounts in North American crudes. So only half of the price upside is there. Overall, however, despite all this background complexity, we're making good progress against the medium-term targets we set out at the start of this year and as communicated earlier, we are delivering on the strategic milestones.</p>
          <p>Turning now to earnings, excluding identified items, the CCS earnings were $6.6 billion. Earnings per share declined 6%. On a Q3 to Q3 basis, we saw lower earnings in the Upstream and broadly similar results in the Downstream. The cash flow generated from operations was $9.5 billion. The dividends in the quarter were $2.8 billion, of which $800 million were settled with new shares rather than cash under the scrip dividend program. And we are offering that scrip program again through third quarter. We are continuing our share buyback program to offset the dilution from scrip, and we achieved just over $1 billion of share buybacks in the first nine months of this year.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the business performance, firstly in the Upstream, excluding identified items, the Upstream earnings were $4.9 billion in the third quarter 2012. That's a decrease of 10% against the same quarter in 2011. Now the earnings were impacted by the lower oil and gas prices, with a strong financial performance from Integrated Gas, both &#x2013; that's LNG and GTL, but also higher results from gas trading.</p>
          <p>We show slight losses in our Upstream Americas business. That's a combination of a loss in the onshore gas business more than offsetting the profits in the heavy oil and the deepwater. The drivers here are primarily low gas prices, Henry Hub, higher depreciation in Upstream Americas, which has increased from $0.7 billion to $0.9 billion on a net income basis Q3 to Q3, and that reflects the build-up in both new production and the amortization of non-productive leases.</p>
          <p>Now headline global oil and gas production in the third quarter was around 3 million barrels of oil equivalent per day. On a Q3 to Q3 basis, we saw a series of volume impacts impacting the differential. We saw divestments of 36,000 barrels a day. The Gulf of Mexico hurricane impact was around 20,000 barrels a day Q-on-Q. The exit from Syria around 14,000 barrels a day, and Nigeria security impacts 9,000 barrels a day. All of those figures more negative in 2012 than 2011. So excluding these effects, underlying production increased by just over 1%. Hurricane Isaac in the quarter itself led to a productions hit of 26,000 barrels a day. Our LNG sales volumes increased by 4% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Let me just update on the gas to liquids facility in Qatar. The last few days, we've been running the total facility at a utilization rate of over 85% of capacity. Each of the two trains has run over 95% of capacity at some point in the last few months. The overall complex is on track to finish ramping up in the fourth quarter, and we're nearly there. This will be an important strategic milestone for the company and of course financially.</p>
          <p>Our three large ramp-ups, Pearl, Qatargas 4 and the Athabasca oil sands expansion project, produced some 340,000 barrels a day in the third quarter. That compares with 275,000 barrels a year ago, and of course the capacity of 450,000. With Pearl ramping up to design rates during the fourth quarter, we should see the full impact of these projects next year.</p>
          <p>For fourth quarter of 2012, I should just highlight that the oil sands project in Canada will have upgrade and maintenance impacts of around 10,000 barrels a day for Shell compared with the current quarter &#x2013; the current third quarter in 2012. That will increase the proportion of oil sands production that's sold as discounted heavy synthetic crude. In addition, we're seeing a combination of flooding and increasing security issues in Nigeria onshore, which could reduce production by 20,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day from the third quarter to the fourth quarter. That's a sequential movement.</p>
          <p>So overall on production, we're running about 100,000 barrels a day below the outlook we gave back in February, which was for around 3.4 million barrels a day this year. It's primarily driven by our own active portfolio management to generate long-term returns for shareholders. We sold producing assets this year. We slowed down North American dry gas drilling, and we've switched the focus there to the exploration and appraisal activity on the liquids rich shale. We've also had, unfortunately, sabotage impacts in Nigeria, and of course the oil price impact in production sharing contracts is quite significant as well. So we are making good progress on underlying growth, and we'll give more details on these 2012 movements when the year is actually closed.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the Downstream. Excluding the identified items, the Downstream earnings were broadly similar to year-ago levels at $1.7 billion, built up from softer Chemicals figures and higher earnings from Oil Products. In Chemicals, we saw weaker Q3 to Q3 margins in Europe, and a broadly similar picture in Asia where margins remained weak.</p>
          <p>In contrast to this, the Oil Products earnings increased, and we were boosted here of course by stronger industry refining margins. Albeit that is against a backdrop of pretty difficult demand conditions overall around the world, and therefore we saw some decline in marketing and trading results, although they still remain competitive, and we believe strong. We are expecting refinery availability for the fourth quarter to be below fourth quarter 2011 levels due to a heavy plant maintenance schedule, and Chemicals availability though should be slightly higher.</p>
          <p>Repairs to the crude distillation unit at the Port Arthur refinery expansion, they are going well, and we're on track for a restart in 2013 as planned. These repairs overall are expected to cost some $100 million on a post-tax basis for Shell. And I think that's far less than some of the headlines I've actually read. So those are the earnings.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the portfolio, where we've been pretty busy. We've got more than 20 new projects under construction in Shell, in deepwater, tight gas, liquids rich shales, integrated gas, and in more traditional activities. These are the projects that will drive the growth into the middle of the decade and beyond.</p>
          <p>So, highlights in the quarter. Firstly, we've taken final investment decision or FID on three new projects. Carbon Capture and Storage in Canada, that will reduce emissions at the Scotford Upgrader plant by 35%. And two new Upstream oil and gas projects in Italy and the United Kingdom, which are expected to add peak production around 22,000 barrels a day for Shell. In China, we updated the contract terms in the Changbei gas field, which will allow drilling and development of new reservoirs there within the license. And in Qatar, we've launched the front end engineering design work feed on a new gas to chemicals plant which would use ethane from Pearl GTL.</p>
          <p>Now you will have seen in the results an after tax $354 million impairment charge from North American tight gas properties. This charge is against the higher operating cost positions in the Pinedale and in Haynesville. We use a $4 gas screening price for our impairment calculation, which of course is the lower end of our planning range for economic decision making.</p>
          <p>In North America, the onshore rig count is about flat, 37 to 36 rigs Q3 to Q3. And we've been refocusing within that all the drilling into liquids rich plays. At the end Q3, that was 21 of the total compared to six a year ago, and we'd reduced dry gas rigs down to &#x2013; from 31 down to 15. Now during October, that ratio shifted further. We're now back &#x2013; three-quarters of the rigs are working on liquids rich plays. The gas drilling that we're doing is primarily in the base of the lowest breakeven price acreage in Western Canada and the Marcellus play in Pennsylvania.</p>
          <p>Production from liquids rich shales or LRS in the third quarter was 16,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day. We recently started up one of the series of new processing facilities in the Eagle Ford formation in Texas. And the LRS production, including the new assets in the Permian Basin, that should reach around 50,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day by the year end. It's a great platform for growth going into 2013. In Iraq, the South Gas Company is gathering around 300 million cubic feet of gas per day as we work towards the start-up of the joint venture and the first Shell revenues in 2013.</p>
          <p>Turning now to exploration, we had two good discoveries in the quarter, gas both of them, one in Australia and one in Malaysia, and we had a successful oil appraisal in the Gulf of Mexico. We've made progress with our Alaska exploration program. The industry of course continues to assess the offshore potential there. Our own program is a multi-year exploration program. It was always five wells over several years.</p>
          <p>And our ability this year has demonstrated I think our commitment both to setting and operating to high standards on sustainable development, and safe and reliable and responsible operations. We are taking a very measured approach here of course. We were successful in drilling two top holes this season, one is Beaufort, one in the Chukchi, both down to around 1,400 feet. We've learnt a lot this year. We're reviewing those lessons, and we'll take all of them on board developing the plans for 2013.</p>
          <p>We've also been busy I think with acquisitions and divestments, accessing new growth opportunities but also keeping a sharp focus on that overall capital efficiency. For year-to-date, we've announced already $6 billion of acquisitions, $6 billion of divestments. We haven't booked all of these yet. In the third quarter, we actually booked $1.3 billion of acquisitions and that's $2.2 billion for the year-to-date. And on the divestment side, $0.8 billion in Q3, $5 billion recognized in the first nine months, so more to come.</p>
          <p>There have been quite a few portfolio moves in the second half of the year. Expect to see them booked in coming months. We've announced increases in our equity in fields where we can add more value, such as Australia and the North Sea. We bought new LRS positions in the Permian Basin in the U.S., and we continue to build new exploration positions such in China offshore and the Ukraine.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we're reducing exposure in other areas to share the risks and enhance capital efficiency, for example in West Africa. Now you've seen this is all about dynamic portfolio management on a strategic and a thematic basis and a global basis, aiming overall to optimize both capital efficiency and growth potential.</p>
          <p>Moving on then to the cash flow and the balance sheet, cash generation on a rolling basis was $47 billion, including $6 billion of disposable proceeds, and that was against an average Brent price of $112 per barrel. Both the Upstream and the Downstream segments generated surplus cash flow after investment. We've taken advantage of attractive market rates during the quarter to add $2.5 billion of new long-term, some of it very long-term, debt to the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>So the gearing at the end of the quarter sat at 8.6%. That's similar to the second quarter, relatively low in the zero to 30% expected range, as of course you would expect in strong oil price conditions. We could see a slightly higher gearing level by year end since we've got several transactions, that $3 billion headline announced but not yet closed, that could come in the fourth quarter. And we also typically pay out higher cash taxes in the fourth quarter versus the first three quarters of the year.</p>
          <p>So just let me summarize before we go for your questions. We are pursuing and delivering on a long-term and consistent strategy against a backdrop, both in the recent past and we expect for the future, a volatile energy market. Third quarter earnings, $6.6 billion. We've announced the $6 billion of divestments this year, and we've been adding those new positions for future growth. We've added new resource positions with the drill bit, we've launched new oil and gas developments, and the series of small acquisitions. New projects are coming onstream. We are maturing new investments for medium-term growth. We are making good progress to deliver a more competitive performance from Shell, and there is more to come.</p>
          <p>With that, let me take your questions. Please could I ask that we have just one or two each so that everyone actually has the opportunity to ask a question? Operator, please could you poll for questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. We will now begin the question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Martijn Rats from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, good afternoon. I'll ask two questions. First of all, I was hoping you could elaborate a bit on the loss in the Americas. Also specifically when would you expect us to see an improvement there, how structural are these losses? And secondly, I wanted to ask about the refining result which benefited of course from slimmer margins. But even compared to the margins, our assessment was that it was a pretty robust result. So I was wondering if the result saw another element of improved operating efficiency or something along those lines to that result that could perhaps be a bit more structural?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Martijn. Clearly those of you who've delved into the detail will notice the loss in the Upstream Americas, around $100 million, and that compares to about $700 million of profit a year ago. Firstly, strategically, the Americas is a very significant growth area for shale. We have around $50 billion of capital employed there. We're investing something like $12 billion, $13 billion per year in the Upstream business.</p>
          <p>As we invest, we expected a reduction in profitability as we see two things structurally: there are higher up front depreciation charges, partly as we amortize non-producing leases but also partly as we see high depreciation in early production of the onshore, and we also have quite a high level of feasibility and exploration expense as we investigate possibilities for, for example, LNG or GTL projects in future. So there are two structural high level of spend.</p>
          <p>We have also seen, if we go year-on-year, much lower gas prices. We've also got those much lower Canadian oil realizations. So if you look year-on-year, the costs, fees, explorations costing around $300 million year-on-year, and the price effect is around $200 million year-on-year. I mentioned the downtime and Hurricane Isaac. That's about a $100 million impact in the quarter, and variety of other smaller issues. There's no real issue other than the ones I've talked about in terms of cost, and the reliability deepwater and oil sands, the heavy oil activity, has been very good.</p>
          <p>The final factor, and structural this year but positive going forward, is we've deliberately slowed down the onshore gas activity. We've switched the rigs. It is now actually 29 in liquids and 11 on gas, as we take on the Permian activity. That has meant we've invested some $700 million less than originally intended on gas, which has significantly reduced production.</p>
          <p>And we've switched it into what's primarily been exploration and appraisal activity on the liquids, which of course ultimately will drive the growth that we expect on the LRS. So if we exit the year on 50,000 of production from the LRS activity and we have a platform for growth there, that actually is likely to be more remunerative than the gas. So that one is, although structurally lower gas production, we would expect structurally better performance.</p>
          <p>Last point I'd make on the Upstream Americas, we're still generating over $1 billion of cash each quarter, excluding working cap, and we should &#x2013; on the rolling 12 months, is over $6 billion. Quite a few of the impacts I've just stated are non-cash items. So still a strong underlying cash generation from that business and it is a growing business.</p>
          <p>Comment on Downstream and refining margins, well, just compared to the market, we are &#x2013; or maybe some of the competitors but generally the market, we're less exposed in the Mid-Continent and the West Coast than some competitors. Therefore, we don't get quite the same proportion of benefit because our refineries are typically on the Gulf Coast in North America. We are well exposed in Europe.</p>
          <p>So we did see manufacturing and supply making quite a healthy profit in the quarter, the first one for quite some time, which has basically offset losses carried in the first six months in that activity. I can't comment on how it compares with your estimates because I can't talk about your estimates there. The only sort of underlying help we see is an overall foreign exchange impact, which is basically an accounting impact between timing &#x2013; on timing of recognizing and paying for crude of about $200 million net positive in the Downstream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One other thing actually, Martijn, the actual operating performance was probably the best we've had in terms of no deferred or very little downtime unplanned in the refineries. It was around 3% for the quarter, and world class performance is typically about 4%. So it was one of our better performances, but that has a relatively small impact. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Martin. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Jon Rigby from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello, Simon. Quick questions on the gas &#x2013; or the North American side again, just to return to that. Can you &#x2013; are you able to estimate at what point the current portfolio onshore turns positive? And also the degree to which your volume sensitivity starts to change, i.e., when do you start to raise gas production again? And I guess circling back on to what your existing production is, what do you think the production is that you've foregone by taking the economic decision not to produce from that portfolio? And just lastly, can you just remind me why are you depreciating on a straight line basis on those licenses rather than holding them back to depreciate them on a UOP basis when they come into the production? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jon. The onshore turning positive, well, $5 Henry Hub would help. Our sensitivity at $1 Henry Hub is about $100 million per quarter, so that would certainly help. I don't &#x2013; we don't give effectively a bottom line income for onshore gas on the grounds that they're significant allocatable expense, which confuses the situation. But I will say the total depreciation's around $3 billion per year at the moment.</p>
          <p>So, when does it turn positive? Difficult to say. When does the potential liquids volume offset the volume loss in gas? Well, Marvin [Odum] tells me he thinks we can catch up by the end of 2014 in volume terms. Of course, at the current gas oil price arbitrage opportunity, that means the cash generation and the earnings performance probably gets better earlier than the end of 2014. That will depend of course on ongoing drilling rates and that's something that we need to assess ourselves as to at what rate we pursue both.</p>
          <p>Why do we depreciate &#x2013; our general approach to signature bonuses for example, is to amortize over the life of the lease. So in Alaska for example, it's being amortized over 10 years. And where we are assigning purchase price premium on where we've acquired assets &#x2013; asset premium, we also do amortize some of that over what we see as the early lifetime of the asset. So I would say we're aggressive in depreciation, and conservative therefore in earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And sorry, and the gas production foregone do you think, as an estimate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The gas...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...maybe what you'd been if we were running it somewhere in the middle of your planning price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, compared to what we might have expected to deliver this year, we're probably about 30,000 short by the back end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it would have probably attracted because it would attract more UOPM depreciation, it would merely have attracted more losses had we done it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I &#x2013; and that's the figure that Marvin saying you can catch up in liquid terms by in 2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Volume terms, we're &#x2013; by &#x2013; in a couple of years' time, we should have offset the lower gas production by higher liquids.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>By higher liquids, yeah. Great. Thanks, Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jon. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Michele della Vigna from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Michele.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Michele.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the presentation. I had two quick questions. The first one is on the big &#x2013; of the three big projects and the 450,000 barrels per day of capacity there, should we expect to get a full utilization of that capacity let's say next year? Or should we assume that your average utilization there is always going to be somewhere below 100% due to maintenance, et cetera, so should we assume something around 90% there? And my second question would be on your dry gas activity in the U.S. and whether there is a specific level of gas price above which you would actually start to ramp up that activity again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Michele. The big project firstly is 450,000. You wouldn't expect to average 450,000 necessarily in any given year, particularly not the first year. And on the oil sands piece in particular, we're actually working our way for the next year result through some of the not quite as rich oil base as well. So what we would hope to do is demonstrate we can operate sustainably and reliably at capacity in all the assets.</p>
          <p>Already done that by the way in LNG, and in practice in the oil sands in terms of tonnage of rock moved, and we hope to get the GTL as well. So, one step at a time. We would like to get everything up and running, show we can keep it there by the end of this year. But I don't think we would run on average at the 450,000 for the full year. As we get more experience, we tend to debottleneck and yes, we would expect to see higher production.</p>
          <p>On the gas price, what price would make it attractive? Well, economic breakeven in West Canada or Marcellus is about $3, but that wouldn't mean that anything above $3 we would ramp up. We essentially &#x2013; to look at our total operating capability and the number &#x2013; that's basically the number of rigs we can operate safely and reliably, and decide where we want to apply that. And I think it's fair to say the focus will be on opportunities like the Eagle Ford, like the Permian. We will continue to drill the Marcellus and in Groundbirch in Canada. But that may be targeted really at the capacity that we already have in place for aggregation pipelines, et cetera, making sure we fill the capacity. And so I think for the next year or so, you will certainly see that the focus being on the liquids rich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Theepan Jothilingam from Nomura International. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Afternoon, Simon. Two quick questions. Firstly, just &#x2013; I mean coming back to volumes, just wanted to get a sense of whether you &#x2013; there was any other sort of significant planned maintenance next year, whether you're in a position to give a more explicit outlook at the group level for 2013? And then secondly, just want to revisit the buyback, just wanted to understand whether you were still sort of hamstrung in terms of how much you can buy back in the market? Any sort of progress in terms of discussions with the Dutch authorities? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Theepan. I don't think we can give a forecast or a projection ahead to 2013 just yet. We'll probably do that with the Q4 result. I will say there are clearly very &#x2013; quite a few moving parts. We're suffering theft of 50,000 barrels a day in Nigeria direct from trunk lines, and we can't measure how much out from everywhere else in the system, plus the sabotage impact, and that remains very material in terms of its impact.</p>
          <p>The &#x2013; what I can say positively is we do have that oil &#x2013; the LRS ramp-up to come. We have the ramp-up of the projects that we've just talked about, the three big projects. We have &#x2013; hopefully we will see cash again come onstream. Hopefully we will get the first commercial production in Iraq. And generally speaking, a fairly robust portfolio. Our decline rate in the quarter was 130,000 barrels a day. That's shading down a bit over the past couple of years from the 150,000 level, partly because of the introduction of the longer lived projects.</p>
          <p>So it's reasonably robust outlook. And remember of course that our actual expectation over the next three years is a cash flow target, not a production target. So $100 barrel should give us $200 billion of cash generation, and that's what we're focused on delivering. The barrels will be what they will be.</p>
          <p>Buyback constraints, unfortunately as you're probably aware, there is a new Dutch government &#x2013; well, fortunately there is a new Dutch government. Unfortunately, I mean the changes that we've seen plus the fact that the government actually fell on budget considerations, there's been no real opportunity to have the discussions around some of the constraints we face, which are essentially fiscal constraints. Therefore, no real move on that, no real discussions. We are in practice limited to 25% of the daily trade in RDS.B shares on the London market, which works out roughly at $25 million to $30 million maximum per day. And that's what we've been doing when we've been in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And just coming back, I mean no significant planned turnarounds in any of the large assets for next year just announcing? Just want to confirm that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There will be some, I imagine. I don't actually have the program in front of me. The planned turnarounds in Upstream is typically about 150,000 barrels a day on average, but it does vary quite materially quarter-on-quarter. And I don't have anything in hand to suggest but it's more or less than that next year. Ask me again in February.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Theepan. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Oswald Clint from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, Simon, thank you. Could you just update us on your Gulf of Mexico performance here in terms of &#x2013; for the volumes you're having, impact of adding new rigs into the offshore, et cetera? And then also secondly, just on what are your thoughts on NGL pricing, especially as you talk about these LRS growth platforms? What's the NGL impact if it stays depressed on kind of unit margins from that growth? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Oswald. The current performance is just under 170,000 barrels a day in terms of Gulf production. We now have eight rigs operating, six deepwater, some of that activity &#x2013; six floaters and two off platform. Some of that activity is focused on exploration, therefore has minimal impact in terms of short-term production. Some of it is associated with Perdido and ultimately moving on to Mars B drilling ahead of that project coming onstream in 2014. We are hopefully seeing pretty much the bottom of the production, the decline that we've seen post the moratorium.</p>
          <p>Turn that round, Perdido is growing well. We will have in fact 11 rigs up and running by early next year as we ramp up the activity. We only had eight pre Macondo so we're actually returning to a higher level. Again by 2014, back end of, we should have sort of brought our Gulf of Mexico production back to where it otherwise would have been if there have been no moratorium. And that's when we should also see the impact of the two new projects, Cardamom and Mars B. They are both doing well, both on track, but I can't really say more about the actual production between now and that time &#x2013; that late 2014.</p>
          <p>NGL pricing, clearly there are volatility in the market at the moment. We are in the process of reversing a pipeline that should help Eagle Ford and Permian production get down to the Gulf rather than going through Cushing, which should help relieve some of the volatility or the bottlenecks. That should be up and running earlier next year. We are also, as a chemicals &#x2013; major chemicals producer on the Gulf Coast, a beneficiary of low NGL prices, as well as a victim of them as a producer.</p>
          <p>So in practice, we're reasonably well hedged against the short term from our viewpoint. But I think structurally there will be logistical changes that will remove some of those short-term anomalies in the market, but it does help to be a consumer as well as a producer of NGL. So I wouldn't like to guesstimate the net impact on Shell, but there is something of a hedge in our portfolio overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very useful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Many thanks. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Iain Reid from Jefferies. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Simon, two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Iain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just before that, did you say earlier that you're losing 50,000 barrels a day due to theft in Nigeria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Straight from the trunk, the pipelines. That's 100% SPDC, we're at 30% of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's on an industrial scale, this there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about 150,000 today in total we believe. And that &#x2013; the 50,000 is only what we can measure down THE trunk lines. The 150,000 is across the whole industry as well, in fact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Amazing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just impossible to measure. And so I think industrial scale is inaccurate. Description, the finance minister in-country has made &#x2013; drawn the obvious conclusion, that's $5 billion to $7 billion a year of theft.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Amazing. Anyway, look, I had two quick questions. Firstly, you talked about the ramp-up of the big three projects. Is it possible to say what sort of cash flow per quarter or per annum we can expect from that at say, current oil price of $100? And secondly, on your write-downs in the U.S., I was surprised that you didn't impair your Western Canada assets, given the fact you paid quite a lot of money for them when gas prices were significantly higher. Was there a reason for that? Are you assuming LNG export pricing in the future do not offset the negatives on domestic pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Iain. First the three big projects, typically quarterly, they've been doing just over $1 billion of cash flow per quarter, and earnings are just under $1 billion. So the aggregate cash flow in nine months is about $4 billion from the three projects. So that's great growth, and obviously there's more to come there. And that is obviously at current oil prices.</p>
          <p>Impairing our West Canada assets, impairments &#x2013; I mentioned $4, are a function of two things: how much you paid for the assets in the first place, and how good the assets are, and I guess also the costs &#x2013; your own development and operational costs. Neither in West Canada nor Marcellus, where we acquired big positions, are we in danger of impairment? No, it's not assuming LNG prices. We would not be able to do that. Of course we look at cash generating units. And in both cases, not only did we make the large headline acquisitions, but we picked up significant amounts of acreage at much lower price.</p>
          <p>The resources in the Groundbirch play alone have doubled relative to the original Duvernay acquisition. We're at 12 Tcf now relative to the 6 Tcf at the original acquisition. So the quality of the assets, the fact that we're producing at low costs, low development cost, great drilling performance, great efficiencies is the reason for no impairment, even carrying the premium that we paid on acquisition. So it's good quality assets, low cost of production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Iain. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Jason Gammel from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Simon, I wanted to ask a question on the LNG business and future strategy. You've done quite a bit this year to increase the optionality that you have in future LNG supply between what you've done in Canada and Australia, and then potentially signing on for U.S. off-take in the future. Can you talk about &#x2013; and I realize that getting optionality gives you the option making decisions in future, but where each of those would rank in your current development queue? And then secondly, how this would affect your appetite for obtaining equity in Mozambique?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Jason. Good questions, very important strategy &#x2013; strategic area. Just refer back to the $2.6 billion in the quarter, integrated gas is not only an area of future growth and value, it is an area of driving today's results. The future strategy, we're working or building 7 million tons of further capacity on top of the 21 that we currently participate in. That's basically all in Australia, and we are investigating over 15 million tons of eventual additional capacity, some of which is in Australia and as you point out, Canada, Indonesia, potentially in the United States on the Gulf Coast are a part of that.</p>
          <p>Difficult to say how they individually rank. Clearly floating LNG we're currently constructing in Korea for Australia looks good, particularly if we could take the cost down the learning curve as we build and learn from the first &#x2013; the number one license plate. So the Indonesia project, although that's operated by INPEX, initially that will be floating. So we'll transfer some of the experience there, so we'll see how that looks. Australia, we have the Arrow project, Browse and Sunrise on the to-do list. The onshore developments in Australia currently do suffer from inflation, as I'm sure you're aware.</p>
          <p>Canada, we are putting together the full value chain from the molecules through to the market with our three Asian partners. We need to secure the pipeline, the LNG opportunity and put the permits together. That's going to take some time to put all of those different elements together, but with the low cost of gas supply and very abundant gas and the very solid partnerships, Canada looks reasonable as well. Gulf Coast depends almost entirely on at what price could you access capacity and ensure that you get the permit. So, I can't give you a ranking, but they're all currently in progress.</p>
          <p>What does that do for Mozambique? Well, Mozambique is clearly a big play, maybe a very big play, but big plays come with big price tags and significant operational challenges. We bid for Cove at a price we were comfortable with. We pulled out because we felt the process would take us to a price we're not comfortable with. I mean you're talking potentially $150 billion or more of investment in that country with &#x2013; given the gas resource, and it's not something that you pay a lot up front or too much up front to get involved in. If you've got that kind of follow-on challenge together with the clearly developing infrastructure with ports, roads, railways, domestic capacity, capability, and consumption. So it looks like a good resource but we're not going to overpay to enter it. Thank you. Move onto the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Kim Fustier from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Kim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just two questions if I may. Firstly on your portfolio strategy going back to North American gas, you've talked about trying to match acquisitions and disposals broadly by geography or asset type. So I can see you've spent $2 billion this quarter buying acreage in the Permian, you've added many other positions in the last 12 months, but I've not really seen any specific announcements on asset disposals recently in North America. So, I was wondering whether you're still very much in acquisition mode, still making net additions to the North American portfolio, and so when you'll start selling positions to effectively high grade the portfolio?</p>
          <p>My second question is on Iraq. There has been some noise recently around Shell not being able to meet its production target at Majnoon by the end of this year. I was hoping you could clarify this point, and perhaps more generally share your thoughts on the key challenges in Iraq such as infrastructure, export capacity, and security?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kim. Good point on Iraq. North American gas, typically what we said before is when Marvin wanted to buy something, we requested he sell something to pay for it. That wasn't necessarily a strategic move to always match geography, the divestments and the acquisitions. Right now, it's a buyer's market for gas, maybe a buyer's market for LRS as well in the right basins, on the grounds that many of the players holding acreage have a bit of a cash flow challenge. We &#x2013; therefore, we're not necessarily a seller either into a soft market.</p>
          <p>What we are in &#x2013; we're focusing the gas assets in Western Canada and Marcellus. We are in the Haynesville and Pinedale. They're clearly from the impairments, the less attractive basins. But probably that means it's not the right time to be selling. We did sell Holstein of course offshore for a nice price in the quarter, but that is &#x2013; colloquially, it's a deepwater activity.</p>
          <p>So, at the moment, we're just looking for the assets that are at the right price in the right basin with the right potential development cost. We're actually in double-digit number of potential liquid basins across North America. Some of these we will not develop, either because we don't see the potential or because somebody &#x2013; it fits somebody else's portfolio better. And that's why we're doing the exploration and appraisal now. But it's looking good in Eagle Ford, in the Permian, the Utica, and the West Canadian basins, Mississippi Lime, one or two of the others maybe not quite so attractive. So, we'll work that portfolio out over time.</p>
          <p>Iraq, we are in three activities in Iraq and in the sense of the general question about developing there, all three fall in the same category. Just quickly, the West Qurna, we're the minority partner with Exxon in their activity on that brownfield development, which is producing revenues, albeit as a minority partner, not significant ones for us at this current time.</p>
          <p>Majnoon is a greenfield development. It is targeted at 175,000 barrels a day for first commercial production. We would expect to achieve that next year, not this year. What we have learned over the past 18 months has been extraordinarily valuable. It has been slower than we might have wished for, but we have been working with the authorities in Baghdad and Basra. We've been working with local communities and very much with Iraqi contractors and suppliers to develop what we think has become a robust way of doing things, robust modus operandi for the country.</p>
          <p>Just as an example, we've been through the cost recovery audit, which is always important in such activities. We've got 99% plus cost acceptance and agreement on the first year of operations there. We are now into the ongoing process of importing equipment after some initial delays and challenges on the way the law was being interpreted. We are drilling; we've got four rigs drilling in Majnoon.</p>
          <p>And on the gas side, the joint venture itself is scheduled to actually it be formally started up next year, early next year, and we're already collecting gas as I mentioned in the speech from some pre-investment that we shall have already done. So we've learned how to operate. We've learned how to work with a wide range of stakeholders. It's just taken us a bit longer than we would originally have wished, but it's now a good platform going forward. So we would hope to see both production in Majnoon and revenues from both Majnoon and South Gas during 2013. So it's some good potential growth for us. Remember we don't get any production volume in the gas activity, but we will get revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hope that gives you a good oversight. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Doug Terreson from ISI. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Simon. My question's on the Downstream and specifically your commentary suggests that the intermediate term outlook for global refining may be challenged and on this point I had a couple of questions. First, given your global perspective, I wanted to see if you could provide more color on some of the global demand trends that you highlighted and that Shell is seeing globally? And then second on Shell specifically, while the Downstream was strong this quarter, the returns on capital have really not improved this year, as has been the case with some of your peers. And so I wanted to see if you could provide an update on the scale and scope of some of the return enhancements that are underway in the Downstream at the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug. Long time, no speak. It's good to hear we've got U.S. listeners on the call. I hope that you're all managing to get through some of the problems of the recent hurricane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The global refining, we still see it as challenged. It's 7 million barrels a day of excess capacity, and we will &#x2013; probably rising to 8 million or even 9 million over the next couple of years, depending on how demand progresses. We see demand for crude oil up maybe by 0.5 million barrels this year, maybe less, against what was a 1 billion to 2 billion barrels a day growth trajectory, on which the basis on new refineries was &#x2013; the investment case. And we see some mismatches and products late as well with much higher demand for diesel than gasoline in quite a few parts of the world.</p>
          <p>So Europe is chronically oversupplied and while the short term, the occasional bankruptcy or maintenance turnaround helps margins, it's not going to get any easier. The U.S. is benefiting obviously at the moment from both shutdowns in the U.S. and elsewhere, for example Venezuela, but also this WTI disconnect from Brent. How long will that last? Well, we don't see demand that strong, particularly on retail at the moment. Overall, always difficult to read the trend. The U.S. industrial and commercial, it seems to be in a better place than Europe. What we don't know is how sustainable that may be. Might &#x2013; perhaps we'll wait until after the election.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The emerging market's doing well, still growing, bit of interregnum in China in the past six months but they &#x2013; that may well come back. But of course refineries are being built so there are still new refineries, many new refineries coming on in the Middle East, in Asia, including China. But we don't actually see it getting any better on average around the world as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Return on capital in Downstream, we &#x2013; still probably below where we might like to be, but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we are improving. The Chemicals is now doing well and we see suggestions that the current &#x2013; the cyclical decline may have bottomed out. And we're still solidly profitable there. The issue is partly the refining base and partly the fact that we carry a great deal more capital in our business than some of our competitors, for example just from FIFO stock accounting. So there are cost improvements, there are ongoing internal process improvements, there are portfolio improvements all in progress, although a lot of the portfolio work is coming to an end, the major moves, that are squeezing out the cents per barrel.</p>
          <p>So there's no real big move, but it's the cents per barrel around costs which have come out and stayed out. There's no &#x2013; the costs are not coming back in Downstream. But we need to be working maybe some of the processes that we have in place with customers and optimizing the value chain around the refineries. They need more work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is more to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, Simon. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Irene Himona from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Simon, I had a couple of questions, please. So firstly in Oil Products, is it possible to say how much came from Brazil from the Raizen JV this quarter, and perhaps what the comparable was last year? And then secondly, if you can give us an update please on plans for Arctic drilling I suppose in the next season now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Irene. The JV, Raizen, doing well, definitely learning to squeeze more out and expand on the capacity that we have. It's around $100 million contribution, slightly better than last year. It's also got obviously the Downstream contribution, the marketing contribution, as well as the ethanol. But so far, very successful collaboration, very well placed. Despite what is actually a difficult ethanol market, a bit distorted by some gasoline subsidies in-country.</p>
          <p>Arctic drilling, just to &#x2013; that's a very important question, just to go back to the context. Our exploration plan, which is multi-year and always was, several years, five exploration wells across Chukchi and Beaufort Seas. We planned originally to drill two of them this year, one in each, and we aim to have those facilities or the capability &#x2013; that's two rigs plus over 20 support vessels in place. We did achieve that, barring one vessel. The vessel that was missing was the containment barge, which is the fourth barrier against a potential blowout and spill incident. A lot of our effort has been projected or targeted avoiding a blowout in the first place.</p>
          <p>But in the event, very unlikely, that that were to happen, the drilling mud, the blowout preventers, dual shear rams, the capping stack would all come into operation, all fully tested, before we would need the containment barge. However, the absence of the containment barge meant that this year we were only able do drill two top holes, and I think I mentioned, down both to 1400 feet. We've pulled off there both of them as of yesterday and the fleet is moving south I think it's fair to say now for the winter.</p>
          <p>We intend obviously next year to go back to those two wells. We would hope to be able to complete the holes into the reservoir. I cannot say any more than that that we would plan. The five well exploration plan remains valid. It is valid for several years. Obviously wells 3 and 4 will depend a little bit on the results of wells 1 and 2. But we are really very well placed. Very positive outcome this year in terms of the regulatory environment, which we now think there's much more clarity on so that we can go forward with more certainty next year, good constructive discussions with the regulators both at the federal of the state level, and we look forward to a positive outcome in 2013. Hopefully that covers the Arctic and thank you for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Lucas Herrmann from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon, hi, afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Lucas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two or three, if I might. I wondered if you might talk a little bit more about the build-out of your tight oil positions. Clearly a lot of capital is going in. What one can't see or that's little transparency on at the moment is the extent to which production has built and is expected to build over the medium term, what are objectives?</p>
          <p>Secondly, just on the Downstream, your fourth quarter historically &#x2013; well, certainly the last three years has been somewhat astray from the performance through the previous three. Are there reasons why we should expect a better performance in the fourth quarter of this year relative to the past? And thirdly, I just wondered if you could comment at all on what's happening with GTL V-Power, the extent to which you're finding you're able to expand market and consequently cement the value from that product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lucas. I'll try and be quick on this. The LRS positions, we'll have invested about $1 billion in development this year including building facilities in Eagle Ford. We should have &#x2013; I mentioned one facility coming online. There's a second facility in the near future. We therefore have around 40,000 barrel a day in Eagle Ford capacity, and we're doing the drilling to start to fill it. We'll be around about 20,000 or so by the end of the year. Added to the Permian and the couple of other basins, that backs the 50,000 barrel a day exit rate in North America. We now have &#x2013; well, we picked up seven rigs in the Permian, so we've now got 29 operating on LRS positions, of which in practice just over half are on development and the other half are on still exploration and appraisal activity.</p>
          <p>We're still aiming, to answer your question I think is the short answer as to what is the appropriate level of development next year. Certainly as we take on new acreage, particularly if it's coming off directly from others, we need to ensure that we're moving to our own standards on safety and operations. And sometimes that puts a slight slowdown on &#x2013; before we can ramp up. But let's see. We start the year at 50,000. Let's hope we can end the year considerably higher. Fourth quarter Downstream, apologies to confirm that you have been right on that over the past couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I was previously wrong, Simon. That's the problem, but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No reason that I'm aware of why the fourth quarter should be particularly difficult this year. We have had good operational performance. We do have some shutdown activity plans in Europe, but that's not necessarily a big hit. I think the one thing we do see in Q4 is it's usually a less volatile trading environment, therefore less likely to make money. I suspect that's because most traders spend the quarter doing things other than trading because they all think they've met their bonus for the year. But that is just a personal insight. So it's a flat quarter for trading rather than a particularly attractive one normally.</p>
          <p>The demand we see is weak everywhere in our major markets. All OECD markets are down. But your first question does point to some mitigation for Shell. Our market share in almost every large market we look at has gone up. Our unit margins are sustained by the V-Power diesel, whether or not it's based on GTL. I would say we're still not fully ramped up in terms of total premium for the GTL product, but we are making steady progress against the parameters we expected, including clean diesel, including base oils for lubricants, and including more specialist chemical products.</p>
          <p>However, we are also growing of course in areas like the U.K. We acquired sites last year. We're growing in Brazilian retail obviously, I mentioned earlier. China, we expect our 1,000th Shell branded site shortly. So we are actually still growing in the marketing, and there's no obvious reason why the fourth quarter should be particularly worse than we've seen in second and third quarters. However, I'll reserve judgment until February.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Simon, one other, by the way, just your license to export oil from the U.S., can you comment on that at all? Intent, hope, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. It's just putting in place the option to do it to the extent we need to do it. It's &#x2013; clearly there is a lot of product export from the U.S. at the moment and there are some mismatches between crude supplies, refining, geographical locations, and in practice we are taking optional positions that we will move product around as and when it's most efficient and effective to do so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Many thanks, Lucas. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Alastair Syme from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Simon, you'll have to excuse my lost voice. Can I come back to your comment on the sensitivities, you talked about the $10 barrel move at the beginning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that some sort of reminder around the $200 billion cash flow framework? I just wanted to clarify that, and sort of what sort of assumptions are built into that framework on those spreads, et cetera you talk about in the U.S.? And I wonder secondly if you could just talk about what level of capital employed was exposed on the write-downs you took in the U.S.? In other words, how much capital is remaining in the Pinedale and Haynesville? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alastair. The comment on sensitivities was more about this year than the next four, be to be honest. It's &#x2013; effectively what I was saying is that the headline from price sensitivity is obviously upwards, but about half of it is being offset by the refining and gas prices that we see. If you look at the full year 2012, 2015 period, then that &#x2013; the half that disappears will be last because we've got effectively lower expectations than for example European gas prices.</p>
          <p>But the full year cash flow generation is based on a $5 gas. So that is one impact, and we'll see where European prices go. We probably don't expect refinery margins where they have been for the last three months but we would expect them better than they were for the previous three, four years on average over the four years. So the comment was mainly about the 2012 performance.</p>
          <p>Capital exposed, relatively low. There's still some capital on the balance sheet but the majority of the &#x2013; we talked about putting $17 billion into acquiring positions in North America and in the past, we've also obviously invested at quite a heavy level but we're also depreciating relatively heavy level. The majority of the investment has in fact been in Western Canada and Pennsylvania. So I can't give you a figure. I don't actually have one, but it's not a &#x2013; it wasn't a huge amount that was exposed and there is a remaining balance. We've not written it all off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just come back to the first part, the target framework, what are you assuming on those Ford forecasts in terms of WTI, Brent, and Western Canadian Crude?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A reversion back more to the mean. Not today's $17 to $20, but certainly the first couple of years we would expect there to be some discount. We do think that there will be logistical solutions. Remember historically WTIs trade at a premium to Brent, not a discount. So it will move in that direction, but I wouldn't want to get into too many moving parts. What we actually deliver in the environment we find ourselves in will be the most important thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Robert Kessler from Tudor Pickering Holt. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your pessimistic view of refining you expressed in no uncertain terms several times today, doesn't exactly present a bullish picture for near-term refining capacity expansions on the Gulf Coast. So it kind of makes me wonder whether you budget any income contribution at all from the Port Arthur expansion, or whether the expansion will bring down the market net to Shell more than the market share increase would benefit Shell. Thoughts on your budget for income contribution there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Robert. I need to be careful about not being too unequivocal, I suspect. The refinery pessimism is global and general. The winners can only be large complex refineries in the right geographical locations, able to process the flexible crude slate and access markets with a level of certainty. And Port Arthur and most of our other refining assets meet that criteria. It is advantaged in terms of the heavy crudes that can be processed.</p>
          <p>It is advantaged in terms of its geographic location, either to trade into our very significant U.S. marketing or for further export back into South America &#x2013; Latin American markets. So we would expect a positive contribution from Motiva overall, not just from Port Arthur, as we go forward. It's big but I'm not sure big enough to move the market in and of itself. But even if it does, the net benefit to us, because we've got the better kit, should be positive. But that's the best I can say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, another quick one for me, on gas trading, you cited there was a positive variance in the quarter. Can you quantify that year-on-year and sequentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. It's not a figure we give out separately. It's difficult to sort of separate it from the underlying LNG. But it's one of a series of factors, and the biggest factor year-on-year really is the GTL in the integrated gas plus the overall LNG volume uptick, which is partly Pluto coming onstream and partly better utilization, for example at Sakhalin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, all right. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Peter Hutton from RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yeah, it's Pete Hutton from RBC. Can you just talk about the Integrated Gas business's record profits this quarter? You mentioned that volumes were up 4%. But could you just sort of give a little bit of background on these sort of near-term medians out, maybe a year out? Given the comments that you're making on the caution in the refining and the downstream and &#x2013; which are generally industry-related, any implications there on LNG, or are you still seeing that as a very robust market in the near term?</p>
          <p>And the second one is more of big picture stuff in terms of the financial framework and the dividend policy. I think you were saying before that you'd look at the dividend when you'd had sort of six solid months running of the new projects. And with Pearl up and coming next quarter and Port Arthur not far away, how close are we now from the clock starting to tick? And when does that translate into the timing of when that dividend review would really get into action?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Many thanks, Peter. Integrated Gas, we're up 4% in volumes. We see a very tight market for the next four to five years out through 2016, 2017 before major new production comes onstream. Thereafter, a lot of new production is actually already spoken for in terms of regas capacity, whether it would be China, Japan, India, or elsewhere. So even for more rest of the decade, it's a reasonably balanced market after the tightness is relaxed a little. Spot market, very robust at the moment and our challenge, if anything, is ensuring we have enough supply to meet that obvious market demand.</p>
          <p>We will have an Investor Day in London on the 14th of November and on the 15th in New York where we'll talk in quite a bit more detail and context of the gas demand framework, particularly in Asia Pacific, on which we are premising the strategy. So hopefully you will be able to follow us in those events, one or the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And dividend policy, the policy is of course to grow in line with earnings and cash flow through cycle sustainably. That's what investors tell us they like, and to do that in measured, affordable steps. We increase the dividend back in February, first time in three years, as we are able to demonstrate the cash flow growth. We've now, as you rightly point out, we're seeing further quarters of underlying cash flow growth of $36 billion in nine months. Just remember back in 2009 when we froze the dividend, that baseline for cash flow was $24 billion. So in nine months, we're 50% higher than we were only three years ago. I know there's an oil and gas price effect in there, but there's substantive underlying growth in the cash flow.</p>
          <p>We won't be jumping into quarterly or unexpected dividend announcements. We of course will need to be looking at this as we go into next year because by then, hopefully we will have seen the underlying sustainable performance from the big projects. So my own logic takes me to having to consider a dividend increase next year. But we're seeing good progress on the underlying metrics we made that affordable and in line with the strategy and the policy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Many thanks, Peter. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Hootan Yazhari from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, Simon, just a quick question regarding your realizations in the U.S., the North American onshore business. You've alluded to weakness in price realizations. Capacity is ramping up throughout the country. I just wanted to think how much the Downstream side is now factoring into your future plans, not just obviously refining but things like expanding chemicals capacity, expanding GTL capacity, cracker capacity, et cetera, to be able to really benefit from the massive amounts of CapEx you're putting in the Upstream to grow the onshore business in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, good question. In the short term, the main Downstream investment is actually in LNG into transport. So we're looking at &#x2013; we're already investing in Canada and looking at U.S. both with Travel Centers and in say the trucking market, but also shipping market in the Great Lakes and on the Gulf Coast. The &#x2013; we will &#x2013; or I should say we are looking at almost all the opportunities you just suggested. Gas to chemicals, particularly in Pennsylvania area, we are looking at ethane supply.</p>
          <p>And some of it's not just the chemicals, it requires aggregation of supply and the treatment there. So, there are some strategic control points we need to consider, where they might be and whether we can make the overall value chain work into an area where we do see something of a resurgence of the chemicals and manufacturing industry is possible on the basis of relatively low cost feedstock and energy.</p>
          <p>The gas to liquids, we are &#x2013; I think is known, we are looking at opportunities on the Gulf Coast. It will take some time to run this through feasibility, design, and we're several years away from any investment decision. But at this point in time, both the chemicals and the gas to liquids look feasible. And you're right that in the long term structurally, there is a value opportunity there for companies that can go through the full value chain and actually turn gas molecules into either liquids or chemicals price exposure.</p>
          <p>That's what we're looking to do. It will be &#x2013; as I say in both cases, probably several years before we can get to an investment decision and significant capital will be involved. So we may need to look at some phasing of the investment as well. But overall it actually looks quite attractive at the moment for a long-term investment, so thank you for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Bertrand Hod&#xE9;e from Raymond James. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi, Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bertrand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One follow-up, in Australia, among your very big list of projects under study: Arrow, Browse, Sunrise, Pluto 2, or even Gorgon expansion, when do you think you will get a new FID? And on which project do you think is closest to FID, and when do you think this could happen, 2013, 2014? Can you give us an update on those projects or your status?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Unfortunately, I can give you an update on the status but I can't answer the question as to when we expect a new FID. We're not actually the operator in several of those areas so for Browse or Gorgon Train 4, we're not the operator. So, the ones that we are operator, Arrow essentially is the prime one. We are already in feed, but Australia overall is subject to cost inflation. You only make money in LNG if you get your capital costs in the right place and have access to premium markets. While we know we can get into the markets, we need to make sure that the costs are in the right place.</p>
          <p>And in addition to the ones that you raise, we're also in Indonesia in Abadi floating LNG, which could have certainly attractive potential, and the Sakhalin project expansion to the third train there would also look to be attractive. So we're balancing all of these and maybe &#x2013; we don't want to max out on any one country exposure as well. So it is important that we don't rush ahead of ourselves just to meet any notional target, so I can't give you a date for any investment decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Colin Smith from VTB Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, Simon. Can we go back to Nigeria? You've obviously warned about problems with production in the fourth quarter, but your numbers have held up pretty robustly through the course of the year. And I just wondered if you could give us a view as to whether the problems you're seeing now are just a blip or whether they're a presage of something a bit more serious? And could you also comment on where you think things are with the PIB and how you are thinking about further investments in Nigeria? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Colin, good question. Not an easy one to answer. At the moment, the issue is more floods, which essentially is more of a humanitarian issue than a long-term sabotage. So, hopefully, we'll be able to get back running there. Now the theft, the industrial scale theft and the associated spillage is structural, endemic, and there is a limit to what a commercial energy company can do in these circumstances. Production's holding up well there, primarily because of gas. We are effectively a major gas producer and a lot of it's going into NLNG. It's more difficult to steal gas of course.</p>
          <p>Our offshore activity remains operating well, but we've not taken any sort of major investment decisions there. We're just trying to keep facilities full, with the main reason being the PIB being in progress. Now it has been in progress since 2008, so we need to put any comment in that context. The government and the president currently are very committed to relief. It's our view and we've &#x2013; I think we've made this public, that the bill &#x2013; the latest draft that we've seen, although it does change on quite a regular basis, is that offshore and onshore gas development would be severely comprised by the bill. They just would not be economic.</p>
          <p>Onshore oil looks &#x2013; because it's already taxed at 85% anyway, is probably less impacted. But the onshore gas development and anything offshore looks very challenged. So, we would hope that there will be perhaps a more pragmatic outcome. And I think not just Shell but the whole industry has being delaying or deferring investment decisions, waiting for a bit more certainty. But it is, as you're probably aware, having followed us for a few years, Colin, that we always talk about we're not quite sure what will happen next in Nigeria. And I'm afraid we're not in much of a better position at the moment. Our current business operates, to the extent it can, very well, very responsibly, and in a very professional manner in what can be quite difficult circumstances. So, we're very proud of what people are able to achieve there, and their operational and safety record is exemplary.</p>
          <p>Now probably worth saying as well just while I'm on the subject, our current investments are actually limited to some onshore gas and infrastructure investments, which are helping take the flares out. We're already less than 20% of total flaring in Nigeria. And the current investments that we're putting in should help reduce that figure even further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, many thanks. I think we're out of questions now. Many thanks for listening today. Thank you very much for all your questions. Just repeat what I said, we are planning to host shareholder engagements which will focus on the global gas, both market and our overall strategy, but specifically looking at Asia Pacific in London on the 14th of November and in New York on the 15th of November. And I hope that some of you will be able to join us for one or other of those events. The fourth quarter results will be released on the 31st of January, 2013 of course. Peter [Voser] and I will both be available to talk to you then. I look forward to that opportunity, and wish you all safe and successful conclusion to 2012. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes the Royal Dutch Shell Q3 results announcement call. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>