<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1136858" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>44094</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Peter Voser, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">John Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="3">Peter Voser</participant>
      <participant id="4">Edward Westlake</participant>
      <participant id="5">Mark Iannotti</participant>
      <participant id="6">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="7">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="8">Colin Smith</participant>
      <participant id="9">Joseph Tovey</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jason Kenney</participant>
      <participant id="11">Neil McMahon</participant>
      <participant id="12">David Cline</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Royal Dutch Shell Q1 Results Announcement Call. There will be a presentation followed by Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would like to introduce our host speaker Mr. Peter Voser.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, operator. Good afternoon, everybody. Welcome to the RDS first quarter 2008 conference call. Let me review the results of Shell and some portfolio activities in the quarter and then take your questions. As usual first, would you please take a moment to read the cautionary statement.</p>
          <p>Let me start with strategy, I think you will all be familiar with how we see industrial landscape and the strategy that we are following. As you know, our industry is going through fundamental changes, robust demand, higher prices, new competitors, increased project complexity and challenges around climate change. We continue to rejuvenate our portfolio through improved operating performance, asset sales and investment in long life growth projects, which will create new hard lines for Shell.</p>
          <p>We generated competitive profits in the first quarter of this year. But this only tells part of the story. These profits are being reinvested in the new energy capacity that we need to grow our company and reinvestments to play Shell's part in ensuring that global energy markets remain well supplied. We are planning for net spending of some 26 to $27 billion in '08, which is the largest spending program in the industry today.</p>
          <p>This will add about a million barrels per day to upstream capacity, some 300,000 barrels per day to downstream. And of course, payout remains competitive during the first quarter. We returned 3.4 billion of cash to shareholders. We delivered another set of competitive results in Q1 '08. CCS earnings were $7.9 billion; we saw an improved operating performance compared to the first quarter '07 with improved volumes and operating rates both upstream and downstream.</p>
          <p>We are delivering on our asset sales program and adding new acreage positioned for future exploration. I would say our strategy is on track with competitive cash generation and strong capital discipline. Oil prices are continuing to reach new highs in 2008. Average oil prices increased by 68% versus Q1 '07 driven by robust demand, market uncertainties and supply growth, and we think by investment activities linked to the weak dollar and the credit crisis.</p>
          <p>However, industry refining and chemicals margins declined in all regions quarter-on-quarter due to limited transfer of oil prices into product prices. US refining margins saw the sharpest declines where industry gasoline inventories were relatively high. Relative to Q1 2008, industry refining margins have improved in the first weeks of April, while the industry cracker margins increased slightly but remain under pressure.</p>
          <p>CCS earnings per share increased by some 22% compared to Q1 '07. Cash flow from operations excluding working capital movements were $14.1 billion. And on a cash flow per share basis, that is an increase of 23% from Q1 '07. Dividend increased by 11% to $0.40 per share and share buyback for the quarter was $1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Let me talk about the business performance in more detail. Firstly, on upstream. Underlying quarter-on-quarter oil and gas volumes increased by 1%. Volumes were supported by stronger European gas demand combined with growth from Ormen Lange, gas in Norway, West Salym in Russia and other smaller ramp-ups. In the first quarter of this year, Ormen Lange produced 200,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day from just three wells, of which 34,000 is Shell's share. Buildup at Ormen Lange continues. E&amp;P earnings increased by 58% to 5.2 billion quarter-on-quarter, underpinned by strong prices.</p>
          <p>Shell's oil and gas realizations remain competitive compared to industry market prices. However, there are pressures industry wide from operating costs and tax. These trends continue into second quarter '08. Gas and power earnings were around $1 billion, an increase of 26% compared to the same quarter last year. Earnings were positively impacted by LNG prices and volumes. LNG volumes increased by 6% Q-on-Q, driven by improved feed gas availability and continued strong operational performance.</p>
          <p>LNG cargo diversions in the Shell marketing portfolio increased from year ago levels with attractive prices and demand especially in Asia-Pacific. Marketing and trading conditions for non-energy activities in gas and power remained broadly similar to year ago levels.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to oil sands. Earnings increased 117%, Q-on-Q to $249 million. Underlying bitumen production declined versus year ago levels with an earnings offset from higher prices. We had an unplanned shutdown at the mine and upgrader in Q4 '07, and operations restarted during January.</p>
          <p>In addition first quarter production at the mine was impacted by the extreme cold weather, which was cold even by Alberta standards. So far in Q2 '08, mining and upgrader performance has been satisfactory. We have maintenance scheduled for May, so we expect that Q2 '08 production will be slightly lower than Q2 '07.</p>
          <p>Let me turn to downstream. Downstream earnings decreased from a year ago levels. Between the three refining margins led to a reduction of oil product earnings. At Shell refining earnings were around 10% of the oil products total in the first quarter of this year, compared to around 14% in the same quarter last year. The reduction in refining earnings were &#x2013; was partially offset by improved margins in retail and B2B activities as well as an increased trading contribution.</p>
          <p>Marketing volumes increased by 2% excluding disposal effects, which reflect Shell's strong customer offering and portfolio position. Refining availability in Q '08 was 92% compared to 85% year ago levels. Refining availability in Q2 '08 is expected to be at similar levels to Q2 '07, when availability was some 92%. Chemicals earnings were impacted by pressure from rising feedstock costs especially in the United States. Chemicals availability Q1 '08 was 95%, and we expect that availability in Q2 will be similar to year ago levels.</p>
          <p>Let me update you on cash, generation at Shell and cash usage on a 12-month rolling basis. Both the upstream and the downstream segments continue to generate cash flows above the capital requirements. At the Group level, operating cash inflow plus asset sales over the last year was around $53 billion including $10 billion from asset sales. Over the same period, we invested some 43 billion in CapEx acquisitions and payout to shareholders. We do expect inflationary pressure on CapEx and OpEx to continue in the industry and perhaps to step up given the increase in oil prices that we are seeing.</p>
          <p>Shell is not immune from that. And we could certainly see those impacts on our new projects. However, we do have some contingencies built in to our planning, so we are on track for the 26, $27 billion of net capital spending for '08, as we told you at our Strategy Update in March a few weeks ago.</p>
          <p>Let me turn to portfolio. As I have said before, our disposal program is part of our strategy to use strong capital discipline to rejuvenate the company. The company did around 10 billion of asset sales last year, and we plan to sell a further 4 billion of assets in '08. We made progress both upstream and downstream with disposal proceeds of 0.5 billion in the first quarter of 2008 further deals are on the way.</p>
          <p>During the quarter we announced the disposal of producing oil and gas assets in Australia and Nigeria for some $0.9 billion. We expect these transactions to close in '08 as part of a disposals -- of a disposal plan -- sorry -- to sell some 50,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day from current production. At the end of the quarter, we completed the disposal of our French refineries for some $1.8 billion. These French assets in total were in loss over the last two years and lost some 65 million in the first quarter '08.</p>
          <p>Turning to the new portfolio, we have added important acreage positions in North America, where we were awarded blocks offshore Alaska in Chukchi Sea. So together with leases in the Gulf of Mexico, we will add around 6,500 square kilometers of acreage in the United States. Early April, we signed long-term agreements for LNG supply from Qatargas 4 to customers in China and in Dubai. And we launched two new upstream projects in Australian Gas and at Gumusut-Kakap in deepwater Malaysia, which we updated you on with the fourth quarter result. In Australia Shell has 22% in the new North Rankin 2 project. This will produce from low pressure gas reservoirs to maintain supplies into the North West Shelf LNG project, and the start up here is expected to be around 2013.</p>
          <p>So let me recap quickly, I think we have delivered another strong set of results in Q1 '08, driven by operating performance. We have made good progress with the portfolio, and our strategy is on track &#x2013; operational excellence, competitive cash flow and capital discipline.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me stop here and call for your questions. Operator can you take questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from John Rigby of UBS. Please go ahead with your question</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, hello Peter. Two questions. The first is on gas and power, can you just give a bit more visibility on the movement year-to-year. What is volume and price in your, sort of, core LNG business, and what is the increasing diversion activity that you see in your business? I mean I don't expect you to be too detailed but if you give me some kind of idea of the various contributions from those two. And I guess those are the reasons why the earnings are up. And the second is, I guess, this is in your domain completely, how are you able to release $2.8 billion of working capital in a quarter when the oil price has gone up so much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, John. On the GP movement, the M&amp;T was flat and just remember that our LNG diversion business we show as part of our LNG results in that sense. Volumes were up 6%. I think the prices you have in the Q or A, we give you there the details including the JCC et cetera. From a diversion point of view, typically we have got 55 to 65 LNG cargoes a quarter, of which roughly 10 to 15% we have as diversions. There is some seasonality in that, obviously as well, and then you have plant shutdowns et cetera, which normally take place more in the second or third quarter. So from that point view you get some seasonality, but first quarter on the diversion quite clearly was beneficial. On the working capital, I think, was your next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I look at accounts receivables and accounts payable, they more or less went up the same amount. So you have to move upward for the higher prices, but we also got the accounts payable credits to that, so because they have increased because of prices. These items largely offset in working capital therefore in the first quarter. Inventories are largely flat, with lower inventory volumes being largely offset by the impact of higher prices on the value of inventory. So I think that's where your movement comes in when you look at -- if you compare the two quarters and than you look at the increasing oil price. So we are looking at a different inventory level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Is that, would that be related to your trading activities or would it be just seasonal or just in relation to your normal course of activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It is actually much more gas and power and the normal oil products business and chemicals business. So it is not related in that sense in major part to trading. There is certainly a small trading effect in it as well, but not too much. So it is actually the normal business. In gas and power for example, it was rather high stocks in Q4 in Europe and in the United States, which we now consumed in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, lovely. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Edward Westlake of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Two questions, one on the downstream. You've highlighted the contribution which marketing B2B businesses and trading make in Q1. At this point is it possible to talk about the outlook for Q2 given that we've another lurch upward in the oil price? And then the second question just specifically, Brazil is obviously still quite exciting. I think you have some exposure there in the presalt in terms of stuff that's drilling BMS-8. Is there any update? Thanks. Brazil, generally and BMS-8. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks Edward. First question on the, let me start with refining. The first few weeks in April, refining has been a little bit up in that sense, not huge but it has been firm in that sense. I would also like to say that the trading results, if I take the two quarters, Q1 '07, Q1 '08, in general was up but it was not up by a huge margin in that sense. And if I talk about marketing business, which is kind, behind your question, quite clearly the B2B business, lubricant, aviation, bitumen, et cetera, were particularly strong, but also retail was delivering quite a bit despite the fact that we have much higher oil prices. Now how this all will result into demand going forward, that's a little bit too early to say because you have seen we have had higher demand in Q1 compared to last year, but we also have seen some, let's say, pressure on the refinery margins which normally means that the market is well supplied and you get some cost pressure from the market back into the value chain, which could actually highlight that there are demand question marks at least. So I think it's a little bit too early to say. I think we are well positioned as a company with the diverse portfolio, global portfolio, but I think we will see in Q2 how the demand actually will come.</p>
          <p>On Brazil, let me just take you through. Shell has got interest in 10 blocks in the Campos what do you call this, Spiritu Santo and the Santos basin, has been active in deepwater EP in Brazil for quite a few years. And currently, in the Campos Basin we have approximately 23,000 barrels of production, and we are currently developing BC-10, as you know, and there will, there where we will have a platform with production capacity of 100,000 barrels of oil. There is obviously more exploration development potential there for Shell. In the Santos Basin, I guess that's where your question goes, we have interest in five blocks which is BMS 8, BMS 43, BMS 29, I think, and then 54 and 45, with total acreage of 6,000 square kilometers. We are involved in a well in the Santos, which is operated by Petrobras, no update at this stage. The operator needs to do that. We will comment further on when we have the result. We think there is sub-salt potentially our acreage, but it is too early days for exploration, and there is nothing at this stage which I can update you, but well on our portfolio map and quite a few prospects, which we are looking in to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you our next question comes from Mark Iannotti of Merrill lynch. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Couple of questions. First of all, Peter, on CapEx, I see your first quarter CapEx running 8.1 billion, and I suggest that run rate its a little bit ahead of your guidance on organic CapEx. Is that just phasing or are you already seeing some pressure on CapEx as you start the year? And secondly, with the highest quarter for volumes out of the way, can you give us some guidance on full-year volumes, say assuming a hundred-dollar oil price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay. Thanks, Mark. On the first one, I think you need to take into account that we have got $2.1 billion of Chukchi Sea in there. So that brings you back to six, and if you take a six and measure it against our gross CapEx number, then I guess if you calculate it, you will come to 20% spending which is in line with our historical performance in that sense. And we have said that the 26, 27 billion that includes the Chukchi Sea, because we have increased that from our earlier guidance in that sense. Regarding volume, in Q1 the underlying volumes, as I said, increased by 1%. We saw the negative impact of PSC, which is around 37,000 barrels. Disposal and decline and a slight year-on-year improvement in Nigeria, and we had some benefit from the colder weather, which was a normal quarter in my opinion, compared to a very warm one last year, and the positive impact from new production at Ormen Lange, Deimos and Changbei.</p>
          <p>We did give you the indication that if '07 conditions <mark type="inaudible" /> Nigeria oil price repeat in '08 and if you include 50,000 barrels a day of announced asset sales, then you should expect a slight decline in '07, '08. Not intending to update on the outlook every quarter, because I think the moving parts are just too too big. The oil price in '07 was $70, so keep that in mind. And the Nigeria shut-in was an average of 186,000 barrels in '07 and the weather was rather warm. So for Q1 we were up a bit on Nigeria in weather related demand and down a bit. on oil price effect, but we are not getting into a quarter-by-quarter update. So no precise guidance. What remains unchanged is the 2 to 3% growth for next year. But I think we had a good quarter. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Irene Himona of BNP Paribas. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Peter. I had just one question on your depreciation charge, which surprised me perhaps declined in the quarter. Wonder if you can give us guidance on the full year, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks for the question. If I go back to DD&amp;A per barrel, our boe increased from 7.4 in '06 to 8 '07, and you can find at 20-F. This is as you would expect as you bring on new projects, where the early years bookings are low relative to the total potential of the fields. Now Q1-Q! DD&amp;A did decline, and that relates really to reserves bookings from fields that were on stream at the end of '07, most in the US and the UK. Now there are some other small one-time positive effects as results of asset sales but not that major. So we would expect some ups and downs in the DD&amp;A quarter by quarter as a result of production mix and new startups. And overall, there is an increasing trend despite of Q1 now in unit DD&amp;A as we saw from '06 to '07, so I wouldn't read too much into the reduction in Q1. I think with long-term we still see an increasing trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mark Gilman of Benchmark. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, good morning. Wonder if you could provide a little clarity on a subject that you talked about briefly in the strategy presentation. Namely, contract expirations and rollovers in the LNG business. Can you give us any sense at all in terms of timing, volumes and how that's likely to play out over the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks Mark. I think I will not give you kind of very detailed timings or volumes. But let me just take you through how this actually -- how this works. So, almost all contracts have price to yield clauses that provide the opportunity every few years to renegotiate the price, should the go to market price be considerably different than those in the contract. It is expected that the LNG vendor will pursue these opportunities as they present themselves, and this should provide upside for companies like ourselves, where we have considerable exposure in particular to Asia Pacific LNG prices. So we expect the impact on the overall Shell portfolio to happen slowly, so as contracts are up for discussion at various times in the coming years. So will have that result for quite a few years, but it will not be as bulky as you might think. This really comes in a slowish kind of pace. But they can be quite sizable from a monetary point of view. We are also at this stage in negotiations on contract. We have already done a few, where we have pushed higher prices in to Japan or in to Korea and then we have also just signed contracts to Dubai and new ones now and to China, which obviously reflect the higher prices. So we are pleased with the progress there. But I cannot give you year-by-year on the volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one other follow-up if I could, Peter. I note in the release the change in the accounting per the Alberta royalty situation. Give us an idea, if you could, under whatever price scenario you want to use, when Athabasca will achieve royalty payout going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That depends on many things obviously, so it's difficult to forecast that. But let me just make sure that we all also understand about the kind of significance of the amount, so the Q-on-Q effect of this change on the royalty was $34 million after tax. So the royalty rate for the project therefore will be revised back to 1% from the 25% since July '07 until achievement of the project cost payout, which can vary depending on production et cetera, et cetera, so as a consequence the adjustment related to prior quarters bitumen production has an impact of some 12,000 barrels per day on the first quarter 2008, and as I said the Q-on-Q effect was $34 million, but we will update you over time on this one as we go forward, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Colin Smith of Dresdner Kleinwort. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Jeroen and Peter. Just a follow-up on the oil sands performance, because it looks awfully strong if you're talking just about a 34 million year-on-year impact. Is the 12,000 barrels a day an incremental piece of that or can you just talk us through how we get from 115 or perhaps more interestingly, 82 in 4Q to 214 then in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We had a good quarter in that sense. And I think it depends if you talk about growth or net production in that sense. But the net production was actually 12,000 down because of these changes. So it was really driven by the higher prices. Slightly offset obviously by we had a few days, not the full production but it was mainly a price differential because if I look at operating costs, actually they were quite comparable in that sense with some exchange rate effects et cetera. So from that point of view, I think a good quarter. And as we always said, this is full price upside to us, and obviously, the oil price then, you really start to see it in our accounts. So nothing else special in it apart from the 34 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Colin. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes good afternoon gentlemen. Maybe a small follow-up on the oil sands question; when do you expect on the current taxation scheme project cost payout? And do the extensions, the expansion, also account for deductions for the roads. And the second question is on your arrangement for shipping gasoline from Rotterdam to the US. Of course we all know that Europe is short on diesel and low on gasoline, but in view of the volatile prices in the US and the obvious transport costs, could you give little color on how these deals, how these arrangements, these long term, can you tell us about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think if I understood the first one, you were asking about payout, et cetera, or average costs, I don't know exactly, but if I look at the original kind of investment which we had, which is now running for a few years, you can imagine that the payout there has already been achieved in the sense because we have the very high oil prices. Now going forward, regarding your royalty point, which I heard out of your question as well, certain parts of the expansion one, we were able to actually view with the authorities and that some of them back into the royalty arrangements for the original construction, and hence we do benefit there from a different royalty regime. How the new royalty regime then will influence later expansions and how that will drive average kind of breakeven oil prices, we will see once we are getting to those. I think in general you can say that Athabasca is not immune on worldwide cost pressure, and hence that also see some pressures in terms of costs quite clearly either for current projects or future projects. On the gasoline side or in general exports from Europe to the United States, these are normally, as far as I know, they are spot driven, so spot cargo driven, they are normally not long-term. We do take full advantage of the differentials in the pricing. I wouldn't say at current oil prices that the shipping cost is a major component in it. Is it really driven by the differential of the various products et cetera. So I think, I will double check, but in general these are mainly spot driven rather than contractually long-term driven. Thank you, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Joseph Tovey of Tovey &amp; Co. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Joe Tovey. Couple of questions if I might. Was the change in the availability of the refineries, a function of also a change in the type of products required or are those simply operational matters that got sorted out? One question. Second question, I was wondering as to whether in view of what the strength of other currencies relative to the US dollar, was that picked up in the margins or has that offset the pressures of lower demand to some extent in Europe? I noticed that the chemical volumes seemed to be down a bit. I assume that's a function of the business cycle or what appears to be some cyclical matter. But I was wondering if you would care to clarify that a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On your first question, these were operational matters, to go back to Q1 '07, we had a quarter with quite a large downtime, so shutdowns, and hence the 7% increase this quarter because we had a little bit less, but still it was quite a heavy downtime quarter. I think on the exchange rate, typically, the guidance we give is for 10% US dollar-euro kind of exchange rate variance. You're talking roughly around 150 to $200 million per quarter on our OpEx line for example. So typically when you run a business in Europe and you have Europe costs when you translate into dollars, it's the 10%, it's roughly 150 to 200. On the capital expenditure side, and so hence it gives you a certain pressure on the margin if your revenue price is dominated in dollars rather than in euros. Certainly that has also affected chemicals. It goes into the same chapter. On CapEx, I can give you as well, it's not margin, but it's also interesting that there a 10% move on an annual basis would result roughly in $0.5 billion higher CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" /> from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Peter. Just a couple of questions, actually. Just on Nigeria, could you just confirm what production is down, Shell share, in Nigeria at the moment after recent disruptions? And perhaps you could give a little bit more color on -- whether there has been any progress in terms of negotiations with the government in terms of financing? And secondly, I think it's been touched on earlier in the Q&amp;A, but I just wanted to ask if you could provide any comments in terms of the market conditions that we're seeing in Q2 in the LNG business for diverted cargoes? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I take just the first two. You may have to repeat the last one. The first one was as per today there are 164,000-barrels shut in. On average in Q1, we were 156. So the incidents of the last few days have added a few barrels. This is mainly security driven, obviously, and I think you have to distinguish between the west and the east. In the west, we're moving back in. That works better than we are at in barrels. In the east, quite clearly we have seen an uptick in issues, and from that point of view, we are losing or we have lost some production there. So we will have to see how this goes forward. This is not a Shell-only issue, Chevron has also as an operator has the same. And on top if it you have, obviously, the Exxon issue, which is an industrial action strike, which has taken more than 700,000 barrels out of the market as well. So I think for us, comparing today to the quarter Q1, it is more or less the same but with some more uncertainty in the east.</p>
          <p>Funding, we are progressing. We are positive on the progress. After the meeting between our Chief Executive and President, we have a kind of solution to work on with our partners, the Nigerian partners, and we're working our way through. So I am positive there that we are going to reach an agreement. And I think the third one was regarding energy volumes, the outlook in Q2, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, typically, second quarter is lower than Q1. This is many times driven and also this quarter by planned maintenance. It is too soon therefore to say how many diversions we can do in Q2, so we need to see how all of this comes together. But as I said earlier in the call, typically you're looking at 10 to 15% of total diversions a quarter and normally those with maintenance and shutdowns, you're most probably at the lower end of the number. Okay. Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Jason Kenney of ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Peter. Just quite a simple question. Why were US gas realizations as strong as they were?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the question. I think that's a demand and supply question in the United States. We also had, I think, a pipeline coming out of the Rockies with gas, which gave us some benefits, which lifted our realized prices, and that has given us a boost in the first quarter. But quite clearly, this is coming out of our Pinedale production in the United States and the rest I would just say is supply and demand driven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So there is nothing to do with the stocks of gas you were mentioning earlier in the Q4 period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that was more a remark on the trading side, which may have a slight effect, but not that much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Neil McMahon of Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just two questions. Back to LNG, again I'm afraid. Peter, could you give us a bit more guidance and clarity on some of the recent contracts with China? I know these are obviously lined into confidentiality agreements, but I -- maybe some guidance as to, in I think it was in 2000, 2001 your historical contracts with Sakhalin to China and places like that were using very much the old contract terms for LNG, and therefore, very much a discounted gas price versus spot rates. Maybe if you could just give us some guidance as to what these new contracts are, if they are very much linked more on a Btu basis with oil prices? Then I've got a follow-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think, first of all, we can say that the contract which we are doing now, we are pleased that we now go with long-term contracts into China. You saw one which we have done out of Australia. Now, we are seeing one out of Qatar. They are following international prices. They normally give us, therefore, international prices at this stage, and therefore, give us in the long-term, let's say, higher international price possibilities. I think that's more or less what I can say at this stage.</p>
          <p>The market is raw to tight. There are not too many FIDs have been taken and there are quite a few in the pipeline, but they are not yet at the stage where you can take FIDs. I think that has fundamentally driven the supply and demand picture across the world, but also across Asia-Pacific and has brought China into let's say the wider discussion of accepting international prices and these contracts. So I think, most of or all of these new contracts are following the same pattern and are normally oil price linked.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And my second question on LNG is something I know you've concentrated on a lot in the LNG strategy is focusing on Iberia. And from the well conditions and reservoir levels there it looks like Iberia is in a reasonably tough spot this year, as it was in 2005 in terms of needing hydroelectric power and something to offset that. Is that an area you're focusing on again with LNG going into the second and third quarters of this year? And how does the strategy set up to provide for Europe in such conditions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, obviously, we have, I have already said we have a diversion policy where we go with more, or strategy, where we go with the cargos to those areas where the prices are actually the highest, and the margin expectation is the highest. It also depends a little bit on regasification capacity, where you can land these energy cargoes.</p>
          <p>What the status you're describing in Spain is the correct one. So, I think Spain is certainly on the map in that sense. But I have to say, for example, in Q1 we didn't have any energy going in to the United States because Asia-Pacific was just much more attractive to us. So, I think we will see how Europeans are positioned to pay the prices. Otherwise, I think there is sufficient demand in Asia-Pacific, but we'll see that in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just one last quick one. You're running $14 billion in cash and cash equivalents, which continues to rise. Given the fact we continue to see strong oil and commodity prices, is there any change in terms of your financial management coming over the next few quarters in terms of dividend policy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we have done on the dividend side, we had kind of 13, 14% increase, last year we have done 11%. We have had this dividend policy, so which means more than dividends for decades, irrespective of the oil price, and I think we are paying a competitive dividend in that sense. So this will quite clearly continue that we are looking there to be in the competitive range.</p>
          <p>We are spending, we have the highest industry spending program. We have made no doubt out of the fact that we think long term we should grow organically. Yes, the oil price is high, and hence I would characterize the current situation as being at the lowest end in terms of gearing. If I look at my oil price cycle, would have hoped to be higher, but with 100, $120 a barrel, it's quite difficult.</p>
          <p>Now, we have enough opportunities to invest, but I've also made it clear if current market conditions are right, then we can further look at how to optimize the shareholder yield, and that could be buybacks, could be more dividends, et cetera. I leave that flexibility in and we'll see what the next few quarters will bring in terms of oil price, in terms of costs, in terms of opportunities from an organic growth point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Just one follow-up question from Jason Kenney. I was also surprised at the strength of your European gas realization at $9. I wonder whether that was simply a function of your normal contractual links to oil and oil products, or whether the ramp up of Ormen Lange, with its greater commercial flexibility, has given an added boost to that realization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think Ormen Lange quite clearly has given us more commercial flexibility and you see that. And I said earlier also that from a gas point of view, we were long in inventories and have used that in Q1 as well. So we -- commercially, we are well positioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from David Cline of ABN AMRO. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just a quick question on the PSC sensitivity. You indicated 37,000 barrels a day in the quarter, but I just wonder how the PSC effect works as we move into these higher oil prices, above $100 a barrel. Can you give some guidance on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have, I think, 2 to 4,000 barrels per dollar. Maybe at the lower end, the higher you get, the Q1, I have already said, I think it's too soon to really have a trend in the longer term. But we are looking roughly at 15% of our volume is PSC driven and that's where you have to apply 2 to 4,000 barrels a day, which then resulted into what I said for Q1. So which way you can see that it was actually not at the higher end of that range it was at the lower end of that range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question is a follow-up question from Mark Gilman from Benchmark. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, the performance of the US Chemicals unit really for quite some time, not just the first quarter has bordered I think on being unsatisfactory. Is there any action plan that is currently being formulated to deal with what appears to be a competitively weak performance of this asset base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Mark. Yeah, indeed we had a few quarters now where, I think, we paid the price. At the end of the day it should be actually liquids-driven in our cracker unit rather than actually ethane-driven as the gas and the oil prices have developed in a different way. So from that point of view, I think there was market circumstances.</p>
          <p>The overall performance from an operational point of view was okay. So from that point of view I think we operated in the right way. Now U.S. petrochemicals market as you know is the largest in the world. And we want to continue to participate in the market. So we want to strengthen our oil lines in that sense, and we have made no doubt that the U.S. for us in that sense is important. We are obviously constantly improving the asset reliability, leveraging even further the oil chemicals advantage; and continue to focus on cost competitiveness. There is quite clearly a plan in place where we look at all of this, also reviewed on a regular basis by Rob Rout and he is driving that, which is a kind of chemicals master plan for the U.S.</p>
          <p>So you can be rest assured it's on the agenda and we are looking at it. But there is a clear, kind of, disadvantage given the way we are structured from an operational units point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, if I could, the corporate category just continues to perplex, and at least from an outsider's perspective, and this quarter was no exception.  And it seems as if we continue to see net positives on an adjusted basis in this category despite your guidance, that I think, a normal quarter would represent net charges of in the neighborhood of $100 million. Update us on your thinking in terms where this category is likely to fall over the balance of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks Mark. It is obviously a difficult basket that one, that's quite clear. But I think I have changed last year already the guidance in that sense that I say it's plus, minus 150, because taxation which is in there and our insurance business can have positive and negatives depending if you have got claims, yes or no, how much disposals you are doing et cetera, et cetera. So I need to have that variance, and the plus, minus 150 is excluding exchange rate effects. Because our Group's central cash management also sits in there.</p>
          <p>So we are obviously trying to manage this as closely as possible and as positive as possible and we have done, I think, a reasonable job over the last few years time in driving this in the right way. But I cannot or I will not change the guidance because if we have got some major claims on the insurance side, this can go negative. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank, Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question or it's the last question, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our last question is a follow-up question from Jason Kenney from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Peter, me again. Just wanted to know the contribution of gas to liquids in the gas and power result. You do mention that it reflected strong gas to liquids product prices, and maybe while you're talking about GTL, just an update on the Pearl if at all possible, how complete are you and whyfore and wherefore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now, the first one is very small because you're talking about 14,000 barrels a day. But it is working very well, has a very high reliability and availability. That's why we are highlighting it, so it is only a fifth of one trend in Qatar. But it is very important to show that we are actually operating <mark type="inaudible" /> at world class levels and are achieving good value for it. But it is in the overall game of $1 billion of profits in gas and power, it is very small.</p>
          <p>Pearl is in line as our expectations in terms of money and timing, within the numbers we have given, also in terms of start-up, which you find in our last chart in the strategy presentation. Not immune from cost pressure, as the whole world is under pressure there, but so far so good, we are in our budget.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you for all joining today. Before we close, let me remind you that we will be releasing the Q2 '08 results on the 31st of July. And I will do that conference call together with Jeroen and update you then on Q2 and where we are on strategy. Thanks again for phoning in. And have a nice day. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes today's Royal Dutch Shell Q1 Results Announcement Call. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>