<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1131045" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-01-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>44094</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jeroen van der Veer, Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Peter Voser, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Nicole Decker</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jeroen van der Veer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Peter Voser</participant>
      <participant id="6">Edward Westlake</participant>
      <participant id="7">Neil McMahon</participant>
      <participant id="8">Mark Iannotti</participant>
      <participant id="9">David Cline</participant>
      <participant id="10">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="11">Lucy Haskins</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to Royal Dutch Shell Fourth Quarter Results Presentation. There will be a presentation followed by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you.</p>
          <p>I would like to introduce our host speakers Mr. Jeroen van der Veer and Mr. Peter Voser. (0001)</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. this is <mark type="inaudible" /> Jeroen van der Veer. I'm sitting here with our CFO, Peter Voser. We have a short introduction that will take between the two of us about 10 minutes and after that Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>On the first slide, we show how we see the business environment, the industry landscape and our strategy. What we like to &#x2013; everybody knows about our high oil and gas prices, we like to see that &#x2013; we still see a lot of cost inflation, so prices up but costs up as well.</p>
          <p>If you look at the competitors, we have not only to deal with our traditional competitors, but we see all the time that national oil companies become stronger and more international. Then, of course, the supplies mainly to the upstream. If I then look at the downstream, then we saw and we see that, in the cyclical industry, we see weaker margins. And part of the world, we have weaker &#x2013; yeah, we have the dollar as it is, but if your costs are in euros, and then you are of course hit by this weaker dollar.</p>
          <p>Now, those trends are in itself not new. We are already now for some years busy with rejuvenating our portfolio plus our strategies there. We have long-life growth projects mainly in the upstream, so we had the big projects, but then you hold when you can start them up, then you have oil and gas projects with decades to come. And on the other hand, we do asset sales, so it is combination of long-life projects and asset sales that drives folks in the company, drives capital discipline and as a basis in the long-term for return to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>We now take to the highlights of 2007. This is a satisfactory set of results that Peter will go deeply into that and we have made good progress in our projects and we took new final interesting decisions. So by and large on the highest level, I would like to say our strategy is on track and we based that on good cash generation for the company on this moment.</p>
          <p>When I go into more details and I look out at new projects, then I have in front of me a slide for the whole world and you see indeed that we have large projects all around the world. Just as an example, Ormen Lange, Norway, we're just starting to catch up that this has to produce for decades and at a certain moment we expect that it supplies 70% of the U.K. demand.</p>
          <p>As already touched on, the new projects is fine, but the escalation costs, they did have an impact and they will have an impact as what I expect and what kind of impact it is, is that full ops</p>
          <p>First of all, it slows down final investment decisions because you have to see whether you can afford it, or you have to take the time to look whether you can make different designs, can technology help, or do you try to find alternative contractor arrangements. An example there is, you can cut a very large project into smaller pieces, and then you'll hope to attract more different contractors and to get more of competition into it.</p>
          <p>If I look at 2007, we started with these new projects where of course, we tried to apply our technology and our capabilities. Example, just announced Gumusut development is deepwater in Malaysia. We started last year with Qarn Alam that is in Oman, that's enhanced oil recovery. Last year, it was decided that Woodside in which we have a share, they started at Pluto, a very large LNG project. An example downstream is Motiva, where 50-50 was Saudi Aramco. We basically doubled Port Arthur Refinery and that will become then the largest refinery in the USA.</p>
          <p>If I looked on more at the exploration side, this is all about how can we create new long-term and sizeable positions. In exploration, we have the big gap strategy, we go for the larger place, noticed track record in 2007, 11 material discoveries and we had a hit rate of 40%.</p>
          <p>If we look at acreage position, we added 43,000 square kilometers, that's about the size of the Netherlands. And what this will bring in additional resources that are not reserves, I say emphasize the word resources, we added at least 1 billion barrels of oil equivalent resources from the drilling and the business development in 2007.</p>
          <p>Let me spend some words about Nigeria. Nigeria has a story where we have three companies, one offshore doing fine, 170,000 barrels per day between Bonga and Erha. One is the LNG, the Nigerian, where we liquefy the gas. That company did find last year, by the way, we built a sixth train on time, on budget, very safe, started up, I think, in a world record time as well.</p>
          <p>And then we have onshore, that is the Delta. The Delta is nearly as big as England. That's where the problems are and we have there security problems. I understand our people cannot work safely there and we have funding problems and vis-&#xE0;-vis the background, all of that for their onshore, we felt we have to take a provision of a bit more than 700 million as we put in our QIA</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn it to Peter for the financial results into more detail and I'll come back at the end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everybody. Turning to our fourth quarter results in more details, we delivered $6.7 billion of CCS earnings. These are satisfactory figures and come despite weak refining conditions and continue across challenges sector wide.</p>
          <p>Our Q4 earnings included one-time items adding up to some $960 million. When you exclude identified items, our CCS earnings per share increased almost by 6% compared to Q4 2006.</p>
          <p>Let me spend some time now talking about the business performance. Firstly, on upstream, E&amp;P earnings were supported by higher oil and international gas prices. However, we saw a decline in high-margin oil production and increased pre-FID costs, as well as industry wide pressures on costs and taxes, these trends are continuing to the first quarter of '08.</p>
          <p>Underlying Q4 on Q4 volumes, including oil sands increased by 1%. Full year production was on target at 3.3 million BOEs per day despite high oil prices and oil sands downtime in Q4.</p>
          <p>LNG volumes in Q4 were broadly unchanged from a year-ago level. The completion of the new train in Nigeria will impact production only over time, as more gas supply is made available to the plant.</p>
          <p>Gas &amp; Power earnings were positively impacted by LNG prices. Pre-operating costs are increasing as is normal with large projects under construction. Gas &amp; Power marketing and trading conditions were not as strong as a year ago. We have seen similar trends in GP so far in the first quarter '08.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to oil sands, which, of course, is a classic bridge between upstream and downstream activities. Earnings were impacted by a fire at the Scotford Upgrader in the fourth quarter '07. Repairs are now complete and the mine and upgrader were started up again late December. Upgrader availability in Q407 was 79% and we expect some 96% availability in first quarter '08. This compares to 93% in first quarter '07.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move to downstream. Those earnings decreased from year-ago level. For Shell, as we saw in the third quarter '07, Q4 refining margins were eroded by the rapid increase in oil prices and light, heavy crude and product differentials, which do impact a more complex refining place. Cracker and conversion unit outages limited our ability to capture margins on higher-value products. We expect some of this downtime to be restored in Q108, with Bukom in Singapore already restarted last week.</p>
          <p>Q1 is our heaviest turnaround period of the year as we have planned outages at Deer Park, Convent and Pernis plus downtime at Clyde. We expect Q108 availability to be some 85 to 90%, broadly similar to a year-ago level. Operating margins increased in Europe and the U.S. and were broadly unchanged in Asia. Also, trading was broadly unchanged between the two quarters but conditions deteriorated late in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Finally on results, 2007 dividend was increased by 13% to $1.44 a share &#x2013; U.S. dollar. We have announced the provisional Q1 '08 dividends this morning as well at $0.40 a share, an increase of 11%. We have done this as part of our financial strategy to show the confidence that we have in future cash generation and to give some clarity to shareholders in today's uncertain markets.</p>
          <p>Turning towards asset sales, important part of our strategy as well. I think it is important to say that our disposal program is part of our strategy to use strong capital discipline to help to rejuvenate the company and Jeroen spoke about that. We have completed around 10 billion of asset sales in '07 and we have announced a further set of asset sales which should complete in 2008. Recently, we have agreed to dilute our stake in Kashagan from 18.5% to 16.8% with disposal proceeds due beginning with first production. I expect further asset sales to be announced this year.</p>
          <p>Turning to the overview, we have raised some $26 billion from asset sales over the last four years. This is some 22% of average capital employed over that period and compares to some 33% of the 79 billion of capital investments in the last four years. This is an ambitious capital recycling program. I look to be able to maintain a relatively high, but stable level of organic spending in coming years even if macro conditions turn down.</p>
          <p>Net spending for '07 was some $23.8 billion. For '08, we expect net spending to be some 24 to 25 billion, broadly unchanged from 2007 levels. Within that, we see at least $4 billion of net disposals. You will see that we did make some small acquisitions in '07, for example, around half a billion lease acquisition spend in the Gulf of Mexico and we could make similar moves in '08 if the right opportunities come along.</p>
          <p>Now let's look a little bit on the environment. Oil prices have increased substantially during this decade and so have industry costs. On CI estimates industry inflation is running at around 20% with what looks like an uptick late '07. We see notable pressure in EPC, rigs, fabrication, labor, subsea, and bulk materials like steel and copper.</p>
          <p>Now at Shell, we are seeing at least 10% inflation in our capital spending during '07. This is to some extent linked to the weaker dollar and higher industry activity as oil prices have increased. We are also taking steps to reduce our costs, discounts from restructuring in the business areas from taking a more global approach to contracting procurement and from creating a leaner functional organization.</p>
          <p>If you look at finance, HR and IT, for example, together, we have firm plans to simplify and standardize the business processes, expand our offshore shared service centers and outsourcing some of our IT activities. With that, let me hand back to Jeroen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Peter. Before I recap, let me make a point about new hires and new recruits. Over the last year, we hired 4,500 new professionals. By far a vast majority of that were mid-career hires. That brings the score for '06 and '07 together &#x2013; so over the past two years &#x2013; to 10,000 new professionals and again, nearly by far the vast majority mid-career hires. Why did we do that? That is on the one hand because we see the increased activity levels as we have literally performed already and to do a quality job there, not only constructing the things but taking all the environmental aspects into account in this all time getting more complex projects. But secondly as in quite some parts of the world, we expect a lot of retirements.</p>
          <p>I am very satisfied with that and I think that Shell will also have the competition to see that, and as we got older people in. Having said that, yeah, of course we will continue to hire more new talent but not necessarily on these very high levels we have experienced over the past two years.</p>
          <p>My recap now is that I think it was a satisfactory result, driven by operational performance, we made progress on the portfolio, that on the one hand for long life projects, on the other hand, the divestment programs and that gives, that results in a more focused company and a company with more capital discipline and which likes simplification and operational excellence. So by and large, our strategy is on track and we are always busy to further improve our operational excellence.</p>
          <p>And with that I stop here and I look forward to your questions. Operator, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you. Our first question comes from Ms. Nicky Decker of Bear Stearns. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Good afternoon, Jeroen and Peter. I apologize, we dropped off for a minute, so if you already covered this, I apologize. Do you have production guidance numbers for 2008 yet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter will say it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We will not give any too precise guidance for 2008, since there are many moving parts, but let me take you through this. In Nigeria, with the shutting of barrels remains a significant challenge. We have already announced some asset sales, which should complete in 2008. Oil prices have nearly doubled from the $50 levels we saw just a year ago, which we had assumed in the previous production outlook. And overall, the oil price impacts our production by 2 to 4,000 barrels a day through the PSC effect. There are many variables in 2008 and a range of outcomes therefore is possible. So if you assume the same operating environment in '08 s in '07, so that means Nigeria, the way that the oil price around $70 on average and factor in the asset sales, that I think we will see a slight decline in 2008 over '07 production and that seems to be then the likely outcome. But at this stage, with all these variables, I'm not going to give you a very precise guidance. So we stick with a slight decline in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Peter. Thank you. It sounds like you are not expecting to lift production in Nigeria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is just too early to predict that. I mean, we have made some progress and getting back into some areas. We have to repair that, you know that in some areas we are missing a few 100 kilometers of pipelines, etcetera. That needs additional funds. We have said in the press release that we are working with the Nigerian government to actually look into the funding position. So I think it is too early to say we are working on it, but we will see during the year how this actually works out. I think we are taking a rather cautious view on how Nigeria comes back and actually does also feature in our long-term growth aspirations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could just ask one more on reserve bookings, Jeroen, you talked about 1 billion barrels added in 2007, did you mean those were reserves that you booked during the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I start, I like to emphasize that our resources &#x2013; that Peter, Peter is the most sold expert of in Shell. So, Peter going to have to make it absolutely clear how it was all about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What we do is actually &#x2013; we are looking at resources on the long side, and then for SEC purposes, we are looking at proved reserves when we file our 20-F. So from that point of view, what we have mentioned in the speech is that out of the exploration site, we added 1 billion barrels to our resources. So this is the total resources we have available from a commercial point of view, which at one stage will come into development. When we then go into this strategy presentation, we will also then update you on what we have added through the new business development into the resource pool as well. On the reserve side, what we have said is clearly when we file the 20-F, we will get the final reserves number. So the RRR, et cetera, on that is still to come, as we have these linked, the financial reporting this year and the strategy presentation, the filing of the 20-F in March, and therefore we don't give that figure at this stage. I think overall if you exclude the impact of accessories and price &#x2013; oil price effects that I can say that I am satisfied with the progress on reserves in recent years. And details you will see in the 20-F in March 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will stand by. Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Nicky. Next question, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mr. Edward Westlake of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon gentlemen. Maybe looking beyond '08, would I be right in broadly saying on volumes that are flattish to 2010 and then the growth thereafter maybe some numbers around that? And then in terms of the CapEx you've directed you've given '08, but are you expecting CapEx to still drift up from there with inflation activity? And then finally, on gas realizations, maybe some comments given the strong gas realizations outside the U.S. on any changing parts that we should be aware of? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me start with the growth picture. The long-term guidance we have is 2 to 3%, that is basically unchanged, and the portfolio is clear towards growth after 2010. That's really &#x2013; when our projects do come on stream as you have seen before, when we showed you all the projects et cetera. Near-term, we have said, we will be below that strength and it depends on after-sales. We have done a few and we have already announced for '08.  And the Nigeria recovery as we already discussed is extremely important on this one. So, I'm not going to tell you beyond 2008 how we do see production at this stage. We will see when we go through it and how the oil price does, how Nigeria does and then we will update you on that. So, the guidance for beyond 2010 stays in place.</p>
          <p>I think you asked about the gas realization. I think the biggest, or we have seen strong European gas prices and they were positive if you compared it to the Q4's, we obviously had &#x2013; already some effects from more and longer which has come up, which we do not mention as well, and that is a positive one. Then the second question I think you had was on CapEx. We have given guidance now for 2008 and I think I said in the speech already, given the way we are progressing with our strategy and what we want achieve on the growth side, we see high spending continuing, but we are managing through capital discipline. And I've said already, the next spending is pretty much unchanged in '08 like in '07. So this has no change &#x2013; this is how we go to balance that in the years to go forward as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Edward. Next question, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mr. Neil McMahon from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I have got a few questions on Nigeria and then a nice accounting question for Peter. If you look at the LNG, the future LNG projects in Nigeria, given your move and obviously your worsening outlook for the Nigerian situation, what threat you think there is for the <mark type="inaudible" /> and Brass LNG projects and indeed your Train 7 if that is still going to exist for the Bonny plant. And secondly, I am presuming on the capital write down on Nigeria, there is a reserve write down as well associated with the joint venture onshore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I understood your last question, Neil, but let me start and Peter will take the <mark type="inaudible" /> &#x2013; let me start with LNG projects. First of all, which I think is positive news, remarkable, is that the fact that Nigerian LNG sold over last year more in volume than we expected. And this, I mentioned briefly, Train 6 on time, on budget, very safe, quick starter, so it is remarkable how you can work. Then if you look at the future, the further future of LNG development, you can of course, the OK LNG, that is a project we are involved, the [inaudile] and the Brass is an alternative project. It is there not only you to have to take a few where you can build that as successful as Train 6 so to say, but how will be the supplies arranged, and does [inaudible] its goes under combination then to make that work. Both of those projects, if they go out, will be extremely large projects and I could well see at the present business environment that they have a tendency to slip compared to the timing indicated some time ago. And to a certain extent, Train 7, we have not taken final investment decision, we do certain preparations, too early to say. Over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks &#x2013; your question on Nigeria reserves write-down, let me just give you a few pieces here. I will not give precise guidance for 2007, that's clear because we wait for the final results to come. As you may remember in 2006, we moved about 127 million barrels from proof developed to proof undeveloped in Nigeria due to the damages to production facilities from civil unrest. So that may be one thing to keep in mind. If you look at 2006 as well, we are showing there the Africa reserves, which are 1.1 billion barrels which includes Nigeria, we don't give the precise Nigeria split, so for Shell Africa means Gabon, Cameroon, Nigeria, Libya, Algeria, etcetera. Out of the 1.1 billion, there was roughly 775 million barrels was oil. So I think I give you those reference points and then the rest will come with the 20-F, which we file in March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one final question, just looking at your CCS earnings, because they are done on a different basis to U.S. GAAP accounting and the U.S. companies are seeing an inventory benefit at this time because of the rundown in their crude inventories, have you tried to compare your CCS earnings to see what they would be if you had to account for them under U.S. GAAP?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I wouldn't say that much on the U.S. GAAP, I think it's what you are referring to is more that we do it on a FIFO and CCS basis, while the competitors mainly the U.S. ones do it on a LIFO basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what you obviously have when you do it on a LIFO basis, that would mean if you have an inventory sell down then you obviously have a positive impact in Q4, which we would not have the way we do our CCS calculations and the FIFO calculations. So quite clearly, this is a usual kind of year-end impact which can happen for those who report on the LIFO if the prices go in the right way. So quite &#x2013; and I think you have seen that some of the competitors have already reported in that matter. So I think you can expect that in the U.S. companies, but we don't have that now. We have certainly done some thinking on this one, but I'm not going to share what we think they can do on the other side. That's up to them to tell you at the end of today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Neil. Next question, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Our next question comes from Mark Iannotti of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon gentlemen. A few quick questions focusing on the quarter. First of all, what was that realize &#x2013; oil realizations look at quite low on the quarter. Can you maybe make some comments there on what's caused those realizations to be particularly wide this quarter? Secondly, can you give us any guidance on the group depreciation charge? It stepped up quite sharply in the fourth quarter, again, what guidance you have maybe for 2008? And also Asian gas volumes look quite light in the quarter. Can you maybe make some comments on what went on there to drive that performance? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I start with the first one. I think what you're referring to is most probably the gap between Brent and router realized price increase. The Q4 gap between Shell  <mark type="inaudible" /> and the price in the Brent market is a function up to speed, so it's a timing issue by which the Brent price increased in Q4. This is quite a normal effect, which we see during periods of very rapid market price increases, and then we normally have this somewhat, let's say, lack effect in that sense. On the DD&amp;A, I think yes we have a rising curve, but I can only draw your attention to the new fields which have come on stream and that has an impact there. I'm happy to take you offline through all the fields. But, we had quite a number of them over the last 12 to 18 months. Can you repeat your last question, I missed that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Asian gas volumes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was that Asia Mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Asian gas volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's mainly coming from new volumes in New Zealand and in China. And the better performance of operating fees in Brunei, which was slightly offset by higher field declines in Australia to the other extent. The results of PSE effect in all of this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, Mark. Next question operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from David Cline of ABN AMRO. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. A couple of questions on your capital investments. Just looking at the break down in 2007. See there was a material decline in capital investment in E&amp;P, and some very substantial increases in gas and power and chemicals. Can you give us some color on that. And can you say whether those figures are in any way indicative of what we should expect going forward? One additional thing can you give us some data on CapEx mix for 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks, David. Good question. On the <mark type="inaudible" /> the last one, I think going forward you have got an 80% upstream which is 10  oil sands, GP and EP and some 20% on the downstream side. Your first question, clearly in GP you have seen now the ramping up of Pearl, because that obviously had only half a year in it in '06, and is now ramping up. So you have more spending. On chemicals it is clearly driven by Houdini in Singapore, which is a petrochemicals chemicals complex investment which we are doing, which is now also in full swing. And I would assume EP, I double-check, but I think that it has something to do and I have obviously  <mark type="inaudible" /> instead of reporting 100% we only report 27.5% and that obviously has a major impact. So I think you need to adjust for that, and then the figures as far as I remember them should actually work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. David, thanks. Next question operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from  <mark type="inaudible" />  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Just on your &#x2013; while there's that oil products somewhere that looks like excluding unusual items, it came in at 562 million, and we have not really seen a number lower than that since the fourth quarter of 2003, when margins looked a lot worse than they were in Q4 '07, I wonder if you can just talk through what was underlying that particularly weak result particularly with a view to how it might improve going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think I need to start with the industry margins. We did see lower realized refining margins compared to the year ago, we saw that already in Q3. Now quite clearly we saw the narrowing also from the heavy and light differentials, with our crude- slates and products- slates which we were running, we had a disadvantage to the market in Q4. This has affected both but it has clearly affected the  <mark type="inaudible" /> number as you say. We also had operational issues which we had affecting that because quite clearly we had some unplanned downtime coming, for example, from the long residue  cap track that's book em which a), you have repair costs in, it hasn't produced and it's normally also producing product in the high value added range. So that gave us a double hit in that sense.</p>
          <p>Now we expect most of these things to be back on stream. I have given you an outlook into the first quarter in terms of our turnaround, so take that into account. So if I summarize the costs, which we have seen as a total in oil product, which were somewhat unusual, let me summarize that for you. The total opportunity lost in the cost of repair in Q4 '07 versus Q4 '06 were over $250 million. The disposal of the refine,  DLA refinery obviously creates an additional Q4 reduction, which is approximately 50 million. So overall I would say, operating impacts and portfolio effects cost us about $300 million in Q4 '07 and the margin environment and other impacts were about 400 million negative if you take Q4 and Q4. So this gives you kind of a framework, which I think can work forward into Q1 '08. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mr. Mark Gilman of Benchmark Company. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter and Jeroen, good afternoon. I had a couple of things, some in a way of clarification. First just to go back to that 1 billion BOE equivalent resource add, could you clarify whether that's just drill bit or whether it's drill bit plus business development?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's only drill bit, Mark and good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Secondly, the reference to exploration discoveries in '07. I don't need to split hairs but the characterization is material discoveries. I have not heard you say, Big Cat discoveries. Does material mean something different than the net 100 million equivalent associated with Big Cat?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the way we look at these markets, our exploration strategy is a Big Cat strategy and that consists of actually fees, where you have expectations of 100 million barrel Shell share. But then when we go into the developments or when we actually think these are commercially to be developed, which will land into projects then actually we look at this in a different way. So these are in significant ones, and we do no longer distinguish Big Cat and non-Big Cats. Can I just go back to your first question, because I think I was too fast in the answer, just to be absolutely clear, this is the drill bit plus new business development, sorry for that I was too fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me just be sure, I understand. So you are not saying that those 11 discoveries, based on your most current thinking would meet the previously established Big Cat test?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct, and our success rate on that basis is roughly 40%. But your interpretation is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I could just one or two more. I want to go back to the oil products earnings. I have got a belief that there is something else going on there outside of the effects, Peter that you talk about such as trading losses or other unusual impacts. Could you comment on trading losses in the fourth quarter, particularly in the  Valze segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will not comment on detailed trading results but I can tell you that between the two quarters the results were the same and you cannot characterize them as losses by no means. So, we had positive results there. We had higher costs which were coming in &#x2013; some of them are repair costs. We also saw some higher costs on the transport and distribution side, which is a function of the oil price, so it's just more expensive. So in general, we had higher costs and the one thing you should not forget is also we have a heavy Euro-driven cost base, and having such a strong weakening dollar in the fourth quarter has also contributed significantly actually to our results. As a guidance there, across the company, when we have kind of a 10% weakening of the U.S. dollar, it is roughly $150 million impact on our results. So this does actually find its way back to the profit and loss very fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one final one, if I could. Can I assume that the contractual settlement, as referenced in the release, relates primarily to Malaysia and perhaps Dua, in a manner similar to what we saw several years back in terms of the first phase of that LNG project?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. They actually relate to European countries so it's not what you're drawing the comparison to, and it's Europe actually also in Q4 '06, there was one country was in Europe, the other one was in South America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from  <mark type="inaudible" /> Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, gentlemen. Just a quick question on your cash cycle. You've indicated another strong increase in the dividend. Is this a reflection on greater confidence in higher longer-term oil prices? And secondly, was it &#x2013; would it be possible to give us an estimate now with the new moving parts on a breakeven oil price for 2008? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the &#x2013; I'll take the first one on the dividends and thanks for the question. I think it's a reflection of the confidence of our long-term strategy, the cash generation of these long life projects et cetera, so that's clearly. We have said we will position the company for these assets which do perform better at higher oil prices. I think we have seen a step-up in the oil price scenarios over the last two, three years. So I think we are on the right track there, but I will not go into the details what are our planning assumptions on the oil price. I think this is a commercially sensitive area.</p>
          <p>I think we have given you all the numbers for the cash breakeven et cetera, I think we are managing the balance sheet in such a way that we can perform on the dividend side on the organic growth and on the buybacks and acquisition side including disposals et cetera. So I think you have everything to work that out, so I will not comment on that further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from  <mark type="inaudible" /> go ahead. I do apologize. Please be paused. The next question comes from Ms. Lucy Haskins of Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon gentlemen. I wondered if I could ask about the U.S. downstream outlook. Do you think you're actually seeing some evidence of recessionary pressures, or indeed the demand instruction given higher oil prices. Is there some push back at the pump now in terms of the high fleets of cost we are now seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I look at the U.S. &#x2013; let me first look at the world downstream. It is basically a cyclical industry, so our whole philosophy is that you can look at one year, but if you look at our refineries, we try to make sure that especially when the cycle is down, that they are still good cash positive &#x2013; and the way to do that is that basically you need very large units on the right deal, capital location, and perhaps we believe, integrated these chemicals. So we have feedstock synergies, utility synergies and people synergies. And then, you take the cycles as they come.</p>
          <p>In itself, in the U.S, it's how demand will react to the situation of the market is not that clear; and the reason that I say that is that we had expected two or three years ago when the prices ramped up that people will drive less. But we haven't seen very much of that in the U.S. so far. So, it makes me a bit more modest to give any volume interpretations what has happened in the U.S. If we looked at the price side of it, it is realized that the U.S is about 20% of the oil demand in the world. So that means that 80% is from other areas, and we still see a lot of growth in the Far East and the Middle East. So we expect that world oil demand for products this year &#x2013; and I emphasize 'world', will be higher than last year. Okay. Operator, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from  <mark type="inaudible" />  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, just a couple of short questions. I was looking for a split of the divestment gains upstream, only approximate between the USA and the world outside the USA. And maybe on the Nigeria aggregate charge, if you could maybe split out impairments versus provisions there just to give us a materiality of impairments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Now we are on the second one, the answer is no, we are not going to split it out as the charge is clear and we leave it at that. On the divestment side, I think as far as I remember in Q4 these were all non-USA. So it's nothing in the U.S. in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Was there not something for Barnett Shale and...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but that's &#x2013; I think in the greater scheme of the number which I have shown there is that's I would say is nothing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Are these all the questions, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have another question from  <mark type="inaudible" /> Would you like to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, good afternoon gentlemen. A few questions; first you mentioned taking on four-and-a-half thousand new people, however I saw that selling and administrative costs had hardly risen. Would it be fair to assume that a similar number has left the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are still to see this. Yes, we have many things going on, you have divestments as well, realize that this has not necessarily left the company. That is again, in the annual report, it is the first time that you have a decent insight on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Second question is on Saudi Arabia, the  empty quarter I understand you have driven two dry wells so far. Are you planning to continue, or is there any cut off point where we decide whether this is worthwhile to continue or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have all the drilling program, and we don't inform the markets before the program is over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And finally on the Qatar  <mark type="inaudible" /> LNG, you mentioned the position cost inflation. Is the budget still on for 12 billion, or will it be higher than previously mentioned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You tried to catch me there. We have never announced a budget there. But of course, we built and acquired some cost escalation. So far the project's on track to where the &#x2013; how it will go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now two questions left.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Two questions left, and then I prefer to stop. So operator, give us the two questions coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from  <mark type="inaudible" /> Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. As the new joint development operator at Kashagan, do you care to comment on the project CapEx please? And secondly. a question on your expanded gearing of 16.3%. Could you just remind us what your target is, range is, and what oil price that range would apply? Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Kashagan figure I think &#x2013; I can have a very long story about Phase 1 and Phase 2 and all those CapEx and CapEx earlier and later. So far we have said we leave all that kind of, they're not really details frankly because they're still very big figures. But we leave that to the present operator to announce that. So only on high level, I can say we are glad that we managed to restructure all kind of things and to have stabilization in all the terms around it, say, and I think that's what really the project needed because we have still a long way to go before it is up and running. So, we better do that in a stable environment and in the recent renegotiations we achieved that. Peter is for about the gearing prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes the gearing is throughout the cycle 20 to 25%, which compares to the one you mentioned the 16 plus something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the last question, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our last question comes from  <mark type="inaudible" />  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon. Just the one question. It goes back to your test requirements. You talk of cost inflation of around 10%. On a very simplistic basis, if your CapEx rises by 10% per annum, your asset sales have to rise by more than 10% per annum each year if you want to keep your net spend flat. Either you have to then rely on rising asset prices or you have to sell more and more assets each year. Is that a fair comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have given &#x2013; we have always talked about 2 to 3% of our capital employed, which is normally, which we turned over in form of asset sales or swaps or whatever you do. And so from that point of view, as you can see we have a rise in capital employed, and it is mathematically correct what you are saying. So we have a rising target there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much operator. Let me say until at the end, to make you aware that on the 17 of March, we have our strategy update and all the details you would like to know about our reserves replacement. Thank you for asking your questions. Thank you for listening. And I close this conference call. And thank you operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>