<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1333874" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-09-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9369</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Denis Fi&#xE9;vet, Vice President, Financial Communication and Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Pierre Pringuet, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Gilles Bogaert, Managing Director, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Sophie Dargnies</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Xavier Croquez</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Alison Donohoe</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Simon Hales</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Melissa Earlam</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Christopher Pitcher</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Ian Shackleton</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Jamie Norman</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Andrea Pistacchi</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Gerard Rijk</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">Denis Fi&#xE9;vet, Vice-President, Financial Communication and Investor Relations</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody and welcome to the Pernod Ricard auditorium welcome to you too who are following us online. Speaking of which, I will ask those of you in the auditorium to please turn-off your BlackBerries to improve the quality of sound for those listening in online.</p>
          <p>So this morning Pierre Pringuet and Gilles Bogaert will take you through our consolidated accounts for the '09, '10 period running from the 1st of July 2009 to the 30th of June 2010. The presentation will last about an hour leaving you a good half hour for questions.</p>
          <p>As we discuss right now, we alternate between questions from the floor and questions that we take from those of you listening in online. The procedure is now well known, you just introduce yourselves, say who you're representing and ask no more than three questions to ensure that as many people as possible get the opportunity to raise their questions.</p>
          <p>So busy schedule this morning, so let me give the floor straightaway to Pierre Pringuet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Denis Fi&#xE9;vet, good morning everybody.</p>
          <p>Strong healthy growth for the period that just ended. Just three figures to illustrate that: organic growth of sales 2%, profit from recurring operations up 4% and as I told you, advertising and promotion expenditure up 5%. Remember that that was the ambition; that is what we said we'd do, that is what we did and of course, free cash flow from recurring operations of 1,160 million.</p>
          <p>Now, just a few landmark events, contrasted economic situation strong growth in most economies, particularly in Asia, very gradual recovery of consumer spending in the U.S. among others, but certainly, consumer spending has picked up as our own depletion figures demonstrate, as the various panels suggest also. Now the situation is highly contrasted in Europe, we're not going to talk about Greece, but there have been various austerity measures and the situation is nonetheless on the up.</p>
          <p>During the financial period, the euro-dollar parity varied from 1.18 to 1.60 just to show you how much the currency has fluctuated, and of course Venezuelan Bolivar, well, we will come back to that later on. Very importantly for the Group, interest rates are a historically low level both in euro and U.S. dollar denominated borrowings.</p>
          <p>We have also completed our disposals program with the sale of Tia Maria and some of our Scandinavian assets. And we have also issued a 1.2 billion bond in March of this year. So come at these figures now in greater detail. Key figures: sales minus 2% published but organic growth of 2%, and if you look at the top fourteen, you will see that the volume was up 2%, sales were up 4%. That means two things.</p>
          <p>First of all, that our strategic brands are actually growing faster than the portfolio as a whole, largely due to our A&amp;P expenditure, and on the other hand we've had a positive mix price effect such as organic growth of 4%, advertising and promotional expenditure. As we told you 2008-2009, we had to cut back on spending in the, because of the crisis, but we assured that we will be reinvesting this year. We have kept our promise. We are now back investing at the same level as before the crisis. If you look at the marketing spend as a percentage of sales, we are back at the same level as in 2007-2008. And of course profit from recurring operations &#x20AC;1.795 million, that's organic growth of 4%. This is despite the increased investment in A&amp;P, but we'll go through this in some detail later on with Gilles Bogaert.</p>
          <p>Our attributable net profit from recurring operations of &#x20AC;1,001 million, we exceeded that 1 billion mark for the first time in 2008-2009. Now if we factor out ForEx, or currency translation, if you prefer, we would have been up 7%. This year that is what we expect to happen in view of foreign exchange trends.</p>
          <p>Now group share of net profit was up 1% to &#x20AC;951 million. Strong cash generation, I won't go back on to this again. And if we adjust or if we exclude conversion adjustments, remember the dollar was at a high on the 30th of June, but if we factor out conversion adjustments, our debt would have been down by over &#x20AC;1 billion, that's &#x20AC;1,090 million, which means that in terms of net debt ratio, net debt to EBITDA ratio we were down from 5.4, which was the ratio at the end of June 2009 to 4.9, which was the ratio as of June 30, 2009 (sic) [2010]. Remember debt reduction was our top priority for the year and will continue to be a priority for the current year.</p>
          <p>So we're going to take a look at sales. First of all, focus on the fourth quarter, where we have achieved 7% growth. That was 3% organic growth, a 6% positive effect of currency translation and of course, corporate consolidation also had a positive effect, despite the disposal of Wild Turkey, Tia Maria and some of our Nordic assets.</p>
          <p>As for the change in Q4 sales, well, this confirmed the positive trends we mentioned when we talked about our interim results, with strong growth in emerging markets, a recovery in certain markets such as Russia, South Korea, both are posting a positive growth again, and of course the Duty Free market, which is particularly important for premium brands. It's also, by the way, a good indicator of say, consumer sensitivity, if they're travelling and spending, it's a very, very positive sign.</p>
          <p>We've also observed a gradual recovery in the U.S., depletion is back where it was in the past. Western Europe, finally, with still persistent difficulties in Spain, U.K. and Ireland, more recently in Greece, Greece was under a positive trend; well, that trend has come to an end with the austerity measures of this year.</p>
          <p>Finally, again on Q4 sales, we had the negative impact; remember that shipments were anticipated in Q3. A number of festivities took place earlier this year than the past, there have also been a number of duty increases or excise duty increases in the countries mentioned as the U.K. China, Greece and Spain. Over the period as a whole, while the published sales figure was down 2%, internal growth of 2%, driven by the top 14, which were up 4% on average. Remember that in the second half of the year, our internal growth was all of 9%, positive organic growth.</p>
          <p>Now the ForEx impact was much weaker over the year as a whole. In the first half year, the impact was over &#x20AC;180 million, that's a negative impact. So obviously in the second half year the situation was reversed, obviously due to the strengthening of the dollar. And I won't dwell on our disposals, which I've already mentioned twice.</p>
          <p>Here you have a comparison quarter-on-quarter from the first quarter of 2008 right up to the fourth quarter of 2010. You see that the previous quarters really mirror one another. If you look at the half year that's on the right-hand side of this chart, H1 was up 5%, two years ago it was minus 3.</p>
          <p>In the second half year we were down 7% in the first half two years ago, we were then up 9% giving us annual growth in '09-'10 of 2%. So the second half year was very clearly a period of strong recovery.</p>
          <p>This chart is an analysis of our product portfolio. Remember that we classified &#x2013; we defined our portfolio. We explained this in our Capital Market Day last May. Top 14 which is really the locomotive of growth is then followed by our 18 &#x2013; Priority Premium Wines, Jacob's Creek among others, the 18 key local brands that did well, up 4% over the year.</p>
          <p>The other products, which were down fractionally, but if anything that's good news because we have disposed of a certain number of businesses that weren't as profitable. So on whole you see that this is positive. So, there is a very positive growth mix effect and once again the locomotive of our growth has been the Top 14.</p>
          <p>So, let's take a closer look at our portfolio. Beginning with the Top 14, that's 55% of the group sales by the way. Top 14 generates 55% of our sales. We'll give the percentages for the other categories as well.</p>
          <p>On this chart you'll see that on the left hand column you have the organic growth, in the middle you have the organic growth of sales, volume on the left, sales in the middle. And on the right hand side you have the mix product effect. In green you have positive growth, blue is flat. That is the price or the mix price effect for our Top 14 brands. There is only one exception that is Royal Salute, which I'll comment in greater detail in a minute. But all the other brands in the Top 14, 13 out of 14 show at least a neutral, if not positive price mix effect. In other words we have created value with our Top 14 over the last year.</p>
          <p>That's a performance that I'd like to draw your attention to in so far as it shows that what we said, we do. We said we would not accept any price compromise. Well that is now clearly in evidence on that chart.</p>
          <p>So, let's take a look at these products beginning with Absolut Vodka, volume up 6%, sales up 6%. And we're talking about internal growth which factors out July. Remember Absolut was taken over on the 27th of July 2008. So for the purposes of comparison we did not include July.</p>
          <p>So, strong performance by the brand with a price mix effect that was neutral overall, but we have reviewed our prices downwards in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Our reference price is now just fractionally below $20. Remember that the increase was decided just before the prices implemented on the 1st of October 2008, bad timing, you're saying; quite right. So however, despite that decrease in the U.S., we've increased our Absolut price in all other markets. Overall the effect was neutral.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., we have reinvested in the brand. We have taken a number of initiatives and a number of examples mentioned here. The Absolut Lemon Drop that you see which is one of a number of cocktail drinks, magnificent advertisement deal with a wonderful video spot that we'd be delighted to show you, if you like, so we've reinvested in the brand and of course, this is in evidence in the figures.</p>
          <p>Negative depletions in the first half year, in fact, down 5%, positive depletion in the second half year, up 2%, if you look at the Nielsen panel figures well they were positive. The NABCA was negative, but more recently the figures have improved. Very strong growth in a number of export markets with double-digit growth from France, Mexico, Canada, Brazil, Greece, without forgetting Africa, Middle East, Oceania and Asia. So, Absolut is a brand that is really in line with our expectations when we made the acquisition, really rolling it out worldwide.</p>
          <p>We've repositioned our prices in the U.K. and Germany with lower off-trade volumes, but a very, very small downturn sales and much better presence in the on trade part of the business, I hope they have it in your favor bar because we're always furious when we find that Absolut isn't being sold in bars so we're remedying that.</p>
          <p>We've taken numerous marketing initiatives I've already mentioned one or two, but I would like to draw your attention to a very original initiative this is the Spike Jonze's video called "I'm Here".</p>
          <p>This is a video that was broadcast online. You have to subscribe to attend so you have to take a proactive approach. But 600,000 people watched it. This is a 30 minute film. So it's not a quick video clip. 600,000 people watched it. 1.2 million visitors to the dedicated website another figure I saw is that we've had tens of thousands of mentions in the press and the various media. So an excellent and very successful initiative among many others.</p>
          <p>This brings me to Chivas; volumes up 1%, sales were up 5%, the mix/price effect was positive, and strong upturn in growth, Chivas 18 up 41% &#x2013; that's on 18 year old Chivas. The situation improved in Europe particularly in the second half year in Russia and even in Spain the situation improved in Spain in the second half year, we saw a very good performance in France too.</p>
          <p>Signs of improvement in the U.S. We've been reinvesting with Chivas, the focus is on the 18 year old version. So despite the negative trend in the past, we've succeeded in turning depletions around. They were up 1% in the second half year. Nielsen panel figures were negative for the year as a whole, yet more recent figures are much more positive, but double-digit growth in Latin America which is a very important whiskey market.</p>
          <p>In Asia the situation has improved somewhat. Remember that we had a &#x2013; nothing the first half year because we took over from the previous distributor in Japan. Difficulties in Thailand, but doubt-digit growth again in China. So very good results for Chivas in Asia.</p>
          <p>Strong recovery of the Duty Free market in the second half of the year, with success of the Live with Chivalry campaign, its being going very, very well and I'd also like to draw your attention to the last campaign called Age Matters.</p>
          <p>We discussed this advertisement with the Scotch Whiskey Association which supported the initiative. This is all about reminding consumers when you put 18 or 25 years old on a bottle of whiskey, this is a sign of quality and that's very important. Consumers, by the way, are convinced of that. They know that Aged whiskies are very, very good. I think the press mentioned this some 80,000 times &#x2013; 80 &#x2013; 80,000 times.</p>
          <p>Ballantine's, situation a bit more difficult because of the Spanish market. Ballantine's Finest in particular suffered. While figures were down in Spain, Germany likewise fared poorly as did Central Europe. However, the sales grew in France and grew strongly in Poland, Portugal and Latin America. And we are very happy with the performance of Ballantine's with the exception of the Spanish market which we hope to see tail off very soon.</p>
          <p>The higher qualities fell 7%, but picked up very sharply in the second half year up 15% largely driven by the Asian Duty Free markets. Again this is a good indicator of consumer confidence.</p>
          <p>We also repackaged the 12-year old versions &#x2013; 12-year old and older versions, extended our Plan B campaign, and were very, very successful with our Ballantine's Open golf tournament in Korea.</p>
          <p>Martell very good growth again, volumes up 6%, sales up 12%, VS was still down. Cordon Bleu (sic) [Noblige] up 34%, Cordon Bleu up 13%, remarkable growth in most Asian countries, the mix has improved.</p>
          <p>We were at the Shanghai World Fair and we chose not to inhabit the French pavilion, but we were on the expo boulevard which is at the entrance to the Shanghai World Fair. This is the main boulevard leading up to the entrance.</p>
          <p>Martell sponsored the art of good living in China, which I think is a very good positioning. This is by the way the seventh Shanghai World Fair that we have attended with Martell.</p>
          <p>This brings me to Jameson. Double-digit growth again, volumes up 9%, sales up 12%. In the U.S. depletions were up 24%, confirmed by the Nielsen figure up 16%, NABCA up 22%. Great success of the Lost Barrel video which was awarded a prize in the U.S that was last May. With the exception of Ireland, Jameson did well in the U.K., in Eastern Europe in the second half the year, in France, in Scandinavia. We accelerated our growth in South Africa, particularly in the second half. So this is a brand that is as successful as ever.</p>
          <p>Havana Club, volumes up 3%, sales up 5%. We grew very strongly in the second half year; volumes up 13% despite persistent difficulties in our two historical markets, namely Spain and Italy. But Havana Club grew in numerous markets, particularly in Germany which has become Havana Club's biggest market in terms of volumes, obviously, driven by the 3-year old version. We were convinced that we could achieve a million cases in Germany, we have and of course with the new communications or advertising platform called "Nothing compares to Havana," a very, very interesting and flexible campaign.</p>
          <p>Now, Royal Salute is the exception to that, as I told you, despite the fact that Glenlivet was up 6%, sales up 1%. This is because of the sales channel mix combination with very strong growth in the duty free market, but duty free prices are slightly lower than in domestic markets. However, there is no A&amp;P expenditure.  Duty free is a very profitable channel because there is no A&amp;P investment, but prices are lower. Now because the duty free market picked up quicker than domestic markets, we have achieved this effect. Remember Royal Salute is one of our top 14, but this is mainly sold in Asia.</p>
          <p>We've taken numerous initiatives, particularly in advertising with the launch of the "62 Gun Salute &#x2013; The Pinnacle of Scotch Whisky," which was positioned at $2200 in duty free. Not many whiskies in that price range. Same type of price as Lord and Martell, this is a &#x2013; these are ultra-premium products. And we believe that this will be very, very helpful for the brand and it's not the only initiative we'll be taking in this area. The Glenlivet saw its volumes up 5%, sales up 7%. Volumes increased in the U.S. with depletions up 4%. All the indicators are in the green. Very strong growth in Asia, particularly in Taiwan and duty free markets in Europe down fractionally, but almost entirely because of the U.K.</p>
          <p>Now, we have great confidence in the future of this brand because we have doubled our distilling capacity and His Royal Highness Prince Charles came to the inauguration on the 4th of June 2010, which is clear evidence of the importance of this brand in the Scottish heritage.</p>
          <p>Beefeaters, volumes stable, sales up 1%. Good performance in France &#x2013; sorry this is Ricard, we confused logos and figures there. This is Ricard to begin with, sorry. Forget about Beefeater for a second.</p>
          <p>Ricard, volume stable and growth &#x2013; sales up 1%. In France, we achieved a growth, 1% growth, our volumes increased 3% in the off-trade market, despite the fact that the market was down 0.3%. But, on-trade was down. I think three or four bars or caf&#xE9;s closing down every day in France, which is a trend that is not showing any signs of being reversed. So anyway a lot of initiatives were taken. We began with a 35 centiliter bottle for the very first time, the idea being that you can have it on the table, if you have a certain number of friends in a bar, you can order a half bottle that's a 37 &#x2013; 35 centiliter bottle, much more moderate.</p>
          <p>Beefeater this time, yes this time it is indeed Beefeater I'm talking about, volumes down 1%, sales up 1%. Beefeater was very resilient in Spain. We outperformed the market, and we were down 2%, but the market was down 3%. U.S. is still a difficult market for Beefeater, we developed Beefeater 24, we're talking about 12,000 cases, but growth was very, very strong.</p>
          <p>Remember selective on trade distribution, we do not sell Beefeater in the off-trade, but even in the on-trade it's only in up market bars. We're really trying to reestablish Beefeater's brand as a premium brand.</p>
          <p>It's actually twice the price of standard Beefeater, and of course, we have an advertising campaign called "Forever London," with a digital version as well. I think we're doing what it takes to support this brand.</p>
          <p>Malibu volume down 1%, sales down 1%, and that's something of a disappointment. We began our new advertising platform in the U.S. "Radio Boom Boom," as it's called. We started to roll-out the campaign in the U.S. This is mainly an online &#x2013; digital online campaign, which went well in the U.S. Depletions were up 4%, Nielsen and NABCA figures were stable or good, but the trend was then reversed in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>There was a lag then in rolling out the campaign elsewhere and of course we can't apply it in France, so we can't roll it out in France for obvious reasons. We also took a number of marketing initiatives the Malibu cocktails, which were launched in large volumes, these are starter bottles, 75 centiliter bottles or in some cases, in 1.5 or 1.7 liter plastic containers. Now that went very, very well.</p>
          <p>This is really for outdoor consumption, barbecues, for instance, beach parties, just add ice cubes and that's it. Another campaign that went very well is one called, "Malibu By U bottle." You decorate the bottle yourself. You can see examples of our consumers' creativity on the screen here and this is all done online. As you can see we're doing a lot of digital advertising.</p>
          <p>Kahl&#xFA;a, volume down 1% sales down 1%. While we knew this was a difficult brand, the initiatives we took in the past didn't go well. In particular, the campaign with the Aztec Gods. We have continued with Kahl&#xFA;a and Kahl&#xFA;a &#x2013; kept them within the Absolut company because there are lot of similarities between these brands in terms of type of consumers and type of consumption. So we'll see in six-months' time, we'll take stock of the situation then.</p>
          <p>Champagnes, Champagne was difficult all year but certainly the second half was better. 2010 saw Champagne recover, I hope that recovery will be confirmed, which we'll see over the full year, the volume was down 9%, in the second half it was up 1%, Perrier-Jou&#xEB;t down 2% over the year, but up 20% in the second half year. So you'll see that the situation has improved drastically in the second half year, we hope that will continue.</p>
          <p>We're pleased with our performance particularly with Mumm in France, but also in Japan with Perrier-Jou&#xEB;t, in the U.S. as well. In the second half year, we've had positive depletions. We hope that the spring will confirm this trend.</p>
          <p>Jacob's Creek volume down 6%, sales down 2% and these two, Jacob's Creek and Brancott between them account for 5% of the Group's sales. This is half of the still wines business which does not include champagnes, of course, just to give you some idea of what proportion of our sales they account for. There you can see very quickly Jacob's Creek.</p>
          <p>Jacob's Creek volume is down 10%, sales are down 5% and the contribution is flat. So as far as Jacob's Creek is concerned, we are still divesting from the U.K. market. Mass retail wishes to sell three bottles for 15 or even 10 sterling. But as you all know, duties are very high in the U.K. and it's not a profitable business. So we've decided to step away.</p>
          <p>So there is a strong decline in the U.K. as far as we are concerned. But conversely, we made inroads on most other markets that are far more profitable: Australia, the U.S., Sweden and China are cases in point and we have this new True Character platform, which has been successful.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Brancott now, so this is the brand that was formerly called Montana. It was called Brancott in the U.S. because Montana is a state, of course, the capital of which is Helena.</p>
          <p>And, of course, it was somewhat confusing. We ran a survey and we reached the conclusion that Brancott Estate, which is the origin of the brand where it's produced is the name with the greatest clout. So we brought the brand together under the Brancott Estate banner. And that will be complete by the end of the year. So as you can see, apart from the U.K., the performance of the brand has been very good. Last but not least, we are the official sponsor of the Rugby World Cup in New Zealand which will further the clout of the brand worldwide.</p>
          <p>Campo Viejo is our Rioja brand, volumes up two, sales are up one decline in the U.K. due to our high value strategy but strong growth elsewhere.</p>
          <p>And finally our Graffigna brand are the wines in Argentina post very good performance. You see that the brand has been declining on its domestic market, Argentina, but it has been growing, very sharply so, elsewhere.</p>
          <p>These are our 18 key local spirits brands. You see that volume and sales increased handsomely with no price mix effect and these brands account for 17% of group sales. So 55% for the Top 14, the top four wines brands account for 5, and here you have 17% of group sales. And you have a detailed explanation.</p>
          <p>And I need to move on. In particular, Imperial is growing once again in South Korea. Imperial is a Scotch whisky available in 12 and 17 year old versions. We were expecting the rebound of South Korea and that has been confirmed and there is continuing strong growth of local whisky brands in India, Royal Stag, Blender's Pride. We have a few difficulties with Ararat in Russia, and with Wyborowa in Poland and with 100 Pipers in Thailand.</p>
          <p>So that gives you an overview of the brands and Gilles Bogaert is now going to tell you all about the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pierre.</p>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. I would like to walk you through our income statement. As Pierre said, we have 4% growth in our profit from recurring operations, which is quite sound because we do have a 2% top line growth, whereas top line was flat last year. But we also have a sharp rise in our gross margin after logistics costs from 58.4 to 59.6%. In other words, we have a favorable price mix effect. In other words, we made no compromise on prices. And finally, we bolstered the investments in our brands with 5% growth. Last year, there was a 7% drop, if you recall. So quite clearly, this profitability is not encroaching upon future potential.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at the various effects. There was a negative, minus 3% group effect, &#x20AC;63 million, primarily due to the disposals; Wild Turkey and Tia Maria. There was a negative foreign exchange impact &#x20AC;58 million, which is solely ascribed to Venezuela because the other ForEx impact &#x2013; there were plusses and minuses and it was a wash in fact. And things improved over the year, in Venezuela the bolivar was devaluated in early January 2010 from 2.15 to 4.30 that's how the rate changed, quite a swing and at the same time there were increasing difficulties to access foreign currency. So what we did to consolidate the accounts of our subsidiary is that we used the parity that we noted for currency transfers in Venezuela. In other words, 6.40 between the dollar and the bolivar. So between 2.15, the official rate last year, all you have to do is divide the bolivar by three from the previous year.</p>
          <p>As I was saying there was a sharp rise in gross margin. Organic growth is 4%. It is twice as strong as the sales growth. There are three factors that account for this very good performance. First of all, price mix effect, it's very good. The top 14 brands increased or grew twice as fast as group sales.</p>
          <p>We defended our prices. We even hiked our prices for a great many brands and a great many markets. So 1.8% price increase overall for the top 14 brands over the year. And we continued to tame our cost of goods sold and we kept that flat for the year.</p>
          <p>Regarding advertising and promotion, as previously announced, we significantly stepped up our investments with a 5% jump, with a 22% leap in the second half, which helps us achieve a 17.8% ratio of A&amp;P over sales. It was 17.2 last year, as Pierre pointed out; we are back to the pre-crisis A&amp;P over sales ratio.</p>
          <p>Three-quarters of our investments are ascribed to our strategic brands, the Top 14. The investment ratio for the Top 14 is around 24%. And there was a qualitative improvement of the mix of advertising and promotional expenditures, because the media spent, which is of course a long-term investment increased faster than our marketing spent because we have an 11% increase in media spend for the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>As a consequence of all of this, the contribution after A&amp;P jumped 4% and the ratio also improved in spite of the fact that we continue to increase our investments in our brands. Regarding structured costs, if you exclude other income and expenses we &#x2013; it was 1% &#x2013; a mere 1% rise in the structured costs.</p>
          <p>First of all, we tamed our costs quite tightly. We reorganized our subsidiaries in a great many difficult markets: Ireland, the U.K., Spain are cases in point. Also, we had frozen the salaries of all Executive Committees at the beginning of the year. And we did not run any stock option plan in June 2009.</p>
          <p>And &#x2013; there was defense, but there was also offense. We decided to beef-up our operations where we have the highest growth potential, notably in emerging markets such as China, India, African markets in Africa; now, there is emerging potential there and Japan, following the takeover of the distribution of Chivas, notably.</p>
          <p>Now all this leads us to a 4% growth in profit from recurring operations, PRO, which is greater than the objective that we guided you to at the beginning of the year, which was between 1 and 3%. And the PRO organic growth rate is identical to last year's. But this time it includes a significant increase in A&amp;P spend, that 5% I was telling you about.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at the performance on a regional basis now. As last year, Asia, rest of the world remained the key driver of organic growth; 66 million in blue here, the 14% organic growth. Conversely, Europe was the most &#x2013; was the region that was most adversely hit by the crisis. This is especially true for Spain and the U.K.</p>
          <p>So let's start off with the leading region for Pernod Ricard. Asia and rest of the world, this is definitely the growth driver. And the Group is a leader on these key markets and we are even stronger now that the year has elapsed. You see a 9% increase in sales, and a 14% increase in PRO.</p>
          <p>China is one of the key countries obviously, double-digit growth there. And there was a very favorable mix quality effect for Martell, and this was the case in previous years. As Pierre mentioned we had a negative technical impact in the fourth quarter given that there were price increases in April, but the underlying trend remains excellent. Wholesaler sales and consumer demand are very buoyant starting in Q4.</p>
          <p>India is still growing strong, mainly on the strength of its local whiskey brands: Royal Stag, Blenders Pride and Imperial Blue. South Korea posted very good news this year, because the trend reversed. The market suffered considerably in the first year of the crisis. But business has recovered. And this is also the case for Duty Free markets which are, of course, of consequential size in Asia.</p>
          <p>Africa, Middle East still a small region, but it's highly profitable and growth there is double-digit, so quite clearly Africa and the Middle East are definitely growth areas as far emerging markets were concerned. Conversely, Thailand declined because of political turmoil. A word about the ratios here, gross margin and marketing expense ratios in Asia/Rest of World are highly impacted by the sales growth or slightly affected by sales growth in India.</p>
          <p>Americas 4% organic sales growth, 1% organic profit from recurring operations growth, Latin America drove that growth. We considerably stepped up our investments in the Americas, as you see 7% above Group average increase there. It is of strategic importance for the Group. This is true for the U.S. and the two South American tigers, if I may say so, Mexico and Brazil.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., the business was flat. If you take a look at organic sales growth, shipments and depletions, everything was pretty much flat, but there was an improved trend because depletions in H2 posted plus one, whereas overall, they were at minus two in H1. Absolut followed the trend owing to price hikes or price changes we were at plus 2% in H2, whereas we were at minus five in H1. Malibu and Glenlivet performed well. The great success of Jameson carried through with growth in excess of 20% and Kahl&#xFA;a and Seagram's Gin slipped.</p>
          <p>Central and South America, satisfactory growth, especially ascribable to the iconic Chivas and Absolut brands and not to mention the Something Special Scotch Whisky. There was a negative ForEx impact in the Americas somewhat ascribed to the U.S. dollar, but essentially due to the negative impact of Venezuela that I have already elaborated on.</p>
          <p>Europe: in France, minus 5% sales growth, minus 3% PRO growth. In Western Europe excluding France there were some difficulties. Spain, the U.K. were difficult, but there are countries that moved up. Germany, which is a major player in the region, and smaller countries such as Sweden and Belgium that fared quite well.</p>
          <p>And Duty Free picked up in the second half. In Eastern Europe, there was good recovery in H2, especially in Russia. Russia closed the year with slight topline growth. Ukraine did well too. The situation was more difficult in Poland, essentially because of our local vodka brands that slipped. The face value decline in the region's PRO was primarily due to the negative scope and ForEx impacts.</p>
          <p>France now overall, France once again posted good performance 7% PRO growth. Flat sales, of course, there are pluses and minuses, Absolut and Havana Club grew sharply. Ricard and the whiskies performed well. By the whiskies, I mean Chivas, Ballantine, Jameson and Clan Campbell, but Champagnes, notably Mumm and Pastis 51 were not sparkling performers. But given the increase in the share of high gross margin brands and contained structure costs in France, we were able to get a sharp rise in our PRO sales ratio, 24.2 to 25.9%, and a 7% rise in profit from recurring operations overall.</p>
          <p>All this gives you pie chart analysis of all this. By geographic regions, sales on left, PRO on the right, Asia &#x2013; RoW has become the group's main region for Pernod Ricard, plus 32% given its excellent organic growth. The Americas suffered from negative ForEx impact. And you see that the contribution of each region is increasingly consistent between sales and profit from recurring operations.</p>
          <p>The new economies, as last year, proved instrumental in the Group's growth an 8% increase in organic growth. They account for one-third of sales, one-third of PRO, just as profitable was mature markets and given the strong positions that we enjoy in these new economies and given the growth potential that remains untapped. This is of course critical for our future growth, key strength for future group growth.</p>
          <p>Still walking down the income statement, now we're moving on to financial income from recurring operations. There was sharp improvement over the year here with a sharp decline in net interest. Of course there was deleveraging and the drop in the average cost of debt from 4.8 to 4.3% this year.</p>
          <p>The other income and expense items, well, overall there is a rise there. Amortization of bank charges paid in relation to the implementation of the V&amp;S syndicated loan. We're looking at &#x20AC;11 million there and there was an increase in other income and expense items primarily due to pension commitments.</p>
          <p>For next year, based on current interest rates, our target for '10-'11 is to maintain the average cost of borrowing below 5%. 2009, 2010 was a decisive step in group deleveraging. It shows up in net debt excluding translation differences, the debt dropped &#x20AC;1.090 million. And there was a strong free cash flow generation to the tune of &#x20AC;1.110 billion.</p>
          <p>And non-recurring cash optimization items, first of all, the disposals, we &#x2013; a lot of headwind, Tia Maria, the Scandinavian assets have generated roughly &#x20AC;200 million worth of cash over the period. And I'd like to remind you that last year we had a cash dividend that was reduced to &#x20AC;0.50 per share, which generated the fact that our cash outflow was limited to &#x20AC;136 million.</p>
          <p>The face value decline in debt was limited to &#x20AC;304 million due to a highly negative translation adjustment as Pierre pointed out. Towards the &#x2013; at the end of June, we were pretty close to the strongest point that the dollar ever hit, $1.23 to the euro, whereas it was 1.41 at the beginning of the fiscal year and at the average it was 1.31.</p>
          <p>So here you have the details of free cash flow from recurring operations, after recurring operations &#x20AC;1,160 million is pretty flat from last year on a like-for-like basis, in spite of factoring, which is less favorable than last year. Last year, we set up the factoring program generating &#x20AC;350 million in cash. The impact this year is a mere &#x20AC;84 million, but still favorable. This good performance in terms of cash flow generation stems from our controlled working capital requirement, which remained pretty much a wash, our strict control over growth of ageing inventories, cognac, whiskies.</p>
          <p>This is very much in line with what we had anticipated. We made efforts to substantially reduce our wine inventory in the Pacific region. It was &#x20AC;40 million decline there, a great many initiatives unleashed, made that performance possible and for other factors there was a &#x20AC;76 million decline essentially due to the disposals of receivables.</p>
          <p>CapEx was down from last year &#x20AC;184 million, quite well curved and borrowing costs declined, which was favorable on the cash aspect of interest. Also you see that non-recurring related free cash flow posts a favorable trend. First of all, there was a decrease in cash outflows relating to the integration of Vin &amp; Sprit and we also cashed in a 105 million tax refund in the U.S. for carry-back. Now deleveraging also bears out in the net debt over EBITDA ratio, as you know there are two ways of determining this, you take your net debt at closing rate and you take your net debt at average rate. Usually when there is not too much currency volatility, there is not much of a difference. But this year given the swing from 1.41 to 1.23, there is quite a disparity between the two approaches here.</p>
          <p>The average rate approach is of course a most salient one and that is the one we use for our covenants, our syndicated loans in late June. We're not allowed to go above 75 (sic) [6.75] and now we are at 4.9. As &#x2013; I need to say that the ratio dropped from 5.4 to 4.9 over the year essentially due to organic EBITDA growth and very strong cash flow generation over the fiscal year. In calculating the ratio, we get 9.8 billion versus 10.5 billion at closing rate, so a very good year in terms of our de-leveraging.</p>
          <p>Moving on to debt maturity, as you can see 2013 and 14 are the big years. Of course there is something to pay back in the next few years, but given the cash we have and given the &#x20AC;2.2 billon, we have in undrawn lines and given the cash flow we're going to generate in the coming months and years, it's fair to confidently assert that we can cover our requirements up until 2012-2013 included. Bond debt represented a little over one-third of our gross debt and as you know our determination is to continue to balance out our financing between banking and bond debt by 2013.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at what this looks like with a currency breakdown, 60% in dollars. The dollar portion increased somewhat especially due to the fact that the dollar strengthened against the euro. The debt breakdown by currency is consistent with that of EBITDA. Well, that's how we structured it. And according to rates &#x2013; the nature of the rates, well our policy is to have one-third of our debt maintained at a variable rate. We were at 32% in late June, so very much on the money as far as that is concerned.</p>
          <p>Income tax. On recurring operations first. We have a 20.9% effective income tax, which is in line with our anticipation and with our guidance at the beginning of the year. It's up from last year. It was at 16.6% last year, and it did benefit from the effects of the V&amp;S acquisition.</p>
          <p>Non-recurring items, well there is a positive &#x20AC;48 million impact there. There are various factors there. Savings related to non-recurring expense and the favorable impact of the foreign exchange movements, which generated deductible foreign exchange losses.</p>
          <p>Minor interests and other items, from minus 21 to minus 27, essentially due to the good performance by Havana Club in Canada and in South Korea, where we have minority stakes.</p>
          <p>So, all told, we have 1 billion in group share of net profit from non-recurring operations down 1%. So, virtually stable in spite of unfavorable foreign exchange effects and higher income tax, reflecting sales resilience and controlling cost. At a constant ForEx, 7% growth in Group share of net profit from recurring operations.</p>
          <p>Net earnings per share from recurring operations. Here we have a 10% drop in the diluted number of shares. &#x20AC;0.37 per share is the simple arithmetic because there was a capital increase that took place on the 14th of May, 2009. It had been prorated last year whereas this time around there was the full year effect.</p>
          <p>Therefore at the AGM on the 10th of November, we shall submit a &#x20AC;1.34 per share dividend, sharply up from last year, because last year the dividend was limited to &#x20AC;0.50. As announced, we were returning to our usual policy of distribution in cash of about one-third of net profit from recurring operations.</p>
          <p>This brings us to non-recurring items. We have capital gains and losses on disposal and asset valuation. A couple of negative impacts due to disposals. A total of minus &#x20AC;60 million. Also the 116 million negative impact on impairment tests, particularly on Kahlua for &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
          <p>We also have a net expense of &#x20AC;43 million for restructuring costs. Other non-recurring income and expenses are actually an income of &#x20AC;88 million, particularly due to the variations to risk for &#x2013; risks and contingencies. The other operating income expenses was a negative 88 million. Non-recurring financial items totaled &#x20AC;10 million, mainly currency translation losses.</p>
          <p>This gives us a group share of net profit after recurring and non-recurring items, up 1% on last year. This is despite the globally negative ForEx impact.</p>
          <p>Let me give the floor back Pierre Pringuet for the conclusion and outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gilles.</p>
          <p>So what lessons are to be learned from the year just ended? I think what's important is at the top of the screen here. We have demonstrated our ability to withstand situations. It's the fact that we are exposed to the global market and the new economies, and this is really what's driving growth, broader exposure and emerging markets.</p>
          <p>There's also the fact that we have always stated the importance of premium brands. This has been our top priority. I know there have been disagreements, but we've been very, very consistent with this premiumization approach, and finally we are once again reinvesting in advertising and expenditure, which is evidence of our &#x2013; the confidence we have in our brands.</p>
          <p>As for the current year, or the year just begun, our priorities are very straightforward. First of all, to continue to develop strategic premium brands, particularly our top 14. Secondly, to continue to invest in marketing at a high level. I know there is a catch up effect on last year &#x2013; the year before last, rather &#x2013; but we intend to keep our A&amp;P at at least the same level as last year.</p>
          <p>And, of course, the third priority is debt reduction, which is one of our three priorities for the current year.</p>
          <p>As for our objectives, well, we will talk about that again at our AGM on the 10th of November next. We will our guidance for the year on that occasion.</p>
          <p>Let me now give the floor to you for questions. Now we need a microphone, don't worry. We need a microphone. Yes, we're into that. [Foreign Language] Now the microphone is ready.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sophie Dargnies from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the microphone working okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is. I have three questions. First of all, the United States, where you said that the market has picked up, but amidst uncertainties. Could it be that end-consumers are depressed? Could this account for a certain amount of depletion?</p>
          <p>Secondly, you've talked about continuing to invest in A&amp;P next year. Does that mean that we will exceed the 17.9% of sales that you achieved last year?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, could you say a few words about the performance in July and August if possible by region?</p>
          <p>And finally, if you could tell us what you think about the mix price effect for next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll take the questions in the order you put them. No, depletion in the region is the same as shipments, so there will not be any decrease. So that is not on the agenda.</p>
          <p>As to the situation in the U.S. market, I'm sure you will have read about the situation in the U.S. I think the real issue is employment in U.S. That said, the situation is much more positive than a year ago. That's undeniable. But I think it would be a &#x2013; you'd hope to expect a very sharp recovery.</p>
          <p>As for A&amp;P, advertising and promotional expenditure. Whatever about the ratio, I am not going to give you any guidance on that. But as I've said, our spend will be at least as high as in 2009-10.</p>
          <p>But let me draw your attention to one point. The priority is our Top 14 brands. We invest more in the Top 14 than in the rest of the portfolio. With the Top 14, the proportion is 24% of sales, and this of course accounts for three-quarters of our total marketing spend.</p>
          <p>So the Top 14 is I think naturally, because of that, going to grow much quicker than the portfolio as a whole. So I think you can draw your own conclusions on the impact that will have on the average proportion of sales for the Group. So that very clearly is our priority. Focus on the Top 14. Okay.</p>
          <p>July and August &#x2013; well, we are quite happy with the start of the year.</p>
          <p>As for the mix price effect next year. Well, let's be cautious about price increases. Let's put it that way. Caution.</p>
          <p>Have we another question? I think we have a question from the back of the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My name is <mark type="inaudible" /> from <mark type="inaudible" />. I'd like to ask a question about the U.S. Have you seen any change in consumer behavior in the U.S.? That's behavior with regard to your products. Have you noticed any change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No. That's, I think, the simplest answer is no, we haven't.</p>
          <p>I think it could be said that the U.S. market is one that responds very quickly to &#x2013; it's in evidence in employment figures. I think their perception of the financial situation is another example.</p>
          <p>But let me take an example. Let's take the example of New York. As everybody knows, New York is very sensitive to the economic situation or financial situation, and New York is doing very well. Very clearly the market has picked up sharply in New York for premium and super premium brands. And particularly with the return to on-trade business. The on-trade performance has improved.</p>
          <p>So I think when people choose to shop down and consume at home, that is under duress. But I think when the situation improves, when consumers want to enjoy themselves, the tendency is to dine out and consume on-trade.</p>
          <p>So I can't say there has been any sharp, major change in consumer behavior. Consumers are not all environment friendly. They are not all focusing on functional products, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if I could elaborate on that question. If the U.S. situation &#x2013; U.S. economy recovers, Americans will consume at the same way, in the same trends and at the same price levels as before. Is that your understanding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's exactly my understanding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from the front. Several questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Xavier Croquez from Cheuvreux. Three questions, if I may. First of all, the free cash flow drivers. We just completed two years when &#x2013; very difficult to sense the underlying trends. But factoring is a caution that I think has been worn out at this point in time.</p>
          <p>So in terms of inventory and stock, there has been an increase. Is that a one shot increase or is this an ongoing underlying trend? I am just trying to get a feel for working capital requirements. Can we expect much in terms of improvements?</p>
          <p>And a similar question regarding capital expenditure, which you toned down. What level of CapEx can we expect at &#x2013; when you reach cruising speed, when your sales are back to a &#x2013; let's say normal levels?</p>
          <p>Secondly, how did you deal with &#x2013; how did you deal with business tax? This is a question we have all sorts of problems with. We'd be very pleased to have your opinion on the business tax onus. Taxe professionelle, in France?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Concerning cash, factoring had an impact last year. This year, it accounted for &#x20AC;84 million, and next year, I think it will depend on how our sales fare.</p>
          <p>As for inventory &#x2013; well, we have the strategic inventory and finished products. And strategic inventory, we have &#x20AC;120 million worth of whisky and brandy. There was an increase last year. I think we can expect a similar increase next year of 120, &#x20AC;130 million in this category, which is because the rationale of growth. Cognacs are expanding. The scotch is a product that is expanding sales or expanding as well. This means that we need to build up stocks, which means that we have to increase our inventory.</p>
          <p>As for the other aspects of working capital requirements, this will depend on how our business develops overtime. Not saying that we are not constantly making improvements or working on our terms of payment to all the suppliers and our clients.</p>
          <p>CapEx is down again this year, and next year we expect a rigorous approach. I think you can expect CapEx to increase by maybe &#x20AC;30 million. Here again to support the growth of our brands.</p>
          <p>As for the technical issue of business tax or Taxe professionelle, the name has changed in France, as you know. Under accordance with accounting standards, it is now classified under current income tax. But the impact is actually only marginal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Alison Donohoe, Natixis. Could you tell us about the synergies from the acquisition of Vin &amp; Sprit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you see any synergies, Gilles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well, we confirmed the &#x20AC;150 million synergies we expected last year 110 million were achieved. This year we achieved some &#x20AC;30 million in synergies from Vin &amp; Sprit. Largely in gross margin, some others in structured costs. But &#x20AC;30 million over the full year. We expect a further 10 million over the next two years.</p>
          <p>I think we can say that to-date we have achieved the bulk, if not all of the synergies we expected from the Vin &amp; Sprit acquisition.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Simon Hales from Evolution Securities. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone, a couple of questions if I can. Firstly, just going back to the U.S., could you just talk a little bit more about the underlying growth trend you saw in the second half. Obviously you had a sharp acceleration in growth in Q3. I wonder if you could explain for your U.S. business in Q4. You said it was flat overall for the year.</p>
          <p>And then subsequent to that in terms of what you've seen since the year end. And I think Brown-Forman last night on their quarterly conference call were indicating that they thought July and August have been a little bit more difficult in the U.S. That perhaps some of the on-trade recovery you were starting to see is starting to slow. I'd be interested in your comments specifically on that?</p>
          <p>And then just secondly away from trading, but &#x2013; on FX, I know you don't want to give any guidance with regards to organic growth outlook for fiscal 2011 at this stage. But Gilles, could you give any indication at all as to what you see the benefit of FX being in the current year?</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gilles will talk about the ForEx impact. But concerning the U.S., as I've said, the start of the year has been very much in line with the previous quarter. The U.S. market is still not a market that has frankly recovered. But this has nothing to do with the sharp decline of a year ago.</p>
          <p>A year ago we had depletion levels of minus 4, 5, 6%. Now we're looking at depletion levels of &#x2013; well, the depletion situation is fairly flat. In many cases, depletions are up, to mention but Jameson. There are a number of other brands that are posting double-digit growth. So, definitely the situation has improved.</p>
          <p>As for how the situation will develop over time, I don't believe in the double-dip, but nor do I believe in a sharp recovery. So we have to remain cautious about the U.S. market. Undeniably, the market is much better now than it was a year ago. Certainly much better than it was in the summer of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gilles Bogaert speaking. Simon, as regard to your question on the ForEx impact, on current rates, we expect to have a positive ForEx impact. Sensitivity of our PRO to the euro dollar parity &#x2013; most emerging currencies are pegged to the dollar. We expect that with $12 million, we've updated that figure. We've updated at the end of June, and the emerging markets account for a bigger share of our sales. So about &#x20AC;15 million impact for 1% variations.</p>
          <p>So if you calculate that on the basis of the average exchange rate for last year, or using spot rates, you'll be able to calculate that the ForEx impact should be a positive 120, &#x20AC;130 million at current exchange rates.</p>
          <p>As for Group structure, given the disposals made more recently in July and August, we expect that the scope of consolidation effects will be negative &#x2013; maybe 40, &#x20AC;50 million over the year.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, can I just confirm what you said about the U.S. You don't think you've seen any real slowdown in the summer months <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that is not what we've seen.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mrs. Melissa Earlam from UBS. Madam, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a question on China. It seems to me that there is some improvement in the overall scotch market. Can you comment on what you see as driving that over the last six months?</p>
          <p>And then can you give a more general comment about what you think your market share <mark type="inaudible" /> for both cognac and scotch? Thank you.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to let Gilles check out the market share figures, and while he is doing that, I will answer your question by saying that, regarding the Chinese scotch market, yes, the scotch market is doing better.</p>
          <p>And why? Well, broadly speaking, the Chinese market is doing well. We are also putting in a lot of effort. We are the absolute leaders in the scotch whiskey market with a market share in the region of 50%, particularly with Chivas.</p>
          <p>The advertisements are specific to China and they have gone very well. Our campaigns have been very successful. So broadly speaking, we are very happy with our performance and particularly the performance of Chivas in China, which is posting double-digit growth. As regards market share, Gilles, have you had time to check out those figures? I think our market share in scotch is &#x2013; well, it's over 50%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes, Pierre, it's down fractionally, has been down fractionally in the last few years. We were very, very clear leaders, in fact we were almost all alone.</p>
          <p>But on the whole, our market share for imported products is 42%. So we are clearly the market leader. Very clearly the leader in the scotch market. And we are also the leader in the XO market with Martell.</p>
          <p>As you know, in China, we haven't got panels that are as specific as in markets elsewhere. We have consolidated our position as number two in the Chinese cognac market, way ahead of the third ranked operator. We believe that we have got a lot closer to the market leader. I'm still talking about the Chinese market by the way. So we are very, very well positioned at number two, much closer to the market leader. I think only we are only a few percentage points away from the market leader. We've consolidated our leadership in the XO category in the cognac market. That's our situation with regard to market share in China.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Chris Pitcher with Redburn Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. A couple of questions.</p>
          <p>Can I just clarify, in the presentation you mentioned that the average price increase for your top brands were &#x2013; was 1.8%. That really looks like all the value growth, the price mix growth, came from pricing in your top 14, and with a limited benefit from mix.</p>
          <p>And then just to clarify, I think, Mr. Pringuet, you said that that you expected limited pricing in the new financial year. Should I imply from that that maybe you &#x2013; without a recovery in mix, that your top 14 brands are unlikely to have the same rate of price mix growth in fiscal '11?</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The 1.8%, so how do we determine the 1.8%? Well, we look at our net sales price per case for the brand market combinations, and there can be some mix effects, In other words, in that 1.8%. You could, for instance, have changes in the mix within the given brand, but this does not harness the mix effect between the brands and the markets.</p>
          <p>But it's for each brand in each market, and I can confirm that that's the way we calculated it. The figure is indeed 1.8% for the top 14 brands.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is a positive mix effect in there.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could come back to the second part of your question, the second part of your question for the coming year, I said we have to be cautious about price increases. And that does not mean that we will not be increasing prices. That would be a misinterpretation. But I have said, let's be cautious &#x2013; be prudent about this.</p>
          <p>Secondly, regarding mix effects, I think we have shown, and even in our past performance, which accelerated in the last half year, we have shown that with Martell and its double-digit growth with Noblige and Cordon Bleu. 18-year old Chivas grew very sharply, over 40%, in the second half year. So there are indeed mix effects.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And could I...</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It could be the trend in the second half year, a very clear-cut trend. And if this trend is confirmed, well, this will have a very positive effect. But I can't quantify that, I am afraid.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And could I ask a follow-up question on the Wine business. You've obviously created a new brand group, premium wine brands. Could you give us a feel for what size the business is now and what its contribution margin is relative to the group? And some sort of feel for the strategy on your wine business, which has obviously been a drag on growth for the last couple of years?</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the actual size of the business, I think we quoted a figure of % of the group's sales. What about the contribution, Gilles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the four premium brands. 5%. But on the whole, the wines contribute about 10% of our sales. So the top four contribute about half of the total wine contribution, which is 10% of total sales.</p>
          <p>As to the profitability of the wine business, well the gross &#x2013; percentage of gross margin is well below that of spirits, as is indeed the investment in A&amp;P, much lower than in the spirits market.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Ian Shackleton from Nomura. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. Two questions.</p>
          <p>One you've given us guidance around the ongoing finance charge &#x2013; the interest charge. Do you also expect an ongoing sort of financial charge particularly from the pension charge? You had 40 million this time.</p>
          <p>And secondly, looking forward to the end of FY '11, what sorts of deleveraging target are we now thinking about in terms of net debt to EBITDA?</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding pension commitments, well this is a net between the updating of our liabilities and the yields on the assets invested with a view to meeting these commitments.</p>
          <p>So our net expense of &#x20AC;40 million in the year ended. We do not expect that situation to deteriorate next year. If anything, that expense should be lower next year.</p>
          <p>As for the net debt to EBITDA ratio, we don't give any guidance on that. We won't be giving you any guidance today. All I was saying is that if you look at our performance at the end of June, that was improved by 0.5 from 5.4 to 4.9, which is a big improvement on last year.</p>
          <p>So our commitment to improve that ratio is a promise that we've kept. We will continue to make that one of our priorities.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Jamie Norman from Evolution. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, gentlemen. Three questions if I may.</p>
          <p>Firstly, the level of promotion in the vodka market in the U.S. has been well documented. Are you pretty confident that the worst is over as we look ahead to the holiday season?</p>
          <p>The second question is on Absolut, where you've seen very good momentum, and I wonder if you would give us a sense of how much of that is coming from taking share from your competitors, and how much is growth in markets not traditionally strong in vodka.</p>
          <p>And the third question, just following up Chris Pitcher's question on wine is, give us a sense of how far down the road you are in the U.K. in repositioning your wine business, and what sort of impact will that have in the New Year? Thank you.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, is the worst behind us? I think that's really a question for our competitors. I can't really predict what they are going to do.</p>
          <p>But certainly as far as we're concerned, we do not believe in wildcat promotional drives. We certainly haven't done anything to deteriorate the mix price effect of our brands, and very clearly, our intention is to continue in that vein next year.</p>
          <p>Regarding your question on Absolut, as for market share, well much depends on what the reference market is. Are we talking about the vodka market, the premium vodka market? Do we distinguish between premium and super premium?</p>
          <p>But my feeling is that, we had set ourselves a priority which was to reestablish the brand's attraction to consumers. This was a brand that was established in the U.S. A brand that was maybe destabilized by a number of other super and ultra-premium brands.</p>
          <p>So our marketing work, our advertising input, our digital work, our promotional drives and the various efforts we made in terms of product range, we launched a whole season of special editions such as the Brooklyn Absolut, this was a tea-flavored vodka, if I remember correctly, which was a world premiere in vodka. All these efforts are gradually paying off, and I think we can claim &#x2013; we're constantly measuring the pulse of consumers, but the indicators are clearly better than they were a year ago or two years ago for that matter.</p>
          <p>But this is, I think, what we need to bear in mind, we'll look at the panel figures, as we are closer in the future and we'll see how we're faring by comparison with our competitors. But my feeling is that we are faring well by comparison.</p>
          <p>This brings me to your question regarding wine, Gilles you remember the question. Gilles what can you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gilles Bogaert speaking. I think wine accounts for one-thirds of our total volumes in the U.K., much less in terms of profitability of course. But clearly our focus, as was the case last year, will be on premiumization, premiumizing the brand. So we will forget about non-profitable promotion drives, we will continue to avoid that. So, we are quite prepare to reduce our volumes, but lower volumes for more value, that's what we're seeking to do, again eking out growth, which we will eke out in a number of markets.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Andrea Pistacchi from Citigroup. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes good morning. Couple of questions please, at the nine months stage you gave us growth rates for China and India. I was wondering if you could give us a figure for the full-year please?</p>
          <p>Also on India, is almost all the growth volume or are you getting any pricing in India?</p>
          <p>And finally please, on Latin America, I think, you characterized the performance as satisfactory growth in Latin America. I think in previous quarters you were talking about strong growth or buoyant performance. So wondering if there is anything has changed recently, anything holding back your performance? Thanks.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gilles, you can put some numbers around that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, regarding China and India, in China we have double-digit sales growth for the fiscal year, and in India, growth is strong double-digit, essentially it's going to be volume growth of our three brands, which are very buoyant, and volume of course plays a more important role than price in this case.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as Latin America is concerned, performance was satisfactory in the fiscal year. We had very good performance for a number of important brands. Absolut performed very well in Mexico and Brazil. Scotch Whiskey grew very significantly over the period. There are few local brands that did not do quite as well. Montilla in Brazil for instance, given the fact that duties skyrocketed, but the underlying trend remains good, and the mix and priority &#x2013; strategic priority trends are very auspicious indeed.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One final question perhaps.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Rijk from AIG (sic) [ING]. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, can I speak?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oui.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes? Okay. Gerard Rijk here, from ING. A few questions if I may. Restructuring costs I saw them in the one-offs, 44 million. Can you little bit where that happens those restructurings and what can we expect from savings from here and from further restructurings in finance year '11?</p>
          <p>Second question is on the COGS, can you comment what you expect in finance year '11? I saw stability in 2010, but what will happen in 2011 what is your &#x2013; your estimate here?</p>
          <p>And third question, you talked about good start July/August, are we then talking about same trends as fourth quarter, is that low single digit?</p>
          <p>And finally maybe about the pensions, you already answered that. You said that again in 2011 there might be expense, why is that? Why didn't you provide enough at the end of 2010? That's it.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will give you a very brief answer regarding the July/August trend, I think it's a good trend, but I am not putting numbers around it. I suggest we talk about it when we meet to speak about our first quarter sales. So I won't give you any numbers regarding the July and August trends we've observed.</p>
          <p>Regarding other things, Gilles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, regarding restructuring costs of &#x20AC;40 million these are all the restructuring programs that we've been unleashing here and there in a great many countries, I'm not going to give you the list. Spain is, of course, a major one. There were costs in the U.S. as well, in Ireland, in the U.K. so you see a string of restructuring programs in a number of countries.</p>
          <p>Moving on to your question on cost of goods sold, next year we are expecting a slight rise dry matter costs should rise very slightly. Glass, for instance, glass is a major chunk in our procurement while the increase should be very minor. As far as wet goods go, there should be slight increase in the price of cognac in the fact that the brandies we bought a few years ago are going to be pushed out of stocks. Regarding grain, the current prices have already increased. And the rise should be just a few million euros. In terms of profitability we're pretty well &#x2013; we are still pretty comfortable as far as grain goes.</p>
          <p>And regarding the pension item, this &#x2013; the impact is the net amount between the financial expenses for the discounting of the pension and the expected return on assets. So this changes depending on the discounting rate, you see...</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...and the interest rates and it depends on the expected yield, in other words the performance of the assets. Our commitments are slightly up, greater than our assets, which is why the negative &#x2013; the impact is negative. But overall, the minus &#x20AC;40 million should not become any worse next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now comes the final question. This will be the last question.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>The last...</p>
          <p>[In French; translation resumes]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have a tiny little question on Kahl&#xFA;a. You impaired Kahl&#xFA;a, transferred it &#x2013; you transferred it to Absolut, but we are under the impression that this is the last resort, that Kahl&#xFA;a is on its last legs. What is your feeling? Volume is pretty hefty. A disposal could help you further deleverage. Could you tell us your sentiment about Kahl&#xFA;a at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I believe our answer was very clear regarding Kahl&#xFA;a, switching our portfolio, when we reshaped our portfolio with the top 14 with the two global brands i.e. Absolut and Chivas and the premium brands and the prestige brands and Kahl&#xFA;a is indeed on the list. So it's not a last resort, as you say. Kahl&#xFA;a is in the portfolio. It's a priority brand and I wish it to remain that way. Kahl&#xFA;a is a brand that is very substantial in terms of volume. It's extremely profitable and it's a very strong brand in our liqueur segment. Indeed the liqueur segment is flying through turbulence as we speak.</p>
          <p>It's not just our products. The liqueur market is flying through some turbulence right now, but there has been strong growth over the past decade. So I'm quite confident Kahl&#xFA;a is a brand that will resume growth. And last year's performance was far from tragic, mind you, and quite honorable indeed. So regarding Kahl&#xFA;a we have no worries regarding its status and needless to say, the brands of the top 14 are not up for sale, they're not up for grabs.</p>
          <p>There you are. Denis, a word of conclusion, you want to wrap up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Thank you very much. It's all I can say and hope to see you soon. Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. Good bye.</p>
          <p>[In English; no translation]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call. Thank you all for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>