<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1454355" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8811</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman">Jan P. du Plessis</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Tom Albanese</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Director">Guy R. Elliott</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Rob B. Clifford</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Jason R. Fairclough</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">James F. Gurry</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Myles Allsop</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Lee Bowers</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Australia) Ltd.">Paul McTaggart</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Australia)">Paul D. Young</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley (Australia) Ltd.">Brendan Fitzpatrick</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Equities (Australia) Ltd.">Peter O'Connor</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Richard J. Hatch</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, <mark type="ph" /> Mark (00:08), can we roll, good.</p>
          <p>So good morning everyone here in London and good evening to those of you joining us from Australia. And welcome also to those of you participating via the webcast. Tom Albanese is with me here in London and Guy Elliott is presenting from Melbourne.</p>
          <p>Rio Tinto has performed strongly in 2011. We have today announced another set of record-breaking underlying earnings and cash flow numbers, reflecting favorable albeit increasingly unpredictable markets.</p>
          <p>This is, in my view, an excellent outcome but also want to acknowledge the significant impairment charge that we've taken in relation to the aluminum assets. This industry continues to be affected by oversupply and rising raw material costs, but I'm confident that we are doing all we can to turn this business around.</p>
          <p>On a more positive note, we were able to return $7.7 billion to our shareholders during 2011 through dividends and our share buyback program, which is now almost complete.  Looking forward, I remain cautious about near-term prospects for the global economy. I said to you six months ago that policymakers would grapple with these substantial economic imbalances that exist and that, of course, continues to be the case.</p>
          <p>But looking further ahead and beyond the current volatile markets, the medium to long-term picture remains positive for markets in metals and minerals with strong demand growth from emerging economies set to continue. The quality of our Tier 1 assets combined with our superior growth options and our positive long-term outlook gives us confidence in the sustainable long-term cash generating abilities of our business. For this reason, I'm recognizing the importance of sustainable long-term returns to shareholders, we have today increased our annual dividend by 34% to &#x20AC;1.35 (sic) [&#x20AC;1.45] per share.</p>
          <p>So that's all from my side. Thank you very much and I hand you over to Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jan. And before I start talking about quality of assets, as you say, Jan, the quality of the video feed's not so good, so Guy, when he gives his remarks will be sort of coming in and out, but you can be assured that the sound &#x2013; he can hear us and we can hear him.</p>
          <p>So let's speak about our full year results. But before I speak about those results, I'd like to start with safety. Last year, there were six fatalities at Rio Tinto managed operations. I deeply regret each of these tragic deaths, the devastating impact they've had on their colleagues and certainly their families. And I am certainly prepared to re-double any efforts to improve safety and tackle the root causes of all those accidents and any risks.</p>
          <p>This year we will focus on critical risks and some of the more serious accidents. But I do think, as a sector, we should recognize we're seeing some new risks out there in the safety front. As the industry continues to expand to meet this increasing demand, more new people are coming on board. We're seeing higher levels of turnover and higher levels of churn. We need to improve how we train new employees to learn safe working practices and how they can play their own part in keeping a strong safety culture.</p>
          <p>So this year, in addition to everything else, we will be focusing particularly on those front-line leaders who are so important in maintaining a safe work place for an expanding work force. The road to zero harm is challenging, but I'm not satisfied until our workforce is entirely injury-free and harm-free across the group.</p>
          <p>So let's now turn to 2011 results. We achieved record underlying earnings, record EBITDA and record operating cash flows. This was despite the severe weather conditions in the first half and the fall in commodity prices we saw through the second half. Our Pilbara iron ore business broke annual production and sales records and shipped record volumes in the fourth quarter, not &#x2013; of course, as Jan said, not all our divisions are enjoying those same tailwinds. At our November seminar, we outlined our refocused aluminum strategy in response to the uncertain and evolving macroeconomic conditions.</p>
          <p>As we did flag, we've had to impair some aluminum assets, which have been written down by $8.9 billion. We're working hard to improve the performance of our aluminum business, which I will come back to in a moment. Although we have made progress, I'm not content with our overall cost performance. Cost increases are an industry-wide problem, and I'm determined to tackle this at Rio Tinto and accelerating a number of productivity efforts.</p>
          <p>We're advancing our industry leading portfolio of growth projects, and it's worth highlighting that Pilbara has the highest quality iron ore expansion in the global sector. Pilbara at 283Mt/a is now fully approved and on track to reach this milestone by the end of next year. We brought forward plans for the next stage of expansion by six months, raised them to 20 million tonnes to 353 million tonnes per year. Subject to board approval, we will reach this capacity in the first half of 2015.</p>
          <p>This is in stark contrast to the broader iron ore industry trend, which has seen some projects subject to significant delay and increased capital intensity. We've successfully completed a number of acquisitions through the year, which complement our organic pipeline and give us further growth options.</p>
          <p>We now have significant Tier 1 resources in coking and thermal coal in Mozambique, and uranium in Canada. And earlier this year, we moved to majority stake in Ivanhoe Mines, further demonstrating our commitment to a safe and successful development of the Oyu Tolgoi copper-gold mine.</p>
          <p>Of course, just last week, we announced that we'll be doubling our stake in Richards Bay Minerals. And, as Jan mentioned, we have been able to balance this investment in growth with the return of capital to shareholders. And we've today increased our progressive dividend by 34%, demonstrating our confidence in the long-run outlook for this business.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to each of the product groups starting with iron ore. The iron ore business has turned another very impressive performance with another year of record production and shipments and our world-class Pilbara operation. Of course, this is underpinned by the highest ever EBITDA and underlying earnings for the product group.</p>
          <p>In line with the broader market, the second half of the year saw high levels of volatility in iron ore pricing, which led to a shift in the shorter term in our sales portfolio, so about 60% of our customers moving away from the quarterly lagged price. We continue to sell everything we produced through this period, and we achieved record prices on average in 2011. We continue to work closely with our customers in order to align our resource base with customer needs, and ensure the value in the use of our products is recognized by the market.</p>
          <p>On the supply side, we estimate that about 45 million tonnes of iron ore was removed from the market in 2011 due to adverse weather in the Pilbara, lower than expected Brazilian exports and rising export tariffs in India.</p>
          <p>We exceeded our production targets for 2011 and increased our annual capacity in the Pilbara to 225 million tonnes, completing our first debottlenecking project on time and on budget in the first quarter last year. This incremental capacity together with the continued productivity improvement from our industry leading operations center helped us achieve these records.</p>
          <p>It is important, of course, to &#x2013; remember, we're currently in the middle of the cyclone season in Western Australia, and already this year, we've seen some disruption and we'll a keep careful eye on all of the weather forecast.</p>
          <p>At IOC, concentrate production was maximized in the latter part of 2011 in response to market demand. The operational leadership shown by our Pilbara team is exceptionally important and all the more impressive when you consider that we're also well underway with the major expansion.</p>
          <p>At Cape Lambert, all the dredging for the expansion of 283 million tonnes is complete and engineering is at 82%. We've just approved the construction at Amaldi Mines, and so this 283 million tonne expansion is now fully authorized. And, of course, studies are progressing well and are accelerated and enhanced expansion to 353 million tonnes. We've already ordered the long-lead items, and just this week we approved $1.2 billion for further early works. Cape Lambert, as shown in the picture here, continues to be the best expansion opportunity in the industry with embedded optionality for further growth.</p>
          <p>We continue to drill out the resource base in our Tier 1 Pilbara ore bodies and over the next five years, we plan to drill another 600,000 meters per year to add to our 2.9 billion tonnes of iron ore reserve in line with our multi-decade mine planning. And our global growth options are not limited to the Pilbara. At our Canadian operations, the first stage of concentrate expansion project is currently being commissioned. And at Simandou in Guinea, solid progress has been made, early works construction is ramping up, including the construction of roadworks and the development of early trucking options.</p>
          <p>Moving on to aluminum. At the start of the year, with a tight physical aluminum market, global economic concerns took hold in the second half, leading to prices falling below $2,000 per tonne. Prices have recovered a little in early 2012 and are now trading about $2,200 per tonne.</p>
          <p>In China, aluminum prices have historically traded at a premium to the LME and have been less volatile. Despite experiencing a rising cost of electricity, higher margin cost smelters in the coastal and central provinces are able to take advantage of this higher Shanghai price premium. This has also led to a further expansion of smelting capacity at the remote but coal-rich provinces in the West, particularly in the Xinjiang province.</p>
          <p>Outside of China, we estimate roughly 2.5 million tonnes of smelting capacity is at a loss-making position at the current prices and input costs. Further capacity reductions are necessary to move the aluminum market to a more balanced state.</p>
          <p>The impact of higher raw material costs were also felt in the second half. The Japanese earthquake had a global impact on caustic soda prices. Costs for other raw materials, such as petcoke remained high and even as the price of aluminum fell. The squeeze effect has led to lower margins across the industry. As we did flag in November, our results were impacted by this margin squeeze in the second half. But the transformation program continued at Rio Tinto Alcan and delivered real benefits during the course of the year. Overall, we did achieve a full year EBITDA margin of 20% despite these headwinds.</p>
          <p>Looking further ahead, we continue to believe in our long-run outlook for aluminum demand growth. But Chinese output of primary aluminum is still tracking internal demand. Production has shifted more towards the Northwest, where stranded coal is being used to generate cheaper electricity.</p>
          <p>We had not previously anticipated the extent of this shift in new smelting capacity to the west of China. These pressures together with the strengthening of some currencies and escalating raw materials may continue to squeeze our margins over the medium term. I continue to believe a 40% margin is achievable, but I can't predict when the prices will recover or when raw material costs will improve to that margin &#x2013; to when that margin can be achieved. So we are focusing all that we can do in areas that we control to improve the performance of our aluminum business and the quality of our aluminum portfolio.</p>
          <p>In November, we've outlined our strategy do just this. We've had to make some tough decisions such as the identification of a number of businesses that no longer fit with our strategy nor our portfolio and so will be closed or divested. And the result will be an aluminum business that's smaller than it is today, but one that is of higher quality.</p>
          <p>Programs are underway to deliver $1 billion of incremental EBITDA from business improvements. And we are focusing investment on the high return creep and modernization projects. We'll be longer in bauxite and alumina, taking full advantage of our exceptional Tier 1 bauxite resources, and with have a portfolio of modern hydro-based smelters supported by leading industry technology.</p>
          <p>This is absolutely the right strategy, but it has required us to relook at the value ascribed to aluminum assets. As a result, we have recorded an impairment charge this year, which Guy will speak to in more detail.</p>
          <p>The current environment in aluminum industry is tough, rising LME inventories, high raw material costs and strong currencies are leading to less investment being allocated to growth projects. But I think the long-term outlook remains intact and my focus to ensure that we've done all we can to optimize our position when the industry improves. But I firmly believe we're on track to secure our position as the lowest cost aluminum producer in the industry.</p>
          <p>Turning now to copper. As we've been saying for the past two years, the physical tightness of copper is leading to copper continuing to trade significantly above the marginal cost of production. While supply and demand factors appear to support the price level, near-term price movements are highly geared to global macroeconomic indicators, the expectation of continued supply deficit and the relative strength of the U.S. dollar.</p>
          <p>In 2011, the copper market was in deficit with the shortfall of supply met by drawing down supplies mainly in China. We expect the market to continue to be finally balanced in 2012. New global copper mine supply is expected to come online in 2012. However, experience has shown that project delivery and ramp-up timelines have taken longer, globally, than expected.</p>
          <p>Interruptions for industrial action as strikes along with continued industry-wide decline to grades will put further pressure on new supply. We produced less copper in 2011 from an anticipated declining grade in all three of our major operations. But it's also important to remember the benefits of our gold exposure in these uncertain markets. Although we don't have any primary gold mines and gold by-products are likely to decrease in 2012, we are one of the larger gold producers in the world and the biggest among the diversified miners.</p>
          <p>They shouldn't go unnoticed, the Grasberg and Oyu Tolgoi are two of the world's largest gold resources. We do expect copper grades to recover in the second half of 2012 and from 2013, we also see new production coming from Oyu Tolgoi in Mongolia. Organic growth will be offset by the absence of production for Palabora, which we intend to divest. This is no longer in line with our strategic focus.</p>
          <p>Just a few weeks ago, just shortly after the expiry of the standstill agreement with Ivanhoe, we &#x2013; our shareholding Ivanhoe increased to a majority 51% interest. The project itself has made good progress. But as you know, discussions continue on security of power source for the project, we still needed to remain on schedule. I have a feasibility study to Phase II to develop the underground block cave mine continues to make progress.</p>
          <p>We're also, of course, moving forward on other Tier 1 copper projects. La Granja received prefeasibility funding to evaluate a three-staged phase development using conventional milling and leaching. The feasibility study at Kennecott Utah Copper to extend the mine life to 2028 is expected to be complete in the first half of this year. And again at Escondida, project approval for OGP1 is targeted for the first half of 2012.</p>
          <p>The Resolution project, the land exchange, took an important step in 2011 with a clearance in the U.S. House, and we now expect it to move to the U.S. Senate. While the land exchange process continues, we did approve of $103 million expenditure with our partner BHP, and the Shaft 9 development is expected to continue.</p>
          <p>So again, now let's turn to our Energy group. In 2011 coal markets were volatile with both global supply and demand disruptions occurring at different times throughout the year after cheering near-record prices in January 2011, following Indonesian and Australian supply side disruptions, global thermal coal markets experienced broad price declines through the remainder of 2011.</p>
          <p>This decline reflected weaker global economic activity and strong supply growth, however, prices remain well supported. While the uranium market is likely to be subdued over the next few &#x2013; five years, uranium will continue to form an important part in the overall energy mix, with long-term demand expected to be driven by strong growth in China.</p>
          <p>Our Energy operations in Australia recovered well from the effects of significant wet weather that occurred extensively in Queensland, New South Wales and the Northern territory in the first quarter of 2011. Disruptions to the supply of explosives in Eastern Australia has impacted overburden removal for some of our New South Wales operations as it has in the rest of the East Australian mining sector, with the consequential effect to the level of in-pit inventories.</p>
          <p>Though there was no overall significant impact to the Australian coal production in 2011, there will be some impact in the first half of 2012. As part of our continuous program to improve our portfolio, we just completed joint acquisition of the minority interest in Coal &amp; Allied in December in partnership with Mitsubishi. And this has resulted in a simpler ownership structure with greater flexibility and access to funds for growth.</p>
          <p>At ERA, extreme wet weather caused the prolonged suspension of operations in the first half, but the operations did recover well in the second half. AUD 500 million rights issue was completed in December, which will allow ERA to fund its strategic water management plan, closure obligations and the Ranger 3 Deeps exploration decline. At R&#xF6;ssing, grade will progressively improve over the next two years as we access lower benches in the mine. Meanwhile, work continues on excavation drilling to extend mine life beyond 2023.</p>
          <p>Our Energy group is now entering a new phase with many prospects for value-adding growth in the near term and beyond. At Australia, our target has increased annual coal capacity to 73 million tonnes per year by 2015. This growth will be underpinned by the development of new mine at Mount Pleasant in the Hunter Valley, which is currently in feasibility study.</p>
          <p>In the short term, we're increasing capacity at existing operations, such as the Clermont Mine and the brownfield expansions into Hunter Valley, Mount Thorley Warkworth and at Bengalla. These will lead to an increase of about 15% to 20% in total Australian coal production in 2012. The Kestrel Mine extension is well advanced and is scheduled to start production in 2013 with incremental annual production of around 1 million tonnes. Infrastructure will be a critical factor in the delivery of this growth, and our position for the future continues to strengthen.</p>
          <p>In New South Wales and Queensland, investment has been made in the coal supply chain to meet this increasing demand. During the first half of the year, we completed the acquisition of Riversdale, which has now been renamed Rio Tinto Coal Mozambique. There's a good photo of it in the upper side of the plant and under construction at present. This does provides a substantial Tier 1 coking coal development pipeline in the emerging Moatize basin. Initial production from the Benga project is scheduled for the first half of this year.</p>
          <p>Following the Riversdale transaction, we completed the acquisition of Hathor in Canada, and these encouraging uranium exploration development opportunities are one of the highest grade uranium basins in the world. With the forecast demand for energy and steel production over the coming decades, I have real confidence the high quality growth projects being pulled together by the Energy team, will deliver excellent results over the long term.</p>
          <p>Turning now to diamonds and minerals. Demand for borates and titanium dioxide feedstocks held up well despite ongoing market volatility. 2011 saw a continued tightness in TiO2 feedstock supply, which is expected to continue over the medium term. Diamond prices were strong in the first half of 2011, but the second half did see lower prices due to high inventories. Long-term fundamentals for diamonds do remain strong with limited supply of new diamonds and further potential for diamond growth in China and India. Diamond production did decline 15%, overall, due to heavy rains we saw due to flooding at Argyle early in the year and maintenance shutdowns that we saw at Argyle in the fourth quarter in the processing plant.</p>
          <p>The impact of the record wet season in Argyle, coupled with the continued strength of the Australian dollars, did result in a further $500 million of capital be improved &#x2013; being approved to complete the Argyle underground project. And we would expect to experience lower grades until the underground mine is at full production by 2014.</p>
          <p>Earnings for Iron &amp; Titanium business did double in 2011 as we continue to replace these multi-year sales contracts with alternative pricing mechanism, increasing the business' exposure to market prices for TiO2 feedstocks.</p>
          <p>At QMM and Madagascar, production steadily increased due to successful dry mining operations. Full capacity is expected to be reached over the next two to three years. As you know, we sold our talc business in August and have created new opportunities in potash through a joint venture agreement in Saskatchewan, home to nearly half the world's potash reserves.</p>
          <p>And finally, just last week, we announced we'll be doubling our stake in Richards Bay Minerals on Tier 1 asset that we've been managing for many years, actually, many decades.</p>
          <p>Overall, each of the product groups have delivered solid results through 2011. So with that, I'll hand it over to you, Guy, in Melbourne, recognizing that you're working on your video quality, but we can hear you and I hope you can hear us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom. Good morning, everybody. I can certainly hear you well and I hope you can you can hear me.</p>
          <p>Let me start by taking a look at how our record underlying earnings were achieved. It will come as no surprise that the primary driver has been price, increasing earnings by $6.7 billion. By far, the largest benefit came from iron ore prices, although, copper and hard coking coal increases were also significant. These benefits were partially offset by the impact of currency movements, notably, the stronger Australian dollar. These collectively reduced our underlying earnings by nearly $1 billion compared with 2010.</p>
          <p>As previously flagged, lower copper and gold grades at Kennecott Utah Copper, Escondida and Grasberg have led to lower sales volumes, which reduced our earnings by just over $0.5 billion. This was partially offset by record volumes from iron ore as increased port capacity was brought online.</p>
          <p>Continued cost pressure is evident throughout the industry and we are not immune. The impacts of inflation and higher energy costs reduced our 2011 earnings by over $600 million. And more importantly, higher cash costs reduced earnings by a further $2.1 billion, which I'll return to in detail in a moment.</p>
          <p>During 2011, we progressed many of our evaluation projects, including Simandou, Resolution and La Granja, as well as our newly acquired Mozambique coal project. The effect of higher exploration and evaluation costs together with the absence of gains on undeveloped property sales, lowered earnings by just under $800 million. And so after the impact of higher non-cash costs and other items, our underlying earnings were $15.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning now to net earnings. Back in November, we indicated that there would be some asset impairment, following a deterioration of macroeconomic conditions and stronger currencies. The valuation used for impairment testing is based on our assessment of fair market value, less cost of sale, at the testing date. This is determined using a number of reference points including current industry share price multiples.</p>
          <p>Strong currencies in some regions, high raw material costs and rising LME inventory are delaying growth projects for new aluminum capacity, and leading to much lower market values for aluminum assets than a year ago. Given these uncertain macroeconomic conditions, the market valuation used for impairment purposes does not fully reflect the value of our planned EBITDA improvement, and the successful implementation of our growth projects.</p>
          <p>The combination of these factors has led us to write off $8.9 billion of our aluminum assets in 2011, of which $7.4 billion was goodwill. Elsewhere, there were net impairments of just over $400 million in our diamonds and other businesses. This was largely due to the higher capital cost now expected for us to complete the Argyle mine. Other exclusions included a deferred tax asset write-off due to change in French legislation and a number of other smaller items. So overall, net earnings came in at $5.8 billion.</p>
          <p>We're turning now to costs. As previously discussed, the whole of the mining industry is experiencing cost pressures and localized inflation far in excess of normal CPI. Markets for raw materials remain tight as activity has increased across the industry. This was particularly felt at Rio Tinto Alcan, as prices for caustic soda, coke and pitch have remained at elevated levels even in a softer aluminum market. Reduced production volumes from lower copper and gold grade led to higher unit cost of production. This effect will reverse in time as we anticipate grade recovery in the second half of 2012.</p>
          <p>The exceptional weather experienced in the first half of the year also impacted our volume and, as a consequence, increased our unit cash costs. And we've also incurred additional cost due to our investment in operational readiness as we prepare to bring online a number of major growth projects, in particular in the Pilbara.</p>
          <p>We are determined to tackle these issues and are accelerating a number of cost and productivity initiatives. In order to combat rising raw materials costs, we are continuing to look at alternative suppliers. We spent approximately $1 billion in China in 2011, up from $0.5 billion in 2010.</p>
          <p>Purchases from China include coke, caustic soda, rail cars and other supply. And we will also continue to mitigate some of these cost increases through our industry leading investments in technology. This will lead to increased automation and improve productivity across many of our operations in years to come.</p>
          <p>Despite these pressures, we generated record cash flows from our operations and this was achieved with the decline in dividends from equity accounted unit, primarily due to the retention of cash within Escondida in order to fund its growth plan.</p>
          <p>Momentum returned to our rate of spend on capital projects during the year, resulting in total capital expenditure of $12.3 billion. We supplemented these investments with just over $6 billion of value accretive transactions. This included the acquisitions of Riversdale and Hathor and the AUD 258 million, we paid to increase our stake in Coal &amp; Allied to 80%. And we also increased our interest in Ivanhoe Mines from 40.5% to 49%, and participated in Ivanhoe's rights offering for a total consideration of $1.9 billion. In January, we moved to a majority stake in Ivanhoe, taking our interest to 51%.</p>
          <p>Let me remind you that our average entry price into Ivanhoe has been under $12 per share. During the year, we paid $6.2 billion of tax, 50% more than 2010. Of course, taxes are paid with a slight lag. We had around $2.5 billion of tax accruals in respect to 2011 that will be paid in early 2012. These amounts relate to corporate taxes only, our total payments to government, including royalties, are much higher, and this will be set out in detail in our tax transparency report, which we'll be publishing in March.</p>
          <p>We continue to balance investing in the business with returning capital to shareholders. During 2011, we returned a total of $7.7 billion to shareholders through the progressive dividend and share buyback program. Overall, after taking into account interest and various other cash flows, we increased net debt by $4.4 billion to $8.5 billion at the end of December.</p>
          <p>As I just described, capital expenditure ramped up in the second half, most of our projects remain on time and on budget in local currency terms. There have been a few exceptions such as our Argyle and Kestrel, primarily driven by decisions made in 2008 and 2009 to slow down the rate of spend.</p>
          <p>We expect capital expenditure of $16 billion in 2012 based on sustaining capital and major projects already approved. This amount is likely to rise as we approve further projects mainly in the Pilbara. Looking further out, CapEx will remain around this level for several years as we complete a number of multi-year major construction projects. This is a substantial program of investment, but one that we are undertaking in a controlled manner.</p>
          <p>We're taking a phased approach to many of our major project approvals, such as our decision to expand the Pilbara in two stages. This phased approach allows us to commit capital in a risk measured way, balancing our capital expenditure commitments with the market environment and other potential uses of cash. This is critical, we're managing an investment program in the tens of billions of dollars, and it means that if market conditions were to rapidly deteriorate, we can defer or modify subsequent stages.</p>
          <p>Our capital spend in 2012, is well distributed, both geographically and by product. Brownfield expansions in Australia, Canada and the United States account for the great preponderance of our plan spend. But we're also investing in new emerging resource basins, most notably in Mongolia. While I believe we have an enviable track record of completing our expansion plans on time and on budget, we recognize it is becoming increasingly difficult for the industry to bring new supply to market.</p>
          <p>This is well illustrated by the iron ore market, where projected industry supply growth has consistently over-promised and under-delivered. There are many different hurdles, technically challenging ore bodies, competition for skilled labor and higher stakeholder demands. Given the challenges that commercial banks are facing, project finance has become more difficult to source for some companies, a situation that has worsened in the past six months.</p>
          <p>Resource nationalism is becoming more prominent. This manifests itself in many ways, one of the more visible in recent times, has been the rapid changes in tax policy proposed by some governments. Rio Tinto's approach is to engage with governments in the development of tax policy, and to be open and transparent about the amount of tax that we pay. These challenges altogether lead to increased risk, and higher cost of capital, not just for project developers but also for host communities as investors seek stable low risk geographies for investment. Rio Tinto is well-placed to address these challenges through our strong balance sheet and our emphasis on sustainable development and stakeholder engagement.</p>
          <p>So to wrap up with our well-established and consistent financial strategy, our balance sheet is strong. Within the parameters of a single A credit rating, our first priority for the use of our cash flows is to increase shareholder value by investment in high quality growth. As I said earlier, we expect to spend $16 billion on capital projects this year and we have a rich portfolio of opportunities ahead of us. And we're committed to a balance of investment in growth and returns to shareholders. As I've said, we returned a total of $7.7 billion to shareholders during 2011 through our progressive dividend and share buybacks.</p>
          <p>The board continuous to see attractive and significant growth opportunities and short-term uncertainty in the financial market, particularly around the euro. For these reasons, the board does not believe that it's appropriate to expand the buyback program at this time. However, we continue to keep this under review. While share buybacks are an effective means to return short-term excess capital, a progressive dividend provides sustainable and predictable long-term returns to shareholders. It also demonstrates our confidence in the long-run outlook for our business. Given this, we've now decided to raise our full year dividend by 34%. This leads to a final dividend of US$0.91 per share and a full year payout of US$1.45. Applying our usual formulaic approach, we therefore expect our interim dividend in 2012 to be US$0.725 per share.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me hand you back to Tom</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Guy. Let me just take a moment for a deeper dive of what's driving our current market conditions. 2011 really was a year of two halves for commodity prices. We did see a strong first half followed by weakness, though, in the second half. And almost all the commodity prices finished the year lower than they started. These price declines that you see in the chart were driven by ongoing macroeconomic uncertainty, associated with the debt &#x2013; sovereign debt crisis in Europe and the impact of policy actions in China aimed at cooling down the economy and reducing their own inflation rates.</p>
          <p>So far in 2012, we've seen some more positive signs, with improvements seen in most of our prices. I've been following closely the performance on the ground and talking with each of the marketing teams, we are experiencing some softness in the European markets, more so in Southern Europe, for example, industrial minerals producers that sell into the ,say, the Portuguese and the Spanish; Thailand is really going tough, but Northern Europe hasn't been so bad. Certainly, in the U.S. we've seen some robust buying conditions. We've got pretty much aligned with what we've been seeing in terms of job creation and GDP numbers of the U.S. And I think, in general, stability in Asia, while everyone sees how Asia businesses come out of the Chinese New Year. However, just remember, we are only in February, we do expect heightened economic and political uncertainties that continue to weigh on sentiment and increased market volatility over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>In Europe, recent indications do suggest the sovereign debt crisis has finally spilled over to the real economy in Europe, with expectations now pointing to a contraction in the eurozone in 2012.</p>
          <p>In contrast, in the U.S., a number of recent indicators have surprised on the upside, leading to expectations the U.S. may be stronger in 2012 than all of us would've previously thought. However, of course, in the U.S. as you know, risk remain with high unemployment and a weak housing market.</p>
          <p>In our key Chinese markets, the signs continue to point to a soft landing, which is what we've been saying for the past year, with growth in excess of 8% in 2012. But of course, there's a wide range of uncertainties and potential outcomes ahead of us, globally, over the short term. There are a number of tensions in the global economy, including the sovereign debt crisis that was on the news on Greece this morning and elections that we see in a number of key countries, not to mention, structural imbalances. So while the risk of European contagion is high, we do expect the emerging economies, particularly in China, to remain resilient. And I believe that impact of current economic concerns on our business should be manageable, unless, of course, financial markets substantially deteriorate.</p>
          <p>Looking further ahead and shifting to the long-term outlook, which drives the decisions we're taking today to invest in capital growth. Despite the volatility we're currently experiencing, our view of long-term demand remains pretty much the same, that is, as the world gets richer, we expect to see billions of people moving through the increasingly metal intensive phases of development.</p>
          <p>The industry, as Guy says, does continue to face challenges with the supply side, from rising raw material and labor costs as well as industrial action and weather events. And projects, as you've heard, will becoming increasingly difficult to finance for some, and the capital intensity for both projects is continuing rise. Resource nationalism and long processes for permitting, stakeholder engagement improvals also have the effect of reducing supply growth. Of course, geologically, the deposits are becoming more difficult to find and, technically, more difficult to develop. And all these factors will continue to put pressure on the supply side within the environment of this increasing demand. This development, of course, will go through periods of volatility such as what we're currently facing right now.</p>
          <p>At Rio Tinto, we have to look beyond the current market turmoil. We do see major structural changes happening in the global economy. So longer term demand picture remains positive and the Chinese growth story does have some way to run.</p>
          <p>By utilizing our strong balance sheet, we continue to invest throughout the cycle on high quality growth options to meet this future demand. We are clear about the strategy that we have been pursuing, which is continue to pursue, that is, invest and operate large, long-term cost competitive mines and businesses driven by the quality of each opportunity.</p>
          <p>We own some of the world's best operating assets. We have an unrivalled portfolio of quality growth options and a proven track record of developing major projects on time and on budget. It's also becoming more difficult to bring new sources of supply into the market. Rising cost, more challenging ore bodies and greater stakeholder engagements are leading us to think more carefully and more creatively about how we will allocate our capital.</p>
          <p>Our phase approach to investment and growth allows us to manage some of this risk, while creating embedded options that can deliver value over that long term. So in line with this strategy, we currently have $33 billion worth of major capital projects underway, including those recently announced.</p>
          <p>The rate of spend for each of these projects ramped up in the second half of 2011, with higher levels of capital expenditure continuing in 2012 and, as Guy said, 2013. Projects are making good progress. The first production from nine of these projects listed here are expected to occur during the course of this year. This investment is focused on large, long-life, cost competitive projects across a wide range of products in line with our strategy. We're also differentiating ourselves through a leadership in the development and implementation of innovative technologies. I, for one, am genuinely excited about the step changes in technology, which include our Mine of the Future program.</p>
          <p>Late last year, we announced we've come out to the expansion of our driverless fleet in the Pilbara from 10 to 150 trucks, the first operational deployment of this technology in deployment in Australia or anywhere else of such a scale. These trucks can be run from the operation center in Perth, 1,200 kilometers away. And we're seeing the benefits of that operation center increasingly becoming evident in our day-to-day production and conduct of the businesses.</p>
          <p>Rio Tinto will also be deploying autonomous drills and driverless trains, expanding our leadership in this area. Of course, in the Copper group, our tunnel boring system remains on schedule. The trial's due to start in Northparkes early in the second half of this year. We're evaluating opportunities also to trial a second boring &#x2013; tunnel boring system.</p>
          <p>Over in the Exploration group, work has led to the finding and developing of the next generation of ore bodies, from bauxite in Brazil through the potash in Saskatchewan, new projects across the globe are delivering promising results.</p>
          <p>So to conclude, 2011 has been another record-breaking year for Rio Tinto. We've delivered record underlying earnings, EBITDA and operating cash flows. Our balance sheet is strong as our investment program continues to gather momentum. We have accelerated our iron ore expansion at Pilbara, which I believe is the highest value, lowest risk iron ore project anywhere in the world. And we've secured future growth options through acquisition of our expertise in ore body knowledge. At the same time, we continue to balance our investment program with long-term shareholder returns through the rebasing of our dividend.</p>
          <p>To summarize, we are delivering exceptional operating and financial performance. We have some of the best expansion options available in the industry today. A leadership position in operations, exploration, innovation and sustainable development, and a long established strategy of focusing on large worldwide cost-competitive and expandable assets. All of these advantages position us well to continue to enhance shareholder value over the long term as evidenced by today by the action on the dividend.</p>
          <p>So with that, Guy and I will be happy to take any questions. What I'll do is I'll start with the audience here in London and then we'll move over to the telephone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Rob Clifford, Deutsche Bank. Two questions, please. Tom, firstly, just &#x2013; could you talk a bit more about the issues surrounding getting power to Oyu Tolgoi, what are the issues there and what are the hurdles?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just on CapEx protection, three-quarters of your CapEx is being spent in Australia and Canada, so this is not the diversification you had in the past, and while commodity prices and currencies are often naturally hedged when you're building a project, you're not producing those commodities. So for instance, the blowout at Argyle changes the economics of that project substantially, so how are you going about thinking on protecting CapEx against currency?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rob. I'll start maybe by talking about power at OT and then I'll ask Guy to comment on the Australian and the Canadian capital projects. I know you asked that question at the interims about hedging and what we do on the currency fluctuations.</p>
          <p>First of all on OT, we have two things that are being done that will need to be done on the power. The first is the construction of the power line on the Chinese side of the border between power generating capacity and the OT operations. And second would be the power supply agreements. While we have continued to, I think, make good progress on the construction activities, there will be a point in time we'll need that power to start the commissioning process to be ready by 2013. We're well within that window now and I'm very pleased with the work that's going on the ground, actually on both areas. I think that part of it will be engineering, engineering activities on the ground. The actual construction, which again, is something that is measurable and definable and I think there are actually good efforts and I'm confident are underway as we speak.</p>
          <p>The secondary, in terms of power supply agreements, that will involve the activity of the Oyu Tolgoi team on the ground but also close cooperation, which we've continue to see between the governments of Magnolia and China. And again, I've actually been quite pleased with the progress on that front. To some extent, we could influence that, to some extent, that is a government-to-government discussion. So with &#x2013; Guy, can you maybe talk about capital and currency?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start by challenging you a little bit, Rob. I mean the purpose of drawing attention to the whereabouts of a lot of our capital spend was to remind you that we have very great opportunities to invest in the heartlands of our business. Some people have perceived that the company has moved in the direction decisively of investing in emerging market regions. And we are doing some of that. We're obviously investing Mongolia, in Mozambique, in Guinea, Madagascar, et cetera. But the point that we're making in relation to the spread of capital expenditure is that a lot of it's going into our traditional heartlands such as North America and Australia.</p>
          <p>Now on the subject of the particular risk you're talking about of currency, this is something we are looking at again. And as I've said before, we will tell shareholders if we make a change. It's actually quite difficult to suddenly lock in when the Australian dollar is at $1.07, your capital expenditure, is that a good judgment or not? That's the kind of question we're asking ourselves. We recognize, as you say, that we have had some currency hit on our project.</p>
          <p>You mentioned Argyle, actually, I mean although currency contributed to that, there were a number of other features to that overrun. The first being that we slowed the project down in the global financial crisis and that had a whole lot of demobilization and then remobilization effects. And on top of that, we have the effect of the weather last year, which certainly has led to some difficult conditions, which had safety implications within the mine. So we had to slow things down. So there were a number of other features in the case of Argyle. But anyway, to reassure you, we are looking at it and if we make a change, we will tell the shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason Fairclough, Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Two questions, if I may. First, just on CapEx, yesterday, we heard from BHP that they're dialing back CapEx expectations a little bit, and that seems to be driven by two things. It's a concern on the bottlenecks in the capital formation process and then beyond that, they're concerned about a deceleration of steel demand growth in China. So just wondering, it's quite a different message from you today. Maybe you could talk a little bit about your confidence about committing this much capital to iron ore still?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Jason. I'm going to talk about iron ore and our longer term view of iron ore. Frankly, we're &#x2013; we probably have some similar ideas of where we might have a different approach from BHP. Our view on steel demand in China is that we are moving toward a point, which you would expect of deceleration of steel consumption growth in China, and that's nothing that would be surprising. I think all modelers and econometric forecasters have been saying, at some point in the S curve, it's inevitable that there will be a slowdown.</p>
          <p>And we're in that stage that you're moving from steel consumption leading GDP to steel consumption beginning to lag GDP, while GDP growth begins to moderate but from a much larger base. And just as a reminder of that larger base, we had very, very rapid steel consumption increases in 2007, which we had been flagging. It's slowed down since then but the overall level of steel consumption in China is more than 40% higher than 2007. So it's slowing down from a much larger base.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile, the Chinese domestic iron ore production is not getting any better. It's not getting any cheaper. It's not getting any more efficient. It's actually rising in terms of its overall cost levels. You have expansions flagged in Australia in Brazil and in lesser extent, in West Africa but you also have production coming out of the market likely on a trend basis from India. So we had to look at all these individual balances when we map out what levels of capacity is there in the seaborne market.</p>
          <p>I do think that, as I said in my comments, we have some of the best quality iron ore assets and I think that &#x2013; I want to refer to quality on several ways. The first is it is closer to the Chinese market than the Brazilian material. The Australian material is actually more accessible and no matter how big you build the ships, it still, proximity makes a difference. So I think that &#x2013; I'd rather have proximity over size any day.</p>
          <p>I think that in the case of, then, the resource &#x2013; it's about having the large amount of resources, that's actually clustered and can be developed as we have been so successful in doing, and the ability to continue to improve and innovate and add to the efficiencies, which is exactly also what we are doing.</p>
          <p>The third piece of it would be the ability to phase the capital. And what we have been doing different than what BHP has been doing is that we have the ability to phase this in $50 million increments, by just frankly, adding two berths at a time to the Cape Lambert facility. That allows us &#x2013; when we look at this capital, we discuss it with the board, it allows us to say, well, we'll take just look at it and then let's wait to see how the markets eventuate before we come up with the next tranche. And by having a series of smaller tranches and having a construction project that's phased and organized actually &#x2013; and actually adapt to those tranches, it gives us time to see what is the actual trajectory of the Chinese demand growth. I mean it has surprised to the upside so far. At some point in time, it's inevitable, it's going to be slowing down, which gives us the chance to manage that.</p>
          <p>And the final step, I think, is capital intensity. I'm very, very pleased with the capital intensity comparative to the rest of the sector, although I'm concerned about the fact that capital intensity in general has increased, which probably has just increased the reason why we do need to phase in some of these next tranches.</p>
          <p>Now in addition to Pilbara, of course, we have IOC, which is basically has added an even smaller bites with these various smaller expansions, especially in concentrate capacity, we have the magnetite resource, it's just a matter of developing the concentrating, the gravity separation, the magnetic separation, so we can increase concentrate production.</p>
          <p>And at Simandou where in addition to the rail line developments, which will take over the next several years, I think I would expect to see parallel road shipping, which allows us again to build tonnes in the market and then as the market continues to grow, it allows the market to understand the quality of material. And I would expect to see a premium value and use for that material. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow up question if it's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In iron ore, I think it's fair to say that you guys got dragged kicking and screaming to the spot market, could you talk a little bit about price discovery for titanium dioxide and how that's going to eventuate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think that the market in iron ore has evolved to a point where, basically, there's been more volume in the spot market from, say, compared to five years ago. So there has been actually a price discovery mechanism on the shorter term. As you know, we've said that we will work with customers who want longer term contracts as long as it's deliverable on both sides of that contract. And so I think you will see differentiation between customers, some which will be ready to live with the good and the bad of a longer term , say, quarterly contract, others that probably could be better suited for a very short-term market.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of TiO2, I think that the structure of the TiO2 market, which is not as big as iron ore obviously, but we have a very big part of it, has been one of contracts on a business-to-business basis. And I think these contracts have served Rio Tinto iron and titanium well over the past 20 years, during a period of time when the sector had been, I think, a mature sector, primarily driven off of North American and European building construction and painting seasons and sort of the conventional attributes of the pigment sector. What we've seen &#x2013; we would have seen in it coming, but it's finally happened, is that the Chinese are beginning to play into these industrial minerals that are more consumer oriented.</p>
          <p>So the Chinese consumer is actually demanding a higher quality of paint, that means these &#x2013; a higher quality of pigment, which means a higher quality of feedstock. So we're well-positioned on the supply side for that, but we still have these existing contracts that we do &#x2013; we will honor them, we will work them through. In some cases, we're finding some of the customers are coming to us saying, well, they're worried about the end of those contracts, while they may get a good price for a longer period, at the end of it, they might not have any supply at all. So again, they're coming and saying, well, we will be happy to talk with you about moving to a shorter term, earlier on, if you can give us some security supply after the end of what would have been the contract.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At the back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks Tom, it's James Gurry from Credit Suisse. I just want to talk about Pacific Aluminum and can you just tell us when do you think you might divest that asset and whether you expect to achieve above book value for that asset when you do eventually divest it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, as we've said that we're not going to be in a rush to do it for balance sheet purposes. We're going to look to the market opportunities. But maybe, Guy, if you could cover both those points?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean we are value driven, and we were over minded as to the way in which we sell this business, we could IPO it, we could distribute it to our shareholders in specie, we could sell it to trade buyers in &#x2013; as a whole or in pieces. So there's a lot of different ways, we could do this. We're not under any pressure, as we said earlier, we've got a strong balance sheet and we're in a position where we can look for value. As to the value that we might get for this business, it is not an easy time to be selling aluminum assets right now. But as I tried to explain, when dealing with the impairment, we have taken the values of the aluminum businesses including Pacific Aluminum down to what we think the market level is.</p>
          <p>Now that's difficult to be quite sure what it is, but we've done our very best through a mechanistic process. And therefore, you might think that it does approximate to the value that might be attainable in a sale. But as I said, we're not going to be rushed into that. We're going to look to maximize value. And one means that we're using to get there is to try and manage the business in a different way. So we put a new team into that business. We have separated the business from Rio Tinto Alcan and we're running it as if it were already a separate entity altogether. And we're hoping that that's going to generate real improvements in the business. That should all help in the sale process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, could I &#x2013; just wanted to say that the team at <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:51) are doing a real good job and even just the first 100 days of work, in terms of thinking about ways to improve the business, thinking about the business differently than in the larger Rio Tinto. And I think we're going to learn some things that we can apply elsewhere to Rio Tinto as a consequence of that.</p>
          <p>So one more question from here, and then we'll go over to phone lines, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Myles Allsop, UBS. Could you talk a bit more about your uranium strategy more broadly. But in particular, Hathor, do you see that as a standalone project or platform for further growth in the region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, Myles. If I look at the uranium markets and I talk with our team in Rio Tinto Energy, my view is that uranium's going to be probably one of the least exciting one of our markets for at least the next five years. And the way we could plot that out is the fact that you can really see plants, either they're in construction or they're not in construction, take many years to get built. And we've seen with &#x2013; certainly with the post-Fukushima world, some countries deferring projects, some countries leading policies, right or wrong, that basically are trying to be moving away from nuclear power.</p>
          <p>And with that being said, there continues to be, especially in China, but I think elsewhere in the world, a need for large central sources of power, a large and &#x2013; distributor systems, the environmentalists might think, that's all you need, is windmills on every house, but that's not going to work. You're going to need large central systems. You've got options of basically hydro and that's not an easily expandable power source. You've got options of nuclear, you've got options of coal and increasingly, there's more and more pressures on future generators to think about something besides coal. And that's even more the case as we see the markets for carbon beginning eventuate, and of course, natural gas. So I guess I think natural gas will probably one in the post-2020, which would go more head-to-head with nuclear. But for those countries that don't have natural gas or they're not conveniently situated for LNG or just LNG is fairly expensive by then, nuclear power looks quite attractive.</p>
          <p>And I think in China and elsewhere, in the post 2020 environment, I do see nuclear power and uranium to be a growing part of the global energy mix. I would not be surprised if by post-2020, global energy requirements are actually higher than what people are forecasting for the same reasons that we're looking at higher steel consumptions and higher copper consumption.</p>
          <p>So for that &#x2013; what it means for our strategy is essentially be prudent, at least for the next five years in terms of what we're are investing in the sector, no big bets. We have some house-cleaning to do at our ERA business. We have to move from open-pit to underground over the next year. We have to deal with the water issues from a series of what were record-high rainfalls. And then we will be well-positioned, I think, in that post-2020 period with options at that point.</p>
          <p>R&#xF6;ssing too, R&#xF6;ssing's a mature mine, the existing ore body is sort of at the bottom of the pit is not &#x2013; there's not a lot of room in the bottom pit to move. We have to undertake the next stage of pre-stripping, which is what's going on at R&#xF6;ssing to basically expose that next generation of ore, which will be in there in the post five-year period. And of course, as the commercial situation of R&#xF6;ssing South eventuates, I would hope to be in a position where we could think about the benefits of unitization, which I think makes sense commercially. They can make sense from a sustainable development perspective. I think it make sense from a national Namibian perspective.</p>
          <p>And then finally in Canada, we should remind ourselves that the Athabasca Basin contains, by an order of magnitude, some of the highest quality and highest grade uranium ores in the world. I mean this is &#x2013; materially, you have to actually dilute before you could put it in the mill, it's so rich, it's 100 times higher in grade than the grade at R&#xF6;ssing. So great grade does make a lot of sense in this business if you can get good grades. Our geologists basically they look around at all sorts of opportunities and all sorts of sectors and our geologists were quite excited about this opportunity that came to us.</p>
          <p>As you know, I've listened to geologists in the past. We've had some pretty good hits, Oyu Tolgoi being one of them, and they said this is a place to look. And I was ready to back the Energy group and the geologists for Hathor. I'm quite excited about what that will deliver. But again, it's not going to be a five-year place. So again, what we've got to do in our sector is we've got to look out past the next five years, and we have to set aside the options for the future generations of Rio Tinto so we can actually create great businesses. And that's where I think we can go with uranium.</p>
          <p>From the phone lines please, if there are any.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will take our first question from Lee Bowers from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and hi, Tom and Guy. My question actually relates to the aluminum business. And what I was wondering is, is there &#x2013; I mean we've seen yesterday, BHP highlight the fact that it'd be willing to make quite aggressive moves in terms of curtailing production, looking to the best assets which quickly become cash negative.</p>
          <p>Within the aluminum business and in particular within some of those high cost assets that are flagged for divestment, including those within Pacific Aluminum, are there any in there that might fit that criteria and is that something you'd be willing to move on quite aggressively, particularly given that they are flagged for divestment?</p>
          <p>And then I guess the second part of the question is we've heard quite a bit in relation to the phased approach to capital which certainly gives you benefits relative to some of your peers. Can you just elaborate on that a little bit in relation to the aluminum assets, perhaps particularly Kitimat, given the magnitude of the spend there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will &#x2013; maybe I'll tackle through the first part of aluminum, but I think, Guy, if you can add to that, and then I'll say something about Kitimat. On aluminum and these markets with a &#x2013; really a strained LME price and higher input cost, I think it's fair to say that every plant manager of every smelter in Rio Tinto and in the global sector is paying very close attention to their own marginal cost of production versus the LME price. And we should remind ourselves the marginal cost for aluminum capacity is somewhere in $2,300 to $2,400 per tonne range or even higher. So there is a fair amount of global capacity that's probably running in the red as we speak.</p>
          <p>You've seen in the global financial crisis and, again, you've seen some of our actions that we've had over past year, so that if a project is not viable on a marginal cost basis, we will turn off the power. And that's something that is appropriate and legitimate. We will do it in a way which is sensitive, of course, to stakeholders concerns, so we've got to look after the shareholder, we've got to look after the business.</p>
          <p>So that's something you've seen us do, frankly, you've seen most others in the sector do, and I would say that every plant manager knows just that, and it's in their best interest, basically, to find a way to run their businesses in this environment of lower LME and high input prices. Guy, if there's anything else you want to say about aluminum first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, look, I mean I think that whether an asset is within Pacific Aluminum or within Rio Tinto Alcan or, for that matter, within anybody else's portfolio, you do have to look at anything that is bleeding cash, and of course, that would happen. At the same time, we've got a plan to improve the Pacific Aluminum &#x2013; well, all our assets but, in particular, we're focusing on the Pacific Aluminum at the moment. And we're hopeful that that will get over those kind of problems. I think we will see a lot of closures in this industry that will help the supply side a bit. So I would down to underline what Tom said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On Kitimat, and certainly we really pushed hard on the system and the engineering teams at Kitimat to create phases there. As you may recall, we had approved the construction of Kitimat before the financial crisis. And then we've basically unapproved it during the middle of the financial crisis. So we have a facility that's actually an older pre-baked facility and will not win any awards for prettiness as you walk through that facility at Kitimat. And it's definitely something &#x2013; anyone looking at it would say, this is probably yesterday's technology, not tomorrow's technology.</p>
          <p>So we looked at the various options. We did push on whether we could create a smaller starting point, but we also have a very large &#x2013; very low cost source of power. I think it's in the first decile in terms of power cost at Kitimat. And we have so much power that actually &#x2013; you have more power that you can actually distribute down the transmission lines. So you've got to find a market for them. I think Kitimat, as we designed it and as we proved it in the December, took into account both our objective for phases, but frankly, we also had to taking into account the fact that we had some of the most attractive, most competitive power anywhere in the world but sitting with some of the oldest technology anywhere in the world.</p>
          <p>Anything else on the phone lines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we will take our next question from Paul McTaggart from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Tom. Hi, Guy. Pretty simple question, yesterday, BHP talked about the rate of pace to cost increases and you obviously touched on that. They did quantify it in a cost sense, generally, and basically noted that it had moved from a 5% inflation rate, unit cost terms, I guess in the previous corresponding half, to a rate of 10%. So I wanted to get a sense of where you're feeling those same sort of cost pressures, If you could kind of quantify in those terms, please? And they also made the comment, which was interesting, that they felt that 80-odd percent of that was non-structural that we really driven by linked prices, input costs, et cetera. So they were, I guess, trying to give us a sense that, yes, we're seeing high costs pressures but at some point they will abate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Guy, why don't you start off with that one, and I may make  some closing remarks about this structural observation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that when we look at our cost increases &#x2013; I'll give you some numbers which are year-on-year as opposed to half-on-half. And the reason I'm going to do that is that last year was a complicated one to analyze because of the effect on unit cost of whether that harmed the first half, and also because of grade, which also reduced volume in the Copper group. But if you exclude royalties, freight and the trading activities, which go on in aluminum to save transport costs, the overall increase in our unit cost was 14.6%. Now that included what we consider to be mining inflation and input price increase of about 8.4% and the effects of weather, which we computed just under 4%.</p>
          <p>So I think that when we look at this, we feel that &#x2013; I mean, of course, it's much too high a level of increase, we're tackling it in the various ways which we described during the presentation, but I think that breaking it down by half is distorted by that weather and &#x2013; particularly that weather effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul. I think maybe Guy would help me with this one too, on the point of 80% is non-structural and only 20% is sort of enduring. I hope BHP is right. I'm worried about that one and I don't think we can be complacent. If we look at what we see around the world, it's very evident in Australia but it's also evident in many other parts of the world. We're seeing rising rates of labor inflation. And unfortunately it's being matched by lowering rates of employee productivity. And if we get that twin challenge of rising labor rates, which basically &#x2013; wage rates don't go down, they only go up over time. And then that's matched by lower levels of employee productivity, partly because of high turnover, partly because the skills may be there, then we're going to see a larger than 20% component of this inflation being structural.</p>
          <p>So we've got actually be ahead of that curve. We've got to do more in terms of first of all, what can we do on the industrial relations environment, particularly in countries that are going through periods of industrial relations reform to ensure that we put productivity in the same box as all the other components of IR. The second thing we've got to do, which is critically important, is to actually look at the labor-capital trade-offs. Can we actually, without necessarily reducing the number of employees, reduce the rate of employee growth by increasing productivity.</p>
          <p>In 2015, I hope to see half the tonnes we move in the Pilbara being moved with driverless trucks, and that's where I come about looking at shifts between capital and labor. So I hope that BHP is right that only 20% of these cost increases are structural, but I think we'd actually have to work harder to keep that from getting worse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe &#x2013; if we have a question from the audience then I'll -couple here then I'll go back to the telephone.</p>
          <p>Operator, you got it over the telephone, do you have any questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We will take our next question from Paul Young from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, Tom and good evening, Guy. Question on your pipeline of projects in advanced study phase on slide 31 of the presentation, can you just talk through how you sequence &#x2013; or you're thinking about sequencing these projects?</p>
          <p>And also on your cash flow forecast, can you actually build all these projects at once and then a question on your aluminum division, I mean Alma, which is <mark type="ph" /> Australian mine (01:13:25) numbers, the most profitable and valuable smelter in your fleet that's running at 30% output. Are there any sort of one-off costs that we should be aware of? Can you give us an update on the industrial action there?</p>
          <p>And then third to that, just the flow-on effects upstream on your aluminum production, where are you placing that 600,000 tonnes of spare aluminum now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Guy, why don't you maybe handle the capital pipeline, while I'll talk about Alma.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Our objective is &#x2013; we have got a lot of high quality projects as you say. They are screened all the time, they go through a process as they're developed, both at a conceptual stage, at feasibility stage, and we are constantly looking for quality and value. And we have to throw things out or send them back to be reassessed and to come forward maybe under some different design, different size, different timescale. We would not propose a schedule of projects that we could not finance, obviously. While it is our first objective to invest in high quality projects, we don't want to do that if it threatens the strong balance sheet that we have and the commitment to a single A that we have. And so for that reason, we are &#x2013; we're tending to delay some of these projects, but the best ones, such as the ones in the Pilbara, for example, are getting through without any real difficulty because they are so high quality, so high return and so low risk.</p>
          <p>And so when I look at these projects, some of them, of course, have not been approved. I think you're looking at the ones that are in advanced study, I mean not all of those will come through for certain, some of them may get rescheduled. At the moment though, we do anticipate &#x2013; they all are in our plan, I have to say. So I think that this is a question that we constantly reassess as we prepare our cash flow forecasts, and we have the flexibility &#x2013; this is the point we're trying to make &#x2013; of phasing them should we need to. And that is why we have a few months before we make the final decision on the 353 project in the Pilbara for example. I think it's very likely that we will take that decision. But &#x2013; so I hope I can give you a sense that we are balancing all the time this question of balance sheet strength on the one hand with the quality of each investment on the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On Alma &#x2013; just a little bit of background for those who have not been following it &#x2013; we were at a period where instead of having a strike we locked out the Alma plant and we are running it with the salaried staff at the plant. And in order to do that on a safe basis, we reduced capacity by about a third of normal capacity. And you're right, Paul, it's one of our lower cost plants. So we're doing one basically because of industrial relations matters.</p>
          <p>The outstanding matters have nothing to do with pay and conditions. They are related to contracting out provisions and the union's request to basically control the plant floor neither of those are acceptable, either at Alma or anywhere else in Rio Tinto operations. And frankly, it's an ask that you don't see anywhere else within Quebec. So we are basically choosing to keep that plant locked out until we come to a point where we can come to an agreement with the union. And that will be as long as it takes.</p>
          <p>Now that does put us in a position we probably have excess water, it will affect the supply chain, and we made moves accordingly, but it has led to us having excess hydro capacity. And so that's allowed us &#x2013; so that's very low incremental power cost with that, and so we have diverted some of that into restarting two of the lines at Shawinigan, which will run as long as that makes economic sense to do that.</p>
          <p>The net effect has probably been to just create some additional tightness in the North American aluminum physical market. And again it does suggest that low LME pricing is a problem in different parts of the world, particularly in the U.S. because you're seeing some buying demand growing, you are seeing some physical tightness occurring in the metal markets.</p>
          <p>So if we can have two more questions from the phone lines, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>So we'll take our next question from Brendan Fitzpatrick from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, two questions on the Richards Bay Minerals transaction, if I might. Just wondering, first one, get a sense for, were there discrete windows during which BHP could elect to exercise the option to transfer the stake, or was it an open-ended timeframe? And the second part, there was reference to the pricing mechanism already being established in the agreement, but given the price isn't disclosed, am I right in thinking there's components to the mechanism still to be determined and can we get a sense for what those might be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brendan, that is a confidential agreement between us and BHP. I think we both chose to keep it confidential and probably best to keep it that way, in both aspects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Peter O'Connor from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, just a thought on your latent capacity in your system. Guy walked through the copper issues of low grade at Escondida, Kennecott and also at Grasberg, I'm just wondering, compared to the tonnage you put out in 2011, what could we reasonably expect in terms of copper units would come back over the next couple of years? And similarly with weather in iron ore and weather in coal, what low capital latent capacity do you have that's available over the next one, two, three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Peter, let me try on that latent capacity as I've listened to those words with interest yesterday. For example, Escondida's was no doubt latent capacity, if they could put another tonne of ore through the concentrator, they would put it through the concentrator. It's not a question of capacity of ore, it's a question of what the grade is of the ore that's being mined. And it is going through a period of lower phases. So I wouldn't necessarily have called that latent capacity, but I think as they flagged what the grade profile would be at Escondida as we flagged it, that's probably what you're going to see. It's not sort of a mill sitting there that's just not running at this time. I think certainly from our perspective, and personally, every one of our businesses, if we can produce a product and we can sell on profit, we are producing a product and selling it at a profit.</p>
          <p>Now a lot of latent capacity one would argue is because of weather, and I wish I could &#x2013; I can predict the weather, but we're no better at it than they were a thousand years ago. So we have &#x2013; I mean you've seen that we can run the Pilbara, for example, at 240 million tonnes per year, and people say, well, if you do that in the one quarter, why can't you do for the whole year? And I do have to remind you that these cyclones do come through and I have been assured and certainly in past several years have seen evidence of this that the cyclonic activity in Western/Northwestern Australia is actually the most unpredictable cyclone activity of any hurricane, cyclone, typhoon system in the world. And these things do literally turn on a dime, so it's very difficult to make any kind of prediction.</p>
          <p>All we could do is basically derate our capacity during these summer wet seasons and then just hope for the best. And then during the dry season, hope we can make up for whatever the gaps were. We had two weather systems that came through the Pilbara. In January, one hit &#x2013; all over Pilbara, hit land and probably made an effect across the board. The second one didn't hit land but also created some sea swells and also impacted production.</p>
          <p>Because with these cyclones, you have three things that could drive the outcome, one is the wind effects and basically, you have to tie down and protect the plants from wind damage. And the wind effects with winds at over 200 kilometers an hour can be quite enormous, so you have to actually shut down facilities and spend lots of days of prep and un-prepping. The second would be rain, and again, so you have not only the rain hitting the site but more likely, because you don't have mature river systems in the Pilbara, you have washouts and you have large valleys that flood with water and that could have the effect on rail capacity and do quite a bit of damage to rail systems.</p>
          <p>And the third would be, which is probably the least noticed, is sea swells, and that is that if the storm's hitting off the coast and it's creating sea swells, and I think the last system is we saw sea swells of three meters in the port, you've got to actually &#x2013; you've got to take the ships out to sea, so you can't load during those periods.</p>
          <p>Unpredictable, I wish I could predict them but I wouldn't have called that latent capacity. I think we got to build our own overall assumption of capacity, making the presumption that we will have a weather factor and we'll try to calculate that as best we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, could I follow on Coal &amp; Allied. And first to congratulate you, after four decades of trying, you've only got there last year. Where did that business go? And how quickly can you make that business actually work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I missed that &#x2013; I never want to miss a congratulations, so if you repeat that again, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Congratulations on your Coal &amp; Allied deal, which is four decades in the making so &#x2013; well done, finally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically yes, I said that in the last seminar that it took us 20 years to do and I was corrected afterwards, and they said no, it's actually 30 years. You say 40 years and you're probably right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:23:15) can you do that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Guy, can you talk about Cole &amp; Allied, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Where we do we go to with Cole &amp; Allied. Well, I think that this business has had a tough, if we go back over that &#x2013; the last 10 years particularly, we have seen a mismatch between what we might have liked to put through that system. It's quite distinct from what we have in the West, in a sense that we don't control the railway, we don't fully control the port either. And so what we would like to do is to see a much higher throughput through that system, and that's the work that we're doing. That's always been the intent, and I'm not going to give you numbers for it. I think that's partly contingent on capital expenditure on things like Mount Pleasant, which you saw in the list that we showed and we were talking about a few minutes ago. But there is, as it were, latent capacity there. If the whole system worked like a Swiss watch, and if we had the mining capacity to match up with the rail and port capacity, more would be produced at a lower cost and so that is something that we would like to take advantage of in future years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can I get one more question from the audience here. We have...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we will take...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's James Gurry again from Credit Suisse. If it took you 30 years to consolidate Cole &amp; Allied, can you just tell us what &#x2013; I hope it doesn't take that long to consolidate Oyu Tolgoi, and how you feel about that asset going forward? And perhaps, how you're in control of the rest of the Ivanhoe? You're the majority shareholder, so how do you feel about the rest of the Ivanhoe assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I hope it doesn't take that long. I think we are &#x2013; and first and foremost, what attracted us to Ivanhoe, what the discussions with Robert Friedland and I were around both of us seeing the potential for Oyu Tolgoi. And we have moved it over the past several years from an exploration project to what is becoming a great mine. We'd have several steps left to go, but I think if you look at our progress from 2006, I think it's been quite extraordinary.</p>
          <p>And while we have been focusing on the proper development of Oyu Tolgoi, we've been doing it under a mechanism that actually are respectful of the commercial regimes, respectful of the markets, Ivanhoe is a listed &#x2013; separate listed company, it has its own shareholder base. We have been making our investment at OT on a risk &#x2013; phased risk-weighted basis, same thing we're hearing elsewhere today, by making individual tranches of investments in Ivanhoe and then the agreement with Ivanhoe was those funds would be reinvested in Oyu Tolgoi for the development of the site. And that's actually provided us with phases of risk assessment and it also provided us with optionality going forward. And that's essentially what we have been doing since 2006. I don't think it's the end of the story, we still have more work to do. We will do so in a way which is of course respectful of all, the contractual commitments, the various exchange requirements and very respectful for what I would say is the partner and the biggest stakeholder would be in the government of Mongolia. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> (01:26:39)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question, maybe you have heard is when we will see a CapEx estimates. It's in feasibility for the second phase, I think it'd be too early to give any time on that.</p>
          <p>I think we have room for one more question from the room here, here we go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Richard Hatch, RBC. Just a quick question on your CapEx. So your aluminum CapEx and your copper CapEx is around about the same sort of money in total. Given the fact that copper's contributing more than aluminum, could you put more money into copper than &#x2013; sorry, given that copper is putting &#x2013; contributing more money than aluminum, would you push more money into your copper assets than your aluminum?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like, maybe Guy, to make some comments about capital allocation in general, but I would say just in terms of the &#x2013; if you just deep dive into the number themselves, you'll see that Kitimat has a large portion of the total capital, which we committed to in December. And of course, we have the Phase II of the Yarwun, which was something we committed to before the financial crisis, which will be successfully commissioned, we expect, middle of this year, whereas copper, the bulk of investments would be in those projects like Oyu Tolgoi, which I just talked about. But Guy, if you want to talk more generally about the principles of capital allocation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't really do it in a way that you're suggesting, in other words, just putting money into things that are making money today. We try and take a long-term view of all the capital projects that we do. We're not deterministic. In other words, we're not trying to create a particular percentage portfolio for copper and aluminum by 2020, let's say.</p>
          <p>And what we're doing is looking at numerous options in all our products and, in fact, sometimes in products that we're not in at all, such as potash, for example, where we recently invested. And so what we look for are individual opportunities, and if they pass muster, in terms of being high quality Tier 1 resources and if they look as if they would generate good value at acceptable risk, then we try to do them.</p>
          <p>And it is true indeed that today, the copper business is earning much more than the aluminum business, absolutely right. But over the next 40 to 50 years, I wouldn't be so certain that was going to be case. I think that copper will have a good few years. And in time, I think aluminum will come back. So I think we're making these investments for periods like that. We're not making them for just a few months or even just a few years. We're making them for a very long time.</p>
          <p>So Kitimat, the big investment that we're making is actually, as Tom was explaining earlier, a very good project indeed, the best probably in the aluminum industry by far. So we have no regrets about that project. And I think that the other point to make is although we &#x2013; it looks as if we're spending quite a lot on aluminum, much of it is just finishing Yarwun, which is, after all, going to be in production in August. So most of that capital has actually already been spent. So the big one, as I've said, is Kitimat and it's a good project as our copper projects, they are also good. And by the way, finding new copper projects to put money into at the moment is problematic. That is part of the bull case for copper. There just aren't very many opportunities that are available in the short term. We'd very much like have more of them and we're putting money where we can, but there is a limit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. With that, anyone that's got a copper opportunity, please see us after the meeting. I think I'll draw that to a close. I guess as you're having a chance to see lots of companies in this result season, there aren't too many of them that are delivering more than $27 billion of cash flow, more than $15 billion of underlying earnings and a 34% dividend all at the same time. So thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>