<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1361119" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call - London</title>
    <date>2011-02-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>667</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Severin Schwan, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Pascal Soriot, Chief Operating Officer &#x2013; Pharmaceuticals Division</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Daniel O'Day, Chief Operating Officer, Diagnostics</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Erich Hunziker, Chief Financial and Information Technology Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Jill Walton</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Sachin Jain</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Andrew Baum</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Michael Leacock</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Vincent Rouvi&#xE8;re</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Amit Roy</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Alexandra Hauber-Schuele</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Mark Purcell</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentlemen, a pleasure today to be back here in London. 2010 has been a challenging year for us, but in spite of the headwinds which we faced, we did fully meet the financial guidance which we gave you at the beginning of 2010. In spite of the more challenging environment, in spite of the setbacks in our portfolio, I believe we took a very firm action, we reacted quickly, we reacted comprehensively by launching Operational Excellence in the second half of last year, and I can confirm to you that we are fully on track to deliver the savings which we communicated in November, that is CHF 1.8 billion for this year and CHF 2.4 billion, as we go forward as of 2012.</p>
          <p>We did have setbacks in our pipeline, however we also made major progress in our late-stage pipeline, and we moved a number of compounds into late-stage pipeline. We have today one of the industry-leading portfolios, with 12 new molecular entities in the late-stage pipeline. You've seen the sales results this morning, up 5% for pharmaceuticals in local currencies above the market and up even 8% for the Diagnostics division, twice the worldwide market growth. So on a group level, 5% in local currencies, excluding Tamiflu.</p>
          <p>I mentioned the headwinds. First of all, we had to digest the decline of Tamiflu of 2.3 billion sales versus the previous year. You're all aware of the discussion in the U.S. with the FDA regarding the indication for metastatic breast cancer for Avastin, and we have seen a decline here in the second half of the year of 125 million in the U.S. And we had a major impact from the healthcare reforms around the globe; in total, about CHF 800 million, a third each about for the U.S., U.S. healthcare reform, the austerity measures in Europe and the annual price cut in Japan. But in spite of that, we kept the growth momentum throughout the year into the fourth quarter 2010. And, we did grow profits faster than sales, core operating profit up by 7% in local currencies and, as you have seen this morning, core earnings per share up by 10% in local currencies.</p>
          <p>This increase in profits, the faster increase versus sales, also is reflected in our operating margins. You see that we again could increase group operating margins from 33% to 35% of sales. Based on these solid financial results, based on the development of our profitability, the Board of Director will propose to the General Assembly to increase dividends by 10% to CHF 6.60. So we achieved our goals as we guided you both on sales growth and on earnings.</p>
          <p>Let me now shift into our priorities for 2011. And it's really two-fold. On the one hand, we are committed to deliver on our efficiency programs. There's still another 200 million to go to capture from the Genentech synergies, and there is another 1.8 billion for Operational Excellence, which we expect in terms of savings for 2011.</p>
          <p>Our strategy and the basis for our growth in the long term is innovation. We continue to invest into research and development. That remains the engine for our growth in the long term, and that will be a priority as we go forward into 2011. We have one new molecular entity which we intend to launch already in 2011, the BRAF inhibitor with malignant melanoma, and there's two other new molecular entities which we potentially file already in 2010, namely pertuzumab and the hedgehog inhibitors. So again, a very strong late-stage pipeline with 12 new molecular entities, which I do believe is one of the leading pipelines in the industry.</p>
          <p>Now let me close with the outlook for 2011 in terms of our core EPS growth. We have guided this morning high single-digit growth in constant currencies. Now on the one hand, we have to digest a number of top-line pressures and risks. We see continued pressure from the U.S. healthcare reform with the excise tax being introduced in 2011. We see the full-year effect of the price reductions in Europe. In total, we expect this effect to be about CHF 500 million. We don't expect the same effect again in Japan, because it's more of a biannual rhythm in this part of the world.</p>
          <p>We did have a sharp decline in our Tamiflu sales into 2010, but still, we had a turnover of CHF 870 million. And a big portion of that was sales to governments for pandemic stockpiling. As we go into 2011, we do not plan for additional sales for governments for stockpiling and accordingly, we expect sales to be low, about 600 million, so that we end up with only seasonal flu sales in the range of about 200 to 300 million.</p>
          <p>Avastin metastatic breast cancer, we have about 900 million sales in the U.S. We have seen a decline in the second half of this year and we see a risk here of up to 800 million for metastatic breast cancer both in the U.S. and, to a certain degree, if we have spillover effects, into other countries.</p>
          <p>We also will have to digest the patent expiries of Boniva sales, which again, should have an impact of about 500 million. So that's quite some items we have to digest as we go into 2011. And on the positive side, first on Avastin, metastatic breast cancer is negatively affected, but we do see still growth for the other indications, in particular with solid growth in the international and emerging markets. So we assume here an additional growth on the other indications of up to 500 million for 2011.</p>
          <p>We want to deliver on the Genentech synergies and on the sooner &#x2013; the cost savings from Operational Excellence; that gives us another 2 billion. And with the organic growth on top of it, this bring us to a core EPS guidance in the high single digits. So here, again, you can see the summary of the outlook for 2011 as we communicated it this morning.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Pascal, I'd just like to add a personal note. It is actually today the last time that our CFO, Erich Hunziker, joins us here for an investor relation conference in London, so I'd like to take this opportunity to thank him for the many years of service with Roche and the many contributions he made to Roche.</p>
          <p>As you know, Erich has decided to retire from Roche at the end of March to hand over to his successor Alan Hippe who joins us from ThyssenKrupp. During the 10 years with Roche, Erich has established an outstanding finance organization, and as you all know, he is the man behind the financing of the privatization of Genentech, remember in the midst of the global financial crisis at very attractive conditions.</p>
          <p>And this is rightly so widely regarded as one of the professional masterpieces of Erich. Again, Erich, thank you very much for the many contributions. Roche owes you an enormous debt of gratitude for what you have done for our company. Thank you very much.</p>
          <p>And with this, Pascal, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Severin. Good afternoon, everybody. It's a pleasure to be here with you today. Severin talked about headwinds a couple of times, and I can tell you in 2010, my colleagues and I in the Pharma division we certainly felt those headwinds.</p>
          <p>We also felt a lot of cost wins very often, and we look forward to days when we can again run with the wind. Those days will come, believe me, but certainly the message for you is despite all those challenges outside Tamiflu we grew our sales by 5%, and this is to be compared with the market growth rate of 1%.</p>
          <p>I know IMS is reporting 4% to 5%, but as I mentioned before, IMS underestimated the amount of rebates paid to managed care in the United States and overestimated the growth in some markets around the world. So if you look at pharma, evaluate the market grew by 1% at constant exchange rate. We grew by 5%, and we are certainly very pleased with this growth rate, and also very pleased with the development in the international region.</p>
          <p>The emerging markets are now representing collectively a turnover very similar to our European business and growing by double digits, so a very, very substantial business for us. Lastly, you can see that this growth rate has been maintained quarter-to-quarter until the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Now if you go a little beyond this, excluding Tamiflu, Tamiflu was 2.3 billion sales last in 2010 compared to 2009. If you also consider the impact of healthcare reform, which was really an unusual development, our portfolio, the curve of our portfolio grew by 7%, which really shows you that there is strength in the remaining part of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Now I like this graph because it shows you that our core products, our main products, despite their pricing, are growing very nicely in the emerging markets that are represented in blue here. The one part I don't like so much is the fact that Avastin didn't grow in the United States in 2010, and we certainly expect the same or worse development in 2011 because of this breast cancer development.</p>
          <p>You can also see here that Actemra is starting to emerge as a substantial growth driver for us. In 2010, the sales essentially came out of Europe. In the emerging markets, we are gaining reimbursement progressively, and in the United States I want to remind you that we didn't have a J-code reimbursement code as yet in 2010. So the sales growth, of course, was limited in a sense, but we slightly overestimate &#x2013; overachieved, sorry, our target in the U.S. for 2010. And finally, we actually had to deal with the CellCept patent expiry which cost us close to $300 million in sales.</p>
          <p>We actually managed to grow our operating profit by 4% despite the sales decline thanks to a proactive cost management. As you can see here, we delivered on what we committed to you, which was to slightly decline our R&amp;D expenses, so we did this. We certainly drove our G&amp;A cost out quite hard, and also managed our M&amp;D, our promotional commercial costs quite aggressively.</p>
          <p>Overall, we managed to increase our operating margin substantially from 38% to 39.9% in the Pharma division, which is a very strong improvement year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Now if we move on to a review of our products. Our oncology portfolio grew nicely overall 7%. Avastin, MabThera and Herceptin all grew 9% for the first two and 7% for Herceptin. In the U.S., no growth essentially due to this breast cancer situation.</p>
          <p>MabThera was driven by the uptake in CLL, and we are starting to get traction out of the maintenance indication. We just got it approval in the United States very recently, and Herceptin is still growing in its current indication breast cancer in the international region and slightly low single digit growth rate in the U.S. and Europe where we have on top of it gastric cancer that is driving sales growth.</p>
          <p>So the message here on this graph for Avastin is that we have seen a rapid decline of our patient share in breast cancer in the United States. If you remember, we used to have about 60% share of breast cancer patients with Avastin, and this has declined to close to 35% toward the end of last year and we expect a further decline, which is why we re-estimated our sales and expect a decline actually in the United States driven by breast cancer.</p>
          <p>I'd like to highlight here the strong growth that we experienced in Japan, 50%. For some reason, the international region has disappeared from this graph, but we grow by a bit more than 30% in international region. So very strong growth rate.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we did quite well in colorectal cancer. We're still growing in lung cancer, and so far we haven't been too impacted by the breast cancer situation, but certainly in 2011 we expect that we may be impacted to a much lower degree than the U.S. of course, but a little bit.</p>
          <p>So this is the Avastin picture, the pluses and the minus. Of course, the threat we know it all, we all know it, but there are reasons to believe that over the mid-term Avastin can grow. First of all, we still have growth potential in colorectal and lung cancer. In particular in the emerging markets, we are only starting, I believe, with colorectal cancer and we have a long way to go.</p>
          <p>We just launched in China. We are successful in Japan. Our colleagues at Chugai have done a great job. Another driver for growth is the treatment duration, and that will be influenced by what the TML study shows, the treatments for multiple line study that we are currently conducting. And finally, ovarian, which we filed in Europe for last year and we'll file later this year in the U.S. This is the other growth driver for Avastin.</p>
          <p>Overall, we re-estimated our peak sales to about 7 billion. This is a risk adjusted number, of course, considering all the risks that we know about and the various indications.</p>
          <p>Lucentis is still growing very strongly. Of course, we are expecting the &#x2013; we are waiting for the CATT study results and those should come up in the first half of 2011.</p>
          <p>This is the big unknown for Lucentis. We are still doing very well. The uptake, in our view, is very encouraging so far. There is, of course, in our view already some use of Avastin, but Lucentis is nicely developing in this indication, and we are waiting to hear about this DME study later this quarter.</p>
          <p>Actemra did very well. We developed &#x2013; our quarterly sales, you see there, are developing very nicely, and we believe we did very well in Europe, in particular in some markets like France. We are gaining reimbursement progressively.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., we've had a nice feedback from rheumatologists so far, but this are still early days. We obtained a J-code in January, this January. This is, as you all know, this is to be expected. It takes about a year to get the J-code so there's no issue, nothing specific here and 2011 should be a year where Actemra growth in the U.S. is accelerating.</p>
          <p>We filed late last year for this pediatric arthritis indication. The data are very strong. This is, of course, a smaller indication, smaller opportunity for Actemra, but this will have a huge impact on these pediatric patients who really suffer from a terrible disease.</p>
          <p>And finally, we are extending the label to include inhibition and slowing of structural joint damage in the United States. In the emerging market, we have experienced a growth rate of about 10 percentage over the last few years and last year we grew by 11%. And the interesting note here is that our core products are growing very nicely, and representing a bigger share of our total sales in those countries. So there is still a huge opportunity for us to grow those products and increase access to patients who until now haven't been able to afford those products.</p>
          <p>I want to cover a few points which I know have been on your minds over the last few months. One is Herceptin and the treatment duration. There's a number of shorter treatment duration studies that are ongoing, as you all know. The point I want to make here is that most of those studies will read at the time or later or after our own study, HER2 reads that.</p>
          <p>HER2 compares two years of Herceptin treatment with one year, and the studies, all the studies will read at similar time, we actually believe that, of course, the two years will show a better result than one year. Some of those shorter treatment duration studies, by the way, are basically &#x2013; will be terminated if HER2 is actually positive. This is stipulated in the protocol. Some of those studies will actually stop if HER2 is positive.</p>
          <p>I also want to say a few words about biosimilars, which is a question we often get. The first point I want to make is as far as the biosimilars is our first and most important response to those is to keep doing what we do, i.e. develop innovative, new treatment and progress this standard of care.</p>
          <p>So if I take the example of HER2 positive breast cancer, we have a positive three-pronged approach here. We have a sub-Q formulation of Herceptin that will help with the administration of Herceptin over a longer period of time, especially if HER2 is positive. This will be a very substantial improvement to the administration of Herceptin.</p>
          <p>With developed pertuzumab, pertuzumab, I believe, is an underrated product because in combination with Herceptin it will dramatically improve the standard of care and improve the clinical benefits that we're delivering to breast cancer patients. And it will also help us manage the HER2 franchise very proactively, and it should reduce the potential for monotherapy Herceptin use.</p>
          <p>It will also help us manage the overall pricing of HER2 positive breast cancer treatment, and as opposed to pricing Herceptin monotherapy, we will be pricing for treatment, the combination of the two agents.</p>
          <p>And finally, we have T-DM1 that we are now developing in second line and also in first line. So you can see that in both events, first line and second line breast cancer we'll have different responses with our different products to address those segment.</p>
          <p>So this is first part of our response to these biosimilars. The second point I want to make is if you look at the EPO market and the G-CSF market in Europe, across Europe, clearly the decline you see has got nothing to do with what you what you would with a small molecule. I don't want one second to make you believe or try to imply that we don't believe that biosimilars will impact Herceptin or MabThera.</p>
          <p>Of course they will. I'm only trying to make the point that the impact is going to be much smaller than what we experienced with small molecular, and you can see here in volume terms the decline we've experience in the EPO market is not as dramatic as people would expect to see with a small molecule.</p>
          <p>And finally, the other point with Herceptin and MabThera is that there's an enormous potential in those emerging markets as the economies are growing. We can see that more and more payers are now able to access Herceptin and MabThera. The clinical benefits are so strong that we're making nice progress.</p>
          <p>And we are &#x2013; we intend to become more flexible with the way we go about pricing those products in these countries. You can see here the level of penetration in China is very low with Herceptin, only 7%, and we are now developing offerings for payers, in particular public payers, to facilitate access to hundreds of thousands of patients who would benefit from these drugs.</p>
          <p>And we are having I must say some very early encouraging results to this. So an enormous potential. As we manage our price down in some countries we certainly can expand volume very, very dramatically.</p>
          <p>So in a nutshell, the response or the storyline line around the biosimilars is first of all, in the U.S. we are patent protected until 2018, 2019 for both &#x2013; for all those biological agents. Second in Europe, the impact of a biosimilars will be less than that of a small molecule. Third, we are working on moving the standard of care forward, and reducing the potential for monotherapy treatment all in the case of MabThera, developing GA101, an improved agent. And finally, we're going to be proactive with pricing in some of those emerging markets to grow volume.</p>
          <p>So overall what we expect is actually a growth of the HER2 franchise over the next few years. I want to say a few words about the pipeline and the 2011 outlook. I don't want to go through all those projects, but just looking at this slide you can see that we have a very rich pipeline. And 2011 will be a busy year again</p>
          <p>I just want to highlight three projects here. One is BRAF, and as you know, the BRIM3 study was positive, and we reached the co-primary end point overall, survival and PFS. We stopped the study. We'll add patients in the control arm to actually cross over and receive BRAF, and we are now planning to file in the U.S., Europe and the rest of the world as quickly as we can.</p>
          <p>The second is pertuzumab/Herceptin. The CLEOPATRA study, you know about the NEOSPHERE study, but certainly the CLEOPATRA hopefully will confirm what we think of pertuzumab, and we may be able again to file early with pertuzumab in 2011.</p>
          <p>And finally, hedgehog for basal cell carcinoma. On the basis of the Phase II pivotal study we're conducting we could also be filing.</p>
          <p>Maybe one last study I'd like to mention is Actemra, the head-to-head study versus Humira. We believe this study has the potential to transform the way RA is treated. Typically, physicians will cycle patients from one anti-TNF to another one. We want to show that this is really not the best treatment algorithm, and this will open the way for a lot more Actemra use.</p>
          <p>A few words. I've covered the BRAF study results already, so I will move on. Hedgehog, we had some earlier results, Phase I results, that were very encouraging, and as I said, we are now running a Phase II study that will read out very soon.</p>
          <p>And finally, the NEOSPHERE trial which I mentioned a few minutes ago gave us some very encouraging earlier results which we hope, again, to be able to confirm in CLEOPATRA and on the basis of those results to file in 2011.</p>
          <p>So finally just to recap on 2011 and what our focus is going to about. First, we need to prepare for launch of the BRAF, the pertuzumab and the hedgehog. Announcing BRAF is actually in a way something a little bit new because we now have to work the Pharma division and Diagnostic and our Diagnostics colleagues in every country around the world are now working very closely with one another to launch the drug and the diagnostic test together and do this successfully.</p>
          <p>Last time we did this was with Herceptin 10 years ago, and to be frank, it took quite a while. We have a strength. We have a strong synergy between the two divisions. We can do something that no other company can do, for instance GSK with BRAF don't have the opportunity to launch a test at the same time as the drug &#x2013; as we are doing it. We need to do this well and we are working hard to make it successful.</p>
          <p>Second, we will keep investing in the emerging market, and making sure that we grow faster than the market in all those countries. We continue to invest in our late stage pipeline, and finally, we have to implement the Operational Excellence project. Some of it has already been announced and implemented late last year, but there's still quite a bit of work to do this year reshaping our development organization in particular, and this will keep us busy this year.</p>
          <p>Thank you so much. I will hand over to Dan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>So good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. We had a very strong year in Diagnostics in 2010 despite some of the healthcare challenges we had out there in many of our countries, despite the fact that we're the largest in-vitro diagnostic company in the world at a 20% share with the next competitor at 12% and a lot of very aggressive competitive tactics, we were able to grow again significantly faster than the market and the sales side with an 8% overall growth.</p>
          <p>That in a market that is growing between 4% and 5% means that we're not only taking share, of course, but we're really in essence growing and creating the in-vitro diagnostics market. And actually feel that the macro economic impact that we see in healthcare is favorable to diagnostics because the better we can provide key medical value assays out there, the more they'll be taken up by the healthcare systems and rewarded in the marketplace as we see across our particular businesses.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of the regional aspect of that growth, we can see that in each of the markets across the world we had market share and market growth that was superior to the market average. I would just point out in particular, now the E7 countries where Diagnostics represent 13% of our overall turnover growing at 21%, we're the number one in-vitro diagnostic company in those E7 markets. China alone grew close to 40% last year and we see this infrastructure spend in development that is driving that growth, and still in my opinion at the very early stages of penetration into those markets.</p>
          <p>What I'm most happy about being able to present to you this year is the significantly improved profit margin. Last year, we had still the same leading market share position. We had two times the market growth, but had a profit picture which wasn't as attractive.</p>
          <p>We grew the profits by 30% over the course of this year, almost 4 percentage points in the profit line to a core operating profit of 21.1%. Now that was done through obviously the strong sales growth across our regions. It was also done by the fact that the products that are driving our growth in terms of product mix are at a higher gross margin, and therefore driving our profitability to be sustainable in the future.</p>
          <p>And it was also done because we systematically put some efficiency programs in place in Diagnostics over the past couple of years that are starting to show through. And you see it specifically on the cost of goods line which in the recent past had been growing faster than sales. It's now in my opinion in control, growing slower than sales, and I will articulate a little bit about why I think that's also sustainable moving forward.</p>
          <p>Good management of the cost line with a 21.1% core operating profit, and it's actually this picture that last year I was a bit more shy than I'll be this year. I still feel that in the broader Roche picture that Diagnostics is significantly undervalued out there in the marketplace, and when you consider our share position or growth rate of 21.1% profitability on a business with a lower risk rate than Pharma, I think it's something that I would ask you all to continue to take a look at in terms of your evaluations of Roche moving forward, both in terms of the Diagnostics business potential and the benefits that it provides to both of our businesses within the Roche group.</p>
          <p>You can see this operating profit margin coming through also and the cash flow line very strongly, which is obviously very important for us as well and in terms of the margin programs that we have in place, I mean at the beginning of last year you heard me talk about the fact that we have five different businesses, but we weren't continuously leveraging our economies of scale.</p>
          <p>So we took our manufacturing operations and put it into under one person reporting directly into me, and that's also driven a lot of our cost of goods improvement. So where we have innovation we'll do that in the five different businesses; where we have the economies of scale, we'll leverage that moving forward from both a manufacturing excellence program standpoint through our service program, which is a major expense line for us that we can benefit from having a more global approach. And of course, active portfolio management, moving those products ahead with high medical value, better gross margins and sustainable improvements in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>In addition, we took advantage of taking a look at our site structure in 2010, and for strategic reasons because we wanted to bring some of our sites together because we develop products that are systems and by having R&amp;D for the assay and R&amp;D for the instrument on the same site, it can add to advantages. So we consolidated both our Point of Care business and our Diabetes Care business by consolidating some sites or announcing the consolidation of sites in 2010, and we'll do that over the next couple of years.</p>
          <p>Now what's driving this 8% growth? Our largest business, Professional Diagnostics, growing at 11%. Again, we have a razor, razor blade model, so the ability for us to place our instruments in the lab is a big competitive to entry for competitors, and then feeding them with our reagent base and that's what's driving the 11%.</p>
          <p>I have an example of that on the next slide. In Diabetes Care you see the disproportionate share in Europe in terms of the growth and those products that we've launched in the Europe in the past several years will enter into other markets. Diabetes Care is a market grew around 1% to 2% this year and we were growing at 4%.</p>
          <p>Molecular diagnostics, we are a 30% share in this business, growing at 4% across all the regions. We also will be entering now into the United States market and to other markets with some of the faster growing areas of molecular diagnostics with the HPV launch in the U.S. this year, as well as a strong oncology portfolio, KRAS, EGFR, BRAF rolling out on our large installed base.</p>
          <p>Applied Science, in fact, underlying growth was quite strong. In sequencing we had in that particular business a kind of Tamiflu effect because in 2009 we had an H1N1 assay that was more than CHF 70 million that did not repeat itself in 2010.</p>
          <p>And in tissue diagnostics, again, impressive growth. In the United States where we have an almost 80% share it was growing at 15%, which shows the potential on this business in terms of automating the pathology labs, and we have a greater than 20% growth in the markets outside the U.S. where we're just beginning to launch those products and truly penetrate.</p>
          <p>I have two examples and a bit more detail. The first one is to look at just the immunoassay business under our Professional Diagnostics business. I like to show this slide because, first of all, the magnitude, 2 billion. It's almost as big as one of Pascal's products which I like to emphasize.</p>
          <p>The second thing is this has been growing double digit for the past ten years the immunoassay business in Diagnostics with a 17% growth last year. And again, this is innovation that provides clinicians with actionable information, and they're also more attractive assays that are helping to drive our gross margin on to our large install base out there.</p>
          <p>This is a graphical example of what I said about the Diabetes Care business. If you look at the orange line, those are our new products that are being launched in Europe, soon to be launched in the U.S. and rest of world which leads me to believe that we have a good competitive position in Diabetes Care moving forward. And of course, we also have the advent in 2012 of our patch pump business which should complement the entire offering within Diabetes Care.</p>
          <p>So when we look at our business strategically, you've heard me talk about this, we have two major focuses. One is testing efficiency for our lab customers, higher automated systems. The second one is medical value, which is what the assays that we provide on our systems.</p>
          <p>I think a lot of companies out there in the diagnostics field can do testing efficiency well. I think we do it well too, but I think one of the unique features in the Roche group is our ability to drive medical value because here we truly benefit from the know-how and knowledge, with the R&amp;D spend that we have in the rest of the group by early identifying biomarkers and establishing their IP. And also the clinical trials that it requires to get these products approved.</p>
          <p>And we separate medical value into diagnostics, those tests that we produce that are not connected with a specific companion diagnostics and companion diagnostics. But to demonstrate just a couple of key announcements that we made last year in the R&amp;D portfolio and why I believe this uniqueness of Roche is sustainable.</p>
          <p>Three key trials that we published and presented last year. You've heard me speak about ATHENA before, the HPV trial. Second leading cause of cancer in women, a significant cost for the healthcare system and obviously a significant mortality.</p>
          <p>The issue with cervical cancer, if it's identified early it's treatable and preventable. And what we did is the largest clinical trial in Diagnostics, 47,000 women prospectively. This is really a pharma grade rate trials where we demonstrated statistically that with the current standard of care in many countries, the pap smear, you're missing one out of 10 women that would go on to develop cervical cancer. And if you used our test, you would catch those one out of 10 women or all 10 women actually with the HPV 16 and 18.</p>
          <p>This has been filed in the United States. We expect approval this year and expect to launch into the largest HPV market in Diagnostics. We also released trial results, further trial results on our NT-proBNP showing significant reduction in heart failure complications in hospitalization by using our proBNP assay to determine therapy intervention in the emergency room.</p>
          <p>And also our STeP study, which demonstrates that if you track your diabetes measurement, blood glucose measurements over several days in a structured way, you have a much better chance of controlling your HbA1c and your glycemic control, leading to obviously better patient results and also better impact on the healthcare system.</p>
          <p>These are just three examples, but it's examples, firm examples of what I mean by the differentiating factor that Roche brings to the diagnostics environment versus other competitors out there in the diagnostics field.</p>
          <p>Severin and Pascal talked about the strong late stage portfolio in the Pharma business, six of which have companion diagnostics associated with them, all six of which are in the Roche group. In fact, within the Roche group today we have more than 160 collaborations on Diagnostics and Pharma and more than 22 of those are companion diagnostic hypothesis.</p>
          <p>The thing I want to point out here is that three of these six come from our tissue diagnostics program, so the Met and the two HERs; two come from elective diagnostics, BRAF and HCV and the last one, Periostin, comes from our professional diagnostics. Now the reason that's important is because within the Roche group we have all the technologies to be able to follow the science of the biomarker, whether it's a protein, a DNA or a tissue-based sample.</p>
          <p>It allows us to leverage, again, the knowledge from the Pharma side on to creating new innovative assays on the Diagnostics sides, and vice versa, given the regulatory hurdles with getting the companion diagnostics approved in many countries, Pharma benefits by having the expertise in Diagnostics and making sure that test is available in a reproducible way out there in a large installed base throughout the world.</p>
          <p>And we know that the quality of our assays discriminate from other assays out in the marketplace, such that you can get between 15% and 20% invalids using some of the home grew assays whereas with our assays you have much more accuracy. This makes a big difference when you're talking about something like BRAF where if you were to miss 20% of patients that were not going to able to take advantage of a melanoma treatment specific to their mutation, that obviously has a big impact also on the Pharma business case.</p>
          <p>Now in addition to the internal innovation last year, we looked outside. We purchased &#x2013; these are two of the acquisitions we did last year. Medingo and the patch pump, which is on target to be able to launch in 2012, which I think will change the way that patients with diabetes manage their insulin by having a very convenient pump device.</p>
          <p>And the second one is BioImagene, which is a product that will be utilized in our tissue diagnostics area that allows what is still a very manual process of reading slides by a pathologist to be automated on a computer system and algorithms that take accounting of slides literally by hand to a much more specific process for more sophisticated diagnoses as well in oncology.</p>
          <p>We had some very successful research collaborations underway in the area of sequencing, HPV and Diabetes Care. And we accessed freedom to operate on three key intellectual property assets that are also with the Roche group under development in terms of pathways on oncology.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion on the Diagnostics side, strong year in 2010. We expect to also have another strong year in 2011 based upon the momentum that we have. We'll be focused on delivering innovative products in each of our business areas, and we commit to driving the Diagnostics business at Roche, again, above the Diagnostics marketplace in 2011, and continuing to refine our profitability and to improve our profitability over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>So thank you very much for your attention. I turn it over now to Erich to cover the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dan. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I know very well that at this time of the day you have digested the financials, and I will try to be as helpful as possible.</p>
          <p>If we go into the key financials, many figures developed along your expectations. I think there were certain exceptions. If we go, if I pick the tax rate, very nice development year-on-year from 2009 to 2010. But even much better if you compare half year 2010 to full year 2010, and of course, the question for you is, it this sustainable or not?</p>
          <p>Good news is that there are two elements in there, in the improvement in the second half year which are from my perspective sustainable. So there is not only a tax competition between Switzerland and other countries, the good news is that within Switzerland there is a heavy competition between the states and the State of Basel City has actually lowered the tax rate for companies, and this has given us a positive boost, and this is a permanent benefit in here.</p>
          <p>And the second element that was really a close call just prior to the end of the year. You may reminded there was this heavy fight about the tax bill of President Obama. The good news is that hidden somewhere in this big package there where the R&amp;D tax credits, and they were also approved. But it was now many consecutive years that the U.S.A. have rewarded innovation in their country by tax credit.</p>
          <p>So I think we can be quite confident that this should be a sustainable effect. Of course, the negative deviations year-on-year 2009 through 2010 are around the cash flow, and therefore I would like to focus for a moment in here because you see the operating free cash flow went down 10%.</p>
          <p>So it this a negative trend? The answer is actually no, but 2009 was especially good year, but however on the operating cash flow situation there were two elements where actually accounting wise or one element where accounting wise the business was reflected in 2009, but cash wise the hit was in 2010. And this was the huge sales of Tamiflu in the fourth quarter of 2009, and as you know, Tamiflu originated at Gilead, which deserves quite a nice royalty stream.</p>
          <p>So we only pay the royalty stream for the heavy quarter, fourth quarter 2009 in actually the first quarter of 2010. And then for those who have followed the situation at Roche, Genentech closely, there was an employee retention program during the transaction to keep people on board because it was no longer reasonable to hand out options to the Genentech management and employees. And this was, of course, this was staggered over a certain time, and in 2010 there was a significant payout cash wise in relation to this retention program.</p>
          <p>And on the free cash flow side also in 2009, we had actually a tax benefit out of the transaction of the Genentech privatization and whereas the interest expenses of all the bond raised, of course, accounting wise hit also the P&amp;L of 2009. Many of these bonds have an annual coupon, so the cash out for the first nine months 2009 of all these bonds was only in the year 2010. So nothing to be worried about. I think there are clear explanations for these trends.</p>
          <p>If we go to the operating performance, it's just adding together really an excellent performance of Diagnostics, and a very good performance of Pharma, ends up with this situation here on the core operating profit. And as we had guided you, we were totally confident to be able to cut out considerable cost out of bringing the two former headquarters, the Roche Pharma Nutley operations, and Genentech South San Francisco together and that's what you see in the various lines of the P&amp;L statement. And this leads as a group, but also for the divisions I think to industry leading operating profit margins.</p>
          <p>For people who follow us very closely, no surprise here, but we have decided as we announced at the third quarter conference call, we have announced to further separate the IFRS statements from the underlying business statements. You see, in the past we already wanted to be extremely transparent, but we therefore had lines of exceptional items within the IFRS statements and we have to respect that the monitoring bodies, the accounting standard boards don't just like this kind of mixing underlying business to the firm's standard, so we give them what they want.</p>
          <p>So they get their firm IFRS statement, but on the other hand, we respect that you want to understand then, the buy siders want to understand a clear trend what is underlying. And therefore we have decided to give you the core P&amp;L, the core operating situation, but what you of course also find is a clear bridge between both accounts.</p>
          <p>So there's no &#x2013; nothing hidden, and this chart gives you an example where you can find where is the difference of the non-core items, and it's split very nicely down, and since the guys travel to London and they like to explain it, it's marketing for Ian Bishop's accounting workshop. I think it is very transparent here, but if you have any questions to this, please join him in his workshop and he will be very pleased to dig even deeper into the details.</p>
          <p>Going below the operating line, I think hopefully no big surprises, except that the cash situation of the Roche group allowed us just before Christmas to call another part of a bond. I think we explained to you that at the moment liquid funds, to have tem risk-free laying around just doesn't make sense. And of course, we had a clear financial plan over several years when we did the Genentech transaction, but at this horizon there was no scenario over swine flu.</p>
          <p>And the good news is that the swine flu just put the nice wave of cash into our boxes, and what you can now see is that instead of having this cash sitting around idle and not generating anything, we used it in 2010 to actually overall to pay down an additional $3.5 billion. And this of course, gives a certain hit in 2010, but it also gives a nice relief in the following years up to the original maturities of this bond.</p>
          <p>Forex results, you have seen how the international markets are nicely developing. That's very nice. On the other hand, some of these currencies have quite a big volatility. If you want to hedge them, you will incur hedging cost, and that's what's in this additional result. And there is one currency which is not volatile, but nobody hedges it anyway or if you know somebody who hedges Venezuela, let my treasurer know. That's at least what they tell me.</p>
          <p>And Mr. Chavez has decided just before Christmas to change the exchange rate for Pharmaceutical and Diagnostics, and this we had to reflect in our accounts. As I told you, tax rate, nice development and I don't want to put any challenge on the shoulder of my successor, but I think &#x2013; we always guided you that you should be on the safe side with 22% to 24%.</p>
          <p>Now I think it could be slightly lower the bandwidth for the tax rate. Cash flow I have explained the development and here again you see quite nicely that even in a year where the free cash flow was a little bit lower than 2009, if you put it in comparison to the net debt remaining, you now understand that we are fully convinced that we can come to a net cash position by the end of 2014. You have the picture of the debt already paid down, and I think it's not a bad situation.</p>
          <p>We are not even two years after closing of the Genentech transaction and 35 &#x2013; 33% of the debt is already gone. And if you have a look at this, maturity schedule, I think it is very nice how you see the additional early calls we had, the 3.5 billion. And I think this is also quite a nice schedule for the future of Roche, and I allowed myself to put a chart in which my team came up prior to the Board meeting and it is actually a good learning chart.</p>
          <p>In 2009, Roche had almost no debt, and we had a net cash position of 23 billion I think. And if you wanted get to an insurance, a CDS for a five years Roche bond at this time, you paid around 72 basis points. And then, of course, when we raised the huge debt in the U.S. in euro and in British pound and Swiss francs and in the midst of the financial crisis, of course the CDS five years went up tremendously.</p>
          <p>You see it, but the nice thing is that maybe also because we always have kept our word to the bond investors, and we have even advanced our repayment here, you see at the moment that our CDS is slightly lower than the CDS of state bonds of Germany. Karl insisted that I should also put the U.K. line in, but I'm a gentleman so I left it out.</p>
          <p>So this leaves me with the balance sheet, which is also on the recovery of our equity situation. I think also this is strengthening again after the impact of the Genentech transaction, and the outlook has already been explained by Severin.</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Erich. With this I suggest that we go straight into your questions. I think we have a question over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jill Walton from Credit Suisse. Firstly, may I echo Severin's comments and thank Erich very much for being an extremely approachable finance director for us in the investment community. You have presided over improved disclosure, both in terms of transparency and consistency of disclosure and I think most importantly, you've turned Roche back into Roche, a pharmaceutical company. So thank you very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps you can give us some thoughts as you're leaving on R&amp;D productivity. You've put Operational Excellence in place. R&amp;D productivity is probably one of the biggest issues that the industry has to face. What's the Operational Excellence program going to be able to do to help address that? And could, Pascal, also talk a little bit more about Page 127, and you do get through all of this disclosure, where you talk about healthcare reforms, and in particular, potentially increasing reforms of 2012 and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Erich, you start off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you have seen in all the charts and I think my last conference was the JPMorgan conference, if you go for Roche, you go for innovation, and innovation has a certain price. I'm personally absolutely convinced that this late stage pipeline is quite unique in the industry, and it will deliver ,and we also have to respect that the development of these unique molecules has become more expensive to a certain extent also due to increased regulations by the governments.</p>
          <p>So I think the program we have set up last year by, on the one hand also bringing certain R&amp;D sites together to get efficiencies out, economies of scale in certain units, but especially also really streamlining, and that's actually Pascal's area, where they have streamlined the development activities and have identified really potential improvement without cutting down on projects and leaving out projects. I personally think they are absolutely on the right track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the question relating to so-called healthcare reform, which is a nice word to describe price cuts in a number of countries around the world. I think what you see here in 2011 is an increase, a mechanical increase due to the fact that a number of these programs only started midyear last year to later in the year. So for instance, the price reductions in Germany which were quite substantial started impacting 2010 in July. So you have a mechanical increase again in 2011. And then a number of countries launched additional programs later in the year. So there's the mechanical effect here, then there's the excise tax in the U.S. which is new, and also a mechanical effect in the U.S.</p>
          <p>I hope I think we all believe that after this we will return to kind of more usual way of operating, if I may call it that way, where we have regular, but much smaller price decreases in Europe. But it's really hard to predict what the governments will do in 2012. It will very much depend on the fiscal status and the world economy. I think we've seen the worst of it all, hopefully.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pascal. We have a question here in the first row please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. It's Sachin Jain from Merrill Lynch. Firstly, just a very broad question. New CFO starting April. Any particular new mandate, focus? What does Alan Hippe bring to the table from your perspective? And then two questions for Pascal. Firstly on the biosimilar erosion scenarios that you outlined, just to clarify the commentary. One of the charts obviously has EPO, G-CSF market share for biosimilars in the 5% to 10% range. The schematic you put up on Herceptin references the German EPO situation where I think the share is close to 60%. So where in that range do you see it? At 60%, isn't that far off the small molecule erosion, albeit over a long timeframe. And then a very quick question on dal-PLAQUE. It was mentioned this morning the data may be at ACC. Can I just clarify that study is primarily a safety study? And do we expect any meaningful efficacy readout from that data? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So if may start off with the succession of Erich. When Erich started to consider retiring, and we started to look outside for a successor, I really had two criteria. One was to make sure that we have a person with a sound track record as a Chief Financial Officer to continue the professionalism which we have experience with Erich.</p>
          <p>And the second element was that he would fit into the Roche organization; that he would be a team player in my team and that he would fit to the organization as a person, and I think he brings both those aspects along, so I'm sure that he will be able to continue the successful work of Erich. Pascal, there was a question to you regarding Herceptin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the rate of erosion. It's a good question. The graph you saw is the kind of average across Europe, so you would say variations from country to country. Cost situation in Germany is a bit worse than it is elsewhere. I think what I'd like to kind of leave you with is not so much to focus on this graph. It was more illustrative. I think you need to keep in mind our main approach is to progress the standard of care. And if you look at HER2 breast cancer, the combination with pertuzumab is going to move the standard of care and it will make monotherapy Herceptin less relevant.</p>
          <p>T-DM1 will also move the standard of care, sub-Q formulation will slow down the erosion of Herceptin monotherapy. So it's really these various products that present the most important part of our approach to this, and in terms of the erosion, it's going to be somewhere in between what we experience on average here and what you see with a small molecule. And our forecast is basically assuming that certainly it will be a little bit worse than what we have here. But I guess the message is it is manageable we believe, yeah.</p>
          <p>And I think the other thing to keep in mind is that what you don't see so much in the EPO market is the enormous growth opportunity that exists in the emerging markets. We see it in China. We have already early indications we can grow faster in Brazil, in Korea we are making some good inroads. So the whole team worldwide now is focused on how do we actually develop creative schemes so we expand access and compensate with volume increases part of what we will lose on price and on top of this, of course, we move the standard of care. So that's the erosion.</p>
          <p>Dal-PLAQUE, essentially we have the results. We are analyzing them. We are planning to file as quickly as we can to a major congress this year. It could be ACC. I cannot confirm that today. This is indeed sized for safety, not for efficacy, but we look at the trends. We've seen the data, of course, but it's essentially aimed at safety because the study originally was introduced or launched as an early safety signal. We have that outcome that is running, of course, and we wanted to see whether there was any safety signal that would emerge at an early stage. You have to remember this is a couple of years ago in the middle of the torcetrapib discussions, so it was dimension for safety at the time. And what I can tell you is that what we've seen so far is basically encouraging us to keep going as far as safety is concerned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A question here, please. Andrew? Yes, please. And then we move forward to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just a quick follow-up on Herceptin. This is <mark type="inaudible" />. What importance do you see to the sub-Q formulations? What part of this tells of Herceptin you think that can replace? And when do you expect the annual study to report? And how does it fit in your <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, the acoustic in this room is not so good, but I will try. I think I heard your question, hopefully. Tell me if I don't answer it properly. What do we hope to achieve with the sub-Q formulation is number one, of course, an improvement in compliance. I think we have to realize that even though we're dealing with breast cancer, even though you would assume patients with breast cancer would actually treat themselves and take their medicines as long as necessary, the reality is that as soon as patients feel better, compliance is likely to decline.</p>
          <p>So especially in the context of two year treatment duration potentially, compliance becomes a very substantial issue. So that sub-Q formulation will improve compliance, and two is we also are hoping for an improvement in tolerability or less reactions to Herceptin. And early indications tell us that it is achievable, so it's not going to be the magic bullet to, of course, hand off the biosimilars completely, but it is something that will help us define our position and improve the way patients are treated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pascal. Andrew, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Andrew Baum from Morgan Stanley. Couple of questions, please. The first one's for Severin on the topic of R&amp;D productivity looking at your CHF 10 billion annual R&amp;D spend. One of the big parts of the legacy of your Chairman when his Phase III pipeline blew up when he was in your job as head officer years ago was he made the courageous decision to exit a couple of Roche's legacy areas and invest almost entirely in biologics. And that was obviously a very astute and wise decision. I guess when you think about your legacy, you're also facing challenges of a different sort. Under what circumstances would you contemplate folding Roche research into Genentech and eliminating some of the overheads in order to drive up R&amp;D productivity? That's the first question. And the second question is &#x2013; I'll let you think about that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have to think &#x2013; shall I take it right away? I don't have to think about the answer here. There is no way whatsoever that we would consider merging what we call the G-rate organization on the one hand which is the legacy Genentech research and early development organization and the P-rate organization which is the legacy Roche research and early development organization on the other hand. I really don't believe, especially in research and early development, very different in late stage development, but in research and early development I do not believe that it is a question of scale. I don't think that you get more productive by putting together everything in a big organization. On the contrary, I'm sure that if we would get big, it would stifle us, it would get a rigid organization and productivity would go down.</p>
          <p>Now there's is a second element to you question and that is the portfolio of products, how much can we afford? Where do we have to streamline? How do we get more efficient? Now we have currently overall spend of CHF 9 billion. That is certainly a big amount, and I think that should be an amount which obliges us to deliver innovative breakthrough medicines as we go forward. We have looked at the R&amp;D portfolio in the context of Operational Excellence, and what we have done is actually two things. On the one hand, on research side we have taken out a number of projects, and we have exited some technologies, mostly importantly also from a financial point of view the siRNA technology where we decided to terminate.</p>
          <p>And that gives relief as we go forward. The second element was late stage. On the late stage side we looked at the portfolio. There was, of course, the open question on taspoglutide, but we looked at the portfolio and we came to the conclusion that we should not throw away those assets, that we should further finance those assets. But we equally said also in development or in particular in development, we have to make sure that we are very efficient, that we are very effective.</p>
          <p>And what we did too is we said are there certain activities in the group which can be done either externally or within the group network in a more efficient manner? And as a result of this discussion we decided to reduce our head count markedly in Nutley, New Jersey, and outsource a number of those functions either externally or even internally. For example, in India we will build up our base from 300 to 600 people to take over mobile team activities which we currently do at also very expensive places like the U.S. Put that all together, I would assume going forward that we keep R&amp;D into 2011 stable, slightly declining.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question was very short, which is for Pascal. You alluded to the Actemra versus TNF trial. Given just at memory, I seem to remember the end point in that trial wasn't ACR20/50/70, it was some softer endpoint which would be &#x2013; have marketing rather than necessarily guideline impact. Could you remind me what the endpoints of that trial were?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, before I do this, actually if you don't mind, let me go back to the previous question for one second because I thought about something after I finished answering this question is that with Herceptin, what we found in some countries is that the product keeps growing even though we think we are treating all the patients who would need to be treated. And as we started digging into what is happening, what we found is that there's an increasing number of patients who are treated on Herceptin and have been on Herceptin for three or four years.</p>
          <p>So in that context, compliance and the sub-Q formulation will also be very critical helping those patients stay on drug longer. There's quite a number of patients who even though the approval is for one year, doctors use the drug for much longer. So your question, Andrew, on Actemra, I think it's actually ADAS-Cog, but I want to double check. Yeah, DAS28. I was going to say DAS28 and that's what it is. So DAS28 score. I would not say it's a soft score. I think it is, how you call it, parameter score that is challenged a little bit in the U.S., but is well accepted in Europe and actually its acceptance in the U.S. market is rapidly increasing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yes, if you have a question here on that side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Michael Leacock from RBS. Two questions, if I may. Firstly, aside from the one-off of Operational Excellence programs, in terms of productivity, one of your peers has targeted their managers with a 5% to 8% annual reduction in costs per output that they get. In other words, a material improvement in productivity year-on-year. What would be your target for your managers?</p>
          <p>And secondly, Daniel, on the Diagnostics, I think we've all been delighted and disappointed in equal measure by the roller coaster of margins in Diagnostics over the past. Could you just reassure us a little more about the sustainability of your obviously excellent performance for this year and also as you're leaders in the diagnostic business, how far can you go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I make a first comment on cost management in general and total resource allocation in general before &#x2013; Dan perhaps you can go into the specifics for Diagnostics. I truly believe that good management is not about cutting cost across the organization. I mean, it's very easy to tell all your people, cut your cost by 5% or cut your cost by 15% or cut it by 20%, whatever. It is not good management. Everybody can do this. Good management is allocating resources to the biggest opportunities, and that means that in certain cases you eliminate the cost. You cut it by 100%. And in other areas, you might even invest, because you have an opportunity and you speed up a trial because the opportunity is really huge because you get new data and therefore you should invest into more.</p>
          <p>I do not believe in management by haircuts. I believe in management by allocating resources wisely to those opportunities which really create value, and that was one of the key considerations which we took when we approached Operational Excellence. It was one of the principles which I told everybody internally, don't fall into the trap of just doing haircuts. Look at how you can do your business differently; look what you can skip altogether; look at new growth opportunities; look at new projects where you can invest money, but don't just simply haircut. This would be completely wrong. You can do this in certain functions. If you think of procurement, for example, there you can say okay, procurement that's something where I want to take every year some cost out and you take a certain number and you give it top down to your organization, and probably that works.</p>
          <p>But if it comes to development, you have to look at the opportunities. If it comes to marketing, you have to differentiate very much. I mean, I wouldn't cut in growing markets like China, stupid. I mean, if you have a growth of 40% like in Diagnostics, if you grow over 20% in markets like Brazil, et cetera, I mean then you invest there because you need this growth. Likewise, you have to be very tough in other markets where you experience severe price cuts, as this is now the case in the U.S. and in Europe and we took very tough measures to completely restructure, for example, our sales force. And where we took out the complete primary care sales force in a very conscious manner. So I do not believe in haircuts. I believe it is important, especially in a situation where the external pressures are increasing that managers apply common sense and that managers allocate resources where the opportunities are the biggest. In this context, Dan, over to you for Diagnostics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've never been a fan of amusement parks, so I can understand your roller coaster hesitancy. I believe &#x2013; I can understand some of the history here. Fundamentally, the things that have driven the margin change over the past year have been things that, in my opinion, are sustainable because they really are, as I said before, first of all, it's dependent upon growing the top line, which is important. Secondly, this product mix is sustainable. I mean, the products that are contributing to our 8% growth really do have favorable gross margins, and they have life cycles that will be there for many years to come. They're not one year products. And then finally, I also believe we've fundamentally addressed some of the cost of goods issues on the manufacturing side. We have more work to do there. Clearly, this is a work in progress, but I do think that's sustainable.</p>
          <p>The other thing I believe is, with the core accounting process now, some of the volatility in the past also dealt with some acquisitions that we had and acquisition accounting that hit our bottom line. I think we will continue to look for acquisitions that complement our business, but I think that should be looked at in light of outside of the core reporting, which will also help us be a bit more steady into the future.</p>
          <p>And then finally, I do believe in terms of the future potential that we're at a good stage right now. I think we can improve it a bit more, but as I said before, the margin return on the Diagnostics business, given the competitive barriers to entry to this business allow us to have a good return on a risk base that has a different risk profile than Pharma. So will we ever get to 30%, 40% profit margins? No, and we shouldn't expect that, given the competitiveness of our business, given the dynamics of our business. But I do believe where we're at today we can see some continued improvement, and I believe it's also sustainable and that's the way we intend to manage the business moving forward. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can we have the question here in the third row? And then next two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Vincent Rouvi&#xE8;re from Exane BNP Paribas. I have couple of questions. The first one is on China and Avastin. You have alluded several times that there is still growth avenues for Avastin notably in China. Can you please tell us what is currently the pricing of Avastin in China versus the rest of the world, especially the U.S. and Europe and what can you expect from the Chinese development regarding the pricing? And more broadly regarding China, what is the margin, the operating margin in China currently and what can we expect in the future?</p>
          <p>The second question is with regards to Avastin in ovarian cancer. Can you give please update us on the filing in the U.S.? When do you expect to file? What do you need to file? And also, when will you publish the OCEANS results? And is it a separate filing? Or will you file the first time and the relapsed indication together?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Pascal, you want to take the two questions? So if we start with China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China, actually when I referred to China I really had in mind the Herceptin and MabThera in term of rapid expansion of access. Avastin at this point, the answer to your question is the price is similar to European price, which is slightly lower than the U.S. price, but not much difference. So I'd say the price of Avastin in China is coherent with what we have in Europe.</p>
          <p>And I was really referring to Herceptin/MabThera. Avastin will remain an out of pocket drug in China for a little while I'm sure. But Herceptin and MabThera have such a strong clinical value and we have the ability now, the possibility to start managing our price and come up with proposals for payers that are such that I think we can actually crack the marketplace, and we have &#x2013; there are signs that some regions are already finding our proposals attractive. So I have really more Herceptin/MabThera where the price flexibility is greater and we're getting to a stage where I think the country can afford it.</p>
          <p>Operating margin in China, I can't give you specific numbers. I don't think we would want to do this. I can tell you it's slightly lower than the other countries around the world, but simply because we invest more. We're growing by 20% plus in China, so we are expanding the sales force. We are investing. Our promotional investment as a percentage of sales is higher than any other country in the world simply because we invest, and we are supporting the growth of our business. It's such an enormous country. Historically, we were focused on the big cities and now we're starting to expand, and we are actually doing it right now for products like Pegasys and Xeloda. Those are really priced at levels that &#x2013; regions that are maybe less rich than the richer region of Shanghai or Beijing. Those regions are now starting to be able to afford those products, so we start with those and then Herceptin/MabThera will follow.</p>
          <p>Avastin ovarian. I think your question was when do we file? So we file this year. I can't tell you exactly precisely when because I wouldn't want to disclose that, but probably in the second half of 2011. The OCEANS data will read at Q1, first half of 2011, and I think your other question was why are we filing the U.S. later? And it's because the FDA asked us for overall survival data, and we will file with those data a little bit later this year. And that's it. Yeah, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Please in the second row, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Amit Roy from Nomura. I have a couple of questions on Avastin. Firstly in Europe, in colorectal cancer penetration you've put on the slide is 45% and stable, the same wording as you used on last quarter. Is it fair to say that Avastin stopped growing in colon cancer in Europe? And a similar question actually for lung as well which has been 10 to 15 for years, to be frank. Second question on Alimta in the U.S. Are you seeing any loss of market share from Alimta competition with Avastin in first line and in the maintenance setting, the sort of combination that you have there in the States? And lastly just around the 800 million of the negative hits on Avastin. Could you help sort of split out how much is that is coming from the U.S. and in terms of the U.S. number, are we starting from 600 first line and 300 off label? If you could just give us clarity as to how much is U.S. and how much is Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. So the colorectal and lung cancer, the colorectal cancer question in Europe is a fair one. It is true that we are not making the progress that we like to see us making in Europe. And to some extent, I mean we have very good shares in France, for instance, so let me start again. When we give you a share in Europe, you have to consider it's across Europe, right? So you have great viability starting in the U.K. and fortunately here patients can't even get access because there is no funding or very limited funding.</p>
          <p>So we have countries like France where access is not so much of an issue where we have patient share in colorectal cancer that are very similar to what we have in the U.S., 60 plus percent and we're doing very well there. So it range from this &#x2013; it ranges from this all the way down to very low in some countries where access is limited. Now what we found in some countries like Italy, Spain and others, 2010 was really a tough year because those countries operate on a regional basis, and various regions of Spain have budgets they have to operate with. And in those regions it was really, access was more challenged. I think in Europe we still have quite a bit of potential in colorectal cancer, and there is no doubt and that is going to be our focus to drive colorectal cancer and increase our share there.</p>
          <p>We can move. We should be moving more than we are at this point, and the same for lung cancer. Actually, in fact in lung cancer we're making some nice progress, not huge progress, but steady progress in Europe since it's really colorectal that we need to unlock. Alimta, we haven't seen loss of share to Alimta in the U.S. and the 800 million, I hope my lawyer here will, Karl, will not actually disagree with me giving some split of this. It's mostly the U.S., mostly the U.S. Close to &#x2013; it's essentially breast cancer as you know or it is breast cancer, and it's about close to 600 million would be the U.S. share of those 800 million essentially because the assumption is losing the indication will have a massive impact on prescribing, of course. And in the rest of the world the impact will be more limited. There will be some impact because payers will challenge us, as you can imagine, even though the indication is still present, but the bulk of the economy would be U.S. driven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Alexandra in the end third row, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Alexandra Hauber from JPMorgan. I have two questions on Diagnostics. On the companion diagnostics I've for the longest time have seen this as mostly as an enabler for pharmaceuticals, but how do you make money on this in Diagnostics? Is this like a fee per assay you're going to run on one of your molecular diagnostics machine? If so, what would be a typical fee for something like a BRAF test? Is that going to be comparable to other assays you run on the similar machine? And if &#x2013; any method how you could bundle this much better with the Pharma division? How do you capture that medical value you're actually creating? And on the other side, can you also talk about what these studies are going to do for you? I think I sort of do get ATHENA, but what does PROTECT and STeP do for you? Are these just going to increase your overall testing volumes? Or some will also give you more market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, yes. Let me address the first one first because I always say to Pascal, there's win-win in the companion diagnostics. It's not all about the value being on the Pharma side. But clearly, there is a value on the Pharma side, as I said before. But in the Diagnostics side, it's two fold. Number one, to your point, I believe that these assays have good clinical and economic data behind them. The BRIM study will produce some significant data, for instance, on BRAF that we can go forward to for reimbursement authorities and intend to get premium pricing on a single assay like that. However, that's I still think a smaller part of the potential. The larger part of the potential comes in with understanding the Diagnostics business model, which is at the end of the day we sell systems. We don't sell individual assays, so when we go into sell a cobas 6000 or cobas 4800 to our customer base, what they're really interested in is, first of all, do the instruments work well in their lab? Can they run a lot of samples on it? Does the IT work? But secondly, these are all closed system, so our reagents only work on our systems. So then what they want to know is, what's the menu you have? And the first thing they need to know is what's the breadth of menu, which I think a of companies can do, but if you have one or two high value assays that are proprietary to your systems, our customers will disproportionally choose our systems versus the competitors because they want to be able to run all the assays on one system.</p>
          <p>Lab space is a difficult thing in most labs, and the last thing they want is one piece of equipment that sits in the corner that they have to run once a week on a couple of assays. It's impractical for them economically, and also just work flow wise within the lab. And we've seen, it by the way. I mean, there's a specific example I can show to you. On the immunoassay menu for quite some time we didn't have the HCV parameter, but we had a lot of other infectious disease parameters on that. And what we saw is as soon as we launched HCV on our systems, on the one hand you saw HCV increased sales, but then you saw the whole infectious disease menu actually increase on the system. And this is what's driving some of our 17% growth on the immunoassay side.</p>
          <p>So for us, it's not about the single assay only, although I think the single assay is important. It's about the mix affect across, and it brings our whole business value forward. And by the way, this is something I have to preach in my organizations too because you can get people that do a business case on one particular assay and say, well it's marginal. And I say, you have to look at the mix, but it does significantly bring our business up. And on the second question relative to what are we going to do with these studies and how will it drive our business moving forward? I think each one probably has a different answer in a different business case, but something like the STeP study for instance. What this allows us to do I believe is first of all increase the market potential on blood glucose monitoring, and then because of the nature of our systems, the automated nature of our systems in terms of capturing that data, we can disproportionally gain market share because it's easier to do structured testing on our blood glucose meter versus others, for instance.</p>
          <p>So each one of these proBNP, I mean, what we have to remember as we do these studies in assays that each assay is unique. So proBNP, our proBNP is not identical to somebody else's proBNP, and they would need to be able to demonstrate the similar clinical data similar to HPV. I mean, the way that we have our clinical cutoffs on our HPV 16 and 18 assay cannot be compared to other assays, which is why, by the way, regulatory authorities in the U.S., the highest regulatory authority would say every person that brings a new HPV assay forward will have to do a similar prospective clinical trial to demonstrate that their clinical cutoffs are corresponding to the benefits they bring to patients. So we have a lot of work to do. I mean, this is new territory for Diagnostics in terms of getting this information into the hands of clinicians, and changing requests of clinician to labs, but I believe we have the data to be able to do it with now, strong data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dan. We take a question further back here. Yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. It's Mark Purcell from Barclays Capital. A few questions. Firstly, on CellCept, I think the patent expired in Europe at end of 2010. What should we expect in terms of the impact for 2011? Secondly on pertuzumab, clearly you're excited about the NEOSPHERE data. Just wondered how we should think about the response rate or the relative response rate benefit we saw there and translating it into a PFS endpoint in the CLEOPATRA trial at the end of this year? Thirdly, I wondered if you could provide us with a little bit more detail in terms of your pricing strategy for Herceptin in international markets, and how you might respond to say 50% price cuts that the biosimilars might bring through in 2012, '13 in Asia and Latin America? And then lastly on Lucentis, VEGF Trap, I was just wondering how you intend to respond to those data? We see some more information this month and your plans, I guess, here for high dose Lucentis trials going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I give a number? Yeah, so we basically now are going to be facing the patent expiry of CellCept in Europe. And the expected impact is about 200 million francs on the CellCept side. So there's still a little bit of U.S. decline, of course, but now we're really talking about Europe and the rest of the world, which is really kind of one of the headwinds that we're facing in 2011 as part of you saw in Severin presentation, this 500 million being Boniva and CellCept. In fact, it's more than 200. It's about 250 CellCept decline. The second question was Herceptin. I'm not sure I actually got that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, pertuzumab.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pertuzumab, yeah. So pertuzumab, you saw the NEOSPHERE data. I showed you this, and essentially now CLEOPATRA is, the end point is a PFS endpoint in combination with Herceptin. We have to see what those results look like. I don't want to speculate. I don't want to speculate because essentially given those results &#x2013; the strength of those results will define whether we can file early or not, and we hope we can file early in 2011, but of course we'll have to see what those results look like. The Herceptin pricing, I'm actually not sure I really got the question because the acoustics, again, playing against me. You were asking me how we would respond in Latin America, for instance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just asking just in terms of international markets, I guess if you could provide some more details on your flexible pricing structures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Flexible pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because I guess we may see some more significant results from pricing...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Yeah. I'm sorry. This one I don't think I would like to answer because of course I would be basically kind of disclosing information that we would want to keep to ourselves. It's confidential. I can only tell you that we are considering very flexible pricing policies in a number of countries. We've defined our policy actually. We've spent a fair amount of time working on it with the various countries around the world. They have a policy, and everybody now is working within the confines of that contracting policy and defining programs and proposals country-by-country, but there's a pretty substantial flexibility around what we can do provided this, of course, helps more patients access the drug.</p>
          <p>Reducing price just for the sake of it doesn't help anybody. What we want to do is make sure that the thousands of patients who could benefit from Herceptin will benefit from Herceptin if we are flexible on pricing. So those kind of discussions take, of course, a few months. We started last year and we'll keep going this year. Instead of VEGF Trap we still see &#x2013; we still need to see the full results, the publication of the full results because if you look at it today, I mean, it sounds like efficacy similar to Lucentis except you give it every two months. But when you look at the data, the monthly administration didn't show so much of a difference versus Lucentis, and so there is a possibility that, in fact, the drug is not more &#x2013; not only more effective, but very similar to Lucentis and actually monthly, on a monthly basis. But today from what we have seen and also on the interim results, this is a drug that looks like having similar efficacy, but can be given every two months as opposed to every month.</p>
          <p>Now you need to keep in mind that the average number of injections of Lucentis per year was about 6, 6.5, so it tells you that a lot of physicians are using Lucentis on a PRN basis. So they adjust the administration. They don't give it every month. In fact, there's all sorts of regimens out there. When you talk to physicians, some of them start with Lucentis, then they move to Avastin, so they do all sorts of things. So it's not going to be as simple saying, okay, it's the same as Lucentis, but you give it every two months, which sounds like a very attractive story, but I think will be more complicated. On top of it, we are developing the high dose, 2 milligram dose of Lucentis, as you probably know. We will have to see what that regimen delivers in term of comparable efficacy or so is it going to be better efficacy or is it going to be PRN? We, at the very least, we believe it will enable physicians to use Lucentis on a PRN, on as needed basis and if we achieve this, then the competitive playing field will be leveled with VEGF Trap. So we still have to wait, but it's possible that the story for this VEGF Trap is not attractive, as attractive as it looks today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pascal. We still have time for one more question before we go into the breakout sessions. Can we have the lady here in the middle, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> I have a few questions and they actually all relate to your 2011 core EPS guidance. The first is I do obviously realize you have very significant headwinds in 2011, but in my calculations, your restructuring program alone should drive double digit core EPS growth in constant currency. So your guidance basically implies that if it wasn't for that program then you would have a decline for EPS, despite overall top line growth, despite incremental Genentech synergies and an improving financial result and tax rate and despite improving Diagnostics margins. So that seems to imply underlying declining Pharma margins quite significantly despite stable R&amp;D spend. So I was just wondering if you could walk me through the remaining cost lines within Pharma on an underlying basis, i.e., pre-restructuring? The related question is I fully realize that your 2011 core EPS guidance for high single digit growth is obviously you best guess right now, and you wouldn't want to put anything that the new CFO might want to do. But I'm just wondering whether at this stage you would rule out growth well into the double-digits? Or whether you just don't want to speculate? And my final question also related to that. If your 2011 growth is largely driven by the restructuring benefits, can you just tell us roughly what conclusions we should draw for the 2013, 2014 period when the restructuring program will be completed and you're going to be facing some biosimilar competition and probably not that much incremental from the late stage pipeline yet? Is there actually a chance that we should see core EPS declining then? Or do you think that the dynamics with the underlying margins would just be very, very different to 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. I'm not sure whether I can give you an answer on all your elements you are looking at. Now we give guidance for one year. We have given out this guidance this morning. I'm sorry, I'm not in a position to speculate about the own guidance we just gave out this morning, and we are not giving a guidance over a longer timeframe. Having said this, on one of my slides you have seen on the one hand the 2 billion which we expect in terms of incremental cost savings as we go into 2011, and on the other hand you see some major impacts from healthcare reform, from patent expiries, from Avastin, from Tamiflu where we expect less sales.</p>
          <p>If you add up the two sides, the headwinds on the one hand and the savings from Operational Excellence, you will not get to a high single digit core EPS if you don't see profit growth from the underlying business. So on top of the restructuring, there is a growth from the underlying business. Diagnostics is part of that, but also on the Pharmaceuticals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. With this, we break up in the various sessions. Eric and myself, we stay here, and Dan and Pascal are going into their respective rooms.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>