<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1410638" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-08-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>49078</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Alexander Palivoda</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="First Vice President-Economics &amp; Finance">Pavel Sergeyevich Fedorov</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Global Markets Research (Russia)">Pavel Kushnir</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Head of Business Planning, Rosneft NK OAO">Evgeny Gribov</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Bank International (Moscow)">Andrey Gromadin</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citibank ZAO (Broker)">Ron P. Smith MBA</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Mark N. Henderson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Alexey Pavlov</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Troika Dialog Group">Alex Fak</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="VTB Capital CJSC (Broker)">Alexander Kirevnin</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for standing by and welcome to the Rosneft Second Quarter 2011 Financial Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. There will be a presentation followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would like to advise you this conference is being recorded today on Monday, August 1, 2011. I would now like to hand the conference over to your speaker today, Alexander Palivoda, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to Rosneft second quarter 2011 financial results conference call. My name is Alexander Palivoda, I'm Head of Investor Relations, and I am joined at our Moscow headquarters by Antonina Kim, Chief Accountant; <mark type="ph" /> Neil Patapof (00:00:49) Head of International Accounting; Gregory Minaev, Head of Accounting Analysis; Evgeny Gribov, Head of Business Planning; <mark type="ph" /> Alexei Polkin (00:00:57), Head of Management Accounting; <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:01:00), Head of Marketing Analysis; Alexander Zubchenko, Head of Downstream Strategy; and finally Pavel Fedorov, First VP for Economics and Finance.</p>
          <p>I will now pass over to Pavel Fedorov, who will make a short overview of the Q2 results and then we'll have a Q&amp;A session. Pavel, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alexander, and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to Rosneft's call. First of all, I'd like to remind you that the recent Annual General Meeting of Shareholders approved the Board amendment to the dividend payment procedures which provide for payment of dividend at a fixed date from the resolution date. It effectively means that dividends for 2010 will be paid to the depository by August 9 or four months earlier than the last year.</p>
          <p>I would also like to draw your attention to the AGM scheduled for September 13, which is focused on the reelection of our Board of Directors. If you're a shareholder as of the end of the record date which is July 20, please do not forget to put your vote in and the list of the candidates will be made available to our website on August 24.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the financial results of the company. The full set of financial statements for second quarter 2011, MD&amp;A and press release, and investor presentation, were made available at our website last Friday. First, about our core business which is doing well ahead of plan. Rosneft continues to post leading production growth rates in the industry. Our crude oil output increased by about 3% year-on-year which is 2% ahead of plan. The key growth drivers were our largest production subsidiaries Yugansk and Vankor.</p>
          <p>Yugansk continues to show better flow rates at mature wells as well as &#x2013; which is a result of good combination of geology and efficient well interventions and well stock management. The number of new wells is in line with the plan, increased drilling speed and better macroeconomics factor allowed us to revise 2011 drilling program for Yugansk and increase the number of plants and new wells from 780 to over 820. This distribution will result in additional crude production of over 100,000 tons this year and much higher initial date of production next year. Yuganskneftegaz is expected to exceed 2011 production plans by at least 1 million tons.</p>
          <p>Vankor is now producing 315,000 barrels per day. And we successfully expanded the oil driven capacity at the fields and further increase in their production of lands for the year-end when it will start gradual launch of the central pumping station of Vankor. The current positive performance allows us to estimate annual production growth rates to be between 1.5% to 2%, which occurred in our last guidance of 1% to 1.5%. So this is our core business and doing well ahead of plan.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we'd like to make notes on the macroeconomics in quarter two which was an important driving factor to our performance. Due to the time lag effect, the extra duty increase quarter-on-quarter was higher than increase in international crude prices together with the increase in the MET rates. This resulted in the material duration of the upstream margin. Second time for May 1, we, as you know, are paying standard export duty on the crude produced at Vankor. Additional export duty payments for the quarter exceeded about $600 million and tax savings were $400 million below the quarter one level. Please do keep in mind that in a couple of days, we'll start paying mineral extraction tax on the Vankor crude, i.e. our total amounts for tax payment will be about $200 million higher at the current oil price.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, the effect from a 90% due to &#x2013; on naphtha was more than $30 million in the second quarter of this year. The refining margin trends was positive. The margin recovered material in May following the decrease in crude tax for net back and modestly growing domestic prices. But still, we're well below export net backs. We sold in third quarter, 0.4 million tons of diesel to agriculture producers at some discounts to market prices, as the price as you know was fixed in November last year. We also keep on accumulating some of the losses in the retail and small wholesale business as we try to carry through the rebalanced the domestic prices in light of the anti-monopoly regulations and current market dynamics.</p>
          <p>So, those are the main, call it external macroeconomic reasons for our financial results. If we go to downstream, I think what's most important to note there is the completion of the acquisition of 50% stake in Ruhr Oel which we finalized in the beginning of May. The acquisition had a material impact on our financial statement. We paid $1.2 billion for equity, which is now reflected in the long-term investments. This sum was split in two parts, the $600 million that were start working in quarter one and the remaining billion was paid in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we paid about $1.9 billion for the working capital. So at this time, it's equally split between the inventors in net receivables. We are now working on optimizing this working capital level, which we believe would be decreased by the quarter. The refineries are working on the tolling arrangements which allows us to consolidate the margins. A special company has been created to supply the refineries with crude oil and then distribute the products. You may see the impact on revenues of $1.8 billion on our P&amp;L as well as impact on the cost of purchase of $1 billion in our statements.</p>
          <p>In quarter two, we were supplying the mix of owned and procured crude, and we're now very quickly working on optimizing the mix of crude supply. We are paying processing fees to refineries, which are reflected in the cost of purchases and the cost of materials. And that diffuse in the refining process is reflected in the operating process. This is the main factor of their material growth quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>Finally, the results of Ruhr Oel itself as an entity reflect in the equity shares of absolute profit. The impact of Ruhr Oel on EBITDA and the bottom line was neutral in the second quarter, as we just started this business and need some more time to properly integrate it. To ease your modeling Ruhr Oel, we plan to start disclosing its <mark type="ph" /> trading (8:26) steps at our website on a monthly basis as we do with our oil production data.</p>
          <p>In May, June of this year, the German refineries processed 1.84 million tons of crude for Rosneft and produced 1.74 million tons of petroleum products. Overall, if you look at our refining volumes, they were materially up quarter-on-quarter due to the acquisition of Ruhr Oel. Domestic volumes were slightly down due to maintenance work at some of the refineries.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter, we also accelerated optimization of our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (9:01) business, which is obviously <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:09:03) given the current market dynamics in Russia. We estimated this work will result in the midterm, an increase of average sales volumes per filling station by about 12% to 20% in the next six months and reduction of working capital by at the very least $100 million. Decrease in the planned CapEx for development programs and a number of other important material improvements that we will disclose in our third quarter results.</p>
          <p>At the corporate level, we manage to keep the tight control over expenses in second quarter. The dynamics of most of the controllable items was below the inflation rate. I'd like to give some more clarity on other expenses, which increased materially in quarter one. In quarter two versus quarter one, there is a one-off accrual in quarter two of expenses on agreements with regions and charity expenses that provided for whole year of 2011, as they were just recently approved by the management board for our annual expense. CapEx number increased with plan and essentially is explained by our budgetary process and the way we are catching up on CapEx as we go through the year.</p>
          <p>$100 million of CapEx at Yugansk, which was planned to grow, is to be spent on additional drilling and will be offset by economies on other projects. We do not change our CapEx guidance for the year. So it will stay at the level of about $11 billion, $11.5 billion at FX of 30.5 and that probably will equate in our $12 billion to $12.5 billion at the current exchange rates.</p>
          <p>I will now stop and thank you for your attention. And we are ready to take the questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Pavel Kushnir of Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks for the presentation. I have two questions, not necessarily related to the results. One question, can you please elaborate on your upgrade program for Tuapse refinery? When do you expect to launch 12 million tons refining capacity and when do you want to achieve a significant 95% light product yield? And the second question is, is it correct to assume that in four or five years time, which is 2015, you'll be producing about the same amount of crude oil as you produced in 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Tuapse, I think our expectation is to launch the refinery next year as discussed. Right, I think the question whether due to a number of logistical constraints, we'll be able to launch the refinery for the full capacity next year. But the primary process will probably launch early next year with total yearly refining target of at the very least 9 million tons. So, that's Tuapse there. On crude, Evgeny Gribov, head of our panelists.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, could you please repeat the second question. We were so much concentrated on your first one. Could you please repeat the second one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it correct to assume that in 2015 you will be producing about the same volume of crude oil as you produce today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No, we will continue growing in our production. And I think that at least we will be growing at least 12% for the next at least five years. Hopefully, we will disclose the strategic targets later this year and you will see the production profile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your question comes from Andrey Gromadin of JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. I have two questions, first one about working capital adjustment related to the Ruhr Oel acquisition. Could you please repeat numbers on this year both on inventories? And second question on CapEx. In the presentation, I see that almost the same picture for CapEx breakdown between major upstream and downstream projects. Could you specify which projects &#x2013; CapEx for which projects would be reduced in comparison to budget one, as of end last year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first question in terms of the working capital for Ruhr Oel, the number was $1.9 billion. As I said, it was about equally &#x2013; say got a few million. $950 million each way, split between the inventories and the net receivables.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the CapEx let us &#x2013; could you please repeat the question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that the, Yuganskneftegaz CapEx will go up in comparison to the budget because of high drilling volume being planned. What projects, for what projects CapEx will be reduced if the target is still the same, $11 billion for the whole company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The inspection's spreadable with the whole portfolio. So it's mostly the rates. So for example, Vankor field, which are own <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:15:07).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will soon talk about the peak of the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:15:17) capital expenditure. And slowly and gradually, the capital expenditure will <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:15:21).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> You have a question from the line of Ron Smith at Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Gentlemen, good afternoon. If you wouldn't mind, could you &#x2013; again, running through numbers because you threw a lot of them at us there. On the Yugansk increased production for the year, you said there would been an extra million tons produced this year due to the higher drilling. Was that the correct number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And also you said that you had Vankor up to 315,000 barrels. Are we still expecting a sharp increase in production at Vankor at the end of the year or are we more likely to see a ramp up continuing through the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we said, in the end of the year, we plan to start gradual launch of the central pumping units. Actually, just a little bit low to start a gradual process which will continue at the end of this year until the beginning of next year as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. You're breaking up on us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we put out a slide in the presentation which shows daily production as planned for this year. So you may see there the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Mark Henderson of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks very much for the presentation, guys. Just a couple of questions from my perspective, the first is &#x2013; I mean there's obviously been fairly extraordinary macroeconomic conditions in the first half, but you've generated almost $5 billion of free cash flow in the first half. And I know some of that has gone towards paying for the Ruhr Oel acquisition. But if we continue with similar macro conditions, then we're looking at a pretty substantial free cash flow number. Do you think there's a case for paying out substantially more dividends to maybe target something closer to what international oil companies are paying out, 40 odd percent of earnings? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is I'd be very interested and I accept that you don't really want to come, but I'd be very interested on your perspective on where these tax discussions are at the moment, because there's obviously a lot of conflicting news flow coming out and I'd be interested in your understanding of where we are and what, perhaps, we should be expecting between now and the end of the year on any potential changes in the tax regime?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for the questions, very <mark type="inaudible" /> (18:19) questions. From our side, we do not have currently any plans to amend the dividend strategy. As you've probably seen in our AGM in June, we announced a change in our dividend policy, and we moved essentially from paying out a share of our net profit to a strategy of favorable dividend growth which is targeted at 20% per annum, obviously we won't be able to continue with this dividend policy forever, but from where we see it for the time being, that will be the policy of the company for a few years to come.</p>
          <p>It does -- if you look at the dividend yields, this number probably somewhat lower than of the <mark type="ph" /> international (19:14) benchmarks, but we do have a strong key through the <mark type="ph" /> lift (19:17) for higher CapEx and higher results in growth for shareholders. This is a tremendous reserve base that the company has, tremendous opportunity to build itself into something much stronger and much bigger on a global scale and that opportunity will be used directly by Board of Directors and the CEO of the company. So that's where it comes to the first question.</p>
          <p>In terms of taxes, your second point, where we are is essentially the biggest tax agenda item for the time being is this 60/66 regime. There is still lots of back and forth on this point. We understand that last month it was, in essence, verbally approved by the Ministry of Economic Development. But we also understand that there were some negative reactions coming to the latest version of the plan from Ministry of Finance as related last week. So for time being, we probably don't have much visibility of when the 60/66 regime will be introduced and when the resolution of the Russian Prime Minister will be fulfilled. That's obviously a critical a point for us given all the pressures that we have on the modernization program. And we need to invest money into this.</p>
          <p>Secondly, there is some progress on the mineral extraction tax for offshore development. We don't see this as a solution to the problem. The change in tax <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:07) offshore projects needs to be much deeper, much more substantial when compared to our proposal. We submit this proposal to the highest executive powers in Russia for consideration and we understand that there will be discussion coming on this subject in coming months.</p>
          <p>Other than this, the export duty on oil products as you know we are paying 90% on gasoline exports and we largely halted and we don't <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:40) having much gasoline exports anyway, but I would probably expect a change in diesel export duties for the next six to nine months that would only be logical to do so for state some business just one expectation we will probably have but let's see how it goes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks Pavel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My pleasure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Alexey Pavlov of Sanford C. Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, hello. I have two questions. One on Yugansk. Basically, you mentioned that you're going to drill more wells on Yugansk. My question is do you see any benefit of drilling horizontal wells or maybe you've done it already? And if yes, how do you think it can improve the recovery rates?</p>
          <p>And the second question is about actually privatization plans. I understand that Rosneft CEO met President Medvedev a couple of weeks ago to discuss the plans and this was raised in the discussion. And from the management point of view, what do you think should be done to prepare the company more for privatization? Because now, our understanding is that there is no clear deadline for privatization. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Yugansk, I will ask <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:04) answer your question and I'll just add additional comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will actually be drilling in Yuganskneftegaz mostly with simple vertical wells, which are fraced immediately after being drilled. That's the most efficient way for developing these kind of deposits, which <mark type="inaudible" /> (23:23). Regarding the horizontal, actually we have like <mark type="ph" /> 12 Horst institutes (23:28) which develop the &#x2013; development programs for different fields and we choose best development plan for every field. So regarding horizontal wells, we &#x2013; this year the plan is to test a new technique of drilling horizontal wells with long horizontal part, multi fracs and try to apply such wells at some deposits, non-conventional deposits was very low permeability. So I think we'll inform you on the results, but as of now, we're drilling mostly simple vertical wells which are the most efficient.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Apologies, we actually had a second part of the question, which relates to privatization we just want to address that as well, if possible. And I think that the answer to that is quite simple, yes there was a meeting with President Medvedev which there were some public comments made, obviously the management of the company as we discussed many times it was very hard with public and private investors to make sure that the company is ready to fulfill any resolutions and decisions of the government <mark type="ph" /> privatization (24:49) with regard to disposing their stake so that's work that's been continuously done.</p>
          <p>I think at the end of the day, the government will make a decision how to best approach the privatization process with regards to disposal and that's what the government decision, I think one obvious comment comes into mind is obviously you would want to privatize an asset like this in the conditions when -- when there is full clarity on the taxation regime because it's important because of the great degree of uncertainty in the transaction fee and the taxes for the industry. And it does relate both to, I think, onshore and offshore developments. If you can establish a tax derivative that's more <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:43) for future investments and you create a certain transparency that obviously would <mark type="ph" /> leads to a pretty major (25:51) valuation impact for the company, and now given that the government is pretty much establishing the rules and given the size across that space, I think this is where certainly, additional work could be done just to, at the very least, eliminate the uncertainty in the process. Other than this, we stand ready to fulfill the decisions of the government and the shareholder of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Alex Fak of Troika Dialog. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes, I was wondering if you could give us any update on the plans to build a 20 million ton refinery on the Pacific Coast because the latest we've heard was that it was downgraded to 10 million tons and that it might not be built at all. Can you give us the latest on that please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Alex. Thank you, I mean, obviously making a step back right, there was a variety of plans discussed, where it currently stands. Generally, it's not a question of second or third quarter of this year. We are certainly &#x2013; there is a long-term investment plan by the company and the eastern petrochemical complex as we call it is in those plans.</p>
          <p>The current consideration <mark type="indiscernible" /> (27:17) plans out is very simple, it takes a 5 million ton complex is about the first line of that. And essentially, it's the primary petrochemical complex for production of polyethylene and ethylene for exports to China, primarily China, that will be based nearby and the <mark type="ph" /> Hodka (27:47) seaport as will have its own port terminal, it will use as a feedstock production from our neighboring refineries. That's what we delivered to the complex &#x2013; we do believe that a complex like this would be very, very profitable given the tax regime and interest rate regime for the petrochem industry in Russia. It does have some fairly unique infrastructure advantages and it could be scaled up to 10 million tons and beyond that with the feedstock of crude from the <mark type="ph" /> east board (28:26) pipeline, which I think is just a few kilometers away. But certainly we're not talking about 20 million tons refinery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a follow-up question what's the CapEx estimate on that, on that 5 million ton refinery, your petrochemical complex?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I said, I mean, this is not a second or third quarter question. So as such, we are working towards pinning down numbers as well as the timing of the launch of the complex at this stage. I think in third quarter, we'll be able to shed the light on some preliminary numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Ron Smith of Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello again, gentlemen. A few questions that have popped up in the course of the Q&amp;A section, one, you were saying you're targeting some low permeability horizons, some unconventional targets with horizontal multi-frac wells, I was curious if that might not be the <mark type="ph" /> Begino shale (29:27) or if you're looking at some other like a low permeability sandstones or exactly what you're looking at?</p>
          <p>And then I'd like to return to the question, taxes in particular have you had any movements and sorry if you've already discussed this on Yurubcheno-Tokhomskoye and what the plans are there right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The two targets for these complex horizontal wells are first, our general reserves resources, we have deposits, with deposits we do develop technology <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:05) some small-sized deposits was broken at <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:10). Second target, some unconventional deposits at <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:19) field with very low permeability where drilling simple vertical wells is not efficient as it <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:22) rated non-commercial.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on Yurubchen, if you get &#x2013; the performance, I mean, that is work in progress we're working through local parties that are stakeholders in the process. <mark type="ph" /> Yurubchem (30:45) is not 100% owned by <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:48) we have <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:50) owner stake in the company. So what we're doing is, we were spending less time to think about our strategic options for this particular development taking into account geological complexity and the tax regime. I think we'll have an update for you at the end of the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You now have your last question from Mark Henderson of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just following on from some of the questions for Pavel, there was some discussion a few months ago that you guys might be considering holding a sort of medium-term strategy presentation, I'd be interested to know if that's still the case and if we might be in a position to get a little bit more color on these plans for the medium term, I mean, I'm again harkening back to this free cash flow point. If you're thinking about higher CapEx, I guess it will be interesting to indentify exactly what sort of projects and given the very deep resource base you talk about, is what you'll be targeting and what medium-term production growth might look like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, thank you for your question. I think this is a good idea. If you could allow us to think about the right forum for this, we'll try to find a way to respond &#x2013; that could take a number of shapes, right, I mean one of way would be for us, for example the host of group of investors will have somebody from our long-term visionaries just as done, just goes through you with through the package of projects that the company has in the table, not necessarily on a quarterly basis but a few years out and explain some of the projects have and how to appoint them, what they're going to enforce, why they make sense, for the overall portfolio is evolving. That might be the wrong way to do it and let us think what is the right time for this; but we'll account to this and will try to come back to you shortly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks a million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You now have a question from the line of Alexander Kirevnin of VTB Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you for the presentation. Can you please specify any details of the CapEx for the refinances second quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alexander, if possible could I come back to you separately after the call?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll send you all the details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> You do not have any further questions waiting at this time. Gentlemen, back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>If there are no further questions, thanks, everybody, and goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11">
        <plist>
          <p>Goodbye. Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude this conference for today. Thank you for participating. You may all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>