<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1367082" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>49078</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Alexander Palivoda, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Eduard Khudainatov, President</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Vadim Mitroshin</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Pavel Fedorov</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Maxim Moshkov</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Andrey Gromadin</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Peter O'Brien</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Oswald Clint</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Artem Konchin</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Lev Snykov</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Svetlana Grizan</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Evgenia Dyshlyuk</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Mark Henderson</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Oleg Maximov</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. And welcome to the Rosneft Full Year and Fourth Quarter 2010 Financial Results. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. There will be a presentation followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I must advise to all that this conference is being recorded today on Friday, the 4th of February, the year 2011. I would now like to hand the conference over to your first speaker today, Mr. Alexander Palivoda. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. And welcome to Rosneft's fourth quarter and 12-month 2010 financial results conference call. My name is Alexander Palivoda, Head of Investor Relations, and I am very pleased to announce that the Chief Executive Officer of Rosneft, Eduard Khudainatov, will lead the call today for the first time, with a strategic overview of the 2010 results and plans for 2011. Then Pavel Fedorov, First Vice President for Economics and Finance, will make a more detailed overview of the operating and financial results, followed by a 15, 20-minute Q&amp;A session with the Chief Executive Officer. And then we'll be glad to answer other questions.</p>
          <p>We are also joined in our Moscow headquarters by Antonina Kim, Chief Accountant; Artyom <mark type="inaudible" />, Deputy Chief Accountant; Neil <mark type="inaudible" />, Head of International Accounting; Alexei , Head of Management Accounting; and finally, Viktor <mark type="inaudible" />, from the Legal Department.</p>
          <p>And, I will now pass over to Eduard Khudainatov.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the conference call dedicated to the release of Rosneft's 2010 financial results. I'm pleased to be taking part in this call for the first time and hope to continue such participation in the future.</p>
          <p>I would like, straightaway, to draw your attention to the fact that Rosneft is currently developing a new strategy that will specify the main vectors of the company's future development. And I'm happy to inform you that our first strategic initiatives are already having considerable effect on Rosneft's market performance, already showing the effectiveness of the work we've undertaken over the past six months.</p>
          <p>The company reached a new stage in its development, creating a stable basis for setting new tasks and strategic goals. We plan to address the issue in more detail in the nearest future. Before the shareholders meeting we will schedule a company strategy day in Moscow and in the key international financial centers, with participation by executives in charge of main areas of operation.</p>
          <p>Now, let me proceed directly to 2010 results. In passing, I will take the advantage of the opportunity to point out that our company is the first among the world's largest oil producers to release a fully audited consolidated financial statement for 2010.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at the figures for oil production, as they are among the most popular indicators. As you know, daily production of crude oil in Russia has increased in 2010 by 218,000 barrels per day. Rosneft accounts for 140,000 barrels per day out of that amount, the highest figure among vertically integrated companies.</p>
          <p>This is the highest figure among vertically integrated companies. With planned oil production growth of 4.5%, we in fact, demonstrated growth exceeding 6%. As a result, hydrocarbons production, meaning of gas exceeding 2.5 million barrels per day, while five years ago we only produced 1.7 million barrels. So the growth amounted to nearly 50% over five years.</p>
          <p>High operating results enabled us to achieve record financial performance. Free cash flow was almost $6 billion, which allowed us to reduce net debt to the level of five years ago. This means that we managed to confidently deliver the promise given to investors years ago to reach the target ratio of net debt to EBITDA at the level of 1.0 by the end of 2010. Last year, the figure was reduced to 0.7.</p>
          <p>Our successful cost-control efforts also contributed to the record financial results. At year-end, the growth of controlled cost per barrel production was again below the rate of real appreciation of the ruble. The company has been showing such results since the IPO in 2006. Cost control remains one of our main priorities. Over the past five years a certain amount of work has been completed, but the potential for optimization has not been exhausted yet.</p>
          <p>We are going to continue working in this direction and we'll keep costs among our priorities. This also applies to capital expense, which for 2010 came in below $9 billion, compared to the originally planned level of $9 to $10 billion. To proceed, in 2010 we paid more than &#x2013; more dividends of over &#x2013; we paid dividends of over $700 million and in recent years dividends per share have grown at a steady pace, to be more precise at the rate of 20% a year.</p>
          <p>As for the plans for 2011, I would like to mention the key points we intend to focus our efforts on. First of all, we're talking about continuing to develop and expand our capacities of the Vankor project. By the end of 2011, we're looking at completing one of the main production facilities for Vankor, namely the central gathering and oil treatment unit, which will enable us to reach the total Vankor production of 25 million tonnes of crude per year. And this will enable us, at Vankor alone, to reach a production by 2012 of 18 million tonnes of oil a year. And by 2013 to reach &#x2013; the installed capacity will enable us to reach the planned figure of 25 million tonnes of oil per year.</p>
          <p>Second thing is the upgrade of our refineries. We are focused on compliance with fuel environmental standards, as well as the improvement of the oil products mix. Over the past two years we have already commissioned a number of facilities that comply with Euro 3 and 4 standards. We are going to modernize and build from scratch over 30 units. In 2011, we plan to invest more than $2 billion in this undertaking.</p>
          <p>Third is the work under agreements recently signed with our foreign partners on continental shelf. We're planning to bring in the state-of-the-art experience, practices and techniques that are in the possession of our partners, which will enable us to realize the significant resource &#x2013; the resource potential on the shelf areas that we have acquired in 2010, which will enable our company to ensure our powerful resource base, which will help significantly increase capitalization of our company in the nearest future.</p>
          <p>Fourth, further dialogue with the government on optimization of the tax regime. For us is the key point, the key point is the development of a tax regime for frontier regions, we're talking here primarily of the continental shelf and East Siberia, which will enable us to adopt new investment decisions.</p>
          <p>A basic concept of such system already exists and we only need to finalize technical details and regs. And currently we're working very closely with the Ministry of Economy of Russia and the Ministry of Finance of Russia. And as you know, the Prime Minister of Russia has also give &#x2013; gave his go-ahead and instructed the government to consider a special tax regime for companies operating on the continental shelf.</p>
          <p>And number five is the internal optimization or the further optimization of internal business. We have initiated now the projects that are designed to get rid of the non-core assets of the company. We are looking at optimizing our services to improve our business processes and improve our work with low profitability assets.</p>
          <p>And I must tell you that to help us with these projects, we have hired the best and, I can say, most expensive international advisors and consultants. But I must assure you that these costs are completely justified. And we expect significant effect will be received out of that an extra revenue and increase in the corporate value. And we're looking at finishing this undertaking in the first six months of 2011 and announce this progress to the market.</p>
          <p>Our priorities for this year also include enhancing the managerial potential of the company. We will undertake a serious work as far as changing the staff policy &#x2013; personnel policies of the company. We're talking here about increasing responsibility and distributing authority &#x2013; redistributing authority throughout the company. We're talking about top executives.</p>
          <p>We also plan to integrate the recently acquired refining assets in Germany, the deal for which we expect to close shortly. Other priorities are- our other priorities is to look for partners for a petrochemical construction project in the far east, as well as certain other projects, especially in the area of exploration upstream.</p>
          <p>Finally, I would like to thank you for your attention and your interest in the company. Thank you for the confidence that you demonstrated by investing in our company and I must assure you that we'll do our best to make sure that the company achieves the best and highest standards globally.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. If you have a few questions, I'm ready to answer them and then, I'll hand over to Pavel Fedorov and Peter O'Brien, and my other colleagues present here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from Vadim Mitroshin from Otkrytiye. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. As far as the dialogue with our government concerning the tax benefits for shelf projects, offshore projects, when we met with Mr. Putin, the Prime Minister. During this meeting we discussed various options, primarily concerning experience, experience from such countries as Brazil and Norway, where special tax regimes are used to optimize the taxes, in order to optimize the taxes and ensure profits on investments in these projects.</p>
          <p>As far as the East Siberia fields, we currently enjoy a tax benefit in the Vankor field for the first four months and by the start of April we are supposed to finalize all our work with the government in order to ensure the exact specific &#x2013; the exact, precise parameters, in order to legalize these parameters with the government and to ensure the high profitability of the Vankor project in line with other similar projects.</p>
          <p>And as far as I'm concerned, I'm pretty much confident that this will be addressed positively. As far as 66 to 6 on downstream projects, our economic model looks much better than similar companies, our peers. We analyze all the risks and our opinion is that there'll be no downside here as far as using this sort of methods in the refining.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If could add &#x2013; step in here and just comment on this in English to make sure we have it relatively well so everyone can understand. As an integral participant we have been part of this process, obviously, our very &#x2013; are watching what's happening with the taxation system. I believe that it will be a step in the right direction. I mean, question whether it will be a step too small, but very hopeful that this will be just the first step towards increased vertical efficiency that would allow us to stimulate our investments in the downstream in Russia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Maxim Moshkov from UBS. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I must say, and this is official, Rosneft is in no negotiations or talks with any TNK-BP shareholders. We are not aware of any dialogue, dialogue if any, ongoing between TNK-BP shareholders and BP. All we know is that an injunction was issued by a London court, which was referred to Stockholm arbitration, which will address the conflict between the parties as is agreed between them. And I will reiterate the fact that Rosneft is in no negotiations and as it pertain with TNK-BP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this stage, we pay no attention to that and we don't see any interest in that. And it's not on the agenda. It's not on the Rosneft agenda as of now. And I will remind you again, and I will reiterate that again, say that again, our alliance with BP has a strategic goal of going to the Arctic offshore together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Andrey Gromadin from J.P. Morgan. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We very much aware what's happening and it pleases me, the key technical solutions of the Vankor project. We've done a lot of work here and expect to get great results from optimization and &#x2013; optimization of capital &#x2013; minimization of capital investments, and we introduced several adjustments to our project &#x2013; to our designed solutions.</p>
          <p>As far as the north part of the field is concerned, the preliminary water knock-out unit <mark type="inaudible" />. We will simplify this unit and we'll spend considerably less money on it. As opposed to a deep treatment of the all of the units, the north part will play its main role knocking water and sand from oil produced, then we will be sending, pumping this oil, via a main field pipeline to the facility, which I said will be finished by the end of this year, the central treatment and processing unit.</p>
          <p>And some of the equipment that was supposed to guarantee the standard quality, commercial quality of oil, has been transferred to the central treatment unit, which enabled us to cut capital expenses by 13%. Therefore, of course, you're right we have delayed, we have postponed the commissioning of the central treatment unit by four or five months, which was supposed to be started in two phases. And to compensate for that, we will commission the whole thing altogether in one phase. And these gave a serious result effect, really &#x2013; produced a serious effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are ready to take one more last question before passing along <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Rosneft loss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All I can tell you now is they key target production level has been and still is 25 million tonnes for the Vankor field starting 2014. No change has occurred in these initial parameters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'll just add in English, if that's okay. If you take a look at the investor presentation that's on our website, and the President will surely add to this in just a minute. But in terms of guidance on volume for 2011, our current plan, based on the current tax regime and investment plan is approximately 1% on growth across the portfolio. And as you know, we will always provide you annual guidance. I think Eduard Yurevich has been kind enough, also, to provide guidance on 2012 for Vankor. But for the total company of Vankor &#x2013; for the total company in 2012, we'll come back to you, obviously, near at the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Oswald Clint from Sanford C. Bernstein. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening. Two questions, please. First one is, you talked about rationalization and potential disposal of non-core assets in your portfolio. I wonder if you could talk about which part of the portfolio they will come from and what sort of dollar amount they &#x2013; those disposals could target?</p>
          <p>Second question was on some of your discoveries in East Siberia around the Verkhnechonskoye field. Do you intend to push those into the development phase? Are they being discussed in terms of development? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can answer the question concerning the service aspect. We are currently making a full inventory of every subsidiary making part of Rosneft. First of all, we'll be looking at its economic efficiency and performance, and if we really needed to, well &#x2013; to ensure our business processes. We're talking here about large property complex and service companies, and this has to be finalized by March this year.</p>
          <p>We have a tentative estimate already of non-core assets. We're talking about, as far as non-core assets, a potential here about $1 billion <mark type="inaudible" />. But currently, our managers are doing some work and trying to ascertain whether we really need these assets. And I hope by the time we are to announce the strategy, this work will have been completed and the results announced.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. My colleagues will take over. Thank you for your confidence and trust to have invested in our company and I must assure you that we will do our best for the benefit of our company to ensure profitability and increase its capitalization. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are ready to take further questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Artem Konchin from UniCredit. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I actually wanted to get a comment on the domestic product market, historically one of the most lucrative segments. You've shown quite a nice table in the M&amp;A &#x2013; MD&amp;A disclosure on the rising excise taxes which are, I guess, the schedule is pretty aggressive. They double and tripled in three years.</p>
          <p>How do you see yourself capable of passing these on to the consumers? Obviously, the integrated companies are still under a very tight focus from the anti-trust body. Do you see &#x2013; can you measure out your ability basically to pass these taxes on to the fuel prices, retail prices? Do you see retail margins being hurt? And basically general comments like that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean, I think I'd actually look at the excises in the following way. The higher quality of product you're producing, the less excise you're having to pay and the less you have pass on to your consumer. That's what we're focused on. You can see that that's we're focused on based on the refinery upgrade program we have. As we work through that and on some of the remaining parts of our product output profile, if you will, we still have to pay some of the higher excise. We're obviously doing our best to keep the optimal netback for ourselves in light of anti-monopoly activity recently, our position in different markets being weaker and stronger depending on how close we are to refinery, how many competitors there are in the region, et cetera. So, I think all in all, if you take a two to three-year view, with our upgrade program now in progress, we're in good shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Lev Snykov from VTB Capital. Please ask your question</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. I have a question on taxes with respect to your share of the <mark type="inaudible" /> project. And the question is, how do you see the investment and production scenarios, how broad they are and what they are possibly depending on different outcomes of the tax discussion? I mean, what will be the production profile if you &#x2013; there if you have tax breaks with respect to export duty and what will it be without or maybe you could just provide some quality statements on that one? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Europe channel, I think the &#x2013; where it is currently is, we effectively decided to postpone our investment in this project, right, given uncertainty around taxes. We are working hard to get this sorted out and I think this has more of a chance of being sorted out in the part of the special targeted tax break as opposed to introduction of the broader tax system.</p>
          <p>So, I mean, we're working very closely with the government on this particular issue. But for the time being, the project is effectively on hold for a few months until we resolve that issue. In terms of the production profile, we are still in the exploration stage, working through some of the geological issues. It's a very basic estimate. Right, we have &#x2013; I mean, the peak production at <mark type="inaudible" /> have probably anywhere from called 7 to 9, potentially 10 million tonnes per year for a period of up to five years. So that's our assessment of the total production that we'll achieve there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that is &#x2013; do I get it right that 7 million is kind of the worst case if, presumably you don't have any tax breaks on it and 10 is the best case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It does depend, both the tax breaks, right? But I think what's the most important too is, it depends on further geological exploration work that still needs to be done, right? I mean, we're still in the early stage there. It's been a difficult project so far and this is one of the reasons why we're asking for the tax breaks, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Svetlana Grizan from VTB Capital. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes. Good afternoon. Thank you for the presentation. Actually my question is about modernization of your refineries. You said that in 2011, you're going to spend around $2 billion for this. Can you say about your plans for 2012 and 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lana, for the question. I mean, you know that we give annual guidance on CapEx around the end of the year. But I mean, I think we've also already made it pretty clear that across the whole portfolio of refineries, the number will come in approximately $1 billion per plant. And the number will go up in 2012 and 2013 as we're near finishing it at the end of 2013. Exactly by how much, we'll tell you later in the year. But 2012 will probably also be the most intensive year, for example, for the Tuapse expansion completion. So I'd prefer not to get into specific hundreds of millions of dollars of guidance, if you will. But I think that should be enough to allow you to model at least for the next three to four years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Evgenia Dyshlyuk from TKB Capital. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Thank you for the presentation. Just a quick follow-up question about the refineries again. I was just wondering when Tuapse refinery operate exactly and this has any priority over <mark type="inaudible" /> and then also do you have any deadlines for your Far Eastern plant project? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'll start with actually last part. In terms of the Far East Petrochemical plant we intend to contemplate partners for, the board took a decision at the end of last year to approve basically the engineering &#x2013; the financing of the engineering and final market work over the next two years, which equates to a budget of about $600 million total for this year and next year, at the end of which we hope to be in a position to make a final positive investment decision.</p>
          <p>In terms of Tuapse, we expect to be finished in full with &#x2013; including with the planned secondary processes which will result in a final light product output, Sasha, correct me if I'm wrong, but I think it's above 90%, with all the secondary processes in 2014.</p>
          <p>In terms of the other refineries, you can see actually also there's a new slide in the Investor Presentation that talks you through by refinery by year, effectively, what new units and what upgrades of existing units we plan to complete. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark Henderson from Credit Suisse. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, guys, for the presentation. Just two quick questions. First, just on the some of the detail of your upstream CapEx, looking at 2011 and the guidance that you've given, it seems that you're talking about fairly substantial increase in the number of new wells you're going to drill in 2011. I worked it at about 15%, quite a large amount of that coming at Yuganskneftegaz. But you're guiding, overall, to just 1% production growth in 2011. So I'm just wondering, is there a productivity issue in Yuganskneftegaz, the first thing.</p>
          <p>And then the second thing is &#x2013; and I'll understand if you won't be prepared to answer this, but if the Ministry of Finance were to approve the cut in the marginal rate of export duty from 65% down to 60%, as was being suggested by the Ministry of Energy's proposal, what additional opportunities might you be able to identify and work on that could lead to your brownfield production improving? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark. Yes, let's start with Yugansk. I mean, I think also you take a look at the Investor Presentation on page 9, you can actually see the amount of wells that we have planned for 2011. You're correct, Yugansk wells are going up about 10%. I think we told you last year that over the last several years, productivity as we as drill the incremental well has started to come down. That said, we did manage to deliver performance in new wells' flow rates, meaning in new wells last year about 20% higher than we planned and workovers were also more productive.</p>
          <p>I think there's a chance that frankly our planning this year has also been maybe a little bit conservative as productivity comes down and we're continuing on our tax discussion. I would add to that, that we think we have a number of years when we can continue to drill out, for example Priobskoye, but we have specifically initiated the tax discussion around Yugansk as the lowest-cost producing asset in Russia, which still in three to four years, if transportation tariffs continue to grow, electricity prices continue to grow, even if we're still producing 50 tonnes at the incremental well or let's say 40 maybe in three to four years, those wells probably won't make sense to drill unless we've had a change to taxation.</p>
          <p>Now, in terms of East Siberia, I think I actually was distracted a little bit here first when you were asking the second part of the question but you mentioned 65% to 60%. I mean clearly, bringing down the export duty to 60%, particularly if we &#x2013; on the incremental, on the marginal export duty rate above $25, as we continue to grow production, add more production volume than say incremental refining capacity, we're obviously exporting more oil, okay?</p>
          <p>So it's accretive for us, whether from West Siberia or for East Siberia. So, I think specifically on Vankor, Eduard Yurich gave pretty good guidance on what's already been discussed with the government, what we need to demonstrate by early April in order to help make the government, hopefully, make the right decision before May and I'd just leave it there for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from Maxim Moshkov from UBS. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And just to follow-up on this previous question on the potential of drilling in terms of &#x2013; in case of the taxation relaxation for the upstream, especially for Yugansk, given that the productivity in this is deteriorating. So, would you be expecting material improvement in drilling volumes &#x2013; producing drilling volumes for the field? And what are the existing costs now for the projects and <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, what can we do, right? We can drill more efficiently for well i.e. per well or specifically per amount of meters which we're doing, which, if you take a look at how CapEx is growing versus the amount that we're drilling. We're clearly getting more efficient. For example, the amount we're able to drill in one month with one rig. I think, since I joined the company five years ago, at Yugansk has doubled. And we're also going to be working harder, including with our own service company to reduce cost.</p>
          <p>But once you're producing 1.3 million barrels per day and an asset for this long, and you go through your drilling inventory, you're going to have issues like this. So, we're working at all aspects, whether it's reducing electricity consumption, reducing capital costs for drilling, rethinking about how, frankly, incremental pads are developed, what kind of electricity capacity, other infrastructures is needed. All of this analysis is being revisited again now in order to try to feel good about or going below 40 tonnes per new well, in addition to the tax discussion, which we're trying to have.</p>
          <p>And, I think there's still a lot of oil, as you all know, at Yuganskneftegaz in West Siberia, including the layers that we're producing currently, but there's also, eventually, Bijan and others. And another area that I think you'll hear a lot more about also in our strategy update is new technologies and hopefully, innovation of Rosneft or others, frankly, that we buy that enable us to increase our recovery factor even by just 1% or 2% at Yugansk &#x2013; I think you all appreciate would have a big impact. So it's a combination of all these elements, both internal and external.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Oleg Maximov from Troika Dialog. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Peter. Thank you for the presentation. Can you please comment on the company's gas strategy? How much gas are you planning to extract this year and if you can mention, what are you doing with Kharampurskoye field now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> is going to be an important part of our strategy, right. I think you're asking the right question, with <mark type="inaudible" />I've seen that with Rosneft gets the resource base in excess of that of BP or Chevron, it actually has great potential in gas. Kharampurskoye specifically the quarter strategy, I think it's more than 8% of the overall resource base that we have and from our sectoral base, thinking about the right access to &#x2013; the right access to the target markets, right. And once we believe that we have obtained that and secured it in cooperation with our partners, we can certainly proceed with the development of Kharampurskoye field and other developments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give exact timing or, at least, approximate timing and volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oleg, I would just add to Pavel's answer in light of your follow-up question. I mean, you were also at the forum that Troika hosted, obviously just a couple days ago and we heard Gazexport's comments on China and the Altai pipeline. And apparently they're planning to announce an agreement with the Chinese this summer and that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you all planning to be a part of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If that pipeline goes ahead, I think we start to get more clarity, generally, on capacity out of West Siberia and in the <mark type="inaudible" /> then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time. Please continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well we've been with you for an hour. Thank you very much for joining. Pavel, did you have anything else you wanted to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think the <mark type="inaudible" /> will be just keeping you posted right. We'll provide a few more commentaries in terms of our performance. We'll be happy, obviously, to chat with you one-on-one as needed to keep you more up-to-date on the job. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question just came through. Are you happy to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>One more just came through. Sure, we'll take one more. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We just have a follow-up question from Maxim Moshkov from UBS. Please ask your question. Maxim your line is open, please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I guess Maxim got his answer. Thank you everybody. Have a good year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude our conference call for today. For those of you who wish to access a reply of this conference, a replay can be accessed by dialing in U.K. on 08-45-245-5205 or generally on country code +44-14-5255-0000. The reservation number is 40375300. Thank you all for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>