<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1272716" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call - US Investors</title>
    <date>2009-11-19</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7790</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Gary Leibowitz, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Malcolm Wyman, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Mark Swartzberg</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the SABMiller 2010 First Half Results Conference Call. I will now turn the call over to SABMiller. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning everyone. I'm Gary Leibowitz, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations at SABMiller plc. Welcome to SABMiller's first half results conference call for our six months ended September 30, 2009.</p>
          <p>With me here today, as usual, is Malcolm Wyman, our CFO.</p>
          <p>First, the formalities. Our presentation will contain forward-looking statements. Those statements reflect the current best judgment of the management but include risks and uncertainties, and the company disclaims any obligation to update these statements outside of our normal reporting and seminar routines. Now, let's get started for today.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased to report that SABMiller has delivered a strong performance for the first half of F'10, against a background of continuing economic weakness. We've maintained broadly stable volumes in the face of very weak consumer demand and we've raised our underlying EBIT by 11%, and underlying operating margins up by over a full point, despite commodity and currency headwinds related to input costs that persisted in the first half.</p>
          <p>We've continued to benefit from the unique operational strengths of the businesses at a local level, which we've built over many years, delivering our underlying profit results through a combination of strong revenues and solid cost management.</p>
          <p>We're capitalizing on our unique strengths, local consumer insights, a leading portfolio of local power brands, as well as effective and efficient in-market execution beyond that of the peer group.</p>
          <p>Our consistent strategies continue to drive value, and in these difficult economic times, the resilience and flexibility of our business model is being proven. And we're continuing to invest in building our capabilities and leveraging our scale for the future.</p>
          <p>All in all, we believe that our medium-term growth prospects remain promising. But turning to the period at hand, it's been a busy first half.</p>
          <p>Turning first to Latin America, we saw a continuing rise in share of alcohol in Colombia and higher beer market share in Peru, our two largest markets, with further mix improvement across the region.</p>
          <p>We continue to extend and improve the management of our routes to market with direct, pre-selling, more control over third-party distributors, more outlet coverage and better specific outlet information. We've been upgrading from traditional van selling to value adding pre-selling and telesales, and our channel developers are now better able to optimize our brand and package assortment by outlet, gain access to better outlet information and shopper insights, and thereby drive better unit revenue performance. And we're achieving better worthmore brand penetration as well as both of these factors are continuing to help drive our profit margins.</p>
          <p>We're benefiting from the firm pricing we've implemented through F'09 and from the improved sales mix referred to just a minute ago.</p>
          <p>We've implemented broad-based cost reductions in general in Colombia and distribution cost improvements in Colombia and Peru, using more efficient load handling and less third-party transportation, for example. And marketing efficiency has also been improved in the region. As a result of all of these measures, underlying EBIT is up 33% from the region, and cash flow is also up strongly.</p>
          <p>Turning to the U.S., in a weak economy, affecting beer volumes and segment mix, we've done well with growth at MillerCoors, in Blue Moon, Peroni Nastro Azzurro, Miller High Life and Keystone Light and have gained market share in the premium/light segment, which is particularly feeling the economic pressure.</p>
          <p>A recent pricing round, as you probably know, took effect in most markets, nearly 80% of markets, last month, and MillerCoors has also increased focus and investment in major on and off premise chain retailers that are the growth drivers of the industry. We're seeing signs of success in MillerCoors' national chain programmes on a larger scale than in the past.</p>
          <p>Our JV synergy programme is on track to deliver $500 million in savings with phasing slightly ahead of schedule. As we've said, this is driven 60% by brewery network optimization, in other words, reducing distribution costs across the country and 40% from other overhead and personnel savings.</p>
          <p>We've seen a large financial benefit with the synergies falling to the bottom line as promised, generating pro forma MillerCoors EBIT growth of 28% over the last 12 months, and a MillerCoors margin uplift from 9.4% to the current 11.7%. And this is on gross revenue including excise as opposed to on net revenue.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, the remainder of the synergy programme comprises just over three percentage points of MillerCoors' current annual revenue, which should go to further improvement in EBIT margin. And two weeks ago, we quantified MillerCoors' continuous improvement savings, separate from and on top of the synergies at $200 million over the next three years, which is equivalent to approximately two further points of MillerCoors revenue to enhance its margin. So all in all, our profit and returns picture in the U.S. is strong as expected.</p>
          <p>Turning to Europe; Central and Eastern Europe continues to be strongly affected by the economic crisis, although some countries are proving more resilient than others. On the downside, Russia looks especially challenged as time goes on, with recent excise and other regulatory proposals that are very negative for the industry there. Generally, however, the health of our brands continues to be a driver of market share gains across Central and Eastern Europe, where we have very strong positions, with strong pricing also delivered through the period.</p>
          <p>Our restructuring activities in Czech, the Netherlands and Poland, are starting to bear fruit, and these are expected to drive an upper single-digit real reduction in total fixed costs for the full financial year and a head count reduction of 5% in these countries. You can see on the slide, however, our significant market share gains despite the cost cuts and despite the strong price increases in the lead markets of Poland, Romania and also in Hungary.</p>
          <p>Turning on the next slide to Asia; we're very pleased with the renewed growth in Chinese volume and market share, now above 20%, led by the Snow brand. Unit profitability has also risen significantly in China, driven by, among other things, synergies from previous acquisitions in the central region, for example in Anhui, Zhejiang, as you've heard at the recent seminar, across distribution, operations and brand portfolio rationalization.</p>
          <p>Snow continues to grow volumes and market share across a broadening geographic footprint with over 18% market share as a brand out of CR Snow's overall 20, Snow is now larger than the market's number two and number three brands combined, as you can see in the upper left corner of the slide.</p>
          <p>Over the last 18 months, further progress has been made in building the consumer equity of the brand, complementing the street-level execution skills of the business. CR Snow has started to focus its marketing on four distinct Snow variants, which will increase its presence in the upper mainstream and local premium segments shown on the slide. These are being sold nationally, each with a different price point, formulation and positioning.</p>
          <p>Turning to Africa; Africa remained in growth despite the global recession, while we continue to expand our footprint, for example in Ethiopia with the acquisition of the country's largest bottled water company, and in non-alcoholic beverages with the acquisition of Maheu in Zambia.</p>
          <p>We've continued to expand our beer portfolios as well in both the local premium and the more affordable price segments. This year, we are pursuing a deliberate "premium beer from here" strategy across the continent. Local premium brands with common positioning elements across countries in order to achieve marketing synergies.</p>
          <p>We're at the early stages in Africa in creating the type of very profitable local premium segment that we have built in Europe at the sweet spot of relatively high volume and high unit margin, benefiting from price premia and scale.</p>
          <p>Turning to South Africa; cost savings targets were exceeded during the period, enabling significant brand and market investment plans which are being activated, including consumer promotions for Castel across the country in 2010 in association with the World Cup. It is notable that EBITA, and EBITA margin performance was good despite the negative volume trend and despite the significant step up in marketing investment.</p>
          <p>We also announced a broad-based black economic empowerment transaction, which has been praised as a role model for future deals.</p>
          <p>Finally, one of the Group's key strategic priorities is to leverage our skills on global scale. The Group's scale has increased substantially over the past five years, as you will have followed, with compound growth for volume, revenue and EBIT of 11%, 15% and 17% respectively. The diversity of the Group has also increased and beer markets are becoming more sophisticated with emerging market consumer tastes and occasions, brand pack portfolios, routes to market and retailing all modernizing. And our supply chain has globalized considerably.</p>
          <p>In this context, we're announcing today that we are now investing to create a step change in our global IT systems, processes and information to better leverage our regional and global scale. These investments are designed to sustain our top-line growth and competitive position, enhance our supply chain efficiency and effectiveness and further reduce costs.</p>
          <p>We expect material benefits from these investments; streamlined, simplified business management with more consistent and deeper market insights; country management teams able to focus more on local commercial functions; globally integrated procurement and back-office systems to centralize and outsource routine transactions, enabling lower costs and coordinated oversight of beverage businesses; common front-office and supply chain management platforms to leverage regional scale, lower costs again, and reduce impediments from national boundaries; faster, easier sharing of information, knowledge and best practices across the Group; and easier assimilation and synergy capture from acquisitions. And Malcolm, in a moment, will talk more about the costs and benefits of this.</p>
          <p>One key development is the creation of a new global procurement company, which will, over time manage the majority of purchases across the entire SABMiller Group. Based in Switzerland, this company will capitalize on the procurement scale of the Group. The past system was based on global coordination and knowledge sharing among commodity movements. This will now move to actual centralized purchasing on behalf of the whole SABMiller Group. All key supplies will be included: barley, malt processing, hops, aluminum, glass and other items in marketing services and capital equipment, for example.</p>
          <p>We expect to be able to raise considerably the standard and professionalism of all our buying. This will result in system efficiency and make use of our scale in attracting and developing talents. It will deliver a significant proportion of the long-term cost savings from the overall suite of capability investments that Malcolm will describe in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>So all in all, it's been a strong performance for the first half of F'10 across the Group, with good progress on our strategies and continuing investment for growth.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll hand over to Malcolm to look at the financial results in more detail. Now, over to you Malcolm here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and good day to everyone. As in the past, my presentation will focus on results on an organic constant currency basis, yet the schedule reflects our underlying performance and profitability.</p>
          <p>Now the Group has delivered good U.S. dollar earnings per share of growth in the first six months, despite having a significant adverse currency impact on both the transactional and a translational basis, resulting from the weakness of our major operating currencies against a relatively strong U.S. dollar in this period when compared with the prior-year period.</p>
          <p>Adjusted earnings per share in our reporting currency of U.S. dollars, was up 6%, while strong adjusted earnings per share growth of 28% was achieved in pound sterling. The interim dividend, US$0.17 per share, which represents an increase of 6% in line with our growth in U.S. dollar earnings per share.</p>
          <p>Total volumes for the first six months were 139.6 million hectoliters were down slightly on an organic basis, assisted by marginal growth in soft drink beverages. Lager organic volumes were down almost 1% for the half year, which we consider to be, nevertheless, a resilient performance, given the economic pressures felt across our markets. Strong lager organic volume growth in China and Africa largely offsets the volume declines in other markets.</p>
          <p>Organic constant currency Group revenue grew 3.1%, supported by price increases taken across some markets in the latter part of the previous financial year. This is a strong result, given the 10% organic constant currency Group revenue growth achieved in the same period last year.</p>
          <p>While as down-trading has become more prevalent, the premiumisation trends is still evident in many of our markets. Underlying EBITA grew strongly, up 10.7% on an organic constant currency basis, reflecting the strength of our diversified portfolio of businesses. Organic EBITA at reported exchange rates was down by just over 1%, affected by the relative weakness of our major operating currencies against the U.S. dollar in the first half.</p>
          <p>The Group's EBITA margin increased 110 basis points versus the prior year on an organic constant currency basis, reflecting a return to our objective of continuing to increase our operating margin. Whilst Group revenue was up 3.1% on an organic constant currency basis, underpinned principally by firm pricing across all of our regions in the prior year, you can see the major adverse impact of almost 10% of Group revenue that the weakness of our major operating currencies against the U.S. dollar has had. However, these currencies have strengthened substantially during the first half with both the South African rand and Colombian peso, approximately 30% stronger.</p>
          <p>Revenue per hectoliter grew across all regions. In Latin America, revenue per hectoliter growth of 7% was achieved as most countries had priced strongly over the last two quarters of the prior financial year. Revenue growth was assisted by marginal mix benefits through growth in premium brands. Revenue per hectoliter in Europe grew by 6%, despite a shift from on-premise to off-premise consumption.</p>
          <p>The region has also seen consumers trading down into more affordable brands, given the difficult economic conditions.</p>
          <p>In North America, MillerCoors' revenue per hectoliter grew by 3%, driven by ongoing price increases across all beer segments. In Africa, revenue per hectoliter grew by some 11% in our subsidiary businesses as price increases were taken basically in line with inflation.</p>
          <p>Strong revenue management in China drove revenue per hectoliter up by 5% in Asia. And in South Africa, two price increases taken in both the beer and soft drink businesses during the prior year generated revenue per hectoliter growth of 9%.</p>
          <p>Our underlying performance in the first half of the year was strong, delivering EBITA growth of 10.7% on an organic constant currency basis. This double-digit EBITA growth reflects the revenue benefits I referred to earlier, lower distribution costs, optimized marketing spend and a reduction in real fixed overheads, all of which offset the increase in raw material input costs.</p>
          <p>On a reported currency basis, organic EBITA declined 1.3%, reflecting the impact of adverse currency moves of some $266 million in that period as a result of our significantly weaker operating currencies against the U.S. dollar compared to the same period in the prior year.</p>
          <p>All of our key operating currencies were weak against the dollar, Central and Eastern Europe and Latin American countries, most affected in that period.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, we delivered very strong organic EBITA growth of 33% in constant currency terms, despite a decline in volumes. Margin increased 410 basis points to 20.9%, as price increases taken in the prior year grew revenue by 7%. The benefits of restructuring initiatives undertaken in the prior year on a cost base continue to be felt in the first half.</p>
          <p>Marketing costs were also lower in the first six months of this year as we cycled high prior-year comparatives, which included new product launches and brand and pack renovations of existing brands.</p>
          <p>Lager volumes declined 1%, as depressed consumer spending, together with political and social unrest in Peru and Honduras, contracted those beer markets. However, we continue to grow our share of total alcohol in Colombia, and in Peru, we increased our beer market share.</p>
          <p>In addition, our premium portfolios across the region showed strong growth and were up 15% on the prior year, supported by robust growth in our Club Colombia and Cusque&#xF1;a brands.</p>
          <p>Soft drink volumes grew 2%, led by a good performance in Central America.</p>
          <p>Our Europe business continued to be impacted by very difficult economic conditions in many markets, as depressed consumer spending contracted beer markets, resulted in down-trading and a move from on to off-premise consumption. Our lager volumes declined 6% on an organic basis. We achieved market share gains in Poland, Romania and the U.K. and strong momentum behind our key brands.</p>
          <p>Solid pricing across most markets, primarily in the prior year, combined with lower marketing costs as a result of high prior-year marketing spend, due to the Euro 2008 Football Championships, the Beijing Olympics, delivered EBITA growth of 5% on an organic constant currency basis.</p>
          <p>Now the results of our North American segment for six months to 30 September 2009 comprise our 58% share of the results from the MillerCoors joint venture, together with 100% of Miller Brewing International. The comparative results for the prior year comprise of the results from Miller Brewing Company as a standalone subsidiary for the first quarter and then, our 58% share of the MillerCoors joint venture, 100% of the Miller Brewing International for the second quarter.</p>
          <p>On this basis, North America delivered good EBITA growth of 7%. The MillerCoors joint venture lager sales, excluding contract brewing in the first half, decreased by 1% on a pro forma basis; while sales to retailers were also down 1% on the same basis, driven by continued softness in the above premium and premium brands.</p>
          <p>Strong revenue growth and lower cost base were achieved through planned synergy savings, which helped drive a 22% increase in MillerCoors' EBITA for the six months on a pro forma basis. During the period, MillerCoors delivered synergy benefits totaling 133 million, largely reflecting logistics and marketing synergies and fixed cost savings as we continued to eliminate cost duplication within the combined MillerCoors business. A total of $211 million in synergy savings is now being realized since the start of operations on the 1st of July, 2008.</p>
          <p>As previously communicated, MillerCoors now expects to deliver incremental cost savings of another $200 million, above its original commitment of $500 million in synergies by the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>For the first time, we're reporting separately on the Africa and Asia segments of our business to reflect the underlying performance of those regions. In Africa, organic lager volumes grew 3% during the period, as our diverse geographic footprint helped to shelter us from challenges in some key markets. Strong performance from our businesses in Uganda, Zambia and Mozambique as well as our associate, Castel, offset reduced volumes in Tanzania and Botswana.</p>
          <p>Tanzania, the effects of a soft economy are compounded by extreme droughts in the northern and central regions, whilst our beer business in Botswana continued to be impacted by the 30% social levy imposed on all alcoholic beverages in November 2008.</p>
          <p>Capacity expansion projects in Uganda, Ghana and Southern Sudan have recently been completed, and new plants in Tanzania, Mozambique and Angola will be commissioned soon to support growth across these markets.</p>
          <p>Soft drink volumes grew 5% on an organic basis with good growth across the region, while other alcoholic beverages declined 5% following a period of very strong growth last year.</p>
          <p>EBITA grew 15% on an organic constant currency basis and EBITA margin improved 190 basis points, driven by robust pricing and a good performance from our associate Castel, which benefited from volume growth in Angola following the commissioning of new capacity.</p>
          <p>In Asia, lager volumes grew 9%, and organic constant currency EBITA grew 29%, reflecting a strong performance from CR Snow, our associate in China, where reported volumes grew 15% in a market that only grew 6%.</p>
          <p>CR Snow's national brand, Snow, continued to exploit its national positioning, achieving significant share gains in the key provinces of Anhui and Zhejiang.</p>
          <p>Our business in India experienced a difficult first half, with volume declining 21% as a result of regulatory issues in the key states of Andhra Pradesh and Uttar Pradesh, and excise increases in Karnataka and Rajasthan.</p>
          <p>In Australia, our joint venture business delivered strong growth in a flat market supported by good sales of Peroni Nastro Azzurro, Miller Genuine Draft, and Bluetongue.</p>
          <p>In South Africa, lager volumes declined 3% as the economy weakened and consumer spending reduced. As expected, our year-on-year market share has declined. Our mainstream volumes performed better than our premium volumes supported by strong growth in Castle Lager and Hansa Pilsener.</p>
          <p>Despite lower volumes, revenue grew 6% and EBITA grew 4% on an organic constant currency basis as we continued to benefit from price increases taken in the prior year, which more than offset higher input costs resulting from higher underlying commodity prices and adverse foreign exchange moves.</p>
          <p>In addition, sales and marketing expenditure increased substantially behind our key brands. And we also intensified investments in consumer facing group to market capability, direct distribution and improved service levels to customers. Fixed cost savings funded the majority of those additional investments.</p>
          <p>EBITA margin declined by 30 basis points in the first half as pricing benefits were weighed down by higher raw material input costs driven largely by higher commodity prices and the unfavorable foreign currency rates that I referred to earlier.</p>
          <p>Raw material input costs, which rose some 16% on a constant currency dollar per hectoliter basis last year, continued to rise in the first six months of the year, although at a slower rate as we began to benefit from some commodity price reductions.</p>
          <p>Total cost of goods sold were up mid-single digits in the first half, following an increase of 12% in the prior year. We have benefited from lower spot aluminium prices in some of our markets over the last six months, and distribution costs specifically have fallen on the back of lower international oil prices. However, high sugar prices, which were recently at a 28-year high and increased glass costs have offset these savings.</p>
          <p>Our medium-term supplier contracts and foreign currency hedge positions plus mitigating volatility in commodity prices have restricted our ability to take full advantage of lower spot commodity prices in the short term.</p>
          <p>Turning now to exceptional items, our total exceptional charges of $239 million have been taken against profit before tax in the first half of the year. Business capability programme costs of some $187 million make up the bulk of these items, and I will provide further detail on these costs and the programme's benefits as we go forward into the next few slides.</p>
          <p>Integration and restructuring costs incurred in Europe, $41 million, relate largely to the closure of Kielce brewery in Poland. This brewery closure was part of the wider restructuring initiatives undertaken by our Europe business last year, which together with restructuring in Latin America, are on track to deliver annualized pre-tax benefits of 37 million in the current financial year as announced in our financial 2009 year-end presentation.</p>
          <p>Integration costs relating to the MillerCoors joint venture of $7 million are substantially lower than the $61 million incurred last year and relate mainly to staff relocation costs. The additional four million of other exceptional charges relate to the unwinding of fair value adjustments on MillerCoors inventory.</p>
          <p>Our business capability programme, the reasons behind it and that it comprises a number of individual but interrelated programmes, which will be implemented at various times over a four-year period has been explained earlier. All regions will be involved, although the impact on each will vary depending upon their circumstances. This overall capability programme involves significant changes to our information management systems, processes and procedures, and also the use of global outsourcing providers, which will benefit our customer-facing commercial activities, our supply chain, our procurement, and also our finance, human resource and IT functions.</p>
          <p>Strong project management has been set up. Accountability for delivery of each of the individual elements of the programme is clear with overall oversight provided by the SABMiller Executive Committee. There are robust project governance structures and programme assurances provided by independent experts. There are important aspects to this programme, notably procurement, finance and aspects of HR, which involve a global design, while customer-facing and supply-chain elements are being designed region by region. Our programme management approach takes this into account with strong regional coordination providing the backbone to implement and integrate these projects.</p>
          <p>As there will be important changes to our organization design and our ways of working as a result of this programme, there has also been a strong focus on change management from the outset to ensure successful execution and delivery. The business capability programme cost is incurred principally in process design, systems builds, and implementation and reorganization costs.</p>
          <p>The majority of the additional costs over our normal IT CapEx will be in our financial 2010 and 2011 years, declining significantly in financial 2012 and 2013.</p>
          <p>Our 2010 exceptional charge of approximately $370 million will be the largest in one year with our financial '11 charged some 40% less and then in financial '12 and financial '13, these will be lower by similar percentage reductions.</p>
          <p>The programme represents a step change in our business capability and we will treat the costs, which cover design, implementation and reorganization, as exceptional items.</p>
          <p>Systems build and hardware costs, which largely replaced planned ongoing IT capital expenditure, will be capitalized as normal. Business case is attractive with steady state income statement benefits exceeding $300 million per annum.</p>
          <p>Income statement benefits will accelerate from our financial 2012 and will be fully achieved in financial 2014. The benefits are derived mainly from procurement and outsourcing savings, as well as a reduction in overheads, but there will be added benefits from quicker decision-making and efficiency improvements.</p>
          <p>We intend to accelerate and increase benefits by introducing process changes and other learnings. There will be cash flow benefits of over US$350 million from working capital, which will largely be delivered over the financial 2010 to 2012 years. As new ways of working are captured, some of those benefits has already been recognized in our half-year cash flow results.</p>
          <p>Looking further forward and not included in the benefits described above, we will see intangible gains from having better information for decision-making, simplification, and market focus for in-country operations. We will also have a stronger platform to support integration and capture synergies from any future major acquisitions.</p>
          <p>I'll now move on to our Group financial considerations. Normalized EBITA, which includes six months of dividends from the MillerCoors joint venture, is down 6% on last year, as the strong organic constant currency performance over the first half of the year is more than offset by adverse currency impacts driven by U.S. dollar strength in that first half. However, normalized EBITA margin improved by 30 basis points.</p>
          <p>Net working capital generated an inflow of $300 million in the first half of the year, following a Group-wide focus on working capital management. Despite our heightened focus on the timing of inventory purchases, higher underlying commodity prices and adverse exchange rates drove inventories up year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Receivables were well managed over the period, but debtor balances did increase in some markets following the extension of credit terms to key distributors, particularly Central and Eastern Europe, given the difficult economic conditions.</p>
          <p>In certain markets, customer credit terms were increased to provide a more competitive customer offering. However, positive working capital cash flows were generated by a disciplined approach and selectively extending payment terms in many of our major markets. The Group will maintain its focus on identifying working capital improvement and locking in the benefits when realized.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure of $739 million was $529 million lower than last year, evidencing the normalizing of the Group's capital expenditure after a period of major capacity and capability related expansions. Some 300 million of the 739 million spent on capital expenditure in the last six months relates to prior-year capacity projects, which have been completed in the current year.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow, being net cash generated after investment activities and dividends paid to minorities, improved by over US$1.1 billion versus last year period, evidencing a significant improvement in the Group's cash generation.</p>
          <p>Group's effective tax rate for the first half of 29.4% is 80 basis points lower than last year's full year rate, reflecting our ongoing focus on managing down the Group's tax charge.</p>
          <p>Our net debt position at 30 September has increased from the financial 2009 year end, largely due to the recent depreciation of currencies against the U.S. dollar, offset to some extent by lower CapEx spend and improved working capital management. However, net debt at 30 September is similar to the level at 30 September 2008.</p>
          <p>Our financial structure remains strong with gearing at 47%. We undertook a major refinancing in July 2009 when we completed a successful debut &#x20AC;1 billion bond issue with a maturity of five and a half years and a coupon 4.5%. This refinancing exercise has established our capability in accessing a new investor base and further strengthened our diversification of sources of funding in debt capital markets.</p>
          <p>Our committed headroom available to the Group has been increased to an excess of US$3 billion as at the 30 September this year. The reductions in floating interest rates have reduced our overall cost of debt and our average interest rate at 30 September has fallen to 6% from 7% at 31 March 2009. 70% of our debt is held at floating rates, and that includes inflation-linked debt to take advantage of the lower interest rates that we had expected.</p>
          <p>Now, the pie chart on the slide shows our net debt profile by currency after the impact of derivatives. As you can see, we have a well-balanced net debt currency profile, given the spreads of our businesses. As we report in U.S. dollars, we also maintain a reasonable portion of out debt in that currency.</p>
          <p>Maturity profile shows that the majority of our debt matures after two years. We currently have substantial headroom available to refinance debt falling due in the next two years in terms of existing, undrawn and committed facilities and cash resources, as well as significant in-country banking facilities.</p>
          <p>Now, the good underlying revenue growth that we achieved in the first half is expected to moderate over the remainder of the year as the business cycle's price increases across key markets in the latter part of last year.</p>
          <p>Price increases will generally be lower than those taken in the prior year as commodity cost pressures ease and inflation drops across most of our markets. Reported results are expected to benefit from favorable currency moves in the second half of the year, given that our major operating currencies weakened considerably against the U.S. dollar over the same period last year. Reduced capital expenditure and a continued focus on working capital management are expected to support the Group's cash generation over the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure for the full year is expected to amount to approximately US$1.4 billion, down by US$747 million on last year. Over the next three years, we expect a further phased reduction in capital expenditure to an annual rate approximating some $1.1 billion. Input costs are expected to be higher than last year's, but lower brewing raw material costs and fuel prices will assist in slowing the rate of increase in these costs.</p>
          <p>Finance costs for the full year will be lower than last year as a result of lower interest rates. In the second half financial costs are expected to approximate those in the first half.</p>
          <p>Finally, our effective tax rate for the full year is expected to be in line with the first half year rate of 29.4% compared to the prior year rate of 30.2%.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll hand the call back to conclude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Malcolm. So in conclusion, from our vantage point, the economic headwinds are continuing, although perhaps moderating on average. Consumer indicators such as unemployment and retail spending, which are relevant to the beer category are lagging the reported possible stabilization of GDP performances. But, of course, this varies around the world with some regions still in growth and others less buoyant.</p>
          <p>But almost across the board, our local brand portfolios are performing well. The equities that we built over time are underpinning both market share and pricing gains. And our cost management has been and will continue to be rigorous, with more cost-flexing achieved than we had anticipated.</p>
          <p>And we are past the peak in our contractually fixed commodity costs, with more favorable currency movements expected to benefit our results looking ahead. So all in all, the Group's medium term outlook remains strong and we continue to build on our strengths.</p>
          <p>And now, Malcolm and I will be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you. The first question is from Lauren Torres from HSBC. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. My first question is relating or related to macro trends, and I guess it's touching upon one of the concluding comments you made. Just trying to get a better sense, if you think current trading conditions are going to continue to be tough in the second half, but you are expecting GDP growth to pick up a bit, I was just trying to get a better sense of when do you think volume performance does catch up to these growth rates. Because it seems like with a relatively resilient category, the beer category, you would think maybe you would see some pickup in that. So I was just curious when you think about being lagging indicator, how do we think about better growth coming back to the category in light of the consumer environment picking up steam over the next several months, or I don't know if you think longer than that. But how do you think about that growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's a very good question because there are certainly some anomalies included in what is happening in the indicators, macro indicators that are coming forward. I think to put it in a nutshell, we are pretty skeptical about the sort of GDP upturn. And whilst it's obviously technically correct, I think it's more to do with industries, which are not necessarily the consumer-based industries.</p>
          <p>So you are seeing pipe filling in industrial sectors and pipe filling maybe in automotive and other areas. And that's resulting in positive GDP indicators. But there is no doubt that unemployment levels continue to rise and retail sales still look soggy. So from a consumer's perspective, I think that's where we see the lagging of the existing technical GDP indicators.</p>
          <p>Now, on that basis, we are saying that current trends in the first half probably are likely to extend into the second half and not pick up with the current GDP trends because normal GDP has a normal relationship to consumer spending in it. And we think that consumer spending will -- as a proportion of GDP, will lag this GDP indicator.</p>
          <p>So whilst we think that, and hopefully the worst is behind us, it's not going to be a very quick upturn. But having said that, we have said because we are spread among six -- around six continents, we do vary country by country. So in many of our markets, like China, for example, and Africa, and also some of our Latin American territories, we are still experiencing volume growth. So it's not a one-size-fits-all.</p>
          <p>So throughout our operations, we would still expect to see many of our markets or certainly some of our markets still perform positively in terms of volume growth; whilst in others, we would hope to see the levels of volume decline coming off and perhaps moderating slightly before perhaps moving more positively into the next financial year. But over the next six months, we see things sort of bobbing along pretty much as they are now, but looking probably slightly better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I could also ask a question on pricing. You mentioned that price rises will moderate. And I was just hoping to get your outlook on the general pricing environment. Do you believe that there will be opportunities to take pricing again in the near future? And just trying to get a sense of your decision now not to take pricing, is it more reflective of your belief that consumers are less accepting of increases because of the market environment, or is it because of the actions of your competitors, or maybe it's just also a combination of the two, plus the idea that obviously with input costs coming down, there's less of a need to take pricing. So I'm just trying to get a sense of how you think about the combination of those or how do you manage that going forward on the pricing front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think, the &#x2013; from a pricing perspective, what we're not saying is that we don't intend to take any pricing in the second half. I think what we are saying is that this is situational. We will look at it on a market-by-market case. And certainly in those markets, where we believe that excise increases will be coming through, we would look to pass those through and take price increases to offset those excise increases. Generally, we haven't put a stop on price increases. We're just trying to indicate that with inflation coming down across the globe and with commodity prices also coming off quite significantly, there will not be the same pressure for price increases to be put through at the same levels as there has been over the last 12 to 18 months.</p>
          <p>So we think that whilst the pricing environment still remains pretty robust, there won't be the needs because you will see some better input into gross margin through lower input costs as you go forward over the next 12 months. And particularly in the second half, we see that with our cost efficiencies coming through, perhaps slightly lower input costs because there we are forecasting mid-single digit increases as opposed to the high single digit that we initially saw, there won't be the same need to put through price increases at the same levels. But as I said earlier, that's not to say that we won't be looking at putting some price increases through during the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lauren, I would amplify that. The pricing environment per se remains strong. And the pricing deltas would moderate, as we've been saying for quite some time, but they're moderating off very high levels. As you know, in most of the &#x2013; in many of the regions, we've been pricing at four, six, eight, even in some cases nine or 10%; in some cases for two years in a row, 8% on top of 8%, for example. So &#x2013; and the pricing environment remains very strong, in that in the vast of majority of cases, there's been no dealing back of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps one other thing I should just add there is that as inflation has come off quite significantly in many of our markets, the increases that employees have been receiving have resulted in a positive trend in consumer disposable income, because now inflation is slightly below the levels of increases that many employees have been receiving. So there is a positive there, whereas 12 months ago, we were seeing food inflation being at a very high level, certainly much higher than salary and wage increases, which meant that that had pressure on disposable income. So in some of our markets, we're actually seeing the reverse and that there is a positive impact on disposable income as a result of very fast falling inflation levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And from a competitive standpoint, I guess, over the last &#x2013; what &#x2013; month and a half or so, do you see similar activity from some of your larger competitors on the pricing side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think just judging it over the last few months would be too short a period, but I'd say that if you probably have a look at what's being said generally around in the industry is that first of all, most of the &#x2013; of our peers as well as ourselves would be looking to try and re-establish gross margins over a period of time, trying to move back towards where we were. So we will obviously be trying to take reasonable price increases where we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Mark Swartzberg from Stifel Nicolaus. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks. Good afternoon, guys. A couple questions here. I guess, starting on a more consolidated basis, relating to your FX and commodity comments. On the FX side, Malcolm, can you be any more specific in terms of bigger than a bread box type comments? Are we talking about a five point, three point, eight point in terms of EBITDA percentage benefit from the weaker U.S. dollar to your 2H results? And then a question on the commodities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Just looking at foreign exchange, in the first half, we indicated that the negative impact of foreign exchange was about $266 million at the EBITA level. And if you just take that as a flow through to the bottom line at say a tax of 30%, that's 70% of that, which is pretty close to $160 million. So that's a fairly hefty sum that is being impacted on our earnings per share.</p>
          <p>Now, going forward into the second half, it really depends on the levels of the currencies during the period. And I'm certainly not making a forecast on exactly how much of that we would get back. But if we got a significant amount of that back, I think, you can see the sums are quite meaningful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it &#x2013; I mean, we hear some of your peers broadly define beyond beer, say if currency were to simply stay where it is today through the balance of our fiscal year, we'd see X kind of impact in terms of percentage impact to U.S. dollar denominated EBIT growth. Can you give us that kind of comment here, if the dollar were to simply stay where it is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you can see from our disclosures today, Mark, that for the first half it was swinging the other way. It was a &#x2013; there was a headwind to it, and that was worth 13 percentage points of underlying EBIT growth. So obviously, if it reversed back by around half of that extent, you'd be talking about seven points as a benchmark. But it depends, you could model the different currencies. Some of them have swung almost back to where they were as in the case of South Africa or Colombia. Some of them in Europe have not swung back quite that far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Fair enough.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we haven't done a detailed model on that. What we've done is some projections, but we've done them on conservative views. And we've run basically a scenario at half of that. And as Gary says, if you take that, you're still looking at a swing of maybe six or seven percentage points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. That's helpful. And then, if we shift over to the commodity situation getting better sequentially, can you share with us a little bit of how you're positioned for the next fiscal year? I know, if I recall, your European business had some fairly long duration commodity hedges that take you well into fiscal 2011, but if we just look at the kind of whole basket, if we &#x2013; if you will, how committed are you to fiscal 2011? And how do you think that might directionally affect that 4% number in fiscal 2011, again recognizing there's a lot we don't know. But given what you do know, can you just give us some visibility on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, again, we've tried not to make it a detailed forecast, but essentially brewing raw materials should in fact show a decline in fiscal '11, just if you take the fact that from a point of view of barley purchases, we only purchase out about 12 to 18 months because of the cycle of the agricultural product. So we will be receiving in our financial 2011, significant benefit from much lower volume prices. But on the other hand, aluminium is &#x2013; we still have some contracts running through into F'11, but they're falling off quite quickly.</p>
          <p>I think Europe is probably more hedged than most of our other areas. So they would have had slightly longer hedges. And then of course we have glass contracts, which again don't allow us to take the full benefit during this period. So on the one hand, we have a lot of benefit coming through from brewing raw materials. We have benefits coming through from distribution variables because of the lower oil price, offset to a significant extent by the packaging raw materials, and particularly when you take our glass into account and also sugar. Sugar is at recent highs, and as a bottler for Coca-Cola, and compared to some of our peers, we'll probably have more volume in soft drink side. So that's a negative. But when you take that altogether, we would expect quite an amelioration in the pressure on input costs in F'11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Great. And then digging down into a few of the regions here, China is clearly doing very well for you all. Can you give us an update specifically on pricing environment, and of course, I realize that's a big topic for a big country, but if you could just perhaps speak in some broad strokes about the northeast and some of the other key regions in China in terms of the behavior you're seeing and how you feel about the pricing environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, I think, we &#x2013; as you know, we did have a very substantial price increase going back now probably about 15 months and that has flowed through since then into our income statement. During the course of this particular six months, you'll notice where we talk about a revenue benefit of about 5% in net producer revenue per hectoliter. Most of that comes from mix benefits and particularly in geographic mix, where we are getting benefits in some of our higher revenue per hectoliter areas, where we're selling higher volumes than on a weighted average basis than we had in the comparable period last year. So the brewers are not actually taking higher prices at this particular point in time.</p>
          <p>In some of the areas, competitive pressures are still pretty high, and the northeast is one of those, so there's quite a lot of tactical discounting taking place against our list prices. In other areas, also in the northeast, where for example, Harbin is where there's a lot of pressure, competitive pressure, but in the Shenyang area, where we control and have a much larger position, we aren't able to get our full pricing without having to discount. So the actual pricing also depends on tactical discounting around China. Places like Sichuan, where we have very good revenue per hectoliter, we had better volumes because of the cycling of the problems we had there in the previous year when there were floods and earthquakes. So again, geographically, we picked up a little bit from a revenue point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean, in the northeast, our volume growth in China was in the teens. And there are three key provinces. In Jilin and Liaoning, we've gained between one and four full percentage points of market share versus the competition that you're aware of. And obviously as we said earlier &#x2013; as I think, Malcolm said earlier, we made particularly large share gains in the central region. This is around the Yangtze River Delta, Anhui, Zhejiang, and that market share was primarily taken from a combination of European-owned, Japanese-owned, and locally owned brewers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then it sounds, Malcolm or Gary, it sounds like you feel pretty good about the mix outlook for China. Is that a fair characterization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think, we're quite positive about China. And I think, we're starting to see some profits &#x2013; profitability benefits come through. We are seeing input costs fall off, probably quicker than in the other territories. And as I said, we are benefiting from mix benefits, where our Snow brand is increasing its volume in relation to some of the mainstream brands. And also we're getting benefits from the geographic mix as well.</p>
          <p>And as a result of that, we're starting to see not only revenue benefits, but also lower input costs. And one of the things that we've also talked about is that we've extended the variance in the Snow brand to cover different segments and different occasions. So, that will allow us to also price differently in this area, which is upper mainstream and local premium. So we're starting to use our Snow brand to expand across the upper mainstream and local premium segments. It allows us to price a little bit better on some of those variants, as against just having the one priced Snow brand. And all in all, we'll use that revenue management practice to try and enhance our revenue in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. That's great. If I could just wrap it up here, in North America, ask you to continue this conversation about mix as pertains to the MillerCoors business, because my numbers say that that business's profits are actually in decline, if you look at them before the benefit you're getting from synergies. And that has a lot to do I think with the mix trends being as challenging as they are generally for the industry. So could you talk a little bit about the outlook you have for mix, where of course the premium light slowdown is a problem, and how you expect to address that? What you're seeing from the competition? And, of course, in that, if Miller Lite could just get a few points of sequential improvement and volume trend, that would be a nice thing to help there. So just kind of the mix topic for MillerCoors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so that's a number of issues there you mentioned. Let me just try and cover them one by one. I think, looking at the profitability of MillerCoors JV, we don't see the underlying business actually in decline, because as you say, the mix is negative at the moment, but if you take out the benefits, you should as we see it and in our budgets we see a continued level of increase in profits. And that's notwithstanding the negative mix.</p>
          <p>Now obviously, Miller Lite is not helping that because as our premium light brands decrease and don't perform as they should do, then what is happening is that, as you say, we're getting a negative mix. To offset that we have in fact had some positive benefits from the MGD 64, which has allowed us to actually make up for some of that.</p>
          <p>So at the moment, I think, we and our competitor in North America are experiencing a negative mix as a result of pressure on consumers. And as unemployment continues to rise in America, I think that that will continue. So over the part of this particular year going into next year, we would still see pressure on mix. But having said that, what I wanted to point out was that, on top of the benefits we're getting in synergies, our calculations and certainly our budget show that we should be growing our underlying business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's right. Even if you take away the &#x2013; around 27 million odd in synergies delivered in the latest quarter from MillerCoors, underlying EBIT was still up, up low to mid-single digits. We quantified mix on the revenue per barrel line as being worth about a point. At the profit line, the increased contribution from Keystone for example is &#x2013; or High Life is offset by the really strong performance of Blue Moon as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Well, thank you, guys. Very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, Mark. Well, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And we have a follow-up question from Lauren Torres from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Just a question, general sense with respect to consolidation in the industry. I'm sure, you're not prepared or would like to talk about interest in FEMSA's beer business, but I'm just curious to get your thoughts about how you see the industry playing out, maybe just thinking about the next year ahead, with respect to further consolidation? What kind of role do you plan to take? How do you think you're positioned to engage in this type of activity again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, I mean obviously we know that FEMSA has in fact made an announcement saying that they are in discussion with various parties in connection with their beer business. But certainly I can't comment on that from an SABMiller point of view. There's nothing further I can really say about that. As far as consolidation in general is concerned, we are a &#x2013; one of the leading brewers and we do see ourselves as a consolidator.</p>
          <p>And we do look at opportunities as and when they arise to see whether strategically and financially they would fit within our matrix of what we find to be value creating for SABMiller and its shareholders. So, we would look at developed and developing market operations, and we would apply a strict criteria to those to ensure that we're getting some embedded value for the company and its shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess from a financial perspective, you feel you are in good standing right now to engage in that type of activity if it's available?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, absolutely. I mean, as you know, we did mention we have a very significant headroom, quite substantial, particularly if you take into account the profits of the company that we may purchase. And we've also said that should there be an attractive opportunity available to us, and we felt that it was going to add value to the shareholders, we would have no hesitation in taking such a proposition to our shareholders to get approval to issue equity as well as to pay debt. So, we would be able to fund major transactions in a consolidating market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you all for joining the call. We'll have a similar call after our next annual results in May. But in the meantime, our next quarterly divisional seminar, to take place in New York, will be for Latin America on January 28. And then we're pleased to be back at CAGNY in Florida on Thursday, February, the 18. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes the SABMiller 2010 first half results conference call. Thank you for participating, and you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>