<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1481048" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call - Presentation US</title>
    <date>2012-05-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7790</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President-Investor Relations">Gary Leibowitz</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Director">James Wilson</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Lauren E. Torres</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Priya Joy Ohri-Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">Mark Swartzberg</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Caroline Shan Levy</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the SABMiller Financial Year 2012 Results Conference Call. We are also inviting listeners to submit questions by the SABMiller website, during or after the prepared remarks. If questions are submitted this way, Gary Leibowitz, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations, will voice these questions during the Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call over to SABMiller. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, operator. Good morning to everyone in the U.S. Good afternoon to anyone in Europe who is with us on this call. I'm Gary Leibowitz, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations for SABMiller plc. Welcome to our results presentation for our financial year ended March 31, 2012. With me today, as usual, is Jamie Wilson, our CFO.</p>
          <p>Just to kick off, first our formalities. As usual, our presentation will contain forward-looking statements, which reflect the current best judgment of management but include risks and uncertainties. The company disclaims any obligation to update these statements outside of our normal reporting and seminar routines.</p>
          <p>So now let's get started with the presentation. The Group delivered a strong financial performance in our F2012 with adjusted EPS up 12% and underlying EBITDA up 8%. This was supported by good organic volume growth of 5%, with 3% for lager, a mid mixed market conditions, focused price increases, further premiumization and production efficiencies.</p>
          <p>We capitalized on economic growth in developing markets through initiatives to further premiumize our portfolio and enhance the affordability of selected brands. Improvements in distribution and commercial execution also helped to bolster volumes and mix. LATAM and Africa were undoubtedly the stars of the year, but Asia and particularly South Africa delivered very credible performances.</p>
          <p>We completed the acquisition of Foster's in the year, which provides us with exposure to Australia's growth prospects and profitable beer industry. You've heard us report on our extensive plans to strengthen this business at our seminar in March in a market challenged by weak consumer confidence, presently.</p>
          <p>Also in March, we completed our strategic alliance with Anadolu Efes, contributing our Russian and Ukrainian beer businesses in exchange for a 24% equity stake in their enlarged group. This offers a much enhanced position in Russia for us, creating a strong number-two player nationally in value terms with a leading position in Moscow and an increased national footprint for the combined portfolio.</p>
          <p>The combined businesses are expected to yield significant cost synergies of at least $120 million per year and provide additional revenue synergy opportunity. The transaction also extends our footprint to include a leading position in beer and soft drinks in Turkey as well as attractive exposure to beer industry growth across the CIS and Central Asia.</p>
          <p>We've also strengthened our strategic alliance with Castel in Africa and the operational management of the businesses in Angola and Nigeria in particular. We've seen further progress in our business capability program, particularly in the area of procurement.</p>
          <p>Net operating benefits again exceeded our expectations, reaching $159 million for the year in F2012 and we're raising our sights on the likely total benefits of the program by F2014, more from Jamie on this in a moment.</p>
          <p>Turning to our divisions, in LATAM, we delivered an excellent performance with robust volume growth in both lager and soft drinks, as you can see here. We've extended the brand and pack ranges in our portfolios, nurturing premiumization, expanding beer's presence into more occasions, and improving the affordability of certain key brands; all strategic initiatives you've heard us talk about a number of times in the past year.</p>
          <p>Our successful premium extensions Club Colombia, Negra and Roja are shown here on the slide. These have reinvigorated the Club Colombia brand franchise and the broader premium segment with craft beers to further build the category.</p>
          <p>Our larger mainstream bottle is also shown here, a 750ml bottle, promoting a sharing culture and addressing on-premise affordability in the entr&#xE9;es as well as home consumption opportunities through the off-trade channel.</p>
          <p>Revenue increased 10%, driven by these volumes as well as selective price increases and favorable mix development within our portfolio. Higher commodity costs were mitigated by efficiencies, while increased brand investment was funded by ongoing fixed cost productivity. As a result, EBITA growth was very strong at 14%, and margins continue to rise, up 70 basis points on an organic basis.</p>
          <p>Turning to the U.S., MillerCoors continued to achieve strong revenue and cost management, offsetting volume reduction to grow profit and margins. Premium lights continued to be pressured by economic weakness among key beer drinkers and by more challenging segment price gaps versus key import brands, which have become more mainstream in both their price and their positioning.</p>
          <p>Premium lights recovery remains important to sustainable cash flow growth in the industry and remains a sharp focus for MillerCoors. There was improvement in the last quarter with Coors Light in growth, and we're optimistic about improvement in Miller Lite following the launch last month of new Miller Time advertising and brand positioning and new can packages.</p>
          <p>MillerCoors investment in retail execution capability continues to increase its share category captainships, particularly in chain, from 24% to 35% of key account volumes over the last three years.</p>
          <p>The craft and import portfolio of Tenth and Blake continues its double-digit growth, driven by <mark type="ph" /> Leinenkugel (5:35), particularly the very successful Summer Shandy seasonal as well as Blue Moon.</p>
          <p>Peroni grew in the high single-digits, primarily in the on-premise, and MillerCoors has deliberately built a very full innovation pipeline for F2013, the year starting now, with new packaging for key brands, the acquisition of Crispin Cider, St. Stefanus from Europe, more craft seasonals, Third Shift, Batch 19, Redd's, Coco Breve and more; it's a very full portfolio.</p>
          <p>Turning to Europe, while there were tentative signs of a slow economic recovery earlier in the year, we're now faced with increased economic uncertainty. Pressure on beer industry segment mix and profitability continues. Competitors' orientation towards the off-trade and the economy segment has continued, coupling with subdued consumer sentiment resulting in lower average pricing and industry margins.</p>
          <p>In this environment, we've chosen to adjust our price point selectively, but we're primarily focused on brand building, premiumisation and innovation to broaden and increase the perceived value of the category to consumers. Current innovations in the Czech Republic, for example, included a premium wheat beer, Phoenix, Gambrinus Radler variants, and new Frisco variants.</p>
          <p>We've built high value positions in some of our smaller markets where we've achieved significant profit growth this year, notwithstanding the economic downturn and uncertainty, and our own supply side initiatives, such as regional manufacturing and in-country productivity improvements are continuing to deliver cost savings.</p>
          <p>In South Africa, our sustained brand investment, improved retail execution and leading customer service has driven a return to growth in the beer category. Our lager volumes were up 2%, with our market share now close to 90%.</p>
          <p>We've made significant share gains in the premium segment. Notable performances were from Castle Lite, the fastest growing and most popular brand in South Africa, and Castle Milk Stout, which was repositioned during the year, gaining share and at a higher increased premium price at the same time.</p>
          <p>Revenue and cost management delivered strong EBITA and margin growth and enabled further increased investment in consumer-facing activities; the virtuous circle you heard us discuss at our seminar. Soft drink volumes were also up by 2% in the year. Our productivity gains, supply chain and packing improvements more than offset the effective increasing commodity costs.</p>
          <p>In the rest of Africa, we've delivered now eight consecutive quarters of double-digit volume growth. This has been driven by many countries across the portfolio, including Tanzania, Uganda, Zambia, and our associate Castel.</p>
          <p>Portfolio enhancements, extended price ladders up and down, wider distribution, and increased in-trade investment is allowing us to reach many more consumers. The Castle portfolio is leading original premium growth as it successfully appeals to the growing middle-class in Africa. Castle Lite is now in nine of our markets.</p>
          <p>In the more affordable segment, we very successfully launched Impala lager in Mozambique, the world's first clear beer made from local cassava. This is complimenting our other sorghum-based products that you've heard about before.</p>
          <p>Margin growth has been softened by our stepped up investment in future growth as we work to alleviate capacity constraints in a number of markets.</p>
          <p>Our brewery operations in China continue to do well and have once again increased market share, although organic growth was impacted by heavy and prolonged rain that affected some of CR Snow's key provinces, particularly in the last quarter.</p>
          <p>CR Snow's 82 breweries surpassed an impressive milestone during the year and sold over 100 million hectoliters in the year for the first time, while maintaining its market share lead versus the key competition.</p>
          <p>Notably, revenue per hectoliter in China increased by 13%, reflecting upper single-digit price increases in the prior year, positive mix and currency effects. This helped to mitigate rising cost of raw materials, higher labor costs, and consumption taxes and some of which dropped to the bottom line and margins grew.</p>
          <p>India had a year of good profit growth as well. We've adopted a disciplined approach to targeting profitable growth opportunities by our brand and pack innovation and commercial capabilities.</p>
          <p>And in Australia CUB, pro forma lager volumes were 4% below the prior year, mainly reflecting continued subdued consumer sentiment. However, revenue per hectoliter benefited from a general price increase and a deliberate return to a value growth focus following a recent period of lower price realization.</p>
          <p>Yeah, I'm now going to hand over to Jamie to take you through a financial review of our results. Jamie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and good day to everyone. The Group has delivered strong adjusted earnings per share growth in all of our major currencies in the year. Adjusted earnings per share in our reporting currency of U.S. dollars, was up 12%. The final dividend, therefore, is US$0.695 per share, which brings the annual dividend to US$0.91 per share, an increase of 12% over the prior year.</p>
          <p>Organic revenue growth of 7.5% was driven almost equally by volume, price, and mix benefits, reflecting firm pricing in South Africa, North America, Africa and Asia-Pacific, together with strong developing markets volume growth.</p>
          <p>Our local premium brands continue to perform well and have improved our sales mix in the year. The favorable currency benefits in the first half of the year reversed over the second half following a weakening of the South African rand against the U.S. dollar. As a result, the full year reported Group revenue was not significantly impacted by currency moves.</p>
          <p>Group revenue per hectoliter grew 4% on an organic constant currency basis, and all regions achieved revenue per hectoliter growth over the full year. Whilst we continue a strategy of price restraint in a number of our markets, Latin America benefited from selective price increases and continued growth of the premium segment.</p>
          <p>While in Europe, the improvement in the revenue per hectoliter was achieved through selective price increases, despite adverse sales mix, and pressure on pricing in Poland and Romania in particular. In North America, MillerCoors benefited from a firm second half pricing and favorable brand mix, including double-digit growth of the Tenth &amp; Blake division.</p>
          <p>Africa grew Group revenue per hectoliter to 5% overall with pricing and mix benefits. Asia-Pacific saw a significant organic increase in Group revenue per hectoliter versus the prior year across the region due to price increases implemented late in the previous financial year and positive brand mix. And South Africa, benefited from the strength of local premium brands, in particular Castle Lite, together with price increases.</p>
          <p>We delivered EBITA growth of 8% in organic constant currency basis largely aided by the volume and revenue benefits previously mentioned. Cost of goods sold was in low single digits due to higher brewing and fuel costs. Marketing investments continue to increase to support the development of our brand portfolio but with the rate of marketing investment as a percentage of revenue overall in line with the prior year.</p>
          <p>In real terms, fixed cost on a constant currency per hectoliter basis were in line with the prior year, despite increased local brewing and distribution footprints in Africa and foreign investments from sales, marketing, systems capabilities across our operations and in the corporate center.</p>
          <p>On a reported basis, EBITA grew by 12%. Foster's contributed to the reported results in the last quarter, and the currency translation benefit seen in the first six months largely reversed in the second half as the weakening of the South African and African currencies predominantly offset strengthening in other regions.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, volume growth and favorable mix, together with improved manufacturing efficiencies, distribution advancements, and ongoing fixed cost productivity led EBITA margin improvement, despite rising commodity costs. EBITA margin in North America benefited from pricing and favorable brand mix, together with successful completion of the synergy and cost saving programs.</p>
          <p>Africa's strong volume growth translated into healthy EBITA growth, but margin was flat due to ramping up of our capacity in several markets, expansion of sales and marketing capability in support of medium-term growth, inflation, and weaker local currencies. Although input costs, wages, and indirect taxes continue to rise significantly, Asia-Pacific EBITA margin improved, thanks to robust pricing and positive mix in China and India.</p>
          <p>South African beverages benefited from pricing and positive mix with the impact of rising raw material costs offset by supply chain productivity. Fixed cost efficiencies were reinvested in sales and marketing. Reduced margins in Europe were due to lower volumes, increased raw material costs, and adverse sales mix, particularly in Poland and Romania.</p>
          <p>Cost efficiency was helped by regional manufacturing and global procurement and most other countries in Europe held or improved margins. On an organic basis, margins overall were flat with Europe's decline offset by broad-based improvement elsewhere. As anticipated, full-year constant currency input costs and cost of sales per hectoliter increased on last year in low single digits. Costs rose across most of the regions driven by higher brewing material costs, including malt, barley and sugar and increased energy prices, which impacted packaging material and distribution. These increases have been partially offset by savings achieved through our global procurement program.</p>
          <p>As noted previously, our global procurement initiative, Trinity, has made significant progress in the area of brewing raw materials, and parcel packaging. Overall 60% of raw materials and packaging of our subsidiaries was being managed by Trinity by the end of the year and this share is continuing to rise. We see further opportunities from leveraging expertise and spreading existing best practice in these categories, not just by reducing costs but also by securing stable long-term supply and advancing our sustainability objectives through strategic approaches, for example, developing local programs in Africa and India.</p>
          <p>We have already extended into other categories, including some IT and freight procurement, started to cover marketing materials and realized savings in procurement of fridges. We see significant further opportunities in these adjacent categories. In the year to March 2012, Trinity delivered net operating benefits of $100 million before costs.</p>
          <p>Our global ERP implementation continues. After the first deployment in South Africa and the corporate centre of the back office component, we have now added middle and front office capabilities and deployed this in Ecuador. This is complementary to the front office system developments carried out in Peru and Colombia earlier in the program to support stronger extended distribution models.</p>
          <p>We have developed a full template product to accommodate relevant go-to-market scenarios and will deploy this first in Poland next year; a large business and quite sophisticated trade environment. We continue to make good progress with shared services. We have centralized our treasury operations for European countries and are extending the model to Africa. This has resulted in both financial and operational benefits.</p>
          <p>We're also optimizing shared service to operations of finance. Without mentioning all the programs which are helping to leverage scale and propel SABMiller towards a truly global organization, I would like to mention the centralization of the European manufacturing organization, which continues to result in significant efficiencies and financial benefits. We're considering how to apply the learning from this success in other regions.</p>
          <p>The business capability program exceptional cost of $235 million reflects some acceleration of the spend into the year, as we have pushed development with the global template to complete models for different go-to-market scenarios.</p>
          <p>Spend will be about &#x2013; roughly $140 million in the year to March 2013, and the program will be complete in the year to March 2014, as previously advised, with spend further reducing in that year.</p>
          <p>As we have seen, net operating benefits reached $159 million this year, well above the previous guidance of $100 million. Based on the success we have seen to date, and the plans now in place for global procurement in particular, we believe it's appropriate to raise guidance for the remainder of the program.</p>
          <p>We expect to deliver approximately $90 million of incremental operating benefits in the year to March 2013, and a further $150 million in the year to March 2014. This will take us up to cumulative net operating benefits of $400 million in that year compared to $300 million previously advised.</p>
          <p>And the run rate of approximately $450 million by the end of that year, March 2014, as we exit the program. These figures exclude $75 million of procurement benefits built into Foster's synergy targets, which will be delivered largely through Trinity.</p>
          <p>Beyond the formal end of the program, we expect the financial and operational and strategic capabilities that will have delivered to continue to build over time as they become business as usual. Adjusted EBITDA, comprising EBITDA before cash flows from exceptional items together with dividends received from MillerCoors increased 10% on the prior year as a result of increased operational profit and higher dividends from MillerCoors.</p>
          <p>We have generated further working capital inflows over the year, building on the significant improvements in working capital achieved over the last two years, largely through better management of payables and renegotiation of terms with suppliers. Capital expenditure was $324 million higher than last year, following continued investment to support growth in Africa, where we have experienced capacity constraints and in Latin America.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow continued to improve, up $560 million versus the prior year, primarily due to higher EBITDA, partially offset by capital expenditure increases. Adjusted net finance costs increased 5% to $542 million following the increase in borrowings related to the Foster's transaction. The group's effective tax rate of 27.5% was 70 basis points lower than the prior year, reflecting a number of small opportunities realized through the year together with some beneficial effects of the Foster's transaction.</p>
          <p>Our net debt position has increased due to the acquisition of Foster's, in part mitigated by the continuing strong free cash flows generated by the group. As a result, gearing has increased to 68.7%, and net debt to adjusted EBITDA to 2.9 times. We intend that the net debt to adjusted EBITDA will be returning to its target range of 2 to 3.5 times within the next two years, in line with our stated financial policy.</p>
          <p>Following the acquisition of Foster's, both Standard &amp; Poor's and Moody's reaffirmed our credit rating and the outlook at BBB+, Baa1 respectively with a stable outlook. The weighted average interest rate on gross debt as of the 31st of March was 4.9%, down from 5.9% as of March 2011. This was primarily driven by the cost of effective financing package put in place to fund the Foster's acquisition, including our $7 billion U.S. bond issue in January, which was issued at an average coupon of just under 3.4%. The majority of our debt continues to be held in floating rates benefiting from low market rates.</p>
          <p>Moving to our financial outlook, we expect continued growth in most of our developing markets with modest improvements in some of our more mature economies. Clearly, there is current uncertainty in Europe given the developments in the eurozone which we will continue to monitor closely. Opportunities for selective price increases and favorable mix benefits are anticipated across most regions as we continue to develop and differentiate our brand portfolios.</p>
          <p>Raw material costs are expected to increase mid-single-digits on a per hectoliter basis mainly driven by increases across a number of brewing raw materials. Capital expenditure for the full year is anticipated to amount to approximately $1.6 billion, with new breweries currently being construction in Nigeria, Uganda and Zambia. And finally, we see potential to keep our effective tax rate near the level achieved in the year to March 2012, in part reflecting the impact of the Foster's transaction. However, we recognize the potential for a little more volatility looking forward. The ETR is expected to fall within the range of 27% to 29% for the next year and in the medium-term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Jamie. So, to conclude, the mixed trading conditions experienced in the first half continued through the remainder of the year. Developing market consumption continued to be buoyant. While there were signs of immediate economic recovery in the U.S., volatility has continued in Europe. Overall, our operating results are strong and resilient against this backdrop. Our organic growth strategies remain consistent, developing the beer category and our leading positions on the basis of local insights and portfolios.</p>
          <p>CUB represents another exciting growth opportunity to deploy these capabilities, and Efes provides an excellent extension to our global footprint. Our underlying financial position as well as our medium-term outlook for growth and volume revenue and profitability remains strong.</p>
          <p>And with that, operator, Jamie and I will be glad to take some questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Lauren Torres from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. You addressed this &#x2013; a question this morning on your earlier call, but I was hoping you could talk a bit more about your confidence in improving margins this year. As we look at results last year and knowing that input costs are higher year-over-year for fiscal 2013 and knowing that Europe is challenging and potentially could get more challenging, I was hopeful that you could talk about where the benefits are coming from, how do you manage this potentially as some of these developed markets get tougher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well, let me see if I can help a little on that. I think the answer is the developed markets are continuing to grow. We see them continuing to grow into the incoming year. So I think in terms of relative situation, relative to Europe, they're in a much better position. And I don't think therefore we'd see them as necessarily being challenged. But certainly there is a scope to grow. I think within that we also said that we had or we believe we have pricing power in all of those regions. I mean, yes, we run an affordability strategy, but we also run a premiumisation strategy where we are seeking to trade people up into premium brands as well as ensure that we've got offerings that meet consumer demands at all value points.</p>
          <p>So I think if I look at that background then we would believe that we would be able to increase margins in those areas as a combination of pricing opportunities on certain brands, mix benefits, but also our ability to control other fixed costs within those areas. And I think what we were saying this morning was as a group as a whole, by the time you take all of the regions together, we would expect to be flat or positive. I think the best guess would be that we'd be a small amount positive in margins for next year and that's where we would be targeting. And it will be a blend of the markets where we're growing margin a little bit more strongly with those where perhaps the margins are more static.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you also address the issue of capacity, too, as far as spending levels? You know what should we expect this year versus last? And if that's going to be any constraint on margins knowing that you may need to spend more in some of these markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean, well, within the capital numbers that we put out in the presentation, and I talked about a short while ago, we said that capital expenditure this year was up on last year, but we would expect the same amount to flow through into the incoming year.</p>
          <p>We have announced a number of brewery expansions, particularly in Africa, which is where the capacity constraints have been most felt, although we've also had some capacity expansion in Latin America and in Peru in particular. I mean the issue with something like Africa is that you &#x2013; you can become the victim of your success.</p>
          <p>We've been growing very rapidly there and obviously it takes time to build capacity. So if the rate of growth is quite high, then sometimes you get stages where you're capacity constrained. Those expansions are currently underway. We're rebuilding Ndola brewery in Zambia, we're building a new brewery in Uganda. We're putting on some additional capacity in Tanzania. We're building a brewery in Nigeria. And we've already completed one in Southern Sudan.</p>
          <p>So from that perspective, these expansions are either just being complete or come on stream towards the latter half of the first half, and in most cases, well in advance of the summer peak season. So we will have some capacity constraint over the next few months, and then we would see that easing thereafter.</p>
          <p>The issue that that causes and you've seen from the results today is that while we have that capacity constraint, we have a slight restraint on margin. It didn't push Africa into negative margins, but for the year it was more flat because we are having to move beer slightly further than we'd like and that incurs transport costs. Also, being at close boundaries; that occasionally can then incur tariffs. But obviously, once the capacity comes on, those elements fall away.</p>
          <p>However, you bring on capacity, which is not fully utilized. So the early stages of bringing on capacity, you get slight inefficiency on your fixed costs, and then as you start filling out that capacity with the growth that we have in Africa, then you'll find that those fall away and then margins will start advancing again.</p>
          <p>So I think it's a short-term issue in Africa, but it's not one that we should be concerned about. I mean the good news is that our brands are becoming very appealing to customers and we're able to grow our volumes, and hence actually generate more absolute revenue. And certainly, if you look at the last year, we grew that revenue very strongly without actually any drop in margins. In the incoming year, we will expect to be able to continue to grow revenue and hopefully actually increase margins by &#x2013; to a marginal extent towards the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and Lauren, meanwhile, as Jamie said, Latin America is growing margins. MillerCoors' growing margins. Asia is growing them. South Africa certainly would be, if anything more strongly, if it weren't for the weakening of the rand, which is the question mark on the impact. So all that's set against the &#x2013; the negative movement on Europe at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's help &#x2013; that helps. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Priya Ohri-Gupta from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Thank you. Jamie, I just wanted to follow up on some commentary that you had in the earlier presentation this morning around the proportion of U.S. dollar-denominated debt decreasing over the couple of coming years as you repay borrowings and further re-denominate them into &#x2013; re-denominate maturities into your other operating currencies. Is it fair to assume then that we won't see you back in the U.S. debt market over the next two years, or is that something that you continue to evaluate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think you can assume that we may welcome back at the U.S. debt market because we will cycle some of our existing debt, and we may choose to refinance that in the U.S. debt market. I think what we're signaling there is that we will continue to look at repaying the facility we took out to buy Foster's, not the bonds with the remaining facilities, which were termed out for a 3 and 5-year term. So as we get to the back end of the two years, we'll be repaying some of that term loan.</p>
          <p>We also have some small maturing U.S. dollar-denominated debt in that period and there will also be some actually Australian dollar debt that comes into that period which was actually acquired by way of Foster's. But what you will see is that, for example, as we see other bonds maturing or lager amounts coming to fruition, then we may welcome back at the U.S. market to actually participate in that bond market. All we're flagging up is that the profile is skewed more towards U.S. dollars than it normally would be not because so much of the bonds but because of the remaining amount of term loan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from Mark Swartzberg from Stifel, Nicolaus. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hey, Gary. Hi, Jamie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was wondering, Jamie, if you could speak a little bit to what's going on underneath the hood or might go on underneath the hood regarding incentive compensation and other &#x2013; other aspects of how you're managing the business and might manage the business differently now that there's been some leadership changes in an effort to achieve the same objectives, but perhaps even be more effective over a period of years getting to those objectives. Incentives and other things that might allow you to even outperform what you've been doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I can talk loosely about that. I mean fundamentally the management change, which you are referring to was obviously last year, and myself replacing Malcolm and now Alan coming in in the Chief Operating Officer role for a 12-month period to then take on the Chief Executive role next year, has clearly been a well forecast change at the top of SAB and has been planned for some time. Alan is a long serving member of SAB, initially being trained in the beer division in South Africa and then passing through ABI and then into Europe.</p>
          <p>So I think you would not expect to see any real change in the way that we manage the business. We believe it is the one that does drive the maximum delivery from our individual business units. It relies fundamentally on the fact that we place a lot of emphasis on the &#x2013; and our country managing directors really owning the numbers and standing up and delivering the numbers that they have promised, while the central functions tend to try and support them with either leveraging of scale or indeed that the center driving the strategies.</p>
          <p>So I think, you know, that &#x2013; that has worked very well for us in the past. And I hope you would agree with that and we will continue to believe that would work well for us in the future. From that perspective, therefore, for our incentive packages that we have are actually designed to support that process. And therefore, there's no real need to change those. I mean, we do benchmark our compensation packages from time-to-time, but fundamentally we believe that they are designed to incentivize the behavior that drives the optimum results for the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. And if I could follow, just remind me if you could, EVA is &#x2013; I believe it's in your incentives and other corporate level incentive package, is that right? And then if you go down to the region managers, do they also have EVA in their incentive comp structure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, fundamentally what we're looking at in terms of our incentive packages is really to look at outperformance of our peer group. We do believe in total shareholder returns, so you can call it EVA if you want to, but in fact we're saying we want to deliver a certain growth rate in total shareholder return and ensure that that is benchmarked at the top end of peer group comparison. And so that is how we incentivize the central team. As we go down through then, we obviously bring in different levers as we try to make sure that the different component parts of the business deliver that result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Great. Thanks, Jamie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question comes from Caroline Levy from CLSA. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning or good afternoon there, sorry. Hi, Gary and Jamie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple of &#x2013; yeah, hi, there. You talked about on this balanced strategy of affordability, but also trade-up, and see how well your craft business and premium business is doing in North America. And I also actually saw your Head of Marketing for CoorsMiller (sic) [MillerCoors] (36:33) speak, and there's some really good advertising coming particularly on Coors. But do you think you need to adjust prices? Do you think you took too much on certain packages or in certain markets? How are you thinking about that versus where the consumer sits on the mainstream beers in North America?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think we do feel that in North America. I think we feel that we've taken an appropriate level of pricing and I think that's been reflected by the other premium players in premium light category.</p>
          <p>I mean, certainly the &#x2013; we have seen some closing of the gap between premium light and the &#x2013; some of the import brands, but I don't think today we've been concerned about that. We try and make sure that we price appropriately for &#x2013; to ensure we deliver value to consumers at each part of our portfolio, whether that's below premiums, premium lights or indeed the craft space. And that's the same strategy we apply in most countries around the world.</p>
          <p>We talked about affordability strategy, but it's really saying, is the consumer &#x2013; the package that we're offering a consumer actually representing really good value for money. And that's the fundamental prospect or underlying principle behind which we price.</p>
          <p>So I don't think we felt we've taken too much pricing in North America. We feel that it's been appropriate. It's been measured. It looks at the input costs and looks at what we are trying to recover. And by and large we don't think that's a driver of volume at the prices that we've been setting it at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Also wondering, on the innovation front, what the news is that you can talk about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In North America or elsewhere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>North America in particular and Asia would be very interesting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, North America, I suppose the one I find interesting is the Punch Top Can which &#x2013; for Miller Lite, which I'm sure you may have seen in the marketplace now, which allows you to get a nice smooth pour out of the can. I think these things are quite healthy too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You've got things like that. You've also seen us continue to innovate and to some extent in seasonals, in the Tenth and Blake portfolio, or indeed bring back seasonals like Summer Shandy for Leinenkugel's, which was there last year and proved to be very successful and has been brought back for the summer season again. And, you've also seen &#x2013; I was just looking at other brands within that portfolio and seeing what the opportunities for them are. So I think it's constantly looking at either package innovation, as in the can line extension, as in the seasonals, or indeed looking to see if there's anything else that we should be doing in that space that you will have seen Tenth &amp; Blake now handling St. Stefanus, which is our Belgian Abbey beer that we have in Europe, which has now bring &#x2013; come through into America and you'll see them starting handling that brand. So, I think it is definitely seeking to look at what the opportunities are.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of China that's different. What you see in China has been a gradual increase in the areas, which we service with our Snow brand. We tend to buy up breweries in different areas, and then we actually introduce the Snow brand. But, within the Snow brand, there are a number of different variants that start off in mainstream and go into premium. So what you see there is more taking that portfolio of brands at different price points and then rolling them into different regions where they've not been so well represented. And so, particularly in China that is where the innovation, if you will call it that, lies.</p>
          <p>However, if you track into somewhere like Vietnam, you will have seen that we've launched the Gambrinus brand which is new to that market, albeit has the Czech heritage and &#x2013; from our business in Czech. But there isn't &#x2013; there appears to be an affinity in Vietnam with Czech beer because they believe it signals high quality. So we have introduced that brand during the last financial year and we really expect to continue to try and drive that there.</p>
          <p>And, then within Asia, I suppose if you drop down to Australia you've seen the Australian business being very innovative in looking at things like its Northern Brewing Company &#x2013; Great Northern Brewing Company where it's got a number of local regional brands in there and also through the Matilda Bay a number of small craft brands in Australia. So I could go on and talk about other regions but it is something that we believe is an important part of our mix debate because by and large you tend to innovate more towards the top end of your portfolio rather than the lower end and so it does help us actually keep the balance of mix and hence the revenue per hectoliter in positive territory and growing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So, Jamie, if I may though, there's &#x2013; Anheuser-Busch was also speaking, the Chief Marketing Officer, on this panel and there's a lot of innovation coming in terms of new products &#x2013; or line extensions is a better way. Are you planning any of that or do you think a brand like Coors Light, you get more bang for the buck by simply advertising it more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think Anheuser-Busch have gone into different variants and we've seen obviously the introduction of Bud Light Platinum and brands like that. We are very comfortable with our Coors and Miller Light positions. We think that there is a lot to do there in packaging as well as in anything else. But we've been playing much more in the above premium space &#x2013; above premium light space and feel that's where a lot of the growth can come from. And we've tried our best to be quite innovative in that area. I do believe Anheuser-Busch play in that space as well. But we feel that we are well set up, whether it's through the brands I talked about or the &#x2013; our acquisition of Crispin Cider or our Batch 19 brand or looking at the Terrapin brand that we acquired, I think I would say that, if we're going into the summer, we're going into the summer with a huge amount of innovation. We've got new marketing campaigns, which you alluded to, but also a huge amount of innovation coming into the market at the same time. So I don't believe in any way we're feeling any lack of product variance for us to work with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Caroline, if you look at slide 7 that I went through, you'll see illustrated there really a very broad portfolio of innovation coming out, whether it's from extensions of seasonals within the existing portfolio of new brands that Jamie was just talking about, new categories in cider, Redd's, etcetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you so much. I have a last question; I don't know if you can comment on any unusual things that have happened in April or May weather-wise, either in China or anywhere else in the world, anything we should watch out for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not particularly. The biggest thing that affects year-on-year, look, in April is where Easter lands because in a number of markets Easter is quite an important factor. So, this year Easter was very early in the month. So, perhaps that means that April is not as &#x2013; wouldn't have that benefit this year, it would have had it last year. But that's not &#x2013; that moves about year-on-year so we're not really too worried about that. I think April weather was not &#x2013; in some areas of the world, it was not great. But, it's been picking up in May again so &#x2013; and at the moment we're comfortable with current trading.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Caroline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This does conclude the SABMiller Financial Year 2012 Results Conference Call. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>