<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1396442" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call - UK Investor Conference</title>
    <date>2011-05-19</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7790</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Ernest Arthur Graham MacKay</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Director">Malcolm Ian Wyman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Mitchell J. Collett</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Trevor Stirling</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (UK Branch)">Philip M. Morrisey</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Matthew C. Webb</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Lauren E. Torres</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Jonathan P. Fell</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="ING Bank NV (Broker)">Gerard Rijk</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jason DeRise</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Finance Director, Europe">James Wilson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Ian M. Shackleton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the SABMiller 2011 Preliminary Results Conference Call. I will now turn the call over to SABMiller. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to SABMiller's results presentation for our financial year ended 31st of March 2011. With me today, regrettably for the last time is Malcolm Wyman, our CFO. But I'm delighted that Jamie Wilson, our Deputy CFO and CFO Designate, is also here.</p>
          <p>First on formalities, our presentation does contain forward-looking statements. These reflect our current best estimates, but include risks and uncertainties and we disclaim any obligation to update these statements outside our normal reporting and seminar routines.</p>
          <p>Right, to get started, our sustained focus on our strategic priorities right across our business, we delivered excellent growth of 12% in organic constant currency EBITA and adjusted EPS grew 19% and our free cash flow increased 23% to $2.5 billion.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased with the competitive performance of our businesses, especially in an environment of mixed trading conditions where improvements in most of our emerging markets were offset by constrained consumer demand in North America and in Europe. Our revenues benefited mainly from resumed volume growth and from selective price increases.</p>
          <p>We've continued to generate some significant fixed cost savings. This enabled increased marketplace investment in Africa and in South Africa, margin protection in Europe and margin growth in Latin America and North America. And the net effect of this was a positive movement in group EBITA margin, which is up by 120 basis points to 17.8%.</p>
          <p>Our volume results improved in the second half of the year. Growth for the year was led by the frontier markets in Africa and Asia, which have proved to be fairly buoyant through the economic cycle. This is complemented by a return to modest growth in Europe in the second half and some slow incremental improvement in the U.S. volume trend.</p>
          <p>Our material markets continue to be held back by unemployment and low consumer confidence amongst key beer drinkers with higher gasoline prices an added problem in North America.</p>
          <p>In this environment, modest price increases were enabled by the strength of our brands. Revenue was also helped by the active drive towards positive mix in brands and packs in the U.S.A., Latin America, South Africa and China.</p>
          <p>Turning to Latin America, our business there has performed well this year despite the fiscal and regulatory headwinds we faced in Colombia and Ecuador combined with exceptional rainfall and flooding in a number of our markets.</p>
          <p>We grew EBITA despite flat volumes and raised operating margin by over two percentage points to almost 26%. We've now seen more than five percentage points of increase in margin over the last three years. We continue to focus on beer category development. We're expanding our international premium segment having launched Miller Genuine Draft throughout the region and Miller Lite in Panama.</p>
          <p>We've created and rapidly developed an upper mainstream segment delivering higher margins and we've launched additional variants of our local premium brands which are shown on the next slide. For example, Cusque&#xF1;a Red, Cusque&#xF1;a Malta, Club Colombia Roja launched over the Christmas period. And our upper mainstream brand variance, Aguila Light in Colombia, Pilsener Light in Ecuador and Pilsen Callao in Peru, which have helped drive the 30% volume growth of the segment this year across the region. Our premium and upper mainstream segments together now represent 26% of our mix in Latin America, up over 4 percentage points on last year.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we delivered good financial performance with profit growth and an 80 basis point margin improvement despite a 3% decline in volumes. While we are beginning to see sporadic economic recoveries, consumer confidence is still weak and going out occasions are noticeably lagging. The second half did see some stabilization in that.</p>
          <p>We've instituted wide ranging restructuring programs and fixed cost reductions, particularly in Romania, Canaries, Italy and The Netherlands, and are benefiting from the centralization of the management of our manufacturing group, all of which drove our margin expansion.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in our leading power brands and are managing for value in competitive European market such as Italy, where a focus on revenue management has driven strong EBITA growth.</p>
          <p>In our larger markets, we've seen widespread competitor price reductions and discounting. Our own pricing has been steady. To protect category value and to grow our own position, we're using better price ladders to preserve the equity and consumer perceptions of our iconic local brands.</p>
          <p>We're introducing new products and packages to open up new segments. And we're investing in relationship with retailers built on a shared vision of value growth. The accumulation of all these steps will continue to build our leadership position in these markets, and ultimately serve to lead and protect category profitability.</p>
          <p>Moving now to MillerCoors, notwithstanding the subdued economy, pricing in the U.S. beer industry has remained firm. More specifically, MillerCoors has continued to reduce the price gap between the mainstream and economy segments, driving up trading and improved sales mix albeit with some volume effect.</p>
          <p>In this context, EBITA grew 20% benefiting from synergy realization and additional cost savings of $275 million in the fiscal year. MillerCoors has improved its segment share in Premium Lights led by Coors Light and complemented by a much improved performance from Miller Lite.</p>
          <p>There's a sales execution by MillerCoors and its wholesalers, is driving distribution and outlet velocity, especially in channels where MillerCoors had traditionally under indexed. Specific activities such as cross-merchandising in supermarkets and single-serve package offerings in convenience stores are aimed at specific beer occasions.</p>
          <p>An intensified through the line marketing with a focus on African-Americans and Hispanics is having a positive impact. MillerCoors has further plans to up its efforts in this space with its new sponsorship of the Primera Division of the Mexican Football League.</p>
          <p>MillerCoors' craft and import business, Tenth and Blake, continues to deliver growth ahead of the category. Blue Moon has now exceeded 1.5 million hectoliters per year and Leinenkugel's has also become a significant contributor. Peroni Nastro Azzurro delivered 7% growth as MillerCoors carefully expands its distribution platform.</p>
          <p>Then Africa delivered a strong full year performance with lager volume growth of 13%. We've now seen an acceleration of growth for six straight quarters. In Uganda, lager volumes grew by 20% with a significant market share gain supported by higher capacity and broader distribution, improved retail execution and a leading brand portfolio.</p>
          <p>And in Zambia, lager volume growth for the year was 28%, driven by more effective distribution, better availability of product and the continued consumer price benefit of the excise reduction in March 2010.</p>
          <p>Lager volumes in Tanzania grew by 5% for the full year having been level at the half year. And this is especially pleasing considering our loss of some licensed brand production. We continue to extend our route-to-market and our brand and pack portfolios with longer price ladders.</p>
          <p>Our regional premium brands Castle Lager, Castle Lite experienced strong growth adding to the margin expansion in the second half of the year which was also driven by improving capacity utilization.</p>
          <p>Our start-up operations in Ethiopia, Southern Sudan and Nigeria are now performing to expectations. We see more opportunity in Nigeria and recently announced a further $100 million investment to build a brewery and bottling facility in Onitsha. And as we said at the interim, we continue to see promising signs of recovery and future growth potential in Zimbabwe. And in this year we saw lager volumes return to historic levels.</p>
          <p>Lager volumes in South Africa grew 2%; the strong performance given that the financial year had no Easter peak. Excellent operational performance across brand marketing through the line activations and sales execution has resulted in our market shares stabilizing. This is quite an achievement given that we under index in the faster growing premium segment. It's been driven by the performance of Castle Lite, which has gained premium share as the segment leader and mainstream brand growth following comprehensive renovation of Castle Lager, Hansa Pilsener and Carling Black Label. There is also evidence that the beer category is gaining share of alcohol.</p>
          <p>Key measured aspects of in-trade execution, SAB's lead versus the competition is widening including both distribution and sales service. In our soft drinks business and emphasis on trade execution and revenue management has also driven greater volume and top line growth. Volumes grew 3%. Across the board, tight cost management and further savings are enabling our continued reinvestment in marketing and in sales. Then in Asia, lager volumes grew 10% on an organic basis with strong growth in China, supported by India and Vietnam and EBITA increased strongly.</p>
          <p>CR Snow continues to enjoy a disproportionate share of market growth. Lager volumes grew by 10% organically and CR Snow increased its national market share to 21%, with the Snow brand itself now accounting for 19% of the market. Revenue per hectoliter increased by 4%.</p>
          <p>CR Snow's success in building high market shares and stronger profitability is now resulting in double-digit markets &#x2013; double-digit margins rather, in several of our provinces. In more recent months, there has been an increase on the average selling prices in order to cover higher costs. CR Snow has continued to grow its presence in the premium segment through brand extensions including Snow Draft and Brave the World.</p>
          <p>India delivered good growth in volume and a substantial improvement in EBITA with the shift in focus towards those provinces which have fewer regulatory restrictions applied to beer. Brand extensions and packaging innovations including the expansion of proprietary bottles in key states in the past year drove increased margin and favorable mix. And in addition, the recent launch of a PET bottle is showing encouraging signs of success.</p>
          <p>And now, I shall give a brief update on the group's four strategic priorities. These are remained consistent and relevant for almost five years now. Over the past decade, we have created a balanced portfolio of businesses, with leading growth characteristics.</p>
          <p>In this financial year, we entered Argentina with the acquisition of CASA Isenbeck, which provides us with an interesting initial entry point. We also acquired a water producer in Kenya as a part of our Africa full beverage strategy. Our associate in China extended its footprint with the further acquisition of three breweries in Heilongjiang, <mark type="ph" /> Jiangsu, and Henan (15:37).</p>
          <p>Our M&amp;A approach is disciplined with a firm economic value approach and a focus on a wide range of businesses and markets in which we can add value through the application of our skills and experience.</p>
          <p>Looking at our other strategic priorities, as regard to our local brand portfolios, we focus our attention in five key areas. First is the expansion of the category across new consumer segments and occasions.</p>
          <p>Latin America, we're working to bring consumers into the beer category from local spirits and develop more occasions where beer is the preferred choice rather than cheaper traditional products that generally have higher alcohol content.</p>
          <p>Examples of this include smaller bottles which encourage picking up the beer on-the-go, promoting beer consumption with meals as well as special occasions when a beer may not have been available or prominently marketed in the past.</p>
          <p>In Ecuador, for example, we've increased our focus on consumer events and now service over 35,000 such events versus early 7,500 the previous year.</p>
          <p>Our second focus is on initiatives to develop premium brand portfolios. As mentioned earlier, MillerCoors has accelerated the growth in its craft segment with recent extensions into more seasonal varieties such as Harvest Pumpkin Ale from Blue Moon and Big Eddy's Imperial Stout from Leinenkugels.</p>
          <p>With our import business in the United Kingdom, we are broadening our portfolio building on the success of Peroni Nastro Azzurro with our other beers of the world, such as Pilsner Urquell from Czech Republic, MGD from the U.S. and Tyskie and Lech from Poland.</p>
          <p>In Latin America and Africa, we are consistently building local premium and upper mainstream segment. In Latin America, these were up 20% in the year and now account for over 25% of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>And in Mozambique, for example, Laurentina Preta, a dark lager selling at a 15% premium to mainstream has delivered three consecutive years of exceptional growth, and now commands over a 30% market share. We continue to strengthen the mainstream brands which were at the heart of our local portfolios.</p>
          <p>In the past year, we've seen a major trend improvement in Miller Lite on the back of packaging innovation and focused intensified marketing of the brands' taste credentials that resonate with key beer drinkers.</p>
          <p>In Tanzania, Kilimanjaro Premium Lager, or Kili as we call it, leverages local football and music which define the mainstream beer category, and was continued to be aspirational for the majority of Tanzanian consumers.</p>
          <p>Peroni has a symbol of national pride in Italy, strengthened its position as the leading brand, while reducing discounting. And that resulted in higher on-premise volume and overall market share and a significant increase in unit revenue and EBITA.</p>
          <p>And the rejuvenation of Castle Lager with intense marketing of the brands' core property of male sociability, the 2010 FIFA World Cup and the South African national sports has led to further in-trade investment and resulted in 14% growth in the year.</p>
          <p>Our fourth and fifth focused areas are advancing our in-trade commercial capabilities. In the Czech Republic, for example, we've significantly improved our approach to revenue management and maintained our lead in building category value. The focus on mix management within our brand/pack/channel architecture is creating value both in premium and for example, in convenience packaging with cans.</p>
          <p>We're improving our promotions to drive higher margin brands and packs and then the rapidly expanding off-premise key accounts channel, our commercial approach has been upgraded to forward retail relationships that build long-term value.</p>
          <p>Simple transactional give and take is giving way to more strategic category management aligning our interests with the retailers in terms of financial incentives overall category margins and joint business planning.</p>
          <p>As regards sales execution MillerCoors is investing heavily in strengthening its relationships with the customers. They are closing a legacy gap versus their largest competitor in sales technology to track execution of retail. The consequence has been increased category captaincies in key account chains from 24% in 2008 to 30% in 2010.</p>
          <p>MillerCoors revenue performance in these outlets is up almost 5%, which is also a win for retailers. And as I've mentioned MillerCoors propositions have been strengthened by increases in cross merchandising in multicultural in-trade activation, and focused category development by beer merchants from Tenth and Blake unit.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to our third strategic priority which is raised a profitability of our businesses sustainably. We continue to manage costs both to enable increase in marketing investments and to raise our margins. For example, in Colombia we've managed to grow EBITA and expand margins very significantly in spite of the volume decline.</p>
          <p>On the costs side, we've optimized our service model and route to market, which improved fixed cost productivity, but closure of the Bogot&#xE1; brewery helped us rebalance the production grid, leading to more efficient operations.</p>
          <p>In Europe, in April 2010, we regionalized our manufacturing organization with a central team now managing our production platform and supply chain. We've seen pleasing COGS benefits and fixed cost reductions, with more flexible working and optimization and manufacturing grid. This has created a sustained improvement in the European profitability. Also it's allowed our General Managers to focus fully on the commercial side of the business.</p>
          <p>In Africa, we are developing local supply chains, which improves raw material reliability and delivers cost benefits. Historically, over 80% of our brewing materials in Africa were imported. We are aiming to reduce this to around 50% over the next three years. Partnering with governments and NGOs we've contracted over 28,000 local farmers, a number we expect to increase to over 45,000 in the coming years.</p>
          <p>In Uganda, we are working towards self sufficiency in grains and we've recently built new maltings plant. In Zambia, we have recently become self-sufficient in barley. Collaborating with the local farming communities also helps generate local stakeholder and government support, excise benefits as one positive consequence. This has enabled us to grow brands such as Eagle at a more affordable price point, while maintaining the same margins as our mainstream brands.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our fourth and final strategic priority, to leverage our skill and global scale. We're progressing with our wide ranging business capability program. Our global procurement operation is now established in Switzerland. We transitioned most brewing materials in the first half of the year and at the last quarter the major packaging materials. Having placed approximately $2 billion of expenditure under centralized management so far, we are starting to see the benefits. More packaging and indirect spend categories are planned to follow during the coming year.</p>
          <p>We've reached significant milestones in other aspects of the program too. The sales and distribution system for LatAm has been rolled out from Peru to Colombia. And we're going to Ecuador next. This will constitute an important building block for the global systems platform.</p>
          <p>The back office application went live in South Africa and our corporate office during the year. Later releases of these modules will be at the heart of the core processors that will be deployed globally. In parallel, we've continued selective outsourcing of finance processes to our partner Genpact.</p>
          <p>The scope of the outsourced work has been extended in South Africa and other countries. They have started with the program in Latin America and in Europe. We've also started to rollout a global treasury application and to reorganize treasury operations for regional scale.</p>
          <p>While the investments in business capability continue to be substantial, we are obviously pleased to see financial benefits building up on the other side of the equation. Ongoing operational benefits exceeded $60 million in the year and we've seen further improvements in working capital with cumulative inflows now over $450 million.</p>
          <p>As our procurement and manufacturing initiatives in particular accelerate, we are confident that these direct operating benefits continue to increase.</p>
          <p>I'd like now to turn over to Malcolm Wyman to take you through the financial slides.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and good day to everyone. As in the past, I'm going to focus my presentation on results on an organic constant currency basis, which remove the impact of currency movements on our underlying performance and profitability.</p>
          <p>The group has again delivered another year of excellent results with strong adjusted earnings per share growth in all our major currencies. Adjusted earnings per share in our reported currency of United States dollars grew 19%, whilst increasing by 23% in pound sterling. Final dividend is US$0.615 per share, which brings the annual dividend to $0.81 per share, an increase of 19% over the prior year.</p>
          <p>We delivered a very strong financial performance this year, enhanced by improved second half volume growth across all divisions other than North America. Lager volumes increased 2% on an organic basis, underpinned by good growth across the number of our emerging markets, including China, Peru, South Africa, Uganda and Zambia.</p>
          <p>Our continued focus on strengthening our local brand portfolios through increased marketing investment and improved availability, supported by general improvement in economic conditions, drove our emerging market volume growth. Momentum was; however, partially offset by tough trading conditions in North America and Europe.</p>
          <p>Soft drinks volumes across our Africa and Central America markets were up by 3% on an organic basis. Organic constant currency revenue grew 5.2% driven by volume growth as well as prior year and current price increases taken selectively across most markets.</p>
          <p>Top line revenue growth together with reduced costs contributed to the 12.4% increase in organic constant currency EBITA. Full year EBITA margin increased by 110 basis points on an organic constant currency basis, somewhat higher than the 90 basis points improvement, we achieved at the half year.</p>
          <p>Lower finance costs following a reduction in net debt by more than $1.3 billion together with a marginally lower effective tax rates resulted in our very strong 19% growth and adjusted earnings per share.</p>
          <p>Group revenue grew 5.2% on an organic constant currency basis with four regions delivering revenue per hectoliter growth. Good volume growth and firm pricing taken both last year and in the second half of this year, together with continued premiumisation within our brand portfolios, particularly in our emerging market operations contributed equally to overall revenue growth.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, revenue per hectoliter grew by 2% on a constant currency basis, principally as a result of prior year price increases, positive mix from strong growth of local premium brands across the region and through the introduction of Miller Genuine Draft in a number of countries in the region.</p>
          <p>Volumes continued to be impacted by downtrading and difficult economic conditions for consumers in Europe. However, revenue per hectoliter on a constant currency basis grew 3%, largely as a result of pricing to recover the significant excise increases levied last year in Russia and the Czech Republic.</p>
          <p>In North America, MillerCoors grew revenue per hectoliter by 2% as a result of price increases taken over the third quarter, together with some improvement in brand mix following the strong growth of the Tenth and Blake crafts and imports division.</p>
          <p>In our subsidiary businesses in Africa, revenue per hectoliter grew 11% on a constant currency basis, following price increases taken generally in line with inflation and the good growth of our local and regional premium brands.</p>
          <p>Revenue per hectoliter grew 4% in Asia due to price increases taken both in India as well as across a number of regions in China in the later part of the financial year. And South Africa delivered good revenue per hectoliter growth of 5% on a constant currency basis due to price increases taken in both beer and soft drinks businesses.</p>
          <p>We delivered excellent organic constant currency EBITA growth of 12.4%, almost double the growth rate of 6.3% achieved last year. Volume and pricing benefits, lower input costs and tight overall fixed cost control, all contributed to the significant increase in EBITA growth. All regions other than Europe achieved a double-digit increase in EBITA, with the trend improving in the second half of the year largely driven by better volume performance over this period.</p>
          <p>Top-line revenue growth, significant synergy and cost savings in North America, lower raw material costs and particularly good fixed cost savings in Latin America and Europe drove the full year EBITA performance.</p>
          <p>On a reported basis, EBITA grew 15% benefiting from the relative strength of the South African Rand and Colombian Peso against the U.S. Dollar throughout the year. This more than offset the adverse impact of weaker key operating currencies in Africa and in Central and Eastern European countries.</p>
          <p>Latin America, full year organic constant currency EBITA grew by 11% despite lager volume growth remaining level with the prior year. Pricing taken in the prior year together with selective price increases during the year and favorable brand mix combined with lower raw material input costs and good fixed cost control contributed to the double-digit EBITA growth. Raw material input costs for the full year were down mid-single digits on a constant currency dollar per hectoliter basis largely due to lower barley prices and favorable currency benefits.</p>
          <p>Fixed cost productivity in real terms was achieved in Colombia and Peru whilst marketing investment increased over the year, EBITA margin increased by 210 basis points. Enhanced sales execution and brand portfolio development initiatives together with economic growth underpinned lager volume growth of 10% in Peru which largely offset the 6% volume decline in Colombia. As previously mentioned the volume declined in Colombia was principally due to the emergency sales tax levied solely on the beer category in February 2010, as well as severe flooding in a number of regions. Encouragingly, sales volumes in Colombia have returned to growth after cycling the sales tax increase. In Ecuador, lager volumes grew by 1% after growing 9% in the previous year with improved product availability and increased sales coverage helping to offset government restrictions on alcohol sales. Soft drinks volumes declined by 1% in the year, impacted by heavy rainfall across Central America in the first half and challenging economic conditions in El Salvador.</p>
          <p>In Europe, the difficult economic and trading conditions led to a full year lager volume decline of 3%. But encouragingly, second half volumes grew by 1% following a first half volume decline of 5% with most markets showing improved volume trends in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Downtrading and competitor discounting remain a feature of the beer market and high unemployment levels and low real wage growth continue to dampen consumer confidence. Poland suffered a particularly challenging first half, which included flooding as well as alcohol sales restrictions during a nine-day national mourning period following the death of the President.</p>
          <p>Volumes in Russia and the Czech Republic continue to be impacted by the excise increases introduced during the last quarter of the prior year, and the shift away from on-premise sales in the Czech Republic. However, encouragingly there was moderate growth in Russia full year volumes as a result of improving economic conditions and good weather experienced over the summer period.</p>
          <p>Lower commodity costs together with production cost efficiencies delivered through the regional management and coordination of Europe's manufacturing operations from the beginning of this financial year and lower year-on-year fixed costs resulted in EBITA growth of 4% on an organic constant currency basis, EBITA margin also improved by 70 basis points.</p>
          <p>The results of our North American segment comprise our 58% share of the results from the MillerCoors joint venture and 100% of Miller Brewing International.</p>
          <p>Our North American segment delivered a strong EBITA growth of 20% for the full year. MillerCoors lager sales and sales to retailers excluding contract brewing both declined by 3% for the year in a difficult beer market that remained under pressure from high unemployment.</p>
          <p>However, positive mix effects and firm pricing offset the impact of this volume decline enabling revenue to remain in-line with last year and generating revenue per hectoliter growth 2%.</p>
          <p>These mix benefits were driven by double-digit growth in MillerCoors Tenth and Blake crafts and imports brand portfolio, consumers trading up into the Premium Lights segment. Cost of goods sold per hectoliter increased slightly due to higher product costs impacted by the favorable mix together with the rise in freight costs.</p>
          <p>MillerCoors delivered $275 million of incremental synergy and cost savings in the full year. The savings achieved in marketing, distribution, supply chain and brewing and packaging materials. Since the inception of the joint venture on 1 July 2008, total annualized synergies and cost savings of $684 million have been realized.</p>
          <p>MillerCoors has achieved the original three-year $500 million synergy target six months earlier than expected and remains on track to achieve $750 million of total annualized synergy and other cost savings by the end of the 2012 calendar year. These synergy figures are for MillerCoors as a whole and SABMiller's share is 58% of these amounts.</p>
          <p>Results of our Africa division include our share of Delta, our associate in Zimbabwe, following the effect of dollarisation of the economy in 2009 and a subsequent stabilization of the local economy. Lager volumes grew by 13% or 9% excluding Zimbabwe on an organic basis. The strong growth is largely a result of the improved focus on route-to-market activities, incremental investments made to support our differentiated brand portfolios, and the benefits of capacity investments in Angola, Mozambique, Tanzania and Uganda. Zambia, Uganda, Angola and our own brand portfolio in Tanzania all delivered strong double-digit lager volume growth.</p>
          <p>Soft drinks' volumes grew 8% on an organic basis or 4% excluding Zimbabwe. Significant growth in traditional beer volumes benefited from the inclusion of our share of Zimbabwe's volumes which drove other alcoholic beverage volume growth of 30% and 3% excluding Zimbabwe. EBITA growth of 20% was driven by strong volume growth, robust pricing, and positive mix benefits as a result of the growth in local and regional premium offerings in our key markets. The 60-basis points EBITA margin decline is attributable to increased marketing investment and capacity expansion related fixed costs, along with higher raw material input costs which have been negatively impacted by weaker local currencies relative to the U.S. dollar. However, it is encouraging to see that following the first half EBITA margin decline EBITA margin gained 20 basis points in the second half of the financial year.</p>
          <p>In Asia, we achieved lager volume growth of 10% on an organic basis. In China, our associate CR Snow delivered another strong performance with full year lager volume growth of 10% and further market share gains. In India, lager volumes we re also up by 10%. Very strong EBITA growth of 33% was assisted by an improved performance in India, following losses reported in the second half of last year and solid EBITA growth in China. The EBITA margin increase of 50 basis points more than recovers the 40-basis points margin decline we reported last year. In China, continued expansion within the premium segment and recent price increases contributed to the strong performance. However, changes to consumption tax legislation for foreign invested enterprises effective from December 2010 adversely impacted EBITA in the last quarter of our financial year.</p>
          <p>Our joint venture in Australia experienced further volume declines in the second half as a result of increased competition in the premium segment and severe flooding in parts of the country. Our lager volumes grew by 2% in South Africa following a period of sustained investment behind our core brands and enhanced sales execution initiatives. This strategy has led to solid core brand growth with a strong performance from Castle Lite following the "Extra cold' campaign during the year and good growth from Hansa Pilsener and Castle Lager. Encouragingly, our market share has stabilized over the second half of the year. Soft drinks volumes grew by 3% with improved trade execution and the focus on immediate consumption packs driving improved mix. EBITA grew by 11% on an organic constant currency basis. Volume growth, pricing from both the beer and soft drinks businesses, and lower beer raw material costs contributed to this result.</p>
          <p>Lower barley prices and favorable year-on-year currency moves drove brewing raw material benefits which were, however, partly offset by higher sugar and PET costs in the soft drinks business. EBITA margin returned to growth in the second half, resulting in full year margin increasing by 60 basis points.</p>
          <p>Turning to raw material and input costs; our full year raw material input costs were down approximately 1% on the prior year on a constant currency U.S. dollar per hectoliter basis. As expected, raw material costs increased in the second half of this year on the same basis as the benefit of lower barley prices in the latter part of the previous financial year was cycled. In addition, the sharp rise in crude oil prices resulted in an increase in distribution costs over the second half of the year. Full year raw material costs benefited from the strengthening of a number of key operating currencies relative to the U.S. dollar, in particular the South African rand and the Colombian peso. Total costs of goods sold were also down approximately 1% in the year on a constant currency U.S. dollar per hectoliter basis, following a 3% increase last year.</p>
          <p>Total exceptional charges of $467 million have been taken against profit before tax for the full year. Exceptional costs related to our business capability program amounted to $296 million for the year, in line with our expectations given at the time of the interims. As previously announced, $149 million of exceptional charges were incurred for the Black Economic Empowerment scheme in South Africa. These are primarily non-cash IFRS2 share-based payment charges relating to the retailer and employee components of the scheme and associated costs.</p>
          <p>Restructuring continues to be necessary in our Europe division and costs of $52 million were incurred, including the costs associated with the closure of the Cluj brewery in Romania, restructuring initiatives in the Netherlands and the Canary Islands, and costs associated with the intended disposal of the in-house distribution business in Italy.</p>
          <p>The group's share of MillerCoors integration and restructuring costs amounted to $5 million. Impairment charges of $98 million were incurred in Europe, relating to the impairment of our in-house distribution operation in Italy, following advanced discussions to dispose of this operation as well as impairment charges relating to the closure of the Cluj brewery I mentioned earlier.</p>
          <p>In February 2011, a profit of $159 million was generated from the partial disposal of the group's shareholding in Tsogo Sun holdings as part of the Tsogo Sun, Gold Reef Resorts merger in South Africa. The group's share of the impairment loss on Tsogo Sun's existing holding in Gold Reef Resorts as a result of this transaction, together with the cost of the transaction, is some $26 million.</p>
          <p>As referred to earlier, our business capability program continues to make progress across a wide range of activities. The development of Trinity, a global procurement organization, has been particularly important with brewing raw materials transitioning to global management in the first half, most packaging/buying transitioning during the second half, and related initiatives in non-production spend beginning to deliver results. As we've said, the regionalization of the European manufacturing organization has started to produce meaningful financial benefit.</p>
          <p>In the systems area, the rollout of sales and distribution systems in Latin America is proceeding well, and the back office platform was implemented in the first half in South Africa. Extension of these models into a global platform is progressing well. Costs continue to be driven by the design, build and implementation of the system's platforms and are broadly in line with the expectations communicated at mid-year, including the exceptional charge of $296 million.</p>
          <p>Net operating benefits in the year exceeded $60 million, ahead of our expectation at the time of the interims. Global procurement and efficiencies from the regional manufacturing organization in Europe are making the major contribution. We are pleased with progress on working capital in general and specifically from the contribution from process and systems changes initiated through the business capability program. On an accumulated basis, working capital benefits amounted to over $450 million, comfortably exceeding our original objective for cash inflows from working capital of $350 million by the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBITDA comprising EBITDA before cash flows from exceptional items together with dividends received from MillerCoors was up 12% on the prior year as a result of increased operating profit and higher dividend from MillerCoors. Following the significant working capital cash inflow of $563 million in the prior year, the level of cash generated from working capital reduced, as expected, to $66 million this year.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure of $1.315 billion was $213 million lower than last year following the completion of a number of capacity-related projects in Europe and Africa in the prior year. Free cash flow continues to improve, up some $460 million this year, principally as a result of reduced capital expenditure, increased dividend from MillerCoors, and lower investments in associates and joint ventures.</p>
          <p>The group's effective tax rate of 28.2% was 30 basis points lower than that of the previous year as a result of a more beneficial geographic mix of earnings, changes in legislation within our Europe division, and the resolution of various uncertain tax situations.</p>
          <p>Our net debt position has improved from the prior financial year-end due to our strong cash flow but this has been offset to some extent by the appreciation of certain currencies including the rand and euro in which a material proportion of our debt is held. Our financial structure has improved significantly with gearing falling to 31.2% and net debt to adjusted EBITDA of 1.3 times.</p>
          <p>Adjusted net finance costs have been reduced, primarily as a result of our lower net debt. The weighted average interest rate on gross debts at 31st of March was 5.9%, marginally up from 5.7% at 31 March, 2010. But this is primarily driven by increases in interest rates in Africa and Colombia as well as the repayment of some low coupon short-term debt. Majority of our debt continues to be held in floating rates benefiting from low markets interest rates.</p>
          <p>We continue to maintain an appropriate and balanced net debt currency profile given the spread of our businesses. As we report in U.S. dollars, we also keep a reasonable proportion of debt in that currency. Our maturity profile, after offsetting cash against short-term debt maturities, indicates that the majority of our debt matures after two years. We currently have substantial headroom available to refinance more than the amount of debt falling due over the next two years, in terms of cash resources and undrawn committed facilities.</p>
          <p>Our access to committed liquidity remains strong with committed headroom available to the Group in excess of $3 billion as of 31 March 2011. Subsequent to the year-end, we signed a new five-year $2.5 billion syndicated revolving credit facility with two one-year extension options to replace facilities of a similar amount which were maturing over the next two years, and which were canceled at that time. We have also renewed existing in-country facilities as and when required.</p>
          <p>The growth in consumer demand experienced in most of our emerging markets over the past year is expected to continue into the current financial year. However, consumer demand in Europe and the U.S. remains uncertain. Raw material input costs are expected to be up low single-digits in the current financial year, due to rising commodity prices which have adversely impacted the cost of brewing raw materials in particular.</p>
          <p>As of the end of March 2011, well over half of the group's barley requirements for the forthcoming financial year were however covered through supplier contracts, but at somewhat higher prices than last year, following the poor wheat and barley harvests in Russia and Northern Europe last summer.</p>
          <p>In addition, some packaging commodities as well as distribution costs are expected to be affected by the increase in crude oil prices. However, we expect that firmer local operating currencies relative to the U.S. dollar will partially mitigate these higher underlying commodity prices in the current financial year.</p>
          <p>We will maintain our focus on cash generation. As you would expect following the significant improvement in working capital cash inflows of over $629 million generated in the past two years, future working capital benefits were moderate.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure in the current financial year will increase to approximately $1.5 billion, driven up by our capacity expansion projects in markets experiencing substantial growth such as Nigeria, Southern Sudan and Peru. We anticipate that finance costs will be lower in the current financial year, given the lower net debt levels we expect.</p>
          <p>Finally, our effective tax rate should remain between approximately 28% and 29% this year, reflecting a level which we believe is sustainable in the medium-term given the current composition of the Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Malcolm. So to conclude, while consumer demand is likely to continue growing in most developing markets, there are uncertainties in the pace of recovery in developed markets. Price increases will be taken selectively, taking into account the competitive context and our drive to achieve affordability in some markets.</p>
          <p>More broadly, our organic growth strategies remain consistent, developing the beer category and our local leading positions and we will continue to leverage scale across our unique global beer footprint. And we see that our medium-term outlook for growth in volume, revenue and profitability remains strong.</p>
          <p>And with that, operator, we will be happy to take questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Mitch Collett from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. On input costs, you said that it should be low single digits per liter in constant currency. And I think you implied that it would be slightly better than that in actual FX. What would it be, if we took the current spots and then extrapolated that out for the rest of the year? And then secondly, you mentioned that you are looking at expanding the price ladder in the European division. I just wondered if you could give us a bit more detail about what that means. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your question on input costs, we've given guidance here that we expect to be up in low single digits, now that takes account of the various level of hedging that we have across the different commodities including our contracts that we have in place. And it also takes current spot and it takes spot for the portion of our commodities, which is not hedged. So in taking into account that low single-digit figure we have assumed that current spots is applied to all of our uncovered portion of commodities. So I think we're being reasonably conservative particularly as we've seen some of the spot prices come off in aluminum and in barley and obviously in oil over the last couple of weeks. And as you know, raw materials and commodities are notoriously volatile, and so we've used the spots at the time of the calculation as opposed to what has happened in the last couple of weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Constant currency, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's just taking into account the underlying figures in constant currency with the benefits of prevailing currency levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So does that include or not include the strengthening of various operating currencies at this stage versus the average for last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've taken that at the spot rates for commodities and we've applied an average over the last couple of months of the currency rates. So to the extent that currencies have firmed since then that hasn't been built in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if today's CapEx was to remain I guess the input costs would do slightly better than the low single-digit you've guided towards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That may be. But as I said, currencies and commodities are notoriously volatile, so we don't really calculate this on an ongoing basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. Thanks. And --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your question on price status in Europe, I'm not sure that I can really give much specific detail there. We do a number of things all the time. We are increasing our support for our global brands at the top of the portfolio. We have strong positions in local premium brands, which we focus on pretty systematically all the time. We have package introductions. We've talked about, for instance, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (59:20) PET in Czech. We by and large don't over index, in fact we under index in the below mainstream position. So what we try to do in general is to improve our mainstream and above mainstream position, so we have a full innovation agenda across Europe, and we have support on global brands and local premium brands, plus packaging innovations in a number of markets. I think that's about as specific as I can be, I'm afraid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Trevor Stirling from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Graham and Malcolm. Just one question from my side, maybe for Malcolm; Malcolm with net debt at 1.3 times net &#x2013; sorry, with debt at 1.3 times EBITDA, at what level would you think is appropriate to start thinking about ramping up cash return to shareholders? Clearly, you want to retain flexibility on the acquisition front, but how much lower would you like to see that debt level go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, we don't have a target level. We monitor this all the time. But our primary focus is obviously on growing the business organically and through opportunities, and so what we do is we like to keep that flexibility. And I think it's fair to say though that if we found that the balance sheet kept on strengthening, and over the course of the next 12 or 18 months, we got to below a level of one times and we could not see on the horizon of 12 to 24 months a significant use of the cash, there is no doubt that we would give thought to all of the options, which have been &#x2013; which the Board considers from time-to-time about how to optimize the balance sheet for shareholder value, and that would obviously include different methodologies for return of capital.</p>
          <p>But that's certainly not under consideration at the moment. We do have and have done during the course of this year; we've expanded the business through some acquisitions in places like Argentina, China. We have a number of items on-the-go in Africa. So I think, at the moment, we are looking at expanding through bolt-on acquisitions in many of our regions. But as I say, it's always up for consideration and those options are being considered should we get to a stage over the next say 12 to 24 months where the balance sheet strengthens inordinately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful. Thank you, Malcolm. Sorry, thank you Graham.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Philip Morrisey from Berenberg. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. Could I ask please on CapEx, I think your prior guidance was for CapEx to gradually decline to $1.1 billion in three years, today obviously $1.5 billion guidance and I just wondered how we should now see the trajectory of CapEx going forward?</p>
          <p>And, secondly, if I could ask on China and the margins, historically, you've obviously pointed out that the key to significant improved margin in China was pricing. And I wondered given Snow's recent move to increase pricing albeit driven by commodity costs, but set against that some governmental restraints broadly on pricing. If you could just update us on how you saw the outlook for China pricing and hence perhaps margins?</p>
          <p>And then finally, if I may on the United States, your major competitors obviously alluded to wanting to see the discount of economy to premium lowered from around 25% to 15%. And I just wondered whether strategically you shared that same view about the appropriateness of pricing in the economy sector as we go forward? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, firstly, Philip, on the CapEx side, yes we did give guidance I think a year or two ago that we would expect the continuation of the trend downwards in CapEx based on what we saw at the time. There are a couple of issues which have impacted that. First of all, currencies are a lot of firmer than we thought at the time, the emerging market currencies. And when you convert CapEx into dollar terms taking into account the firmness of those currencies, we've seen an up-tick purely through a technical nature of translation of underlying currencies into the U.S. dollar. And that's been part of the up-tick.</p>
          <p>The other part is that we've seen stronger growth than we expected in countries like Africa &#x2013; countries in Africa. And we've entered Sudan. We are putting down a new brewery in Onitsha in Nigeria, and Peru has been growing at 10% volume growth.</p>
          <p>So when you take those markets into account, we need to ensure that when demand looks as though it's going to exceed supply, we put down more capacity ahead of that, and that's what we are doing, and where opportunities for regional bolt-ons arise that we take those opportunities in good growth markets. So this represents those two issues of higher underlying CapEx because of translation and additional opportunities that we didn't foresee at the time that we made this forecast.</p>
          <p>As far as the other markets are concerned, we are very much in line. We have spare capacity. We don't intend to increase CapEx in places like the United States. I think Europe has capacity in virtually all of its markets. But again, China and maybe India, as demand rises, we may put some further capacity down there. So it's a balance of trying to meet supply when it starts to exceed demand and also underlying translation impacts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Sorry, could I just ask, the $1.5 billion, as we go into fiscal '13 and beyond, should we assume that accelerates or indeed rolls over and gently declines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, at this stage, we haven't given any forecast for that. Philip, so I wouldn't like to expand that. But I think, bear in mind that there was significant CapEx in our past figures which are rolling out right now. So unless we see significant opportunities, I wouldn't expect that to increase substantially. But we always reserve the right and it would be appropriate for us to put capacity down wherever we see growth opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Philip, if I could just remind you that there is a significant lead and lag on CapEx compared to growth, because &#x2013; so really what your question boils down to, is what is the volume growth outlook beyond F'12. Because both in container CapEx and in production CapEx, there is a more than proportional relationship between growth and CapEx, obviously. We can accommodate low &#x2013; in many of our markets, as Malcolm said, we can accommodate low levels of growth for a good long time without any significant CapEx. Once you go above a certain trigger level, you actually have to trigger major projects. I mean, Europe, for instance, has been in a rationalization phase for a long time now, but you may remember going back several years, actually they had an equally major CapEx expansion program going on when the global financial crisis hit. So CapEx is a bit jerkier than pure volume growth, is what I'm saying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your margin question in China, yes, I mean, I think &#x2013; the positive side there is that &#x2013; is that prices have become more fluid, and therefore there is more flexibility emerging overall in the pricing environment. You're quite right that the government is trying to apply pressure to get companies to restrain pricing. That hasn't been directly delivered so much to the beer industry as much as the spirits industry we believe. But still there is pressure from the government to do that. What the real net effect of that pressure is, I'm not sure.</p>
          <p>But I think that what we are pleased to see is that there is general movement, because what &#x2013; what happened in China for many years as you probably remember was that there was absolutely no movement in nominal prices for year after year after year. And so I think that a general atmosphere or environment of some movement, even if it is to cope with raw material price increases, increases the general flexibility in the market.</p>
          <p>On your question about the U.S., yes, I've quite often remarked that when we went into the U.S., when we bought Miller we discovered that the market leader had allowed or encouraged the discount between below premiums and premiums to widen dramatically over the previous perhaps 5 or 10 years from a historical number of about that 15%, to 25%, even 30%. And there seemed to be no logical economic reason for that. And there was no economic reason that we could see that AB would have done that in the past. So we think it's not supported by good economics, and so we are, we are relatively supportive of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Matthew Webb from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just two questions, please. Firstly, you seem to be pursuing quite a different strategy to the competition in Central and Eastern Europe in terms of pricing. I'm just wondering whether you could flesh that out a bit, sort of explain your thinking behind that and also maybe indicate which markets that that's a particular issue in.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, you are obviously having a lot of success in the upper mainstream segment in Colombia. I was just wondering whether you could sort of talk about how you're driving that and also what, where that volume is coming from. Is it cannibalization, is it incremental, is it taking from other categories, please. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in Central Europe, as I have said, we tend not to operate very, particularly enthusiastically or strongly in the discount segments, and we've tried to maintain industry structure. There have been substantial moves down in a couple of markets. Poland, perhaps I would highlight, where there's been very substantial discounting by one of the competitors in particular and we've tried to avoid following that and we've used fighter brand tactics to stop that.</p>
          <p>In Czech, the same thing, although in Czech it's a company quite strongly by the move out of on-premise to off-premise, and in particular to key account off-premise. So it's a channel mix effect going on in Czech.</p>
          <p>In Russia, some of the very high priced premium &#x2013; Russia has a very, very long price ladder, if you like, and the brands right at the top, our brand for instance, Miller Genuine Draft was sitting at a weighted average market price index to mainstream of about 230%. And there has been a lot of down trading or competition at that level to attack those price points.</p>
          <p>What we've done is try to avoid following, we've relied on marketing, we've relied on the sale support, we relied on innovation and brand introductions to avoid following there and to avoid collaborating in category value destruction overall, but it's guerilla warfare rather than a silver bullet to fix the problem.</p>
          <p>In Colombia, yes the price mix has improved. We have Aguila Light at a premium, the Club Colombia Roja brand that we mentioned in the presentation has done very well. Our information is that the Roja brand in particular, as an example, has sourced most of its volume from other categories outside beer. So we are pretty happy with the rate of cannibalization in the sense that the cannibalization is low. Of course there will always be some cannibalization, but the net effect has been beneficial.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Lauren Torres from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. My question also relates to your pricing initiatives. It's interesting to see ABI actually taking some pricing at the expense of losing some near-term market share in some of their larger markets. I'm just curious, how do you think about this balance, particularly in light of softer consumer conditions in the U.S. and Europe, if you're willing to take pricing at the expense of market share.</p>
          <p>And also with that <mark type="ph" /> strategy (73:00) you talk about volatile commodity costs, the offsets here as these pressures particularly increase maybe as we course through the year. Are the offsets still on pricing or are there more cost savings initiatives that you think will act as the best offset? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this topic, this pricing topic is a very complicated one, because we don't control or have a strategy for pricing at the center. It's very much market-by-market, and we've said in the text and the release that we look to price selectively depending on the various pressures in the different markets. So if you focus on the U.S. and I think your remarks about ABI probably apply to the U.S., we note that, yes.</p>
          <p>We don't think that you &#x2013; we would not be happy with a situation in which &#x2013; in any market in which we constantly lost market share in order to price up. That's not a healthy situation to be in. The U.S. market is a bit more complicated than that, as you, I'm sure, are aware in the sense that there is good growth in the top of the market, in the craft segment in particular, but the craft and import over the medium-term more generally.</p>
          <p>Now we participate in that growth. In fact, we take more than a proportional share of it through our Blue Moon and Leinenkugel franchises. So, that pricing activity is going on between the &#x2013; what they call premium and sub-premium segments. It's not focused on &#x2013; it's not the whole of the market.</p>
          <p>So I'm not sure that I can give you a more definitive answer. We wouldn't be happy to see a constant loss of market share through pricing actions in any market over the years. The &#x2013; in other markets, yes I think I've talked about Europe, I don't really have very much else to add there. You mention the commodity costs. Well you've heard from me and Malcolm that although commodity costs are volatile, most of our positions are already bought in for this year that we're in, and are hedged therefore. And we don't see dramatic pressure as a result of commodity costs in the coming year. We've talked to low single-digits and that remains our guidance. So there is nothing dramatic going on that we feel that we have to react to through pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you tend to offer what percentage of your costs are hedged, I mean, you say a majority, is that 70%, 80% or even higher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's well over 50%, and if you look at different commodities, some of them we're hedged probably over the 50% level, other we're hedged, if you take some of the items like hops, we're hedged to 100%; malt conversion we're well hedged, close to the 100% level. And I think what everyone is focusing on is the wheat and the barley prices which are substantially up on the prices last year. But if you take into account favorable contracts that we have in things like glass and cans, and also the fact that aluminum prices are at the moment not too dissimilar to prices that we incurred during the course of last year. You can see that when you look at a balance across all of the commodities, how we would get to our low single-digit figures. So we do have some beneficial areas which are offsetting the obvious ones, which I think are obvious to people, where you look at the barley and the wheat prices which look up more than low single-digits. But that's &#x2013; we're looking across the portfolio of packaging raw materials and brewing raw materials, and to a certain extent packaging raw materials are offsetting the brewing raw materials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also our levels of cover are obviously greater, much greater in the near months than they are towards the end of the year. But if you talk about barley inputs, grain inputs, the crops that will be starting to malt for the end of this year are still in the field now. So we don't know what the barley situation will be in the next calendar year which is towards the end of our fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. That's helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Jonathan Fell from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody. Two things. First of all, just with regards to the U.S. and following on from Lauren's question. We've seemed to have been in a situation now where, the comment that hopefully volumes will start to pick up in six to 12 months, that's been the comment for a while now. And given you've said that you can't go on putting prices up and losing share forever, when should we start to worry that as an overall industry trend this becomes unsustainable?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, with regards to Colombia, quite a decent share loss to Aguardiente in the last year. As you look to Colombia to recover this year, does your recovery plan intake &#x2013; involve taking that share back? And is that a purely tax and price thing, or has that sector of the market got more organized in terms of how they brand as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, you know, the U.S., I mean your point is quite valid in the sense that the U.S. has continued to disappoint. The U.S. is very much a story of two halves, well I suppose of 80% and 20%. The bulk of the market, which is premium lights or premium and below is, of course, not looking too perky at all and continues, as I say, to disappoint. But it's very strongly correlated to unemployment amongst key beer drinkers, and that is effectively low level or employment in the lower socio-economic levels in the U.S. and that is not really showing any strong uptick at all. The higher end of the market, crafts and imports, are actually doing fine and those index to wealthier consumers in effect and they're growing very, very strongly.</p>
          <p>So the question really boils down to, well what can be done at premium pricing and below given the unemployment level. And I am sure, I am afraid there is no easy answer to that. I don't think the situation is unsustainable or unlikely to be &#x2013; or likely to be unsustainable. It's just not all that attractive.</p>
          <p>The other point though about all of that, put all that together is that revenue numbers are not too bad in the U.S. so the gap closing tactics and the firm pricing have made volume &#x2013; physical volumes look a bit drab with this minus 3% that we are reporting. Sales revenues are a lot better than that, and I remind you that most markets in most consumer segments, they look at revenues not at underlying volumes. We happen to have a volume measure in beer which is easy to calculate. So yeah, I mean that's about it on the U.S., I'm afraid.</p>
          <p>On Colombia, yes, we have been losing market share to Aguardiente, and that is principally due to pricing. You may know that the 8% increase in price that was passed on to the consumer, although it doesn't appear in our books because it's an add-on tax, it's not an add-in tax. That has affected consumer demand quite dramatically. And in fact, it's undone about four years of price restraint in which we've been trying to get prices in Colombia down to more affordable levels for the populus.</p>
          <p>So the effect has been principally price. There have been other factors as well, of course. I mean, there is quite a lot of &#x2013; has been quite a lot of bringing in of contraband, of beer, principally from Venezuela as a result of the tax being passed. So that's eaten away at the edges, at the margin. And there is also quite a lot of what they call adulterated, unregistered bathtub type Aguardiente in the market which is being sold at very low prices and which has also affected the markets. So it's not just the formal Aguardiente market.</p>
          <p>And in addition, the Aguardiente producers have done something of a better job with new variants, the so-called sugar-free variants and also lower alcohol variants. So if I were to roughly attribute the share loss, it would probably be more 80% or so to purely price relativity and perhaps 20% to Aguardiente putting up a better show of things.</p>
          <p>Many, if not all, of those trends are starting to in our view bottom and look a bit healthier though, so we don't anticipate a continuing bleed in that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Gerard Rijk from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. Three questions, if I may. First one is about the business capability program, concerning the US$296 million exceptional charge; is that, is that full cash or is that not the case? And looking forward for 2012, what I have here in this category is 154 for 2012 and then moving down to around 100 for '13 and '14, is that still in place for those &#x2013; for those exceptional costs, and also cash costs?</p>
          <p>Concerning the fixed &#x2013; the second question is about the fixed cost benefits, you had quite some fixed costs benefits in 2011. Do you have new fixed costs benefits from closures here and there or is that &#x2013; has that finished?</p>
          <p>And the third question is about your interest cost. In your cash flow statement, it's &#x2013; you are paying 150 million more in interest costs on balance, net than in your P&amp;L. What is the &#x2013; what's the difference there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Let me just take &#x2013; take the first and the last one. Under the business capability program, we obviously do have a split between cash and non-cash amounts, which will be shown fully in the detail, but most of that would be cash costs, of that US$296 million. And indication for that, basically in line with what we put out to the market at the interim, that we would be around about this level, decreasing by 15% which would take you down to, let's say, about $180 million next year, down by another 15%, which would take you down to say somewhere around about $120 million, and then a similar amount for the year after so your figures are roughly in the ballpark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as interest cost is concerned, there is obviously amounts that &#x2013; the difference between what we incur in the income statement and when we actually pay some of the interest because of the six month. And also because we closed out some of our debt and we would have paid certain amounts as we closed out the debt, whereas we would have incurred that previously, and we would have shown that in previous balance sheets. So it's not necessarily an exact science but &#x2013; in the cash and the interest shown on the P&amp;L.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the fixed costs level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the fixed cost level, well &#x2013; I think your question was that, what do we intend doing in F '12. And, I mean, obviously we &#x2013; this year we had &#x2013; and we showed fixed cost productivity and the intention is to do the same next year. But again, you need to look at this market-by-market, because it's not a group question.</p>
          <p>In some markets like Africa, where we are expanding our business, fixed cost will definitely go up. But in other markets like Europe where there is a restructuring going on, obviously the intention there is to show fixed cost productivity as it would be in some of the markets in Latin America and, of course, in the United States that we still have a cost program running, which has not yet finished, and we would intend to show more fixed cost savings there.</p>
          <p>So, country-by-country, in those areas where it is part of the strategy, we would be looking to show fixed cost savings, but where the strategy is growth and we see more opportunity for growth and we'd obviously be putting down fixed costs to support that growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Europe, do you have any closure upcoming in Eastern Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we've announced the closures and we've also announced the possible sale of our distribution business in Italy. But there is nothing else that I can report back on now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Jason DeRise from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking the questions. Wondering if, one, you can talk about &#x2013; in the business capabilities program, if you reconfirm the size of that in terms of the benefits, or if you think that because it's maybe going a bit better than expected, maybe the number should be a bit higher than the original $300 million to $350 million that was previously guided as the cost benefit in the P&amp;L?</p>
          <p>Second, in Europe, it's a little surprising that there is so much just kind of considering, if the cost rising excise going up. Do you think that this is sustainable? Have the competitors found a way to make this work, or do you think this is a temporary issue that you'll have to deal with?</p>
          <p>And then lastly, just the view about creating a balanced and attractive global spread. When you say balanced, how are you thinking about that? Does that mean merging versus mature, or is there another way of thinking about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well perhaps, starting with your business capability program, we reconfirm the benefits in November, and what we've said at the moment is that, as far as the guideline for this current year which initially was $50 million in benefits, we brought that back down to $30 million to $40 million at the interims, and we've actually now delivered more than $60 million. So I think we're getting a better feel of the level of benefits as they are coming through.</p>
          <p>As far as working capital benefits are concerned, as you saw, we had expected $350 million by the end of 2012 in aggregate, and we're running well over $100 million ahead of that now and before we get close to the end of 2012. So certainly in working capital benefits, we are ahead.</p>
          <p>As far as operating benefits are concerned, I think that it would be premature to try and guide the market on a six-monthly basis. You know, this is an enormous project right across the group and its multiple projects running at different time periods. And I think the &#x2013; particularly now over the next 12 months, we will be going live, not only with back office in some of our countries, as we've done in South Africa, but we'll be going live also with front office and logistics, and also business process outsourcing.</p>
          <p>So I think the appropriate time to update the market will be, as we go through and we see how that has been implemented during the course of the next six to 12 months, and I would think at this time next year, we would be able to then assist what is a fairly complex and wide-ranging certain projects making up the business capability program. And we would have a better opportunity then to assist those costs against the benefits and update the market. I think what I'm trying to do that on a six-monthly basis is probably at worse, misleading, but at best, misguided.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your question of discounting in Europe, I mean, who knows whether this is long-term sustainable? We're not the people who're doing it. So in a sense, you're talking to the wrong people. But the situation does vary dramatically from market to market. I mean for instance, I mentioned earlier, the bringing down of very high price points in Russia. Now, because those &#x2013; that segment of the market is pretty highly priced. I think that the downward pressure there could go on for a quite a long time without seriously undermining the viability of any individual player in that segment. Although, obviously, it does take margin out of the market as a whole, profit out of the market as a whole, but &#x2013; so one couldn't accuse anyone of behaving unsustainably there.</p>
          <p>I think in Poland, the question is much more relevant, because there what we are seeing is previously mainstream or upper mainstream brands being discounted at &#x2013; right down at bottom levels in the discount segment, and that can't be healthy or encouraging for long-term equity of those brands. I think one has to query how long that could go on.</p>
          <p>However, all of these things always look sort of irremediable or very dire while the storm is going on. And we have to remember that this stuff is going on, we assume, because of the economic conditions and we don't expect the economic conditions that we've seen in Europe to continue forever. So I would have to &#x2013; I do believe that the overall pressure on pricing in Europe should be alleviated slowly over time. But that's more on &#x2013; well, it's entirely on general principle and from any inside knowledge of what's in the head of our competitors.</p>
          <p>As far as balance of portfolio is concerned, yes, you are right. It is between emerging markets and developed markets. And we look for value wherever we can find it. Traditionally, it's been easier to find in emerging markets because there are tailwinds. There is underlying growth and it's easier to extract value growth where there is a rising tide, to change the metaphor. But we do have a balance between emerging and cash and developed markets, and many of the developed markets are very strong cash flow providers. So they have their place as well.</p>
          <p>Jamie &#x2013; let me just ask Jamie whether he wants to add anything on the Europe situation, because Jamie Wilson who is sitting here as our CFO Designate. He is, in fact, also Financial Director of Europe. So he's been intimately involved with these considerations in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Graham. No &#x2013; I mean, I think the points you are making are valid. I mean, I think the Russian point is absolutely correct, in the sense that you've got some quite high prices there and therefore, it's quite sustainable to move them over time into different positions. But you have to be more concerned in the markets like Poland and in Romania where, clearly as you're taking these brand equities down, then you're getting to quite a low margin in some of these products, and therefore it becomes much less sustainable over time. So I would agree with you. I think we have to question how long people will continue to run those prices.</p>
          <p>But the critical thing for us is really to say that the consumer still recognizes the brand equities that we have. And therefore, it's much more in our point of view to actually focus on maintaining the relevance of our brand equities and then encouraging the consumer to follow those rather than necessarily follow-on price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Europe, who do you think the main problem area is? Is it the big global players that we'll be familiar with, or is it local players that are causing the problem?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's both. But I am not prepared to be drawn any further on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The last question comes from Ian Shackleton from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. I've got two that questions really came out of the interviews that I think were posted up first thing. The first one was around marketing spend. I think Malcolm made the point that you expect globally marketing spend, in terms of net sales remained fairly stable in FY '12. Because it's likely that some markets like Africa will be up. I think MillerCoors has also flagged quite an increase for this year. I would just be interested in getting a bit more color around the reasons, because it does sound like there's going to be some quite big ups and possibly some negatives to offset that?</p>
          <p>And the second question then, again, coming out of the interviews, talking about the businesses capability program. It was Graham, I think, in the interview who talked about the ups and downs of the program. I think you've done quite a good job of telling us about some of the ups, where you are ahead, particularly on the procurement project. I just wondered where the downs were.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Ian, first off, your question on marketing is right, but the tendency would be up rather than down. We are expecting the volume growth to reassert itself in some of our markets. And so the &#x2013; much of the increase that we hope would be catered for by revenue would be diluted by revenue increases as well.</p>
          <p>Overall, the tendency would be from marketing expenditures to rise from here, and we would &#x2013; as Leo Kiely often states in &#x2013; or has stated in the U.S., you want to be on the front foot and lean into the market improvements as they happen. So we are watching for that. So the tendency would be up. I don't think it will affect the numbers perceptibly. But certainly, we are looking to improve or to lean forward in turn, upturn.</p>
          <p>On the BCP, you know, I'm not going to get into any great detail, but I think just to say that, of course, we have a very large design-and-build process going on, covering multiple countries, customization from multiple countries and multiple modules of the system. The system consists of a large number of modules, covering a large number of functions in business. And so, as normal in any of these projects, you get some difficulties and some slippages from time-to-time in design-and-build activities, because the eventual product is uncertain until you get there. You never sure that everything is absolutely perfect until you run two or three cycles of testing. So we have had some of those.</p>
          <p>To add to those two issues and to reconcile your views on the marketing spend, that it's &#x2013; that's a forecast which come with all the caveats that forecasts normally come with. The concept we have, as Graham has mentioned is that, generally depending upon market, but around the Group, marketing spend will go up. But we see that justified by the fact that we think volumes will also tick up, and revenues as well. Now, obviously what happens will &#x2013; and so our percentages will stay roughly the same. That's the forecast. We may not see the tick-up in volumes, and therefore our marketing may run slightly ahead.</p>
          <p>But the plan is that, as Graham said, that we will revest our marketing, and the idea is that our volumes and revenues will cover that. So proportionately, from a Group point of view, we will be spending in proportionate terms the same amount, but it really depends on what happens in the volumes and revenue during the course of the year. And as far as the business capability program is concerned, as I said few moments ago, it's very difficult to give an update almost on a six-monthly basis on such a wide-ranging and complex program with multiple projects right around the Group.</p>
          <p>And, of course, we have had areas where our first go-live in South Africa resulted in a lot of post-go-live support. I suppose one could call that a down where, as we spend more time, efforts and money in making sure after we went live that everything worked according to plan. And we spent more time and resource than we had anticipated, but from that, I think the other side of the coin is that we learned a lot from that. And there is a specific program to take those learnings forward into the next release. And that's the way we're planning this, that; A, we don't expect this to be absolutely zero-fault implementation, but we expect our people to learn quickly from that. And as we start implementing more releases, we should learn a lot from that. So that the later stage or the latter stages of the releases into different countries go a lot more smoothly than the first ones did and I think that is common with just about every project. So there will be ups and downs during the period. We just hope there are more ups than downs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I come from an IT background and I have never heard of a perfect project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>