<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1227461" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>59558</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Alfredo S&#xE1;enz Abad, Second Vice Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jos&#xE9; Antonio &#xC1;lvarez, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Fernando de As&#xFA;a &#xC1;lvarez, First Vice Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3">Santiago Lopez</participant>
      <participant id="4">Antonio Ramirez</participant>
      <participant id="5">Carlos Berastain</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="7">Eva Hernandez</participant>
      <participant id="8">Daragh Quinn</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jeff Dawes</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jernej Omahen</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first section of this results presentation, I will speak about the fundamentals of the quarter and I will review the Group's results.  Then Jos&#xE9; Antonio Alvarez, our CFO will analyze the evolution of the different business areas in more details.  And finally, I will conclude with some conclusions about the semester and also our priorities for the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>And the first point I'd like to make is that the Santander Group has once again had an excellent quarter in an environment which is still difficult.  As I explained at other times, this is a great acid test for distinguishing the good and well managed banks from the rest.  And so in the second quarter the Santander model continues to demonstrate its strengths, because of the consistency of its results, strongly supported by the evolution of our business areas, and with results which reflect our management priorities.</p>
          <p>Mixed management, very strong cost discipline, large provisions in accordance with the point in the economic cycle and very active risk management, both in terms of anticipation and also of recovery; second, because of the strength of our balance sheet.  Credit quality, which is better than that of our competitors, large provisions, solid solvency ratios and ability to generate capital and to continue to pay dividends.  I'd like to look at each of these points in turn.</p>
          <p>First of all the consistency of our results; we've ended the quarter with ordinary profit of 2.7 billion euros, which is 4% less than the same quarter last year but it's 17% more than in the first quarter of 2009, and this way we reach a profit of 4.674 billion, which is 9% higher than the second semester of the previous year.  And these are all ordinary recurrent revenues.  They do not reflect the impact of any extraordinary revenue derived from the latest sales or those underway.  The sale of the Banco de Venezuela and the Cepsa stake did not contribute any capital gains, and the exchange of preferred shares that are still underway and the results will be incorporated in the third quarter.  As for the capital gains obtained from the VisaNet IPO in Brazil, all of them have been assigned for anticipating write downs and so had no impact on profits either.</p>
          <p>And this evolution is better if we look only at business units which are up 17% in this second quarter versus the second quarter of the previous year, in part of course benefiting from the increased <mark type="inaudible" />.  There are some points however which spoil, so to speak, the business performance and prevent it from being fully reflective in the Group's profits.  Principally they are the reduced income because of the use of the equity accounting method, smaller dividend volumes received and lower gains on financial transactions at the corporate center, which Jos&#xE9; Antonio Alvarez will discuss later.</p>
          <p>Going back to the operating areas; in this slide you can see the full details.  I should underscore first of all the considerable diversification of our businesses, which confirms the resilience of our units to the cycle.  By geographic areas, the retail units of continental Europe has maintained fairly stable results.  The two Spanish and Portuguese units have increased their recurring profits over the first half of 2008.  The worst performance was that of Santander Consumer Finance.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., this semester once again confirms the sustainability of our business, albeit still growing strongly to which we now add the positive contribution of Alliance &amp; Leicester and Bradford &amp; Bingley.</p>
          <p>Latin America was very hard hit by the impact of exchange rates versus the dollar, but in constant exchange rate terms, Brazil's trend in the last few quarters has been clearly growing and its second quarter profit was 25 higher than that of same period of 2008.  The rest of Latin America is basically stable, and it reflects the negative impact on our exit from Venezuela which has contributed no results to the semester.</p>
          <p>Finally, I will also underline the excellent results shown in these last semesters by Global Wholesale Banking, where we have been taking advantage of the market situation and the gap left by other competitors, while maintaining strict risk liquidity and capital management as our CFO will discuss later.</p>
          <p>Going back to our income statement, I'd like to clarify a point to start with.  As we did in the first quarter, the first column of changes is the purely accounting one, and therefore reflects the favorable perimeter impact and the negative impact of exchange rates.  That's why we have included a second column without the perimeter increase or the exchange rate impact in order to facilitate the analysis of the underlying performance.</p>
          <p>Additionally, the results obtained from the VisaNet IPO have had no impact on profits since we have established provisions for the same amount.  To facilitate the analysis of the account, they are not included in the different lines of the income statement but below in the area of write-downs and extraordinary provisions.  These capital gains of 262 million euros correspond to the sale of our initial 5.67% stake.  There's an additional tranche which was closed in July and which will bring in another 272 million reals or about 95 million euro, which will also be allocated to provisions.  The income statement continues to reflect the economic recession and also the management priorities.</p>
          <p>The first, very active management of spreads and loans reflected by growing net interest income offsetting a worse performance of fee income more affected by reduced activity volumes. Second, strong cost discipline; costs have been growing at almost zero or negative rates in every unit. These costs are beginning to benefit from the first synergies derived from the integrations underway. As a consequence of the evolution of costs and revenues, our cost to income ratio has been growing, and as has our net operating &#x2013; our efficiency ratios, at rates at close to 20%. Thirdly, active risk and recovery management, which is beginning to show some positive signs although there's still a strong increase versus the first semester 2008.</p>
          <p>In summary, the net operating income after provisions was 4.3% higher, which compares very favorably with the first quarter. If we compare these changes with those we reported in the first quarter, we see that things are improving in almost every line. Basic revenues remain strong, overall growing at 10% still. Costs are still dropping. We have moved from almost 2% growth in the first quarter to almost zero in the first half of the year. Provisions continue to rise strongly year-on-year, but at a lower speed; and as a result our net income, our net operating income after provisions, which dropped slightly in the first quarter, has now grown by 4.3%, as I just reported.</p>
          <p>Let's now look at each of the main lines of the income statement. First I'll speak about the solidness of our most commercial revenues, that is, our net interest income without dividends and our fee income.</p>
          <p>Fee income has been harder hit in some of its lines by circumstances in the environment and also by our recruitment strategies, especially those related to securities, the mutual funds, while net interest income is still performing strongly.  Looking ahead, it is reasonable to assume that this current trend will slow down with lower growth in net interest income but with slightly better performance of fee income.</p>
          <p>If we look at the different areas in the slide, the bottom half of the slide, you can see how even in this very stressful scenario of the last quarter, Europe and the U.K. have continued to show growth as has Latin America if we subtract the exchange rate impact.</p>
          <p>Focusing on net interest income, it has risen by 24% or 18% if we don't take into account the perimeter effect or the exchange rate effect and this reflects our successful management of spreads and volumes and prices. We have improved our spreads on loans very significantly in recent quarters in order to offset the fall of spreads on deposits.</p>
          <p>In volumes, both loans and deposits demonstrate the Group's management priorities and the needs of the environment. Excluding acquisitions, lending rose by 3%, lower growth than in previous quarters due to the economic downturn and of course also due to the demand in each market.</p>
          <p>In Spain, growth has been flat for last 12 months. In the U.K. we have grown 4% without taking into account the new companies. And in Latin America, Brazil is still showing double-digit growth, while in Mexico, lending dropped by 6%.</p>
          <p>As for customer funds, we are still focused on deposits which have grown by 19% in terms of organic growth. If we include acquisitions, growth rates are much higher, 16% for lending and 36% for deposits. And we have improved by 17 percentage points the ratio of loan financed from deposits in the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>So in summary, our combination of price, volume and liquidity strategies are being successful throughout the Group and as a result most of our units, especially our large units, have shown significant increases in their net interest income, as you can see on the right-hand side of the slide.</p>
          <p>Mexico's drop is due to the deep recession in the country and also to our own deliberate policy to change our mix towards lower risk products in the last quarters.</p>
          <p>Chile repeats because its performance has been significantly hit by drop in inflation rate and its impact on U.S. index portfolios since net interest income has grown very successfully, double-digit growth. In any case the trend is clearly better than that of the first quarter where total net interest income dropped by 7%.</p>
          <p>The second basic pillar behind these results is sustained efficiency improvement in an environment with less growth. Stricter cost management is a priority and in this sense our total costs, deducting perimeter and exchange rate effects, have been basically flat with respect to the first half of 2008, only rising by 0.3%. This is a result, on the one hand, of our usual cost containment approach but also we're benefiting from the first synergies of the various integrations.</p>
          <p>We are optimistic about attaining, or in fact exceeding, the initial forecast we had made for 2009.  As you can see in the slide on the right-hand side, cost savings are going very well in the U.K., Germany, and especially Brazil. Also in Sovereign we have also seen that it will be possible to achieve savings in the year exceeding the 100 million that we had initially envisaged. This performance is reflected in the good progress made by all our units whose costs are registering zero growth or in fact decreasing, as in Brazil's case. Thus we maintain our efficiency improvement track record. Our Group's ratio is at 41.6% and all our large business areas have improved significantly.</p>
          <p>I'd like to underscore that Sovereign has really been incorporated last quarter with cost income ratio of 74.5%, which we have brought down in the first half of the year to 66%. These were Abbey's levels at the time of the acquisition and today Abbey is already at 41%.  Excluding the recent acquisitions, our cost/income ratio would be below 40%.</p>
          <p>Third point I would like to discuss is provisions.  The faster deterioration of the macroeconomic environment in every country has hit our credit quality and has pushed up loan loss provisions.  In the second quarter, they were 51% higher than in the same period 2008.  In like-to-like it would be 32% if we did not take into account the perimeter effect.</p>
          <p>As you can see on the right-hand side of the slide we should stress that in the last few quarters there has been a decline in specific provisions.  In fact in the second quarter 2009 these were 2% lower than in Q1.  The opposite has occurred with generic provisions since in Q2 we have recovered less at the Group level than in Q1.  This was due to the gap between releases in Spain which as we will see later were similar to those of Q1 and also lower recoveries or in some cases provisions for other units such as the U.K., Germany, or Sovereign.</p>
          <p>Beginning with the chart on the left for specific provisions, there's no change with respect to previous quarters.  The increase was slow across the board particularly in Spain both for our retail networks and for consumer finance.  There is currently a change due to our increased perimeter which is reflected in Europe consumer finance in the U.K. and Sovereign.</p>
          <p>As for generic provisions we have released in the first half of the year the Group level &#x20AC;601 million most of which 431 in Spain both through our retail network and our Global Banking &amp; Markets business.  This figure is in line with our targets for the year which we had reported in previous quarters.</p>
          <p>After the provisions of the previous quarter, we have a total loan loss provision of 15.7 billion after rising by 600 million in Q2.  Of these, 6.16 billion were generic.  That's the breakdown you see in this slide.  For Spain we have &#x20AC;3 billion after using up 431 million in Q2 which is basically the same as the 406 million we used in Q1.  This decline is not reflected in the Group's total because of the additional provisions made in other units and from a favorable impact on a generic fund from the evolution of exchange rates in Q2.</p>
          <p>As for the recent changes in provision requirements by the Bank of Spain, they've had a positive impact of &#x20AC;217million for their group in the mortgage area which we have allocated to anticipate specific provisions.  As for consumer lending, changes do not involve provisions since we were already completely covered.</p>
          <p>Our Group's NPL ratios have risen as you can see in this slide but in any case they're still good if we consider the current environment.  Our Group's NPL ratio is at 2.82% and coverage is at 72%.  And if we look at the different business areas, the NPL ratio for all the businesses in Spain that is Santander, Banesto, Consumer Finance, etcetera, was at 2.7%. Abbey is at 1.5%, lower because of the higher mortgage component which also means lower coverage; and Latin America is at 3.97% with a coverage of almost 100%.</p>
          <p>How do these ratios compare with those of our competitors'?  As we have done on previous quarters, we compare very well at the Group level but also in each and every one of the geographies and business areas where we operate &#x2013; Spain, the U.K. and Latin America.  In all of them the Group compares very well with its peers and in fact the gap has widened in the recent quarters especially in Spain and the U.K.</p>
          <p>The second component of the strength of our balance sheet is capital.  We have ended the second quarter with a core capital ratio of 7.5% calculated in accordance with Basel II criteria.  It's a ratio that we feel very comfortable with.  In the quarter, we have improved the ratio by 20 basis points and we are still generating free capital in an environment of reduced growth in Risk Weighted Assets.</p>
          <p>To end this first section, I will make some comments about the exchange offer for shares, its operation which is part of our desire to manage our capital efficiently and strengthen our balance sheet.  With the new issues we maintain the capital ratios and the capital gains generated will be used to reinforce our generic provisions.  We don't yet know what the final result of the exchange will be, although so far I can say it has gone very well.</p>
          <p>Today we have <mark type="inaudible" /> exchanged in Europe and the U.K., 54% participation that is 3.1 billion of the 5.7 billion of it with gains of &#x20AC;555 million.  In the U.S. the offer's underway and we expect the final results in August.  In any case, our expectations given the type of issue are for substantially lower acceptance level than that we've had in Europe.</p>
          <p>And now, I'm going to give the floor to Jos&#xE9; Antonio &#xC1;lvarez, who will explain the different business areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  As usual, I will speak first about the main areas, the geographies, the corporate headquarters, and then I will review our Global Banking &amp; Markets and asset management and insurance businesses. I'll also give you some comments specifically about Sovereign and its performance in this Q2, our first full quarter after integration.</p>
          <p>In Continental Europe, our attributable profit was &#x20AC;2.66 billion, 13% more than in the first half 2008.  So with or without the perimeter, the growth has been similar although in terms of gross income, because of the incorporation of the units to Santander Consumer Finance basically.  So the top part of the income statement has changed slightly but at the bottom the difference is very minor.</p>
          <p>We see consistent income generation, double-digit growth, extraordinary given the current environment.  Costs flat; so our net operating income has risen by 18% which, after including provisions, gives us a net operating income after provisions of 15%.  You can see that net operating income retail banking has registered sustained growth in the last few quarters and attributable profit has behaved consistently.  Also, as I will explain later, our Global Banking &amp; Markets area has performed excellently.</p>
          <p>Going down to the four large units in Continental Europe, here you can see the three regional banking units &#x2013; Santander, Banesto, and Portugal branch networks with similar performance, revenues growing, net operating income growing well, fee income growing more slowly.  Good cost control which has enabled our net operating income to grow and after provisions and excluding extraordinary provisions, we have between 3% in Portugal and 9% in Banesto.</p>
          <p>Santander Consumer Finance grew strongly, but there have been higher provisions.  In Santander Consumer Finance, there is a different performance by country, very successful performance in Germany and drive in the U.S. &#x2013; in Germany 185 million in profits, in Spain rather weaker.  And then finally global banking markets in Europe have doubled their attributable profit in comparison with assets of first half of 2008 with excellent performance in this semester.</p>
          <p>Looking at the different units, the performances are similar, slow growth in lending, very significant growth in deposits accompanied by improving spreads in lending which I think is behind the income levels we have seen.</p>
          <p>As for risk management, as we have explained in Q1 and in the AGM they have behaved better than expected on the risk side with asset recoveries and slowing default ratios 30% below what we had seen in previous quarters.  And so in this context with rising spreads, flood costs and improved recoveries we have been able to generate significant income.</p>
          <p>I won't dwell on Banesto's results since those have already been reported.  I'd say the underlying aspects are the same as discussed. Voluntary provisions have risen significantly but you all know what the performance was throughout the quarter.  As for Santander Consumer Finance, here we do have a significant change through perimeter effect because of the GE and Royal Bank of Scotland business in Germany.  It helps in the operating lines of the income statement but not so much on profits for the contribution's still small.</p>
          <p>As a consequence of that, we had strong growth in volume, improving spreads, which is basic in this business.  The elasticity of when rates rise or drop is less than one, so your spreads improve consistently quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>Costs are flat excluding the perimeter effects, so good cost control.  And we are focusing on our core units, so there are some discontinuities in certain businesses in smaller markets like Hungary or the Czech Republic.  Provisions are still growing strongly.  We said in February when we reported the results for 2008 that we expected an NPL ratio of between 5.5 and 6% for the unit by the end of 2009, and we still expect to be at that level by the end of the year and the trend is on line with that.</p>
          <p>As for results in this unit, probably we are at the lowest or worst point for a comparison because the second quarter last year was the best one in the year, especially in Germany, and so the quarter-on-quarter comparison will improve towards the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Finally Portugal, I think <mark type="inaudible" /> Spanish retail units; a little bit more growth in volume with significant changes in the mix where basically there has been a term transfer of mutual funds to deposit, costs remaining flat.  There are greater provisions because of economic cycle, although the figure for the quarter is not the bank rate -- that would be a little bit lower, good cost discipline and it is in line with the expectations as &#x2013; that we had mentioned earlier.</p>
          <p>If you look at the second geographical area, the U.K., I think figures speak for themselves, very high rate and growth rates at constant perimeter as well as with the change in the perimeter.  Without perimeter, the Abbey has an excellent performance, gross income 30%, and then after provisions there is an increase in provisions that grow at 33%, the attributable profit, to that we can add the <mark type="inaudible" /> which also adds to the profits.</p>
          <p>If we look at it in further details on the right-hand side, we see that Retail Banking is consistently showing better results to which we can add a good, and this is constant in all geographies, a good performance of Wholesale Banking, which adds to the earnings.  Cost control allows us to keep the spread rising at almost 50%, in other words a net operating income.</p>
          <p>But the most important thing in the U.K. is the sustainability of the results and their consistency.  Why?  Well, here we can give some indications of why we see the sustainability.  I would say that the first reason is the strong asset spread improvements, which is improving quarter-to-quarter.  Improvements in terms of new production as well as in the retention of mortgages combined with good active management of deposits, and then costs.</p>
          <p>The draws are very big and number three, and very important, we have very good credit quality as our CEO mentioned, and this is something that the market is requiring less provisions because we have very little exposure to the riskier mortgage market segments.</p>
          <p>When it comes to business turnover volumes I think it reflects very well the priorities that we have pointed out. On the one hand we have a production of mortgages, globally speaking growing at 1%. Excellent performance of deposits, not only because of the change of perimeter, deposits in NAV are growing at 17%, in A&amp;L 9%, loans to companies are not growing very much, and at the bottom we see some of the things we mentioned. The securities portfolio of P&amp;L continues to fall, and this is something that we had announced, and we will continue to reduce it and the UPL business, which for return reasons we have been reducing, so in A&amp;L as well as the one that came from NAV. So that continues to fall at about 22% on and off.</p>
          <p>Also the change in the brand, unifying under the Santander brand, and that will be another milestone in the consolidation process of our franchise in the U.K., so therefore very good performance of the U.K. business, and good prospects for the future, thanks to the re-pricing and improvement of spread, particularly on the side of assets.</p>
          <p>And Latin America we presented in the previous presentation, the figures in dollars. The capital gains of the IPO that doesn't have an impact on the group's results, that has been neutralized as the CEO mentioned. So let me just refer with the part without exchange rate, where our net operating income is growing at 24% and costs declining at 2%. This is thanks to the Brazil integration process that the CEO mentioned also that we were getting ahead of our plans and strict cost control in the other units which are reaching levels of flat costs. Remember that costs were growing at two digits in the past.</p>
          <p>And then there's another thing that we should point out which is that we deconsolidated Venezuela, therefore the attributable profit in constant dollars of $2,204 is the best result in the last eight quarters. And the high impact of exchange rate means that the figures are distorted in the different units as we can see on the left-hand side.</p>
          <p>But if we take a look at the next level, the units, I'd like to mention the significant improvement in Brazil. I reminded you that in the former quarter we were talking about zero growth in constant dollars. We also pointed out that the comparison was not favorable and we will see this later on, we see that Brazil is improving, revenue is growing 15%, mean operating income is growing at 20%.</p>
          <p>Mexico, the situation in Mexico is difficult. The economy is going down, revenues remain flat, costs are also flat and a greater demand for provisions is also something that is affecting us there.</p>
          <p>In Chile we had the negative impact of the USE but nevertheless the generation of results is reaching almost 9%.</p>
          <p>And there's good performance in the other units, Argentina, Uruguay, Puerto Rico, Peru and the New York office which is included here.</p>
          <p>If we look at the Brazilian unit which represents about half of our Latin American business, it has made profit in the quarter, 1.28 billion. Revenue is growing at 15%; costs continue to fall at 3.3%. So we're getting near net interest income of 30%. So a 12% improvement as compared to last year. On the right hand side I'd like to mention the flattening of the net operating income is because, well cost is growing at 6% as well as net interest fell. Net interest income plus income 6% more than in the first quarter and costs are 1% lower. So the trend is very good and this allows us to be very optimistic regarding the objective of getting profits of more than 20%.</p>
          <p>What are the drivers here? Still good growth of volume, not so much in the past few months where the growth of volumes is weaker. The credit spreads in an environment of lower interest rates is the main driver together with cost management where we have negative costs. Provisions continue to grow. Here there are two components. A little bit area of growth of NPLs and the effect of homogenization of criteria after the integration.</p>
          <p>But just to add a few comments on the integration in Brazil. We've already unified the central services in many of the global areas. We've improved the services and operations and therefore customers can do basic operations in both banks as if it were a single bank. Also in the second quarter we did the legal merger of the two banks that was completed.</p>
          <p>With regards to Mexico the situation is very difficult because of the economy. The attributable profit for the first half of the year was 307 million which compares badly with the same period of 2008. Basically because of the credit card business which is falling at more than 20%. And it also affects the credit spread because credit cards have high spreads. And this is due to the mix effect together with the credit card business. Costs are converging to zero.</p>
          <p>The NPL rate in credit cards and recoveries in credit cards are showing a certain improvement. This is one of the keys for the future, the performance of this business which requires about 80 to 85% of provisions in the Mexican unit. So this stabilization is very encouraging for the future.</p>
          <p>In the case of Chile, 343 million of attributable profit in the first half of the year, obtaining 185 million in the second quarter which was better than the first quarter, 17% better. Inflation continues to have a negative impact on our net interest income. This is offset by trading gains. Inflation was negative in the second quarter. Not as negative as in the first quarter, good cost control with jump of 17 points, therefore there's an improvement of the cost to income ratio. Higher provisions, we have set up a new unit for recoveries, similar to what we've done in Spain, so we think this will give us results in the future. So the lower part of the account reaches a double-digit growth.</p>
          <p>Finally, to finish with the main areas, in corporate activities the second quarter is comparable to the first, and the first half of this year is comparable to the first half of last year. The first quarter is very similar to the second quarter with the exception of the charge of Metrovacesa which is what explains the difference between the first and the second quarter. And there you see the main items which explain basic differences between the first half and the second half of 2008.  Basically it's the items that you see there. There's the breakdown there of this effect.</p>
          <p>If we look at the secondary segment and if I focus now on the two areas which I think require further explanation, we have Wholesale Banking and the insurance business, and Global Wholesale Banking. Exceptional results, because of good management of the opportunity offered by the market. We have been gaining market share, improving our spreads without making intensive use our balance sheet as we will see later. Therefore we have sustainable growth quarter-to-quarter, which stems from the different components.</p>
          <p>If we now look on the side of our revenue, most of the revenue is from customers. What type of revenue is it? On the right-hand side we see traditional corporate banking growing at rates of 34%.  This is basic financing, trade, trade finance cash management. The second area which is doing quite well is the selling of derivatives, growing 64%. Weaker is equity securities, although the second quarter has shown a significant improvement as compared to the first quarter.  Therefore a business focused on customers, on traditional products where the core market, 80% basically of the revenue, is generated in Spain, Brazil and the U.K., which is where we have our full commercial franchises.</p>
          <p>The drivers, I mentioned them earlier, on the one hand market share. The intensity of competition is lower now so this has allowed us to gain market share and we have also been profiting from higher spreads. That's on the top part of the account. On the other hand this is combined with excellent cost management. There's been an adjustment in the structure which means that the costs are falling as compared to last year by 15%, 13% as compared to the first half of 2008. So this acts as a lever and gives us an operational leverage which helps us generate results.</p>
          <p>And finally we have a commitment with capital discipline and <mark type="inaudible" /> the level of provisions is low. There is more revenue. Risk assets have remained basically flat and this has not required more liquidity requirement, so excellent performance of the unit with an underlying quality which is very good in revenue as well as in cost management, as well as excellent credit quality.</p>
          <p>Finally, asset management and insurance. The area still represents about 9% of the Group's total revenue. We see that the generation of results, as a whole is basically stable, although there are two underlying realities. On the one hand we have asset management where volumes under management have fallen by 130 million, they reached their minimum level of 100 million and then they started to go up again. Good cost management with a fall of 17%, but this has not been enough to offset the fall of revenue.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, when it comes to the insurance business, the performance is more favorable with significant growth in Brazil, Germany, the U.K. and that fall in Spain because last year we sold many saving insurance products that we have not sold this year.</p>
          <p>Finally, a few words about Sovereign. The result is 10 million negative, 25 in the previous semester. Therefore we still think that we can generate a result of zero for the whole year.</p>
          <p>And if we look at the underlying trends, we see that revenue is growing at 9%, costs are falling by 11%, this was also mentioned by the CEO, we're going to save more than 100 million in costs this year.  And the net operating income is growing by 66%, greater provisions, provisions for loan losses has increased and the loan-loss provisions already represent about 3% of our Sovereign portfolio.</p>
          <p>Here we see the performance. We see the loan portfolio and that reflects two realities, our priorities and a weak market environment. Our priorities, well, we defined when we made the acquisition, that there were some businesses that we did not consider to be core and therefore we discontinued the activity in those segments. In some cases, it's segments, so the portfolio has fallen, the loan portfolio &#x2013; up to 20% from the moment we made the acquisition. So weak demand together with being more selective in our lending in the current environment in the United States means &#x2013; that explains that fall in the loan portfolio.</p>
          <p>On the deposit side I would say more or less the same thing. On the one hand we're doing a repricing of deposits and we see very good trends, a fall of institutional deposits, which are expensive, of about 20%, and significant growth in side deposits which are growing at 10.6%. So this is something that we saw in previous trends and therefore this will be translated into greater capacity to generate margins or spreads and therefore we will see a gradual improvement in the results.</p>
          <p>As compared to December well we can say that Sovereign is in a very good liquidity situation which will allow us to develop the policy in the future which we think are most appropriate once given the situation of the market. So now I'd like to hand over to the CEO so that he can give the conclusions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to finish by giving you a summary of the presentation. In this context which I don't need to remind you, is very difficult, in 2009 we have obtained recurrent profit of 2.423 billion in the second quarter. In the first half of the year we have obtained a recurring profit of 4.519 billion without extraordinary income.</p>
          <p>All the extraordinary income achieved so far has been used to strengthen our balance sheet.  With a solid net operating income that multiplied it by 2.5 times the provisions made. And among other reasons due to our diversification, the U.K., Global Banking and Markets, Brazil are being the main drivers of our earnings.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, we increase our advantage over our peers in credit quality. We have more than EUR6 billion in generic funds and in the second quarter we have generated capital to raise our core capital up to 7.5% and that's been also very positive. We are surpassing the targets with <mark type="inaudible" /> synergies in the integration already underway.  In short, sometimes they show it in the first half of the year a sustainability of its earnings based on the strength of its business model.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to the second half of the year we will continue to focus on the traditional pillars of our model.  In revenues using all the levers that can allow us to improve our revenue spreads, product mix, fees and commissions that will allow us to offset the environment of foreseeable lower spreads and volumes, we will maintain the emphasis on cost management and on the job and of course on obtaining integration synergies.</p>
          <p>We will be very demanding in our integration of the new units to accelerate their contribution to the business, and now we're on the first phases of this integration and we have not yet reached the level of profits that we expect from them but they're doing very well.  Brazil, the U.K. and Germany, and we are also managing the first phases of integration in Sovereign where everything is going according to schedule.</p>
          <p>Another important point is that we remain very much focused on risk management in order to reduce entries and extract value from the Recoveries business, and as always we will remain very disciplined in the use of liquidity and capital.  Well for all these reasons we feel very optimistic about the future.  We think the second half of the year will be very good and we're convinced that we can achieve our goals that we have announced for the year.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Who is this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  We're going to start with the questions we received over the web, and as we did on the previous case we will do it by areas.  On strategy, that would be the first subject because we are going to divide the questions into subjects.  Regarding strategy, Alafora Medes Carlos Ameda Farastine from Deutsche Netherlands is from Morgan Stanley, and others asked about the possible IPO in Brazil.  What would be the rationale for doing it?  What would be the percentages?  It's going to be an increase or a sale?  If you're going to issue new shares, strategies regarding this transaction in the country?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to place 15%, and these are going to be new shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second subject is on the financial area.  Santiago Lopez from Credit Suisse asks why the fall of equity reserves that have fallen by 4.6 billion in the first half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's the other way around.  I think there are less negative adjustments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from BBVA asks about the tax rate.  If it's lower than in other quarters, why is that?  And what do you think is going to happen in the future with the tax rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The tax rate is about 20%.  It's always been 20, 22, 23% and I think it's a sustainable rate.  There is no change there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Antonio Ramirez from Keefe asks two questions.  One is about the breakdown at the level of the consolidated group in the income statement of the 510 million in negative provisions, and can we elaborate a bit more on the ALCO portfolio with maturities, yields, contributions and details for the U.K. and other relevant portfolios?</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>America, 362 million; Europe, 88.  The European part is basically the 70 million that Banesto explained in its earnings announcement.  America 102 million; 366 is Brazil in line with other quarters this is quite recurrent, and another 49 which is basically for the appraisal of real estate and other things but this is the main one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Carlos Berastain from Deutsche Bank asks about the interest margin, interest spread in Mexico.  Do you think it will lose the momentum in the second half of the year?  And why the net operating income is lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well the first part...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...will slow down because here we see an adjustment impact because of the repricing of the assets at market rates where the strong fall of interest rates, the repricing, there's a lag and this will be noticed in future quarters.  So my first answer is yes, a clear yes.  And most probably this will also have been in Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second part of the question was on the performance of the net interest income in the corporate center. Why this impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the former question I forgot to answer about the ALCO because that was one of the questions that I didn't answer.  The management of interest rate risk depends on the currency. Where we are more active in having portfolios to manage the interest rate risk is in those markets where we have a volume of core deposits, significant ones.  These markets are basically Mexico where we have a portfolio of about 6, $7 million of Mexican public funds to control the interest rate risk.  And the other part of the world where we're active is Europe, basically Spain where Banesto already gave its details, and in the corporate center we have a portfolio I think it's &#x20AC;12 or 13 billion with a duration of basically three years.  With a yield -- well it has certain capital gains. Right now the mark-to-market has certain capital gains of a few hundred million and that is where we're very active.</p>
          <p>There are other portfolios available for sale.  The Alliance &amp; Leicester portfolio is available for sale but it doesn't have an interest rate risk function.  In the U.K. we don't have ALCO portfolio because the commercial dynamics make them unnecessary and also Sovereign had a certain portfolio which is classified there, although as we mentioned during the previous presentation of Sovereign it was short in interest rates. So it had a very low portfolio back then.  Those portfolios in the case of the parent company, its contribution is at the corporate center and this explains in part that performance of the net interest income in the corporate center.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question from <mark type="inaudible" /> JP on the goodwill.  What about the goodwill?  Why these variations?  And <mark type="inaudible" /> from Morgan Stanley asks about a transfer of assets to the ICC unit or similar movement in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We haven't transferred anything to AFS. Although I have to say because during the Banesto presentation I said that Banesto had that two billion as a maturity portfolio, we don't have any portfolio at maturity. At the consolidated level we don't classify it that way, and therefore there is no transfer between trading and available for sale, and they aren't in any of these portfolios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then credit quality and risks. Eva Hernandez from Morgan Stanley asks about the new NPLs. What about those 5.2 billion more compared with 4.5 in the past? Can you break these down and can you say why they've gone up, and how do you think this will perform in the future, and the impact of Sovereign and GE in the first half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The first comment is why there's been that gap I guess between the last quarter of last year and the first this year, right? That's because of the Sovereign incorporation, and also the General Electric incorporation, so there's obviously a perimeter effect, and if I'm not mistaken that's in the quarterly report with a footnote that says there's a gap or a difference, which is it says 4.5 billion in the Q3 2008 and first quarter of 2009 and there's an asterisk which says it's been a incorporation of GE and Sovereign and then it drops again in Q3. So really in the 5.2 billion of the second semester, which is I think this comparison with the 4.5 of Q4 in this 5.2. There's a reduction of 1.3 billion with respect to the previous quarter, but that already includes Sovereign and GE. So it's not really a rise, it's actually a drop in relative terms. There's an increase of one billion, just under, 800 million really, but of course first there had been a one billion rise because of that integration. And as for the breakdown, what you asked me for, I guess it was constant perimeter, right, what would be the breakdown? I don't have it to hand of course. I don't know if you do?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay there's a slightly more general question about where we expect NPL rates to be concentrated in the future and where we expect to see worsening NPL rates in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think we've already given you that it's pretty focused in Spain, and in Spain we've already given you an overview of what we expect for 2009 which is we expect to be at 3.5%. A quarter ago or two quarters ago, we spoke about 4.5 in January, now we're talking more about 3.5 and we trust and hope that this is definitely our forecast and we can confirm it. But of course in the next quarter we'll be able to be more specific, but we don't really see anything that might move us away from the trend that we announced in previous quarters and in this quarter the highest ratios are obviously in Spain and some geographies like Mexico, relative trends, but everything else we really don't see anything worth mentioning anything really different in the growth rates NPLs. We spoke also I think last quarter and we confirmed that idea that in the U.K. we would finish the year with an NPL rate of about 2% and we ratify it now, so there really isn't any change in Santander Consumer Finance which might be a question implicit in that general question. We still confirm that we'll be about between 5 and 6% by the end of the year. So same thing we said in the previous quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There are three analysts, Antonio Ramirez, Ignacio and Eva Hernandez who asked for an update in real estate &#x2013; assets, accumulated stock provisions and so on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Our real estate assets, same level, 4.1 billion more or less, same number as in the previous quarter. We already said in the previous quarter that the policy that we began a year or a year-and-a-half ago was to keep an eye out and it made sense at a certain point, but didn't really sort of at the same level. That policy is the same, it hasn't changed. We provisioned when we include it, 10% and then we will have valuations and an update to the market if necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Daragh Quinn from Nomura is asking about the situation in Brazil, looking at how we're going back to a clear growth of the economy after some doubts in previous quarters. Do we think that the NPL rates have reached their peak in that country? And the second question they're asking is about the new Bank of Spain requirements for provisions and whether we expect any impacts in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I guess we'd still have to wait a little bit to ask that, to answer that first question. I don't think there will be substantial increases in Brazil but we'll have to wait and see what happens to the Brazilian economy. But we are seeing positive signs of growth. And as for provisions, in our numbers, the figures are not very significant. We already said earlier that it's maybe 250, which has been used to anticipate specific provisions based on the criteria used by our risk analysts, but of course for the future we don't think that, that's going to have any sort of important significant impact on our numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a question from Daur Ramirez from UBS about where we expect the coverage ratio to be by the end of this year, 2009 and also our forecast for 2010? And there's some other analysts who are asking something that's already been answered, as for our NPL rate forecast and whether we expect flat cost growths? So I guess the only new question is about the coverage really. And as for, well Himeres Havil from Netbrand is asking about recoveries and whether we could be more specific about how we've managed to increase that recovery percentage in the quarter? And what efforts are we making?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that sort of would be telling, wouldn't it? But in general what we've done is to implement a priority in which we have prioritized recovery over other business aspects. We have involved our whole retail network, all of our branches and that in an organization like ours, which is very efficient in complying with the objectives that have been set gives us recovery percentages which were much higher than those we had before we made this first recommendation, and that's why.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dominico Santaro from BMP is asking us to elaborate a little more about the investment banking environment, and about the evolution for the second semester of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our wholesale and markets business is not really investment banking at all. It's more retail banking with large customers. It's just not at all the same thing, and in fact we emphasize several ideas related to this a lot. The business model is again a retail banking model. Basically the traditional business &#x2013; basically a traditional &#x2013; with our customers, first of all. In fact the majority of the revenues are derived from customer activity, and secondly 80% of these are within our footprint, so where we have banks, not in areas where we don't have a bank. So they originate in Brazil and Mexico and Spain and the U.K., and that's another defining characteristic of ours and our business model. Thirdly, these growth rates we have had as Jos&#xE9; Antonio &#xC1;lvarez explained, when we were talking about wholesale and markets, and without reducing the Group's liquidity, which is really important too; and all that means basically that this growth has been the result of increasing spreads, also commissions or fees, but mostly spreads.</p>
          <p>So the different &#x2013; people responsible for this division consider that the kind of growth they've had will probably not be repeated over the next quarters. I think 2009 will continue because we already have a pipeline which is strong enough to continue that growth.  So 2009 overall will be a very good year of strong growth in this business area, but I think possibly in 2010 because of spread management the growth of profits in this unit will slow down.</p>
          <p>Speaking about credit quality there's two final questions. Raymond James from loan equities asking about the breakdown of our real estate assets amongst different asset classes. And from Citigroup they're asking about the refinancing book whether we've done any or not and so on.</p>
          <p>Starting with the second half, the refinancing book: numbers are extremely marginal in Spain. I think we have maybe 100 million so it's really tiny. I think we said it already last year. As for real estate assets there is really nothing to mention. There is sort of like three parts which basically reflect the composition of our portfolio. Our company would establish Eltameta the rest are houses which are in the construction phase which will be put up for sale when the construction process concludes and legally available for sale. And the second part is basically borrowing and that's to do with a percentage &#x2013; well that's in the percentages of the portfolios.</p>
          <p>There's a couple more questions about strategy and commercial management. But strategy; Raymond James from Euro Equities is asking whether we could talk a little bit about regulation and the new requirements, whether we expect higher solvency ratios and what we would do to keep pace with these regulatory changes.</p>
          <p>About this point of course we could talk about this for hours because it's quite an extensive issue but I'd just like to say one or two things, very simply. First, I don't think there will be any substantial regulatory changes, at least not until the situation has changed. And that's really our view, our mindset. And the second point, as time and months go by things become &#x2013; for example, there are some issues where we are seeing a much more realistic take on what a big bank is and what the different risks are. So we don't really think that there's going to be any real threat beyond the more general aspects. Perhaps higher capital requirements, but always after the crisis ends and I don't think that these are the ones that the Santander Group generally has &#x2013; they're thinking more about security businesses and trading businesses. So for now we don't see any, so that's &#x2013; and in fact the type of business model that the Santander has, I think within this ambiguity which we see, I think it will be enhanced eventually.</p>
          <p>There's another one by Inigo Locavali which has been answered, the thing about the wholesale banking. Sergio Gamez from Merrill Lynch is asking whether what we are thinking for Brazil, about the IPO, whether we could do this with other units like the U.K.?  And we've spoken about a minimum core capital of 7%, but given such strong internal capital generation, do we expect an increase in pay-out at any point? And finally could we update our synergies in Brazil? And are they on the rise?</p>
          <p>I'll answer the first question, there's nothing to say because there's really nothing to say on that point or about pay-out. Pay-out has been defined at 50% and that's something that's been recommended by the supervisor and so in any case we will always maintain it, regardless, in the group. And what's the third question? I've forgotten it, about synergies in Brazil. All right. Sure.  Yes, we do in fact expect to see those improve over our initial target. In fact when I spoke about costs in my presentation I already said that in Brazil we were exceeding our targets in annual terms, we were ahead of the targets for synergies that we have set for ourselves. We had spoken in the first year of synergies of $800 million &#x2013; sorry in reais &#x2013; for year one and we are now, for year one, at 1.3 billion. So in the first year &#x2013; so I think I can confirm the improvement.</p>
          <p>And in the financial area there's two good questions. Question from Dexia, can we say how much we have lent, how much we have been lent by central banks, specifically by the Central European Bank? And Emerico Sentura from BNP is asking about whether we can quantify the impact of hedging and how it might evolve in the future and what our policies are?</p>
          <p>In the Central European Bank &#x2013; we operate with the Central European Bank, the Bank of Spain and the Bank of England, but I think that the assets available for discount or write-down must be at nearly EUR100 billion. There is one in the U.K. we used up when the Bank of England provided three-year liquidity and there's some occupational uses for this with the Central European Bank, but it doesn't mean &#x2013; but there were discounts available for EUR85 billion which have not been used.</p>
          <p>Situation of markets is now substantially better, especially for short-term lending and there is abundant liquidity and finance costs are improving. As for the second question about the impact of hedging, what kind of hedging do they mean? I suppose it's exchange rate hedging? There's been no change, really, in this policy basically. As you know we have two sorts of hedges for results where we try and cover or have 100% of the results budgeted covered in the U.K., in Brazil, in Mexico, and in Chile, and the same thing with the usual balance sheets.  Normally depending on countries sometimes the hedge is perfect. For in others it's done <mark type="inaudible" />.  There's really been nothing significant or negative or positive in this activity.  It's a slight negative, some slight positive in some cases, but not real net impact.</p>
          <p> Matera Amenday from UBS is asking about that change in &#x20AC;200 million in our financial margin in the first quarter versus the second. I suppose that you're referring to the metro assessor transaction? I guess so.  It doesn't say but I think that's what they're calling, what they're referring to. I think in the brochure in Corporate Activities, we explained that between the first and the second quarter there's been change in the classification of <mark type="inaudible" />.  So that's really the only change; I suppose that's what you're referring to.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the units, there's not a lot of specific questions about the units in the U.K. <mark type="inaudible" /> is asking not just about England but also about Brazil.  Card exposure U.K. and Brazil and what effect are we seeing on the business?</p>
          <p>Okay, exposure in cards basically in Brazil.  Lending, it's about &#x20AC;1 billion of exposure, theoretical exposure in Brazil; revolving is only about 30%.  You will see in the balance that it's 2.6 but 2.6 is what you pay.  The risk premium is relatively stable.  In the case of the U.K., the card transactions, A&amp;L have no cards, Abbey didn't either, so the card business, most of it is what has been bought there, and there's that 1.7 billion on the business that we have developed starting from scratch in Abbey which was 717 million total with the arrears in over 30 days and stable, relatively stable figures of six and 7%, and also in Abbey just 5.5%.</p>
          <p>There's also a question about the reason for falling coverage rates in the U.K., if there's anything specific and why it's been dropping.</p>
          <p>In the U.K. it's basically two or three portfolios.  One is mortgage portfolio, very large with a very low coverage ratio.  And there's another one with a very high coverage ratio on the evolution of the UPL portfolios which as I showed has dropped and the mortgage one has good and slightly, it means that the mix with a very high coverage of UPLs which are now fewer and the lower coverage for mortgages which are more is what makes that difference but there really isn't anything.  There's a bit more but basically that's the effect.</p>
          <p> Eric Coss from Citigroup is asking &#x2013; well he is congratulating us again because of presenting this first or second quarter and Abbey which is very impressive he says.  And he's asking whether the financial margin or assets or the interest margin can continue to lengthen or improve in the next quarter given the excellent situation we're reporting.</p>
          <p>Well I think it's hard to improve it but to continue of course.  Our plan for Abbey especially for the retail business because of course in Abbey it's part wholesale and part retail.  But we certainly expect the next quarters I'm not speaking only about 2009 but also about next year there will be significant improvements amongst other things because of the incorporation and the efficiency gains derived from the incorporation of Alliance &amp; Leicester and Bradford &amp; Bingley so definitely we are optimistic over the next quarters about that.  In the retail part we'll probably will see less growth based on our general view on the retail business overall.  But within the U.K. as a business we'll continue to grow next year and strongly, strongly next year.</p>
          <p>And in writing, two from Brazil asking about in Brazil the other income and other provisions &#x2013; the other income and other provisions line and why is it where it is? I think we've explained this Pierre in other reports and that's the recurrent <mark type="inaudible" /> bottom part of the <mark type="inaudible" />, but we can talk about that later if you like. And we're asked about the evolution of the quality.  The NPL rates are up on how much is like-for-like, how much is not and how much is it worsening and what do we expect in Brazil.</p>
          <p>Well we explained I can't remember the exact numbers off the top of my head but we're really not concerned significantly over the NPL trends in Brazil.  There have been some minor moves in the first quarter. Perhaps the economic circumstances were not the best.  The expectations are now reasonably good. So beyond the specific numbers which I can't remember off the top of my head, we're not that concerned really.</p>
          <p>Okay. And then finally I think there is two questions in English over the phone.  So let's hear the first please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Our first question comes from Jeff Dawes from Fox-Pitt, Kelton.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Jeff Dawes here from Fox-Pitt, Kelton.  Just two further questions for those already submitted.  One is on Brazil, one is on Spain.  First of all on Brazil, can you give us a few comments on the write off trends?  So we've obviously seen the loan loss provision run rate increase and we've seen coverage come down after being stable for several quarters.  So have there been any major changes in what you're writing off in the Brazilian unit or changes to your policy there and any particular sectors where that might be taking place?</p>
          <p>Second question is on Spain. Can I ask about the funding model going forward? So Spanish banking operations typically run 200% plus loan-to-deposit ratios. Do you see this as sustainable going forward and do you think the mortgage bond framework needs to be revised to create some market for them if that is to be sustainable, particularly because there have been some problems with mortgage bonds issued by some of your peers? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess for the first question, I think it's basically the same we answered earlier about the problem of the provisions and whether we changed our policies in any way. I am not aware of that. And the only thing is that in Brazil, as I mentioned last quarter, there's been some sectors with particular problems, some industrial sectors where we've had some write-offs, but we have no specific concerns really with the evolution of provisions in Brazil. We've said that we expected double-digit growth, which so far has not actually happened in our loan book, and we expected growth in provisions of 30 or 40% in Brazil and we still expect that to happen.</p>
          <p>And as for Spain, and the financing model: first of all the loan deposits, loans-to-deposits ratio and so on.  As for those numbers, the Spanish retail network, which I guess is what you're referring to not the Spanish business overall but the Spanish retail network, the loans to deposits ratio is I think distorted by the fact that our retail network sells quite a few products, which in accounting terms do not appear as deposits but which are retail funding.  We have those preferred shares, for example, we've just placed, and all the insurance products we sell are not reflected as deposits or customer funds either. And so really the ratio you've mentioned at 200% is something that really I would say is 150% or even 100%.</p>
          <p>And as for whether we should review our finance model for mortgages and replacing mortgage bonds or not, the market has actually shown very consistent interest in our public bonds. In fact we issued some two months ago, I think 120 points over LIBOR five years and they're trading at 70. Plus also if you look at the current growth model that has simply changed in the current context.  We're seeing zero lending growth and deposits growing in Continental Europe at 15%. So there is a gap in Continental Europe and in Spain, which is most of that, is negative, so deposits are growing more than loans by about 10 and 20 billion a year at this point. So I don't expect that, that's going to mean, in this context, deleveraging, but that's something that we need to revise or change in terms of our business model. Okay, I think there is one final question in English which we're going to hear now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jernej Omahen from Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi there.  Can you hear me well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, perfectly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah? I'm assuming you can hear me. Okay, I've got three questions. The first question is on your plan to, or at least as I understood it from this call, your plan to part IPO the Brazilian subsidiary. Just for accuracy sake, I think there was a little bit lost in translation there.  Can you just please repeat in English what you have said? Is it indeed the plan to sell 15% of Brazilian shares in an IPO over the coming weeks?</p>
          <p>And if that is the case I will just have a follow-on question on that. I think you rightly point out that Santander has a very strong capital position with your core Tier 1 ratio, one of the highest in Europe. I think that the part IPO in Brazil would increase that ratio even further. Do you think Santander in that case would be in a position of capital surplus? Or how would you view your capital position in that scenario?</p>
          <p>And just the second question, and my final question, would be on the net interest income dynamics in your Spanish business. I think there's been zero loan growth over the past year but net interest income is up 21% in your network and 10% in Banesto. Can you just please explain how much of the increase in net interest income in your Spanish business is due to your actions taken in your ALCO strategy? And how much is it due to spread expansion? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Jim <mark type="inaudible" /> England was what I said in both eight year of Brazil.  We've said that we intend to sell <mark type="inaudible" /> IPO of 15%.  It is not a sale, it's issuing new shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regards to your question, and I think we already mentioned the business in Spain, the performance of the net interest income. Banesto growing at 20, the networks are growing at 21% and Banesto 10%, and how do we see looking forward? We already mentioned this during the presentation. This will become weaker. It will become weaker because of the reasons I mentioned.</p>
          <p>The only positive driver right now, well there are two. A very intensive one which is the spread of new lending, which has an impact on the problem as renovated which is a non-mortgage part of it, and there we continue to work, and the spread has increased significantly, and we continue to work along those lines. And then a second part which is as deposits continue to grow, although deposits give us low spreads, so there's going to be a gradual reduction in these growth rates.  The ALCO policy I already explained. We have been very conservative I would say in the coverage of ALCO because the book doesn't have the size of our core deposits and securitization is too high. So the impact and the results is in line with the book, and we don't see we have excess capital, we have a very demanding dividend payout policy. We will continue to have that policy with a high payout ratio and therefore we don't see that we will have capital surplus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that is the end of all the questions. If there are any questions that have not been answered in our department of relations with investors we will be glad to answer them. Thank you for coming and we'll see you next quarter</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>