<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1347590" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-10-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>14643</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">S&#xE9;bastien Martel, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Chris Viehbacher, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Hanspeter Spek, President, Global Operations</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Wayne Pisano, Senior Vice President, Vaccines</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me Contamine, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Graham Parry</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Luisa Hector</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Timothy Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Vincent Meunier</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Andrew Baum</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Mark Dainty</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Mark Beards</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Justin Smith</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Sanofi-Aventis Third Quarter 2010 Results Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. S&#xE9;bastien Martel, Head of Investor Relations. Mr. Martel, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the Sanofi-Aventis third quarter 2010 results conference call. As you know, our slides are available for download on our website.</p>
          <p>As always, I must advise you that the information presented in this conference call contains forward-looking statements that involve known and unknown risks, uncertainties and other factors. These may cause actual results to differ materially. Please refer to our Form 20-F on file with the SEC and also our Document de R&#xE9;f&#xE9;rence for a description of some of these factors.</p>
          <p>With us today on the Q3 call are our CEO, Chris Viehbacher; our President, Global Operations, Hanspeter Spek; our Senior VP, Vaccines, Wayne Pisano; and our Executive VP, Chief Financial Officer, J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me Contamine.</p>
          <p>So without further ado, let me turn the call over to Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, S&#xE9;bastien.</p>
          <p>Good morning, good afternoon, everybody. I'm going to start on slide five, titled "Growth Platforms and Cost Savings Compensate for Impact of Generics," which also would be, I guess, the main message of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Progressively, as we've gone through the year &#x2013; we talked about this at the end of the second quarter &#x2013; you're starting to really see the transformation of Sanofi-Aventis in numbers. As we'll show you a little later on, we will lose over &#x20AC;2 billion in sales this year as a result of the genericization of some of the brands that have driven this company for many, many years. But you're also seeing the emergence really of the growth platforms, which start to really compensate for those losses.</p>
          <p>And so as you look at the slide on the left side, where we've got quarterly sales in bars, you can see that we've continued to make progress in 2008, 2009 and 2010. And really, I think, the fact that sales are as robust as they are is, I think, a growing sign of the sense of the strategy that we have been involved with.</p>
          <p>So, obviously, sales up 5.7% on a reported basis. We had a very nice tailwind from exchange rates, which is not likely to last. But even at a constant exchange rate basis, only losing 1.7% and actually being up on a year-to-date basis at 0.9%, I think, again is testimony to the importance of the growth platforms and some of the moves that we as management have undertaken.</p>
          <p>On the earnings per share line, down 2.3% on a constant exchange rate basis, but up 6% nine months to date, again at constant exchange rates. We've been able to leverage really the growth in the business, largely through extremely tight cost control.</p>
          <p>So I think we're working our way through the patent cliff. We've got a plan. And I think that the longer-term guidance of achieving the same level of sales and earnings in 2013, as we did before when we went into the cliff in 2008, is certainly increasingly an assured outlook.</p>
          <p>As we look at slide 6, we've enabled to now get a better feel for how the business is doing. At the second quarter, we guided you to 0% to minus 4%, largely on the back of an approval of a substitutable generic in the U.S. for LOVENOX. In the meantime, we've provided a little bit more of an update later on that. But we're seeing that we're not &#x2013; that the erosion of LOVENOX is not quite as dramatic as one might have feared. How long will that last? We don't know, but that certainly seems to have helped.</p>
          <p>And then in the meantime, of course, we've also seen very strong performance in the rest of the business, and again, the tight cost control, all of which really now I think allows us to calibrate our guidance a little bit more precisely. And our current view is that we will finish the year somewhere between flat and 2% up versus 2009, always of course on a constant exchange rate basis.</p>
          <p>This guidance takes into account naturally the fact that we have competition at least for one form of Ambien CR in the U.S., since the middle of October, and a possible entry of generics of Taxotere in the U.S. and Europe from middle of November, and of course, further erosion from LOVENOX generics.</p>
          <p>If I turn to slide 7, again, this comes back to where is the growth coming from? Emerging markets, and Hanspeter will give some color to this, but you can see this part of the business is 29.6%. We now sell more in emerging markets than we do in the U.S. We probably have the most geographically distributed sales profile of pretty much any company in this industry.</p>
          <p>The 30% represents a very significant &#x20AC;2.3 billion and that grew at a very robust 13%. And again, our emerging markets puts everything in. Puts everything expect U.S., Western Europe, Japan and New Zealand, Australia and Canada. So we are not picking kind of the sexy countries, we are not picking the fastest countries growing. We'll show everything, and you have obviously quite a mix of countries in that.</p>
          <p>Vaccines, I think, had an extremely good quarter, up 8.9%. Actually sales would have been higher and close to 15%, but of course last year we have the initial sales of H1N1 vaccine. If you take out the H1N1 vaccine, then that 8.9% grows to the 15%. We're off to an extremely strong start on season flu. Wayne will give us a little bit more color on that as well. And of course, I would remind you that we had significant sales of H1N1 in the fourth quarter of 2009, and we will not have any of those sales in 2010.</p>
          <p>Diabetes up 6.7%, very good, on market share, and again, we will see more detail later. Consumer healthcare at 45.8%, of course, looks pretty outstanding. Obviously helped by acquisitions. The underlying growth rate organically though was still nonetheless 9.5%. And given that we're still in an economic crisis and these are products that people are paying for out of their pockets, I think 9.5% growth is extremely strong.</p>
          <p>The next box is something I'm happy about seeing. We are not known as a company that has much in the pipeline and not much in the products. MULTAQ delivered &#x20AC;46 million, and we now have that product approved in 23 countries, and we're just starting to roll that out across Europe. And we have launch meetings at the end of September for Italy, Spain and France.</p>
          <p>JEVTANA off to a phenomenal start at &#x20AC;41 million. That's only in the US, and that's only for three months. And the FLUZONE high dose, which is a higher dose vaccine for people aged 65 and older, doing very well, and again, above expectation at &#x20AC;41 million.</p>
          <p>Animal Health, plus 8.8% and I would make same comment as I did about consumer health. We talked about products here that are not reimbursed. There is no health insurance or not much. And seeing 8.8% growth is clearly a very strong performance, and one we're very happy to see.</p>
          <p>Now we move to slide eight, and of course this is the flip side of the coin. Slide seven was all about the growth platforms. Slide eight is why we need the growth platforms.</p>
          <p>You can see that we've had significant generic erosion of PLAVIX in Europe of over &#x20AC;200 million. LOVENOX already in the US, &#x20AC;208 million.</p>
          <p>And I'd just add for those of you who have &#x2013; appear to have not had the full impact of generic, thinking that there was no generic erosion July, that's true, but I think many people have forgotten fact that whenever a product goes generic, especially in the US, you're going to get returns, so you need to allow for at least two weeks of the previous months sales coming back in to &#x2013; in at least in the basis of a reserve.</p>
          <p>ELOXATINE, down 71, but we're seeing a progressive uptick again, since we've been able to achieve an equitable agreement with generic companies.</p>
          <p>Allegra D, down 39 million, but I'm getting increasingly excited about the Allegra Rx-to-OTC switch, which is expected in the first half of 2011. I think we're seeing extremely strong interest in the trade, with the head of one major pharmacy chain calling this probably the most important Rx-to-OTC switch for the next five years.</p>
          <p>So slide 9 is a slide that you have seen many times before, and you'll probably see many times in the future. We continue to plug away at the strategy that is working for us. We clearly have three major axes here, and it's increasing our innovation and research and development. It's using our cash flow to pursue external growth opportunities, and of course, adapting our company to future challenges and opportunities.</p>
          <p>And you'll see that we're making some very big resource allocation decisions, away from things that are not growing into more things that are growing. So that strategy is really trying to not only compensate for the loss of sales to generics, but I think when you look at those growth platforms and the longevity of those businesses, it's really trying to achieve a profile of a business that is much less dependent on patents and much more oriented to businesses that have longer term and more sustainable growth prospects.</p>
          <p>Now, the next slide on slide 10 is really, again, coming back to, wow, we have actually four pretty interesting medicines that are going to &#x2013; either have hit the market or about to hit the market.</p>
          <p>JEVTANA launched in the U.S. but we've already seen a number of other countries approve. And we, of course, over the next couple of quarters are going to launch this in a number of other markets. Very strong launch in advanced prostate cancer, with sales estimated to peak between 300 and &#x20AC;500 million. And we also now have new studies to expand indications on that, including cancer, and some of you have seen this from our investor seminar at the end of September. So I won't go into too much detail on that.</p>
          <p>But this is obviously an extremely interesting product. Initial indication in triple negative breast cancer, but we're also fully involved in Phase III and Phase II studies in lung and ovarian cancers, and they're up and running. So we've got a very active program to really make sure that we have a full set of indications. It's increasingly believed that PARP inhibition plays a range with a wider range of tumors than originally thought. It's not just where PARP is over-expressed.</p>
          <p>Lixisenatide, our GLP-1 in a GETGOAL program, and you have seen that two positive Phase III trials already announced. We've initiated in the middle of this year a cardiovascular outcomes trial, and we are still on track for planned submissions in the EU in the first half of 2011 and then first half of 2012 in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Teriflunomide, I think we had a very good session at ECTRIMS. Phase III TEMSO study showing 31% reduction in relapses. And I think what's important here is it's an extremely favorable safety profile. Obviously, as you all know, that whenever you're dealing with drugs that are affected by the immune system, safety and efficacy are often flip sides of the same coin. I think what we've seen here is that we've got very strong efficacy without the typical safety penalties that go along with that. And of course, we just announced the start of another Phase III trial as an adjunct to interferon.</p>
          <p>Now, when it comes to external growth strategies, and I'm moving to slide 11 here, as you all know, we commenced a tender offer to acquire all of the outstanding shares of Genzyme's common stock for $69 a share on October 4. We believe, as we believed at the time we launched it, that this is a compelling offer for all parties.</p>
          <p>And let's look again at what this means to both companies. So on the left side here, if you are Genzyme shareholder, this provides immediate and certain value and represents a substantial premium. It captures not only business today, but the potential Genzyme's business in pipeline. And quite honestly, it's going to shift the execution risk to us.</p>
          <p>We believe we can enhance Genzyme's rare disease businesses as a center of excellence and create value for Genzyme's other product lines because we are a bigger company with global reach and resources.</p>
          <p>Now for our shareholders, this creates a new platform for sustainable growth. It increases our biotech exposure, expands the footprint to an attractive and growing rare disease market. It allows us to increase our presence in the U.S., where we are really going to see the impact of patent expiries, both commercially and from an R&amp;D point of view, but also while expanding our R&amp;D pipeline of Phase II and Phase III products.</p>
          <p>The transaction meets Sanofi-Aventis value creation criteria, and here, we just don't mean accretion. We are also looking at creating value through such things as return on invested capital, IRR, cash payback. And of course, our strong balance sheet will preserve our strong capital structure even after the transaction closes.</p>
          <p>Now before I move on, let me just take a moment to address some of the information communicated by Genzyme last week. There was obviously a great deal of data presented on their earnings call and at their meeting in New York. And really I think the voice of the market is probably most relevant here. Like investors and analysts, we think some of the information presented by Genzyme ignores the realities of the market and the company's current situation. It also demonstrates the lack of realism in management forecasts.</p>
          <p>I think that's particularly true when it came to two specific issues, the company's aggressive financial forecasts, including those for Campath, and its disregard really for the issues still inherent in its manufacturing.</p>
          <p>On the financial outlook, keep in mind that Genzyme has lowered its EPS guidance numerous times over the course of the last two years. And on the heels of missing Q3 2010 consensus estimates and fine-tuning its 2010 EPS guidance to the lower end of its previous range, the company is projecting results for 2011 and beyond that are dramatically higher than most expect.</p>
          <p>In addition the forecast for Campath is extremely high. In the first year, this is expected to sell more than twice the sales of Dominia and even Avastin didn't achieve the first year sales that were projected. So you can pretty much take whatever pharmaceutical ever has been launched, and I think the sales forecast for Campath, I think, stretches the bounds of reality in anybody's mind.</p>
          <p>On manufacturing, I think it was fair to say we were surprised at the company's statement that its manufacturing issues are largely resolved. Keep in mind that 6 out of the 12 key upcoming milestones listed by the company directly depend on its manufacturing issues being fully resolved.</p>
          <p>As you remember from our recent presentation, companies under consent decrees have often taken longer than expected to resolve the issues, so we think a bit more caution is warranted here. And as you know, until the new Framingham manufacturing facility is actually approved, Genzyme will continue to work with minimal levels of inventory for Cerezyme and Fabrazyme, and any additional manufacturing delays will likely impact supply of these products, and therefore potentially create further opportunities for competitors like Shire or Protolix.</p>
          <p>So I think the bottom line is we didn't hear anything of substance that would cause us to change our offer. As we've said all along, we intend to continue to be disciplined and patient. As we proceed with our offer directly to Genzyme shareholders, our preference remains to sit down and hold constructive discussions and negotiations with Genzyme's board and management.</p>
          <p>We've listened with great interest to the process Genzyme has undertaken to understand its value. But clearly, any process that does not Sanofi-Aventis, the one company that has put a fully financed, $18.5 billion, all-cash offer on the table, is not one that stands to benefit the company's shareholders. We've reached out to the company through its advisors as to when and how we can fully participate in this process.</p>
          <p>So I think that's all I really want to say on Genzyme at the moment. Let's move on to slide 12.</p>
          <p>Now, one of the things that I think you'll see also, as Hanspeter talks, part of the transformation is really around making strategic choices. And it's going after where we have growth opportunities. But equally, you can't just have every resource incremental.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we also have wanted to make sure that we're not putting our organization through multiple restructurings. So the US organization's recently announced a significant reduction, 25% of overall head count, with the idea of being able to launch a new company, that just didn't go through a restructuring, but that went through an entire reengineering, to say this is a company that's going to be selling LANTUS, going to selling oncology products and diabetes products. It's selling MULTAQ, it's going to be selling an MS drug going forward, with teriflunomide. Let's redesign the company around the things that it needs to sell, and move forward and build a new company.</p>
          <p>So those resources of course are now going to be redeployed towards strategic priorities such as diabetics, oncology and A-Fib, consumer healthcare, business development, and of course you're seeing significant increases in head count in those countries where we're seeing significant growth.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 13, let me just bring this to a close slowly here. We have a number of targeted milestones for the coming year. Obviously, as far as Genzyme is concerned, we have a tender offer that's set to expire on the 10th of September (sic) [10th of December] . We have the launch of MULTAQ in France, and next year, we have the first US filing of iniparib in Q1. We have expected closing of the Merial Intervet JV towards the end of March.</p>
          <p>Q2, we'll start with the EU filing of iniparib, and we'll expect a positive and hope for a positive CHMP opinion for JEVTANA. We'll have further lixisenatide data from the GET GOAL program. And we'd expect to have a FDA decision on MENACTRA Infant/Toddler. And of course you're seeing some positive news, by the way, coming out of the AICC just this week. And Wayne, I'm sure, will be able to answer any questions you have on that later.</p>
          <p>So with that, I guess, Hanspeter, I'll turn that over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris.</p>
          <p>Yes, good morning, good afternoon, everybody. I would like to give some additional lights on the commercial performance in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>As you see then on page 15, we have obtained approximately 7.8 billion sales, and you also see that the ForEx impact nearly exactly outpaces the negative impact we had during the third quarter from generification. Nevertheless, we also had nearly 0.5 billion of incremental sales coming from positive performance, giving us the overall sales growth of 5.7% on a reported basis.</p>
          <p>Besides generification, I think it's worth to say that the third quarter was again a difficult quarter in the European market theater, coming from price cuts. To name the most dramatic definitely has been Spain. But also of course, we start to suffer for the time being a negative impact coming from the healthcare reform in the United States.</p>
          <p>On page 16, the point on the emerging markets Chris has alluded to. You see we have a 13% growth rate, even 22.6 on a reported basis in this market segment, which for the first time has outperformed, in terms of absolute size, Western Europe, which for us is a certain turning point, being the leading company so far in Europe now. We have even stronger sales in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>If you focus further down on the so-called BRIC-M markets, you see our growth rate of nearly 20%. So we continue to perform very strongly there where we are market leaders. And on the right lower side of the chart, you see that this is true for most of all our growth segments, which show a two-digit growth rate for the quarter.</p>
          <p>On page 17, you will see growth which may perhaps raise a little bit your eyebrows for the diabetes sales. We have achieved 900 million, 6.7% growth, which looks a little bit modest. It is partially due to a technical effect, but it is also due to the fact that, overall, the diabetes market has slowed down in nearly all of the world for various reasons, which I'm absolutely happy to answer during the Q&amp;A session. Nevertheless, LANTUS has become the number one diabetes brand during this quarter worldwide.</p>
          <p>In the previous quarter, I had reported to you that we see a slowdown in prescription in the U.S. for LANTUS, and on the right side, you see then that our investment &#x2013; our increased investment during the second and the third quarter now really has led to a nice &#x2013; I would even dare to say sharp &#x2013; increase in total prescriptions within the injectable market of the United States.</p>
          <p>More good news, more news also in the light that we continue to approach this market in a holistic manner. We have introduced our new devices for measuring blood glucose during the European Congress for Diabetes in Stockholm. The products have been received with a lot of interest. And perhaps even more importantly, our approach to not only sell pharmaceuticals but also to go more and more into services and devices around diabetes has been greatly appreciated.</p>
          <p>We also during the quarter had the opportunity to report a very well progressing phase III clinical trial program for lixisenatide, and we have announced that as one of the first products &#x2013; I believe even the very first product that we have initiated a large cardiovascular outcome study in order to prepare the launch of this product further.</p>
          <p>On page 18, you see our performance in oncology. I believe it's fair to say that we get back to previous growth. This is on one side true for Eloxatine. You know of course that we have gained in the courtroom again access to the U.S. market by overruling previous decisions concerning the protection of Eloxatine.</p>
          <p>You see that we have a nice increase of sales already in the second quarter, which accelerates in the third quarter. This 120 million. And we are confident that during the first quarter 2011, Eloxatine will go back to old standards, which means a product above 1 billion on an annualized basis of sales in the United States.</p>
          <p>Chris has commented on the very good &#x2013; for us even surprisingly good performance of JEVTANA in the United States, 41 million. It's the first full quarter we have this product at all. And you see on the right side of page 18, how the product benchmarks against all recently launched products in the American oncology market. And you see that we outperformed everybody so far.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, yes, we expect an opinion from CHMP during the first half of 2011 for entering the European marketplace. And of course, given the overall perception and reception of the product from a scientific and a medical point of view, we are optimistic also as far as Europe is concerned.</p>
          <p>One page 19, you see the progress we made with MULTAQ. And in the previous meetings, I had indicated that it is a not-so-easy battle. We have several times adjusted our investment into the product. We invest today, to say it in very broad terms, heavily. We have increased our spend via sales force, but we have also heavily increased our investment in terms of medical application. And this is a product that's reactive.</p>
          <p>We expect this year sales of probably above 160 million, which means if you look to historical benchmarks, I think it is affordable to say that the product is on the way to become over &#x2013; let's say two or three years from today, a blockbuster product. And it's even more as we continue to invest into the clinical development of the product.</p>
          <p>You see on page 19 that we have just initiated an additional clinical trial, PALLAS, with nearly 11,000 patients, which is aiming for an additional indication for this product, which would be those patients which are in the permanent atrial fibrillation, which is today excluded from the scope of approved indications.</p>
          <p>On page 20, yes, PLAVIX and evidently LOVENOX are already are still blockbuster products. I believe that the real message of the page is that both products have a very good chance to remain blockbusters, even after securing the out-of-patent situations for PLAVIX in Europe and LOVENOX in the U.S.</p>
          <p>You see that PLAVIX, yes, of course, is showing a sharp negative trend in Europe, with minus 55%. But the product has a very high, two-digit sales growth in Japan and China. Thus, the product will become a blockbuster for those two marketplaces during the next year. And you see that the product continues to grow with nearly two-digits also in the United States, which gives an overall a very impressive growth rate.</p>
          <p>On LOVENOX, a word. I think the most important takeaway is that we ensure today in the U.S. market 67% of the volume market, which we find impressive. There is another fact, which we find encouraging, which is the fact that this is a stable situation off of two consecutive months. It is, therefore, evidence that at least in the hospital segment we have managed to stabilize the market to a high degree, as the American hospital market in broad terms is depending on seven GPOs.</p>
          <p>Out of these seven GPOs, six we have succeeded to contract on. And given our service and also of course our flexibility in commercial terms, so six out of seven remain stable and reliable customers for us, in country, in the retail segment where the market follows other rules, in essence a direct substitution of the pharmacies. We see the usual picture, which means we see a sharp deterioration of our market share. But once again, overall, I believe that 67% in terms of volume after three months of generic competition gives a good conformation of what our American salespeople are able to do.</p>
          <p>On page 21, the 2 other growth platforms, consumer healthcare. Chris has pointed it out, yes 40-odd, nearly 46% and at constant exchange rate, even at 58%. They are also driven by our acquisitions in this field. We feel very much encouraged by this performance. We are currently working on more acquisitions in Asia Pacific, but equally important in Latin America, where we see very interesting opportunities. And yes, we feel fully confirmed in our strategy to continue to build up another important element of our overall portfolio policy.</p>
          <p>Generics equally done well. 19 or nearly 30% of growth. There, in essence, we are extremely content with our two major acquisitions in this year, Medley in Brazil and Latin America, and Zentiva in Europe do very well, and we are very content with what we see in terms of performance.</p>
          <p>And this is a very good bridge into vaccines, for which I pass on to Wayne Pisano.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hanspeter.</p>
          <p>As projected, vaccine sales have strengthened since mid-year, and we had a very strong third quarter. Third quarter sales were just above &#x20AC;1.2 billion, up nearly 9%. And if we exclude the pandemic and just look at our base vaccine business, we were up nearly 15% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>We had strong growth across a number of franchises. Obviously, the biggest franchise in the third quarter is the seasonal influenza vaccine. We recorded sales of &#x20AC;448 million, and this is up nearly 40% at a comparable basis to third quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., we delivered 40 million doses by the end of the third quarter, and this 40% above last year on a comparable basis. We will be finishing our deliveries in the U.S. by the end of next week, and this clearly will be a record year in the U.S. in terms of volume of doses delivered.</p>
          <p>During the year, we had a number of product launches in the influenza franchise. In Europe and Asia-Pacific and Latin America, we introduced the first intradermal influenza vaccine, Intanza. And we had very positive feedback and patient receptivity to this. We'll launch this product next year in the U.S.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., we launched the high-dose Fluzone, which has been developed strictly for the elderly patients over 65. We received our Medicare coverage in late June, and we've had very good uptake in its first year in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>To give you a perspective on the full year for influenza, we expect a strong fourth quarter exceeding fourth quarter of 2009. And as a reminder, last year, in the fourth quarter, we had &#x20AC;440 million of pandemic sales. Obviously, that's not going to repeat this year. On an annual basis, in the first half of the year, we recorded &#x20AC;452 million of sales for pandemic, which is comparable and which is in line with our projections.</p>
          <p>Another strong performance came from the booster franchise in the third quarter. ADACEL sales were in excess of &#x20AC;100 million, up 40% nearly it would have been for the quarter.</p>
          <p>In the bacterial  meningitis marketplace, our brand MENACTRA had a solid quarter with &#x20AC;192 million of sales. Sales were off 4% over the previous year, and this is despite the fact that we're dealing with a catch-up market that continues to shrink in terms of size and opportunity. And in the U.S., we had our first competitor launch in late first quarter. MENACTRA is clearly the market leader, and in the U.S., market share is in the range of 90%.</p>
          <p>On the R&amp;D front, a number of things have occurred with our dengue vaccine. We've completed the Phase IIb enrollment in Thailand. This is our pivotal efficacy study. And we've begun our Phase III studies with our consistency lots, which began in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, we also started the Phase III studies for our quadrivalent seasonal vaccine. The CDC is encouraging the manufacturers to develop a seasonal vaccine that contains two B strains, both lineages. The reason they're doing this is that in many years, both B strains are circulating, and the B strains have a very high disease burden for the pediatric population.</p>
          <p>Finally, in September, we signed a binding agreement for the acquisition of VaxDesign. VaxDesign is a biotechnology company that develops and manufactures in vitro models of the human immune system, and they use a proprietary technology, which is branded MIMIC. We expect the MIMIC technology to shorten development times and increase the probability of success of future vaccines.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion, the vaccine division had a very good quarter, and I will turn it over to J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me Contamine for the financial aspect. J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Wayne.</p>
          <p>I will move to page 24. Of course sales have been already presented. Maybe here you have another angle of view, which is the contribution of acquisitions. During the third quarter, there was not much because those acquisitions we did had already been accounted for in the Q3 2009, so the main gap is coming from Chattem and to a lower extent Oenobiol.</p>
          <p>On the full year, on a year to date basis, the overall contribution of acquisitions, which is a another leg of our strategy is an increase of 2.1% against last year. As we all know, this doesn't include sales from Amaryl, which are not considered consolidated, as long as we are considering entering into the joint venture with Merck, with the merge between Merial and ISP, as we all know.</p>
          <p>You see also from the slide the nice tailwind from exchange rates. Of course, the U.S. dollar is a main contributor, but as I now tend to say on every quarter, I mean the fact that we are very much exposed and present in many emerging markets or various markets shows that there is also a positive contribution of the strengthening of emerging market currencies from all over the world, which I think is a trend which could be not just a short-term trend, but could have been more of a medium-term trend, to the extent you can predict currencies.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, while you see the impact on the gross margin of the shift of activity. Obviously, we are losing sales with very high gross margins from some of our blockbusters. We've done some acquisitions, and we are replacing that with sales from them being more generic or CAC.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, all in all, we have reached just &#x2013; well, limited decrease by 1.3% of our gross margin over the quarters of last year, despite the fact that not only we have the impact of the generification, but also the impact of the increased costs of heparin, which is still hurting our P&amp;L. Even if now heparin costs are stabilizing because of the delay of production of LOVENOX, which is roughly speaking a nine month delay, from start of production to delivery to the market. This heparin increased cost is still going into the COGS and will continue to go into the COGS at least up to the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Actually we're able about to compensate for that with two effects, partly. One is the improved reduction of provision costs, and helps us to bring down this provision cost by unit. And also the second thing has been the positive impact of the currency during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 26, for R&amp;D, the R&amp;D ratio is down by 1.1%, which is significant. Now we are around 14%, as you can see from this slide, as compared to 15.6%, which is &#x2013; well, a sign of both where we are controlling our costs, but also the way we are completely shifting the way we spend money on R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>So behind the decline of 6.4%, you have a much stronger decline of our internal cost, which is a result of transforming and some increase of spending on either clinical trial or external partnerships, which leads to this overall reduction of R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>So it's really the impact of gross portfolio rationalization, reduction of internal R&amp;D cost, and also a shift to more external spending and therefore variablization of our cost, which you can see from the overall R&amp;D spend and the ratios, which I think is positive.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A, well, we have spent a bit more on sales and marketing cost during the quarter, this has been already mentioned by both Chris and Hanspeter. In fact, here again, this is a big shift between significant reduction in mature markets for declining products, either blockbusters becoming genericized or day products on more spend either on new products such as MULTAQ and of course JEVTANA that also increase spend in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Still, I mean, on a like-for-likes basis, and if I exclude acquisition, SG&amp;A has gone down by 1% quarter-on-quarter from 2009 to 2010. And the ratio of SG&amp;A to sales has gone down over the period, if I compare the fourth quarter &#x2013; to fourth quarter of 2009, sorry, which was a ratio of 35%, to the 24% level for the first three quarters of 2010.</p>
          <p>If I go down in the P&amp;L, on to page 28 and thereafter 29, maybe just a few other comments. A, as you may recall or remember, we are not benefiting any more from royalties from Zentiva and Copaxone since the second quarter of 2010. From a like for like basis, it's still hurting us on the other current and operating income expense.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, we have a stronger contribution of our share of profits of the BMS Sanofi-Aventis partnership in the U.S. venture, and we benefit also from the 100% contribution of Merial, as well as better performance of Merial's over the quarter as compared to the same quarter in 2009.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, as you can see, the minority interest has a lower negative contribution on a like for like basis, and this is of course the result of lower sales of Plavix in Europe.</p>
          <p>All in all, as you can see, our business operating income is up 7.1% on a published basis and slightly down 3.4% on the constant exchange rate basis.</p>
          <p>Now if I go down to the net result, here we arrive to what you know already. A, an increase of net margin, despite of the decrease of sales and the decrease of &#x2013; slight decrease of sales and the impact on the gross margin, we have been able to more than offset this through a decreased operating cost and also increased contribution of non-consolidated joint ventures, and good control of financial expenses, as well as slightly lower tax rate, so that the overall net margin rate is up from 30.7% to 31.6%.</p>
          <p>The business EPS is up 8.6%, down 2.3% on the constant currency basis from 1.74 to 1.89.</p>
          <p>Cash, next slide. Here again I think that it's really a sign of the very strong financial health of the group. Over the first nine months, we have generated 7.7 billion of net cash from operating activities. We have spent around 900 million of CapEx, which by the way is less than last year. We show that we have good control of CapEx spending.</p>
          <p>We spent around &#x20AC;1 billion, out of which 700 on the restructuring cost, so the cash out of restructuring cost, which is linked to the reorganization of the group, which was launched last year, has of course impacted cash flow. But in spite of that, we have financed over the three quarters both all the acquisitions, &#x20AC;2.2 billion, dividends 3.1, and we have been able to reduce our debt by 500 million over the period. So keeping down &#x2013; again, going down to a very low gearing at the end of Q3.</p>
          <p>So if I have to summarize before we move to Q&amp;A, the growth platform clearly limited significantly the impact of loss of sales from key genericized products. We have been able to continue to reduce our OpEx-to-sales ratio from 38.1% to 37.5%, compensating partly the decrease of gross margin. We have a high business operating margin sustained and a resilient business EPS, despite the patent cliff.</p>
          <p>We have upgraded our guidance slightly to the level of between 0 and 2%, as mentioned previously. Of course, this takes into account the fact that in Q4, we could expect some erosion of LOVENOX sales, as well as generic competition on Taxotere, and as it was reminded by Wayne, the fact that we don't expect of course sales of H1N1 vaccine in Q4, contrary to Q4 2009.</p>
          <p>We think now that we will be able to deliver cost savings of more than 1.2 billion by end of 2010. So we will have reached 60% of our overall 2 billion plan over two years, clearly being somewhat ahead of our schedule. We have generated strong free cash flow and, therefore, been able to finance gross dividends and acquisitions and reduce debt over the period by &#x20AC;500 million.</p>
          <p>So I think, now, I can turn to the operator. We can turn to Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Operator, we're ready to take questions now.</p>
          <p>As always, I'd like to ask participants to limit their questions to one or two at a time to allow as many people as possible to participate in the discussion. You can always come back into the queue with a follow-up question, if you want to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have the first question from Mr. Graham Parry from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks for taking my questions. And just first question in regards to the strategy seminar you're planning for second quarter next year. Is the timing of that because you are expecting to have Genzyme wrapped up by then? And should we think of this as a forum for new mid- to long-term guidance for the Group?</p>
          <p>Second question for J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me, just an update on the COGS expectations for the full year. I think you talked about 29% early this year. Nine months, you're running below 28% presumably because of some of the FX benefit, and if you could just clarify what the FX benefit was in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>And then in LOVENOX, if you could just give us a bit more of a feel of what proportion the sales exactly you think you are preserving in the hospital setting versus retail, and some kind of feel for what's happened to pricing, and where the price differential is on your product versus the Sandoz product now.</p>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Graham, I hate to disappoint, but on the strategy session, we actually announced at the end of the second quarter already before we were even very far down the path, that we were going to do this in mid-2011. Largely, it's around my view of when investors might be willing to listen to such a message.</p>
          <p>I mean, I think, again, I won't harp on PE ratios based on 2013 earnings, but I think it's fairly clear that at this day, investors aren't really looking beyond the patent cliffs and are preoccupied by short term issues and short term patent issues than who is actually going to make it coming through the patent cliff. I actually think Sanofi is extremely well placed to come out as one of the stronger companies, post patent cliff. But I think we have to get a lot closer to the patent cliff before people are really willing to think seriously about that period.</p>
          <p>My judgment is by mid 2011, you are kind of 12 to 18 months away from it, and I think that's more in the investor horizon, and that's why I chose it. I just think, especially given the volatility of the markets and another uncertainties, it could be a bit of voice in the wind if we were to do it any earlier.</p>
          <p>And J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me, you want to take the margin question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the COGS ratio, yes, there have been some positive impact on the current ratio, for the Q3, which accounts for around 0.7%.</p>
          <p>Now if I take the year-to-date, the exchange rate impact is basically nil. So the overall COGS to sale ratio over the first nine months is down &#x2013; or increased, I could say, by 2.2% from 25.6 to 27.8.</p>
          <p>We should still assume, and we have always some uncertainty because it may depend exactly on how much we are going to sell on LOVENOX, for instance, for the first quarter. Also you need to keep in the mind the impact of the fact that the mix of vaccine sales will be somewhat different, because we don't have H1N1 sales in Q4.</p>
          <p>So I would expect, depending upon the exact exchange rate, something slightly better than the 29% that we gave at the beginning of the year as a guidance, somewhere between 28.5% and 29%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, LOVENOX, to answer the third part of your question, the first answer is an easy one because it's a very positive one. We ensure today and as I indicated before, this is for us is stable in two months. Nearly 90% of the institutional market, which is in essence the hospital market, and that's really an amazing figure.</p>
          <p>On the commercial policy, I regret that for understandable reasons, I cannot give you a lot of details. We have discounted LOVENOX before the end of patent, and we continue to discount. I have to leave it with this general statement. I think what we do today is reasonable in the overall context of having a generic competitor which is substitutable. So it remains in terms, but evidently they had to increase our discount policy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mrs. Luisa Hector from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. On LANTUS, can you expand a little bit more on the difficulties that you alluded to in that market?</p>
          <p>And maybe give a bit more color on the U.S. sales where you were impacted by the reforms, but also by inventory levels? So just any color around that, and whether inventory was significant and changes going into 4Q?</p>
          <p>And then on MENACTRA, again, a bit more color. I think you mentioned changes or the latest comments coming out of ASIP. But anything you can add on the competitive outlook with MENVEO, particularly now that we have the infant data on MENVEO, or certainly some headlines on how that fits versus MENACTRA, and given that the timing is looking to be perhaps fairly close now?</p>
          <p>And final question, just what was the 171 million impairment charge, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll go ahead with LANTUS. I think the good news, once again, is that LANTUS is the number one prescribed insulin and remains it, of course. And it's growing by approximately 5% in total prescriptions on a year-to-date growth versus the previous year.</p>
          <p>The growth of the insulin market is lower. It is in the neighborhood between 3 and 4%. So I believe specifically for the U.S. market, there are, in broad terms, two effects. One is the healthcare effect, which of course translates into accelerated discounts. And you can estimate that about half of what we have made as an accrual for the healthcare reform is due to LANTUS. So this may be a ballpark of 30 million approximately, 40 million perhaps, for the quarter.</p>
          <p>In more broad terms, I believe that the American market is suffering by general economic factors like unemployment and so on and so forth, which makes people have less means to pay for the medication, and consequently, they continue to see less frequently their doctor, which of course is deplorable.</p>
          <p>But overall, there is a change in the market. This is what is historically a market dominated by two and half competitors, Novo Nordisk, us and to some extent Lilly, and it's a market which is today much more crowded. If you look to let's say share of voice, three or four years ago, you see today a totally different picture, we see new competitors like Merck, like Novartis, like GSK and others.</p>
          <p>So as a consequence is our main status besides share of voice, of course, that insulinization is getting delayed, which is today a negative effect, but over time, at the end, we get the patients all. This may sound cynically, but that's the way it is, that you still get the patients, but you get them later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The impairment charge, Jerome?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Luisa, so in fact, as you know, all this has no cash impact. And of course, as you know, allocation of goodwill and intangible have been created at the time of the merger between Sanofi and Aventis now five years ago. And have been allocated to various products.</p>
          <p>So we are regularly reviewing the value of these products on the balance sheet versus the actual economic value. And regularly, we take some impairment here and there, when of course, we don't upgrade the value of other products, such as raw materials or whatever. So it's mainly coming from various products.</p>
          <p>The other thing is that as you &#x2013; as it was mentioned during the IR seminar on diabetes, we are evaluating the recent pre-clinical observations and performing some additional preclinical work on the insulin sensitizer that we had acquired from Wellstat. And we took, let's say, the cautious view that we should write-off what we have on the balance sheet on this product, at this stage, even if we don't know the exact outcome, which accounts for one of around 40 million, which was what we paid as the initial maestro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On MENACTRA, Wayne, you want to take MENACTRA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. First of all, yesterday, the ACIP made a recommendation to add a booster dose of mening conjugate, which obviously is MENACTRA, at 16 years of age. And they did this because of the concern that this age group, as they enter college and military, will need a booster dose to have full protection. So I think this recognizes the severity of the disease.</p>
          <p>This is the first step in the process. It now goes to CDC for approval. It needs to &#x2013; it will then be published in what's called the MMWR, which is a notice to the healthcare providers, and then will go into the BFC program.</p>
          <p>So I think what we're going to see is that there will be an expanded marketplace in the U.S., and we'll start to see some of the benefits of that in the first half of 2011.</p>
          <p>As it relates to Novartis's product, which you indicated had shared data on their infant indication, and they've reported that they'll file for that indication later or sometime in the fourth quarter. We have filed for our infant toddler indication, which is 9 and 12 months, earlier this year. We expect licensure around midyear in 2011.</p>
          <p>And the reason we've pursued an infant toddler is that the &#x2013; number one, they have a very crowded immunization schedule in the first year of life, and a two-dose product clearly would be more cost effective than a four-dose product. And there has been evidence shown medically that if you immunize it at the infant toddler stage, that you will provide broad protection against &#x2013; for all age groups, because of the effect of herd immunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you. Next?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Tim Anderson from Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have a couple of questions. The other pharmaceuticals sales figure in Western Europe of &#x20AC;628 million showed a fairly big decline presumably due to various austerity measures. And then in the other direction, that collection of products did well in emerging markets. How should we think about the trend on this line item going forward, both in the aggregate and then in these different geographies?</p>
          <p>And then second question is kind of a broad one on emerging markets related to pricing. Specifically, what is pricing power like in these regions in terms of drug companies' abilities to take price increases?</p>
          <p>So if you look at your book of business in emerging markets for example what did pricing do year on year, ignoring one-off things like Turkey? In places like the U.S., you can obviously still take price increases. Does the same happen in emerging markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's absolutely true what you say. The negative trend in Europe is largely caused by price decreases. I think I mentioned the very sharp decrease we had to suffer in Spain. It is also true for Greece, which is a market overall in turmoil, not only in respect of pricing. And it is also true for Turkey, which is not geographically inside the European community but part of the emerging markets, of course.</p>
          <p>In all those countries we have suffered price decreases in two digits. Up to 25% for example in Greece.</p>
          <p>I believe that overall that the trend unfortunately which will persist for the quarters to come because all of the events I was mentioning, except Greece, happened after the summer period, so we have at least two or three quarters more to come until we will then come to the level post price decrease.</p>
          <p>The question about increase prices. It's an easy one. We can de facto not increase any prices in the European community. There's very, very few exceptions, if hospital products are concerned.</p>
          <p>In contrary, in Turkey, we still have a kind of price increase system. This is a government-installed system, which allows that, according to inflation, over time, you can charge the prices for imported products. This is something which is today in place. It has been historically always in place.</p>
          <p>Of course, there is a certain risk that this could be subject to change. But I must say I believe that's a decision not so easy to be taken by the Turkish government because the Turkish market to quite some extent is depending on importation of pharmaceuticals. So I believe that overall there is not so much of a risk there.</p>
          <p>But inside the European community, when the prices are down, unfortunately they remain down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And emerging markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the emerging markets, of course, it is one of the positive aspects in emerging markets there are totally different rules. You really have to measure yourself, benchmark yourself against your competitors. Can your customer, most of the time &#x2013; evidently, if the patient can afford to pay for it. And then in many markets, you are really free to adjust your prices, even in a market like China. And there, even for relatively high-priced innovative products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Vincent Meunier from Exane BNP. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Thank you for taking my questions. The first one is on Genzyme. Can you please tell us what will be &#x2013; what will make you decide to give up the process after December 10?</p>
          <p>And regarding your margins, the first question is on R&amp;D. After two quarters at 14% and also taking into account your comments regarding the shift of R&amp;D spending, is the current level sustainable?</p>
          <p>And on SG&amp;A, also, is the 24% level approximately a safe assumption for full-year '10 and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. On Genzyme, we've got a long way to go through 2010. So I would propose we deal with that when we get there.</p>
          <p>We've &#x2013; I think we have an extremely compelling offer out there. And at some point, shareholders will have a choice of going with some of the rosy forecast and hanging in with management, or taking a cash offer. And I think it's premature at this stage to really judge how are they going to choose. And obviously, we'll spend most of November ensuring we're listening to shareholders.</p>
          <p>On margins, I'll defer to J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me. I would just say on the R&amp;D, you know, R&amp;D spending can some times be lumpy. What we're really trying to do on the R&amp;D side is split the budget between essentially fixed infrastructure costs &#x2013; so sites, people, depreciation, energy, security, grass cutting, the whole thing &#x2013; and really try to manage that as tightly as we can. And then look at research and development projects a little like we do doing capital projects. So there have to be return on capital metrics, paybacks, risk assessments.</p>
          <p>And so that number will kind of go up and down as we have projects. So the difference is really versus giving a site or a team a budget. And typically, what you used to find is if something went down in the pipeline, people decided, well, that's my money. I am going to go spend it on something else.</p>
          <p>Here, it's a project by project basis, and only those projects that meet not just financial but also development and commercial hurdles are going to be developed. So you may find that number fluctuate around a little bit.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A, I will turn it over to J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would tend to say a bit of the same on SG&amp;A. It's clear that on one hand, we really continue to cut cost down on day products as well as across any spending which was linked to a genericized product. But on the other hand, we need to keep in mind, if we start not into '10 but into '11, that we are going to launch &#x2013; I mean, in Europe, JEVTANA. After launching in the U.S., hopefully we are going to launch Iniparib. We are going to launch our BGM. So you also need to sustain these launches.</p>
          <p>So here at this stage, if you look at the return on commercial investments you can make, you need to think a bit about around the years 2011 and 2012, and how we build the growth of these new products. And this is where I mean the ratio as such will not necessarily be exactly be meaningful.</p>
          <p>So are we going to continue to decrease our more stabilized SG&amp;A to sales ratio next year? I would tend to say a bit more of the latter. So after several years of decline, we'll continue kept from mature areas that spend more on some new areas or new product, taking once again into account the fact that we have fewer launches to take place next year.</p>
          <p>So it's a rough idea at this stage. Of course, we'll be in a better position to give you more precise ratios at year-end accounts release. But let's say, at least, we will maintain this level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, again, as Jerome has said, the idea is to take fixed cost out, and take cost out where we're no longer able to grow.</p>
          <p>So you're certainly seeing us do that in the U.S. and also Europe, but there is also investment in markets that are rapidly growing, not only geographically but also business lines, such as consumer health. And obviously, we have the launch of Allegra, for example, where we'll certainly want to make sure that's a successful launch.</p>
          <p>So it's more &#x2013; it's not just a question of margins, it's also trying to variabilize cost to a maximum degree, so that we can adjust our spend to the growth opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And maybe a follow-up question on this. What is the proportion of fixed costs at year-end level and the SG&amp;A level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In R&amp;D &#x2013; and here, my answer will be more &#x2013; well, yes, in R&amp;D, the aim is to be in the range of 50:50. We are not yet &#x2013; we were around 70:30, let's say, end of 2008. This year, we are more around 64 to 65. If I look ahead, the ratio will continue to decrease.</p>
          <p>Of course, also it depends upon how much we spend externally, because I mean if you increase the external spending, I mean you more easily improve the ratio.</p>
          <p>So I mean we are not yet at the 50% ratio, which could be a sort of a golden rule in our view, that year after year, we are decreasing the share of fixed costs. And again, I mean, in 2010, we should be around 64 to 65.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Andrew Baum from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you for taking my question. And just a couple, please.</p>
          <p>Firstly, what percentage of your U.S. LANTUS revenues do you think you can protect post 2015 from the risk of generic insulin, given that currently you've only got 16%, I think, of insulin administered via a pen but obviously you have your GLP-1 compound?</p>
          <p>And then, second, when do we get an update in terms of the patent term extension for your part for JEVTANA? And then is there any chance that MULTAQ in the U.S. you may maintain exclusivity beyond the current 2015 timeframe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Andrew, let me start with LANTUS. I think that's really so far down the road that I personally would not like to commit to a figure. So I really have to remain very quiet.</p>
          <p>Once again, I believe, Andrew, you will remember just like I told you some years ago &#x2013; it's the same for LOVENOX, I believe &#x2013; that the LANTUS markets will follow different rules than let's say an average chemical compound, because it's a complex market. It's a market where switches definitely will not easily occur. A patient who is content on a product, the physician will be very much hesitating to switch him to a generic.</p>
          <p>I have to remind you that also today there are no clear guidelines in the United States how biosimilars of insulin will be handled from an FDA standpoint overall, to name just two important factors, which will be determinating penetration of generics when they  towards our LANTUS.</p>
          <p>On patent extension for MULTAQ, yes, we believe we have a number of options. I ask you to understand that I don't want to go too much into the details. In any case, we have a situation which is 2011 plus five years at the minimum, so this makes us into 2016, and definitely we see good opportunity to have a pediatric extension, which would evidently give us six months more. And beyond, we see a number of opportunities to protect the product further.</p>
          <p>And then finally on JEVTANA, yes, JEVTANA is the same situation. We have a five year additional protection and we have ten years more to go in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Mark Dainty from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just two quick ones. On the guidance you gave for JEVTANA at the Oncology Seminar, did you include competition from Albuferon in that?</p>
          <p>And secondly would you consider in the sort of the medium term ever moving to a reporting structure that gave EBIT on a divisional basis? And by divisional, I mean do you see generics, and I know you do for vaccines already. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The oncology &#x2013; the JEVTANA guidance includes competition. I can confirm that. And -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the second question, it's a fair question. The point is that it's easy to ask, not easy to do, because you can have this view to look at divisions but you can't have another view to look at the regions, for instance. And of course, you have to cross information between the margin on the region, such as Asia or such as Europe, or such as U.S., versus the margin you can generate per division.</p>
          <p>So I would say at this stage, the way we are organized doesn't allow us to go too far in the allocation of &#x2013; we do that, but to have a fair view on the allocation of cost, beyond, let's say, allocation of cost of course of COGS as well as marketing spending.</p>
          <p>Well, one of the advantages of Sanofi-Aventis is also to have a global spend, so that we can share quite a number of cost, whether it is medical costs, whether it is G&amp;A costs, on a country by country basis, or a region by region basis.</p>
          <p>So, yes, we are following that for internal objectives, but I would say at this stage, I would not consider releasing on a regular basis this type of information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I can go again on the previous question on Albuferon. I believe that when we had the seminar in Paris, we were not aware of the clinical outcome data of Albuferon, which came out very shortly after. I must say that we have been pleasantly disappointed. The rates are not as strong as we had built in into our models.</p>
          <p>And second, I think, it's important to underline once again that amongst all products, JEVTANA is the only one which has proven its efficacy against an active comparator, which evidently is the established treatment with Taxotere. JEVTANA is very easy to be administered, and we believe that in fact we have a very, very robust set of data and product arguments which makes us not afraid at all of upcoming competition.</p>
          <p>And on top of it, we believe that any kind of improvement in those fields increases the overall interest into the possibility for treating those patients and will expand the overall market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Mark, the guidance provided on JEVTANA only reflected second-line prostate cancer. As you know, we are going to embark into other studies next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Mark Beards from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you for taking my questions. Firstly, I just wondered what would need to happen for you to start thinking of an authorized LOVENOX generic in that market?</p>
          <p>Secondly, just some more quantification on the European pricing pressure that you've seen this quarter and then going forwards?</p>
          <p>And then, thirdly, the &#x20AC;321 million share repurchase in the quarter &#x2013; does that in any way signal a change in stance on cash utilization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just on the authorized generic on LOVENOX, I am sure there are all kinds of other people who would love to know that answer, so you'll appreciate it if we don't particularly want to tip our hand on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I take your question by the words you said, when would you start thinking of, there I can easily say that I think it's a couple of years about it, which means we would be ready when we believe that the right scenario occurs. For the time being, that's not the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One the share repurchase, <mark type="inaudible" /> I would say the policy has been to compensate for a dilution of any exercise of stock options. And actually the &#x20AC;300 million we bought back &#x2013; we had bought back during the first quarter as a way to stabilize exactly the number of outstanding shares. And I think we will continue to go along these lines.</p>
          <p>But it's clear that beyond that, we still feel that there is more value to create to our shareholders by using our cash to do the right acquisitions on a selective basis and resume growth &#x2013; a sustainable growth for the group as a whole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And EU pricing pressures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the EU pricing, I mean we can give you some figures &#x2013; well, what we can say for 2010, and the overall impact &#x2013; and here I will include Turkey, which as a matter of fact, is not Europe, as Hanspeter has mentioned. And also I mean was decided somewhat independently at the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>The overall impact for 2010 is the range of 200 million for the full year, so i.e., around 50 to 60, &#x20AC;55 million, let's say, during the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Well, are we going to see more of that? Of course, this is the impact &#x2013; you could say that this 50 million is something which is &#x2013; represents what could be the impact of what we know today, and which is reproducible for the fourth quarter. Well, we don't see anything else coming, but I think the general comment that there may be some other price cuts coming into future as a way for European governments to take care of their public spending and public deficits, which as we all know, is an issue.</p>
          <p>But on the P&amp;L, on a profit basis, we are compensating not all of that, but a significant part of that through our cost reduction and cost cutting on a regular basis, as long as we have been used to that now for 10 or 12 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I don't want to put it this way, but I supposed if there is one good aspect about patent expiries, is that it actually exposes us less to both things like healthcare reform in the U.S. as well as EU pricing pressures. The more we move into businesses like vaccines, consumer health, generics, actually the less we are exposed to those pieces.</p>
          <p>So as you look at the evolution of the business over time, actually the patent expiries are clearly the bigger part of the impact on the pharma businesses. And then the EU and U.S. impact becomes increasingly less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Steve Callahan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have three questions.</p>
          <p>First, if another generic LOVENOX were to enter the market, are your contracts such that share would be retained, or should that not be the expectation? So in other words, did you enter multi-year contracts post the Sandoz entry?</p>
          <p>Secondly, for Wayne, could you revisit the &#x20AC;4 billion forecast for vaccines in 2010? Given the solid Q3 and the confident comments about Q4, it seems that you're on pace to even exceed that forecast. Would you agree?</p>
          <p>And then, lastly, I may have misheard. But did J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me say that Sanofi is getting a bigger share from Bristol of the PLAVIX joint venture? And if that's true, can you explain why that's the case? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Like I answered the last question, that's not true. Maybe I did not express myself well. I mean there is a higher contribution because the sales and the profit for U.S. are increasing. We will get a bigger &#x2013; I mean the value is higher, but of course the share remains the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the LOVENOX, I really can't <mark type="inaudible" /> in the sense that we will not go into our agreements in detail.</p>
          <p>But nevertheless, in the environment, I think, it is important to look to the fact that at the end of last week, another generic company decided to sue the FDA because the FDA had decided to ban importation for their future generic product from Chinese factories. So I think that's a certain indication for the competitive environment in the U.S. But you understand that I cannot answer directly to your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you think it'd be unlikely for a generic to sue the FDA right before they get an ANDA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean before you do that, you probably have really given up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Wayne, do you want to take your forecast number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, currently, we estimate that our 2010 reported sales should be close to the 4 billion objective &#x2013; 4 billion a year objective that we set at the beginning of the year, and it's going to depend upon how the seasonal flu finishes over the course of the next several weeks. So I think we are pretty much on track to achieve it or be very close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and if I may, it will depend upon exchange rates, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The U.S. dollar will tell you if we make the 4 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are just in budget process, so I am sure Wayne is going to be hedging his bets before he goes into the budget for 2011.</p>
          <p>We have probably time for one more question I think, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question is from Mr. Justin Smith from MF Global. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Thanks for taking my question. Just one Genzyme for you, Chris.</p>
          <p>I understand while you disagree with a lot of the assumptions that Genzyme put out last Friday, but nonetheless, your offer still implies a lot of long term value creation at the company. I just wonder if you could help me understand where that long term value comes from? Or I understand if it's too premature to answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not sure I understand the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, when we look at where Genzyme is trading, with all of them in our BCS, and certainly your offer implies a lot of value creation, beyond the end of the decade. I am just trying to understand where you see that coming from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think you are right that it's probably is premature. It's probably a question I would love to go into some excruciating detail on, once we own the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I think that's it.</p>
          <p>Well, folks, I appreciate you dialing in. Obviously, over the coming weeks we will have an opportunity to talk to some of you as we go out to various investor meetings, and obviously our investor team is at your disposal.</p>
          <p>Again, I'll finish by saying I think given all of the storms that are around &#x2013; generic entry, patent expiries, healthcare reform, EU reform &#x2013; I think our company is weathering those storms well. I think the decisions we made last year to re-shift our resources to new growth areas and to trim our costs, as well as, I think, to really reinforce our pipeline, are starting to bear fruit.</p>
          <p>We've got a long way to go yet. But this time last year, we were still thinking about the patent cliff as somewhere in the future. If you look at this year, we've seen Plavix in Europe is basically gone. Eloxatin is gone in Europe and will come back for a brief cameo over the next 18 months in the U.S., but I think that's pretty much certain. Ambien CR has now got a generic, and it's &#x2013; we'll see what happens with Taxotere.</p>
          <p>So we're already a long way into the patent cliff here. Obviously, Plavix and Avopol will be out there going forward.</p>
          <p>But I think, increasingly, uncertainty is being lifted. We no longer have the uncertainty of what's going to happen with the LOVENOX generic. And so, I think increasingly, we're seeing clearly where we're going. And I guess going back to Graham's first question is I think a lot of that increased certainty will give us an opportunity to have a better discussion with you next year on sort of more longer term strategy, and how we see the company evolving, and particularly trying to give some picture, not just for an update on 2013 but really about where is the company going in the post-2013 period. Because I think as we go into 2011 and even what I'm hearing from many investors as I go around is that people are getting increasingly interested in not just what happens at the end of the patent cliff but what does that look like going on out into the '15-'16 period.</p>
          <p>So we're working on that. We would hope to be able to share some things with you at that seminar. In the meantime, thanks very much for your interest in Sanofi-Aventis, and we'll talk to you all soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call. We thank you all for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>