<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1287466" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>14643</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Chris Viehbacher, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Hanspeter Spek, President, Global Operations</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Wayne Pisano, Senior Vice President, Vaccines</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me Contamine, Executive Vice President, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">S&#xE9;bastien Berthon</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Graham Parry</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Laurence Debroux</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jo Walton</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Eric Le Berrigaud</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Philippe Lanone</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Alexandra Hauber</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jean Jacques Le Fur</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There we go. Hello, everyone and welcome to the sanofi-aventis Full-Year 2009 Annual Results. It's a pleasure to have you here. As always, I'd like to remind you that today's conference is actually also available through live webcast and the slides that we'll show today are available on our website.</p>
          <p>I must remind you that today's conference will contain forward-looking statements. And those statements will involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties and other factors that could cause actual results to differ materially. You can find details on &#x2013; about those factors in our Form 20-F on file with the SEC as well as in our documents de r&#xE9;f&#xE9;rence.</p>
          <p>Today with us is our management team with our CEO, Christopher Viehbacher; Hanspeter Spek, President of Global Operations; Wayne Pisano, Senior Vice President of Vaccines and J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me Contamine, our Executive VP and CFO. The presentation will be followed by a Q&amp;A session. And at this stage I will actually hand the conference over to Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, S&#xE9;bastien. Good afternoon, everybody. Welcome to Paris. Some ways, it seems a lot longer ago than one year that I, I think, I stood up and presented the first set of results for sanofi and it's certainly a pleasure to think back now after certainly my first year in office. And I think a lot has changed. I think a lot has changed in the industry and a lot has changed very positively within the Company.</p>
          <p>So, what's changed in the industry? Well, I think one of the things that's getting interesting is that the famous cliff is now getting on to the spreadsheets. This is no longer something that's out there in the future, we're now into '11, '12, '13 and beyond. And I think the entire industry is starting to recognize that really share price is not being driven by our quarterly results any more but more of the long-term. You know, I was talking to one of the bigger biotechs out at the J.P. Morgan Conference and you know, it's incredible, we don't have any patent expiries before 2017, but we've already got people asking us about how we're going to replace our patent cliff in 2017.</p>
          <p>And there is this element where the cliff gets anticipated, and what people are really looking for is this sustainable growth. And so, it's great, and we need to have regular quarterly earnings. But I think the whole industry is now kind of recognizing we need to address this issue beyond the cliff.</p>
          <p>I think we were kind of innovative last year, we put out a floor guidance for 2013, which was really meant to have people focus on the fundamentals of sanofi-aventis, and to really kind of dispel some of the myths like for instance, if we could commit to the same level of profit as we did in sales in 2008. It was also a commitment that we didn't believe that margins would erode on a net basis as we moved into more diversified businesses. And I think we've seen some other companies now put some of those numbers out for the 20 &#x2013; post-patent cliff period.</p>
          <p>I think we're all looking much more seriously at research and development. When I came into the Company, my view of where we were as an industry is that up to now we'd really only being doing tweaking, not real fundamental change. And I go back to some of the research I did before coming into the Company, which indicated that there were two things related to innovation.</p>
          <p>One is there has to be some element of disruptive thinking and, two is that big companies, not just in our industry, but in other industries, are not very good in innovation, partly because we do everything to avoid anything disruptive, including disruptive thinking. So I think there is a real rethinking of the model, how much we're investing in it, a lot is going to be dependent on how you execute on that.</p>
          <p>I think a lot of it is people related, it's not structurally related. And people will come up with different solutions, but I think as we get close to the cliff, as we see that some of the tweaking hasn't worked, I'm certainly seeing some of our own colleagues, and we are certainly doing the same.</p>
          <p>It clearly is a global market. This was a business where the investor base really focused on the U.S. We can buy those weekly scrips, sometimes some of you get really keen and buy the daily scrips, and we've got analogs everywhere. It's a business that was very easy to value. And now, actually we're seeing markets in China, in India and Latin America, are real true growth drivers.</p>
          <p>Although I would say, when I talk to CEOs in other businesses, everybody's excited about Emerging Markets, whether you're in cement, whether you're in transportation, whether you're in electronics. And I sometimes think that actually in the healthcare sector, we still haven't really appreciated what kind of economic revolution is really going on in some of those markets.</p>
          <p>You know, I remember five years ago, we had huge issues of image. We can go back to the days when we sued Nelson Mandela, but I mean, we had issues on some of the marketing programs here and there was litigation, product withdrawals. And, you know, if there's one thing that at least has come out of the &#x2013; positively out of healthcare reform in the U.S., and I &#x2013; your guess is as good as mine if anything else will come out of it, but I think we were not the bad guys.</p>
          <p>When we worked our way through leading up to healthcare reform, we as an industry were very conscious that we did not want to be perceived as being the cause of the problems. And I think as we went through healthcare reform, even though we had Democrats in power in the Whitehouse and Congress who are not the traditional allies of the pharmaceutical industry, we weren't the bad guys. And I think it goes some way to demonstrating what this industry has done in starting to repair its image. And as I like to say, I thank the banks for their contribution to us having a better image, and we also have the economic crisis.</p>
          <p>Now, the economic crisis &#x2013; it's funny when you sit down with financial journalists who spend about 90% of their time covering the economic crisis. They say, wow, it's great to sit down and talk to someone in pharmaceuticals because you're not talking about the crisis for once. And it's true that as an industry we haven't yet really been hit by the crisis. I mean, as I look at social security deficits in Europe, I wouldn't get too excited for very long, as this will have a boomerang effect on us at some point.</p>
          <p>But there have been a few hidden issues. With the economic crisis, the IPO market really definitively dried up, for example. And with that, it became obvious that the only way for certain investors to really exit from some biotechnology investments, for example, was through big pharma. And so you've seen some changes in the valuations and ability to access assets in the biotech space.</p>
          <p>And I remember getting asked by a number of our investors the earlier part of this year about how we saw 2010 and I said, well, you know, one of the factors that is for me interesting is, does the IPO window open up again? And I wasn't terribly optimistic at the time, there were others who were. Everybody I talk to today believes that that's not going to happen any time soon, which actually opens up opportunities in our industry.</p>
          <p>So what happened with sanofi-aventis over the past year? You know, I think I stood up in front of most of you last year and said, if you thought about sanofi-aventis, you thought about Plavix and you thought about Acomplia. One had just been withdrawn and the other was about to go away. And there wasn't an awful lot of real understanding about the rest of the Company. And a phrase that I used very often in 2009 was, it's not the 20% of the business that goes away that's really interesting about Sanofi. It's the 80% that stays.</p>
          <p>And on the basis of those very strong fundamentals, we identified a strategy really to go after long-term and sustainable growth, to move away from the boom-bust cycle of small molecule patents based in Europe and the U.S. Out of that, we grew the five growth platforms that were not only just promising growth, but because of the inherent nature of these businesses, huge capital investments, deep competencies, deep trust and confidence in brands, that you build natural barriers to entry that go beyond patents. And those are the types of businesses that we wanted to be a part of in order to stabilize a little bit the inherently risky and volatile nature of the pharmaceutical business.</p>
          <p>Now, I think, I was also extremely transparent this time last year, stood up and said, we do not have enough new products in our portfolio to replace those things that we're going to lose to generics. This was a revelation to none of you, but it was an important admission so that we could actually get on with taking a much more radical view to what we want to do with research and development. And it became a strong rationale for entering into an external growth strategy because if we don't have enough, then we need to go and do deals. And I look on the list here, 33 partnerships and acquisitions, 6.3 billion in actual cash flow out the door, a little more if you include Chattem, which we did before, but for which the cash flow will flow later.</p>
          <p>On R&amp;D, we went through the portfolio and governance and I'll cover that in a minute. We developed a new R&amp;D organization, which we are actually now able to roll out just this week as we concluded, particularly in France, some of the social consultation.</p>
          <p>We identified a program of cost reductions, not just to reduce cost, but because we are shifting resources, reallocating resources, getting into different businesses, getting into different businesses with different cost structures, we had to become leaner, more nimble and certainly more empowered when we looked geographically. And so we identified that cost reduction program and we have some new blood in our leadership, and I'll talk about that in a minute.</p>
          <p>Now, it's great to talk about strategy and it's great to talk about the long-term. Sometimes you hear people talk about the long-term, it's because the short-term is not so good, and that's a trap. So first message is, yes, we are focused on building a long-term business, but we haven't forgotten our obligations short-term. And I think you see where the 13.1% increase in earnings per share at constant exchange rates that this is a very strong performance.</p>
          <p>We got a nice little gift from the U.S. Government at the end of the year when the agreement was signed between France and United States on taxation, which added about 1.5 points of growth. So the underlying growth rate is pretty much in line with the guidance that we had given at the end of Q3.</p>
          <p>Sales at 5.3%, also a very credible performance. This is a slide, I think is something we are going to use on a constant basis. For now the orange bucket on the right side of this slide contains only Plavix in Europe and Eloxatin. Later in the year, we will be able to add Taxotere.</p>
          <p>We'll certainly see the Plavix effect for our full year, we'll see the Eloxatin effect for our full year. Do we see something for Ambien CR? Don't know. Do we see anything for Lovenox? Don't know. But what is true is that we know that between now and 2012, the inevitable is going to happen. We will lose sales to generics. But you know, I don't spend my days looking at the market share for Plavix.</p>
          <p>I look at Plavix as an area under the curve cash pile that we have to reinvest in the business in new sources of growth. And when I look at the left side, there you have those five growth platforms that we defined last year.</p>
          <p>And look at the growth rates, 19%, 19.4%, 19.2%, 26.8%, and these aren't &#x20AC;100 million businesses. You've got &#x20AC;7.4 billion almost business in Emerging Markets growing at 19%. I mean, 7.4 billion growing at 19% is pretty sexy and we got some new products being launched.</p>
          <p>Today, those five growth platforms represent over 50% of the sales and that green bucket is really what the future of sanofi-aventis looks like. Because as we lose those generic products, that business is the one that carries through. It always going to grow at 19%? Maybe not because as the base grows bigger, it will be harder to do. But a number of those businesses we have set ourselves targets for doubling on, Emerging Markets, Diabetes and Vaccines for example.</p>
          <p>Now of course not all of that growth is organic growth, and I think we have been very good at doing the bolt-on acquisitions and J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me will take you through what's organic and what's been acquired.</p>
          <p>So let me just take some of those and just do a few things. Emerging Markets is something that Sanofi has a clear leadership advantage in. And yes, everywhere you're going to go and all these results announcements you're going to you hear lots about Emerging Markets. But we've been in those places a lot longer than some other places, been in India for over 50 years. Been in China since 1982, first foreign company to set up in China.</p>
          <p>And the interesting thing about that is, you develop actually deep relationships with governments and you have a solid management, you've got training capacities to find yourself selling and marketing people. You've got a range of products. The fact that this Company said there is no such thing as a small product, no such thing as a small market, when everybody else was trying to trim and eliminate their tail business, is now proving to be a strength of the Company because you need a range of affordable medicines as you see emerging &#x2013; as you see a middle-class emerge.</p>
          <p>Now these are all of the Emerging Markets. We just don't show you BRIC-M, we don't just pick sort of the selection of the most rapidly growing markets, we put everything in there. This is everything that's not the United States, Canada, Europe and &#x2013; Western Europe and Japan. And what was interesting is only a third of those sales are actually the BRIC-M, which shows you how widely spread the sanofi business is. We are also in the Indonesias and Africas and Thailands and Vietnams and Venezuelas and Algerias. So it's a business that is also nicely diversified because you look at the different colors according to the different regions, we've got actually good balance across there. And of course, we've got leading positions, number one in Eastern Europe and Latin America and in African Middle East. Number three in Asia, very, very strong basis on which to build upon. And the other question of course, is always, well how profitable is that?</p>
          <p>42% is still a pretty nice operating margin and considering that I'm not going to invest 15% of those sales in R&amp;D, we can keep developing those businesses without diluting our overall margins.</p>
          <p>Lantus, Lantus was a clear issue for us this year. We had those articles published in Diabetologia. Fortunately, all of the world's leaders have opinion, and all the regulatory agencies stood up and said that these studies were not of high quality and could not really sustain the conclusions that some were drawing for them. And I think you see that in the sense that that business has continued nicely. We decided to go the extra mile, we worked with the leading physicians and regulatory agencies to do the right studies and we'll have results in 2011.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, 285 million people worldwide are living with type 2 diabetes. You go talk to the Chinese Minister of Health, and you will hear their top three priorities, type 2 diabetes, oncology, and cardiovascular disease.</p>
          <p>India has got the biggest population of type 2 diabetes patients. This isn't just a western disease today. This is expanding everywhere. We've got mega trends to have people moving from rural areas to cities. That's changing their lifestyles. But it's also changing their income levels. As people get more money, they not only spend more money on healthcare, they spend more money on food, and that also leads to risk factors and type 2 diabetes.</p>
          <p>Clearly with Lantus, superb product over 3 billion in turnover growing at 22%. GLP-1 in the pipeline, not sure it's going to be that competitive on its own. But I think it'll make a nice product in combination with Lantus. We've got a new insulin sensitizer that we brought in from Wellstat. And obviously, in creating a diabetes unit, what we're really trying to do is start with a type 2 diabetes patient and see how we can help that person.</p>
          <p>I love the Vaccines business. First thing that I told Wayne Pisano when we first met, good news is I love the Vaccines business, bad news is I love the Vaccines business. So you're going to get lots of love and attention. And the reason I like it is because in a world where healthcare costs are spiraling, my personal view is that we will not get those costs under control until we actually do more in prevention and vaccinations is the sweet spot of that. Ask Bill Gates where he'd rather spend his next dollar out of his foundation, he'll tell you it's vaccines, and the fact that at Davos you saw that he doubled his commitment to vaccines from 5 billion to $10 billion, and we're certainly going to be looking for our market share of that.</p>
          <p>Fast-growing market, it's an increasing share of our business up to 12% of total sales now. And we decided to strategically strengthen that business last year with the acquisition of Shantha. That brings us a portfolio of new vaccines in development that are adapted to the Emerging Markets. We didn't have a rotavirus vaccine. You don't have a rotavirus vaccine, you will never be big in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>We have now an ability to produce a polio vaccine at a very low cost. Bill Gates is putting $400 million into India to fight polio. And I'm sure you've heard me talk about the 25 million babies that are born in a country where there are 600 million cell phones, so it tells you that there is a huge potential in pediatric vaccines.</p>
          <p>Consumer Health Care. Consumer Health Care is an important business for two reasons. First reason is inherent in its business. I mean, we have a brand like No-Shpa in Russia that's been around for 60 years. You have other brands in other countries that have been a long, long time. It's that faith and trust in a brand that protects the business. There is no patent on Doliprane, it is the number-one selling paracetamol in France. It is our number-one selling product by volume in France, and soon to be the number-one selling product by value as well. So that's one reason.</p>
          <p>The other reasons is, if you ever look at what happens when you do surveys of employees in companies of different industries. One thing that is particular to the pharmaceutical industry is that we always score low on any kind of customer orientation. I think being in a consumer business, is extremely important to bringing back a customer focus, which is sadly been lacking in this business. We would start with a technology and then go find a customer. Now we need to start with patients. Now we were missing obviously a presence in the United States, which is obviously one of the key markets, we had an opportunity to acquire Chattem. Other people had tried to acquire Chattem and they said, no thanks.</p>
          <p>Our team came up with the idea, well, we have Allegra to switch. Chattem does about $450 million of sales. Over-the-counter Zyrtec and over-the-counter Claritin today sell over $400 million each.</p>
          <p>Now, if Allegra can get anywhere near that level, we can dramatically impact Chattem sales. Plus we are obviously going to look in that portfolio and see what we can launch in Latin America or in Canada.</p>
          <p>Another point now, obviously, it's not just in the U.S we want to expand but I know Hanspeter will come back it, we've done this in China as well. We are also not &#x2013; we are also still mindful of our core mission which is to bring new hope and new medicines to patients and we made a very good start on that, launched a product called Multaq for atrial fibrillation in the United States.</p>
          <p>Big milestone for us, because after the whole Acomplia debacle, there was kind of a sense of could this Company get a major product approved by the FDA. And we managed to get that hurdle out of the way with, and showed that we can. And we are off to an extremely strong start on the launch, getting very good reimbursement pick-up, tracking well to our expectations, had a very strong launch in Germany and we'll be rolling that out in the rest of Europe throughout the year.</p>
          <p>We put two cancer products to the FDA who provided us with approval to file a fast track submission. These are basically rolling submissions. Now there's not too many companies who can say that they got two fast track approvals, process approvals in one month.</p>
          <p>And one is obviously our own homegrown Cabazitaxel for which we've had some extremely positive results in second line prostate cancer. And the other is obviously the PARP inhibitor first-in-class, which is progressing well Phase III, tracking ahead of progress in terms of recruitment in Phase III.</p>
          <p>Pentacel, pentavalent vaccine which took over 70% of the market. Panenza, which was our non-adjuvanted H1N1 vaccine. And of course, we extended our Lantus franchise with very successful and award-winning devices, notably SoloSTAR and ClikSTAR. So these are &#x2013; this is where we have been with our growth platforms. Really to drive those things, I set myself three objectives, where was I going to spend 90% of my personal time?</p>
          <p>You come into a new company, there's all of kinds of things you can look at, you can get distracted on a lot of things. I wanted to spend personal time in three areas. Increasing innovation in research and development, external growth because we don't have enough new products short-term to fill &#x2013; to create growth. And third, was obviously transforming the Company because it's one thing to say you want to be in OTC, it's another &#x2013; it's one thing to say you want to be in Emerging Markets. But the resource and the drive of the Company is still Plavix, Taxotere and Ambien. So you go to ship a 110,000 person organization in a different direction.</p>
          <p>So if I look at R&amp;D, we have had four products approved, 15 new projects in clinical development, 30 projects terminated. So as you saw, our research and development expenses declined in the fourth quarter by about 7%. Nothing to do with our commitment to R&amp;D, it's just simply that we weeded out projects and we had savings.</p>
          <p>We have actually reinvested significant amounts of money in the projects that we have brought in. We have really boosted the R&amp;D budget for vaccines, but despite that, we were able to recover money. Now, this is mostly variable costs that were associated with the projects that were terminated.</p>
          <p>One of the other things I remember saying last year was, nobody thinks sanofi-aventis is having any interest in biologicals. 60% of our development portfolio today are biologics and vaccines. Now, partnerships was another area where there has been absolutely massive cultural change. You go outside into Paris, go ask <mark type="inaudible" />, go ask somebody at a university in Paris, go ask a French biotech company, go ask an American biotech company, what kind of relationship did they have with Sanofi and they'll tell you, well, actually not that much. We were a company like a lot of pharmaceutical companies that believe, hey, we have everything we need, thank you very much, and we'll work on an internal basis.</p>
          <p>Credit to Marc and his team, in the midst of actually redesigning an organization, we have also been able to sign a significant number of partnerships, and in-licensing deals, where clearly R&amp;D have to be there as champions. To me the biggest single change that I think I've seen in the Company is this rapid opening up of being willing to sign on partnerships. Now it's easy to sign deals.</p>
          <p>Look, if you go talk to a CEO of a biotech anywhere today, they're looking at sanofi with completely different eyes. The way we did not integrate BiPar, the way we did not integrate Fovea is a model actually of how big pharma will need to work in collaboration, not in domination with smaller more creative companies. And of course, the new R&amp;D organization, as I say is already being rolled out.</p>
          <p>So for 2010, where 2009 was kind of a cleaning-up process, getting some cultural change going, signing some deals. 2010, certainly, where I'm spending my time, where Marc is spending his time, is now building that pipeline. And our objective and our ambition is by 2013, not necessarily to have all of those things launched, because that wouldn't be realistic. But I do think that we can move an awful lot more assets into Phase III and have a reasonably robust Phase III portfolio by the time we get to 2013.</p>
          <p>So we got &#x2013; we've moved things in progress, we've got new regulatory submissions. Wayne will talk about some of those in the Vaccines, and of course, we have had a number of approvals this year. And what's also heartening to see is, is this is not a Company that was previously known for life cycle management.</p>
          <p>Life cycle management has an important role. It's not a substitute for innovation, but you can't ignore it. And I think things like the flu high-dose in the US are a great example of that. I think the &#x2013; if we look at the Plavix for atrial fibrillation, that's another example. So when you look at it, we've actually been busy. I mean we've got not only the existing partnership, but an enhanced partnership with Regeneron, which is our platform for creating monoclonal antibodies.</p>
          <p>We've got cancer deals going on with the Exelixis and Merrimacks of this world and you see other molecules. We have partnerships with some of most prestigious academic institutions in the world, Caltech will apparently views us now as their preferred partner. We're in China now, with partnerships here in France. We've talked about BiPar and Fovea, which becomes our ophthalmology platform and of course Vaccines has already led that and we've already just signed our first deal on &#x2013; in Sanofi Pasteur this year with the KaloBios deal.</p>
          <p>Acquisitions, number one question I got all year 2009, are you going to do a big deal? Said never say never, but what we're really focused on is small to mid-size acquisitions that fit with our growth platform. I think we have been boringly consistent with that message. We have developed acquisitions and partnerships in vaccines, Consumer Health Care.</p>
          <p>Generics, which really for me is an emerging market story, not real generic diversification. Of course we had the other half of Merial more less drop in our lap when Merck decided to acquire Schering-Plough. And we are obviously now in the end phases of discussions with Merck as to whether or not we take the next step and merge our Animal Health business with Merial, with Merck's Schering-Plough intervet business. I would expect a decision in the next few weeks on that.</p>
          <p>So I'll finish and say we also have &#x2013; none of this was possible without a highly-engaged and motivated team. When you come into an organization, especially if you come into a CEO, you know nobody. You do the first budget reviews, you don't know who's a sandbagger, you don't know who's a hopeless optimist. And yet you have to create massive change rapidly.</p>
          <p>What do you do with your leadership team? You can fire everybody, bring in everybody new, and then they're all as blind as you are in terms of what's good and what's not in the organization. You don't do anything, you don't get any new blood, any new energy. I think we've got a good balance, we have nine numbers in the executive committee, three have come from outside the Company, three we have promoted from within and three bring that solid experience and expertise that we desperately need.</p>
          <p>We are as international as our Company, 90% of our sales are outside of France. We have a global team. We got more passports than members of the executive committee. So this is the team that did it and I actually as I sat back over Christmas and thought about the year, I was amazed and impressed at how well this Company responded to the challenge to transform. Changing a 110,000 person organization is like steering a big tanker ship. But it is turning and we are making progress, I'm not about to declare victory yet, but I think we've made excellent progress.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll ask Hanspeter to take us through some of the details on some of our operations and he'll be followed by Wayne Pisano.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. Good afternoon. As Chris said, I will try to guide you through our performance results in 2009. Evidently let me start with the sales, you see the overall sales figure of 29.3 billion and an overall growth of 5.3%. You further see that there has been a growth in all parts of the world, 3% in Europe, 2.8% in United States, 12% in the rest of the world. You will also see that the fourth quarter brought an acceleration of growth with the exception of Europe due to the increasing genericization of Plavix, but our sales in United States accelerated to nearly 10% growth and in the rest of the world sales accelerated to 18%.</p>
          <p>This is partially, but not only explained by what you see then in the fourth quarter for vaccine sales 65% of growth which have largely contributed to the increase of sales in United States but to a much lesser extent to the acceleration of growth in the rest of the world.</p>
          <p>Overall, I think it's fair to say that we have well resisted the generic competition. I dare to remind you that this is a kind of competition which we had originally not planned for 2009. We were not supposed to lose the protection of Plavix in Europe and we continue to fight against it on various levels and we were not expecting to lose by a court decision the protection of Eloxatin in the United States at the point of time when it happened and also again this we continue to litigate.</p>
          <p>Now, how has this been construed overall by a process of strong growth rates and I start with Lovenox and Lantus. Both products have now overpass &#x20AC;3 billion of annual sales. While this may be to some extent for Lantus being nearly normal given the underlying disease and its increase as outlined by Chris. Lovenox is, from my point of view really remarkable for a product which is about 20 years on the market to continue to grow by nearly 9%.</p>
          <p>Taxotere continues to do also very well, one of the truly leading oncology products, aid indications now as oncology drug would have more of indications and Lovenox, excuse me, Taxotere selling this year for the first time, more than &#x20AC;2 billion of sales. I have nothing to add here on the vaccines. Evidently, Wayne, after me will go into detail, but let me make two comments on Consumer Health Care and Generics.</p>
          <p>In both fields, we have undertaken important steps. We have made acquisitions, we have made organizational changes, we have made also management changes, and you see very impressive growth rates, Consumer Health Care on a level without Chattem, achieving 1.4 billion sales has been growing 27%, and our generics mainly through Zentiva, but also through Medley in Brazil and Latin America has been growing by nearly 200% from a small base, but meanwhile also achieving 1 billion of sales.</p>
          <p>For the first time you see a figure for Merial, which we started as we incorporate by acquiring the outstanding 50%. You see a modest growth rate 0.4%, which clearly indicates that Merial was struck by the economic crisis. I give you some more insight on Merial in an instant, but I would like to indicate already here that Merial sales according to the overall recovery of the economy, nicely re-accelerated then in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Talking about organization, Chris also has mentioned it already. We have decided to create two divisions, an Oncology division and a Diabetes division. And the underlying motivation is quite evident. We have competitors who perform strong and then we analyzed them, why are they strong, it's simple to say, because they focus on one disease. And as a reference, our competitor in the field of Diabetes of course, is Novo Nordisk. Now it's good to see that the gap between their sales level of total sales in Diabetes is getting smaller and smaller. You see then from the chart in 2006, there was a gap of 39% and in 2009, we have closed this gap to 25%. And yes, it is true, it is our ambition to become the leading company in Diabetes. And I believe, we are on a good way.</p>
          <p>Overall, our sales achieved nearly 3.8 billion in Diabetes composed of approximately 3 billion growing by 22.5% for Lantus, but meanwhile also Apidra doing well with a growth rate of nearly 39% and of 137. Beyond, we have more than half a billion additional sales from other products, which are historical products of the Company but playing still a very important role especially in the developing markets.</p>
          <p>We have undertaken important efforts in the field of device. We sell and we give away today our devices, which are entirely developed and produced in-house so we control the total value chain and we control innovation, and it's fair to say, and it's recognized from the external growth that our devices today have market leading positions because of their flexibility for the patient. So we put all of this together, industrial development, commercial resources, R&amp;D resources and we have regrouped it around our insulin production in Frankfurt, which is by far the leadest product &#x2013; the largest production site for insulin in the world. So, the focus, we built a Company inside the Company of sanofi-aventis and we believe that we leapfrogged towards our competition and we see that we are on a good way already in 2009, when we have started to do so.</p>
          <p>Similarly in Oncology, in Oncology we have undertaken the same endeavors. The headquarters will be bi-national. We will have an headquarter here in France, and another one in Cambridge in Massachusetts, United States.</p>
          <p>We went to Cambridge, despite the fact that we have various installations in New Jersey and in Pennsylvania. But we believe that Cambridge is really the heart of oncology today. And we intend to benefit from this as an environment as a neighborship.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned before, Taxotere is the locomotive of this portfolio today with sales of nearly 2.2 billion, with a solid growth of 6%. We are active in life cycle management. We have filed for another ninth indication, early-stage breast cancer and we have new forms, which will be launched as of now in Europe and in the United States.</p>
          <p>And finally, we have also applied for a pediatric extension in terms of protection for this product. The new Oncology division, which we have created in 2009, has an extremely good start and a lot of headwind, because we have three products, which approach launch.</p>
          <p>One Jevtana, Cabazitaxel which comes out of our own research supposingly it will be indicated in prostate cancer, where we have a huge franchise. Prostate cancer is the lead indication for Taxotere, and Taxotere is the mostly used cytotoxins as indications. So Jevtana will go in the second line therapy after Taxotere.</p>
          <p>We have received Fast Track designation by the FDA and we have a rolling submission, which will be finished by the end of the first quarter. So we are optimistic, confident to be able to launch this product by the end of 2010 or very early in 2011.</p>
          <p>BSI-201 is a totally different story. It comes from acquisition. It is one of the most fortunate acquisitions at least this Company ever has made. Perhaps it's even a reference in the industry because very shortly after the acquisition, the acquired company came up with very, very positive Phase II results and on those results, we have received another Fast Track designation in triple-negative breast cancer, which is a devastating disease today with nearly no treatment at all and we have been granted this Fast Track by the FDA and the relative trials are very, very well progressing and we are supposed to submit the final files and the final details by the end of 2010. So we are looking forward to a launch in 2011.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, Aflibercept, all three Phase III trials are progressing exactly with &#x2013; in line with our planning and we are supposed to conclude all those trials by the end of the first quarter with the subsequent submissions then approximately three months after. Aflibercept goes to another major indication in cancer, which is colon cancer, which is a historical position we have still today evidently with Eloxatin and we are eager to continue then with Aflibercept.</p>
          <p>Some comments on Multaq. I have said earlier today that Multaq, of course is a classical cardiovascular product. The performance in terms of penetration is in line with those products and you see that we are progressing quite well into United States.</p>
          <p>We have achieved 90,000 scrips in approximately four months. We do better than the competitors. We have been launching in the same months as Onglyza and for us more importantly Prasugrel and what we see today in dollarize the new prescriptions is that the performance of Multaq is approximately twice as strong as the performance of those two competitors. And especially referring to Prasugrel we continue to follow up since there's interest also from the angle of Plavix of course.</p>
          <p>We are in the market in Germany since two months and I can only say with all prudence after two months, as said, we are doing extremely well. We believe that we have very well prepared this market. Germany is a very interesting market, historically very sensitive for antiarrhythmic drugs. And once again we have the same benchmarks and we do so far much better than the other products but of course I have to remain prudent because it's only two months but nevertheless it is a very strong beginning.</p>
          <p>We see in the second major market we launch &#x2013; some launch in France is imminent and of course we will continue to launch over the year in all other European markets and also overseas.</p>
          <p>A little bit more of detail for Plavix and Lovenox, I gave just the overall figures already before. Now on Plavix, I think it's impressive to say that the U.S. sales are growing by nearly 13%, once again our product of this age. Once again to be underlined the product is facing for the first time real competition from prasugrel. For the last 10 years we hardly hadn't any competitor except Aspirin, of course. So as the product continues to do extremely well, we have filed for de facto patent extension by a pediatric extension. We are supposed to file in the third quarter for patent extension.</p>
          <p>You see sales performance of Japan, 339 million and I think it's worth to put this a little bit in perspective is what we are losing in Europe. In very simple terms, we have compensated everything we lost in Europe through the unexpected appearance of generics by increased sales in Japan. So we have lost approximately 150 million and you see there's a growth rate of nearly 60%. We have fully compensated this in Japan. And that's even more remarkable because in Japan we don't share anything with Bristol-Myers Squibb and Japan has been not part of the overall agreements, which means that the gains in Japan are entirely ours, while in very simple terms, we share the losses with our partner in Europe. So overall, at least in 2009, this was a very well-balanced performance due to an excellent performance in Japan where, yes, I strongly believe Plavix will become a blockbuster product on the market alone.</p>
          <p>On Lovenox, I have commented on the really fabulous magnitude of product. Nevertheless, let's keep in mind that this is what we are discussing permanently in the U.S. is only &#x2013; nevertheless, but only 60% of those 3 billion. The other 40% are de facto in a generic or competitive situation since years. Since more than 10 years we have either generics in some markets or we have products, which are very similar, there is Pfizer on the market, there has been historically Sandoz and Novartis on the market.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, in those markets Lovenox continues to grow at nearly 10%. For the U.S., we have nothing new. We know as much as you, nevertheless we believe that this is a subject of public health and it in this respect that we continue to fight, that we continue to defend the positions that we are convinced it is necessary if the FDA gives access to generics, are they substitutable or non-substitutable, that they should be based on clinical evidence as the European &#x2013; sorry, it is EMEA has decided &#x2013; excuse me &#x2013; within their guidelines. In this respect, we have in pharmacy U.S. Pharmacopeia and have received positive feedback. We have to see what the final stand of the FDA will be in this respect.</p>
          <p>Consumer Health Care, we have today in 2009, without and before the integration of Chattem shares of approximately 1.4 billion and they have been extremely doing well with a growth of nearly 27%. And this we have achieved more or less with household remedies. We have done some life cycle management, we have started to structure our portfolio, we have optimized our portfolio, we have started to organize from a local level and yes, we have also reinforced our management team. By the end of 2009, we have made the recruitment and have nominated an overall worldwide responsible for CHC development and is a direct responsibility for the European market.</p>
          <p>Chattem has finished the year 2009 well, very well, those results are public, and we are working today in line with the overall opportunities and with the necessities because it still is not close to integrate Chattem our strategies. And a major part of the strategy of course is as mentioned by Chris, the switch of Allegra which without any doubt is an extremely strong brand not only the U.S. but especially in the U.S. It's an extremely customer friendly &#x2013; friend because it has the lowest rate of sedation, it has a very, very attractive package insert from a customer point of view. And we will file for switching in the first quarter 2010 and are confident that we will then switch the product early 2011. And the Chattem management is eager in doing so because it gives Chattem the opportunity to double its size over a number of years to come.</p>
          <p>I promised you to give you some insight into Merial. I am experiencing Merial with a lot of pleasure, it's a real excitement and not only for the decision which is imminent, no, because it's a business which is close to pharmaceuticals and nevertheless it is very different to pharmaceuticals.</p>
          <p>And for me, the most impressive is the strong correlation with the business and the overall economic condition of the market. And then when you see here that approximately 66% of Merial sales are Companion Animal sales. Cats and dogs largely driven by a front line, which is the leading brand, which is by the way, by far the leading brand of the total animal health business selling more than 1 billion. It is clear that this type of product is sensitive to overall economic recession.</p>
          <p>And so, yes, it is true that during the first three trimesters of 2009, Merial had negative sales. The fourth quarter came back with a growth of nearly 4% and so overall sales have been stabilized for the total year, which in respect to our competitors is a good, even very good performance because all the other major companies, we are currently number three in the animal health market, are in regression for the total year 2009.</p>
          <p>You see further that according to the portfolio around companion animals, of course Merial is strongly U.S. based. That's the good and that's the bad news. The good news definitely is that there is significant potential outside the United States, in the Rest of the World section, and we believe that sanofi-aventis can contribute in guiding Merial or the future combination with Merck given our experience in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>And here we are. The chart on the right side gives you some illustration of what the recession meant, yes. I think it is easy to state that the first quarter 2009 had an impact in terms of overall economic conditions but then you see that our sales strongly came back already in the second quarter and we continued until the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Overall, 7.4 billion sales, 19%. If we focus on only BRIC plus M, an even 24% and overall with a market share of 6%. And also this figure has been mentioned before, it's for us to be repeated 25% of our today's sales come out of those parts of the world and this is without any doubt a strong promise for our future.</p>
          <p>In wrapping it up, I think it's fair to say we had a strong fourth quarter supported by Vaccines but also by underlying growth overall, 5.3% of sales growth in 2009. We have a very, very good start with our ambitions in Consumer Health Care and Generic which were boosted by targeted and well fitted acquisitions. We have a very encouraging start with our new product coming from research, Multaq, in the U.S. and also in the first major market in Europe. We have given us a different direction in terms of organization for our growth platforms, Diabetes and Oncology. Oncology, with have a very, very promising short-term future end of 2010 and 2011. And, yes, we have continued to build up our historical strength in the emerging markets and also this gives us a lot of confidence and trust into the upcoming years. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Taking a look at the Vaccine division, 2009 was both an exciting and overall excellent year in terms of our performance. Revenue was slightly over 3.4 billion, up 19%. We had strong performance across all of our franchises. As Hanspeter referenced, we had an exceptionally strong fourth quarter, over &#x20AC;1 billion of sales. A lot of that is linked to H1N1 and the pandemic and I'll address that in a moment. But before that, we'd like to look at our base business.</p>
          <p>In our Polio/Pertussis/Hib franchise, our Pediatric franchise, we had over 20% growth. The business today is over &#x20AC;750 million and this business is being driven globally. In the U.S., first full year of the Pentacel launch, Chris referenced that our market share now against one other competitor is now at 70% after our first full year in the marketplace. Our product Pentaxim, another pentavalent vaccine that is used throughout the international markets continues to grow significantly. This was introduced in 2005 in Mexico and Turkey, it is now being introduced throughout the Latin American region, throughout eastern Europe and the Middle East.</p>
          <p>Our pneumo and meningitis franchise was up 6%. The catch-up market for bacterial meningitis is &#x2013; has probably &#x2013; has reached its peak in the U.S.</p>
          <p>We continue to grow. The greatest opportunity for bacterial meningitis now will be in the international marketplaces long-term, and new indications in North America. The Emerging Markets was up 16%. Our business is approaching &#x20AC;1 billion now in the international markets and so strong growth there.</p>
          <p>Now, total sales on H1N1 in the fourth quarter were &#x20AC;440 million. And this was in line with the guidance that we gave where we had projected sales to be about $1 billion between the end of 2009 and 2010.</p>
          <p>So let's take a look at the Influenza marketplace. This was a record year for the Vaccine division. Sales for Seasonal and H1N1 were in excess of &#x20AC;1 billion. I think the thing we're most proud of is our performance in the Seasonal marketplace. Nearly &#x20AC;600 million of sales, market share globally at 45%, in the southern hemisphere over 70%.</p>
          <p>On the chart, we're showing the seasonal vaccine sales of sanofi pasteur, GSK, and AstraZeneca. Novartis does not report their sales by Seasonal or H1N1 so we don't have that data. Directionally, we think it's similar to GSK. The importance of the Seasonal business is that this is a sustainable business. This is the business that is repeated year in and year out.</p>
          <p>A pandemic is a global health emergency. It's opportunistic. It's our role and responsibility as a manufacturer to meet the expectations of the World Health Organization and the governments but it's not a business that is going to repeat itself year in and year out, that's the Seasonal business.</p>
          <p>We were the only manufacturer to deliver 100% of their Seasonal commitments in the U.S and this was an interesting year from a Seasonal manufacturing perspective because the B Strain that was selected by the World Health Organization was an exceptionally low yielding B Strain based upon historical norms.</p>
          <p>We were able to use one of our facilities in the U.S to continue production of Seasonal into September and deliver an excess of 50 million doses in the U.S marketplace. And again, we're the only manufacturer to deliver their full commitments.</p>
          <p>As it relates to H1N1, we began production in France in September after we completed our Seasonal production. We began in June with one of our facilities in the U.S and switched that over, the second facility over in October.</p>
          <p>We produced over 200 million doses of bulk antigen and delivered slightly over 100 million doses of H1N1 in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>We had a contract with the U.S. Government. It was our largest contract to deliver 75 million doses by the end of December. That's exactly what we did. We had also delivered 5 million doses to Mexico by the end of December, which was our commitment to Mexico.</p>
          <p>We fulfilled the remainder part of that commitment, which is for additional 15 million doses in the first two months of this year. As we look forward into the Influenza marketplace I mean, clearly, H1N1 is an issue still in the first quarter particularly in the southern hemisphere as they now move toward their &#x2013; the Influenza season in the late second quarter.</p>
          <p>We expect sales to be comparable year-over-year 2009 and 2010 as it relates to H1N1. We have a number of new products that we will be introducing for Seasonal vaccine. The Fluzone High Dose IM product was licensed in late December. This product provides superior immune response for the elderly. This is important because the elderly do not get the same level of protection as healthy adults. Their immune system, they are older &#x2013; the immune system doesn't respond as well. This product truly provides superior immunogenicity and we have very high aspirations for it, starting in 2010.</p>
          <p>And then in Europe and in Australia, Australia actually in three months we'll be launching an intradermal seasonal vaccine, which provides tremendous patient convenience because it's a dermal injection so it's not intramuscular.</p>
          <p>We also are expanding our overall flu capacity. We brought a new facility online in the U.S. this past year. But we are building facilities in Ocoyoacac, Mexico and in Shenzhen in China. These facilities are on track and scheduled to come online in 2012.</p>
          <p>Looking at our pipeline and the progress on R&amp;D, in the upper left hand corner are the products that were approved in 2009. Fluzone High Dose, I mentioned that was approved just before the Christmas break.</p>
          <p>We licensed the H1N1 vaccine Panenza here in Europe as well as in H1N1 in the U.S. and Intanza, the intradermal vaccine was licensed in the first half of the year and will be launched in Europe this coming season.</p>
          <p>The upper right-hand box is the submissions that were submitted and are under review right now. IMOJEV is the first once-a-day or single injection vaccine for Japanese Encephalitis. We have filed in Australia and Thailand. As it relates to Europe and North America, this has been more so a travel vaccine. The real need and opportunity is in Asia-Pacific where the disease is endemic. There are over 30,000 deaths a year from Japanese Encephalitis. We have filed with Pediacel, this is a pentavalent pediatric vaccine, it's an all liquid product. It is standard of care in Canada, the UK and the Netherlands. So we have a full European dossier that was submitted. And we've filed for our adjuvanted pandemic vaccine Humenza. That's under final review right now here in Europe.</p>
          <p>In the lower left hand corner, it gives you a perspective of the projects that were added to our pipeline in 2009. There has been a lot of work being done in the Nosocomial area. We have &#x2013; Chris referenced the deal with KaloBios that is for a disease called Pseudomonas aeruginosa. This is a disease that it's &#x2013; it's a bacterial disease predominantly found in hospitals and this is an issue for patients who are on mechanical ventilators. And 60% of patients on ventilators for more than four days contract this disease. And this is a project that now is in Phase I.</p>
          <p>We also have a staph aureus vaccine that is in exploratory phase and through the acquisition of Shantha we have basically strengthened our I/O platform for the developing world, but more importantly have added to our pipeline and it's very complementary. Rotavirus is in Phase I and actually will be entering Phase II this month. HPV is another product in the pipeline from Shantha. And then we added a periodontal vaccine. Periodontal disease is caused by bacteria and so we have a product that is now in the exploratory phase for that.</p>
          <p>Looking at the milestones and there were many, but the two I would like to focus in on are basically Clostridium difficile and on the Dengue vaccine, both projects have entered Phase IIb. Our Dengue vaccine has a very large clinical program and last week we completed the enrolment for the pivotal efficacy study in Thailand for the first dose.</p>
          <p>So looking forward, we expect the vaccine industry to experience significant growth over the next five years and sanofi pasteur is poised to participate in that. We expect strong sales performance in 2010.</p>
          <p>The role of the Emerging Markets, same as Pharmaceuticals is going to continue to grow. Coming off of a base of &#x20AC;944 billion, we clearly will be over &#x20AC;1 billion in 2010. We have a very strong position in our key franchises, Polio/Pertussis/Hib, Meningitis and of course Influenza. Our pipeline continues to progress as planned. And the final piece, which is very important in Vaccines is to have the capacity to produce the vaccines for the large populations of the Emerging Markets.</p>
          <p>We have 15 capital projects underway right now. I mentioned the two Influenza ones in China and Mexico, but we have a new Hib facility under construction in Marseille. We have expansion of our Polio facility in Marseille to take it to &#x2013; to meet the needs associated with Polio eradication. A number of new filling facilities will be coming online, and of course the Dengue facility in Neuville is under construction and it will be online in time for the launch by the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>I'd like to thank you and at this point, turn it over to J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me Contamine. J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Wayne. So, good afternoon. I will now go through the financials. You had already a lot of comments about the sales. And I'll just here to emphasize the contribution of both organic acquisition and Forex impact.</p>
          <p>First of all, for the full year and then for the fourth quarter. So for the full-year, the overall growth, organic growth has been 4%, which is quite good. And the contribution of acquisition, or in fact of change of structure has been only 1.3% as long as &#x2013; I'll just remind you that last year, we were still consolidating sale of Copaxone, which we are not consolidating anymore this year.</p>
          <p>We just get the payment from Zentiva. So, this has a negative valuation or impact on the like-for-like basis. So, on the other hand, clearly, we had the positive contribution of both Zentiva, and Medley. We do not consider that Merial, as you know because we are planning to go for the Phase II, which is a combination of Merial with ISP therefore, we are continuing to just take the net result of Merial in our P&amp;L basically and not consolidating the sales.</p>
          <p>The Forex impact for the full-year has been limited, at the end of the day, only 1% but as we all know there had been high fluctuation of the currencies, and this is continuing during Q1 2010. The overall positive contribution of the dollar has been around 2% and the yen also had around 1% positive contribution. The other currencies having a slightly negative contribution leading to this overall 1%.</p>
          <p>When it comes to organic growth, the 4% in fact includes the impact of the generification of cost of both Plavix and Eloxatin &#x2013; Plavix EU and Eloxatin. If I take out that just to see what is the underlying growth for the overall group that Plavix in Europe and Eloxatin in the U.S, we come to around 6% organic growth, which is I think a very good achievement.</p>
          <p>Now, for the fourth quarter, some more variations. First of all, on the Forex because if you recall, if you remember in 2008, the Q4 was very high for the U.S dollar against the euro. So, we are exactly the opposite situation as compared to the one we had during the first three quarters. So, we have a negative impact of the currencies.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, internal structure we have the all &#x2013; the overall contribution, the full contribution of both Zentiva and Medley and also <mark type="inaudible" /> which have not been listed here because it's smaller and we don't have any more, by comparison, any more negative contribution of Copaxone. And the organic growth has been above the average, 5.6%. If I go into this 5.6%, I can say that, on one hand, is that it's been helped by the pandemic flu sales by 362 million. But on the other hand, it has been hit with the full impact of both the generic competition of Plavix in Europe and Eloxatin. So if I exclude these two elements, you gain the underlying organic growth of the rest of the activity has been 6.4%.</p>
          <p>I go quickly through the P&amp;L because you've been &#x2013; now, I think you have been looking at it since the morning. The overall gross margin has been slightly above last year, helped by more Other Revenues, as we all know, Other Revenues are mainly royalties we get from our partners and particularly from BMS in connection with Plavix and Aprovel and also of course helped by the increase of net sales.</p>
          <p>The R&amp;D expense for the overall year has been slightly down than the constant exchange rate level by 1.4% and I will give some more comments later on, on that. And SG&amp;A has been kept flat, in fact, plus 1.1%, despite of the contribution of acquisitions. The acquisition have contributed by a bit more than 200 &#x2013; 230 million. So if I exclude acquisitions, the SG&amp;A overall absolute spending has decreased as also compensating for inflation on salaries and so on, which is really the result of the good cost management that we have embarking on &#x2013; or embarked on, and we will continue to do.</p>
          <p>There other operating income and expenses has been up and here you find the payment, mainly the difference is due to the payment made by Teva on Copaxone, so we end up with a very nice increase on the operating profit margin from 35.4 to 38.1%.</p>
          <p>A few comments on the various ratio, on the evolution of cost of sales, SG&amp;A. Well, first of all, cost of sales, when you look at the overall year we are basically flat from 26.6 to 26.8% ratio of cost of sales to sales. Now if you look at Q4, you will see some thing, which is different as the ratio has gone up from 27.2 to 30.2. Here I think you deserve some explanation because some of them are just one-off and some of them will continue next year. What's a one-off, one-off are mainly this impact of the donation of H1N1 vaccines to WHO, you remember that we have taken this commitment.</p>
          <p>We have taken the cost of that into our cost of goods, some of those have taken it into the SG&amp;A, it doesn't change much. So this, this counts for around 0.6 % on the negative side. Also the accounts here variation, which was positive over the first three quarters has been slightly negative in the first quarter. Clearly, we are producing more in euro when we are selling in dollar which will go the other way around in Q1 2010.</p>
          <p>And on the other hand, there are two things which will last over 2010. The first thing is clearly the mixed effect, we are selling less blockbusters in the U.S., we are selling more products, more volume in Emerging Markets. We are selling more Generics and as we had the opportunity already to say, this will have some influence, despite all the efforts our industrial colleagues are doing in the cost of sales to sales ratio. So looking forward, and looking in 2010, you could consider that the overall impact of both this mixed effect linked to the switch of the business but also of the acquisitions, we count for around 1.5% increase of the cost of sales to sales ratio if you compare 2010 to 2009.</p>
          <p>The only other impact which will last about 2010 maybe not forever is the increase of all material costs, in particular for raw heparin. You know that the raw heparin cost has increased since the heparin crisis last year, very significantly. This has started to go first into inventories and now is going into cost of sales. So you have nothing that immediately now cost of sales in 2009 to a low extent, you start to see it in Q4.</p>
          <p>If I look forward into 2010, you should expect here again around 0.6 to 0.7% of impact of this case of raw heparin. Of course, it could come back but I feel this is sure because it is in the inventories today. So all in all, if I &#x2013; I want to give you a sort of guidance you could assume that your cost of sales to sales ratio should be in the range of around 29%, let's say, depending upon the exchange rate situation, depending upon various &#x2013; various elements.</p>
          <p>And as you know, when we gave this long-term guidance for 2013, we clearly said, well, it will be a change of mix. So clearly, you will see some increase or decrease of the gross margins due to this effect of mix, and you will see some compensation both in terms of industrial reduction cost but still you have a net impact on the gross margin.</p>
          <p>And also some compensation both in terms of SG&amp;A and in terms of R&amp;D cost. So that at the end of the day, on the bottom line you will see a stability of &#x2013; basic stability of margins in 2013 as compared to 2008. So we are really now in this story. And fortunately figures for both R&amp;D and SG&amp;A are going in the right direction. While R&amp;D &#x2013; well, there is no magic figure, and of course, I mean, we always said we don't aim to spend either 15 or 16 or 14% of sales.</p>
          <p>The point is to make the R&amp;D more innovative, to have more products, and to make it also more efficient. This is what we have started to do as part of the transforming program, which has been largely commented upon already.</p>
          <p>If adjusting 2009 it's starting to see that there is a start of shift of the R&amp;D spending to less internal spending, more spending into partnerships, more spending into Vaccines and overall a slight decrease on the overall spending of R&amp;D on &#x2013; even more if you look at the ratio of R&amp;D to sales.</p>
          <p>In other terms you can see here the Pharma R&amp;D has gone down by 6.5%. And if I exclude all what we spent on new partnerships, we have been even down more than 10% and we have reinvested into new partnerships into &#x2013; into in the range of around 5% in 2009. And this trend will clearly continue as part of transforming in 2010 and you will see a real shift in the way we spend the R&amp;D, in the way we could use our fixed costs. And in the way we put more contribution into external research and also external products or products which are coming from external sources.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A is a tradition in sanofi-aventis we are among the best and we continue to be among the best. So one point more, we are down on 25%. This is really the result of all efforts we've made to cut down cost. Of course, we adjust our sales and marketing spend to products and to the generification when it comes but it goes beyond that.</p>
          <p>New way of doing marketing is having more efficient sales force. It's also shift production, our business, our activity, our sales from high cost countries to low cost countries from the mature western world to Emerging Markets. And also we have embarked when it comes to G&amp;A, into a series of cost reductions through a sharing of our expertise, a sharing of a common shared service and this will go on in 2010. So once again, it's notable &#x2013; quite notable that we have stabilized our SG&amp;A while we have increased our sales and while we have done acquisitions which by construction have brought some new SG&amp;A, newer sales and marketing costs and general costs as well.</p>
          <p>A few more words on the cost savings plan, which is part of this whole story and if I say that we are able to compensate for the evolution of the mix of business, it's clearly that it's coming from the cost saving program.</p>
          <p>We're more than on track. We are ahead of schedule. In 2009, we have already saved 480 million on the base of activity of 2008, which is our reference, is our baseline. And obviously if you remember, we said that we aim to save at least &#x20AC;600 million in 2010. Obviously have been achieved, having achieved 418 in 2009, which are recurrent cost savings, which we will continue in 2010.</p>
          <p>We should clearly save more than 600 in 2010 and contribute to the guidance and the evolution of the net results, Chris will comment in a few minutes. So we can say that we are ahead of schedule for the whole plan and that most probably, we will achieve the 2 billion savings before 2013, will it be in 2012 or '11. I mean, it's bit early to say, but this is where we are.</p>
          <p>All areas I have mentioned that I really don't need to spend more time maybe at this stage, all areas of the Company have contributed to the cost savings plans and will contribute in 2010.</p>
          <p>If I now, I go down to the net income, here I go very quick. First of all, clearly, what is most noticeable is an increase of the net income to sales ratio of 26.1 to 28.9%.</p>
          <p>On this slide, I would just comment one thing, which is the profit coming from associates. It's partly what we get from our partnership with BMS, which is our &#x2013; our interest in the BMS profit, in the BMS venture profit in the U.S mainly and here, you all now see in clearly if I could say so the contribution of Merial.</p>
          <p>Merial is a 50% over nine months and is 50 &#x2013; 30 &#x2013; 100% &#x2013; sorry, over three months. So all in all, it makes a nice increase also somewhat helped by some translation impact but still there has been an underlying increase of the contribution of Merial despite the fact that Merial has been in the sort of selling in euro with the stability of sales as Hanspeter has described a few minutes ago.</p>
          <p>Also, two other comments, more financials. First of all, on the cost of debt, the second, on tax.</p>
          <p>For cost of debt, of course, we have increased our overall debt due to the acquisitions not that much but still and we have been able to stabilize basically our cost of debt, our net financial expense. This is due to the reduction of the cost of the gross debt from 4.8 to 4.1%. We have done two bond issues which were nicely placed all over the year, and which now gives us high visibility in terms of maturity from four to 10 year. On the other side to a lower extent, the emanation we get on the treasury, on the cash is very limited. So it somewhat compensates this improvement of cost of debt. But still we have been able to stabilize the overall net financial expenses.</p>
          <p>Tax rate, we had a nice of course we expected that, let's say, for a while, but we had a nice gift let's say from both sides of the Atlantic, from the U.S. and France. Going forward we are not going to pay withholdings tax on the dividends, we pay from the U.S. to France and this has a retroactive effect back towards the 1st of January 2009.</p>
          <p>This is why we have revised our tax rate for 2009 from 29 to 28%. And going forward, this will continue. So in other terms for 2010, I think we can plan today to have a tax rate which should remain around 28% instead of the 29% we were used to before. So this is where we stand today. And so, I think you can take that into your computations for 2010.</p>
          <p>Well, just to comment on Q4, I mean, we have had the best performance with &#x2013; on the conservative basis plus 18%. You could wonder how much is this the contribution of the tax rate evaluation. In fact not that much because I remind you that last year, end of 2008 for different reasons, more the German situation also. We had also revision during Q4 of the year average tax rate.</p>
          <p>So if I compare on a like-for-like basis, the positive contribution on the evaluation of the quarterly EPS from this decrease of tax rate has been around 3.4%. So if I exclude that, we were still at 15% during Q4. On the normal year, this is a contribution of a bit more than 1%, 1.3, 1.4. So as it was said at the very beginning, our underlying operational performance has been in line, slightly ahead of the guidance we gave at the end of Q3.</p>
          <p>I just remind you that from 2010, we are going to report on one aggregate, which is not anymore simply the EPS, but a business net income. The reason for that is to make it simple and not to struggle about the fact to know where amortization of intangibles should go. Is it up, above or below the adjusted net income? Basically if you do an acquisition it goes &#x2013; it used to go below. If you do in-licensing, it used to go above.</p>
          <p>Now everything will go below, what that could consider more as a cash earning per share. Does it make a big difference? I think this has been disclosed to you also in several occasions including end of last year. If I take the 2009 figures, as you can see the base will be 8.629 billion and in terms of earning per share, the business earning per share has been in 2009, 6.61. The rate of growth has been exactly the same if I take the adjusted EPS or the business EPS. And you will see &#x2013; you can get in your documentation the trend for the previous years and you'll see that there is also not very much difference.</p>
          <p>So, I mean, once again, the guidance we are going to give and the quarterly results we will give in terms of aggregates would be based on this business net income going forward and not any more on the adjusted net income. Of course, the consolidated net income is not changing due to that, it's not a &#x2013; it's just a question of repartition of the various lines of the P&amp;L, as it is described once again from the slide on which maybe I will not comment precisely.</p>
          <p>A few words on cash. Actually, I mean, we have generated a very strong free cash flow I must say that. When I came in one year ago, I was really wondering can we really generate 4 billion of free cash flow? Yes, we can. Yes, we can. So we have generated 4.3 billion after dividend of free cash flow this year, which is really a record. After spending CapEx and CapEx on new plants and vaccines, new plants in &#x2013; in biological plants and for industrial and but before acquisitions. So we have been able to finance a large part of acquisition through this free cash flow. And the overall 6.6 billion of acquisitions had been financed, let's say, by more than two-thirds by the free cash flow.</p>
          <p>So that the net debt, even if it has increased, remains very low at 4.1 billion as compared to 48 billion of equity, that's compared to an EBITDA which is around 12. So this is a ratio of net debt-to-EBITDA which is around, well, 0.3, which keeps us among the best in the industry, obviously shows that we still have ample &#x2013; I mean, we do have the financial strength to do acquisitions. So the question of acquisition is not a question of financing, it's a question of attractiveness of these acquisitions both from a strategic point of view and from a financial point of view. And finally, dividend, so what we are proposing today and what we intend to propose to the general meeting is an increase of dividend by 9.1%, round figures from 220 to 240, make things simple.</p>
          <p>As we said on many occasions, we will &#x2013; we don't want to go for a payout policy when we know that there will be fluctuation in our P&amp;L quarter-after-quarter, due either to exchange rate variation or due to an immediate impact of generification on one quarter. So we've taken the view that we should have more medium-term strategy when it turns to dividend evolution, which is compatible with the medium-term and long-term system, it will grow that we want to deliver and along with what we have said when we released our long-term guidance.</p>
          <p>So what we clearly say today is that we want to be able to continue to at least maintain, regularly grow, and of course grow progressively our dividend and this is our commitment going further, while we are increasing the dividend by 9% &#x2013; a nice 9% for 2009 to be penned, I think on the 25th of May 2010.</p>
          <p>So a short wrap-up. You have already lots of that, so very solid performance, continued cost management, EPS growth ahead of sales and slightly ahead of guidance. Strong cash flow generation and as Chris mentioned already, the transformation on the Group, and you know it's true, if you just look at the evolution of the contribution of the growth platforms into sales, if you take the overall 2009 as compared to 2008 is 47 as compared to 42. But if you take just Q4, it's already 53 as compared to 45. So clearly, if you look at 2010, the contribution of the growth platforms, which will be much more than 50% of the overall sales of the Group. So it will be &#x2013; I mean the main contributor and shows how we are transforming the Group.</p>
          <p>Chris, maybe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I thank you, J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me again. So, what does 2010 look like? I am not going to apologize, it is going to look like 2009. We've got a strategy, you don't change your strategy every year. I think where we really are focused on execution I think, I've said before. Strategy is actually the easy part, execution is the hard part. So our formula for growth remains unchanged. And we're going to continue to pursue it with the same passion and energy that we did in 2009.</p>
          <p>In R&amp;D, as I said I think whereas we were looking more to clean up, change, getting some cultural change to occur, we want to put some runs on the board now in terms of actually bringing in more innovation into research and development. We clearly have an opportunity to accelerate high potential late-stage candidates like our PARP inhibitor.</p>
          <p>There are some exciting things in early-stage. And I think our policy is not going to be to say, let's go do big pipeline reviews and everything else. My experience is that, you can talk an awful lot about R&amp;D structures, you can an awful lot about R&amp;D portfolio and you get zip for it in your value and you give an awful lot of information to your competitors.</p>
          <p>So we'll probably not talk an awful lot about anything that's in early stage and really wait until we are couple of years from market. But there are some interesting things, I was talking with one investor recently, and it's not on the list, but you know we had our PCSK9 in there, what, you have a PCSK9? This is hot property in pharmaceutical industry. And yes, we have one of those. And these are things that we would clearly be looking to really accelerate and bring forward.</p>
          <p>Obviously, Wayne has a very robust Vaccines portfolio. Sanofi pasteur really started to look outside and do the research collaboration before the rest of the Company. There is a significant shift in budget going on. One of the things actually I look at most is not so much how much are we spending in R&amp;D as a percentage of sales. That's going to go up and down depending on what the opportunities are. I'm not committing to a number and we will spend it even if we don't have something to do, which is something I've certainly seen in my career.</p>
          <p>But what is important is to me the fix to variable cost ratio. This is a business in R&amp;D, wherever you are, whether you are in biotech or you're in big pharma, we fail more than we succeed. And what you really need is flexibility to move resources. You give a team some money for a number of years, not 10, but probably more than one and you measure that. And if you get something you continue to finance them, if you don't, you're going to pull that money back and put it into an opportunity that looks even better.</p>
          <p>You can't do that if you do not have more flexible spending. And of course we're now just actually starting the new R&amp;D organization. Again we're moving from 11 management layers to six, Marc? Significant flattening of the organization, empowering the people, putting scientists into scientific jobs instead of management jobs.</p>
          <p>We're going to continue spending. If you want to know what we're going to do, look at what we've done. I think it's a model that works. One of the things that we are able to do is we can buy an insulin plant one day in Russia, buy a vaccines company in India, we can then go buy a generic OTC company in Brazil. We can buy a biotech company on the West Coast, do a few research partnerships. There's an awful lot of stuff. I had one investor tell me, wow, 33 deals. For some people that's a whole career. For you guys, that was one year.</p>
          <p>We could only really do that for two reasons. One is I think, Laurence Debroux, who is sitting up here has an absolutely incredible team I think best in class in the industry in being able to screen, evaluate and close transactions. But the other thing is by doing those size organizations and having them as bolt-ons to your global &#x2013; to your growth platforms, you can then quickly pass them into the line management. So if we do a Medley, it goes off to our general manager in Brazil and that's his job to make sure it all works. We buy the insulin plant in Russia that's up to our general manager in Russia to deal with afterwards. And we have I think extremely high quality general management in our operating companies.</p>
          <p>You can't do that if you have these giant deals where you're going to get bogged down, but you can do that when you've got crack team upfront, hunting, searching, closing and then a team to actually drive the value out afterwards. So we're going to continue to do that, if they are going to be consistent with our growth platforms. And the R&amp;D model will continue, recognizing that you can't have those kinds of deep relationships with a hundred companies. So we will continue to do that, but you need to be selective and really be partnering with the best.</p>
          <p>Because it is actually an awful lot of work managing these partnerships. The growth platforms are there and, you know, we've been able to acquire companies. I remember people asked me a year ago, well can you really buy anything in OTC? I have to say if you asked me a year ago I would have said, probably not that much to buy in OTC. I remember my U.S. team saying, well we are interested in OTC. I don't think there's anything to buy in the U.S. Guess what? We found something to buy in the U.S.</p>
          <p>A lot of people say, is there anything ready to buy in vaccines? Well, we found something in India. So if you hunt, you will find. And I think we'll continue to do that and I think we've been very good at that. Yes, we are seeing, we are ahead of track on cost savings. I think that's a natural fall-out as we move the business into other areas. And we will evaluate and see whether we need to update our targets at a later stage.</p>
          <p>So guidance. I mean if J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me and I have had one conversation, there's been a hundred conversations on guidance. We thought we had it nailed and then there were all these rumors came out about Lovenox and how do we deal with Lovenox. And does Lovenox actually face a generic before we get the guidance and, so here's what we decided to do and we will be very open and transparent with you.</p>
          <p>I tell you, we really don't know what the impact of Lovenox generics will be in 2010. It depends on whether this is a substitutable or a non-substitutable generic. This may depend on whether there's one or there's two. And if you're out there, you hear all kinds of things. So, rather than try to come up with multiple scenarios, what we decided to do is say let's take Lovenox out of the equation. Because quite honestly, you know as much as we do about what's going on with the Lovenox generic. So let's give you an anchor point, a reference point, that you can then take as to what's happening in the rest of the business. So we have taken into account Generics in Europe for Plavix and for Eloxatin in the U.S., for Taxotere later on and the others. But we haven't taken Lovenox into this number.</p>
          <p>If you don't take Lovenox into that, then we believe we can do two to 5% earnings per share growth at constant exchange rate, which we believe is a little bit more than most of you were expecting. Obviously, we don't bring that into account. We don't really know what is happening. I think Hanspeter talked about certainly letters that we've had with the U.S. Pharmacopoeia.</p>
          <p>We remain firmly convinced that there are significant safety issues to a substitutable generic and we will continue to do what is needed to make sure that those in decision-making situations are aware of that.</p>
          <p>However, although a Lovenox generic and in particular, a substitutable one, would have an impact that would probably depending on when it came have some impact on our 2010 numbers, it doesn't really have an impact longer-term. When we did our 2013 numbers, we didn't assume that Lovenox just continues to grow at eight, 9% as it has the last 20 years.</p>
          <p>We did assume that the new two oral medicines that come along take a share of that and we decided to put in there really from the point of view of re-orienting the Company, a non-substitutable generic. Turns out that actually when you do that, there is so little left of Lovenox in the U.S. that were a substitutable generic for Lovenox to be approved very shortly, we would not change our guidance for 2013 in terms of our minimum floor on sales and profits.</p>
          <p>Now while we're on the subject of 2013, a number of you have wisely pointed out, well, your guidance is versus 2008, you just did 13%, and now you're offering another two to 5%. And I look and this goes up and I go down here to 20 &#x2013; what happens in the meantime? We don't want to get into the game of giving long-term guidance every six months, we will update it at the right point in time. I would point out that it has always been a minimum guidance. There are a number of levers that we can look at.</p>
          <p>There is going to be some turbulence over the next two to three years. I think, I mentioned last year that our goal is to try to continue to exceed expectations. I think, we were able to do that in each and every quarter this year and that's going to be the way we are going to do it. But I would say, I stand here before you extremely confident that no matter what happens on generics we will be able to, at the minimum, achieve that 2013 guidance.</p>
          <p>So with that, I think we'll turn to questions. Obviously in addition to Wayne, Hanspeter and J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me, we've got Marc Cluzel, who heads Global Research and Development and Laurence Debroux, who heads our Mergers and Acquisition team, Long-Range Planning as Chief Strategy Officer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, S&#xE9;bastien?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. S&#xE9;bastien Berthon from Exane BNP Paribas. Two questions please, one on Diabetes and one on Emerging Markets. I noticed your target of over-taking Novo Nordisk within the next few years in Diabetes, there is a 25% gap on sales, as you mentioned. I hardly see how you can further gain market share against Novo given that they are launching their own GLP-1 analogue probably two years before yours and also have a next generation wave of insulins, which is probably three, four years ahead of yours. So should we assume that this gap will be plugged by acquisitions? That's the Diabetes question.</p>
          <p>And regarding Emerging Markets, obviously growth has picked up over the year, it still seemed, I mean, your growth still seems to be slightly below the Emerging Markets Pharma sales growth. Any particular regions where you see a particularly intense competition and should we assume in the future that as a big leader in Emerging Markets, which you are right now, you will have to give a little bit of market share to your competitors or you're still confident you can grow at least in line with the market there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I started to &#x2013; you may have noticed that I didn't give a year &#x2013; when we take over Novo Nordisk, that it's a target. It's overall a target. Evidently, Novo Nordisk will continue to grow. It depends on various aspects. I believe that we have a certain advantage in the developing process, it's world where we are usually stronger, even much stronger than Novo Nordisk.</p>
          <p>So it will largely depend, can we take advantage of it and will we even enlarge the distance? So second element is definitely new products, they have just launched a new product in the U.S. which took them some while for reasons we all know. We have to see how this product and the whole class will perform. In any case, they have a new product. For the time being, we have to manage with the products we have. On an horizon of let's say three years from today, we believe that we are in a better, in a better position once again. We have a number of single agents under development and yes, I personally have quite some expectations of the combination which was already mentioned earlier today by Chris of our GLP-1 with Lantus. We also work as you know, on a long-lasting Lantus.</p>
          <p>So it will be the race on new products, which will contribute. And the third one is the environment of pharmaceuticals, which means mainly blood glucose monitoring and other devices like pumps. I believe that everything is for the time being open, but I am confident that we will be a little bit faster than Novo Nordisk on blood glucose monitoring, which is not a simple blood glucose monitoring. But it is, who will succeed to connect best those devices with the individual pharmaceutical product offering. Who comes up with this first will have definitely once again an advantage in this race.</p>
          <p>But overall if you look, we have gained about 15 points in the last three to four years. So I think it's fair to say, it will take us at least another three to five years to match up with them. But it's a nice <mark type="inaudible" /> as you say in French. On the Emerging Markets, I think we have to be really careful when looking to IMS and the Emerging Markets. We know that the IMS figures are entirely wrong in those markets, which have high shares in free goods, in natural rebates in any kind of discounts, payment advantages and so on and so forth.</p>
          <p>So as a consequence, the data for Brazil for example, is totally misleading. It's misleading, so what we have started to do, we really benchmarked ourselves with our own sales against what our major competitors report in their financial reporting. Who are the major competitors? I think once again it's easy. Our major competitors in those parts for historical reasons is GSK. They have an edge today still in the English-speaking Africa, whilst we have a leading edge in the rest of Africa. In Asia-Pacific we are really head-to-head, and in South America once again we are in front of them.</p>
          <p>Novartis is third best and then yes from Pfizer I see a lot of communication, but when you go to the markets you see a lot less. This is easy to say, but not so easy to do when you are a company like ours being now 20 years in China. This is really a large advantage, fixed costs. You have really cultivated, you have developed your structures and you have the adequate management which in all of those markets is the key. You have the good management. You can conserve your advantage, which is what we intend to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And I would just add on that. To me it's not a market share game. Market shares really if you got a developed market and you got to go steal share from somebody. There is going to be an element of competition in those markets, but the real issue is really the growth in those markets. If you take China for example, there's pretty much everybody on the East Coast of China. But the further you go inland, and particularly as you go west of the Sishwan provinces, not everybody is there. And so you're not interested in whether your share's bigger or smaller than Bayer or Pfizer at that point. It is how do you find reps, train them up, get them in front of physicians? Do you have a range of products that you can use to match that?</p>
          <p>You take a Brazil, there is more of a market share game, and a Mexico, but you've got other markets where it really is a market expansion, market development issue. And so for me I think one of the core things is how well is that business growing. And if it's growing at a nice strong double-digits then you do want to benchmark yourselves in some ways. But it is also all about growth. We also know that not all of the products, not only do you not have the issue in IMS because of the rebate mechanisms, you also have a whole range of products that aren't always covered.</p>
          <p>I mean, vaccines are actually very poorly covered, even in places like the United States. You also have very poor coverage of some OTC products in that regard. So it is a benchmark. We have a kind of a look at it, but personally I'm looking at top line growth and making sure that that's growing. Generally, the best way to measure this is what's macroeconomic growth doing. If macroeconomic growth is good, you've got more emerging middle class, and they're going to be spending more and are you really &#x2013; do you really have the organization and the product portfolio to go after that growth.</p>
          <p>Right there, Graham.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Graham Parry from Bank of America &#x2013; Merrill Lynch. Three questions. The first one is just going back to your commentary on generic Lovenox. You sound a little more cautious than perhaps in the past.</p>
          <p>I just wanted to clarify whether that was just due to the chatter that we've heard about the wholesaler requests or whether you're hearing anything specifically from the FDA that indicates the decision may be coming soon? Secondly, your former colleague at GlaxoSmithKline just recently put some hard numbers out there on internal rate of return on acquisitions, and also on internal rate of return on R&amp;D expenditures. I was just wondering if you had any similar metrics you could share with us?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly, a question on Emerging Markets growth. I think in your press release, you refer to about 8.9% fourth quarter growth at constant exchange rates, if we exclude acquisitions. Just wondering could you segue that to the 19% which includes acquisitions? So how much is acquisitions and how much is currency? And is there anything specific that you can point us to as to why that growth was relatively slow just in the fourth quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So, with Lovenox, we don't know anything more than the chatter. FDA talks to the generic applicants, not to us. So we're just prudent in listening to that and we've heard the rumors that they're talking to wholesalers and the like. We had a fire drill early in December where there was all kinds of chatter that this was going to be a Christmas present to Momenta, and Santa Claus didn't deliver and we had another fire drill in the second week of January.</p>
          <p>So we just said, well, there's lots of chatter out there, it seemed to be more intense than typical chatter but we have no information on that.</p>
          <p>In terms of IRRs and things like that, I mean, to a degree, and I'll let Laurence and J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me take a crack at this. It depends on, to me a little bit about what type of business it is you're buying. An IRR makes no sense on a, to me on a biotech company. It's either a valuable investment or a total waste of money, and there is no medium happy ground in there. If you're buying an OTC company however, then I think you will &#x2013; you can get into more traditional return on investment criteria. But Laurence, maybe I'll give you a crack or J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me if you'd like to answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we do calculate a number of metrics including IRR on every project. I cannot tell you there is a magic number that we apply and we discuss each project on an individual basis, and based on its merits, and based on the type of project that we're looking at whether it's more R&amp;D oriented or totally OTC type of project, and we discuss that with J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me really in-depth to see what should apply on a project by project basis. So I don't think we will give you a target at the Company level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can say that of course all projects have to be &#x2013; all acquisitions, say, have to be or have to have an IRR which is significantly above the cost of capital of the Group. Then you need to think about what is the cost of the capital you should take, and here you have to weight that with the area, the geographic area you are in, so clearly you would do that. It would be a expected IRR for a project in Thailand is right or not much higher than the one we would get in the U.S. Second, one important issue is also, I mean, to what extent it is a long-term, do we have a long-term perspective or not. So here I would say because very frequently you have the question when do you get the return on capital which is above your cost of capital?</p>
          <p>And here I would say, if you are into a multi-series like Chattem, where you have a five generation of production and you have a very, very long horizon, you could really expect to have a return on capital which is above the cost of capital. Let's say after year seven or year eight. And if you go into a more, more relaxed product, clearly you have to assume that you need to have a cost of capital, your return on capital above the IRR in year four. So and that may well be around year five, year six, that it could be a range and we will accept to go through these type of range when going for business which offers long-term visibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Personally, I think if you ever make an acquisition decision on that type of analysis, you're not going to get very far. I think I'd like to look first at a company and say, what do we bring as management that current management isn't doing? What can we do in terms of sales growth and where is there a good business rationale for synergies. If you can really come up with a good equity story around that, then the numbers will generally work, if it's a good margin business. If you have to go and decide on an IRR quite honestly, I'd rather not touch the business, since it's probably too close to the line to call.</p>
          <p>On the growth rate of the 19 point whatever in the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Emerging Market the overall growth rate has overall been 19%. There is no guaranteed effect. All this is at the constant rate &#x2013; on the constant discount rate basis. If I recall properly the organic growth rate for the full year has been 7.5, keeping in mind that this includes the impact of the economic crisis at the beginning of the year specifically in Latin America. And you remember that during the first quarter I would say there is the two first quarters, the growth in Latin America was slightly lower, particularly Mexico and to a certain extent in Brazil. We are really recovering from that, so the fourth quarter organic growth rate has been above the average growth rate of the year.</p>
          <p>So we're catching back to the 10% average we're aiming at. Once again, I mean, this year, I mean, people tend to forget, but when we're in Q1, we're still at the end of the financial crisis. I mean the consumption was going down. So yes, I mean, the key thing I like you to get from that is, we're seeing an increase in the organic growth rate of our Emerging Markets sales over the year and particularly Q4, it has &#x2013; if I compare to the previous quarters and I think on average of 10% objective, which we have organic plus acquisitions is definitely something which remains our objective and remains achievable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want to add to that, Hanspeter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, you had a slide that actually showed that Q1 was slower -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the slide, that's the only thing you will see again where you will definitely see a strong dip in the first quarter. Second quarter which was at least on the level of the previous ones and then an acceleration in the third I suppose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It wasn't actually just the economic crisis, I mean Mexico, in particular was hard hit also because they suffered particularly hard from the H1N1 crisis. They went through a two-week period where they shut down travel and businesses and I think the Mexican economy was down something like 7% at the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>Brazil was started also in negative territory and moved into a neutral zone and sort of halfway through the year and came back into growth in the second half.</p>
          <p>When you consider that we have a huge exposure to Latin American economies in particular, I mean we have over &#x20AC;1 billion of sales certainly in Brazil and close to that in Mexico that will actually start to weigh on the result but I think J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me is right. We would expect to be growing in double digits in those markets and enhanced by acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Oh my. There? Oh, this side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jo Walton from Credit Suisse. I have got a couple of general questions and a few little product ones. The general one though, is really to do with R&amp;D expense. I wonder if you could tell us of your 6 billion of licensing and acquisition spending, how much of that was effectively buying R&amp;D externally but other companies who did the same work but did it internally would've put through the P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>I'm particularly concerned that we see a reduction in the R&amp;D as a percentage of sales.</p>
          <p>We're not actually seeing a reduction in spending and I wonder how investors are supposed to mark you to this because now you're not even including the amortization that might ultimately come out of it. Seems to be getting a free ride on this spending that's never going to appear in an earnings number that you ask investors to look at.</p>
          <p>Could you also give us some help on the profitability of Lovenox in the U.S? Just very, very crudely, if it does go in the U.S, is this a more than averagely profitability product? A less than averagely profitable product? Do you have any variable costs that you can remove from it in terms of promotion or would the loss in sales pretty much go through in the short-term to the bottom line?</p>
          <p>And then I'd like just to ask on Multaq. Can you tell us whether a 34% Tier 2 for the Part D is actually &#x2013; access, is that good or bad I don't know. It doesn't sound brilliant, but I guess you feel that it is. So what could that go up to? And a final one for your flu product, you talk about your High Dose Flu for the elderly. Can you give us some sense of what proportion of the market for flu vaccines is delivered to the elderly? Is that like a big opportunity and could you get a price premium, any sort of basic type endorsement that would actually drive the market share towards that product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let's take the R&amp;D question first. I mean first in terms of whether you put the amortization in or not isn't going to make a difference for quite a while because you don't start amortizing until you actually launch a product. So and if we get there, we will all be happy. Two is we actually do disclose the number, as far as I understand we are not putting it in that number just to be consistent and we've actually looked at what our peer companies do.</p>
          <p>So we want to be in line with that. And sometimes, by the way that amortization number in my experience doesn't actually land up on the R&amp;D line. It lands up on a cost to sales line, for example. So I think we'll try to do that. We have had a net reduction in R&amp;D spending internally. And we have added back on projects. So if you see a reduction in the &#x2013; the minus 7% is actually a net reduction in spending. Yes, you buy in R&amp;D, but if &#x2013; it was R&amp;D that you didn't spend from the past. And I think that number, Laurence, was around 600?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No we have invested in in-licensing 325 million for 18 partnerships. So I think you have to compare, what you can compare. I think about what it means in terms of range of products, coming from exploratory to Phase II, this doesn't include investment in BiPar. And in BiPar as you may recall, it has been disclosed and the overall spending if we go to approval to obligation is $500 million, but we are not yet there. I mean we are quite far from that. So if I put all that together, and we discuss that regularly with Marc. I think the cost of external R&amp;D versus internal part bringing a product in a phase where it is remains definitely quite competitive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also as we've done some early agreements on R&amp;D, which are really research collaboration. You put in your assets what you pay as milestones, but then after that our R&amp;D is going to work on these products and that's going to flow through the P&amp;L. So what you put in the assets of course will only be amortized the day you launch a product or if you are not lucky get impaired at some point. And that's going to be below the business net income. But then when you get them in a portfolio, they continue their life within the portfolios. So you have the expense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think, so if we Regeneron as example, Regeneron flows through Marc's budget. If you take BiPar, the cost of developing now this asset in Phase III is sitting actually in R&amp;D expense. What we're also doing is, hey we're going to do an R&amp;D partnership, wonderful. But that doesn't necessarily come on top. So we are also looking at allocating resources according to where the best project is. If we're going to do this, we will probably stop doing something else. I don't know any other way to actually present it.</p>
          <p>We can certainly look at how we do it. For me the biggest advantage is if you buy this, it's a different thing than if you spent it yourself, because by the time you buy it you've discharged a huge amount of risk whereas if you've been expending it, you've got a lot more risk, because you are still in that process of not having discharged risk. So for me net-net you are in a better situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lovenox.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lovenox. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Jo, as you know we don't publish individual profitability of product, so I have to remain a little bit cryptic. Lovenox is a very profitable product for us in the U.S., but we have even more profitable products. Now you can guess. We have a significant cost allocated. We have massive sales force behind it.</p>
          <p>We promote the product of course in hospital. But we also promote it in the retail segment, which depending on the outcome we would cut. I think I, we discussed the issue before as there is a huge difference between a substitutable and a non-substitutable. I heard today that somebody from Novartis seems to have said, if they would have a substitutable, they see a big opportunity. If they would have a non-substitutable, they would perhaps even hesitate to commercialize it. This perhaps is a little bit exaggerated because then they would have to write-off their participation in Momenta.</p>
          <p>So it's very difficult to say, but if you would have a non-substitutable, we would very, very moderately adjust our spending. If we would have a substitutable we would radically of course, reduce head count and also variable expenses. So 35 &#x2013; 34% in commercial are reasonable, are reasonable given the fact that we had less then six months to achieve it and that we have launched in the second half. I understand that it is getting more and more difficult to get on the coverage as more as the year is progressed, because you have more and more difficulties to get access. I think our maximum coverage would be 70% approximately, which is what we have with our top product. I am much more proud about the fact that we have nearly 60% coverage in managed care, which is definitely a very good result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll echo that. Pretty much now most managed care organizations will want to have an experience with the product for six months before the P&amp;T committees meet and to the extent that you're on Part D formularies, that's even worse. And when you think that the average person with AFib is over the age of 70. You've got quite a bit of exposure to Part D. Now 57 is not good compared to say a product that has been on the market for three or four years. I mean, the big blockbusters typically get to 80, 90% Tier 2 coverage. But to do that before that even six-month window is up is actually pretty good. If it the number is on one of our slides, it's usually good news.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With high dose...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yeah, high dose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the high dose formulation in the U.S., 79% of the population over 65 was immunized for influenza in the U.S., so like most developed countries that is the large market segment. U.S. market varies in size from year-to-year because of the supplies and shortages but ballpark, 120 million people immunized. At least half of that is the elderly population.</p>
          <p>We have been in discussions with regards to reimbursement with Medicare, it will be reimbursed. Your question on premium price, yes, it will have a premium price. I'm not ready to give you a specific price other than to say, more than double intramuscular vaccine. And in terms of ACIP, ACIP is scheduled to meet in June, that's when they make their recommendations for the upcoming influenza season and we feel very strongly that they will be recommending this product for the elderly population. The data comparing immunogenicity is absolute. This product provides a superior immune response and that's irrefutable, and I think the thought leaders are pretty excited about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some over here. Take this side of the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric Le Berrigaud, Eric Le Berrigaud, Raymond James. Three questions, the first on operating cash flow, it seems that in 2009 operating cash flow was flat versus 2008 at 8.5 billion on the back of working capital negative by 350 million. Could you say a little bit about what you're doing in terms of working capital to make it &#x2013; to make some improvements there especially in terms of inventories for instance for the years to come beyond profits?</p>
          <p>Second on Merial, is it fair to expect that you would exercise the second option to merge Merial and Intervet, if and only if accretion is larger than the three, four percentage point EPS accretion that you mentioned for Merial as a standalone company? Or is there any other metrics that you're looking at to whether or not exercise the second option? And lastly in terms of diabetes, could you elaborate &#x2013; elaborate a little bit further on the next generation insulin that entered into Phase I, the concept behind it in terms of very long acting, and also on PN2034, perhaps just to tell a bit more on what kind of mechanism of action it is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You do the operating cash flow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On operating cash flow, well, first of all, you should, well I don't want to add too many details, but first thing is that the operating cash flow takes into account, the restructuring costs as we are going to, we are just spending. So if I exclude this element, I mean you can exclude it or not, but you know that we have embarked on a certain number of restructuring. So this impact is around 500 &#x2013; plus &#x20AC;550 million, if I exclude that, you would see an improvement of operating cash flow by 500 million.</p>
          <p>The second thing on &#x2013; in terms of working capital, yes, you are right to say that the working capital has increased by 840 million, if I quote properly, but first of all the activity has grown by &#x2013; so if you take the inventory-to-sales ratio, actually here you have some variations because we took some provisions on some Clexane last year, linked to &#x2013; so I mean, if you compare on the net to on a gross basis, it varies. But it remains that we have inventories in the range of nine months, and I think Philippe could comment on that from industrial activity, that well we have some plans to reduce that. But still I mean, in this business, what I learned is that the first thing is never be short of product when you're able to sell it. So it's different to other businesses. We have always a balance to keep for many reasons, both for public health reasons, and from just business reasons. So that's my comment.</p>
          <p>In terms of receivables, we are, we see a slight increase of receivables to sales. And this is basically due to the extension of activity on different carriers such as generic business, typically Zentiva. So we have some plans to where on which we work together with Zentiva to reduce the receivables. Now let's be clear, I mean, there are some countries where the payment timing is decided upon by states.</p>
          <p>So I mean, we can't do much around that, particularly with hospitals. So last thing which has been negative this year, and won't be the case the other year, that because we are spending much necessary we are spending less. We have less debt to our suppliers which is negative on our working capital. So in short, we are working on our receivables. We have some plans to re-use our inventories, but still I think this will remain an advantage also to have product available. So I'm not that concerned all in all with the working capital level. But we have some plans to reduce it in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So concerning Merial, obviously it is going to be a factor as to what does the combined unit look like versus a Merial stand-alone. And I'll let, perhaps Laurence comment a little further. I mean, I think you would say that if you looked at a Merial with the significant part of its business really in two products in pets sectors, particularly in the U.S. Now we don't expect to see generic activity in animal health like you see in human health, but there are some generic activities which would be expected to affect growth.</p>
          <p>If you look at an Intervet business, this is a business that's really production-animal based.</p>
          <p>And in fact in that part of the business, they don't even really think of themselves as being in the animal business, it's protein production. And essentially, if you look at the emerging markets opportunity, the fact that you've got a growing world population, a population that is expected to expand by 3 billion people over the next few decades, there's a huge increase in interest in productivity around food supply and food chain, which also has a direct factor related to that as being the underlying health of the animals that generate the protein.</p>
          <p>Also as you have Emerging Market macroeconomic growth, people tend to want to have better food. And what you see is that, as people gain more money, they want more protein. So you have to look at first of all, a strategic element, and come to some conclusions about</p>
          <p>the relative value of both propositions, but perhaps Laurence, you'd like to comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we gave you an idea of accretion of the step one. If we stayed at step 1, it's obviously quite a short-term metric. And whenever you compare two projects, if one of them includes combining with someone else. So having to divest some products immediately for competition reasons.</p>
          <p>And the other one is staying standalone, if you compare only on these kind of metrics, you handicap the combination project, if you look very short term. And accretion is by definition something that you look short term, which is kind of the sanity check, which of course we will take, and we are taking when we look at this project. But I would say it's definitely not the driving metric. Driving metrics is generation of value long-term, free of the business and long-term growth that we can have with this project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the diabetes? So our product from one stat in fact is an insulin inhibitor. It is an insulin sensitizer to give you an idea if its potency, it's exactly the potency of the BiPar, but without the side effects of BiPar and it is definitely not the BiPar. We have a FDA confirmation on this side. And it's extremely active on diabetic side restoring sensitivity to insulin, and at the same time we have proof of activity on this compound on top of most of the active anti-diabetic oral anti-diabetic compound with a very good activity.</p>
          <p>Before to go into Lola, which is our long acting insulin. I would like to go back a little bit to what was already said by Hanspeter about the association of our GLP-1 and Lantus. We have more and more the feeling speaking with keeping also a little bit with patients that what is extremely important is not the best control of HbA1c, but in fact is also the control of the peak of glucose during the day. And that you can achieve that only with a good association of a relatively short acting GLP-1, which is our case.</p>
          <p>And in fact I should say also GLP-1 without too much side effect, and I should say that in terms of the mitigating effect we are really, at least with what we've observed so far in the low range of side effects.</p>
          <p>So it's really an association, which is willing to address not the problem of HbA1c, but the problem of control of HbA1c and the peak of glucose. And so it is interest of the once a day GLP-1 because you cannot achieve that with the once a week GLP-1. And for Lola, which is a long acting, you have to consider two points that one day it's perhaps not enough. So we're looking to increase the duration of the action of insulin. So we do not know exactly how long it can be but, should be definitely more than one day. And at the same time you know you can always write the washers and what it does on white. So we have very few hypoglycemia with long use but we've seen some kind of the hypoglycemia with long use, and so we are aiming with a longer duration of action to reduce at the maximum, as a possibility of hypoglycemia with an insulin, which is quite an achievement again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll try this side of the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Philippe Lanone of Natixis Securities. Three quick questions, sorry. First on the combination of Aventis with the GLP-1, what &#x2013; could you elaborate a bit more on the timeframe. As it is a combination product, will it be a fast to go the market or we're looking at three, four years before the market?</p>
          <p>Second question on Taxotere, when did you file for the pediatric extension? Are you confident that you will get it in time before the generic arrives in May? So should we put in the model actually generic for Taxotere in November? And last point, I noticed that the others line in the sales model, which is &#x20AC;6 billion in sales, was only declining by 2% which is better than the past. And actually in the fourth quarter, it was up. So does it mean that generic &#x2013; that Emerging Markets are catching on here? And should we project a growing or a stable size here versus declining before that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. GLP-1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Taxotere exclusive, pediatric exclusive, we did our job, so I expect that we will have a extension up to November. For GLP-1 versus Lantus, we started already in fact the work, not with the definitive device. So as your reason I will say is close to 2013 for the combination of GLP-1 plus Lantus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The GLP-1 will get approved and be launched first and then the combination will follow. So on Taxotere, we've answered and then the other revenue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you're right that a part of it comes to &#x2013; from the fact that we are a &#x2013; I mean, we benefit from a higher sales in Emerging Market. But looking forward, I mean you have always to know you have two ways to make your projections.</p>
          <p>And one is to really look by product, another one is to look by growth platforms. And try to combine these two to see where we are heading, because we are really another way to look at the metrics of sales which is to say, well, here are the growth products, here are the other main products which are new to be generified, and then there is a same product in mature countries and then the products in mature countries, I mean still doing reasonably well, but probably still continuing to decline. So &#x2013; but basically your answer is &#x2013; your point is the right one, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the reasons I think it's good to look at Emerging Markets, and you're going to have products that are growing rapidly, some that aren't. But there is a portfolio effect in some of these markets where you need to have a range of products. Some of them will grow well, and so it depends on which matrix you're looking at it.</p>
          <p>If it's part of the growth platform, it will get lost, because the high growth products are offsetting that but you need those other ones to be present in the marketplace, and &#x2013; but that's fine. I'll also show you the line-by-line so you can see that, yes, there is still a part of the business that is stable but it doesn't decrease much and in some cases can grow.</p>
          <p>Next, Alexandra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Alexandra Hauber from JP Morgan. First question is just a follow-up question again to the GLP-1 combo product. When I first saw it, I thought, well, probably you're going to do once the GLP-1 is approved, you can probably do some sort of paper NDA so that's going to go quite quickly. But then you were talking about potentially looking at different endpoint as in the glucose P, so I thought well, that's going to delay, but still you talk about 2013. So how should I reconcile the two things? Is it that you're just going to try it on the market and then generate the data later on potentially on that endpoint?</p>
          <p>Second question is on &#x2013; coming back to the Fluzone High-Dose, let's assume you've got a tremendous recommendation from the ASIC. Could you &#x2013; would you be able to ship something like 30 million doses of that? And could you just go through how we should think about this? What's happening on the distributor versus the doctor level because I understand with a typical flu vaccine. You actually just sell to a distributor whereas this one you probably would mark to a doctor. So maybe you could win on both fronts this year, but how would it look like next year?</p>
          <p>Third question is completely different. I think on Greece, one of the reasons why the debt numbers got so bad is because all of a sudden that includes the healthcare payables. So I was just wondering given that &#x2013; we know it's particularly high-risk figures in the hospital business and since you have Taxotere and Eloxatin, what's your exposure to Greece if anything and how you deal with this? As in, have you been taking any kind of write-offs, is this is a number we should worry about that's sitting at some point your P&amp;L?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>GLP-1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will not show you &#x2013; still for nutrition inhibitors, HbA1c is to <mark type="inaudible" /> so we're just GLP-1 and HbA1c with also cardiovascular study, which are needed now at the present time.</p>
          <p>It is true that in terms of positioning, which is a little bit different than registering, we will try to position the association brands and GLP-1 as a treatment of choice in order to control in fact the daily peak of glucose and we will do study to demonstrate that we have good &#x2013; we have the better control of the peak of glucose and with any kind of association. But I think I'm not sure that we need definitely to have that in the label at the time of the launch. Definitely we need to have data to support our assumption that we need as a symptom to have a better control of HbA1c but also a better control of the peak of glucose. There is a lot of that happening into this direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And high-dose flu?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We're not going to sell 30 million doses in 2010. I think it's going to take a couple of years to build this product in the U.S, so will there be 30 million at peak sales? We believe so, which is one of the reasons why we built the new flu facility in the U.S. because the high-dose IM consumes four times the amount of antigen as a typical IM influenza vaccine.</p>
          <p>So you have to have the capacity to handle that, first. And in terms of the distribution, you may recall, maybe not, but 10 years ago there was a severe influenza vaccine shortage in the U.S. and the entire industry shipped through distributors and the stock market for flu vaccines went from $5 a dose to 25, 30, $40 a dose. After that year, we took all of our distribution direct because we bore the brunt of the complaining of the price gouging and yet it really was &#x2013; it was in the distribution channel where that occurred.</p>
          <p>That has given us couple of advantages. One is, we have a much closer customer intimacy because we do ship direct. So we have more consistent loyalty. Customers &#x2013; we know who cancels orders, we know who basically sticks with us, good year and bad year. And obviously we rank those customers and as a loyalty that builds both ways. So I think in 2010 will be the launch year and peak sales probably three years out and that'll be when the facilities are fully online and operational to support that kind of volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me on Greek hospital debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all the beauty of the sanofi model is that we are present everywhere. So we are dependent specifically upon any country or whatever. So actually, Greece represents a bit more than 1% of our yearly sales. We have got &#x2013; sorry, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. These have been partly accumulated over many years those payables. So -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, in terms of sales it represents a bit more than 1%. So I didn't &#x2013; I made a little mistake 1% of our overall sales.</p>
          <p>In terms of outstanding receivables, actually if I take the ratio of outstanding receivables to sales it has even slightly decreased last year and that is &#x2013; all in all if I include the public and the private sector much below one year. And we have improved the situation again beginning of this year and I think that goes much better on myself and the finest people. We are following that very carefully.</p>
          <p>Well, we have taken some provisions &#x2013; some reserves against that, but not much because experience has shown that we have already &#x2013; always been paid. So, I mean, the exposure is, at the end of the day rather limited and I think that, well, even if there is some concern about the future of the Greece economy, should you still believe that you are not going to be paid by Greece hospitals, I doubt that it would be the case. Because at the end of the day, it would mean back to an older question around, risk of a country belonging to the Euro zone.</p>
          <p>So yes, this exists. I mean, we're going to face &#x2013; we have been facing crisis in Venezuela, or in Russia or maybe one day in India, or one day here and there. But at the end of the day, the risk is really, very, very mitigated and once again, I mean, the overall outstanding receivable is around 200 million on which we have taken already a reserve. And within that only a small part of it is hospitals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Back there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's <mark type="inaudible" /> from ICAP. Question on Emerging Markets, please. GSK has said they've had to walk away from a number of Emerging Market deals because the prices have become too high and announced that a lull in activity. Your 2013 guidance includes further Emerging Market acquisitions, as you just said. So, how do you plan to extract more value than you peers so you don't destroy value in Emerging Markets?</p>
          <p>And then a question on the debt level after CapEx and debt, you have around &#x20AC;4 billion left. If you plan to continue acquiring, should we assume the current debt level is one, which you're comfortable with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start off with the Emerging Markets. I can certainly say that, we've looked at a few deals that GSK did that we didn't get anywhere close to even looking at. So I would say if anything, our hurdle rates on that are much lower than where they were, because we were scratching our heads as to how they could justify doing the ones they did do. Do you want to take the &#x2013; I mean, the reality is, is that there is an awful lot of stuff out there. And the deals that you're talking about are things, for instance that another big pharma company like BMS have been selling off. There are other deals out there and you do have to go looking and for us, I think you've heard we put higher hurdle rates on some of these investments, if it's in an Emerging Market, it's got a much higher hurdle rate to achieve than elsewhere.</p>
          <p>And we haven't actually done that many deals actually in Emerging Markets. Not because there aren't companies. There's 4,000 companies in China alone, there are 400 pharmaceutical companies in India. But you do have to find those ones that really do add value and I would say that when you look at what we have done, I think we actually have met what shareholders would expect us to do in terms of driving value. Do you want to take the debt question, J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean, we're starting with a very low-level, basically we were at 1.8 billion net debt. As you said, because of acquisitions, we have increased our net debt up to 4 billion. Still, I mean take these 4 billion and think about that 4 billion of free cash flow, we are going to generate over one year after dividends. It means basically that if we were not to do any dealing in 2010, which won't be the case. We have already done Chattem, we would be able to bring down to zero by the end of 2010. So I really feel that we are definitely still very comfortable. Also ratings agencies share this view, we have regular discussions with them, you know that we have AA rating which doesn't impose on the A1 rating with Moody's. And they both agree that we have a headroom to do some, to do further acquisitions and of course, this will depend upon which acquisitions you do, how strong is the cash flow is generated by these acquisitions.</p>
          <p>How visible also is the cash flows that you are going to generate. But clearly, I feel and if you compare to the competition, I mean a lot of our main competitors or last competitors have debt to EBITDA ratio, which are much beyond one even 1.5, or even some of them two, not to speak about smaller companies.</p>
          <p>So I don't say, we are going to do to going to go to two, but I feel that with a 0.3 ratio of debt to EBITDA, we are really on the lower end of the level of debt that we can bear. So once again I think that it will not definitely our &#x2013; should not limit our ability to do deals and acquisitions, to the extent these deals make sense both from the strategic point of view, as it was largely discussed today. But also from the return point of view, on a case-by-case basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Any questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean Jacques Le Fur, Oddo Securities. Some questions about BSI-201. The first one is, if I well understood Hanspeter &#x2013; saying that the filing date is expected to be late this year for breast cancer. So my question is, is there any chance to try to find, with the Phase II that are earlier than late this year. So, that means a few weeks or months?</p>
          <p>The second question is, will we have a chance to see the Phase II that will launch in the next few weeks. And in which manner we can see this data. And last question on BSI is, could we have an update on the patent situation? As if I remember well, the patent is to expire in 2013. So what is your expectation for the U.S to get for probably a five-year additional extension? And I have another question on the combo Lantus with your GLP-1. Just to try to understand the advantage of a GLP-1 is not to have any dosage of glucose in the blood. So when I think an insulin you will have to do such a dosage. So don't you think you will lose the advantage of having a GLP &#x2013; also GLP-1 with combining with an insulin? Thank You.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's a good question but I think you need to look the other way. Once you need insulin &#x2013; in fact the risk with the quick acting insulin is in fact is to get rid of the peak of glucose but at the same time you expose your patient to hypoglycemia.</p>
          <p>So if you are able to add inpatient who needs insulin, Lantus plus a GLP-1 you get rid of your peak of glucose without hypoglycemia and on top of that, with a potential advantage on weight, because you know that with insulin you are getting weight.</p>
          <p>In terms of BSI for submission, no, it's based on an interim analysis of the ongoing Phase III study, which is in fact going more faster than expected but still I do not expect that it would be possible to do the interim analysis also we need to be absolutely sure to have a definitive advantage in terms of survival and so because it might be &#x2013; the drug is active, we have less event that expected and so we are increasing a little bit the time in order to get these events. The third question that I do -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Will we see with Phase II data?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On breast cancer's initial results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lung cancer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, on lung cancer the research is just starting. Sorry. For that I apologize, I don't know exactly when it's supposed to be published so I cannot answer this question now. But I'm sure that S&#xE9;bastien can tell that. And the third question. The patent. It is true that we have one patent in 2017 but we have many other patent. So we are not commenting on that, we were submitted so I'm not commenting on patent we've submitted and taken but we are expecting &#x2013; in fact making this large life cycle management program, that that patent would be extended after 2020.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We know that 2013 date is absolutely irrelevant anyway, because you have at a minimum five years of data exclusivity from launch, plus the fact you can't launch &#x2013; you can't file for a generic in that five-year data exclusivity period. So you're typically going to be working with at least seven years from launch.</p>
          <p>We know that there is a patent extension that could take you up to 2018 depending on what indications and general counsel's sitting right over there. But I think you could even imagine a patent situation that goes beyond 2018. But I think what we've certainly said is we're going to have those seven years in U.S. And then obviously in Europe we got the 10 years and we don't want to lose anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a patent for the use in cancer, which goes up through 2018 plus the extension time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we have also &#x2013; I would not go into all the detail but we can &#x2013; because, when &#x2013; since all the patent on it is still registered, but we have patent, which is covering the product likely above 2020. It's why we are making &#x2013; starting our Life Cycle Management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So you've been very patient. We thought we might &#x2013; if you'd like to continue the discussion and questions in a little bit more convivial fashion, we'd like to invite you to a drink outside afterwards. We'd certainly like to celebrate our first year as a management team together. I think we had a great year. We appreciate the support of investors and analysts alike. And look forward to having a drink with you. So thank you very much everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>