<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1227459" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>59558</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Alfredo S&#xE1;enz Abad, Second Vice Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jose Alvarez, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, I'm going to begin the results presentation of the bank's first quarter and I'll divide the presentation into three parts. In the first, I'll speak about the highlights of the quarter and I'll review the Group's results. Then I will give the floor to Jose Antonio Alvarez, Group's CFO, and he'll analyze in detail the performance of the different business areas. And finally, I will close with some conclusions about the quarter and our priorities for the year.</p>
          <p>First thing, I would like to say is that Santander has had an excellent quarter in a very complex environment. As I explained before, this environment is an acid test for banks and it's going to identify the well managed banks which will standout from the rest. Santander as you will see is clearly amongst the good ones and there are two key aspects in the quarter, which confirm what I've just said. First the very consistent results we've obtained, brought by the performance of our operating areas and an income statement which demonstrates our management priority. Mix management, volume management and return management. Strong cost discipline and an effort to provisions based on forecast.</p>
          <p>We have been carrying out very active risk management, both in terms of anticipation and of recovery. And the second factor, confirming the consistency of our results is the strength of our balance sheet. Our risk quality is better than that of our competitors. We have large provisions. We have strong customer ratios and we have great ability to generate capital organically and to continue to pay out dividends. I'm going to speak in a little more detail about each of these aspects.</p>
          <p>The first is the consistency of our results. We closed the quarter with &#x20AC;2.096 billion in attributable profit, 5% less then in the first quarter of 2008, but it is 8% higher than the attributable profit of the fourth quarter 2008. And this profit has been obtained through the contributions of all the operating areas as you can see in the chart on the right hand side. The attributable profit in the operating areas have grown more than the Group profit, both in annual comparisons and with respect to the last quarter.</p>
          <p>First quarter of 2009 is the best in this whole series that you have in the chart. The operating areas have grown their profit by 9% if we look at the profit in the local currencies. There are however some aspects that have a negative impact on these results. The reason why they're not entirely reflected in the Group's profit, a strong negative impact of exchange rates in the operating areas, which subtract the &#x20AC;148 million from the growth. And secondly, the lower profits of corporate businesses mostly because of the decrease in revenues with the equivalent method and ROSs.</p>
          <p>We will explain when we talk about the different business areas. In order to understand the underlying performance in the Group, we should discuss the results of each unit in the local currency and this is the complete picture from this perspective. And the first conclusion we can draw is the enormous diversity of our businesses. And this diversity increases the resilience of our units downturns in the economic cycle. By geography the retail units in continental Europe have performed in line with the first quarter last year and clearly better than in the fourth quarter 2008. In Spain, our two retail networks, which 28% of the Group are growing between 6 and 7%, their profits in comparison with the first quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>In the U.K, which is our second major geography, the quarter once again demonstrates the sustainability of our British business. Abbey continues to grow strongly and the new contributions from Alliance &amp; Leicester and Bradford &amp; Bingley. Latin America has been hard hit by the exchange rates. But in constant currency they show sustained growth in this last quarter both in Brazil and in the rest of the regions. Finally, I would like to highlight the very successful performance of GBM where we've taken advantage of the gap left by other competitors whilst strictly managing risk, liquidity, and capital consumption.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the income statement, I would like to mention that in the first column we have included the Group results and that's including Sovereign, Alliance &amp; Leicester and the smaller acquisitions, Santander Consumer Finance from General Electric and Royal Bank of Scotland. The first, the column of percentage change reflects this favorable perimeter change adding 2% approximately to the profit although differences in the different lines. And the negative impact of the exchange rate between 7 and 8% for that reason we've added this last column on the right hand side where we have subtracted the perimeter effect and the foreign exchange effect and this I think will allow you to understand the evolution of the underlying results better.</p>
          <p>In this income statement of course we see the impact of a strong economic recession, but also the management priorities we announced last quarter. The first very active credit spread management or asset spread management is seen by the increase in our net interest income offsetting the lesser growth of fees due to decreasing activity. Secondly, our strong cost discipline, with costs staying stable or even dropping in some units. These costs are starting to benefit from the initial synergies of the integrations under way, but there is still a long way to go. The consequence of this evolution in our cost and income is a further improvement in our cost income ratio even including the new companies whose ratios are worse than Santander's.</p>
          <p>Net operating income is growing at double-digit rates, 15.4%, at 17.5 if we excluded the perimeter effect. Thirdly, very strong recovery activity, which is starting to show results and slight deceleration of NPL ratios although the growth is still significant if we compare it with last year. And now let's speak about our most commercial revenues, that is net interest income. If we look at fees and commissions, we will see that in some line fees and commissions are affected by the dropping volume. However, net interest income remains solid of course this is enhanced by the new acquisitions.</p>
          <p>You can see on the chart at the bottom that even in a very difficult scenario like that of the last quarter in Europe and in the U.K, our growth trends continues. There is only a drop in Latin America because of the exchange rate impact, subtracting that they are also very stable. What this demonstrates is the successful commercial performance of our unit and our strong resilience because of our geographic diversity and very diverse businesses. This evolution of net interest income which has grown in the year by 22% or 19, if we subtract the perimeter and exchange rate effect shows the success of our spread management policy. In customer spread in the last quarter we have been able to offset the drops that have been experienced by customer spread with the lending spread.</p>
          <p>In volume, volume in loan and customer deposits have followed suit, loans have decelerated because of less economic growth and falling demand. In Spain it has grown by 2%. In the U.K. by 8% in pound sterling without the new acquisitions, In Brazil and Chile double digit growth, and in Mexico we have actually decreased our lending. We don't have any liquidity or solvency issues and so we're still funding the needs of families and companies as long as the projects are viable and fit with our own strict and prudent risk management policies.</p>
          <p>We've been very active in lending programs for individuals and SMEs promoted by the ICO or the Official Credit Institute of Spain, and also by the Portuguese Government. And as for customer funds, we're still focused on deposits. We've grown by 15% organically, and then there's the acquisitions. And we have substantially improved the ratio of internal finances in the Group from customer deposits. So, overall we have succeeded at this policy and so most areas are showing significant increases in their net interest income as you can see on the slide.</p>
          <p>The drops in Mexico and Chile are due, in Mexico to strong recession in the country, but also to deliberate change of mix towards lower risk products in the last month. In Chile, the activity is greatly affected by dropping inflation rates, which will be offset as the year progresses. Since our customer policies have been very successful. The second basic engine is our improving efficiency. In the current scenario, we need to have stricter cost management and in this sense our total costs subtracting the perimeter and the foreign exchange impact basically remained flat with respect to the first quarter 2008. Also as you can see on the right hand side all the units are well under control with almost zero growth in real terms. This control of costs and the growth in revenues has enabled us to keep our and it was open for 5% absorbing the impact of the new integrations because without them the margin would be between 7 and 8 points.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we are still improving efficiency, we have dropped our cost income ratio already by 4%, 3% would be without the perimeter effect. But the efficiency ratio without the new integrations would be at 41.9%. We have improved with respect to the first quarter of the previous year in the three major segments. In summary, we continue with our successful policy of cost income improvement. In the past few years we've improved year-on-year and there is only a slowdown when we integrate companies with worse ratio and we then continue improving our cost income ratio by controlling costs and promoting revenue.</p>
          <p>For example, we have just integrated Sovereign whose cost income ratio was above 70%. I remind you that these were the levels Abbey had when it was acquired. Nowadays Abbey's cost income ratio is 40%. Now the third point, I would like to mention, is provisions. The macro environment has worsened faster and more deeply than expected and as a result there has been a worsening credit quality and a strong increase in provisions versus the first quarter of 2008 provisions have grown by 73% which with a constant perimeter would have grown by only 54%.</p>
          <p>As you can see on the right hand side, upper right hand corner, it's important to point out in the last quarter subtracting integration, there has been a deceleration in the establishment of specific provision. On the other hand, generic provisions have &#x2013; we have started to recover more intensely in the last two quarters and we have used about between 350 and &#x20AC;400 million a quarter.</p>
          <p>In the Group, I'll remind you that in the fourth quarter of 2008, the number was higher because we incorporated 380 million in one go, because of substandard credits. Starting on the left with specific provisions, there is no change with respect to the previous year. There is slightly more &#x2013; there is slightly greater impact in the Spanish network because of increasing NPL ratios in the sector. Additionally, there is a perimeter effect which is seen in Santander Consumer Finance, Sovereign, and the U.K.</p>
          <p>As for generic provisions, in the last quarter we used up &#x20AC;420 million in the Group overall, most of it in Spain where the Santander and Banesto network have used &#x20AC;326 million. This number is inline with our estimates that we reported last quarter and that is to use up between 1 billion and 1.5 billion in 2009 in Spain. All of the provisions, since the last quarter and the Sovereign incorporation give us a total loan loss provision of over &#x20AC;15 billion of which over 6.3 billion corresponds to generic loans, a number which has grown in this quarter because of Sovereign integration.</p>
          <p>In Spain, the allowance is at this level which if we used it up the same rate as the last quarter would keep us going for the next eight quarters. Finally, I'll just comment about the Group's ability to absorb larger provision. As you see on the chart, strong provision growth in the last year has been offset by spread management and operating leverage. As a result, our net operating income over net loans has remained almost entirely stable. That is even if we were to double the provisions with respect to today's rather high figure, the Group would still be profitable and also with a clearly advantageous position in comparison with our competitors.</p>
          <p>In the wide spread economic crisis our NPL ratios have grown as you can see in this slide and they will continue to grow, but in any case our ratios are very good. The Group's NPLs are at 2.49% and our coverage is above 80%. Considering the mortgage guarantees the coverage is of 115%. And by areas, the overall NPL ratio of all the businesses in Spain, Santander, Banesto, Consumer etcetera is at 2.4% with a coverage ratio of 81%. Abbey is at 1.25, lower because of the mortgages in the portfolio higher mix also lower coverage for that reason. Latin America has a high ratio 3.27, but quite stable in comparison with December 2008 and coverage is over 100%.</p>
          <p>How do these ratios compare with those of our peers. Well , as we've reported in previous quarter, we compare very well at the Group level but also in the three main markets where we operate, Spain, the U.K., and Latin America. In all of them, we clearly outperform most of our peers. In Spain, in the last quarter, we have outperformed the sector and the gap is widening, today we're slightly more positive then in the previous quarter because then we said that we expected our NPLs in Spain to reach 4.5% by year-end. Now we feel that we won't reach that level.</p>
          <p>Second, set of strength in our balance sheet, our capital base. We have ended the quarter with the core capital ratio of 7.3% to calculated on the basis of Basel II requirements. This was 7.5% in December and that's slightly higher than what we reported initially. When we use Bank of Spain criteria, the main difference is because in the Bank of Spain criteria, you subtract IT investments, which are amortized in our case in three years. It's a high ratio, especially from a qualitative point of view for two reasons. First because of the low risk of our balance sheet, it is very plain vanilla, very retail.</p>
          <p>Because of our very strict core capital definition where we subtract valuation adjustment and we don't' include generic provisions and because of our ability to generate free capital in a context in which there is low increase in risk weighted assets. In fact in the quarter, we generated 20 basis points of capital which has been offset by the negative impact of the consolidation of accounts from our acquisition. Additionally, and given this plain vanilla character and this retail character of our balance sheet. Our capital ratios compare very well with our peers in terms of tangible common equity over tangible assets.</p>
          <p>Going to Bloomberg data for December 2008, we are number two amongst this ranking of our peers. We have reached this ratio and this place in the ranking, thanks to our ability to generate capital recurrently in the most difficult part of the cycle while continuing to pay our shareholders our dividend by March. &#x20AC;7.83 a share, figure which has been growing continuously quarter-on-quarter for the last years.</p>
          <p>As a result our book value per share has grown by 46% since the end of 2005 and the current share price of our book value in this context would be a 0.8. If we take net asset value per share in a stricter sense, that is if we don't include in preferred or minority holding subtracting value adjustment and goodwill and intangibles the evolution is just as consistent growing every year and every quarter.</p>
          <p>Now, I am going to give the floor to Jose Antonio Alvarez, so he can explain in more detail the different business areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, as we usually do every quarter I am going to look in more detail at the different business areas, geographical areas. And I also talk about the secondary segments and the corporate centre and I also make some specific comments on Sovereign because this is the first time that it has been included in our accounts.</p>
          <p>The first thing, I wanted to say is that our earnings have performed very well. The CEO already mentioned the reason for that is spreads, the costs are basically flat, they've grown about 1% without perimeter with the change of perimeter a little bit more. And this means that the increase in revenue as well as good cost control gives us a possibility of making earnings increase by 7%, excluding the impact of exchange rates. And also excluding the impact of the perimeter which in the current context I think is very good given the economic circumstances.</p>
          <p>We have obtained the highest profit ever in our operating units. Therefore, if we look at the first important operating area which is continental Europe, the profits that has been achieved is &#x20AC;1.289 billion, 9% more than the same period last year. The drivers are still the same. We are still generating earnings in the global businesses that we will see later on particularly global wholesale banking is also having a very good year in terms of earnings and good cost control, which allows us to absorb greater provisions. Not so much part of retail banking, but basically in wholesale banking.</p>
          <p>If we look at the different units, you see in the different geographical areas, these revenue are growing ex-perimeter, there is a change in perimeter in Santander Consumer Finance by a digit. The net operating income, thanks to good cost control, is already two digits that after provisions and the use of joint provisions means that we have a growth of 6, 7 and 3% in the different areas.</p>
          <p>In Consumer Finance there has been a change in the perimeter and we will see this when we talk about this unit, but nevertheless there is good cost control there, it is an increase in spreads. Continuing with the trend from previous quarters in the others I would like to point out to very good results of wholesale banking in Spain. Although it hasn't done so well in the world of insurance and asset management where the fall of the volume of assets under management has had an impact on revenue.</p>
          <p>If we look at the network, this we also see in the Banesto network and also in Portugal where we see an increase in volumes and lending on the 3%, quite low very good performance on deposits and improvement in the spreads. On this slide, you can see the net operating income over total assets and costs are under control and this means with the flat evolution of the provisions because we had used up about 350 million in Spain between Santander and Banesto, this gives us results that was the ones we have shared with you a minute ago.</p>
          <p>In the case of Banesto, well we can say more or less the same thing, the growth is more or less the same as in Santander, the growth of deposit is greater than the growth of lending. And the use of generic provisions also allows us to keep provisions at level similar to those of last year which gives us a result of 6% in the case of Banesto a 6% before the $20 million put into the generic provision.</p>
          <p>Let me talk a bit more on Santander Consumer Finance because here there has been a variation in the perimeter. Here we have on the one hand very good performance of the spreads, we expected this, we had been announcing this in an environment of lower interest rates then the &#x2013; there we have the lending spreads which are going up quarter-after-quarter. A significant growth in volume because of a change in the perimeter, but even without the change in the perimeter the volumes would be growing significantly, 13% in lending, 33% in deposits. So, with and without a change of perimeter volumes are growing well.</p>
          <p>Cost control. Costs are basically flat, ex-perimeter sometimes, in some cases they fall significantly because of synergies for integration and the provisions are under control. NPL I'll will remind you than in the previous quarter, we talked about 5.66% of the end of the year in NPL rate, we feel very comfortable with our level, right now provisions, increased strongly, but all over, but since revenues are growing, we are very pleased with our results in the current economic circumstances.</p>
          <p>In the case of Portugal, more or less a same situation although the volumes have grown a little bit more. These spreads have increased more a bit, in provisions remain at low levels and the income statements show recurrent trends with one digit growth, but in sustainable fashion, the net margin and the provisions you can see have grown a little bit, one digit growth.</p>
          <p>If we take a look at the U.K., gross figures in the U.K. are very high for two reasons, first of all a change in the perimeter, but without a change in perimeter, the growth of Abbey is also very strong and let me elaborate a bit on something which might surprise you given the negative view that we have on the economic situation of the United Kingdom. Retail banking in the U.K., the net operating income we see is growing consistently. We will see later on that this is an evolution of the combination of an increase in volumes and also a good performance of the spread.</p>
          <p>Revenues grew 25% without change in perimeter and 67% if we include A&amp;L and the Bradford &amp; Bingley business. The contribution of costs, well costs are basically flat, they grow at only 2% and this gives us margins of about 50% which after provisions go down to 30% in Abbey, 50 or 60% if we were to include A&amp;L and B&amp;B which in the quarter give a result of &#xA3;60 million.</p>
          <p>Perhaps more than the results &#x2013; more than the earnings and the quarter-to-quarter growth let me elaborate a bit more on the sustainability of these results, why is this happening? Why are we having this excellent result? While if you look at the right hand side of the top the improvement of the spreads on assets is a drive, our quarter-to-quarter asset spreads since our first quarter of 2008 have come up from 374 to 686, in the last quarter it has improved by 40 basis points. This improvement in the spreads, on assets pays for the fall on the deposit side and therefore this trend which is still in the market allows us to be very optimistic with regards to the next few quarters when it comes to our business in the U.K.</p>
          <p>On the side of volumes, we see that they do reflect our priorities very well when we acquired A&amp;L we said there is a priority and we see that we have a stable stock of mortgages growing at 3%, different performance in Abbey, A&amp;L with 8, and 11% growth respectively, also a growth in deposits. So as a franchise, in Abbey 50%, A&amp;L 12% and if we put Bradford &amp; Bingley there too we have a growth of 35%. Corporate loans are growing at a good rate in the current circumstances, 8%. We see that they are growing more on the A&amp;L side, which has more business with SMEs and Abbey. Personal loans the UPLs, we have reduced our book of UPLs since we acquired Abbey by 50% and so far 18%. And the securities portfolio which is not our core business has also fallen 8%. And this reflects what our priorities are in the U.K., which we already announced when we made the acquisition of A&amp;L.</p>
          <p>The portfolio has excellent credit quality, our NPL is half of that of the industry. Our coverage is significantly higher than the average of the industry. And the quality of the underlying portfolio is significantly better than the industry, we don't have buy to let, only 1% of the book. The allocations are very low and we don't have self certified, which indicates that the difference in credit quality vis-&#xE0;-vis the industry is going to only improve.</p>
          <p>So things are going as expected, we have gotten ahead a little bit when the integration of Bradford &amp; Bingley technologically speaking, and the integration of A&amp;L is right on schedule. So, in brief, I would say that the U.K., we're very optimistic about the performance of the business in the U.K. and the capacity to generate results in this environment. Given the underlying dynamics of spreads, volumes, and provisions of the business.</p>
          <p>Latin America, which is the third important geographical area, the exchange rate impact against the dollar is up 20 basis points, we have an income statement where revenues are growing at 13% without the exchange rate impact cost and local currency are also flat. And the margins of 22%, which pays for that provision &#x2013; that increase in provisions. On the right hand side, we see that ex-exchange rates we're talking about levels of the first, second, and third quarters of 2008 and clearly more than fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Given the effect of exchange rates in this part of the business I am going to deal &#x2013; I am going to talk in constant dollars so that we can see the percentage changes in local currency, because it's better to understand the business. In Brazil we have good performance of revenues slightly better than we expected, we have less constant volume, the spreads are a little bit better than we expected, In investors day we expected an increase in interest rates in Brazil but clearly now they're going down.</p>
          <p>Costs are falling, that is something we announced as a result of the integration and therefore the net operating income is going to 27%. Provisions are also on the rise, there are some sectors in Brazil which have requested provisions. We see that profits are flat but also profits are significantly higher than in the previous quarters and we think this is a good basis on which to build on our objectives &#x2013; the objectives that we announced on Investors Day in Brazil. We still have good growth in terms of volume.</p>
          <p>Credit spreads are the same or slightly up. Costs, we have a strong potential to reduce these costs. We've already done some of that, but we still have some way to go there and we affirm the objectives of investor day although with a lower volume, but better spreads and what we except when we made the announcement in investors' day.</p>
          <p>Finally, with regards to the integration, I'd say that it's right on schedule. The Central Services have already been changed, we are doing all the integration. We have made a lot of progress, I would say that we're on schedule and as proof of these integration synergies in the quarter have been R$300 million, we announced for the whole of 2009, 800 million in synergies. Well, we are on the right track to achieve this objective. And the legal merger will become effective soon. Mexico has a weak income statement because here we don't have decrease in volume. We have stable spreads and therefore degeneration of income is weak that together with the increase in provisions comparatively speaking gives us a significant drop in the results in local currency.</p>
          <p>If we look at it by quarters we see that the comparison with the first quarter of 2008 is the most acid if we compare to the last quarter of 2008, we see a significant improvement. Why do we have the situation? Well, on the one hand we have a fall in lending, 6%, but even more important to understand the income statement is that there has been a drop in the credit card portfolio of 16% it's a very profitable portfolio, which has a high impact on net interest income and also on provisions. I'll talk about that later and that has a very strong impact on the revenue. We are managing the cost, we're going to zero cost growth, we come from two-digit cost growth.</p>
          <p>The situation in Mexico is different than in other countries. We had a increase in provisions, strong one because of the credit card business, we adopted measures, the entries in arrears of credit cards is improving. So, we are optimistic, we think that the arrears rate will go down in credit cards and so will provisions. So if 80% of provisions fall for credit cards, provisions for other parts of the business will go up, but in any case since there is no growth in volumes, there is no growth in revenues because of course we're in a recession.</p>
          <p>Chile, the CEO referred to Chile in his presentation, we have strong growth of revenues, we have of course the impact of negative inflation on the UF hedging portfolios, revenues of minus 60 million. But in the next few quarters we will go back to normal figures, normal recurrent figures that would be double digit in China despite the fact that provisions are right. In Chile we have good growth in volume, two digit, the growth of deposits and lending. Cost are falling and we have an increase in provisions and the effect of the UF as I mentioned earlier, but also an increase in provisions that with this dynamics of cost and revenues we should be able to absorb this through the net operating income without that impairing the profits of the unit.</p>
          <p>And finally a slide where we see the profit of the other Latin American units, the situation is different in the different countries. Argentina and Colombia, very much depend on deposits and the Santander Private Banking is suffering because of the fall in returns and volumes in market.</p>
          <p>Finally, the corporate center, here we're talking about variations vis-&#xE0;-vis the first quarter of 2008. There is a negative percentage change of minus &#x20AC;108 million. Last year it was minus 285, and this year it's minus 473, because of the equity accounted method that has been applied for Cepsa and Sovereign. That's at &#x20AC;112 million. Also lower gains on financial transactions impacted by &#x20AC;190 million of Metrovacesa, equivalent to &#x20AC;45 per share. And the rest of items, well, we have basically higher costs from renting the Grupo Santander City.</p>
          <p>And secondary segments, I'm not going to say much about retail banking, because we already went over that. The evolution is very consistent quarter-to-quarter and it shows high returns. In global wholesale banking, which I mentioned in passing when I talked about continental Europe, the performance has been very positive. The trends are very good in terms of revenues and very good cost control. The drivers of this is basically the spreads, and earning market share, these are the two drivers.</p>
          <p>The balance sheet is not growing, but lending is growing at 2%. Fair value at risk is basically stable, $34 million the first quarter of 2008 &#x2013; or it's 34 now, sorry 29 million in the first quarter of 2008, and we are earning market share in the world of syndicated loans and project finance, because some of the traditional competitors are in more difficult situations. And this has allowed us to earn more market share in this segment.</p>
          <p>Finally, asset management and insurance. There's been a reduction of 6% in the total revenues of the Group in this business; less intense in insurance. Well, they improved in Germany and Brazil but they fall in Portugal and Spain; and a lower volume of assets under management.</p>
          <p>Finally let me say a few words about Sovereign. We did global integration of Sovereign in the first three months of the year. This is the weight of Sovereign in the Group, 6%; a little bit more in deposits, slightly less in lending. But about 6% of the Group is now represented by Sovereign. In business, not in results unfortunately, not yet, but in the different item of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>If we look at the balance sheet, Sovereign, 78 billion in assets, this is purely retail banking, 51 million deposits and the remaining is portfolio available for sale and liquidity on both sides. We have 60% SMEs, 40% are retail customers and we have a coverage of 92%.</p>
          <p>The securities portfolio, which has been a reason for concern in some of the units has a volume of $8.7 billion, out of which 4.8 hundred are basically liquidity short term federal bonds with an average duration of three or four months. The portfolio which we have states and municipalities and mortgage backed securities, which is put at mark-to-market is about 4 billion. And the rating average is AA. And with the mark-to-market we feel very comfortable vis-&#xE0;-vis the current market circumstances.</p>
          <p>In terms of deposits, this is the space of deposits in Sovereign, basically retail 82% of retail deposits 9.2 billion, 20% more or less are more institutional in nature. The most important thing to point out here is that the deposit were falling 50 to 43 billion in the six months from September to March. Then there's a recovery of deposits and we are at the level of deposits that we had prior to the acquisition and the crisis in September with the Bank of Lehman and which generated a lack of confidence.</p>
          <p>Where are we right now after two months, after the &#x2013; completing the integration? Well, we are reducing risks. The securities portfolio has been adjusted. In fact, the balance sheet when we sold the Securities portfolio is short in terms of interest rate risk and this has affected the spread significantly, because of this reduction of this portfolio. We're reducing some lending activities that we don't consider to be core business, basically motor finance or car finance and others. So the risks have been reduced.</p>
          <p>We have increased our write-off. We were saying that we would need 700, 800 million. We have increased provisions in the book to 2.7% of the portfolio and we're now seeing the first cost savings. In this quarter we have already lower costs than in previous quarters and this is just the beginning of the cost synergies that we're going to achieve.</p>
          <p>All in all, the income statement for two months is not &#x2013; doesn't tell us much, but the results are 25 million with a cost to income ratio which is &#x2013; can be improved at 75%. That's what it is for this first quarter and with a high level of provision.</p>
          <p>With this scenario and with the plans that we are drawing up we can confirm the vision that we announced for the years 2008, 09, sorry '09, '10 and '11 for Sovereign in terms of the capacity to generate income for the Group. And now let me hand over to the CEO who will give you the conclusions before we take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so in order to conclude let me give you a summary of the presentation. Santander in the first quarter of 2009 and in a quarter which has been a very difficult one, we have obtained profits of &#x20AC;2.096 billion. The operating areas obtained &#x20AC;2.568 billion, which is a record in this quarter. The net operating income is very solid, more than double that of the provisions we made.</p>
          <p>We widened our advantage over our competitors in credit quality and we see better ratios in Spain than what we had originally envisaged. Plus, we have more than &#x20AC;6.2 billion in generic funds, we generate capital to keep our core capital above 7% and remain one of the best among our peers in solvency.</p>
          <p>And lastly, and also very positive, we are attaining our objective in synergies and the integration, which I interpret as a better trend than that first announced. In short, the Group's strength and our business model enable us to confidently face the next quarters and maintain our earnings.</p>
          <p>And if we look ahead, Santander's management will continue to revolve around two main elements. On the one hand, re-affirm our traditional management drivers, the strength in commercial revenues via spreads with a focus on deposits, maintain the emphasis on cost management and other jobs. We will extract as much value as we can from the business of recoveries through the creation of new units and, of course, we will remain very disciplined in the use of liquidity and capital.</p>
          <p>And the second element is to extract value from the new acquisitions for the Group. All of them are in the first phase of integration and, therefore, have not yet reached normal levels of profit generation. In this sense the integration is going very well in the UK, as Jose Antonio pointed out. And we are managing the first stages of Sovereign where everything is following its normal course, and we will report on this in the next quarters.</p>
          <p>For all these reasons we are very positive about the Group's recurring profit for the rest of the year, of course, within the complex environment. Thank you very much for your attention and now we will take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, let's take the question that we've received over the Web. We're going to organize questions by subject. Now when it comes to the strategy, that would be the first group of questions, Antonio Ramirez from Keefe asks, how do we think the financial system in Spain can be restructured, particularly the savings banks? And what is the position of Santander regarding organic growth? Or are we thinking of making acquisitions of assets in the Spanish market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The theory at Santander is the same for the banking sector as a whole and I think it has become very clear from the AEB. I think they even published a document on this. I am not going to repeat what the schema is but in turn at least based on the information we have, it looks like it responds literally to what the government and the Bank of Spain are preparing as the roadmap or however you want to call it for this restructuring plan. Basically, we're talking about the establishment of a new fund for operational purposes with additional amounts, which will be used for the plan which the Bank of Spain in agreement with any banks in trouble may require. I would say that our plan is &#x2013; our view is very much in line with that of the Bank of Spain. We are exactly in the same line, and so we agree. We specifically feel that this is a problem that has to be solved by each sub-sector and each company. If there are some banks in trouble, it should be the banks; if it's the savings banks &#x2013; the savings bank and to each his own basically. We don't have any interest in that &#x2013; second part of your question. In asset management, we're not interested in participating in any of these processes if they were to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sales strategy aspect, almost the same question, any potential acquisitions in Europe in the UK or in Europe if the prices were attractive and in connection with the UK talk also about the equity portfolio, if there's been any write-offs or same thing about the loan portfolio and do we have any portfolio that's very high risk in the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't have any plans for any acquisition. As we said in the last result's presentation and we said again today in Europe or outside Europe, so our answer again is no, in terms of our interest or our potential, any possibility of Santander Group pursuing an acquisition now or in the future. As for the portfolios we have in the UK I guess that's the question, there is nothing worth mentioning. The portfolio as we go out from Alliance &amp; Leicester, which was the only external one because Bradford &amp; Bingley did not entail any growth of our asset portfolio, has performed as expected. There has been no write-offs beyond the usual events in our loan portfolio, so it's behaving completely normally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far dividend policy and profit per share, Santiago Lopez from Credit Suisse is saying that we are in line to get an EPS of about a &#x20AC;1 and are we going to &#x2013; the question is if we're going to pay the same dividend per share we paid &#x2013; we've paid last year, which would be a 65% payout?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, payout policy will be defined at the time by the board and so to define it now wouldn't make much sense, not for the time. But I do &#x2013; but I can give you some guidance in general on this point. We plan to maintain the level of profits we obtained last year and since our payout policy remains the same, 50% payout and cash dividend without capital increases or acquisitions, so basically the answer would be around sort of what you said in your question. But in any case this decision has to be made by the board. But in any case for now we're not planning any changes in the general payout policy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daragh Quinn from Nomura, also talking about payout and dividends, which has also been answered. He is also asking about treasury stock, which has grown significantly, 5% he says it's evolution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well right now we have under 2% or less &#x2013; again less than 2% treasury stock, so we think that's a fairly normal level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Ronit Ghose from Citigroup has a question about refinancing and restructuring in 2008-2009. Have we done any and what's the policy we have for refinancing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well the debt restructuring we do is based on strict criteria defined by our risk management unit. We do refinancing and debt restructuring. Some cases have already been reported and are known. They are always based on solid feasibility plans, which make sense, which are well constructed with the solid and believable and feasible industrial basis or entrepreneurial basis.</p>
          <p>And secondly, any refinancing or restructuring always entails improved guarantees, additional collateral, always normally we do not increase the initial debt but perhaps reduce the principal to some extent or the bank's exposure to that particular debt. And I think basically that's the parameters that we handle in our refinance protocol. These are the points that'll have to be reviewed in any kind of case of this type.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From the financial perspective there's quite a lot of questions about capital, David Vaamonde, Fernandez, and some additional analysts are asking about our reported core capital for the first quarter of 7.3 and a difference with respect to the core capital we reported in December. Although I think you explained that already in the presentation, but it seems that you might need to explain it again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think it was explained quite clearly in the presentation, the core capital we reported in December was based on Bank of Spain criteria of 7.3. We're now using Basel II criteria comparable to lot of our peers, 7.5 in December and the 7.3 we've published now, but we explained that difference in the presentation. The Bank of Spain requires that the valuation of IT applications, in our case personnel &#x2013; the personnel valuation, which is amortized in three years in our case is deducted in one case and not in the other, that's the difference. So for like-for-like comparison with the rest of the sector, we have now reported the pure Basel II number, another Bank of Spain's method that's the only difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And talking about capital, Giovanni Carriere from Execution is asking whether we can give him the break down of the core capital increases of about 1 billion. I think it has already been explained too but also he's asking about that increase in reserves of 8 billion from December, especially because of the profit in 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's the retained profit from 2008</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the changes in the core capital, do you want to say anything about that, that 1 billion increase, 20 basis points you mentioned you want to describe it, provide any detail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also when our CEO was talking about the evolution of our core capital apart from adaptation to Basel II criteria we've generated an additional 20 basis points of core capital. We said that in normal conditions we would generate capital we said 15 basis points a quarter. This year risk-weighted assets haven't grown much, probably less than what we expected, but it does mean normal capital generation and consumption of 40 basis points for acquisitions; that's basically few basis points from the integration and rest is the Sovereign integration. And in Sovereign's case perhaps because during the acquisition we spoke about around 20 basis points, it's risen to 30 some basis points basically for two reasons. One reason is because when we made the proposal to acquire Sovereign, our core capital target then was six but now it's seven, and so that change in the target means that what was 20 basis points, is now 30. And then in the last quarter also Sovereign made some adjustments in its portfolio of 200, $300 million which has also increased that by a couple of basis points. So that's the plus 20 which is normal and the minus 40 is those two impacts of Sovereign and GE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daragh Quinn from Nomura is asking about our outlook for risk-weighted asset growth for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we talked about 5%. It will depend on the cycle. It would be there or maybe a little less, since lending institutions are growing very slowly this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ignacio Cerezo from JP is asking why again there has been this quarterly increase in the goodwill? That's been answered already. Why is the reduction in risk-weighted assets in the wholesale market in Europe and why such a strong growth in net interest income in that division and can we explain the valuation adjustments in comparison with the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, as for the wholesale markets' business, drop in risk-weighted assets, and improving spreads. Okay, the wholesale markets business, we established targets based on some parameters, which are growth in risk-weighted assets and the growth in liquidity used up by the business. Perhaps we're focusing more on managing those and that's the impact on risk-weighted assets. I also said that loans had grown by only 2% but net interest income had grown significantly. Improving spreads is simply a reflection of market conditions. If you look at the CDS' of major companies now and a year-ago, you will notice that there has been a significant growth in spreads, and the first quarter has a small impact but on the following quarters the improvement in the portfolio would be significant.</p>
          <p>And there is also as I said in the presentation more market share in some segments because of let's say the fact that people feel that Santander is open for business while some of our competitors perhaps are not quite as open or not perceived as being quite as open. Growth of risk-weighted assets, wholesale, financial margins there and valuation adjustments. We've already spoken about value adjustment, the mark-to-market of the portfolios available for sale. It's not significant in the quarter. There is a significant improvement actually because there's been an appreciation of the pound from December 31 to March 31, and also I think of the real and as a result the valuation of the goodwill improves. There is a drop in negative aspect. Opposite things happened. In the first quarter last year there was a strong adjustment. There are some depreciation and now there is a slight improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a question from <mark type="inaudible" /> about the possibility of any branch closures. How do we see the sector's result &#x2013; the sector's reaction to excess capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we right now are not really considering any sort of capacity adjustment in terms of closing any branches.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Looking at risks, or in the risk area and coverage, Santiago Lopez from Credit Suisse is asking about our current coverage policy, equity and income statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well there has been no change in our coverage policy in general. We are still covering the book value of the subsidiaries and different currencies. Basically we're still hedging the pound, the peso, and the real. It's the same thing for our income statement. I think we are close to a 100% either with forwards or option tunnels or hedges in all cases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Javier Bernat from Caja Madrid, Antonio Ramirez and Santiago Lopez from Keefe and Credit Suisse are asking about net NPL ratios growth in the quarter, any impacts from the perimeter change and information about the distribution and the growth of NPLs by area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well NPL in the quarter was 6.5 billion. I think that's the number and in the previous quarter it was 4.5. So basically there's been an increase from 4.5 billion to 6.5, so an increase of 2 billion. Basically, due &#x2013; it is exclusively due to Sovereign and GE. With the same perimeter our NPL in the quarter would have remained constant 70 basis points maybe difference and they are between the fourth quarter and the first. The difference all comes again from Sovereign mostly and the rest from GE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daragh Quinn from Nomura again is asking about the macroeconomic situation in the UK and Brazil and do we see any worsening of credit quality or the cost of risk in either of the two countries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in fact we had expected it and in our budget we expected rising NPL rates, and so some worsening of credit qualities in both markets, but again it was expected. It was in the budgets when we spoke about our outlook for the year, it was clearly included this worsening of credit quality. And so far in the UK we've not had anything worse than what we had targeted. We have seen a slight increase in Brazil, but we think it's purely circumstantial because we don't quite have our recovery systems fully up and running, because we're integrating them for the two banks. And when this happens over the next few weeks we think that the slight difference of the first quarter will disappear. So yes, as for your underlying question, in the sense that we do expect to see NPL rates to rise in both markets. But no in the sense that it might exceed what we had already expected at the end of the year for 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are a couple of analysts asking how our results are affected by the country risk classification, Brazil by the Bank of Spain. Have we changed our classification for that country's assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we've always had Brazil in Group III and so it's not changed the rating at any time. In fact the provisions we have for country risk for Brazil is significant just over 700 million, although of course it's true that in Brazil's case because of circumstances and performance and improving credit, we are probably tending towards placing it in Group II instead of III which is where we always had it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from First State is asking again about coverage and can we give some guidance about where we expect it to move, are we comfortable with the coverage levels we have? Could they worsen, especially when credit quality will continue to worsen in the future, hasn't touched bottom yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well in that case our coverage --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, we can't hear you too well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, our coverage ratio is not an input for our model. It's an output of the different coverage or hedging policies we have in the group. So it will depend on where the defaults are happening. If they are happening in high-risk segments, coverage levels for that are high. Look at Santander Consumer Finance where defaults can grow very fast and so their coverage is at 90%. If its mortgages with a loan-to-value of under 80% or coverage calendars are lot slower, coverage will be lower. But that's an output. It's not a particular policy. There will be units where the coverage is and will remain high and there's others where it will drop because of the weight of mortgage collaterals is significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and finally to finish with these risk and capital and financial questions, we were asked whether we still have any GE assets to integrate and Sergio Gamez from Merrill Lynch is asking whether &#x2013; or what is our guidance for capital generation in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For GE there is nothing left to integrate and we've already given that guidance. We've spoken about that quarterly generation figure which remains the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and for Spain, Sergio Gamez also from Merrill Lynch and David Vaamonde and Antonio Ramirez, are asking for an update on the real estate assets for this quarter, break down, have we started selling, provisions we've made? So he wants to be updated on the real estate figures we reported in December?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As for changes our position in December was about 3.8 billion. We have basically executed in January what we had already committed in difference processes, 500 million. We have written off about 100 million. We've sold another 100 million, so our position in March is 4.1. There's additionally some of our real estate that has been sold, but contract not yet signed for an additional 100 million. In the previous quarter we also explained what that would represent for the NPL ratio. 12% of this portfolio would have gone into default today, if we hadn't bought those assets in lieu of payment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As for risks in Spain they're asking whether we have a new guidance on NPL for 2009. With respect to that 4.9 we mentioned. How many generics have we used up in the Santander network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was 250. It's in the slides, in the financial numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alfonso Gomez from Citi and Matteo from BBVA were asking and Paco Riquel is asking since provisions have been low from your point of view and considering worsening NPL ratios, do we have any idea about how this will evolve? I guess he means recoveries also and whether we have any advance indicators that could tell us in 30 or 60 days how it might evolve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I said in the presentation and that when we reported results in January, we said that our best estimate for NPL ratios in Spain at year-end would be 4.5%. And that was a guidance we gave, as I've said, back in &#x2013; at the end of January. But right now the only thing I wanted to add is that I think it will actually be lower considering how it's been going, especially in the last few months and what we expect from the coming months, that we will not reach that 4.5%. We will remain at a lower percentage. But I can't really be a lot more specific than that right now. Just to emphasize again, that right now we feel, let's say, slightly more optimistic than we did three months ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay final question about Spain, about Metrovacesa, can we explain the 190 million provision you mentioned in your presentation, where and how and price of share I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I've said that. It's been charged against our earnings from financial transactions of the corporate headquarters and it's equivalent to &#x20AC;45 a share of Metrovacesa, which is what the auditor has valued it at the end of 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And for the UK there are several questions about financial margins from several people, Alberto Cordara too. Question basically is about the evolution of net interest income and financial margins. Why is it growing so fast? Do we have an outlook for that income? Are we going to maintain that strong growth? And any guidance for spreads in the country, I think that's basically the top lines of our income statement questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know what the number is that he's referring to. Let's not forget that in the acquisitions that we made in 2008 &#x2013; in the last part of 2008, the most important, let's say, were the ones in the UK. And so in the numbers, in the UK we have Abbey, we have the new acquisition, and we also have Global Wholesale Banking, the London office, the wholesale markets' business, which is based there. So it's a combination of all three things and possibly that's why it looks like the net interest income is growing so much.</p>
          <p>But if we break that down and look at the sustainability of each of those elements, I'd have to say that the retail business, that is Abbey plus Alliance &amp; Leicester and Bradford &amp; Bingley, are reasonably sustainable and will continue to grow in the current competitive context in the UK. Spreads will evolve as we expect. So we're not really seeing any changes. So in the coming two quarters, maybe three, and then later we'll see. It doesn't seem like this is going to change much, so a positive outlook and sustained growth.</p>
          <p>Same thing goes for the global markets &#x2013; Global Banking and Markets business, mostly because, as we know, the lending spreads to corporates in Europe, which are the ones that are managed from the London office and which contribute to this growth, we expect will continue at least in the near future to be quite high. So we feel that these spreads in the UK basically are sustainable and will continue over the coming quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And finally, about the UK two questions, also about spreads and margins; one from Antonio Ramirez and whether the liability spreads are really offsetting the growth in the lending spreads, and how we expect this to evolve?</p>
          <p>And there's another one from Alberto Cordara about the standard variable rate, mortgages and how our spreads are evolving there and our margins, are they growing, since generally the price set by Abbey for these products tends to be high? And do we expect to be able to maintain those spreads and those prices for that kind of product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I've said this already. I don't know whether Abbey has big market share in standard variable rate. I'm not certain. But in any case the impact of rising spreads is felt in every market in the UK, and especially in Europe in mortgages and that's consistent and continues, and we expect it to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, moving on to Santander Consumer Finance, there's just one question from Paco Riquel and he says, the cost of risk in consumer finance has stayed flat in this quarter in comparison with the previous quarter at 3.5% in spite of worsening NPL ratios. Could we discuss this cost of risk? Has there been any generic provisions used and what's our outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yes, in effect the Consumer Finance, to talk about the trends in the NPL rate and in risk we would have to do it by geographical areas.  We have Germany, which is practically half of the business and more than half of the earnings, which is doing very well in terms of volume growth and risks. The NPL rate is going up but very little. We have Drive in the U.S., which is performing very well as well in volume as well as in the capacity to generate earnings. And then we have our weakest part, which is in Spain where the NPL rate has gone up &#x2013; went up strongly in 2008 and now we are at levels where it still goes up, but at a lower pace.</p>
          <p>The cost of credit in Drive is related to the secondhand car prices. These prices have gone up in the U.S., and this is why costs have gone down, because we get more recoveries, although I'm not certain that a 100% that that is the effect. But we said in December that the NPL rate was going to be 5.5%, 6% and we think that is still the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we go into Latin America now, Francisco Riquel asks about the offset between trading gains and the net interest income. He doesn't say it by country. He asks in general terms for the division as a whole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in Chile it's very clear with the U.S. effect, the U.S. brings down the net interest income, and normally there is a part &#x2013; not all of it, but a part of it, which is offset by the trading gains. In the other countries, I don't think there is any compensation, any direct offset. It is true that the trading gains have performed very well in Brazil and in Mexico in a context of lower interest rates. The reduction of interest rates hasn't been as strong as in Chile, but it has happened and that affects the trading gains. And then, of course, we have ALCOs in other countries which have some capital gains, but we haven't obtained significant figures of that &#x2013; from the ALCO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From Mexico, David Fernandez from La Caixa and Ronit Ghose from Citi have questions. Both of them ask about the performance of the interest margin over assets, which is falling. What are the reasons that explain this drop? Is it going to continue to fall? And if that happens, how are we going to offset that with perhaps other cost cutting exercises?</p>
          <p>And they also ask about the fall of the portfolio for the division; the portfolio Mexico. They say it falls from 230 billion pesos to 245, there's been any transfer or selling of portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Mexico I think I mentioned this in my presentation. The main fall is in the credit card portfolio, which is a portfolio whose spreads are about 20%. When there is a fall in that portfolio, the other &#x2013; the remaining part of the portfolio, basically the commercial portfolio with lower spreads, 3 or 4%, that has a directive impact in the interest rate margin, a strong impact, which has not been offset by increases in volume in other portfolios, which tend to increase those spreads, but the net effect is very negative. The fall of 16% I think comes &#x2013; I'm speaking about euros. &#x20AC;12 billion in portfolio in Mexico, the credit card portfolio represented 3, 3.5 billion, so therefore that drop is very strong and that explains that performance.</p>
          <p>Is it going to continue to fall? We don't think so, at least not at the same pace. We've started to introduce measures in February 2008 when it comes to credit cards. And this is the effect of several quarters taking measures on admissions and sales procedures and recoveries in credit cards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They also refer to operating cost. Have you taken any measures to offset the fall in margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the presentation I also mentioned that the costs were going up two digits and this year they think they're going to grow zero. In fact, we are reducing the structure in the country and we think this year we will have about zero cost increase in Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To finish with Mexico, there's a question on whether the provisions and the impairment of the credit quality if we take &#x2013; if we hit rock bottom or things are going to get worse? This is a question from Ronit Ghose from Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we think in credit cards we left the &#x2013; worse has already passed. In the rest of the portfolio our credit quality has been impaired. 80% of the provisions in Mexico were for the credit card business. And, therefore, we see a certain fall in provisions because of the credit card portfolio, because a fall in the volume and because of an improvement in quality, and an increase in provisions in the other portfolios, because given the economic circumstances in the country, there's going to be also an impairment of the other portfolios apart from the credit card portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brazil; two or three questions, Santiago Lopez from Credit Suisse, do you have that &#x2013; still that objective of 100 million real in the net income announced on Investors' Day in November?</p>
          <p>What is the performance of spreads that you expect in the future for 2009, and if we have suffered a significant impairment in the credit quality of the consumer portfolio? This is from Alfonso from Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The objective, yes. The performance of the spreads, I would say that it's relatively stable. It has improved a little bit, but we could say it's relatively stable. In the spreads &#x2013; there's a reduction in the spreads, but they're more or less stable.</p>
          <p>The impairment in Brazil is related to some industries in Brazil, particularly the meat industry which is suffering, and is in a very difficult situation, and that is where we see an increase in the NPL rate and, therefore, an increase in provisions more than we expected. This has not &#x2013; this isn't really too related to consumer lending, but to the industrial sectors that are suffering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's it for Latin America. Now Sovereign, two questions from Giovanni Carriere from Carelli Execution; one is the reconciliation between the historical data and the presented or reported data. But you will find that information on the web. Can you give us an idea on the increase in the NPL ratio in Sovereign? And what about the objectives that you announced in &#x2013; the day the acquisition was announced? Or in terms of profit, do you still have those same profit targets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the increase in the NPL rate, well, it's because of the market circumstances. We have given it broken down portfolio by portfolio. Too much of our real estate, for example, is suffering; companies a little bit less. We've gone through the whole portfolio in detail, and we think that the levels of coverage and provisions are the right ones and, therefore, we feel comfortable that we will be able to achieve those figures that we announced when we made the acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now to finish the last question from Ignacio Cerezo who asks about the Wholesale Banking. You already discussed this but his question is on the strong increase of the net interest income over total average &#x2013; the average total assets. What do you expect there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we mentioned this. These corporate portfolios, despite the fact that in our case they're not too significant in size, they come from the old world of very low spreads, and every renovation or extension of a credit line means bringing up the net interest income. Most of the companies included here have a CDS, and if you look at the CDS of companies today compared with CDSs of companies two years ago, you will see that they multiply by five to 10. The mix was getting worse. But now for 18 months, we have been improving the mix, and this is just the result of that. There is no volume, only a 2% increase in the portfolio, so it's pure spread.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that &#x2013; I think we have no further questions. We haven't received any calls over the conference call. We hope we have answered all your questions. And if we have not answered all the questions, we got over the web, please do get in touch with the Department of Relations for investors and we will answer your questions there. Thank you again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>