<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1398586" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>769</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Stefan Gruber</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Co-Chief Executive Officer">William R. McDermott</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Co-Chief Executive Officer">Jim Hagemann Snabe</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Werner Brandt</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Adam D. Wood</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Technology Officer &amp; Member-Executive Board">Vishal Sikka</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Rick G. Sherlund</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Marc A. Geall</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Philip A. Winslow</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Gerardus Vos</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="William Blair &amp; Co. LLC">Laura J. Lederman</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Baader Bank">Knut Woller</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Michael J. Briest</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to SAP 2012 Second Quarter Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Stefan Gruber. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning or good afternoon. This is Stefan Gruber. Thank you for joining us to discuss SAP's results for the second quarter 2012.</p>
          <p>I'm joined by co-CEOs Bill McDermott and Jim Hagemann Snabe, our CFO Werner Brandt, as well as Vishal Sikka. Bill and Jim will begin the call with remarks on this quarter's performance, and then Werner will review the financial highlights. We'll then have time for Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Before they get started, as usual, I want to say a few remarks about forward-looking statements. Any statements made during this call that are not historical facts are forward-looking statements as defined in the U.S. Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Words such as anticipate, believe, estimate, expect, forecast, intend, may, plan, project, predict, should, outlook, and will and similar expressions as they relate to SAP are intended to identify such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>SAP undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements. All forward-looking statements are subject to various risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from expectations. The factors that could affect SAP's future financial results are discussed more fully in SAP's filings with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, the SEC, including SAP's annual report on Form 20-F for 2011 filed with the SEC on March 23, 2012. Participants of this call are cautioned not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements, which speak only as of their dates.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Bill, I would like to note that starting with the reporting for the second quarter 2012, SAP will report both software revenue by customer location and software revenue by location of negotiation, because this better reflects the reality where our business is done. The focus of our communications with the capital markets will be on the reporting by location of negotiation. For additional information, please refer to the appendix to our Q2 earnings release as well as our second quarter 2012 interim report; both documents are available in our website.</p>
          <p>And now, I would like to turn the call over to Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stefan and thanks to everyone for joining the call today. We really appreciate it. As you can see from the numbers, SAP's momentum continues. Q2 was our best ever second quarter. We exceeded &#x20AC;1 billion in software revenue for the first time in the second quarter. We beat market expectations, delivering results at the high end of our guidance with 26% year-over-year growth, 19% at constant currency in software license sales. Our software and software related services revenue in Q2 grew 21%, 15% at constant currency, and came in at the midpoint of our guidance.</p>
          <p>This is our tenth consecutive quarter of double-digit software and software related services revenue growth and it's been driven by stellar growth in mobile, HANA, and cloud, as well as our core business. Our operating margin was 30%, slightly impacted by the SuccessFactors acquisition and severance expenses. We also invested significantly in future growth during the first half of this year by adding approximately 5,200 employees, of which about 2,000 were from acquisitions. With our 61,000 employees worldwide, we will drive innovation, further expand our global reach, and accelerate growth like never before.</p>
          <p>We delivered double-digit growth across all regions, despite the volatile global economy. Companies are leveraging technology from SAP to innovate, reinvent business models, and to grow. We have the broadest portfolio of innovations in the industry. If you want to be more efficient and productive in any operating environment, you need SAP. It's clear that we've entered an era defined by a consumer driven technology revolution. Consumers will fully own their value chain, and companies have to automate and personalize their business models to keep up. The Internet of things will lead to 50 billion connected devices by 2020, allowing businesses to completely change how they interact with their customers. We are already seeing intelligent vending machines, connected vehicles, connected healthcare devices, and smart meters driving this.</p>
          <p>To anticipate the needs of this new consumer, companies are rethinking the way they manage their business. I believe that information technology is becoming business technology, because companies are shifting technology spend towards strategic software that helps them reimagine their customer interactions, mobilize their workforce, gain instant intelligence from big data, and drive operational excellence through the cloud. Our customers are turning to SAP as their preferred platform for knowledge driven innovation and the future of their business. As a result of this, we continue to gain market share from our competition. On a trailing 12-month basis, we are growing 20% faster than our nearest competitor, and we have strengthened our number one position in the enterprise applications market.</p>
          <p>Now, let me move on to our outstanding regional performance. I'll talk about this in nominal currency. The Americas delivered a strong Q2 with a 32% year-on-year software growth. The U.S. delivered solid double-digit growth and has good momentum following the adjustments we made at the start of the quarter. We continue to win new customers, such as Crocs, a leading maker of footwear, to raise their game and accelerate their growth. Crocs chose to move to SAP from their existing software vendor. With over 300 styles of shoes sold around the world, they need to optimize global production and distribution.</p>
          <p>The NBA, the professional basketball league in the United States, selected SAP to run better. By leveraging our world class analytics, we will deliver the NBA deeper insights and better connectivity not only to improve the action on the court, but the game behind the game. This is really exciting.</p>
          <p>Latin America delivered a record quarter with strong contributions from our breakthrough innovations. Mexico, Chile, and Colombia were instrumental in driving this growth. And one of our big wins in Latin America in Q2 was Grupo P&#xE3;o de A&#xE7;&#xFA;car, the largest retailer in Brazil, who will use our retail solutions supported by HANA and mobile innovations. Additionally, one of our first HANA customers, a Mexican retailer who piloted our flagship in-memory technology a year ago, came back and made a significant investment in SAP HANA and will use it to power their entire inventory system.</p>
          <p>EMEA, everything we've been hearing about Europe, here we go. We delivered excellent results in EMEA, 22% year-over-year growth in software revenue and outstanding performance considering the very strong second quarter of 2011. It's even more convincing given the ongoing macroeconomic uncertainty in Europe. We added over 2,000 net new customers in EMEA including many in the small medium size enterprise sector.</p>
          <p>We saw a strong contribution from the UK, France, Austria, and Switzerland in particular. The investments made in Russia and the Middle East and North Africa, they're paying off as well. And I'd like call out Germany's excellent performance, which grew once again by double-digits this quarter. In EMEA, we grew twice as fast as our nearest competitor in Q2 and four times faster than them on a trailing 12 month basis. We continue to win customers from the competition. TUI Travel for example, chose to replace its Oracle financial system in the UK and Central European subsidiaries with SAP.</p>
          <p>Asia-Pacific and Japan, APJ reported their best Q2 ever with stellar 25% year-over-year software growth. We are significantly outperforming competition in APJ and growing eight times faster than our nearest competitor on a trailing 12 month basis.</p>
          <p>In this region Japan and Australia stood out in particular. A customer I'd like to call out is Japan Post Holdings who replaced their Oracle system with SAP BusinessObjects software to better analyze and manage their costs in real-time. China grew by more than 30%, our best Q2 ever in China. We continue to invest in China and have increased our sales head count there by 50% this year alone. These investments are starting to deliver tangible results.</p>
          <p>We also had strong success in Australia with our cloud solutions. For example, in the Australian public sector, we recently closed the largest SAP Business ByDesign win ever for financials and payroll as a service, beating Workday and Oracle in the process.</p>
          <p>Industries, another growth driver is our unmatched industry expertise. You know, we go to market in 24 industries and we're good at them all. This quarter we saw a stellar performance in financial services and retail in particular, which both grew by more than 60% year-over-year. Banking was an industry where we had limited presence just two years ago. Now it is our fastest growing industry. We also grew more than 20% in more traditional verticals such as manufacturing.</p>
          <p>Ecosystem update &#x2013; a key element of our growth story is our open and ever expanding ecosystem. Our indirect channel business now represents one-third of total software sales. We are on track to reach our goal of 40% of revenue through indirect channels by 2015. Partners continue to play a critical role in delivering our innovations, especially for our small and mid-sized enterprise customers. For example, our SAP Business One partners now deliver in-memory analytics through our SAP HANA Edge edition to many small customers around the world.</p>
          <p>Our services partners see our momentum and are embracing SAP innovations as well. They are significantly increasing investments in their SAP practices. They are now adding more than 50,000 trained consultants to their SAP practices in the last six months alone. And they are building on our culture with our customers of co-innovation.</p>
          <p>So, how about the outlook? In summary, our Q2 performance was excellent. Our pipeline is strong across all regions and industries. Our growth strategy is working, and we continue to be the better choice to help companies run like never before. We are confident that we will achieve our full year 2012 revenue and profit outlook.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn it over to my partner and Co-CEO, Jim Hagemann Snabe. Jim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Bill. Well, you said it nicely, 10 consecutive quarters of double-digit growth. This proves that first of all, our innovation strategy is the right strategy and secondly, that we're executing well.</p>
          <p>You may recall that two and a half years ago, we decided to drive our growth through innovating the future instead of consolidating the past. We decided to focus all of our attention on customer driven innovation of business software delivered without disruption, instead of going into hardware, or <mark type="ph" /> disrupting (13:00) customer IT landscapes.</p>
          <p>When we analyze the results now 10 quarters later, two things are clear. First of all, our strategy delivers strong growth opportunities for SAP. With our innovations in mobile, database and cloud, we have doubled our addressable market. In addition, the business software market is the fastest growing segment in the IT industry. While the total IT spend is likely to grow with maximum 5% per year the coming years, innovative business software, our segment, is growing by more than 11%. This shows the transformation of IT spending, which SAP's strategy capitalizes on.</p>
          <p>Secondly, customers appreciate our strategy. IT landscapes are transforming radically, data moves from disk to main memory, IT infrastructures move to private or public clouds, and the user experience moves from PCs to mobile devices. By delivering innovation across our five categories based on a consistent architecture and road map, we offer customers a smooth transition to future landscapes without major disruptions or costly upgrades and we deliver business value at every step of the way.</p>
          <p>For example, a large manufacturing company in Nordics choosing SAP to consolidate the majority of its applications from various different vendors into one consistent core application, SAP Business Suite 7, and leveraging mobile devices for their mobile workforce to improve efficiency and speed. They also selected to run the Business Suite on the ASE database from Sybase to allow them to transition to HANA as the future technology platform later without disruption. We have great momentum across all innovation categories, and we are definitely increasing the gap to competition.</p>
          <p>Let's look at each of the five categories and the strength of our innovations. First of all our core, the applications and analytics. In applications and analytics, our experience in core business processes coupled with our deep industry knowledge is a key advantage and differentiator for SAP. We gained market share in applications for the seventh quarter in a row. We have the most modern installed base, with more than 80% of our customers now on our latest on-premise product, SAP Business Suite 7. This is an important indicator for customer loyalty and future growth opportunities. And in the SME space, SAP Business One is the most successful solution in the market with well over 35,000 customers. The latest version of Business One will be running completely on HANA in main memory.</p>
          <p>The reason for our success in our core is very simple. We offer innovation without disruption that help companies navigate and optimize in unpredictable times. During the second quarter, SAP received a number of industry recognitions in these categories. For example, IDC ranked SAP number one in business analytics and Gartner ranked us first in business process management. This is a clear sign on how we have extended our leadership in our core.</p>
          <p>Mobile, we had an outstanding quarter in mobility, with &#x20AC;54 million in revenue. We are on track to double our mobile revenue this year. We closed the largest mobile device management deal in our history, perhaps in the entire mobile industry, with a major hardware company that was standardized on SAP solution for mobile security. We're also seeing good traction for mobile business applications. For example, banks are leveraging our Sybase mCommerce 365 product for mobile banking, and Syclo, our latest acquisition in the mobile area, has already made a significant contribution to our mobile apps business.</p>
          <p>Let's look at database and technology. SAP was recently named by IDC the fastest growing enterprise database vendor in the market. SAP HANA, our next generation database platform, is accelerating our growth in this category and transforming the market. HANA wins the gold medal this quarter, with an &#x20AC;85 million in license revenue in Q2 alone, and we are on track to achieve our plan of doubling our HANA revenue for the full fiscal year. This product is proving to be truly transformational for the 100 companies that are already live and the nearly 500 companies who have purchased HANA so far.</p>
          <p>One of the largest growth drivers in the HANA business is Business Warehouse on HANA. And with the rapid deployment timeline for BW on HANA, which installs often in less two or three weeks, our customers are quickly realizing the value of HANA and understanding its transformational nature. Customers who have tried HANA are coming back to invest in it as their platform for the future.</p>
          <p>Our high performance database solutions from Sybase also continue to gain traction. We are seeing more and more customers adopting Sybase ASE as the database to run SAP applications.</p>
          <p>And finally cloud, the acquisition of SuccessFactors combined with SAP's own cloud assets now make us a major player in the cloud business. With more than 16 million users, we have the largest installed base in the business cloud. SuccessFactors business continue to accelerate under Lars Dalgaard's leadership and the SAP family, with billings up more than 100% in Q2 compared to SuccessFactors standalone.</p>
          <p>A large German pharmaceutical company, also an SAP customer, chose to replace software from our competition to run many of its HR functions in the cloud with SuccessFactors. This is one of the deals that would not have been possible without the strong synergies between SAP and SuccessFactors. And notably, SuccessFactors is now running SAP Business ByDesign to run its business and successfully closed its books this quarter with the system for the first time. We continue to see increased demand for SAP Business ByDesign from upper mid-market companies and subsidiaries of large ones as mentioned by Bill.</p>
          <p>When you look at the solutions in the five categories, the true value is in the combination. We have strong momentum as you've seen in each one of the five categories, but our unique ability to combine the innovations from these five categories, together with our unmatched industry experience across 24 industries, allows us to offer solutions to fundamental business challenges in ways no one else can. Through our best practices experiences by industry, we make it easy for our customers to deploy these solutions at high speed.</p>
          <p>The key is our rapid deployment solutions, which combine best practices, software, and services, for rapid time deployment and value. This approach allows customers to implement proven best practices at a fraction of cost and time of traditional implementation processes. Over 1,000 customers purchased more than 1,800 RDSs [rapid-deployment solutions] since their introduction in September 2010, and almost half of those were sold in the first two quarters of this year.</p>
          <p>Finally, let's talk about operational excellence at SAP. Besides driving innovation for growth, we've also focused on improving our operational excellence inside of SAP. We have increased SAP's R&amp;D effectiveness, which is our core process, for 10 consecutive quarters. For example, we have accelerated our innovation cycles for SAP Business Suite by 29% since last year. Overall, we increased the number of products delivered by 34%. In addition we implemented our cloud and in-memory technology to increase efficiency in our internal processes in general.</p>
          <p>So let me conclude. With our current momentum on the top line driven by innovation and our efforts to improve operational excellence, we are confident that we will reach our guidance for this year, and we are on track to reach our 2015 ambitions to achieve more than &#x20AC;20 million &#x2013; &#x20AC;20 billion of revenue, a 35% operating margin, and reach one billion people with our software.</p>
          <p>I will now turn over the call over to Werner for additional financial highlights from the quarter. Werner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jim. Both Bill and Jim gave you an overview of a great second quarter coming off a very tough comparison from last year. We grew double-digit in all regions and our new innovations are performing extremely well. Having said that, I want to give more insight on the top line and the overall results in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Before I do so, let me provide more details about our non-IFRS results, which are the figures that we use internally to look at our operating performance and as the basis for our guidance. I also want to make a few comments concerning non-IFRS adjustments and our future cloud segment.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter, we recorded non-IFRS adjustment of &#x20AC;134 million for acquisition-related and restructuring charges, &#x20AC;98 million for share-based compensation expenses, and &#x20AC;2 million related to discontinued activities. In addition, there were deferred revenue write-downs from acquisitions of &#x20AC;18 million. We have also updated our expectations for the 2012 non-IFRS measures. The details can be found in the press release issued earlier today.</p>
          <p>We plan to establish a separate cloud unit, combining the SuccessFactors and SAP cloud business. The cloud unit is expected to qualify as a separate reportable segment. However, due to the short time since the acquisition, we have not yet finished defining the cloud unit and we will not have finished adopting our management reporting of the new structure until the beginning of the third quarter. This will provide even more transparency into our cloud business.</p>
          <p>Bill already gave some color on the tremendous top line performance across all regions in the second quarter. In addition to his comments on the strong software and SaaS performance, I want to go into more detail into our recurring revenue stream. Non-IFRS support revenue increased by 10% at constant currency. I'm very pleased with the adoption rates of the enterprise support offering, which stood at an all-time high at 96%. This consistent high percentage adoption rate shows the trust that our customers have in us. Non-IFRS cloud subscription and support revenue increased to &#x20AC;69 million in the second quarter, up from &#x20AC;35 million in the first quarter. The increase was mainly due to the inclusion of SuccessFactors for the entire quarter as well as the accelerated momentum that SuccessFactors is seeing as part of the SAP family.</p>
          <p>Also we have noted that our largest competitor records its cloud subscription revenues together with its on-premise license revenue in one line item. We take a different approach in order to provide more transparency into our cloud business, and report cloud revenues in a separate line item called cloud subscription and support. Our license revenue growth rate would be substantially larger if we follow our largest competitor's way of reporting. Please consider this difference in reporting when comparing growth rates.</p>
          <p>Now some comments on our gross margin for the quarter. Our SSRS gross margin increased by 90 basis points to 84.4%. The professional service gross margin decreased by 2.9 percentage points year-over-year to 21.2% due to specific developments and the small number of consulting projects. The overall gross margin increased by 1.3 percentage points to 71.9% year-over-year. This is not surprising since our product business grew at a faster rate than our professional service business, which results in a more favorable business mix.</p>
          <p>Looking at the expense side of the P&amp;L, you can see that total non-IFRS operating expenses in the second quarter increased by 20% year-over-year. From this increase, 6 percentage points were due to currency. In addition, our workforce grew by 6,929 FTEs year-over-year, thereof 2,356 FTEs from acquisitions. Sales and marketing costs, which increased by 30%, also impacted operating expenses leading to a sales and marketing ratio of 23.4% on increase of 2.1 percentage points compared to prior year. This increase is primarily driven by adding almost 2,900 FTEs year-over-year, primarily in the cloud and traditional sales organization to capture future growth opportunities, Bill talked about. These additional FTEs will contribute to our top line in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Our non-IFRS operating margin at constant currencies for the second quarter decreased by 120 basis points at constant currencies to 29.6% year-over-year. There are two main effects which impacted our operating margin performance in the second quarter. Number one, the acquisition of SuccessFactors, and you all know that SuccessFactors operates at a different margin profile compared to SAP. This effect accounted for approximately 100 basis points. Secondly, several expenses occurred in the quarter in the amount of &#x20AC;31 million.</p>
          <p>The non-IFRS tax rate in the first half of 2012 was 26.7%, which is a decrease of 2.2 percentage points year-over-year. This is below of our guidance of 27% to 28%. The year-over-year decrease in the effective tax rate mainly arises from the regional allocation of income. Despite the better tax rate performance in the first half of this year, we believe that our tax rate guidance for  the full year is realistic.</p>
          <p>Now to cash flow. In the second quarter, operating cash flow was impacted by higher tax payments. Operating cash flow for the first six month increased by 6% to &#x20AC;2.4 billion compared to prior year resulting in the best ever half-year cash flow performance. As a result, our free cash flow in the first six months of 2012 increased to &#x20AC;2.1 billion. The improvement in free cash flow was due to better managed working capital, focusing on receivables, which were 13% higher than in the previous year. DSO also improved once again. We were able to take another two days off the result from the previous year, showing that our continued focus on working capital management is paying off.</p>
          <p>To finish up, let me say that based on the strong Q2 results and our robust pipeline, we are reaffirming our outlook for 2012. We continue to expect full year 2012 non-IFRS software and software-related service revenue to increase in a range of 10% to 12% at constant currency, with full-year 2012 non-IFRS operating profit to be in the range of &#x20AC;5.05 billion to &#x20AC;5.25 billion at constant currency.</p>
          <p>Now thank you very much, and we are happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Werner. Back to the operator for the Q&amp;A session, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Adam Wood from Morgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, thanks very much for taking the question and congratulations on such strong execution in the quarter. A couple if I could, just on the pipeline first of all, I think that's the one concern people have. You obviously flagged it was strong. Could you maybe just give us a little bit more information on that, the build of the pipeline through the quarter? Did you see it getting better or worse, maybe the linearity of the second quarter versus a normal Q2, and is there any reason we shouldn't expect normal seasonality in the licenses for rest of this year?</p>
          <p>And maybe secondly, you've alluded today, I see a few times on the call &#x2013; could you maybe give us a little bit of an idea about how important that's becoming for you? Is the conversion you're seeing more at the SMB level, sort of greenfield adoption, or are you also seeing use cases for larger enterprises moving away from the traditional relational-based basis there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Adam, this is Bill McDermott. Let me first of all say that the pipeline in the company is very robust. We measure ourselves on a three times operating plan for the pipeline, it is achieving our objective, and we have the strongest pipeline we've seen in a long time. If you look at new innovations like HANA, talking about a &#x20AC;1.5 billion plus pipeline, mobile &#x20AC;800 million plus pipeline, and the cloud is also a triple-digit growth pipeline; that's why those three businesses are anticipated to grow in triple digits on a year-over-year basis. If you look at the core business, the core business is poised for double-digit, as Werner, Jim, and I have reiterated today in the guidance.</p>
          <p>On the seasonality side of things, let me be clear, we did not pull Q3 forward to achieve Q2. We did not pull Q3 forward to achieve Q2. Q2 stood on its own merits, the linearity was very consistent and predictable throughout the quarter, and it wasn't swayed by any one big transaction. It was consistent double-digit all over the world. We expect the seasonality that is consistent with our historical trends to play out in Q3, and therefore the business remains ever strong.</p>
          <p>Finally, on ASE, and I'm sure Jim would like to make a comment on this as well, or Vishal, but I want to let you know that the ASE business is becoming more and more part of the story in combination with HANA. If you look at big companies like Canadian Rail for example adopting ASE, I think it's a strong testament to the fact that it's not just for the small and mid-size ones, although we're happy to take that business, but it's also the big ones especially in combination with HANA that value it. ASE grew 60% on a year-over-year basis in Q2, and it's up 30% on a year-to-date basis, and I do believe that that makes it the fastest growing database business in the world. And if you couple that with HANA at triple digits, you got a real runaway growth story on your hands here. Jim, any comments? Or Vishal?  3429</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe I can just put some light on that. With those growth rates with ASE, this is becoming a very important part of our business. And I think what you're seeing there is a very successful integration of Sybase into SAP, giving us now a huge momentum. So, I want to thank the team for making that happen at such a professional way.</p>
          <p>The key here is that we're beginning to see the first customers who go for the combination of the SAP apps with the ASE as the database. And I mentioned one example in Nordics where that was the case, a very last transaction, and the reason is very simple: Vishal and his team and the Sybase teams have found a roadmap &#x2013; have declared a roadmap for ASE, which allows customers to start leveraging the benefits of ASE today and move in a smooth transition to a HANA-based world when that's relevant. Maybe you can shed some light on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Like Jim and Bill, like you said, the key is to &#x2013; that we have outlined to our customers, and we already saw the first results in Q2 of a strong compromise-free roadmap that enables a non-disruptive evolution from ASE and IQ to a reality of HANA. We are absolutely convinced that HANA represents the architecture of the future for the database, and to get there, we can get there non-disruptively, and we already started to see the first results of that and you see that reflected in the numbers as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Let's take next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Rick Sherlund from Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and great quarter. The SuccessFactors transition, I wanted to touch on it, Sapphire, Lars had mentioned that he wanted to more loosely couple the HR and financial models from ByDesign. I'm wondering if you can give us an update on that in terms of when you think we'll be able to see traction from the leverage associated with those products being put into the hands of the sales organization for the cloud.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so Jim here. Thanks, Rick, for the question. We're pursuing two markets in the cloud. The one market is the suite for the SMEs, where we now have two products: ByDesign really going after now an upper mid-market, we saw the first big transaction in Australia as Bill mentioned; and Business One is being delivered in the market as a suite in the cloud to our partners, a very solid solution for smaller companies.</p>
          <p>And in parallel, as you said, Lars outlined a strategy for a line of business solutions in the cloud, which are really targeting the large companies, who want to have certain parts of their business under their control on premise or in a private cloud, and then consume Edge solutions from the cloud, the public cloud. And Lars outlined a strategy for four pillars in that Edge solutions &#x2013; a focus on the talent management, the HR topic; the money, the financials as the second one; and then the two relationships, the relationship to customers and the relationship to suppliers.</p>
          <p>We are already active in three of these in a very strong way and we will deliver the financials, the fourth one, the financials later this year. So that means we're now playing in four categories line of business as extensions pre-integrated with our on-premise software and becoming a very serious player.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Let's take next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Marc Geall from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everyone. A couple of questions if I may. Firstly, I just want to sort of think a little bit or understand how you measure success. And I don't mean this from a license standpoint, but if we think about success in technology and infrastructure, which you're clearly sort of achieving as we think about your mobile ambitions, then we probably need to start thinking about the number of employees that are using or interacting with SAP data within the business. And I'm just thinking how we should think about measuring that. And sort of following on from that, share of wallet probably becomes an increasingly important metric, and is there anything you can help us with, maybe looking forward to show success against that plan?</p>
          <p>And as a follow-up, as you think about the ramp-up towards the Business Suite on HANA and in particular ERP on HANA, I'm assuming that part of that ramp-up process will be an internal deployment of the suite or at least financials on HANA. I just want to understand where we are against that goal, and also how you sort of manage the risk around that, because until that is complete, then customers will be obviously very reluctant to take that to the next level. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Marc. Your first question about how we measure success, obviously, the only true measure of it is the business volume and the market share we're gaining in the market. However, we are adding measures of adoption and active usage of our solutions, and we have this very ambitious target to reach 1 billion people with our software, which is basically only possible through a very active mobile strategy. But I still believe that net-net, the true measure of success is the revenue we can make with our portfolio of solutions and not breaking it down to individual pieces at the end of the day.</p>
          <p>It is clear that with our growth now &#x2013; where many other companies are showing no growth in IT, we have very strong growth, 26% in software &#x2013; that the share of wallet strategy that was a cornerstone in our strategy is working. We see the shift happening from hardware to innovative software and with the five categories we now play in that all are showing very strong momentum, we are significantly increasing our share of wallet at the customers.</p>
          <p>And then finally on the Business Suite on HANA, we have not announced this product yet, but we are certain that over time you will see transactional systems running on HANA. Business One will be the first productive system; we already have customers with that. And obviously we will be making sure that these complex large company systems runs not only faster, but as robust in a HANA world before we go to market with that. We're very confident about the future of this, but right now we don't have a product announced. Vishal you want to comment further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Marc, I just want to say that we are making great progress on running ERP on HANA as well as CRM on HANA internally. We are working with a bunch of customers on this, and we are extremely excited about this. Like Jim said, we haven't announced a date on this yet, but we expect to see tremendous performance improvements, but also drastic simplification in the amount of code that is necessary to run the same processes non-disruptively. So, we are extremely excited about this and on track with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Let's take the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Phil Winslow from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, guys, and a great first half. Bill, just got a question for you. Obviously we've seen application software really outperform the other areas of tech, and within apps, we've seen SAP outperform the rest of the your competitors. What's really changed for this segment versus other areas of tech in this sort of obviously kind of strange macro climate? And also similarly, what's changed for SAP versus the competitors?</p>
          <p>And also just for Jim, you mentioned HANA, BW on HANA. Wondering if you could give us a sense of how that's that contributed to the pipeline for the second half, and just what your expectations are for that product. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. Thank you very much, Phil. First of all, we see a world where customers respond well to innovation that is non-disruptive. And if you look at what we've done on the application platform side of the equation, we've given tremendous innovation to the customer and we haven't disrupted their enterprise. If you look further, we've captured the big trends in our strategy; we have a good strategy and it's working. And that includes what we've done on mobility; it includes what we've done on the cloud. And obviously HANA, in combination with what we did on the Sybase deal, I think really puts together a powerhouse set of solutions for our customer.</p>
          <p>When you then couple them with 24 industries and our strong domain expertise in industry, and then our ambition to grow not just in the core mature markets, but to spread our wings in the BRIC, you saw what we did in China and the Middle East, you're just dealing with a company that's acting on behalf of the customer, but also an aggressive management team.</p>
          <p>I believe that customers are in a world of business technology, not just information technology. And we appeal to the C-level executive that wants to invest in technology that drives business outcomes. What CEO doesn't want to mobilize their workforce or to make their supply chain, get their value chain right for growth in expanding marketplaces so they can be more competitive? That's what we do. We're not pushing hardware, we're not trying to push services, and we're not trying to make our customer behave the way we want them to based on our business model; we've built the company around the customer and what they want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well said, Bill. And the question on BW on HANA, I am convinced, and I'm sure Vishal will support that maybe even with stronger language, that HANA is one of the biggest transformations that are happening to this industry since the last 10 to 15 years. With HANA, we're solving problems that were unsolvable before. We are analyzing DNA to individualize cancer treatment in healthcare. We are helping large consumer products to manage successful trade promotions in real time and understand change of customer behaviors. We are helping insurance companies get to real time fraud detection, and we are helping banks to become much more real time in their risk management. These are big problems that have high value, but also require high touch.</p>
          <p>BW on HANA is the volume play for HANA. It gives the opportunity for us to show the power of HANA in a risk free environment. Where customers have a great business case, they get a BW that is simplified at a tremendous performance and a reduced cost of infrastructure. And once they've gone through that experience, they come with a big problem that we need to solve for them. Therefore, this is strategically very important. My estimation is that half of our current pipeline, a number of customer interactions is BW on HANA related, and they typically come back later and with a value conversation. Vishal, you want to add something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it makes sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Gerardus Vos from Barclays. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my questions. A couple if I may. But first of all, on the head count, we've seen significant increase in sales and marketing head count in the first half of the year. What should we expect for the second half or kind of full year, fully built out? Then secondly, on the HANA and mobility pipeline, what was the equivalent number at the beginning of the year? And then finally perhaps on HANA, are you seeing anything like a lengthening of the sales cycle now you're moving from more the kind of bespoke kind of solution to kind of OEM ready? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Gerardus, thank you very much. Just a couple of things. First of all, on HANA and mobility, the pipeline I'd itemize for you is &#x20AC;1.5 billion and &#x20AC;800 million, respectively. It's probably increased by more than a third, and that's after we've dropped the results to the bottom line. The HANA sales cycle if anything is going to get shorter. One of the things that we've done in the company to really reinvent the company and make SAP a knowledge company is we've really focused on design thinking in our company. And this idea of desirability, feasibility, and viability is in the hearts and minds of our HANA team and all of our employees. So we can show that in volume business on BW on HANA, but we can also show that in transformational examples such as the one Jim outlined, where we're going into industry and we're changing the game. So that's pretty much the strong story there.</p>
          <p>In terms of the head count in sales, smart sales organizations invest in the early part of the year so they can get the leverage and the tailwind in the back end of the year. That's what we anticipate to do, so you shouldn't expect a whole bunch of hiring; you should expect a whole bunch of execution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, I like that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Laura Lederman from William Blair. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Can you talk a little bit about Ariba and sort of the goals of integrating that and any updated thoughts on Ariba? And similar, just the whole concept of acquisitions &#x2013; if you look at your portfolio, you've obviously gotten a lot of new products and are very successful with them. If you'd look broadly at acquisitions, would we expect to see additional acquisitions to add other large components to the suite either vertically or horizontally in terms of applications? Or given the recentness of Ariba, are we not likely to see anything for the near future? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Laura. Jim here. First of all, the Ariba transaction is not finalized yet, so we can't share too much more details on other than what we already said, and let me repeat that. We feel that Ariba fits extremely well into our portfolio as we see the cloud move to its next phase, where it's not just about consuming software through the cloud, but it's about connecting companies with companies. We have arguably the largest installed base with the most relevant companies in this world running SAP. We connect them through the network of Ariba, the synergies that we can create with Ariba are significant. So that's the reason we did this, but we can't say much more than that.</p>
          <p>On the acquisitions in the future, I want to reiterate as well that our strategy is based on primarily organic innovation to drive growth. And when we acquire, it's not to consolidate past technology, but it's really to accelerate our pace into future areas. We added three categories in our portfolio. In mobile, we did an acquisition of Sybase to jumpstart and we are now the market leader in business mobility. We went for SuccessFactors and Ariba to accelerate our momentum in the cloud, and the in-memory computing is an organic invention by SAP. It's really the power of the combination, where roughly two-thirds of our growth come from organic innovation and one-third comes from growth, and we feel comfortable with the transactions we've done and our ability to create value both for customers and shareholders in this strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'll ask one follow up if I could, any signs at all of European issues? Obviously your numbers were fine, but did you notice any even subtle changes <mark type="ph" /> at the end (50:27), because your tone was obviously very positive and your results were positive, but the macro headlines are a little scary, so if you just give us any sense of did you see any issues anywhere that would. -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, when we came into the &#x2013; when we came into the quarter, there was a lot of these similar questions, and we mentioned at that time that we would manage our European portfolio, and we would &#x2013; even if southern Europe was down, we'd be strong in Germany as an example, which we were in Germany, UK, and Austria and other places. So -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just talking -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; what we see right now, we see right now is a strong momentum, a very good pipeline. We are obviously cognizant of the headlines as you are. And we are confident that what's unique about SAP is our market share position in Europe, the brand and how it's truly respected in Europe. And as Jim took you through the innovation strategy of the company, we just have a lot of solutions for people to manage risk, manage compliance, optimize supply chains where they have to cut cost and be more efficient and do with less, but also the ones that have to compete and have to expand in Europe or beyond Europe to grow, we cover that base as well. So, we got them if they're hurting, we got them if they need to grow. And bottom line, we got them, because we got the brand and the company and the know-how in Europe to win.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Let's take the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Knut Woller from Baader Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you very much. Just a brief question regarding the topic social. We have seen a lot of M&amp;A activity by your competitors in this area. So, I am interested in your view on this topic. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a very important topic. We're seeing how the Internet is moving away from just interacting on information to actually connecting people and companies. So, social is key. At SAP, we don't think it's a separated category. It needs to be integrated within the applications so that you have transactional, analytical, and social capabilities to improve people's productivity and that's our strategy. We have one of the fastest growing social tools in our pipeline in our portfolio with Jam, which was acquired through SuccessFactors, and we bring this technology not only to all employees at SAP and the millions of people who are using this already now, but within our applications we're building it in. So, it becomes an integral part of how you do business in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Let's take the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Michael Briest from UBS. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Bill, you said it was a normal quarter; in terms of the deal volumes, it seems to have been pretty much flat, but obviously the ASP was very strong. Can you talk a bit about the mix of large deals and small deals? And then in terms of BW and HANA, looking at the ASP, I think last year we were looking at about &#x20AC;800,000, &#x20AC;750,000 per appliance. It seems to have come down somewhat, can you maybe talk about what sort of levels you're seeing with HANA on BW, ASP?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all Michael, thanks for the question. What we are seeing is strong same account revenue growth. So, when you have a very loyal customer and you can bring them innovation without disruption, they will invest further with SAP. And we did have a very nice increase in terms of our share of deals greater than &#x20AC;5 million on a year-over-year basis; that was one of the nice outcomes of the quarter. So, if you're looking for a specific piece of information, it was 30 versus 15 on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>As it relates to HANA, I wouldn't read anything into the ASP going down. I would simply read into the adoption going up. There is many more customers now that are adopting HANA and some of them will start small and we'll take that small start and make it big over time. So, as you spread HANA's wings you might see that little inflection, but don't read anything into it. The ASP on HANA is actually as strong as ever and if not stronger than ever.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. So this concludes the earnings call for today, and thank you for joining and goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>