<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1199827" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>769</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Stefan Gruber, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Werner Brandt, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">L&#xE9;o Apotheker, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Bill McDermott, Executive Board Member</participant>
      <participant id="5">Gerardus Vos</participant>
      <participant id="6">James Dawson</participant>
      <participant id="7">Ross MacMillan</participant>
      <participant id="8">Sarah Friar</participant>
      <participant id="9">Michael Briest</participant>
      <participant id="10">Raimo Lenschow</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mohammed Moawalla</participant>
      <participant id="12">Philip Winslow</participant>
      <participant id="13">Marc Rode</participant>
      <participant id="14">Neil Steer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to SAP's Second Quarter Results Conference Call. This call is being recorded. Today's call will be hosted by L&#xE9;o Apotheker, Werner Brandt and Bill McDermott. I will now turn the call over to Stefan Gruber. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning or good afternoon. This is Stefan Gruber. Thank you for joining us to discuss SAP's second quarter 2009 results. I am joined by L&#xE9;o Apotheker, Werner Brandt and Bill McDermott.</p>
          <p>Werner will discuss the Q2 financials in detail, Bill will comment on the current business environment, our strategy and product successes. And Bill will provide some further color on our regional and industry performance, and our go-to-market strategy. Following the prepared remarks, we have time for Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>I will now make a few remarks about forward-looking statements. Any statements made during this call that are not historical facts are forward-looking statements as defined in the U.S. Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995.</p>
          <p>Words such as anticipate, believe, estimate, expect, forecast, intend, may, plan, project, predict, should, outlook, and will, and similar expressions as they relate to SAP are intended to identify such forward-looking statements. SAP undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements. All forward-looking statements are subject to various risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from expectations. The factors that could affect SAP's future financial results are discussed more fully in SAP's filings with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, including SAP's Annual Report on Form 20-F for 2008 filed with the SEC on March 26, 2009. Participants of this call are cautioned not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements, which speak only as of their date.</p>
          <p>And now I would like to turn the call over to Werner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stefan. Before I begin, let me inform you that I will be speaking mostly about non-GAAP figures as they are more in line with how we internally look at our operational performance. Also, these non-GAAP measures are the basis of our guidance. The difference between U.S. GAAP and non-GAAP figures in the second quarter of 2009 is the result of the excluding of acquisition-related charges in the amount of &#x20AC;67 million, compared to &#x20AC;66 million in the second quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>More detail on our non-GAAP measures, the reasons for their use, and reconciliation to the most comparable U.S. GAAP measures are provided in our earnings press release.</p>
          <p>Also, let me remind you that all numbers that we have presented today are preliminary. Our final numbers will be presented mid of August in our half-year report. Subsequent events that may occur until then are to be reflected in our Q2 2009 financials as far as they provide additional evidence with respect to conditions that existed at June 30th of 2009.</p>
          <p>Please note that the incurred restructuring expenses of &#x20AC;160 million and &#x20AC;5 million in the first and second quarter of 2009 respectively, resulting from the previously announced reduction in positions. Our non-GAAP measures are not adjusted for these restructuring expenses. Therefore, both our U.S. GAAP and non-GAAP numbers are negatively impacted by these charges.</p>
          <p>With that, let me say that we are pleased to report extremely strong operating margin despite a challenging business environment. Let me give you the highlights of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP software and software-related service revenues for the second quarter of 2009 were &#x20AC;1.95 billion, which represented a year-over-year decrease of 8% or 10% at constant currency. For the half-year, non-GAAP software and software-related service revenues decreased 5% or 7% at constant currency.</p>
          <p>Sequentially, Q1 of 2009 to Q2 2009 non-GAAP software and software-related service revenues  increased by 11%.</p>
          <p>The year-over-year decrease in the second quarter was the result of a decline in 40% in software revenues at constant currencies, an increase in 30% in non-GAAP support revenues at constant currency and an increase of 8% in subscription and other software-related service revenues at constant currency.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter of 2009, our recurring revenues accounted for 55% of our total revenue. Second quarter professional services and other service revenues was &#x20AC;610 million, which was a decrease of 23% at constant currency. Consulting revenues of &#x20AC;550 million decreased 20% at constant currency and training revenues decreased 39% at constant currency.</p>
          <p>The decrease in consulting and training revenues was not unexpected due to the decline in software revenues over the past few quarters. Consulting revenues usually lag software revenues by around nine to six months.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP operating expenses decreased to &#x20AC;1.86 billion or 18% (5.06) at constant currency, which represents a decrease of 391 million adjusted for currency. This number includes restructuring charges of &#x20AC;5 million related to the previously-announced reduction of positions, which was at first half of 2009 totaled &#x20AC;165 million.</p>
          <p>The number of positions reduced associated with the &#x20AC;165 million charge was approximately 2,800, roughly 2,050 of these employees have already left the company as of June 30. The rest will leave in the following month according to the labor laws in their respective country.</p>
          <p>For the full year 2009, we expect a total of around &#x20AC;200 million of restructuring charges relating to the reduction of positions. Previously, we had provided a range of 200 million to &#x20AC;300 million.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP R&amp;D expenses decreased 11% to 375 million for the second quarter and represented 14.4% of total revenue, which was flat compared to the second quarter of last year. The decline in revenues offset by significant cost saving measures resulted in a flat R&amp;D ratio for the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP sales and marketing expenses decreased 18% to &#x20AC;543 million for the second quarter and represented 21.1% of total revenue, a decrease of 1.6 percentage points compared to last year's second quarter. The decrease in sales and marketing expenses was mainly a result of lower personnel expenses due to head count reduction and tight cost control in all areas.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP general and administrative expenses decreased 25% to &#x20AC;126 million for the second quarter and represented 4.9% of total revenues, compared to 5.8% of total revenues for the second quarter of last year. This decrease in general and administrative expenses was the result of effective cost saving measures, mostly in the area of non-customer related third-party expenses, travel expenses and personnel expenses due to the head count reduction. In addition to this, the first half of 2008 was impacted by one-time expenses for G&amp;A due to the acquisition of Business Objects in an amount of &#x20AC;11 million.</p>
          <p>Overall, the company's non-GAAP operating-margin at constant currencies was 27.9% for the second quarter, which represents an increase of 3.5 percentage points compared to the second quarter of last year. Also keep in mind that on top of the excellent performance, the second quarter 2009 non-GAAP operating margin was negatively impacted by around 20 basis points due to restructuring charges from the reduction of positions.</p>
          <p>Let me now give you some details on the gross margin. The non-GAAP software and software-related service margin was 89.9% for the second quarter of 2009, which was a decrease of 50 basis points compared to the second quarter of last year. The lower margin was a result of a decline in software and software-related service revenue due to the difficult environment, which could not be fully offset by a 5% reduction in the cost of software and software-related service revenue.</p>
          <p>The professional service margin was 23% for the second quarter of 2009, which was a decrease of 140 basis points compared to the same quarter of last year. The decrease was mainly driven by a decline of seven percentage-points in the training margin rather the consulting margin was relatively flat year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Because of the slight change in business mix, the second quarter non-GAAP gross margin increased by 100 basis points to 67.9%. Other non-operating income and expenses was down &#x20AC;38 million year-over-year, which was mainly the result of currency losses from cash-flow hedges and currency losses from our subsidiary in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>Our U.S GAAP effective tax rate for the second quarter was 29.3% compared to 31.4% for the second quarter of last year. For the half year, our U.S. GAAP effective tax-rate was 30.3%. For the full year we continue to expect a tax rate of 29.5% to 30.5%.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow for the first half of the year of 2009 was &#x20AC;1.7 billion, which was an increase of 44% compared to the first half year of 2008. The increase in free cash flow was primarily the result of positive changes in working capital.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, total liquidity was &#x20AC;3.4 billion, including the net proceeds from the issuance of a private placement of a promissory note for two terms. Bank liabilities were &#x20AC;3 billion, which included in 2.3 billion from the financing of a syndicated loan related to the acquisition of Business Objects and 700 million from the private placement I mentioned before. In addition, in the second quarter, we paid 594 million in dividends.</p>
          <p>Let me now give you an update on head count. As you know, in January we announced a reduction of positions to 48,500 FTEs by the end of this year. At the end of the second quarter, head count included 48,569 FTEs, which is a decrease of 2,975 FTEs compared to December of last year.</p>
          <p>Let me finish up by saying that we have updated our outlook for 2009. Please refer to the press release issued today for the complete outlook.</p>
          <p>I would now like to pass the call over to L&#xE9;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Werner. Welcome, everyone, to today's call. I am pleased to provide you with an update on the business environment and our product successes.</p>
          <p>Let me begin by discussing the market environment. Things are still tough, but I think it is safe to say we are seeing some more stability in the environment. The pipeline has steadily improved since the beginning of this year, but we need to bear in mind that closure rates are more volatile than they were in the past. Therefore, as we see it now, 2009 will remain a difficult environment, but I am cautiously optimistic that the worse might be behind us with hope of some improvement in 2010.</p>
          <p>That brings me to what our customers are thinking and doing. While customers seem to be a bit less pessimistic in Q2 compared to Q1, their buying behavior has not changed. Order sizes remain smaller as customers are more willing to buy smaller packages.</p>
          <p>Let me touch on our results, which Werner has already discussed. I want to emphasize that while software and software-related services were down year-over-year, it should not be a surprise. We have spoken on many occasions about the tough top-line comparisons we expected in the first half of 2009 compared to 2008. Due to a more difficult operating environment this year, 2009 no longer including the positive effects from the acquisition of Business Objects. And a tough comparison due to strong results supported in the first half of 2008, which was prior to the economic crisis that disrupted the global market in the third quarter of 2008. In light of the difficult operating environment, we have been focusing on margin growth and we have delivered.</p>
          <p>We owe our very strong margin performance over the past three quarters to the strength and flexibility of our business model, one that can be defensive in times like these and one that can provide for top-line growth when the economy rebounds.</p>
          <p>On the defensive side, we can still deliver a relatively good revenue performance. One reason is the high percentage of recurring revenues, 55% in the first half of this year. Additionally, we generate strong positive cash flow, which was up 44% in the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Moreover, despite the decline in revenues, we still reported very strong margin growth. In fact, since the crisis faced in September 2008, we have reported year-over-year margin growth of 460 basis points in the fourth quarter of 2008, 450 basis points in the first quarter of 2009, excluding the negative impact of restructuring charges, and 350 basis points in the quarter just ended. I think this is an impressive performance.</p>
          <p>I want to note, however, that while we have delivered outstanding margin growth thus far and even raised our margin guidance for 2009, it is important to remember that the margin comparisons in Q3 and Q4 will become tougher; especially in Q4 when, you may remember, in last year's Q4 we slammed the brakes on spending. In other words, it will be tough to maintain the cost reduction run rate in the second half of 2009 that we have achieved over the past three quarters.</p>
          <p>As for top-line growth, when the economy rebounds we are geared up for profitable growth. The strength of our business model allows us to continue to innovate during these tough times. That innovation is the foundation for future growth as history demonstrates.</p>
          <p>Two good examples of continued innovation are, one, SAP BusinessObjects Explorer which we introduced at SAPPHIRE Orlando. It is a very powerful, very easy to use and extremely fast tool for data analysis for all users in an organization. Second, our development of on-demand applications, which I will speak about in a moment.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, and just to set the record straight, we are the undisputed market leader in business applications, with the deepest and broadest store-enabled portfolio of software solutions in the industry. We are the undisputed market leader in 20 out of 25 industries with our more than 25 end-to-end industry platforms. We are nearly twice the size of number two and our win rate is 80%.</p>
          <p>Additionally, we are the clear leader in business intelligence as evidenced by recent reports from leading market analysts, and in the small and mid-sized market we also have the clear lead as shown by our leading market share.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn it over to Bill to provide a brief update on the regions, industries and our go-to-market strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, L&#xE9;o. As mentioned, software and software-related services revenues in each of the regions was down year-over-year. This was not unexpected considering the current environment and the fact that each of the regions reported very strong double-digit rates in comparative second quarter of 2008. You'll remember at that time EMEA was up 27%, Americas up 37% and APJ was up 40% at constant currencies.</p>
          <p>As L&#xE9;o said earlier, the environment and customer buying behavior generally applies to each of the regions. The operating environment remains difficult, in particular for large purchases. Customers are cautious regarding their strategic investments and often require multiple levels of approval, including in many cases, Board of Directors. This does result in longer sales cycles.</p>
          <p>The good news is that the pipeline in each of the regions is steadily improving and there is a high level of qualified customer participation in our SAPPHIRE and global SAP World Tour events with more than 70,000 customers, prospects and partners in attendance validating the strategic relevance of SAP.</p>
          <p>Additionally, we saw positive sequential growth in each of the regions and better sequential growth overall than we have seen in many years, with the exception of course of 2008 which exhibited unusual seasonality due to the acquisition of Business Objects.</p>
          <p>The Asia Pacific Japan region, which reported the highest sequential growth among the regions, benefited from an improving liquidity situation in the region compared to the first quarter. This resulted in a strong performance from small and mid-sized enterprises in particular. Key contract wins in the EMEA region were Shell Information Technology, Olympic Air, Warburtons Limited and OMK Stahl (18.07). In the Americas we signed Norfolk Southern, Sara Lee Corporation and City of Ottawa. And in APJ, key wins were China Petroleum &amp; Chemical, Sterlight Industries India Limited (18.19) and Singapore Power Limited.</p>
          <p>As for our industry performance, while many industries are mired by the current economic environment, I'm pleased to report that we saw a good rolling fourth-quarter growth in consumer products, financial services, healthcare, public sector and higher education. As L&#xE9;o stressed earlier, we are the clear leader in industries. No other company has our domain expertise, installed base or referenceable customers.</p>
          <p>And the good thing is, we've adapted our go-to-market strategy to succeed in this new reality in three ways. One, we drive volume sales through our broad product portfolio. Clients are investing in business outcomes, in solutions that can be implemented quickly providing fast return on investment, efficiency, competitiveness and clarity in their businesses. We are addressing these customer priorities with products from our Best-Run Now initiative, our new Business Suite 7, which, as you know, became generally available in May, and of course, the BusinessObjects Solution Portfolio which continues to sell very well.</p>
          <p>Two, we invest in our customer relationships. We are building strategic partnerships with our 390 largest customers in particular, which we call our Premier Customer Network. We do this by collaborating more closely with them on enabling their business strategy to a longer-term technology roadmap that aligns their software purchase and consumption with the value SAP delivers. Moreover, we have taken more than 400 customers through our Value Academy teaching them how to maximize the value from their investment in SAP.</p>
          <p>Three, lastly, we have made the ongoing education of our sales force a top priority through an initiative we call Value University. This is where we provide training to all of our customer-facing professionals globally. We do this to ensure the alignment with customers' priorities and purchasing behavior. This will enable us to drive volume and value for SAP and our customers.</p>
          <p>While we are focused on execution clearly, we are also strengthening our workforce and customer relationship in all markets and industry globally.</p>
          <p>I will now turn it back over to L&#xE9;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bill. Let me now take a moment to speak about our undertaking in the development of on-demand applications. Our on-demand offering encompasses a portfolio of solutions dedicated to different target groups: large enterprise, business user and the mid-market.</p>
          <p>For the mid-market there is Business ByDesign, and I am pleased to say that Feature Pack 2.0 is ready for product review. It was released on time and according to plan. 2.0 includes many new features with a lot of additional functionality and end-to-end business scenarios.</p>
          <p>We also announced a new collaboration agreement allowing SAP Business ByDesign to be pre-configured to use nine complementary web services from Business Wire, Falk Online, Google and others.</p>
          <p>We are broadening the controlled availability of Business ByDesign as part of our overall step-by-step release plan. For the business users, there is SAP BusinessObjects OnDemand offerings, dedicated to business users small to large. These include Crystal Reports and SAP BusinessObjects BI OnDemand.</p>
          <p>And then there is our on-demand offering for large enterprises. We have and are continuing to develop a portfolio of on-demand solutions deployed at many of our customers. These solutions include SAP Customer Relationship Management, SAP E-Sourcing, cap and trade acquired through the Clear Standards acquisition, and expense management software which is expected to be announced in mid 2010.</p>
          <p>We are in the process of extending our on-demand offering for large enterprise aimed at our very large installed base. We have brought on a new senior leadership team to lead the effort. We know that large enterprises have very specific requirements for on-demand applications and we believe that they have a unique and compelling strategy for success. One important element is that we are going beyond basic integration with our on-demand solutions. There will be no integration issues created by disparate software solutions.</p>
          <p>Integration is extremely important because we are already seeing the so-called best-of-breed problem picking up again in the market due to companies using many different on-demand applications from different vendors.</p>
          <p>Let me finish up by saying that our three-pillar growth strategy via organic co-innovation and acquisition remains intact. Once the economy rebounds, we expect to return to organic growth driven by our existing broad portfolio of products for large and small enterprises. Business user solutions, new innovations like on-demand for large enterprises, solutions for the midmarket and the most extensive industry solution portfolio in the business.</p>
          <p>For co-innovation and partnering, there are many examples from this past quarter alone, including an extension of our global services partnership and new go-to-market agreement with Atos Origin; a reseller agreement with APOS Systems to resell so that APO Solutions to help customers enhance management, monitoring and control of the deployment of SAP BusinessObjects XI solutions; a new agreement with Teradata to provide SAP NetWeaver Business Warehouse on the Teradata database; and a global services partnership with Cognizant.</p>
          <p>Finally, on the acquisition front, our strategy has not changed. We continue to look for smart strategic deals that help improve our technology and product portfolio. In the past quarter we announced two acquisitions. First there was Highdeal, the leading provider of real-time bidding solutions for telecommunications. The acquisition will allow us to provide customers a packaged consumer-to-cash business process platform to support high-volume billing and enable a reduction in cost of ownership. Second, there was Clear Standards, an innovator of enterprise carbon management solutions. With this acquisition, we expect to accelerate our ability to meet the carbon management requirements of organizations in this time of increasingly stringent government regulations and expectations for better transparency by the public.</p>
          <p>With that, I want to thank you for listening, and we will now be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question is from Gerardus Vos from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my questions. I have a few, if I may. First of all, how should I think about the OpEx base going into the second half? The run rate is now roughly around 1 billion, there are still around 800 people coming out into the second half follow according to your head count plan and then you have normal attrition.</p>
          <p>And secondly, could you perhaps discuss how do you think the environment has changed in BI after IBM's acquisition of SPSS.</p>
          <p>And then finally, you made a comment about if we coming out of this recession and organic growth. What do you think is a kind of a sustainable organic growth for the cycle to come for SAP? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me address the first part of the question related to the operating expense base in the second half &#x2013; rather the first half. First of all, what we normally see that we have higher sales in the second half of the year compared to the first half, which result in higher variable <mark type="inaudible" /> figures (27.00). Then, this also applies to the normal bonus we pay to all of our employees for the full year, that you had in the second half a higher part of these expenses in the expense base. Personnel expenses in Q3 and Q4 of 2008 were significantly positively impacted by reduced bonus accrual due to lower than planned sales in the second half of 2008; we have to keep this in mind.</p>
          <p>Then the stock-based compensation expenses might increase. We had in the first half only 20 million, in the second half of 2008, only 11 million, and according to the evolution of the share price, we might see higher stock-based compensation expenses. Severe expense reduction measures had been executed already in Q4, don't forget this, where we already said that they would not be 100% sustainable.</p>
          <p>And finally, the positive impact of the reduction in provisions for Germany will be only partly visible in 2009. And if you look to the entire expense base and now take out the restructuring charges, then we had in the first half of the year a base of roughly &#x20AC;3.7 billion. And I think if you go into the second half, you always have to assume what I said before, an increase year-over-year.</p>
          <p>You specifically addressed personnel expenses. That's something where we will also see the benefit from the reduction in positions as most of them occurred in the first half, during the first half, and we will see the benefit of &#x2013; at least the full benefit, in the second half. So this speaks against what I said before regarding the overall expense base. If you look to personnel expense itself, you'll see a positive impact also from the reduction in positions. I hope this answers your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, very complete. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bear with me and I'll try to be as complete when it comes to SPSS -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wait, wait, wait, I still need to answer a question. Just on SPSS, I don't expect SPSS acquisition by IBM to have an impact on our relationship with SPSS. You should note that we are addressing the predictive analytics market requirements via partnership with SPSS and this partnership is working very well.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, SAP and IBM already are successfully partnering in many, many areas. So in fact, the fact that IBM might acquire SPSS could actually simplify our overall offering and therefore might be better news than what many people expect.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, regarding our long-term sustainable growth rate, I would suggest that we talk about that next year when we talk about our guidance. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from James Dawson from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my questions. I have a couple. Just in terms of the geographic performance, I wonder if you could talk a little bit about &#x2013; perhaps the U.S. was a bit tougher here, obviously, it's usually a little more exposed to big deals &#x2013; I wonder if you could talk about the pipeline comment that you made for the Group in perspective with the U.S. and how we should expect that for the rest of the year? And perhaps if you could talk &#x2013; maybe you could give us some granularity around the European performance. Was there some areas that were better or worse?</p>
          <p>And then my second question is on cash. You're doing pretty well there. If we don't see acquisitions, should we expect to see a return to some buybacks from you guys next year because the cash number's going to start to get too high versus your target? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Bill, James. I'll answer first on the U.S.. You are right that the U.S. does have a larger deal dependency than other geographies, that's fair. And you should also know that the U.S. has a very steadily improving pipeline as we look at the condition of the business going into the second half. A lot of that is a springboard off of our SAPPHIRE event, which I mentioned earlier, but there's also better execution in each of the regions that are the central, west, north, east and southeast corridors of the U.S..</p>
          <p>As it relates to EMEA, I think you should think of the performance as pretty steady across the geographies. There were some that were slightly stronger than others, but it was not a big difference from one location to another. But I would also mention in EMEA that there was again a very steadily improving pipeline as we look into the second half, and we're pretty optimistic on EMEA right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Regarding cash and buyback, as you have seen, we have a 3.4 billion in cash in our hands. This correlates with a debt related to the Business Objects acquisition of 2.3 billion and the newly-issued promissory note I mentioned earlier during my speech with the 700 million.</p>
          <p>So the net cash as of June 30 was roughly &#x20AC;440 million. And from our perspective, we identified a strategic cash position for SAP in the range of &#x20AC;1.5 million. But as long as we haven't achieved this, we wouldn't start to buy back shares again. And share buyback during these tough days is really dependent on the overall economic situation we will see in 2010. So a clear let's-see-and-wait perspective regarding share buyback as of today, looking into 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Ross MacMillan from Jefferies. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Werner, historically I think you've talked about outside of head count reduction, some other discretionary cost reduction that you didn't think you needed to dial back up in recovery. Could you just recap on what you said in that regard and to what extent could some of that still be ahead of us rather than already in current operating expenses? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ross, if I understand you correctly, the question is whether the cost reduction, operating expense reduction in other areas than personnel expenses is sustainable. Is this your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And specifically, has all that been done or is there anything more to do? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think if I look to the non-personnel related expenses, we first of all look into third-party expenses. And there in all categories, whether it's customer-related, whether it's non-customer related or whether it's licenses commission related, we had significant decreases if you look to a half-year perspective, half-year over half-year.</p>
          <p>So from that perspective, I would say that we did a lot. And the key here is that we look to keep it at this level. So it's more a question of sustainability at the end of the day that we really keep tight cost control on third-party expenses.</p>
          <p>The next one is travel and entertainment, and here we also saw a significant decrease year-over-year or half-year over half-year. And I assume if business come back, we will see business travel again. But overall, our way how we addressed travel activities will not change; we will not simply open it up again. We will travel more, but at a lower level, at lower cost as we did in the first half of this year and also in the fourth quarter already.</p>
          <p>Marketing is an area where we saw reductions half-year over half-year, and we have to see how this plays out when the economy comes back and we see software revenue coming in again, whether we spend a bit more. But again, also here we have to be very careful with accelerated spending also on the marketing side and the same applies for the infrastructure. Is your question answered with this comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's certainly very helpful. And then just on head count itself, obviously you're not talking about next year yet, but how are you thinking about even head count as you go into the second half of this year? You've obviously got the additional 800 to come out. But excluding that number, do you think you have to start to hire in anticipation of next year? Or how are you thinking about when you may start to hire in anticipation of improving demand? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would argue that from today's perspective, it's too early to start to hire. What we will do of course is that we replace and we have some programs in place where we shift and lift between functions, between regions within one function where we really adjust the head count to where we actually need it rather than having it somewhere we don't need it.</p>
          <p>So this program is ongoing. We will replace, but not actively coming back to hiring in the second half. We have to see how the second half goes and then we decide on what we do in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Sarah Friar from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon. Thank you for taking my questions. I have two for you in terms of demand, maybe for Bill. Bill, do you have any sense of pent-up demand as we head into the second half as you've talk to customers? It seems like we're hearing that they've definitely underspent budgets in the first half of the year, so maybe there's a bit more to spend as they get into the seasonally stronger part of the year.</p>
          <p>And then secondarily, could you talk a little bit about volume selling? You talked about last quarter more emphasis on more tactical smaller deals. How is that coming along for you? And are there any additional investments around volume selling that we should be thinking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much for the question, Sarah. First of all on the pent-up demand, as I said earlier there is a steadily improving pipeline in all the regions of the world, and in all industries, in fact. So the pipeline clearly is getting more robust as we go into the second half. You would expect that because seasonally our business is normally stronger in the second half and therefore sequentially, we expect the pipeline to rise.</p>
          <p>As it relates to pent-up demand and customers making decisions, I think we'll have to take an execution oriented focus on that in Q3 and Q4 and give you the answer as the deals are made and the decisions are actually granted.</p>
          <p>On the subject of volume selling, clearly a major focus. What we are doing is driving sales productivity in every region, every geography, every industry and we are driving more and more activity per a rep. As the deal sizes are smaller in this market environment, you have to do more deals. So we're doing that with our sales force and we're also extending that to our ecosystem, to very good partners in the indirect channel, encouraging them to sell into this environment.</p>
          <p>I explained to you our Best-Run Now packages which are prepackaged, ready to run, installed quickly with fast ROI. Business Suite 7 is also helpful, and of course BusinessObjects Portfolio is hugely important in this environment. So all in all, volume selling is clearly the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Michael Briest from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thank you very much. To go to the large deal metrics, could you maybe tell us what proportion of orders in the quarter were for deals over 5 million, because that's been low for the last couple of quarters? And on the same vein, you're beginning to offer now subscription type deals to the Premier Customer Network. Can you talk about the level of interest you're seeing and how rapidly you think there'll be adoption there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, why don't I try to give you some information on that, Michael, this is L&#xE9;o. Our last year metrics in Q2 it is above 5 million whereabout 12% and regarding what Bill described early on in PCN relationship that we are building with our close to 400 top customers, there is quite some interest for establishing long-term relationships. And as we are engaging in this conversations, of course many forms of contractual relationships are being discussed, among them of course also, subscriptions are not exclusively, but it's one of the options people are looking at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When do you think that will come through to sales or deals?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, some of them are happening already. A few of them have closed very recently, a few of them have been in a classical form of one-time licenses, others have been more subscriptions, so we can see both happening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And then just final one for Werner. I noticed there was another &#x20AC;10 million sales allowance in the quarter. I thought you put a big chart during Q1 and thought that was enough for the year. Can you maybe talk about where the increased caution is coming from, and again if you think there'll be anymore in the second half? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, we have to differentiate, I think here between the sales allowances and the debt provision. And I must say without going into detail here that we have taken into account a quite significant bad debt provision and also sales allowances. As a consequence is that what we had on the balance sheet and what we have in our P&amp;L so far is &#x2013; can be considered as &#x2013; I wouldn't say risk free, but that we had reserved everything we think we could reserve for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you say what the bad debt provision was in Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it had the same amount as in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>87 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the first quarter, if you look to the individual bad debt provision, it was around 35, and this quarter, it's a bit below 40 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Raimo Lenschow from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thanks for taking my question. Two question if I may. First, Werner, following on from Ross's question on the cost base, if I look at the year, you'd probably end about with about around 500 million in savings on OpEx, on operating expenses. Can you just help us to understand how much of that would be kind of one-off stuff in terms of travel and how much of that is a structural change? So how much of that could we lift into 2010?</p>
          <p>And then second question is, on the Q1 call you were asked about seasonality in the year, and I know you've talked about a better pipeline going to the second half, but how should we think about Q3 and Q4 in terms of seasonality? Also, in light some of your competitors have talked about that Q3 might be slightly tough because it's only  actually to September to sign big deals. So we should be a bit more careful there, but maybe you can help me understand how I should think about drawing pipeline but also then the seasonality between the quarters. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me take the first part, regarding the operating expenses. If you exclude restructuring charges, then we expect that the year-over-year reduce our operating expenses including stock-based compensation expenses by roughly 650 to &#x20AC;700 million. So the base in 2008, to be very precise, was 8.4 billion and we reduce it by this 650 to 700 million.</p>
          <p>The question, what is sustainable going into 2010, I only can make two comments. The first one is, if you look to the personnel expenses, we haven't seen then the full benefit on an annual basis regarding the personnel expenses from the reduction in positions, number one. Number two, of course we will have some expenses like I several mentioned before, like marketing, where we will also see an increase in spending, but I cannot quantify this for you at this point in time. We haven't done any exercise regarding the budget for 2010 and it's too early to comment on our expense base in 2010. But the majority I can say already now definitely will be sustainable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and let me maybe try to talk a little about seasonality. Actually, we expect seasonality to be in line with previous years. But we do have to keep in mind, and that's very important for you as well, that we didn't have the usual seasonality in 2008 because we had a very strong first half followed by a weak second half due to what happened with the overall economy. Therefore, I would assume that 2009 seasonality will be in line with the previous four, five years, if you exclude 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you. That's all I have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Mohammed Moawalla from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Can you comment a bit about the dynamics in the emerging markets. You indicated that you certainly saw a recovery in the second quarter, and specifically if you could drill in by some countries. And just curious to know what the shape of the pipeline is looking like there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Mohammed, Bill and I will try to answer that. Our only choice, let me try to give you a bit of an overall picture here and Bill can certainly give all of the detail. Emerging markets have been a very important focus topic for SAP, since quite some time. We have been in all of these markets present since the early days, plus as far as we are concerned they're not emerging; they emerged quite some time ago. And we are encouraged by what we see in many of them, we see good things happening, at least medium-term wise in Brazil, in India, in China; Russia is a bit of an exception because of the very particular economic situation there. So overall, I think BRIC countries or the emerging markets in general will continue to be a very important or increasingly important part of the SAP revenue mix. Bill, would you like to add something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, L&#xE9;o, I think you said it very well. I would just add simply that we have built a infrastructure within the company to especially focus on the BRIC, Middle East and Africa to enable these emerging markets and workforces that might be somewhat less matured than the larger market to ramp up quickly and scale their business by leveraging the value dynamics that we have proven successful in industry and geographies, again, in major markets around the world. So that's becoming a craft at SAP that we're getting pretty good at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have time for two more questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Phil Winslow from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, good quarter. I had a question for Bill. You commented that large deals were still difficult to close during the second quarter. When you look at your buy pipeline for the second half, have you seen any sort of return of at least large deals in the pipeline?</p>
          <p>And then also, both to Bill and L&#xE9;o, when you think about the sales force, this utilization rates and if you were actually to see a return to an increase year-over-year and license sales, how do you feel about just the idea of adding head count in sales. Do you feel like the utilization level's low enough right now where you wouldn't have the need to add incremental heads as licenses actually start improving maybe in 2010? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, thank you for the question. Like you, we all want large deals in the pipeline. And candidly there are large deals in the pipeline. What we have to be mindful of, however, in this environment, they're just simply less predictable than they were in the past. And oftentimes they'll have to be phased or subscribed as opposed to recognized upfront. And we want to do business in the manner in which our customers want to do business with us, because it's all about long-term here.</p>
          <p>So, they are there, now we need to see how the execution goes and how many we'll be able to recognize in the quarter and the back-end of the year. But customers clearly view SAP as their strategic business software partner, there is no question about that.</p>
          <p>Secondly, in terms of our sales force. We have tremendously improved the volume and the participation rates in our sales force by driving the volume effect and not relying on big deals, but simply selling to the customer the way they wanted to. Werner has mentioned lift and shift. We plan on making an art form of lifting and shifting assets so we can put them in front of the customers were they could be most productive for our shareholders. And we'll have to see how it goes in 2010 to determine how many feet on the street we need based on the market demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There's time for I think one or two questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Our next question is from Marc Rode from MainFirst. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. Two quick ones, one on services. And it's quite impressive, you're showing a 23% margin despite also a 23% decline in the second quarter. Is that because you're very, very selective on the business you take, i.e., a very extreme price before volume strategy? Or do you think your volume performance is in line with the sort of overall markets SAP-related services business. That's point one.</p>
          <p>And the second point is, you let yourself quoted L&#xE9;o by saying the visibility has improved a little bit and there were some comments already on pipeline. I was wondering whether we could look at it slightly differently. To what extend do you think the pipeline is reflecting a comeback of previously delayed deals, though people having put in their work to evaluate what they want to do and then now coming back? Or to what extend is it new business or genuine new interest? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, first the question regarding the margins. Two answers to this question. The first one is that of course we adjusted our consulting force to the demand we see today in the market right away when we saw the decline in the consulting arena. And even more important is the fact that we really increased the profitability of the consulting business in the Business Objects arena, where you remember in the first half of 2008 we had very, very low margins and we turned this completely around. So both leads to the fact that we have this high margin despite the significant decrease in consulting revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and as to the pipeline, Mark, let me maybe say the following. This is a dynamic evolution of a situation that you need to put a little bit into perspective. Let's remember that Q4 and Q1 were very, very, very tough and challenging quarters from a pipeline perspective with the meltdown of the global economy.</p>
          <p>Q2 started to show that the pipeline was starting to fill again with what one could call more normal type of opportunity. Things that had actually more sustainability to us from a budgetary point of view, from a needs point of view, from a capability of the customer point of view to actually execute a particular deal.</p>
          <p>How much of that in turn was coming from priorly-related decisions or whatever and what is really net you is hard to say, because we had this kind of black hole for a number of months. So I think what is really important is we see a gradual but very steady and very regular uptake of the pipeline that is more and more quantified and I think that is the most important piece of news from our perspective regarding the pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you. Can I just &#x2013; sorry, there was one point on the services with regards to the volume. Do you think that trend that you saw, the 23% organic, is that representative of the market or is that because you were specifically selective on price before volume perhaps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you look to all the service providers, you feel &#x2013; you would see margins which are lower than 10%. So this is already a unique situation we are in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That makes sense. Yeah, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So we have time for one final question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question is from Neil Steer from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much indeed for taking my question. In fact, just before I ask my question, can I just have a point of clarification. Werner, I think when Michael Briest</p>
          <p>asked a question earlier on about the bad debtor provisions in Q1, you said that the figure was 35 million. I thought from the Q1 statement it was substantially larger than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I referred only to the individual debt deposit at 85 million, yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. The questions that I have are first of all there's, there's clearly been a focus as you've mentioned on a number of occasions on the top 400 customers. Can you &#x2013; Max Attention, and so obviously the enterprise support offerings, has became quite an important point of focus over the last six months. Can you tell us how many of those 400 customers actually are on Max Attention now and whether if they're on the underlying enterprise support, whether they have payments terms or contractual terms that are different from the enterprise support spoke that were announced earlier on this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Bill. First of all on the Max Attention, you probably have around 10 to 15% of that base that is on Max Attention. On ES, Enterprise Support, that is our only services offering at this point. So you will see the majority of the 400 on Enterprise Support. What we are very focused on is software and related-services and a combination of Enterprise Support, Max Attention providing critical focus on mission-critical business processes and a procedure we call safe guarding to ensure the quality controls of a well implemented project are all areas where we focus on software and related-services to drive that high margin software-related services line for the company. That's essentially the best 400 customers in the world to utilize all of these services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one very final question. You've obviously &#x2013; there's been a fantastic focus on cost. And we potentially be at the point where the market is starting to at least recover. In the last two cycles, when we've actually seen this, there seems to been a little bit of a push from SAP to win market share. And that has meant to some degree the operational leverage of the business through the &#x2013; as a positive side of the cycle hasn't really driven the margins up to expected levels. At SAPPHIRE this year you've clearly mentioned that your medium-term target to achieve a 35% operating margin, it's clearly very early days going into 2010, but if you keep control on costs, do you clearly anticipate if the cycle experiences a substantial further increase in operating margin next year, is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me put it this way &#x2013; this is L&#xE9;o, and I'll tried to indicate when I spoke earlier. When the economy will pick up again, we are ideally positioned to drive a new cycle of profitable growth. And I wasn't just talking about growth, I was specifically mentioning profitable growth. We believe that we have everything we need to drive such a cycle forward. We will continue to be a very disciplined company. I think that one of the advantages that have happened over the last few quarters is that we have used the opportunity also to become a significantly more leaner and more agile company. Therefore, we are capable of driving more innovation at a lower per unit cost of innovation, if I may say so.</p>
          <p>So going forward, once the economy start to improve, ones the top line starts to improve again, I think we will able to achieve that with a much higher profitability, which will help us to achieve the 30% margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. This concludes our earnings call for today. Thank you all for joining. And goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This does conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation, ladies and gentlemen. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>