<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1262222" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>769</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Stefan Gruber, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Werner Brandt, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Bill McDermott, Co-Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Jim Hagemann Snabe, Co-Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Philip Winslow</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Gunnar Plagge</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Michael Briest</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Ross MacMillan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Knut Woller</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Sarah Friar</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to SAP's Financial Analyst Conference Call. For your information, today's conference is being recorded. Today's call will be hosted by Jim Hagemann Snabe, Bill McDermott and Werner Brandt.</p>
          <p>I will now hand the call over to Stefan Gruber. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Good morning or good afternoon. This is Stefan Gruber. Thank you for joining us to discuss SAP's first quarter 2010 results. I'm joined by Bill McDermott, Jim Snabe and Werner Brandt.</p>
          <p>Werner will discuss the Q1 financials. Bill will provide some color on our regional and industry performance and our go-to-market strategy and Jim will comment on our product strategy. Following the prepared remarks, we will have time for Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>I will now make a few remarks about forward-looking statements. Any statements made during this call that are not historical facts are forward-looking statements as defined in the U.S. Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995.</p>
          <p>Words such as "anticipate," "belief," "estimate," "expect," "forecast," "intent," "may," "plan," "project," "predict," "should," "outlook" and "will," and similar expressions, as they relate to SAP are intended to identify such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>SAP undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements. All forward-looking statements are subject to various risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from expectations.</p>
          <p>The factors that could affect SAP's future financial results are discussed more fully in SAP's filings with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, including SAP's Annual Report on Form 20-F for 2009 filed with the SEC on March 25, 2010. Participants are cautioned not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements, which speak only as of their dates.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Werner, I would like to remind everyone that we have SAPPHIRE NOW, our customer and user conference coming up in May. It will be collocated in Frankfurt and Orlando. We'll be able to get a first-hand impression of the new products and services we are bringing to the market and will have a special focus on a memory technology and, of course, Business ByDesign. Our financial analyst symposium will take place in Orlando on Tuesday, May 18.</p>
          <p>And with that I would like to turn the call over to Werner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stefan. Before I begin, let me remind you that we are no longer reporting in U.S. GAAP. Therefore I will only refer to IFRS and non-IFRS numbers, with a focus on our non-IFRS figures as they are more in line with how we internally look at our operational performance. Also these non-IFRS measures are the basis of our guidance.</p>
          <p>We are pleased to report a strong top line performance in which software and software-related service revenues grew double-digit in addition to reporting further margin expansion.</p>
          <p>Let you give me the highlights of the first quarter. Non-IFRS software and software-related service revenues for the first quarter of 2010 were &#x20AC;1.95 billion, which represented a year-over-year increase of 10% in constant currencies.</p>
          <p>It was driven by an increase in software revenues across all regions and a very strong support business. In fact, support revenue increased sequentially by more 2%, which demonstrates that we are well on track with the retention and adoption of enterprise support within our customer base and for new customers respectively.</p>
          <p>There were also positive effects from currency and lower sales allowances. As a result of the strong top line, the SSRS gross margin increased by 0.7 percentage points year over year to 81.6%, resulting in an overall gross margin of 67.7%, which is up 3.3 percentage points year over year. Looking at the expense side of the P&amp;L, you can see that total operating expenses decreased 6% year over year. In contrast to the first quarter in 2009, the first quarter 2010 was not impacted by restructuring expenses which were 160 million in the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>However, reorganizations in the first quarter of 2010 resulted in severance expenses of 27 million and unused lease space expenses of &#x20AC;9 million. The first quarter 2010 reorganization expenses negatively impacted the R&amp;D expense to total revenue ratio by 40 basis points and the sales and marketing and general and administration expense to total revenue ratios by 50 basis points each.</p>
          <p>The strong top line performance and the reduction in cost resulted in further margin expansion. Non-IFRS operating margin in the first quarter of 2010 increased 8 percentage points to 24.4% year over year. Of the 8 percentage points increase, 6.6 percentage points came from the negative impact of restructuring charges in the first quarter of 2009, with the remaining 1.4 percentage points, or 60 basis points as constant currencies, resulting from additional margin growth that we managed to deliver despite severance and unused lease space expenses of 36 million earned in the first quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>This first quarter of 2010, 36 million expense negatively impacted the margin by 140 basis points in the first quarter of this year. We are striving to increase the operating margin in each and every quarter which we already demonstrated in Q1 despite the negative impact resulting from these reorganization expenses.</p>
          <p>Given the tight restrictions on expenses we maintained mostly in the first half of 2009, we expect a stronger impact on our margin expansion in the second half of 2010. We will continue to stick to a tight discipline on expenses and balance investments needs accordingly. This is also reflected in the head count number, which stayed sequentially almost flat in the first quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>The IFRS effective tax rate in the first quarter was 25.7% which is a decrease of 6 percentage points. The decrease is mainly the result from tax effects from changes in foreign currency exchange rates. We continue to project an effective tax rate under IFRS of 27.5 to 28.5% for the full year of 2010.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow in the first quarter decreased by 46% year over year to &#x20AC;750 million. The decrease is mainly due to the late maintenance billing as a result of the introduction of our new two-tiered support offering. The customer was asked to make their initial choice between enterprise support or standard support by March 15.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we bought back 3.5 million shares, for a total of approximately &#x20AC;120 million. For the full year 2010, we continue to expect to buy back shares in an amount of at least 250 million.</p>
          <p>On the dividend, the Executive Board and the Supervisory Board have recommended that shareholders approve a dividend of &#x20AC;0.50 per share at the annual general meeting in June. If the shareholders approve this recommendation, the total amount distributed in dividends would be approximately &#x20AC;594 million.</p>
          <p>Another highlight in the quarter was the successful placement of a Eurobond with a two-tranche structure consisting of a &#x20AC;500 million four-year tranche and a &#x20AC;500 million seven-year tranche. The transaction was heavily oversubscribed and generated strong international demand, with the majority being placed in Germany, Switzerland and the U.K.</p>
          <p>While we saw a strong demand from retail and private banks, SAP also achieved a well-diversified distribution among core institutional investors such as fund managers, insurance companies and pension funds. The proceeds for the transaction, which helped diversify our sources of financing for future increase our financial flexibility, will be used for general corporate purposes.</p>
          <p>Let me finish up by saying that we have maintained our outlook for 2010. Please refer to the press release issued today for the complete outlook. I would now like to pass the call over to Bill. Bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Werner, and thank you, everybody, for taking the time to join the call with us today. We see clear signs that the market environment is improving. This is underscored by our return to double-digit software and software-related services growth in Q1. We reported software and software-related services growth in all regions. We also reported double-digit growth in our small and mid-size enterprise business, in SAP BusinessObjects and in our focus industries.</p>
          <p>I'm really pleased and so is Jim with the execution in the first quarter. Another positive sign is that volume has stabilized with strong deal volume across direct and indirect channels and there's a healthy mix of small to large transactions. We also saw a return to some large transformational deals. That's deals over &#x20AC;5 million, which accounted for 27% of order entry compared to 12% in last year's first quarter. And the average deal size was up, 36% year over year.</p>
          <p>Most importantly, we captured the positive momentum and extended our leadership position in the fastest growing segments of the business software market. In the BRIC countries, we doubled our business, with particularly strong results in Brazil, Russia and India. In our focused industries like financial services, high-tech and retail, we capitalized on the strong demand across all geographies for our industry-specific solutions, such as our core banking solution. All of these verticals were in double-digit growth and some high double-digit growth.</p>
          <p>In business user, we reported strong double-digit growth, good competitive wins in all areas of the product portfolio, and we extended our market leadership in DI, analytics, and performance management. Its leadership position is highlighted in a recent Gartner study. Business from new customers in the business user segment represented 37% of sales. This is a positive sign and signals that we can expect continued strength in business user as we continue to successfully capture synergies from the BusinessObjects portfolio within the SAP customer base.</p>
          <p>In our small and mid-size enterprise business, we saw a return to double-digit growth. In fact, it was up 13%. We're successfully evolving our go-to-market model to be more scalable and volume-oriented and this is in combination with our inside sales and our channel partners, all expanding nicely. There's also strong anticipation for our new Business ByDesign solutions across the world.</p>
          <p>Let me now briefly touch on the regions. In EMEA, we're seeing more optimism. The strongest regions were UK, France, CIS and Iberia. In Germany customers are once again talking more about investing in software and the pipeline is building nicely as we've brought back a proven leader to run the business.</p>
          <p>Key wins included Gazprom, P. Troy Trumm and Sons and HLL Lifecare Limited. In the Americas, we're seeing a re-emergence in the United States. Latin American continues to report the fastest growth primarily led by strong growth in Brazil. And Canada's results were simply outstanding. Key wins included Dawn Foods International, McKesson Corporation and Banco del Bajio.</p>
          <p>In APJ we're seeing return to normalcy, meaning more traditional buyers are forming a pattern where customers are once again investing for growth, not just efficiency. Moreover, the SME market has strengthened, which is important to us considering it's one of the largest SME markets in the world.</p>
          <p>We're starting to see an improved business environment and an improved sentiment in Japan too. Key wins included Taiwan Fertilizer, China East Airlines and Astellas Pharma. I'd also like to address the trust that markets, customers and partners are putting in the SAP brand and our business model. Examples included overwhelming number of customers choosing our enterprise support offer. As Werner rightfully pointed out, our public bond offering in Q1 was significantly over-subscribed and the continued strong relationships with our ecosystem and alliance partners prevail as they continue to invest and believe in SAP.</p>
          <p>In closing, the outlook for our business is very compelling. We have put customer centricity and innovation at the center of our business. All SAP people are engaged and passionate to make our customers best run businesses.</p>
          <p>As growth is coming back on the agenda and business and IT interests are converging, SAP is uniquely positioned to help customers transform and grow. SAP is the only company in the business software industry that combines integrated business process expertise, transactional integrity, industry best practices and a global delivery capability based on proven end-to-end solutions. The in-process measures for our business underscore this point. There is in fact a strong pipeline Q2 and the remaining quarters. There is strong momentum in key growth markets and categories.</p>
          <p>We have a major upcoming milestone with the simultaneous SAPPHIRE NOW in Orlando and Frankfurt, where we will be making key partner and product announcements. Let me stress that we are committed &#x2013; Jim, myself, the Executive Board, all management across the company &#x2013; to accelerate SAP's resurgence in the coming quarters. And we see a clear path for doing so.</p>
          <p>Jim, I'd like to now turn it over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bill. Thank you, Werner. And welcome, everyone, to today's conference call. Q1 was, indeed, a very strong quarter, and we are very happy with the company's performance. While Bill and Werner provided details on this quarter's performance, I'd like to take this opportunity to give you a brief update on our innovation pipeline and product strategy.</p>
          <p>Innovation remains at the center of our growth strategy and our customers appreciate this. Bill and I have been visiting a lot of customers during Q1. We see a clear change in the strategic agenda of our customers.</p>
          <p>While tight cost control remains important to all companies in all industries, we see clear signs that growth is back on the agenda. And the performance in Q1 demonstrates how SAP and our innovations and products are becoming more relevant than ever before.</p>
          <p>SAP's innovations are focused around three main areas. First of all, we are determined to continue to expand our leadership position in the on-premise market. SAP is today the undisputed leader in on-premise business applications.</p>
          <p>With Business Suite 7, we have delivered the most modern and consistent Business Suite in the market, supporting mission-critical processes in more than 25 different industries. We will continue to deliver enhancements to the Business Suite.</p>
          <p>And with the acquisition of BusinessObjects, we have also taken the lead in analytics as recently demonstrated by Gartner. Our customers appreciate the power of consistent business processes and leading analytical applications to help them run their business better and cheaper.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we're entering into the on-demand market. While we expect the major parts of business applications to remain on-premise, we do believe that software-as-a-service will be growing rapidly in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>SAP Business ByDesign is without doubt the most important innovation from SAP for the on-demand market. We have worked hard to ensure that the technology platform in SAP Business ByDesign is not just a me too, but in fact, a next-generation on-demand platform. We believe that there is an opportunity for us to disrupt the on-demand market with this platform. And we continue to be confident that we will deliver SAP Business ByDesign in a volume-ready version mid-this year.</p>
          <p>The third innovation area is mobility, or on-device as we call it. Mobile devices are becoming the preferred interaction point with business applications. We want to make sure that SAP solutions can be accessed from all leading mobile platforms, like RIM, Nokia, Apple, Google Android, et cetera.</p>
          <p>We are building and delivering mobile applications on these platforms and in addition, we will allow partners and customers to build unique mobile experiences on top of the SAP software going forward. With the investments and innovations in all these three categories on premise, on demand and on device, SAP represent the most complete and consistent application and technology portfolio in the industry, a portfolio that will deliver superior value to our customers and expand our addressable market and fuel our growth.</p>
          <p>In addition, we continue to leverage in memory computing power to achieve an unprecedented speed and simplification of applications going forward. With this technology we plan to pave the way for real real-time analytics and finally remove the decade-old barrier between business applications and business intelligence. At the same time, we are taking measures to improve efficiency and speed of innovation at SAP. This will allow us to act more like an entrepreneur in terms of speed, while keeping the power of scale and robustness we are known for today.</p>
          <p>In closing, while a software company is all about innovation, products and efficient processes we only deliver true innovation due to our people. Realizing that people are our most important asset, Bill and I are very happy to announce the latest addition to the SAP Executive Board, Angelika Dammann. Angelika will join SAP's Executive Board by mid 2010. She will lead a newly created human resources board area and will also serve as SAP's Labor Relations Director. Angelika will join us from Unilever, where she was responsible for Human Resources and Labor Relations.</p>
          <p>So in summary we're off to a good start and we have a very strong pipeline of innovations to come. I want to thank you at this stage and we'll now be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question today will come from Philip Winslow with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Great quarter. Bill, just a question for you in terms of sales and marketing. You mentioned the large deals were starting to come back into the pipeline, you saw very successfully this quarter. When you think about the leverage in the sales force and the sort of spending there, where do you think the utilization rates are on the sales force and can those trend higher, especially as the large deals come back? Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Phil, thank you very much for the question. I appreciate your nice comment regarding the quarter. We feel good about it also. And the sales force right now as we look at how we've retooled the sales force, we built them for transaction volume. As the market dynamics in 2009 were challenging, it also gave us a chance to change. So the reps are now equipped to sell-in to line of business executives as well as CIOs. As you see the convergence of business and IT taking hold in the market, it's clear that business executives and IT professionals are going to partner on being more agile and coming up with new ways to innovate and grow. As that takes place, I expect the deal size to increase, and I believe our sales force is known, very well known, in fact, for doing the larger transformational deals. And yes, there is leverage there. We absolutely have built a volume and a value machine in the organization and I'm confident that we're ready for anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, guys. Good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. The next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll move now to a question from Gunnar Plagge with Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Thanks for taking my question and congratulations as well. And on the support revenue growth, I mean, 10% as you commented was a really a strong number. Could you maybe comment were there any specific dynamics this quarter? There are so many influences now. So that would be very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what you're seeing is the power of giving our customers choice on this service offering. We have given the customers the opportunity to choose between the standard support and the enterprise support and we're seeing a vast majority of customers going for the enterprise support. So I think that's a recognition that this support offering is, in fact, superior in the market and it's the right kind of service offering for mission-critical software, like we are delivering to our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you say, the vast majority, I mean, could you maybe quantify it a little bit? And the question that I had was in support revenue growth going forward. I mean, is it possible to maintain this high year-on-year growth rate going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we do not comment on growth rates regarding specific line items in the P&amp;L, but I can give you some indication. Globally, I think the adoption rate for enterprise support was close to 90% and this is a strong signal from the installed base, but also from net new customers, that they recognize the value of enterprise support.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question today will come from Joseph Lorrey with Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Thank you very much for taking my call. Just I would like to get a little bit more color on the customer behavior in EMEA and the U.S. I see in the EMEA software sales were still relatively weak at 2%, but software and software-related services were very strong at 11, whereas in the U.S., it was the reverse. Software was already 12% decline. Is it fair to say that EMEA was driven by maintenance upgrades and the Americas was more driven by new licenses? If not, could you clarify a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I will take this question. Werner here. I think if you look to the simple maturity of European markets, then the support revenue takes a big, big share of the total revenue in these markets. And that's the opposite in the U.S., number one. Number two, if you look to the buying behavior of customers in the United States, as soon as they see that the common economy is coming back, they invest immediately and that's a bit different in Europe. That's the second argument. That's the reason why you see strong demand in the Americas for software. That's the first thing they invest in and by the way, that's also true for Asia-Pacific. We see a clear investment path in Asia-Pacific here and that are the two reasons why we have the situation as we have it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, excellent. Thank you. And just if I make a short follow-up to the prior question to me in terms of the actions of your customers on the maintenance decisions. There were clearly two things that could happen. Some people might upgrade to the enterprise, but also you are giving the chance to some customers to downgrade if they want to. Can you give us as well some comments on how many of your customers actually have chosen to downgrade?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very simple. That's a difference between roughly 90% and 100%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And we'll take our next question today from Gerardus Vos of Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. Hi. It's Hoyt in. Thank you very much for taking my question. I've got three questions if I may. On the pipeline, I'm just kind of interested in how your philosophy will impact the numbers, perhaps later on this year and when will we perhaps see a quarter-on-quarter acceleration in growth and if there are any indications there? And then secondly, just on the strategy of buy versus build, I just wonder if you guys have any kind of update on that topic? And then finally perhaps your aspirations for Business ByDesign in terms of how you're performing against the competition and how it will change the landscape? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much for your questions. This is Bill. I'll comment on the pipe fibers versus build and then Jim will take on Business ByDesign. First on the pipeline, we see an ever-increasing pipeline building. We obviously have learned from Werner's comments that Asia Pacific and the Americas are showing more robust pipeline, but Europe too is growing and in Germany in particular we see the fastest movement in the pipeline with new leadership and a focus on the customer. So the pipeline is building. We're actually feeling very good about our business, very good. And we're also feeling very good about the customer's endorsement of our on-premise, on-demand, on-device strategy. It makes a lot of sense.</p>
          <p>The buy versus build, you know, it wasn't too long ago when the retail industry did more building versus buying packaged applications. And we now see that that has become a tipping point where packaged software and the idea of buying as opposed to building themselves, is taking off. We see this as well in banking and insurance.</p>
          <p>And in terms of our philosophy if that was part of your question as well, buy versus build. We've always been an organic growth company and we build our own technology and integrated technology because that gives the customer the best end-to-end business process execution. We'll continue to do that.</p>
          <p>But in areas where the company can move forward such as business intelligence with BusinessObjects, you can see that we know how to buy and we know how to integrate and we know how to grow. BusinessObjects portfolio is the fastest growing segment of our business. So if there was a property that could extend our lead in the category and expand our reach, we would look at that very favorably.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And let me take the ByDesign question. We, today &#x2013; just to make sure we have the facts straight &#x2013; we have today approximately 100 customers running ByDesign productively. And what we are bringing out mid-this year is a &#x2013; what we call a volume-ready product. As you all know, we have been working hard on the ByDesign software. And as I mentioned in my introduction, we really wanted to make sure that the infrastructure of ByDesign is the next generation infrastructure for a cloud base delivery model and now the current generation. With that, we believe we can disrupt the market. So we'll be bringing out mid this year, the ByDesign a next version, and with that, we will go more aggressively into the market. However, if you look at the financial numbers for this year, be aware that this is a subscription-based model in an SME market. And so we have not factored in lots of revenue for this product this year. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you very much. Well done in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll take the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Your next question today comes from Michael Briest with UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning or good afternoon, thanks. There was a question on the subscription revenues. I mean, I think, it was the Q4 that you gave guidance for the year of 360 to &#x20AC;380 million. If I look at the Q1 run rate, you're not far off of that level. Could you talk a little bit about subscription adoption plans? Were there any GEAs or Flexible License Agreements in the quarter? Also whether you're seeing maybe a switch back to license purchasing and whether you're still comfortable with that guidance of 360 to 380? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, this is Bill, Michael. How are you? First, on the 360 to 380, that guidance remains the same. There is no change. There was a few FLAs in the quarter, but you're also right. The customers now are investing again in business software. And there's less of an issue with the CapEx versus the OpEx debate, because business software is regarded as a key investment.</p>
          <p>And in times where things are improving, we're noticing that the wallets are opening up again toward investing in this is a capital expense. So that issue has really gone the other way in a certain sense.</p>
          <p>As you know, we only have about 14 GEAs and pretty much the same on an FLA basis globally. So there's no reason for anybody to think that this is going to be any different than our 360 to 380 guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe if I could add something &#x2013; Jim here. In terms of buying pattern of our customers, those customers who have a chance to make a strategic position on the future infrastructure, the vast majority of them choose SAP, also in very competitive situations. And I strongly believe that they do that because of the consistency in the portfolio. The pieces fit together and they cover both the efficiency, the growth opportunity from a process point of view as well as the analytics to give them the necessary insight to run their business. I think that's the strength that we're seeing and that's why we see some of these large transactions coming back again, because companies are making strategic moves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. If I could just follow up with one on the guidance. You've obviously had a very strong start to the year, 10% SSRS growth. The guidance is 428, the trend seems very positive. I mean do you think it's going to maybe raise the guidance at some point as visibility improves? I think on the prior call, I heard you say maybe in July you'd revisit it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course, Michael. Now it's too early based on one quarter to change our guidance. We always said and said this at the January press conference, that we see potential external factors which could impact the buying behavior of our customers and prospects. And this is the case, unchanged. We will see how the second quarter goes and then based on half-year results, revise &#x2013; look into our guidance again and may revise it at that point in time. But today it's really too early to do so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And well done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Next question today comes from Ross MacMillan with Jefferies. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Bill, you made a interesting comment around &#x2013; I think you said 37% of sales from new customers in the business user segment. Can you just do two things, one clarify what you mean by that 37%? Is that order entry? Is that new licenses? And then how has that trended &#x2013; how should we think about that for example relative to the last year and what does it tell you about where the dollars have been spent within the customer base? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so the main thing it tells us is that BusinessObjects and the portfolio of BusinessObjects solutions is every bit is relevant to customers that are non-SAP as customers that are SAP and we plan to make a lot of inroads this year in selling to non-SAP. And as evidenced by the 37%, we know that that could be a very, very good growth story for us. It's trending up. What you have to understand about BusinessObjects in the whole portfolio is that it grew in every region of the world in double-digits and every single product in the BusinessObjects portfolio also grew in double digits. So it's helping us penetrate non-SAP. It's also helping us up-sell and cross-sell SAP, so it's really a very, very positive story within our portfolio. And it's more and more becoming a larger part of our overall business, proving once again that if SAP puts its mind to something that makes sense for customers, we can do an acquisition. We can integrate it well and grow it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then let me just a follow up. As we &#x2013; if we do see more transformational deals I guess going back to the bread and butter of kind of core ERP and so forth, put it this way, do you have the capacity to do that and keep the pedal to the metal on the BusinessObjects and business user front? So in other words, will you get the leverage from core ERP on top of what's happening with the business user strength? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean the answer is definitively yes. There is tremendous opportunity for us to leverage our infrastructure, our sales and marketing force, on core ERP. And to the extent we're able to do that on the transformational side, the BusinessObjects will simply be a force multiplier on top because all of these large transformation deals almost always include the business intelligence platform conversation.</p>
          <p>And similarly, if transformational deals do come back on the table, which we expect they will, as we looked at this past quarter, we replaced the competition in 70 very key wins, 24 of them with a well-known competitor. And what we're seeing is the BusinessObjects, or the line of business conversation, is in many cases now the precursor for the ERP conversation. So no matter how you look at it, this is a very powerful product category to be the market leader in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sir. Your next question today comes from Knut Woller with UniCredit. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Thanks for taking my question. I have just basically two questions. You were just elaborating on business intelligence, that it was a major driver of your success in this quarter and growth across all regions. Can you give us some idea of what drove besides the demand of customers? That's the first part of the question. And then second on Business ByDesign for Jim, in former comments when you had the first launch of the product you were targeting these margins and that would not dilute the margin of your core business. Can you give us an update about that and the mix you expect to achieve these targets? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the highlights from a product perspective, definitely industry solutions, NetWeaver, director components on NetWeaver, and also our custom development project, which contributed to the growth on the product side.</p>
          <p>I think it's very important just to underline that, that if you look at the quarter, it's a solid quarter where growth comes from all regions, but also all product categories. And then that means that we have companies looking at their infrastructure, both from a process and an analytics point of view, and the strategic deals are then combining the two and that's where we're very strong.</p>
          <p>So coming back to your questions around ByDesign and the margin in that business. The key technological improvements that we have done on ByDesign was to get the TCO of running ByDesign significantly down. And when I say significantly, I mean significantly. And this means that we are able to go in and offer, with the ByDesign, a solution at a competitive price, which also has a cost for us that makes it a viable business to be in. That is why we decided not to go for volume before we had that version of the platform and that is the version that we will have ready by mid-this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. We have time for one final question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. We'll move now to Sarah Friar with Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much for putting me in. Two quick questions, Bill. You've just walked through how successful you guys have been with the BusinessObjects acquisition, which clearly begs the question, how are you thinking strategically right now about acquisitions as a vector for growth? And then I have a quick follow-up, if I may.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes so on the M&amp;A front, we are really proud of BusinessObjects and we have a strategy in our company &#x2013; and Jim talked about that in his opening comments around on-premise, on-demand and on-device and how we orchestrate between these levels of technologies for our customers. We will look in our strategy to expand our addressable market and we will address strategic choices with regard to the on-premise, on-demand, on-device, and things that can move our company forward that makes great sense for the customers we're open to and we'll be strategic in our moves. So I think you should know that this is an ambitious management team, a team that understands customers and a team that knows how to win and we also make sure that shareholders are well rewarded for the moves we make.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then if I could follow up on BBB. As you think about a year from launch, what are you thinking about as the key metrics you'll use to define success? Is it number of customers on the platform? Is it margin like you just got asked? Is it the revenue generated and what are really the key things that you as a senior management team will look at and say okay now this has been a successful launch?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Business ByDesign offers us an entry into an on-demand market, which is today relatively un-mature. And we believe that there's a new play to be played there. So this is in addition to the current business that we have. We're targeting a very specific customer segment and the way we will be measuring the success of this part is very simple. This is a volume-oriented product for an SME market in very large countries. So we will be measuring the number of customers as the key metrics of success.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This closes our conference call today. Thank you all for joining and we look forward to see you at the upcoming SAPPHIRE NOW conference in May. Thank you very much and good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>