<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1338656" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9947</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Dmitry V. Zhdanovich, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Anton A. Karamzin, Deputy Chairman of Sberbank's Board</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Alex Kantarovich</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Natalia Orlova</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Thomas Giles</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Rustam Botashev</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Olga Veselova</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Dave Nangle</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Marta Czajkowska Baldyga</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Alex Thumlert</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Andrew Keeley</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Cristina Marzea</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Simon Nellis</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Bob Kommers</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Dmitry Trembovolsky</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, my name is Dmitry Zhdanovich, I'm Head of Investor Relations of Sberbank and I'm pleased to welcome you to the presentation of Sberbank's consolidated financial statements results in accordance with International Financial Reporting Standards for 2009.</p>
          <p>The format of the presentation is straightforward.  We will first provide an overview of the main highlights of the full year 2009 financial performance, Sberbank's competitive position and operating environment and this will be followed by Q&amp;A session. The main speaker for today is Anton Karamzin, Deputy Chairman of the Board and CFO of the company.</p>
          <p>The presentation will be accompanied by the PowerPoint slides that were sent to you earlier. Anyone who doesn't have the slides can find them on our website www.sberbank.ru/com and then in Investor Relations section.</p>
          <p>So the presentation will be conducted in English with simultaneous translation into Russian on a separate line. Please note that the presentation may contain forward-looking statements and please refer for the last page of the presentation.</p>
          <p>And with that please allow me to pass the microphone to Mr. Anton Karamzin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello, ladies and gentlemen, welcome. Thank you for joining our traditional annual conference call representing our consolidated financial statements in accordance with the International financial reporting standards, IFRS, for the year of 2009. I'd like to firstly apologize for starting later than the indicated time. We had our previous press conference over run for a few minutes for technical reasons.</p>
          <p>I would start with a brief highlights of the numbers and then pass it on to you for your questions. We have closed the year 2009 under IFRS with a net profit 24.4 billion rubles compared to 97.7 billion rubles for the previous year of 2008. This accounts for 1.1 ruble earnings per ordinary share and that's compared to 4.5 rubles last year.</p>
          <p>We continue to show &#x2013; the Sberbank Group continues to show steady growth of major items of operating income having increased by 32.9% our net interest income; having increased our operating income before provisions for loan impairment by 44.2%. Our net commission income has grown by 17.3%. We have continued to practice throughout the year or exercise our conservative approach to provisioning for loan impairment. We have charged in total 388.9 billion rubles of provisions through P&amp;L, which is roughly four times the amount &#x2013; the comparable amount for 2008; at the same time, continuing to exercise effective cost control and management.</p>
          <p>We are reporting full year cost income ratio declining to 35.4% compared to 49.3% for the preceding year. Our balance sheet remains highly liquid, 17.4% group total assets have the remaining expected maturity of on demand and less than one month. And we continued to maintain strong capital adequacy ratios. The group's total capital adequacy ratio according to Basel 1 Accord as of the end of the year is 18.1%.</p>
          <p>Our local Russian regulatory capital adequacy ratio stays equally as high, 23.2% as of the end of the year. I'd suggest I'm not going to go deeper into the details in the introductory section and let you ask the detailed questions. I'd probably spend a minute or two on highlighting how this reporting is different from the preceding periods.</p>
          <p>We've significantly deepened and broadened our disclosures, especially in the loan disclosure section. We &#x2013; due to many requests from the users of the financial statements amongst the professional community of analysts and investors has started disclosing our NPLs and provisions by product and by tenures, showing restructured loans by product types.</p>
          <p>We report that the number of &#x2013; the proportion of restructured corporate loans as part of the total corporate loan portfolio has changed from 15% we reported last quarter to 17% this year &#x2013; at the end of the year, and we will be disclosing that parameter on a quarterly basis starting from now on. Whilst we are on it, I'll probably mention that also, which is a frequently asked question, that NPLs within their restructured loans, i.e. those loans that have been restructured but are still non-performing are less than 1% of all restructured loans. That's in corporate book.</p>
          <p>Generally, corporate together with retail book, total restructured loans at the end of the year were 12%, and they were also &#x2013; yeah, they are detailed by product as I mentioned before. We've also continued to broaden other disclosures &#x2013; notes and disclosures. We have significantly increased disclosure in note 36, which talks about our subsidiaries.</p>
          <p>Our accounts, whilst we are on subsidiaries and consolidation, I would want to mention that the bank in Belarussia, which is now number three bank in the local market that we purchased at the end of 2009 in December, is already included in our consolidated statements. The purchase price allocation has been fully included into the accounts. We have got negative goodwill. And the same exercise has been done for &#x2013; the PPA has been done for all the acquisitions that we've done this year.</p>
          <p>The final comment on the accounts themselves that I'll probably made in the introductory part is that we're releasing them 75 days after the reporting period, which is six weeks better than in 2008. Hopefully that makes them more relevant and close to the best practice globally.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll probably close the opening remarks and open it up for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of &#x2013; just a moment please. Our first question comes from the line of Alex Kantarovich. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you. Alex Kantarovich from JPMorgan in Moscow. Anton, good result and thanks for expediting the publication, very, very helpful. I have three questions. The first question is on net interest margin dynamic in terms of outlook for 2010 before we discussed erosion between 50 to 100 basis points year-on-year, whether you can confirm it or provide an update. And also we noticed a sharp decline in net interest margin in the month of February according to the Russian standards. I would like to know whether seasonality is a factor.</p>
          <p>Second question is on provisioning in term &#x2013; we spoke before about, right back by the year end, if we can get an update on this, and also whether you are seeing a peak in loan loss reserves. And third question would be on management option program. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello, Alex. Thanks for the questions. Net interest margin, just for those of you who haven't had enough time to have a look at the presentation, we're reporting it at 7.8% at the end of 2009, which compares to 7.1% for 2010. We are sticking with the previous outlook of margin comparison of between 50 and 100 basis points for 2010.</p>
          <p>Yes, NIM, under Russian accounts for February, is subject to seasonality simply because there's less interest accruing days in the calendar this month. So we're not particularly concerned by that.</p>
          <p>Provisioning, again, sticking with our outlook that from the number that we're showing in this reporting at the end of the year of 10.7% of loan portfolio provided should probably max out at around 12, 14% hopefully by some time mid-year, maybe third quarter.</p>
          <p>From then on, one might probably see some reduction in levels, but material releases should probably be coming no earlier than 2011, which we think is somewhere between sensible and conservative assessment.</p>
          <p>And stock options, well, the proposal by the management to the Board and to various bodies that coordinate the approach to long-term incentives in the companies with state ownership have been &#x2013; this proposal had been formulated a while ago. We have said before that it contains best practice as the world and the various regulatory bodies globally see it in the post-crisis environment. The discussions are undergoing at various levels but the decision has not yet been made, unfortunately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Natalia Orlova. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello. Natalia Orlova from Alfa Bank. Anton, Hello. Dmitry, hello. Well, one follow-up question to elaborate on what Alex asked you. So in terms of the net interest margin, you reported quite sharp decline of return on your assets in the fourth quarter. So I'm just wondering do you see the possibility to reduce further cost of funding in 2010, or do you see that the return of your assets will stabilize at the current level or decline only slightly? What's your current trend and what are your projections?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Natalia. Good question. We do see that both from interest rate environment perspective and from the risk environment perspective, the trend for reduction in interest rates will continue this year and will have impact on both the liabilities and the asset side on our financials. And long before we feel uncomfortable financially about this, most of our competition will feel much bigger pain. So we're relatively comfort in that downtrend in the interest rate environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In short terms, yes, we do see the cost of our liabilities continuing to reduce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, another question is on cost growth. So you have declined quite substantially the number of staff last year and also the staff cost have declined, I think, around 3%. So do you see possibility to continue this trend in 2010? If you can come with any guidance for the staff cost growth or cost-to-income ratio for this year would be very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the cost side, those of you who have the presentation in front of you, Page 14 shows the head count reductions throughout the year, which is just around 20,000 people that we have reduced. In fact, this is consolidated numbers because we've taken on a few companies that have got significant staff including BPS, which is the Belarusian Bank. But, in the core bank itself, we have actually reduced the head count by more, by bigger number.</p>
          <p>In accordance with what we've said in our five-year strategy, we will continue increasing our efficiency and therefore realize the positive effects of that in reducing the head count all the way through 2014. The strategic target remains not more than 220,000 employees by 2014, which means we will be doing material cuts every year.</p>
          <p>In terms of cost-to-income ratio and the guidance for 2010, I'll probably repeat what I have been saying before, is that we have shown our ability to control costs in the tough times. A big proportion of the cost cuts that we've shown in relative terms, in terms of cost-to-income ratio is sustainable but some of them is obviously one-off for the year. But, our strategic target, again, for 2014 is to come up to about 40% cost-to-income ratio, which is pretty respectable as far as we can see in comparison to comparable competition. But, in the mean time to partially compensate for some of the savings that we've made or maybe slower spending on our strategic initiatives that we've made in 2009, we would have to catch up in 2010 and 2011. However, I would like to stress that our cost-to-income ratios would still remain in the low 40s, which is again healthy and comfortable for our financials.</p>
          <p>So that's the outlook. We will be catching up, but all of that investment we do see will be generating further efficiencies to the way we operate and to our bottom line as well in the subsequent periods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for this detailed answer. And final elaboration then your provision <mark type="inaudible" /> I think, just again to have more clarity. So you were previously guiding for 12% to 14% provision-to-loans range by the end of 2010. Will you have any &#x2013; well, would it be fair to say that now with the very good NPL-to-loan ratio you reported as of end of 2009 of 8.5%, you can be more comfortable staying at the low range of this 12% to 14% provision-to-loans coverage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Difficult to say. Within 1% and 2%, that difference that you're referring to, that very much depends upon not only the NPL creation and provisioning itself for the companies and individuals that are borrowers that may be feeling actually worse, it also depends very much on the pace of the recovery work which is very much different from company to company and client to client. And that is also &#x2013; don't forget about the denominator which is the loan portfolio. And again, we've been mentioning before and we're sticking to the outlook of pretty modest growth in the size of the loan book just above inflation. So it's difficult to say; too many variables to be precise about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So at the moment you will just stay with 12% to 14% guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sort of, yes. And again I would specify that again, it should peak out by around mid-year third quarter. Then there may be some releases, but nothing particularly material. And again, you have to perceive this in the right context. I don't think any country in the world can boast that there'll be big material recoveries just one year after the big-hitting crisis going on. Usually recoveries take a little while longer, more than a year or two, three. So we have to be sensible about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much, Anton.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good afternoon, gentlemen. I'd actually just like to come back to a question that was made earlier. And rather than actually than making questions, give some encouragement or urge something. But, first of all, I'd just like to congratulate you in your handling of the bank through the crisis which is very impressive and management deserves a good deal of the credit. Also well done on the increased transparency in the disclosure which is much appreciated.</p>
          <p>But, to come back on the issue of the management share option program where much progress has not been made, and I'd like to say that Sberbank is one of the largest banks in the world now, not having a management share option program, it doesn't help attract stable, long-term investors to your shareholder base. And so I'd encourage you to strongly consider deciding to go ahead with the program as it should be a very positive sign to the capital markets. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you. Thank you for your support in this particular area and thank you for the strength that you've noted at the beginning. Not all of those decisions, unfortunately, are in the hands of the executive management team. They are obviously decided at higher levels including the Board and the shareholders. So we are doing our best to support this decision. However, again, we ought to be showing some modesty too because we're an interested party. So probably not further comments on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Thomas Giles [Nevsky Capital LLP] . Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I just have a couple of questions and I'd also like to just back up that comment in the last call. I mean, it's been a long time coming this management options program. I think we've already seen quite a lot delivery on what you guys have promised to deliver. And it would be a very large negative to lose the sort of management team that's currently in place. I'm not suggesting that's imminent or about to happen but certainly management teams need to be properly incentivized. So, I too think that. I don't expect any comment from you on this. I'm just making the comment. So that's the first thing.</p>
          <p>And then the second thing is do you think you'll be in a position to give guidance at any point in the next few months? I know some of your competitors have. Perhaps you're being just a bit cautious to see how things pan out before you're willing to give any sort of 2010 guidance in terms of bottom line and perhaps the component parts of the balance sheet and P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>And my final question is just on loan growth and your liquidity. I mean, you've obviously increased liquidity quite significantly both in '09 and in the first part of 2010. Whilst loan growth remains, I guess, fairly stagnant, you're putting this liquidity into sort of lower-yielding securities. Do you need to have this much liquidity for as long as loan growth remains stagnant or is this sort of a bullish sign of how you see loan growth developing later on this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, thank you for your support on the first item. The outlook for 2010 will confirm the one that was mentioned before in terms of the net profit being at least 100 billion rubles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know this is conservative and modest but that's probably the requirement of my job to be such.</p>
          <p>In terms of the structure of the assets, we &#x2013; again, we &#x2013; now if you look at the Page 16 of our presentation, you'd see the dynamics of the asset structure showing that the loans have decreased gradually from 2007 and 2008 down 2009, from 80% to 76% to 69% of the balance sheet, which is actually, in terms of loans-to-assets ratio, somewhere between 70% and 75% is probably where one would be. So, so far the proportions liquid and therefore less-yielding assets on our balance sheet is probably sensibly healthy. So we're not particularly interested in changing that materially.</p>
          <p>Now, yes, there is some pressure from the abundant short-term liquidity on the liability side or rather abundant short-term liquidity in the banking sector in Russia and in the world, and abundant liquidity per se without the short-term definition on our balance sheet, and sort of weaker demand for loans from both consumer and real sector which puts pressure on the margins. But again, so far, we're comfortable that we can go quite ahead with more or less symmetric moves on repricing our assets and liabilities with limited pressure on the margins. And we can go much, much further than any one of our competitors, at least in Russian markets, before we feel any pain. So that's quite our position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that. I suppose I was trying to &#x2013; I think 15% loan growth has been mentioned for 2010 for Sberbank specifically. Is that right? Are you happy to sort of stick with that sort of number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you see, the biggest variable there is what is going to happen with oil prices and inflation and other external factors. So far, the interest rates and inflation trends are downward in the economy. We're cautious whether that could be &#x2013; there is some risk that it may not be continuing throughout the whole year 2010. And given the respectable voices in the markets such as representatives of the regulators, macroeconomic think tanks who cover Russia voice different scenarios, there's a lot of uncertainty in that variable.</p>
          <p>We are saying, and have been saying, that given our size, given our proportion to the rest of the sector, given the structure of our loan portfolio, everything points out to the fact that the loan growth on our books would be somewhat above the inflation level throughout 2010. Now, since we last mentioned 10, 15% outlook for loan growth, the inflation has gone pretty much significantly down. So while still saying that the loans should grow somewhat above inflation, it would brings us much closer to 10% nominal growth from that to 15%, 10% maybe being a bit on the high side. So that's the environment we're living in. And, unfortunately, no one can probably be more specific than what I've just described.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one more follow-up thing. I wouldn't persist too long. I mean, historically, one-times nominal GDP growth has been like a reasonable guidance for &#x2013; or at least that for system loan growth. And because Sberbank is &#x2013; because I would suggest a large part of the Russian banking system isn't liquid, it isn't sufficiently capitalized. That's going to sort of benefit disproportionately the banks that are capitalized and are liquid. And so wouldn't you therefore expect to grow a premium to system loan growth which in turn is growing at least in loan growth and therefore actually instead of it being 10%, it could well be higher? Because a lot of your old competition, when there was wholesale funding available, are no longer able to lend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah. I'd welcome your optimism about the levels being above 10%, but I don't think the outlook and the objective indicators that &#x2013; or rather the indicators that the analysts are putting out are supporting that. Now our internal think tank have last week told us that their outlook for inflation for this year is probably between 7%, 7.5%. They are now in the process of updating their own outlook on the nominal GDP growth. But the last time they were talking about it &#x2013; last month, I think they were talking about 3.8%.</p>
          <p>So we definitely believe and share your view in the assumption that we should be growing faster than the rest of the system but that is also has its nuisances in it because the good sustainable demands for credit is scarce and even between the very few banks that are capable of lending on an industrial scale in this environment who are liquid and well capitalized, there's fierce competition for good credit. That's in the corporate part.</p>
          <p>The rest of the economy, well, most of the banking sector is still to learn how to successfully lend to SME segment in Russia kind of on an industrial scale, including us. And this is a big race, whoever gets there first gets the sweetest return. The trick is obviously to balance risk and reward rightly and that's what we're focusing a lot of efforts ourselves to actually win that race.</p>
          <p>In the retail space, we believe that technologically, we have already won this race. The systems that we have installed and rolled out for pretty much all urban European areas of the country and will complete roll out for the rest of the country by the end of this year entirely put us ahead of anyone, in terms of speed, quality, risk management, etcetera. The biggest trouble there, though, is that the end-consumer demand is still very weak. And despite all that, despite our approval rates being good, despite our inflow applications being good and competitive situation being good, the sector itself is not putting up enough demand for credit for us to be talking about anything meaningfully bigger than inflation there. So that's the way it looks now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Rustam Botashev. Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, it's Rustam Botashev from UniCredit Securities. Well, first of all, I would like to join the previous guys and say congratulation to you for the first publication which came far ahead of the competition, I think it's a great achievement. And, so my questions &#x2013; my first question is about the NPL. For the first quarter last year, your new NPLs were about RUB 29 billion which is about a third, what you saw in the third quarter. I'm just wondering, is it seasonality or you see the same level for the quarters to come in 2009? Or even decreasing because I would guess that the loans which you issued post-crisis or during the crisis were of better quality. That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I actually exactly captured that. I have caught that you're talked about provisioning of our NPLs in absolute terms, in ruble terms as opposed to relative terms, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm talking about the NPLs in absolute terms. Is the level of NPL increased minus the write-offs increased by about RUB 29 billion in the first quarter and about RUB 89 billion in the third quarter? So the decline is two-thirds during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Part of the slowdown in creation of NPLs or rather in NPL growth is visible is that &#x2013; can I put it this way, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And was it because of the seasonality in the fourth quarter or you think that this is a trend and we can see the levels of new NPLs in absolute terms &#x2013; new loans for entering payouts in absolute terms in 2010 at approximately fourth quarter level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I don't think there's anything seasonal about NPLs in these particular numbers, maybe sometimes there is, but definitely not in this case. And we do see the slowdown in new NPL creation. However, we would caution that NPLs themselves in absolute terms would still grow pretty much all the way throughout 2010. And that difference as compared to the level of provisions which we've just discussed a few minutes ago, whilst the provisions we think should be picking out sometime in the middle of the year, third quarter and then stabilize and maybe then decline a little bit. The NPLs themselves should be behaving somewhat differently and the reason being that the provisioning actually reflects the more up-to-date perception of our risk profile because we create them the moment we see the problem release then the moment we see that the problem is sustainably resolved in each particular transaction.</p>
          <p>But NPLs, it's a pretty technical definition that actually is manifesting itself on our balance sheet about three, six, maybe nine months after the problem has actually hit our borrower. And that's particularly applicable to plain vanilla bilateral loans that we've got on our balance sheet, both corporate and retail sector.</p>
          <p>So therefore, the new NPL creation that we see actually reflects the problems &#x2013; financial problems hitting our borrowers about half a year, three quarters ago, which were still pretty tough times back then. So provisions react with the time lag to the environment in terms of how they show up on the balance sheet and P&amp;L. So &#x2013; sorry not provisions, NPLs react with the time lag.</p>
          <p>Therefore, we would still see them continuing to grow with that time lag throughout 2010. But what we are relatively comfortable with, actually we're quite comfortable with is that the provisions to NPL ratio should be staying within the comfortable levels of whatever the analyst and investor community proclaim to be comfortable levels of between 80% and 120%. As you can see we have moved this quarter from third quarter, from 110% to 120%. So &#x2013; but as long as we are between 80 and 120, we're comfortable about it. And we think that that shouldn't be giving us any particular concerns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the second question is the last question. Investors keep on asking about the Depositor Seeds Program. Now when you seem to have no legal obstacles to launch this program, can you give some kind of guidance or more clarity on this issue, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That won't be anything new or unique as compared to what I've been mentioning to the press in the past couple of months is the &#x2013; and that echoes the comments that our CEO have made in the beginning of the year in a couple of the big conferences. That whilst there is no restrictions for us to actually go and broaden significantly the universe of our potential shareholders by doing a DR program, we're actually a bit concerned with the propensity of the markets &#x2013; financial markets to form bubbles because the liquidity overhang, a lot of which is speculative, both locally in Russia and in the world, is still big. And people are looking for opportunities.</p>
          <p>So tactically, it's probably not a good time right now to do any short moves in increasing the accessibility of our instrument &#x2013; our stock to which broader categories of investors only to see within the nearest month that our stock becomes the subject of a bubble. So what we have agreed internally is that we are now on a short notice. We are compliant with pretty much any imaginable rules in terms of ability to qualify for various listings, et cetera, et cetera, maybe except Sarbanes-Oxley. But &#x2013; so on a month or two notice, we can choose the right moment tactically when we feel the markets are good and calmer and less overheated to actually go and do a DR program. So it's just pure tactical decision on when is the right moment to move.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just imagine if you decide to launch the program tomorrow, how long it's going to take you to finally launch it? Is it a month, three weeks or how long it's going to be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, whatever it takes, technically, around a month, maybe five weeks, whatever.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's what I mean. Did you estimate how long it takes technically to launch this program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, we have. That's why I'm giving you the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Four or five weeks, if we choose a decision, it will take us to actually do something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, terrific. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Olga Veselova. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, it's Olga Veselova calling from Troika Dialog. My first question is, what are your thoughts on subordinated debt from the Central Bank? Would you rather prefer it to pay it back or prefer to decline the interest rates? Or you feel comfortable with it the way it is now at its current interest rate? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is, what margin erosion you would consider as crucial for the bank? I realize that the answer will depend on other lines of the income statement, but you might give us just your thoughts on what you think is low and of comfortable margin range for the bank. That's my second question.</p>
          <p>And the last question, if possible, is the continuation of previous questions. Would you expect loan growth to resume in the first half of this year? And what would be conditions <mark type="inaudible" /> naturally and we should try to expect in the second half? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sub debt, we obviously cannot be happy with the third option. It's a bit too expensive at 8% now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we are equally comfortable with reducing the rate to market levels, which can be easily verifiable in our case. And we are aware that there is a &#x2013; that actually requires changes in the law, and that there is an initiative by one of the deputies in the Russian Parliament to reduce the rate to 4.75%. We don't know &#x2013; it's not in my position to comment on how likely is that to come to fruition and when, et cetera. But equally, we would be happy to repay big part of that. It's not all of that actually. Our liquidity and capital adequacy allow us to do that. So, there's some dialog going on about this. We'll see where it goes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just to ask here. I realize that cut-off rates will require changes in the law, but the paying back of the debt will not require changes of legislation, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as I am aware, the procedure &#x2013; the regulation changes that have been brought by Central Bank about two or three years ago actually amended this to not require change of law in case where the lender is &#x2013; where such repayment is approved by the Central Bank as a regulator. Obviously, in this case, it is the lender as well. So to the best of my knowledge, no. But that's probably not the right question for me to answer. We better ask the lawyers and specialists in that field. Dmitry Zhdanovich, our Head of IR, will be happy to pass the question on to our experts and then get the answer back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of margins, the way you're putting your question suggests playing with a multi-factor model and seeing what would be critical or non-critical for us as dependent on inflation, interest rate environment and level of risk. So it will be difficult to me. We obviously have our model explained with that but difficult for me to try just verbally without visualization aid or to throw up a couple of scenarios here in the air for us to discuss it. And besides, that venture is in those little proprietary sectors of how people model things in each shop. So I don't think I can say more than just repeating our outlook that the margin compression should be around 50 or 100 basis points in 2010.</p>
          <p>And similarly about the loan growth interest, half of the year versus second half of the year, too much uncertainty. I wouldn't be comfortable forecasting in that level of granularity. The way it feels, and just intuitively, that at least for the nearest quarter or two, the inflation and interest rate environment, the downward trend in interest rates and inflation, have the basis to continue. What happens there, where it stabilize there or where it will continue at what pace, whether they might be pushed back from inflation due to excessive liquidity, how effectively is the monetary policy going to be in this coming six months, how much excessive liquidity Central Bank will be able to sterilize. Actually, all those variables prevent us from being more specifically. So &#x2013; but probably, the trends we see now can continue overall for the next six months. And how this translates to our loan growth, I think it's relatively easy to predict from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay, right. Okay, thank you, Anton, for your thoughts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of David Nangle. Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. It's David Nangle from Renaissance. Hi, Anton.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I have got two questions and a follow-up statement, but I'll go one by one with the questions. And on the loan growth, I know you're saying you're seeing sluggish loan growth year to date and you're talking inflation plus and for the full year, but what are you actually seeing in lending growth today? Is there any area you're seeing a pickup or demand in whether it's big corporate, certain sectors, SME, retail. Where is the bright light on all of this or is it all pretty sluggish across the board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All in all, in real sector and the corporate sector, it is pretty sluggish although there is bigger diversity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some parts of the demand still get weaker and weaker, some parts of the demand get a little bit better. I suspect I've already mentioned that interesting number that some of the macro guys were quoting in the press that the level of external corporate debt by Russian corporates have &#x2013; in December already have reached the pre-crisis 2007 levels. So those good credits in the corporate space that have had access to external debt markets have already restored that in full back by December. And if they need more they can probably gain access to more of it and less expensive, but then there is huge competition for that.</p>
          <p>The large but not largest segment is the sweet spot now because those guys are probably feeling not as bad as some of the middle sized companies. But then again, even those of them that feel financially comfortable are firstly still suffering from relatively weakened demand, and secondly, are much, much cautious about building their leverage. People have been burned on this in all the countries, so. And then as I mentioned before, the SME segment, no one's really cracked properly on an industrial scale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's where those two segments, in addition to fierce competition in the largest segment, in those two segments, we're putting a lot of effort in making sure we can find credits meeting our underwriting standard and risk appetite and lend to them successfully and profitably. And a number of competitors are doing that. So what is going to be the result of that? Well, we've never had these conditions in the macro environment before and pretty much within Sberbank in terms of what we're doing internally either. So difficult to predict but that's me summarizing the way it feels. Again demand for consumer loans is still very weak. We can satisfy much, much bigger. Again, the machine that I was advertising last year and then the year before announcing that we're going to be implementing fancy, super-modern retail lending and risk management machine, the machine is in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the demand is not yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's clear. And the second question is on cost. I know you've given guidance on cost income ratio of about 40% and &#x2013; but as I am looking at year-on-year cost growth 2010 versus 2009, if you look at head count, you said you've shifted about 20,000 employees in '09, I don't know if you can tell me --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That actually, David, actually has been more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the bank itself, it's actually more. We've purchased a bank with a few thousand head count.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've also consolidated some of the businesses that have fallen into our lap through default and they have quite a number of people. We've actually reduced a total of 10%, about 9% of our core bank workforce in 2009. And yes, we are going to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, well, if you do a similar kind of head count reduction this year, even a little bit less and you get the benefit of last year's reduction into this year, also this year you've got single-digit inflation and <mark type="inaudible" /> a little bit higher than that but are we looking at another year of single-digit cost growth at Sberbank due to all these factors? Or is there a big cost expansion program in the background which kind of gives us double-digit cost growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Difficult to say. We're probably somewhere on the border. But you are absolutely right in spotting the parameters that make an impact on that number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we are going to be continuing to reduce costs. It's easy to calculate from where we stand now to come towards 200,000, 220,000 head count by 2014. It would take us about 5% head count reduction on average a year &#x2013; well, every year until then. What exact number is going to be coming out each year, it doesn't really matter that much. It is probably roughly about 5% because the big and the painful cut this year that we needed was actually made. And yes, the financial impact of those we'll largely be seeing this year. We will be catching up on investing into strategy in IT platforms and systems, relevant platforms because we have been under-investing into that previously, not as much into hardware and IT. That we've been pretty good at, but &#x2013; in systems, but then again, that's bringing the proportion of the cost structure to healthy comparable to best peers stance and inflation &#x2013; yeah, inflation is lower. There is this big rebasing exercise internally that we're doing to make sure we pay people transparently and motivate them better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That will involve this year ironing out the wrinkles in the way we pay people because in some regions, in some employee categories we're actually paying slightly over the market. In some regions and some categories of employees we are under-paying. But net-net, that should probably be zero impact from that exercise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, well, yeah that's the way it is going to be panning out because there's more than three factors impacting that. It's hard to say precisely whether it's below 10 &#x2013; single-digit or double-digit growth. Hopefully, again, and I hope we will be able to surprise you positively, but then again don't forget, we need to catch up on some of the spending that we've held off on in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's all very clear and thanks for that. But I would like to finish with a statement, because the whole area of stock options and management remuneration has been brought up on the call so just because I want to throw my opinion in there too and I think I speak for Renaissance Capital when I say essentially it's madness that the scheme has not been put in place yet. It is simply global best practice for management remuneration of big banks. It's a transparent way of paying management and given your delivery to date, from my opinion anyway, and I see what you guys do on the ground, it would be wrong if you were not properly remunerated for that job that's being done. So it's not a question or no response is necessary. Because it was brought up already in the call, I feel it was worth saying,</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for your support.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Marta Czajkowska. Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. It's Marta Czajkowska calling from KBC Securities. Two questions please. After a decline of the consumer lending in 2009 and with your credit card growth strategy, the question is whether you are planning to ease lending criteria and what impact would that have on the fee income and on the P&amp;L? And maybe if you just comment on the fee income outlook whether you have any room to reprice upwards any products or what else would be the driver of fee income this year?</p>
          <p>And the second question would be on the retail deposit market share. We recently heard that it's a priority for Sberbank and we saw when market share declined from 50% in October to 48.8 in February, maybe you can comment on what initiatives have been put in place? Is this going to be only a matter of price or any other factors? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. These are good questions. Our retail risk appetite, again talking about the fancy machine for retail lending and risk management that we have put in place where that moves the dial in terms of the risk appetite is very clear. Historically, Sberbank was kind of prohibitively conservative in terms of retail risk appetite. We simply were putting very high barriers on the pure credit risk itself, that is kind of pre-2008 story.</p>
          <p>We were still &#x2013; we were showing somewhat better than market average final losses on retail loan portfolio because of that and that was compensating our poor processes on handling fraud in terms of consumer lending. Now we are putting that right by having input new system and roll these out for most of the European part of the country, at least in the urban areas.</p>
          <p>We are very comfortable that we can move the risk appetite from ultraconservative to somewhere between modest and conservative and which is where the bank of our size should actually be. In fact, so far we are showing under that new technology of lending that we do, which is not point-of-sale lending with classic branch loans which is done very well in terms of underwriting, we're showing much better final losses results. And we are planning on very good application approval rates.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; but again the dial is between moderate and conservative. And that's where we're going to stay. And even with that because we're getting much &#x2013; very good at cutting out the potential fraudulent obligations and we have reduced the time to cash &#x2013; time from about 10 days to actually under 2 days, this is a bit of a revolution in Sberbank terms. We see that that will put us into a comfortable position of a market leader, true, quality market leader when the demand for consumer loans will resume and restore. But we'll not compromise the quality of the risk.</p>
          <p>The fees, well, we've been showing good results between ourselves in terms of the growth and the pace of growth for the fee income. But you are right to point to this item on our revenue side because we ourselves internally are not particularly happy about it still. We want it to grow faster. We do see the opportunities for that, and not from being greedy and ripping off our customers, but actually providing much better quality, speed of service, much better wallet penetration and much better experience overall, and then that's both retail and corporate banking.</p>
          <p>Our image is, unfortunately, in the eyes of our clients, is very far from where we would want it to be. And this is where there is a lot of effort being put internally. This is a cultural change within the company. And our CEO is one of the biggest proponents of that. He has a firm belief that that's where we should be sustaining the financial success through providing better quality of non-risk-related services that bring in fees and commissions.</p>
          <p>In terms of retail deposits market share, the most recent data that we've published, and there has already been some comments about this in the press in the past couple of days that I have read that Sberbank has reduced retail deposit rates in January. But the February statistics that have just been published this week show that our market share in retail deposits inflows has actually increased instead of reducing.</p>
          <p>In fact, a number &#x2013; we've had our regular Assets and Liabilities Committee today. And our head of retail businesses have quoted a number from the official statistics by the Central Bank today to us saying that in February the total inflow of retail deposits into the banking sector in this country has been just over 100 billion rubles, and at least 80 billion of that, which is just under 80%, have been in favor of Sberbank and that's on the back of us reducing the rating in January. You can take that as a very much symptomatic and characteristic of the perception of Sberbank by its retail deposit base.</p>
          <p>We are not &#x2013; we are purposefully not competing on price and we've been repeatedly saying that, we're competing on access, which is a given, there's nothing to boast about it. We are 20 times bigger in terms of branch network than anyone else, but also we're putting a lot of effort in competing on speed and quality and the quality of service. And obviously, one of the biggest factors is our reliability and safety.</p>
          <p>So we are comfortable so far that all these efforts will allow us to keep this around the 50% threshold &#x2013; rather the 50% level of market share in retail deposit space. A lot of people in the press and non-professional community, not analysts, not investors, try to put a little bit more charisma into that number itself. But we're pretty easy between 48 and 52%, as long as we're there we're where we want to be and we're not going to be dragged into pricing competition just because of a few tenths of a percentage point in the market share in this category. So we're taking rather a long-term view on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Alex Thumlert. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Hi. Alex, I'm from George Weiss. Most of my questions have been answered already. I just want to congratulate you guys on the performance. And one quick question, are you guys planning to come to the U.S. for some sort of investor trip anytime soon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very well-pointed question. I want to apologize in front of all the investors and shareholders community for not finding an opportunity in the past two years to actually go over to the American continent. But I'm hoping to correct that in the coming months. There is couple of opportunities and conferences that are coming second quarter that I hopefully would try to make.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Andrew Keeley. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. This is Andrew Keeley from Troika Dialog. I have a couple of questions. Just first of all, just following up on your comments on deposits. I mean, if you were expecting about 10% loan growth this year, what deposit growth would you say you'd be targeting? I mean, you have retail deposits that are ticking along at 20% plus. Are you happy to reduce this growth and possibly by cutting rates and conceding a bit of market share?</p>
          <p>My second question is on your lending dynamics. I mean, it's very clear what you're saying in terms of very weak demand and I'm just wondering whether this implies that you're going to really have to cut rates quite a lot further. I mean, if we look at the bond markets at the moment kind of leading corporates can borrow on the ruble market at sub-10%, and so clearly there's not much incentive for them to take out loans perhaps above those rates. And I'm just wondering if you need to kind of bring down lending rates probably quite a bit further to kind of stimulate borrowing, then isn't this going to make it quite difficult to get to kind of NIM compression of 50 to 100 basis points?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're getting again into an area where it's difficult to be precise in your outlook. I would say one thing, deposit growth is obviously going to be faster than the loan growth. But I would also point out in one parameter, in the interest rate environment level that we are going into, i.e., single-digit pretty much, the public is &#x2013; from a competitive standpoint, the public and the borrowing public, the depositing public, retail and corporate are becoming less sensitive due to price differential.</p>
          <p>A few tenths of the basis points are actually not as significant as compared to a few percentage points that we've been observing pretty much throughout 2009. And that is on top of the fact that, again, as I mentioned before, we're quite comfortable symmetrically reducing the rates in both the assets and liabilities. That is nice icing on the cake, where the lower we go, the more client preferences are going to be to quality, reach, accessibility, ability to do certain things better than the competition, and that's what we're counting on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And just one final question. The NPL data was obviously very good in the fourth quarter and you did bring down your provisioning. But as you've referred to earlier, your provisioning coverage went up quite strongly in a Q-on-Q to 125%. You say that provisioning is more of a kind of leading indicator. Is there anything in terms of concerns you have about any maybe kind of chunky NPLs or anything coming through in the next couple of quarters as to why this provisioning coverage has gone up? Or is it something we really shouldn't be too concerned about just for one quarter?  Because it seems a little bit kind of counterintuitive to the fact that you've got very good NPL data coming through but you're actually increasing your coverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, you're right. Again, as I think I've mentioned on some of the discussions earlier, now we're in a territory where month-on-month and quarter-on-quarter comparisons in provisions, NPL coverage ratios, NPLs themselves are going to be a bit volatile simply because of &#x2013; whatever happens to specific transactions plus or minus, they're not going to be interpreted on a short time spans as forming any trends. I don't think we're talking about any particular big transaction that may have impacted the last quarter. No, this is just a combination of little specific things that have been happening throughout that particular short period of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thanks very much, Anton. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from the line of Cristina Marzea. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good afternoon. It's Cristina Marzea from Merrill. I wanted to dig a bit deeper into this margin driver. Just to clarify your guidance of 50 to 100 bps does not include any potential positive benefit from the repricing of subordinated loan. And then following on where you see the timing of the repricing of assets versus liabilities, your cost of funding on retail deposit is still going up, you have cut prices in the first quarter, but am I correct to think that this will take a while before we see the benefit of these lower prices? And then on the asset repricing, how much has it already been done? What kind of prices are you charging to new corporate loans versus sort of the average for the book? And also thinking about the mix in the asset side, how do corporate loan yields compare to what you're getting on your securities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Cristina. The last question is easier. Obviously, securities are yielding less. Again, starting with the easier ones, the outlook of 50 to 100 bps, NIM contraction doesn't exclude anything that may happen due to sub debt. If we repay or reprice the sub debt, that will be the icing on the cake on top of that.</p>
          <p>In terms of timing of repricing of assets and liabilities, it tends to go in kind of in waves, it's not linear. In the current environment, the loans are pricing down in a bit more linear fashion than the liabilities. But then again, we're still prepared to go further down on cutting the cost on the retail deposits. So this is a difficult question to answer not because we don't have the answers, we actually do, but because of the broad spectrum of products, maturities, currencies and client segments both in the assets and liabilities side. We can probably talk averages. But they become absolutely meaningless and then there is only &#x2013; and if not averages, you then characterize the pricing behavior of a particular product type of client segment which doesn't give you the ability to generalize the picture.</p>
          <p>This is very well illustrated on the page 10 of our presentation which talks about interest expense and in page 9, which talks about interest income. Look, the lines there on the graphs at the bottom pretty benign, I mean. And that is throughout going through one of the most shocking events in the economy. So it's difficult to say, yes. Even throughout interest rate increasing environment, when everything was going through the crisis, our assets were probably repricing somewhat faster than the liabilities. And now maybe they are pricing down a little bit slower but that is only just a feeling. Actually on average they're very, very close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. So it will be volatile. So we should expect volatility quarter-on-quarter. I was just wondering on the new pricing, looking at 13% yield on corporate loans. I mean, should we expect that to go towards the 10% level or, I mean, just how much more pressure could we see on the corporate pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, there will be some. But then again, hopefully, that would be compensated by the fact that whilst top quality credits are going to be priced down in terms of yields, the more effort we put to get into the SME and medium to large segments of the corporate borrowers, the margins there are still quite healthy and are not going to be as volatile. So we were hoping to compensate for that with a push into those segments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sure. That's very clear. And last question from me on your international strategy, I assume the reason that you're changing your target in terms of CIS, 5% market share in key countries and then looking into India, China. However, your name has been associated recently with some assets outside this area.</p>
          <p>And given that we would expect more assets to come on the market, I was just wondering, should we expect Sberbank's name to be mentioned on these lists of potential interest? And how strong that interest would be? I think nobody has any issue with somebody looking at a new potential acquisition just as &#x2013; to do the due diligence et cetera. But I just want to get a feel, is there a change in your appetite that we should expect going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I haven't heard our name mentioned in the press, certain association with any rumors that would be outside of our broad strategic definition. Maybe you've heard more. But between all of us on this call, we actually know that &#x2013; and I have been constantly mentioning that back from the early 2008 when I joined, that every other week there's an investment bank knocking on our door saying look how good an opportunity has come up.</p>
          <p>So we've long ago established a practice to not mentioning those rumors. The only thing I would say is that our approach has not changed. We're looking at the areas that we've highlighted in our strategy. We &#x2013; some of the examples last year and in 2008 may have been indicating that some of the sellers wanted our name associated with this object of the sale simply to generate more interest or get better prices from the other bidders, and that's not unusual either. So, take all of those rumors with those couple of pinches of salt that I've just mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. No, the name I had in mind was Garanti and I thought there was some sort of official communication on your side, maybe I'm mistaken. Okay, but that's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no. Official communication that I've issued last week and I was the only talking at it from Sberbank on that topic, that's for sure, was no comments and again, that's very much consistent with a lot of comments that we have made on M&amp;A except the ones that had been long discussed like BTA, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from the line of Vadim Kovshov. Please go ahead with your question and announce you company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. This is Vadim Kovshov of Discovery Capital. Would you mind explaining the dynamics behind the sub debt and whether the repricing will happen or not? What are the circumstances that you're considering and what should we be looking for in terms of deciding whether it will or will not happen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I don't think I have anything to add to the comment that I have made about 20 minutes ago. We can go either way, either repaying or reducing the rate &#x2013; reducing the rate will require a law change. There's an initiative brought up by one of the deputies in the Parliament. I'm not in a position to comment on the likelihood of it being adopted or when that may or may not happen. That's probably it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Simon Nellis. Please go ahead and announce the company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Simon Nellis from Citigroup. I'd actually have a follow on question to Cristina's question on M&amp;A. You did mention BTA, can you give us an update on the situation there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the update is very simple. We've mentioned before and it was also mentioned in the press by the other side of the negotiations that we will get back to a bit more specific &#x2013; we've taken a pause and we'll get back to a bit more specific conversations and discussions sometime in the second quarter of 2010. So, if there's any news coming from that we will make further comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I &#x2013; I might have 3 other questions. I think you also mentioned publicly that you're looking at maybe expanding into the consumer finance area in Russia? You're obviously quite down beat on the growth prospects near term but is this still a strategic move that you're looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we're looking at it &#x2013; we're perceiving that product segment in strategic terms. There may have been &#x2013; actually trying to recall what comments could have been made but if anything that would have been pretty much tactical things by our retail guys maybe, but nothing material that's behind that, so....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then just last question. I saw that your branch numbers have gone down by slightly over 700. I was wondering are there further branch reductions planned and how many branches would you kind of see as being the ideal amount longer term for a franchise of your size?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, when you &#x2013; there's definitely no such scale of absolute reduction in our branch network. What there is going on is actually a bit of a restructuring in the &#x2013; within the branch network itself. Some of the offices actually lose the official status of a branch but get a status of an operating office or something or sub-branch or something like that because we're doing a bit more of decentralization.</p>
          <p>In terms of our overall approach to branch network, those branches that are in remote rural areas are no longer that much a drag on our cost base. They are more or less breakeven. So it's not a burning kind of item that we have to deal with. There will be further optimization and some reduction of the branches but that will be driven by 2 parameters. One is the efficiency and the quality of remote channels and the readiness of the client base to operate and get the banking services through those remote channels. We're putting quite a lot of effort there. But also that that will have to be balanced by the simple principle that banking is very often, much more a relationship business than anything else and we will &#x2013; and it will be criminal for us to forgo the advantage of being in every, not only middle or a large city in this country but actually in every city in this country.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; and having the opportunity to speak to our clients face to face. And that &#x2013; we're not going to be compromising either. So it'll be gradual evolutionary change in the branch network going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Just one last question if I may. I noticed on your cash flow that net interest income in the cash flow is actually slightly higher than what you're showing in the P&amp;L. And this is much different than what a lot of your competitors are doing. And I'm surprised that with 12% restructured loans that there's not a bigger difference but actually the cash flow is less. Can you kind of give some more color on how you're restructuring loans and why your cash flow in your income statement might be more similar than, say, some of your competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I would be able to straightaway comment on the arithmetical nuances but we can provide you an answer offline once we actually rationalize that. But I can provide you with some comments on the way we approach restructuring. The litmus test is of any credit type restructuring as opposed to any other type of recovery on the loan, is whether the business model of a borrower after restructuring can operate and can service basic level of interest rate burden as if it was a normal business. Because if it's not, then we would be fooling ourselves and extending a life of a non-sustainable business model for longer and that's not something that is good to do. That bites you much stronger later on.</p>
          <p>So, it's better &#x2013; if you restructure you restructure  and you do it well and it never comes back as a bad loan, or you use other types of recovery. You decompose the business into assets or whatever may be more appropriate or you sell the loan or anything else.</p>
          <p>That is why when I was &#x2013; in my opening remarks, I referred to a particular parameter and was saying the structured corporate loans versus NPLs. The NPLs on the restructured loans that we're showing now is less than 1% of all the restructured loans. So, once we've restructured, 99% of that actually performs. Yes, there may be some part of the interest rate burden shifted for later months or years in the loan tenor, but the main principle is that that business model should carry the base rate of debt servicing throughout these times.</p>
          <p>The extra risk premium that we charge, yes, some of that may be postponed, but we're not really going below the base rate on all the credit restructurings.</p>
          <p>Now, obviously, there's other situations where it's pretty much not only credit restructuring but the business is feeling much, much worse. And you'll be strangling it by charging high rates. When you are front seeing that the recovery rate will be much less than 100% and you actually just need to decompose it into asset pieces and sit on those and protect them from deterioration until such time the market dislocation for those asset is over and you can sell them at a decent price. So, there obviously you don't want to strangle the borrowers or the business with the &#x2013; or the companies that hold those assets with extraordinary interest rate burden when you've already took possession. So, that's the way we approach it there. And the 1% NPLs on the restructured loans is a very respectable testament to the quality of the work that we've put into restructuring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. Would it be fair to say that when you do restructure a loan that the terms that you are giving to the clients are maybe not as generous as some of the competition out there, at least that's what the cash flow seems to suggest, that you're not being as lenient...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always a very individual decision that you take for every particular transaction and there's much more art to that than science. And actually we, as compared to all of the rest of the competition, have a very big advantage. A lot of our credit officers actually have gone to the same school, to the borrowers because we're so much better represented locally. And they can assess the quality parameters of whether this business is actually going to recover and fly again, much better than anyone else. So, what we practice is we use that advantage wisely. We still take financial decisions as they should be taken but we assess the non-financial parameters much better than many other competitors and we, therefore, individualize the solutions.</p>
          <p>And yes, there's probably some generalization to be done from there. But what the experience of the '98 crisis in Russia has shown is that we've, as compared to competition, we've been pretty good at recovery. And most of the &#x2013; our regional business leaders and recovery people have actually stayed with us since those times. And they exactly, being in the position of Sberbank, know the real price and the meaning of taking the right decision or the wrong decision when you're a lender of last resort. How much loyalty you get when you as a lender of last resort actually save as survival business model or how much pains you get from actually making that wrong and struggling to recover years and years after that? So it's individual approach each time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much for that detailed answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Bob Kommers [Deutsche Bank], please go ahead and announce the company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Bob Kommers at Deutsche Bank. I have a few questions. First of all, yes, following on to Simon's question, I was just wondering, you talk about recovery rates and you said you did a good job, was better at doing a good job in the '98 crisis. Could you please indicate what the recovery rate was of Sberbank in the '98 crisis and also what you budget as recovery rates on NPLs, and what you budget on restructured loans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Too early to make those generalizations and outlooks for this time around. In fact, I'd probably challenge you to get a decent answer, business-specific answer on that from any other big bank in the world, probably too early. The recoveries from the crisis like that would probably be longer in the timing schedule than the average for the last 5 crises. That's definitely longer than a couple of 2, 3 years, sometimes 5, 7. So, too early to form any trends, meaningful statistical trends on that.</p>
          <p>Again, equally so, I'm not keeping in my memory the financial result to the level of detail such as recovery rates on bad assets back from '98 crisis. But I'm daily speaking on credit committees and on risk management work and recovery work with actually those regional business heads that have been around in '98, and also the overall general performance of Sberbank financials for the past 10 years are not highlighted to us in general , any material impact from non-recovery in credit terms.</p>
          <p>So, the &#x2013; what is important in terms of the recoveries is not those statistics but then again, how does the managers, the business heads and recovery unit heads that are out there in the field working with it day in, day out and that have been doing it 10 years ago as well is actually how it feels. What is their gut feel or not and how quickly they can recover in what and whether it goes well and where it goes worse and what needs to be done to improve that. So, I'm making my comments based on those impressions as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah, regarding the provisioning that you make, I mean, I think the important factor is probably the collateral value and I was just wondering, I mean, there were recent numbers out suggesting that 70% of the collateral Russian banks is real estate. I just wondered whether that is representative for Sberbank's collateral structure and what's the &#x2013; what do you stress test at your provisioning &#x2013; the impact of provisioning of a swing of say 20 or 30% in real estate prices. So what is the sensitivity of your balance sheet provisions to real estate prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we do have some disclosure on that &#x2013; on note and loans and domestic customers, page 39. I'm not going to be digging into numbers right now calculating the proportions if you allow me. But trust me, there's enough numbers for you to play with. I know we've just released them so you haven't had time, but there's some meat there more than we've been showing before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of collaterals, the thing in Russia is that &#x2013; well, firstly, it's not the time of recovery and the profitability that kills the banks' liquidity. As long as you have the balance sheet stamina to seek the market dislocation out, and then sell the collateral at regular, more normalized prices then you'd be good. And we &#x2013; as far as that parameter's concerned, we're pretty comfortable.</p>
          <p>In terms of the real estate market itself, the way we see it, yes, there's a lot of collateral that have been burdened with debt here in the country. But equally so, there's huge unsatisfied demand for real estate in commercial, retail, the housing real estate. The trouble is that the market pricing has actually run away out of reach of most of the public in the business and the retail. And the pricing will have to be coming down on one side.</p>
          <p>But on another side, the interest rate environment, reducing rates actually pushes it somewhere closer to the levels from where retail mortgage lending may start becoming more effective and stimulating, the end demand for real estate, which can pay for it. So again, whether it will go as far down in the mortgage rates below 10, 11% to see &#x2013; the real impact yet to be seen. But overall, again, in some mid-term perspective, that shortage of physical assets in the real estate will drive the pricing back and further up, and hopefully, the end demand will and the mortgage lending will support that. We're prepared to wait.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for that but two final questions. One is much has been said about shareholder friendliness and &#x2013; by the importers of management option program and potentially the R listing. But there are other things that Sberbank could do and one is a significant increase in the dividend payout, particularly if you are in recover, and most likely your ROE will be higher definitely in 2010 than your asset growth. So what is the &#x2013; what are your thoughts on the dividend policy? Are you planning to significantly increase the payout to, say, 25% or 30% in 2010 or 2011? Or do you really want to sustain the current capital ratios that you have?</p>
          <p>And the other thing on shareholder friendliness is what are your thoughts on the pref shares? I mean, it's a very small program compared to the common shares and it's &#x2013; I think it's &#x2013; it would &#x2013; I mean, improve the &#x2013; yeah, it would simplify the structure of your shares significantly if you would consider doing away with the prefs. Is that anything that Sberbank may consider at some point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dividends. Well, the worst thing that we could probably do is do any sharp, unpredictable moves in the dividend policies. And that's any more than corporate finance textbook supporting that. We are somewhat going to over-capitalize as it stands now. But that's also partially because of the sub-debt. We're going to see what happens with that. If we repay that that will probably bring capital structure to a bit more optimal and efficient. So if that happens, I think, and that actually is my personal view as a shareholder, because I am too, is that it'll be probably wiser for the Sberbank investors to let the dividend, the potential dividend to be reinvested into the growth in the medium term over the next couple of years probably.</p>
          <p>So, I don't think &#x2013; we are not currently thinking about any material changes in our approach to that. You may change a year or two down the road, but we'll see. Pref shares, yeah, the arguments for simplifying the capital structure are pretty appealing. We're actually looking at that and analyzing various ways of doing that. It will be good at some point in time to probably get rid of them, but I don't think it is a particularly burning question for the next month or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And my final question is about the costs. I just wondered, I mean, you've had seven consecutive quarters of, say, I mean, operating costs of about, say, around RUB55 billion, and then in Q4 2009, RUB65 billion, is a 20% increase Q-on-Q. And I just wondered, I mean, whether there were any one-offs in that that were depressing it, maybe a one-off goodwill charge or maybe something else that will not be recurring in 2010?</p>
          <p>And the other question on costs is &#x2013; yeah, it's regarding just cost inflation. I mean, you highlighted that inflation has come down, so which should be positive for the cost inflation your other cost, but at the same time, you've not increased the wages in 2009, and I think there might be a catch-up on that in 2010. There has been a word of an increase of 15% in staff remuneration. So could you comment on that, on the total cost inflation and also whether there were any one-offs in the fourth quarter 2009 that caused that, say, RUB11 billion quarter-on-quarter increase in the costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the quarter-on-quarter, there's a bit of a seasonality in that. In fact, if you look at the page 14 of our presentation, we actually directly mentioned that. We held off a little bit in first two quarters and waited in the third quarter. But in the fourth quarter, we said yeah, let's catch up a little bit on what we've held up on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's recurring &#x2013; that's recurring &#x2013; that's recurring in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say, some of that is compensating for quarter one and two, so the quarterly number itself is not actually recurring at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the average in &#x2013; the average for 2009 is probably still going to be somewhat higher, or rather the average quarterly in 2010 is going to be somewhat higher than 2009. And then again, the good measure to track is keeping the cost/income ratio in the low 40s area. Yes, as I mentioned before, there's some re-shuffling in the structure of pay between categories, types of pay and types of employees and regions that were doing net, net, that are probably &#x2013; will be relatively a benign impact.</p>
          <p>There was some mention publicly that our CEO have made &#x2013; or rather that was the press commenting, quoting his &#x2013; what was it, December monthly <mark type="inaudible" /> or November, I can't remember which month. Well, he said that on those categories where we are underpaying employees in a particular category or particular region, we will be prepared to go as high as 15% high cap to compensate to make sure that they're paid in accordance to market. And also, that the total paycheck cost may go, in nominal terms, as high as into double digits.</p>
          <p>But on doing further detailed analysis, we see probably better balance between overpaid and underpaid people. So that net, net impact may not be actually that high. So, yeah, that's the way the dynamics are hopefully going to be panning out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks a lot. Thanks a lot, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question for today comes from the line of Dmitry Trembovolsky [Goldman Sachs]. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, guys, it's Dmitry Trembovolsky. Can I please &#x2013; just one, ask a follow-up, one follow-up question on the &#x2013; on your provisions and the coverage ratio. You were saying that you were comfortable with 80% to 120% coverage ratio. You are already above this at 125, I guess. So will this be a fair assumption that in the next quarters, we will not see a further increase in the coverage ratio? And rather than that, the coverage will be stable so you will only provide for the new NPLs? Is this a fair assumption or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We hope so. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay, okay. One other thing, you said that &#x2013; yes, I just want to be clear on definitions because there were lots of things about the recoveries write backs, and whether it's positive P&amp;L charges, negative P&amp;L charges. Are you sticking to your, I think, latest guidance that we are not going to see any positive P&amp;L charges this year, and if anything, the cost of risk can come down pretty significantly but still will be a significant negative?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty much so. I'd just say that look there may be some positive dynamics and then positive charges to the provision line, but then the materiality of those, and not only to the side of the provisions that are created on the balance sheet but actually to the overall P&amp;L, is probably going to be very limited. It's just too early. Recoveries take longer than one year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's like &#x2013; that's everywhere, in every country. I don't think it'll be reasonable for us to expect anything sooner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood, but because it's &#x2013; just because it's a quite sensitive topic, okay. For example, fourth quarter 2010, can we see a zero cost-of-risk charge and a P&amp;L charge, or that's something that you would rule out as...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well &#x2013; look, look, look, look, this becomes too specific nine months ahead of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...because we hopefully are going to be growing the loan book. And that carries new provisioning creation with it at whatever level, 1% or whatever, but you're still lending out. So, we'll see. And again the pace of recoveries are specific to each particular deal, so you cannot forecast that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay, clear. And the last thing is coming back to margins just for the time being. So you &#x2013; on the Russian accounting standards where you actually reported, you lost &#x2013; in the first two months, you lost around 60 bps comparing to October, November of 2009. Just to make sure, you sort of are still &#x2013; you still seem to be quite adamant in your guidance of 50 to 100 bps, which pretty much &#x2013; if we take the average, which pretty much implies that you're going to come back to the margins we have seen in 2008. I'm now looking at the page in your presentation, so from 7.8 to 7.9. So despite the fact that you've already lost around 60 bps, you still feel very strong about your guidance, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is, and I probably ask you for the time being not to go into statistic fiscal generalizations and trending out on the basis of just two months. We ought to be looking at a bigger number of months before we generalize the trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, clear. [Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further questions registered. I'll hand the conference back to you for any closing comments. Dmitry, I'll hand the conference back to you for any closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much for being with us. We are very proud that we still have so many investors on the line. And we promise you to keep doing the best to maximize shareholder value. Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen, very good questions and all the best of luck to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation today. This concludes today's conference. You may now disconnect your lines. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>