<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1513311" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2483</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Comptroller &amp; Manager-Financial Planning">Raul Jacob</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Carlos De Alba</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch SA CVTM">Felipe Hirai</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays CTVM SA">Leonardo Correa</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Corretora de Valores SA">Leandro Cappa</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Casa de Bolsa Credit Suisse Mexico SA de CV">Santiago Perez Teuffer</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Grupo Burs&#xE1;til Mexicano">Juan Jos&#xE9; L&#xF3;pez Q.</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="AIG Asset Management (US) LLC">Jim Drury</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Mandeep Singh X. Manihani</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Jamie Nicholson-Leener</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome to Southern Copper Third Quarter and Nine Months 2012 Results Conference Call. With us today, we have Southern Copper Corporation's Mr. Raul Jacob, CFO of the Peruvian Operations and Investor Relations of Southern Copper, who will discuss the results of the company for the third quarter and nine months 2012 as well as any questions that you may have.</p>
          <p>The information discussed on today's call may include forward-looking statements regarding the company's results and prospects, which are subject to risks and uncertainties. Actual results may differ materially and the company cautions to not place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements. Southern Copper Corporation undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. All results are expressed in full U.S. GAAP.</p>
          <p>You may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Richard, and good afternoon to everyone, and welcome to Southern Copper's third quarter 2012 earnings conference call. In today's conference call, we will begin with an update of our view on the metal markets. We will then talk about Southern Copper's key results related to production, sales, operating cost, financial results, expansion projects, and capital spending program. After that, we will open the session for questions.</p>
          <p>Focusing on metal markets and prices, during the third quarter of this year, metal markets continue to be driven by negative macroeconomic events that affected consumer expectations. The most important ones being Europe's debt crisis and the possibility of a slowdown of the Chinese economy. 2012 is also a transition year with changes in the administration or elections in favorable key economies as it is the case of China and the United States.</p>
          <p>Even though we believe copper fundamentals are sound, the name has been repeatedly affected by the macroeconomic outlook for Europe, China and the economic slowdown that characterize elections and administration changes.</p>
          <p>At present, we perceive the difference in the situations of the Asian markets and the developed markets. In China, analysts point to a growing copper demand of approximately 6% for this year, which should give support to the copper market in the next few months particularly if a stimulus program is launched for the Chinese economy.</p>
          <p>In the United States demand appears to be stronger as consumer confidence has increased and the economy is recuperating. However, European demand is decreasing and with no signs of recovery in the short-term. Analysts currently estimate that there will be a total refined copper demand growth of 2.5% for 2012.</p>
          <p>On the supply side, CRU is estimating a production increase of 2.4% for the year due to lower than expected labor and risk and ore grade declines. Even though this combination of weak demand with better than expected supply is giving a break to the copper market tightness, we believe copper fundamentals are strong as shown by copper inventory reductions.</p>
          <p>Over the past 12 months, copper inventories in public warehouses have decreased 34.4%, which we believe demonstrates solid market fundamentals. We think that several structural factors are still affecting copper supply, which will very likely result in weak growth in the coming years.</p>
          <p>However, Southern Copper believes it is positioned to take advantage of this unsettled situation through our aggressive investment program of organic growth.</p>
          <p>Focusing on our production and starting with copper, in the third quarter of 2012, copper mine production increased by 3% to 160,379 tons. This compares with 155,689 tons in the third quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>This increase was the result of higher production at the Cuajone, La Caridad and Buenavista mines, which increased production by 14%, 2%, and 3% respectively as a result of higher ore grades and recoveries.</p>
          <p>Molybdenum production decreased by 6.8% in the third quarter of 2012 from the third quarter of 2011 due to lower production at the Toquepala mine, partially offset by higher production at La Caridad and Cuajone due to higher grade and recovery.</p>
          <p>Silver mine production increased by 2.3% in the past quarter when compared to the same period of last year, principally as a result of higher production at our Cuajone, Buenavista and La Caridad mines. Total production was affected by a lower production at IMMSA that holds a 45% share in our silver production. And Toquepala, which decreased also production by 15%. Refined production increased by 10% in the third quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Zinc production increased by 1.1% in the third quarter mainly as a result of higher grades and recoveries, and gradual production recovery at the Santa Eulalia mine, but the flooding problems of prior years are being resolved.</p>
          <p>Going into our financial results, for the third quarter of 2012, sales were $1.5 billion, 11% lower than the $1.7 billion of the third quarter of that year due to lower prices in all main metals produced by SCC and lower volume in sales of molybdenum, which decreased 6.5%; zinc which decreased 7%. The decrease in sales was &#x2013; in sales value was partially offset by a 14% increase in silver sales volume.</p>
          <p>The company as part of a cost in this past quarter, the company has recorded a charge to cost of $316 million. This was part of Delaware Court's judgment by which the company received $2.1 billion on the derivative lawsuit related to Minera Mexico transaction dating back to 2005. However, in the same decision the judge awards, as I mentioned $316 million in compensation payable by the company to attorneys that initiated the litigation.</p>
          <p>This charge has been reported as part of our statement of earnings. Beside this charge, we had some moderate cost changes. We have a higher energy cost, labor cost and third party copper cost, exchange rate depreciation and other operating materials increases that were partially offset by lower diesel and fuel costs, workers' participation and inventory consumption.</p>
          <p>Overall, our cost increased from $784 million in the second quarter of this year to $1.1 billion in the third quarter of 2012, this including the mentioned legal fees.</p>
          <p>The EBITDA in the nine months before non-recurrent expenses was $2.9 billion, 57.4% of margins and $849 million or 55% margin for the third quarter of 2012. Including the court ordered legal fees, our EBITDA for the nine months was $2.6 billion, 51.1% margin and $532 million or 34.3% margin for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Operating cash cost per pound of copper before by-product credits was $1.78 per pound in the third quarter of 2012. This compares with the $1.71 per pound in the second quarter of 2012. The $0.07 per pound increase in operating cash cost is the result of the already mentioned cost increments as we indicated.</p>
          <p>Southern Copper operating cash cost including the benefit of by-product credits was $0.82 per pound in the third quarter of this year. Regarding by-products, we had a total credit of $337 million or $0.96 per pound in the third quarter of 2012. These figures compare with the credit of $388 million or $1.11 per pound in the second quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>The lower by-product credit results from our reduction in our main by-product prices, molybdenum and zinc particularly, is partially offset by better silver and gold prices and higher sales volumes of silver that increased 2.7% less the increase of 10.6% when compared to the second quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Net income in the third quarter before extraordinary and non-recurrent expenses was $534 million or 34.4% of sales. Including the payment of the court order fees, our net income for the third quarter of 2012 was $217.9 million or 14% of sales.</p>
          <p>Focusing on the company expansion and capital projects regarding the Buenavista operation, the Quebalix project has an overall progress of 98.9%. In October of this year, the company started the final testing as part of the project commissioning and expects to start operations by November of 2012.</p>
          <p>Through September 30, 2012, we have invested $71 million of a total budget cost of $75 million. This investment consists of a crushing, conveying and spreading system that improves the SXEW copper production by increasing recovery and reducing the required time to extract copper from mineral.</p>
          <p>The SXEW III Project, also at the Buenavista mine is moving forward. Plant equipment from Tia Maria will allow us to increase the annual plant capacity from 88,000 tons to 120,000 tons. Overall progress of the project at the end of September is 32.8%. The new plant should begin operating in the first half of 2014 and has a total budget cost of $444 million. Through September 30 of this year, the Company has spent $126.3 million of that budget.</p>
          <p>The construction of a molybdenum plant for the current concentrator is at 66% of progress and through September 30 of this year, the Company has spent $9.2 million of the $38.2 million total budget cost. The project is expected to begin operations in the first quarter of 2013. And it is expected to produce annually 2,000 tons of molybdenum contained in concentrate.</p>
          <p>The Buenavista mining expansion project includes mine equipment acquisition and a new concentrator with an estimated annual production capacity of 188,000 tons of copper and an additional 2,600 tons of molybdenum.</p>
          <p>This project has a capital budget of $1.4 billion and it is expected to begin operations by the first half of 2015. Regarding mine equipment, through September 30 of this year, we have received 2 of the 5 shovels, 27 of the 41 trucks and the 5 drills acquired.</p>
          <p>Basic engineering for the new concentrator is complete and detailed engineering and equipment acquisition are moving forward as scheduled. The bidding process for the steel structure and earthmoving equipment was conducted. Overall progress of the project is 27.7% at the end of September.</p>
          <p>For the Angangueo project, the basic and detailed engineering are moving forward as to schedule to develop these underground polymetallic deposit in Michoacan in Mexico. With an estimated investment of $131 million, Angangueo will have potential annual production of 10,400 tons of copper, 3 million ounces of silver, 9,700 tons of zinc, and 3,900 tons of lead. The project is scheduled to begin production in the first half of 2015.</p>
          <p>The Toquepala projects, through September 30 of this year, we have spent $220 million on them. These expenditures include a new crusher and a conveyor belt system to replace rail hauling and other cost, which will allow for future savings.</p>
          <p>In the case of the Cuajone projects, as of September of the year, the company has spent $122.2 million on two projects related to this unit's production plans: the Variable Cut-off Ore Grade project and the High Pressure Grinding Rolls project.</p>
          <p>Current production is showing the initial benefits of both projects, which will be at full capacity by the third quarter of 2013, adding an estimated average of 22,000 tons of additional capper and 700 tons of molybdenum to Cuajone's annual production.</p>
          <p>For Tia Maria, we continue to work on a new environmental impact assessment study that will address recent government guidance on these studies in order to reach an agreement that is mutually satisfactory to all parties.</p>
          <p>For the case of the Tantahuatay investment, in these mines where the company holds a 44.2% interest. In the nine months of 2012, we have recognized a $38.2 million in earnings for our share of the net income of the mine. At this point, we're expecting to spend approximately $1 billion in capital expenses in 2012.</p>
          <p>Regarding the recent dividend announcement, in order to determine the appropriate quarterly dividend, it is the company's policy to review at each board meeting the capital investment plans, available cash resources and expected future cash flow generation from operations.</p>
          <p>In this quarter, as a way to maintain a more efficient capital structure, our Board of Directors have decided to declare a dividend that consists of payment of approximately 100% of our third quarter 2012 non-adjusted net income and the full $2.1 billion received from AMC in satisfaction of the Delaware Court decision.</p>
          <p>Therefore, the board authorized a cash dividend of $2.75 per share payable on November 21, 2012 to shareholders of record at the close of business on November 8, 2012. With this in mind, ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much for joining us and we will like to open up the forum for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question-and-answer session <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Carlos De Alba from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Raul, the first question that I have is regarding CapEx and clearly the CapEx ramp-up. I see that the company continues to do to make good progress on the growth project. However, it seems that the CapEx guidance declined from $1.5 billion for the year to $1 billion. And we do see a little bit of a slowdown in your CapEx deployment. Can you talk a little bit about this what were you expecting and why the delays and what is, if you have any guidance for 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Carlos. Thank you for your question. Well, yes, two factors here. In some cases we have &#x2013; we're seeing some delay in equipment deliveries that was not &#x2013; were not expected to happen that is affecting a little bit our census on CapEx. On the other hand, in some cases, we're well on track in terms where we want to go or where we want to be in terms of the execution of the project, but the terms of payment have changed a little bit and are much more favorable at this point for the company and that's why we haven't spend as much as we believe we were going to spend at the beginning of the year. At this point, we understand that we are going to spend, as I said, about $1 billion in 2012 for capital expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Felipe Hirai from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, everyone. So, I have two questions. The first one is related to your sales in the third quarter. We saw that there was a slight decline in this quarter, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (20:00) if there was any particular reason for this issue. And if you could give us some guidance of what you expect to keep in the production for next year if there was any change on that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, mainly our sales decreased as a result of lower prices. The prices for the year, as we know, have been decreasing when you compare them to last year. We compare this quarter with the third quarter of 2011, copper is at 14.2% lower, molybdenum 19.2% lower; zinc is 14.9% lower; silver is 22.5% lower and gold 2.7% under what we expect &#x2013; what we had last year.</p>
          <p>Regarding sales, the company has managed to maintain its copper sales as well as &#x2013; but we have some decreases in molybdenum and zinc sales that were partially offset by 14% in round numbers in our silver sales.</p>
          <p>Now, regarding the forecast for production for next year, we're still in the process of reviewing our plans, but we are expecting to be at the better level next year. This year as I've been mentioning, that we are going to fulfill our forecast of 640,000 tons that we indicated at the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>In that forecast, about 2.5% of the production will come from third parties copper, the rest will be our own copper. That number has improved from where we were at the beginning of the year. For next year, we're expecting a little bit better production that what we have forecast for 2012.</p>
          <p>Richard, can we go ahead with the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question on line comes from Leonardo Correa. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon everyone thank you. My first question is regarding the Quebalix project. Raul, as you mentioned, the project is close to conclusion, close to start up. I just wanted to understand exactly if you can quantify maybe a bit more the overall impact on costs and production rates? That would be very helpful.</p>
          <p>And the second question is a bit more broad with &#x2013; just trying to get your thoughts on the copper price outlook that potential yield is within your budget. Considering that 2013 will be a year of a bit more of a supply turn in this market, are you expecting copper prices to be higher year-over-year? So just to get your latest thoughts on where copper prices are higher. Thank you very much, Raul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hello, Leonardo. How are you? Well, the Quebalix, it's a facility that is related to SXEW production. Quebalix basically process the mineral that is &#x2013; then deposit on the plants that the company use for processing the cable for producing the SXEW copper.</p>
          <p>If you don't have a Quebalix, to put it simply, you will probably separate less copper on the mineral that you deposit on the plants and you will not have the same recovery rate. In other words, you recuperate more copper and in less time with Quebalix.</p>
          <p>The effect of this is already embedded in our cost. Since we already have two Quebalix and this one is going to be the third one that the company will operate in Mexico at the Buenavista operation, as part of the SXEW project, we will recuperate the benefits of the Quebalix through the higher production and low cost that the SXEW plant in Buenavista has.</p>
          <p>And your second question at least, Leonardo on the copper price, right. Copper, well basically, we're following the supply and demand of copper. We believe that structurally speaking, the supply is limit. We're seeing a little bit more than what we expect at the beginning of the year, however, we also believe that on the demand side, the structure of the world demand for copper has changed. And as soon as we see a more stronger recovery from the emerging economy, we will see a much stronger demand for copper that will impact in the price.</p>
          <p>At this point, we don't have a guidance on price for next year, but we believe that copper will maintain its characteristic of being the basic metal with the best fundamentals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Leandro Cappa from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much. So can you give us an update on the Tia Maria in the licensing process? And also, we are seeing some global mining companies reviewing its projects, its budgets and postponing most projects. Do you believe you can review your projects and postpone some of the other big projects in light of the macro conditions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me address the Tia Maria concern. Basically, we're working on our environmental impact assessment. We expect to finish it through the fourth quarter. On this impact assessment, the company is focusing on one of the alternative that we have in the past, which we indicated is using desalinated or seawater for the process.</p>
          <p>Not taking any water from other sources or land sources to say it so. And regarding postponing projects the company has no intention of doing that. Since we have a very competitive cost position; we usually review our capital budgets at the time of the first board of the year. That's going to be in January of next year. At this point, we are not considering postponing any project and I don't think that we will do that since these projects are in general terms very competitive cost wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Santiago Perez-Teuffer from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Raul, how are you and thanks for your time. This is Santiago Perez-Teuffer. My first question is regarding corporate structure. Raul, as I recall, the day the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:55) came out SCCO was announcing a bond issuance. Do you think there's a chance that this could repeat or do you think we could be seeing in the midterm? And my second question is, can you give us a little more color on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:08) production and an update on this project's permit and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:13) if it's been approved and everything? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the bond issue, the company is basically analyzing if we are going to proceed with these initiatives. At this point, we have no decision. We have no final decision on this matter. We are still looking into it.</p>
          <p>Regarding Toquepala, we have a lower ore grade in the Toquepala operation this year. Our mining plants long term are basically very stable at this point in terms of ore grade and the such. However, we now and then have kind of rough spot to say so where we have a lower ore grade for a period. That's the case this year with the Toquepala operation and that is affecting the production of this unit.</p>
          <p>Regarding the environmental impact assessment for Toquepala, we're still tending the final meeting for the approval of this investment and we're working with the national as well as the regional authorities and committees to explain what the project is about and how is this going to benefit the regions where we operate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Juan Jos&#xE9; Lopez from GBM. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Raul. Good morning, thanks for a great conference call. I had some questions. First one will be regarding the adjustment payment you received from Grupo Mexico. We look at the balance sheet and look and observe that you are equity of what and you made that a provision of receivable for the payment.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, you didn't recognize that payment, but to combine the dividend payment to the income statement. I just want to help you or maybe if you could tell me in the next quarter when you actually reduce the cash flow, the inflow and the output for the dividend, are you recognizing anything beyond that especially for tax purposes?</p>
          <p>And the second question would be regarding molybdenum production, which was down quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year. Are you retracting your guidance or you could give us an update on one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you very much Juan Jos&#xE9; for your questions. Regarding the $2.1 billion payment that AMC to Southern Copper. After looking into this matter with our accountants and our auditors, the company register it as part of a pay-in capital in the capital or equity part of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>We're not &#x2013; according with the U.S. GAAP, we are not having these some P&amp;L elements. So we're not having these as part of our sales or revenues in other sales or other income, et cetera. And in the case of the legal fees that we paid related to this lawsuit judgment, basically it is an expense, financially speaking and we already incorporated it to our P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>And on the case of molybdenum production, we have seen a decrease in the Toquepala production. It's related to the ore grade temporary reduction that I mentioned. At this point, we are not changing our guidance for molybdenum production for the year since a significant portion of the production lost by Toquepala reduction has been carried by the other operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Carlos De Alba from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Raul I'm back. Do you have any more specific guidance for CapEx in 2013 and volume growth of productions on copper in the next few years in the La Caridad and Buenavista, a more detailed guidance? So, I wonder if you have any updates on that and also, can you comment about the well, do you have any updates on that? And also can you comment about the Pilares project. It's not listed in your press release, earnings release, and I wonder if there is any update on that one. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me start by the CapEx. For 2013, our current estimate is about $1.9 billion; for 2014, $2.1 billion; for 2015, $1.3 billion; and for 2016, about $600 million. Regarding the copper production, as I mentioned, we are at 640,000 tons for this year 2012. For next year, we have a forecast that is under review of about 670,000 tons and that's depending on how we proceed with our projects will escalate to over 1 million pounds in the next four years. We will be more specific on this, Carlos, at the next quarter's call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much Raul. And what about Pilares?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pilares, in the case of Pilares, basically the company is still working on this project. We have some talks with some local communities regarding some of the issues related to the project. And that's why we're not reporting it as part of our current pipeline. Once we solve these matters, we will incorporate it into our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jim Drury from AIG. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Raul. Thanks for taking the question. Just a follow-up at this point. Most of my questions have been answered. But I guess in response to the question from CS about financing plan, you said it's still under evaluation. I was wondering if that's something that's also has to be discussed at a board meeting or could that happen any time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We have &#x2013; this has been reviewed at our board and we have some guidance on what to do on this matter. However, we don't have a final decision on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Thank you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mandeep Singh from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Raul. Congratulations on the results. Thanks for taking my question. My question is related to Toquepala project. I just wanted to get an update on where the project is considering there was very limited increment in terms of the amount spent on the project in the last quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Mandeep thank you for your question. In Toquepala, we have at this point two projects, one is the expansion project that is in which we are in talks with the local communities the regional government for having the final all ins and we expect to have this sometime between the fourth quarter of this year and the next quarter of the first quarter of 2013. That project will increase our milling capacity from 60,000 tons to 120,000 tons of copper or mineral mill per day.</p>
          <p>And in terms of copper that will increase our production by about 100,000 tons of copper and 3.1000 tons of molybdenum. That's on the expansion project. On that as you mentioned, we have not spend as much as we expect at this point. In the case of the second project, we have a technological improvement project in Toquepala.</p>
          <p>This project consists in two major things, a new crusher that is an in-feed crusher that process the mineral that goes out of the mine and sends and will send it through a conveyor belt to our concentrator. This project aims to produce savings at our current process. It will replace our rail haulage by conveyor belt haulage of the mineral to our concentrator.</p>
          <p>We are moving forward with this project and it's basically at a good speed and in line with its budget as well as its timetable. However, on the expansion for Toquepala, we're still requiring the final goal, which is the approval of the environmental impact assessment in order to go ahead with the project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Jamie Nicholson from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for the call. I just have a quick clarifying question about the legal fees, which show up on your balance sheet as accrued legal expenses. And I'm just wondering what is the timing when you expect to be paying that out in cash and do you expect to pay it over time or in one lump sum? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Jamie, thank you for your question, because that allows us to clarify this matter. We already received the $2.1 billion from AMC and we paid already on October 9 the legal fees for $316 million. However, at the time of &#x2013; as of September 30, we have to record this as a receivable as well as a legal fee or a payable in the case of the legal fees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Ignacio Ochoa (41:13) from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. As a follow-up on Carlos' question, can you give us more color on how the terms of payments for certain products has improved? And does this mean that any specific project CapEx have decreased?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, couldn't copy you well. Could you repeat your question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. As a follow up on Carlos' question, can you give a more color on how the terms of payments for certain products have improved? Does this mean that any specific project CapEx has decreased?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Capital expenditures or capital prices, to say so, having the decrease and that is not the reason for our lower capital expense. What I meant is that once you have your budget down, you go back to your vendors of equipment and start negotiating for terms of payment. And in several cases, we have improved the budget that we have in order &#x2013; considering certain payments at certain number of months. That's a part of the benefit that we have for spending less capital in 2012. However, that does not mean that we have lower prices for capital goods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Perfect, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Dan Richmond (43:11) who's a private investor. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you for taking my question. My question relates to your provision for income taxes. How much of your income tax expense for the third quarter relates to the Delaware court settlement net of the attorneys' fees and how much of that is current and how much of that is deferred as a deferred inter-company transaction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you for your question <mark type="ph" /> Mr. Richmond (43:30). This is according with our following U.S. GAAP, our accountants has indicated that we need to record the revenues of the Delaware, the AMC compensation as paying capital. As such, we don't have to consider a tax on that until the time where you sell the stock to a third party and that has no specific date in the case of the revenues. In the case of legal fees, by the same token, they're &#x2013; we're not recording any tax credibility related to them since they are part of the same transaction.</p>
          <p>So, at this point, we have no tax reflection in our financials of these two parts of the Delaware related transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from Juan Jos&#xE9; L&#xF3;pez from GBM. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's me again. I have another question. It is related to your idle refinery. We see a decline in production of smelting and refining copper. We know that by the news that they shut down the idle refinery during the September. Is it ready now? Is it working at full capacity? Which date?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the first days of October, actually what &#x2013; we do bi-annual maintenance on the smelter. The smelter produces the input that the refinery processes. So, each two years, we do our major maintenance of our smelter. You have to shut it down for almost a month. We had these maintenances skill for August.</p>
          <p>However, we managed to postpone it to September? In September, we started the maintenance of the Ilo smelter and we stopped the production of copper and also in regard of the seat of the refinery. That maintenance ended at the beginning of October.</p>
          <p>Currently, both facilities are working in full capacity and we have made at the same time the smelter maintenance certain improvements in the process, the smelting process that the company has in Ilo. So, we're expecting to have a much more efficient smelter for the next 24 months until the next major smelter maintenance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much Richard, and well with this, we conclude our conference call for Southern Copper's third quarter results. We certainly appreciate your participation and we expect to have you back with us when we report our fourth quarter results of 2012. Thank you very much and have a nice day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen. This concludes today's conference. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>