<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1494240" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2483</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Comptroller &amp; Manager-Financial Planning">Raul Jacob</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Carlos De Alba</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial &amp; Administrative Officer">Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz Quintanilla</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Oscar Gonz&#xE1;lez Rocha</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch SA CVTM">Felipe Hirai</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Corretora de Valores SA">Leandro Cappa</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays CTVM SA">Leonardo Correa</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Mandeep Singh X. Manihani</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="BB&amp;T Capital Markets">Garrett S. Nelson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Renaissance Capital Ltd.">Rene M. Kleyweg</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse">Luciano Coster</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Casa de Bolsa Credit Suisse Mexico SA de CV">Santiago Perez Teuffer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to Southern Copper Corporation Second Quarter and First Six Months 2012 Results Conference Call. With us this morning we have Southern Copper Corporation's Mr. Raul Jacob, CFO of Peruvian Operations and Investor Relations of Southern Copper, who will discuss the results of the company for the second quarter and the first six months of 2012 as well as answer any questions that you might have.</p>
          <p>The information discussed on today's call may include forward-looking statements regarding the company's results and prospects that are subject to risks and uncertainties. Actual results may differ materially and the company cautions do not place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements. Southern Copper Corporation undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. All results are expressed in full U.S. GAAP.</p>
          <p>Now I will pass the call onto Mr. Raul Jacob. Please go ahead, sir</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Michelle, and good morning to everyone, and welcome to Southern Copper's Second Quarter Earnings Conference Call. Participating in today's conference are Mr. Oscar Gonzalez Rocha, Southern Copper's CEO and Mr. Daniel Muniz, Grupo Mexico's CFO.</p>
          <p>On today's conference call we will begin with an update of our view in the metal markets. We will then talk about Southern Copper's key results related to production, sales, operating costs, financial results, expansion projects, and capital spending program. After that we will open the session for questions.</p>
          <p>Focusing on the metal markets and prices of the metals that Southern Copper produce, during the first half of 2012 metal markets continued to be driven by negative macro economic events that affected consumer expectations the most important ones being Europe's debt crisis particularly the problems in Spain and Italy and the possibility of a slow down of the Chinese economy. Even though we believe copper fundamentals are sound for 2012, demand has been repeatedly negatively influenced by the macro outlook for Europe and China.</p>
          <p>At present we perceive a difference in the situations of the Asian markets and the developed markets. In China, several sources point to a growth in demand of approximately 7% to 8% for this year. And that's for copper, which should give support to the market of copper in the next few months. In the United States and Europe although demand is weak, inventories are extremely tight and we see them increasing to more normal levels over the next 12 months particularly in the United States.</p>
          <p>Demand from emerging economics are also growing and this is somewhat offsetting the weaker consumption in the European and the United States markets. CRU currently estimates that there will be a total refined copper demand growth of 3.5% for 2012. If we consider global copper demand of about 19.3 million tons per year, this will represent approximately 675,000 tons of additional refined copper demand.</p>
          <p>On the supply side, production has under performed badly in 2012 due to labor unrest, power shortages, weather conditions and ore grade declines. All of these events are still continuing constraining supply and maintaining a tightness in the copper market. Currently, CRU estimates a supply growth of less than 0.5% &#x2013; less than 1% for the year 2012.</p>
          <p>Focusing on the company production, in the second quarter of 2012, copper mine production increased by 10% to 160,595 tons, which compared to 146,240 tons in the second quarter of 2011. This increase was the result of higher production at our Cuajone operation that increased its production by 31% compared to last year, La Caridad plus 13%, and Buenavista plus 5%. All of them had better ore grades and recoveries in this past quarter.</p>
          <p>Regarding molybdenum production, it increased by 4% in the second quarter of 2012 when compared to the same period of last year. Again, Cuajone production was 43% higher, La Caridad 10% higher, and this was mainly the result of higher grade and recoveries.</p>
          <p>Regarding silver, silver mine production increased by 10% in the second quarter, principally as a result of higher production at our Cuajone and Buenavista operations, as well as La Caridad. Refined silver increased by 9% to 3.5 million ounces, and that figure compares to 3.2 million ounces in the second quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Focusing on our financial results, for the second quarter of this year sales were $1.7 billion, 8% lower than the $1.8 billion we had in the second quarter of 2011. As a result of improved operating performance, we were able to offset some of the effect of lower metal prices in the second quarter of 2012 vis-&#xE0;-vis the second quarter of 2011, with increases in sales volume.</p>
          <p>Copper sales volume increased by 7%, silver by 25%, molybdenum by 2% and zinc remained equal. These increments in volumes sold partially offset the lower prices for copper. For instance, copper prices decreased by 14%, molybdenum prices by 17%, silver by 23% and zinc by 15% in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Going to our operating cost, our total operating cost and expenses have decreased from $833 million in the first quarter of this year of 2012 to $784 million in the second quarter of this year, a reduction of $49 million, or 6% in operating cost. Lower energy costs, lower workers' participation and lower inventory consumption were the main reasons for these cost reductions and they were partially offset by the cost of third-party copper and other cost variances. The EBITDA for the second quarter was $972 million, with a margin of 58.6%.</p>
          <p>Our operating cash cost per pound of copper, before byproduct credits, was $1.71 per pound in the second quarter of 2012. This compares with $1.82 per pound in the first quarter. The $0.11 per pound decrease in operating cash cost results from the already mentioned cost savings.</p>
          <p>Southern Copper operating cash cost, including the benefit of byproduct credits, was $0.59 per pound. Regarding byproducts, we had a total credit of $388 million or $1.11 per pound in the second quarter of this year. These figures compare with a credit of $424 million or $1.30 per pound in the first quarter of 2012. The lower byproduct credit results from a reduction in byproduct prices, partially offset by higher sales volume in molybdenum and silver, when compared to the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Net income attributable to SCC holders in the second quarter of 2012 was $563.5 million or diluted earnings per share of $0.66. For the year 2012, our Board of Directors approved a $1.5 billion capital expenditure program, which is being used for our projects in Mexico and Peru, as well as for maintenance and replacement capital.</p>
          <p>The projects for Buenavista are composed by a Quebalix project, a molybdenum plant and a new SXEW plant and an expansion of our Buenavista mining &#x2013; conventional mining facility. The Quebalix project overall progress is 98% and this facility will begin operating in September of this year. Through June 30, 2012, we have invested $71 million of the $77 million budget. This investment consists of a crushing, conveying and spreading system that includes the SXEW copper production by increasing recovery and reducing the required time to extract copper from mineral.</p>
          <p>In the case of the molybdenum plant, the construction of the plant is at a level of 48% of progress. The project has a budget of $38 million and it's expected to begin operations in the first quarter of 2013. It will produce two <mark type="audio gap" /> (10:27)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this is the conference operator. Today's conference is having a few technical difficulties. We will commence shortly. Thank you for your patience. <mark type="audio gap" /> (11:40)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Raul, you're on the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Ladies and gentlemen, my apologies for this interruption. We are experiencing some technical problems at the carrier of the conference call.</p>
          <p>Now, let me recap starting by expansion on capital projects. As I said, the Board of Directors approved a $1.5 billion capital expenditure program 2012, which are being used for our projects in Mexico and Peru, as well as for maintenance and replacement capital.</p>
          <p>Regarding the Buenavista projects, the Quebalix project's overall progress is 98% and this facility will begin operating in September of this year. Through June 30, we have invested $71 million of the $77 million budget. This investment consists of a crushing, conveying and spreading system that improves SXEW copper production by increasing recovery and reducing the required time to extract copper from mineral.</p>
          <p>The construction of our molybdenum plant for the current concentrator in Buenavista is at 48% of progress. The project has a budget of $38 million and is expected to begin operations in the first quarter of 2013. It will produce 2,000 tons of molybdenum contained in concentrate.</p>
          <p>The SXEW III plant, also at the Buenavista mine, is moving forward. Plant equipment from Tia Maria will allow us to increase the annual plant capacity from 88,000 tons to 120,000 tons. Basic engineering was modified by the supplier to include the construction of an additional conveyor line. Overall progress of the project at the end of June is 31%. The new plant should begin operating in the first half of 2014, and has a total budget cost of $444 million.</p>
          <p>The Buenavista mining expansion project includes mine equipment acquisition and a new concentrator with an estimated annual production capacity of 188,000 tons of copper, and 2,600 tons of molybdenum. This project has a capital budget of $1.4 billion and it is expected to begin operation by the first half of 2015.</p>
          <p>Regarding mine equipment, through June 30 of this year, we have committed $307 million in purchase orders for the acquisition of five shovels, 41 trucks, drills and other mine equipment. Basic engineering for the new concentrator is complete. Detailed engineering and equipment acquisition are moving forward as scheduled. The bidding process for the steel structure and earthmoving equipment was conducted. Overall progress of the project at June 30 is 22%.</p>
          <p>The Angangueo project, which is a zinc polymetalic deposit in Michoacan in Mexico, is moving forward as scheduled to develop this underground mine. It has an estimated investment of $131 million. And Angangueo will have the potential annual production of 10,400 tons of copper, 9,700 tons of zinc and 3,900 tons of lead. The project is scheduled to begin production in the first half of 2015.</p>
          <p>Through June 30, we have spent $212 million in the Toquepala projects that the company is undertaking. These expenditures include a new crusher and a conveyer-belt system to replace rail hauling and other costs, which will allow for future savings. Subject to obtaining the appropriate permits, the Toquepala expansion is scheduled to start production in the first quarter of 2014. This project will increase annual production by 100,000 tons of copper and 3,100 tons of molybdenum.</p>
          <p>For Cuajone, as of June 30, 2012, the company has spent $113 million on two projects related to this unit &#x2013; the Variable Cut Ore Grade project and the High Pressure Grinding Rolls project. Current production is showing the initial benefits of the variable cut project, which will be at full capacity, with the high pressure grinding rolls, by the third quarter of 2013. These two projects together should add an average of 22,000 tons of copper contained and 700 tons of molybdenum to Cuajone's annual production.</p>
          <p>Regarding the Tia Maria project, we continue to work on a new environmental impact assessment that will address recent government guidance on these studies in order to reach an agreement that is fair and mutually satisfactory to all parties.</p>
          <p>For the Tantahuatay investment that the company has as a joint venture with Buenaventura, we started production in this project in August of 2011 and in the first months of this year 2012, the mine has produced 66,700 ounces of gold and 418,000 (sic) [418,600] (16:50) ounces of silver. In the six months of the year 2012, we have recognized $24.7 million in earnings for our share of the net income of this mine. Southern Copper's share in this investment is 44.2%.</p>
          <p>Regarding dividends, as you know, it is the company policy to review at each board meeting the capital investment plan, cash resources and expected future cash flow generation from operations in order to determine the appropriate quarterly dividend. Accordingly, as disclosed to the market on July 26, the Board of Directors authorized a cash dividend of $0.24 per share of common stock payable on August 28, to shareholders of record at the close of business on August 15.</p>
          <p>So, with this in mind, ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much for joining us and we would like to open up the forum for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from Carlos de Alba from Morgan Stanley. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Raul, I would like to ask you three questions. The first one is, on the sustainability of the lower costs that we saw in the second quarter, and clearly a very good performance that underpinned the results, but you mentioned reduced workers' participation and reduced energy costs as the main pillars of this decline, can you comment a little bit about what you are seeing in the third quarter? And to what extent these reductions are sustainable?</p>
          <p>And the second question is regarding the dividend policy. We have seen dividends being part share buybacks, part cash, and an increase or a full cash dividend of around $0.50-something per share, and now a decline to around $0.25, $0.24 per share, could you comment what is the company's policy? And what can we expect going forward as you accelerate the CapEx deployment?</p>
          <p>And then finally, could you talk a little bit about the reasons behind the six months delay on the Buenavista SXEW III project and the Angangueo project? And also I noticed that the CapEx for these two projects did not increase despite the delays, so if you can clarify why that was the case I would appreciate that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Carlos, let me comment first on the cost. Basically what we are &#x2013; we have better cash cost in the second quarter due to the response in ore grade and recoveries of our operations of Cuajone, Buenavista and Caridad. We believe that we will sustain the current levels of production for the rest of the year for these three operations. And that's on the production side of the cost, as obviously we produce more copper, our cash cost decreases somehow.</p>
          <p>Regarding the prices, what we're seeing is that energy and fuel are helping us a little bit cost-wise. Cost reductions, driven by energy, were about $6 million in the second quarter. In the case of workers' participation, we have a reduction in this quarter, when compared to a prior one, but as the company faces higher prices, obviously that figure may change. The reason why workers' participation has decreased is mainly the result of the lower earnings before taxes.</p>
          <p>Regarding the dividend question, I would appreciate if Daniel Muniz could make a comment on that please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Carlos, thank you. As you know, we don't have a definite policy written in stone, what we do <mark type="audio gap" /> (21:33)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, this is the operator. We are experiencing technical difficulty. Our speaker's line has dropped. Please wait for a moment. We will reconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carlos, we're still on the line. Let me focus on your third question, while we wait for Daniel to reconnect. Basically, on the Buenavista, the SXEW III plants, I'll ask Mr. Gonzalez to comment on the equipment delay and the postponement of the start up of the investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Normally what it is that the delivery of the equipment that we are buying for this project of the portion of the concentrator of Buenavista mine is delaying. And for that reason we are extending the termination of the project in order to be in operation. And in Angangueo, that was the other one that you mentioned, we are starting a little late for some problem that we have with the government of the state in Michoacan. And we hope that we can resolve that and recover the timing in order to be at the beginning of the 2015 year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:17)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to clarify, if I may. On the Buenavista, I was talking about the SXEW III project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ok.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think you mentioned the concentrator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The SXEW plant, we are using the equipment that Tia Maria bought for that project, and we are sending that to Buenavista, and I hope that they will receive it on time and starting the installation. And that will be really not having any delay. I don't know which dates you had before, but that is in the beginning of 2014 &#x2013; the start of the operation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And Angangueo will start in the first half of 2015, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o from Ita&#xFA; BBA. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, everybody. First question is as regarding the Quebalix project in Buenavista, which is, it's going to be starting up third quarter. What could be the benefits that this project brings in terms of potentially a little bit of higher production because of the increasing recovery? Or a little bit of a lower cost? What could we see in terms of benefits of this project starting up in the second half of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marcos, how are you? Well the Quebalix is a facility that allows us to exploit the tax for the SXEW plants in a better way. By reducing the size of the rocks through the crusher and then spreading them more orderly through the conveyer belt system, what we get is two benefits.</p>
          <p>The first one is that we increase the recovery of the contained copper in the SXEW &#x2013; in the oxides and material process for the SXEW plant. In our case, that recovery increases, broadly speaking, from about 50% to 70%.</p>
          <p>The second benefit comes from the time that we have to &#x2013; for getting this material or this copper recuperated. Usually you have at Quebalix, your recovery rate will take about five years in order to recuperate all the mineral that is contained, or that most of the mineral that is contained in the ore, while in the Quebalix that figure reduces to three years. So those two benefits are part of what we're expecting from the Quebalix. This project is tied to the SXEW III partially, but will also benefit our current SXEW operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Felipe Hirai from Merrill Lynch Brazil. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Raul, Daniel, two questions. My first question is regarding CapEx. You maintain the guidance for this year for $1.5 billion, but I guess they was seeing CapEx running well below this level. What should we expect for the second half as you think &#x2013; do you still think it's achievable to get to this $1.5 billion? And also, if possible, if you could provide some kind of guidance for next year it would be great. That's my first question. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Felipe, well regarding the budget, our current view is that we will accelerate our capital spending through the year, so we believe that in the second half we will have much more CapEx expenses. At this point, we have not changed our view on the CapEx for 2012. For the remaining or the future years, what we have scheduled at this point, and this is certainly will be reviewed at year-end and at the beginning of next year, we're expecting to spend about $1.6 billion in 2013 to accommodate the projects that we discussed in this conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And if I may, a second quick question. Could you provide an update on your current hedge positions, if any are done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very simple, we have no hedge positions at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, that's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Leandro Cappa from Deutsche Bank. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much. So until this quarter you used provided an estimate for the status of the Tia Maria project on your earnings release, but now there is no more estimates provided. Do you still believe it's feasible to the degree by 2015? Could you detail a little bit more on the project timeline? That's my first question. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hold on a sec, please, Lean. Leandro, Tia Maria is scheduled to start-up at the beginning of 2015. We arrived at that figure assuming a certain timeline for getting the appropriate permits that we need to get, after finishing our environmental, the new environmental impact assessment that the company is preparing on the delivery of the new plant that we will need to buy because we mentioned that the plant that we buy for Tia Maria was send to Buenavista.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just one more question. So what's the annual production you expect for the Tantahuatay mine to reach? And how much do you expect it to contribute in your earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well for the year, Tantahuatay is currently scheduled to produce about 118,000 ounces of gold and 565,000 ounces of silver. Depending on prices that should convert into an additional benefit for the company. At current prices, the contribution amount is a little bit ahead of $3.5 million, so in six months that will be about $21 million of additional contribution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Leonardo Correa from Barclays Capital. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, everyone. Good afternoon. My first question, Raul, is regarding the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:27) environment in Peru and if you can share with us your latest thoughts on what can change and how the miners have been involved in those other projects that are expected in the region, especially now with the recent cabinet changes that we saw. So if you can just give us an update on what's happening and how potentially more confident you are with the recent changes that Humala has been adopting.</p>
          <p>And my second question is still regarding CapEx and projects, the understanding here that we had is that the Angangueo project was reduced in size in terms of its future copper production, so maybe if you can walk us through on why exactly you downgraded future expectations that would also help us a lot.</p>
          <p>And then finally if you can go back to Carlos' question on dividend, that would also be helpful for us. So thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question was about &#x2013; I couldn't understand well what you said, but I believe that you want us to give a comment on the current operating circumstances for a mining company in Peru due to the recent change in cabinet, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's right, I mean just basically an evaluation of what the recent political changes and how that can potentially impact the business confidence in mining activity and growth projects, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well currently the Mining and Energy Minister is the same in the new cabinet, so we're expecting the same policies to hold, or no changes, in other words. So on that, we're not seeing any variances. The government is trying to help companies to go ahead with the projects and that's the case for us as well.</p>
          <p>And your second question &#x2013; I'm sorry that we couldn't get you well to the phone, but I understand that you referred to the &#x2013; why the change in production in Angangueo? Is that your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we were working with a number which was closer to 30,000 tons, 40,000 tons and now the recent number is closer to 10,000 tons, so anyways we could be missing something, but I thought there was a bit of a reduction in future output from Angangueo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, sorry Leonardo, but we can't copy you well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, was there any, Raul, what I'm asking is, was there any change in the Angangueo project in terms of future output of copper?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. The thing here is that between the prior quarter and this one, and that could be a source of confusion for what I certainly like to apologize, if that's the case, it's that in the prior quarter we had a clear idea of how much concentrate was the Angangueo mine going to produce, while, in this quarter, we have to find the figures that we have for production and that's why we're indicating the estimated production for the metals of the Angangueo, the metal content. In other words, on the prior quarter, the report indicated about 36,000 tons of copper concentrate. Now we have a much clearer view on that and that's why we have today contained copper, which is 10,400 tons of copper, 9,700 tons of zinc and 3,900 tons of lead. And is Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz back on the call?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am. Thank you, Raul. I apologize. There's been a lot of technical difficulties today, but I'll be happy to take the dividend question. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good. Thank you. Well as I was trying to explain, Carlos, and I figured that you couldn't listen, we don't have a dividend policy written in stone at Southern Copper, but, however, we've been trying to maintain a steady track record throughout the years. This time, the way the board has decided to reduce the payout ratio based on the CapEx that Raul has just explained, and to not only based on estimations, but also based on our commitments for those expenditures. We have $1.5 billion 2012 CapEx budget, and we've committed for certainly more.</p>
          <p>So we looked at the copper environment and the drop in all the metal prices and the macro environment, and our board decided that it was prudent to decrease the payout ratio and to decrease the dividend, okay, and the dividend paid. So we are committed to fulfilling it and completing our projects, and that's the rationale of our prudence in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Whether we're going to keep on with this payout ratio going forward, I'm sorry I'm not able to tell. We really debate it every quarter. So we'll look at it next quarter. But we do, or our board and the company has a commitment to really deliver these projects, so we are working on it. And that's the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mandeep Singh from JPMorgan. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Raul. Congrats on the results, and thanks for taking my question. The question is related to your copper production that saw strong recovery in your own mine production, and the run rate has now reached above the 2012 guidance. So the first part is, was the improvement in grades and recoveries as expected or was it better than what you were earlier expecting? And what do you expect for production for the rest of the year?</p>
          <p>And if you could please comment on the impact that it has, if at all, on your production guidance of 640,000 tons, and the mix between own production and the third-party concentrates?</p>
          <p>And my second question is related to your CapEx. I understand that you're maintaining your CapEx budget of $1.5 billion for the year. But if you could just elaborate a little bit on the projects where we will see accelerated CapEx in the second half. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me start by the production guidance. We are maintaining our guidance for the year, which is 640,800 tons of copper. However, we are reducing the share of third-party copper on this total number from 30,800 tons that we indicated at the beginning of this year, to 21,300 tons. That is our current forecast for third-party copper.</p>
          <p>Regarding capitals, we are expecting &#x2013; usually capital budgets usually are lower at the beginning of the year when budgets are being developed. Because, let's say, in the first quarter you basically put purchase orders, have to do some advance statements, but they are not as important as the ones that you have to do when you start getting the equipment that you already put the purchase order for.</p>
          <p>So that's why we're expecting to have much more expenses on the second half of the year than on the first part. So what is the maintenance CapEx? Now in the case of the projects we have been working through 2011 very hard in defining the projects, defining the basic and detailed engineering and now we're in the process of purchasing of the equipment. As part of that process the company, as we indicated through the call, transferred the SXEW plants of the Tia Maria to Buenavista. And also the purchase orders on several mining equipment was mentioned in the call. So we will start getting that equipment in the second half of 2012 and, as a consequence, our CapEx will increase accordingly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Garrett Nelson from BB&amp;T Capital Markets. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. You've outlined the progress of each individual growth project, but is there any change to your longer term copper production and CapEx forecast through 2016 from the previous numbers you've published or can we assume that prior guidance is still intact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, there is a little change in the guidance due to the delay of the SXEW plant the start up on that. And also we are considering now the Angangueo project would &#x2013; some production that was not there since the beginning of the year. But there are minor changes basically to our guidance. For next year we are expecting to have about 654,000 tons of copper, for 2014 that will be 712,000 tons, for 2015, 996,000 tons, and for 2016, 1.1 million tons of copper, that's our current view on the company's increasing production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. That's very helpful. And then as you mentioned the equity income recognized from your 44% interests in the Tantahuatay mine added $0.02 or $0.03 to earnings for the quarter, can you help us with how to think about the gold and silver production and costs at that mine going forward? I'm just trying to get a better sense of what your equity income might look like in Q3, Q4 and into next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well for Tantahuatay, we already gave guidance on production for the year. It's about 118,000 tons of copper and 650,000 tons of silver &#x2013; I'm sorry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was gold, Raul, not copper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That will be great, but I'm so sorry that, that cannot be the case. I meat ounces. I'm so sorry to everybody. So let me repeat it again. It's 118,000 ounces of gold and 650,000 ounces of silver. That's for the year. At current prices, that should be about $3.5 million per month and that is basically what is coming to our P&amp;L. Besides this, the company is getting back some stockholder's loan that the joint venture did and that will certainly help our cash flow as well. But the numbers are in the range of what I mentioned regarding the profits as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Juan Lopez from GBM (44:27). Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Thank you for the conference call. Most of my questions have been already answered, but, Raul, I have a question that may not be familiar right now, but I have &#x2013; I would like to know regarding the two power plants that Grupo Mexico is planning to build, how would it be related to Southern Copper mining production if the company will pay that market prices or if some cost-benefit are to be expected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oscar, will you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. As you know, <mark type="ph" /> Juan (45:19) the power plants are being built by Grupo Mexico, but of course the off-taker and the idea is to lower the electricity consumption costs for Minera M&#xE9;xico. As you know Minera M&#xE9;xico has, in Mexico, electricity costs are very high compared to the U.S., and sometimes higher than Peru. So the idea is, we're working on it. The plants will not be ready now. They're being worked on. And they're being built, as you know, by Siemens on the front of the infrastructure division of Grupo Mexico. And the idea is definitely for Southern Copper to save costs. We have not concluded the independent engineers' modeling, et cetera. We'll give you exact details when we have them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Rene Kleyweg from Renaissance Capital. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Just two things. One, if you could provide us a bit of an update on the timing of permits. We talked about Tia Maria just in terms of when internal expectations are and what the next big bench &#x2013; big sort of time-critical events are on those.</p>
          <p>And then just, I guess, more for Daniel, you know you've got this extremely attractive financing in place at 5%, but because of the cash balance you're running &#x2013; you're interest on your net cash balance is effectively nearly 10%. You just cut your dividend, and yet we're only talking about a $1 billion or so in cash, which is not really sufficient to do anything in terms of any major acquisitions.</p>
          <p>So I'm just trying to understand the dynamics at work. I mean I appreciate CapEx spend is going up in the second half of the year, but operating cash flow will cover that. So, you know, just trying to get a better feel of how we should be thinking about that over the next two, three years. And what is the point of keeping that cash balance on the balance sheet, when it's not really sufficient to make any sort of significant acquisitions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In the first question about Toquepala and Tia Maria we have said that, that would be at the beginning of year 2015 if we have all the approvals of the environmental impact studies in both of the projects, and start production maybe in the Tia Maria in the middle of 2015, and in the case of Toquepala expansion, either at the end of 2014 or beginning of 2015.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. It was more in terms of the permitting, the timeframe on the permitting, as opposed to the production. Apologies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The permits? Rene, We have to comply with several permits in order to go ahead with expansion. But usually you have &#x2013; the first thing that you have to do is you have to present your environmental impact assessment. In the case of the Toquepala expansion, we already did that. We already did some workshops that we have to do with local communities and there is one final workshop, which is the most important one that is with the authorities participating in it and the local community's representatives.</p>
          <p>That one, we had it in September of 2011, and was &#x2013; even though it was a specific meeting with no problems at all, due to the fact that about 80 kilometers away from where we were having the meeting we had some social unrest, due to that fact, the authority decided to &#x2013; not to go ahead with the environmental impact assessment approval.</p>
          <p>The company has been in talks with local communities and with the regional government of Tacna in order to clarify the benefits of the projects for the region and we think that we're moving forward in these talks. But we need to &#x2013; what we need to do it's to have that last meeting happen. And, after that, we will start the construction. We're assuming that we will get to some solution on this by year-end.</p>
          <p>In the case of Tia Maria, we're currently doing the environmental impact assessment. After that, we will present it to authorities and then there is a process of, first, the authority have, legally speaking, 30 days to answer back the company. Usually it takes a little bit long. We're assuming some cushion for that. And also, we should get some questions or concerns from the local communities. That has a defined timeframe and we already answered most of the questions in the past process for Tia Maria. So we believe that we shouldn't have that many questions and concerns from local communities because we already tackled those in the past.</p>
          <p>However, there could be the case that there are some questions. So assuming certain timeframes for each of these steps, we arrived to about the first quarter of 2015 as the startup moment for the Tia Maria project and then the ramping-up will take project to be at full capacity by mid-2015.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And that's so the Tia Maria you're assuming EIA by the first quarter of next year? Or is it more second, first half of next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. At the beginning of next year when we &#x2013; definitely we need the approval of the environmental impact study.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The listener had a question that I ask, Daniel, if you can comment on that please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. Mr. Quintanilla's line has been dropped again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry for the inconvenience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all right, Raul. I will catch up at some other point on that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from Jamie Nicholson from Credit Suisse. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Hello. Thanks for the call. This is Luciano Coster on behalf of Jamie Nicholson. I just wanted to ask the $1.3 billion budget for 2013 in CapEx, do you think you will need to finance that in the debt market or most of it from cash flow? If you could just comment and provide some color on that, that would be great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this point we have no specific plans of tapping on the debt markets. So the answer will be our own cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Santiago Perez. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Raul, Daniel, thanks for your time and your questions. I know you have answered most of my questions, but I only have one remaining. Would you be able to give us a timeframe or more of a scheduled execution plan regarding <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:26) production credits for the rest of the year and the following one, 2013 please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Santiago, I'm sorry, but we couldn't copy you well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just wanted to know if you have any execution, scheduled execution plan for production for this year or the following. It would be great if you could shed some light on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For this year I think we already mentioned that we're still holding the forecast of 640,800 tons and for next year 650,000 tons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Raul. Maybe you didn't hear me. I meant hedges. Are you planning to hedge any part of your production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hedge?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hedge. Yes. Copper production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. At this point we have no hedge &#x2013; we don't have any hedge position and we are not considering doing anything like that at this point, Santiago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot. Congratulations on your results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I have no further questions in queue. I turn the call back over to the presenters for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, with this we conclude our conference call for the second quarter. We certainly appreciate your participation, and we expect to have you back with us when we report the third quarter results. Thank you very much, and again let me apologize for the technical inconvenience that we have had through the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>