<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1387806" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-04-19</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2483</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Manager of Financial Planning and Investor Relations">Raul Jacob</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Corretora de T&#xED;tulos e Valores Mobili&#xE1;rios SA">Leonardo Correa</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Oscar Gonz&#xE1;lez Rocha</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Santander Central Hispano Investment">Victoria Santaella</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets Ltd.">David S. Radclyffe</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch SA Corretora De T&#xED;tulos E Valores">Felipe Hirai</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="NBT Holdings, Inc.">Jamie Smith Nicholson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley Mexico Casa de Bolsa SA de CV">Alfonso Salazar Herrera</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Corretora de Valores SA">Rodrigo Barros</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Santander Central Hispano Investment">Sergio Matsumoto</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Ixe Casa de Bolsa">Rodrigo Heredia Matarazzo</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to the Southern Copper Corporation's First Quarter 2011 Results Conference Call. With us this morning we have Southern Copper Corporation, Mr. Raul Jacob, Manager of Financial Planning and Investor Relations, who will discuss the results of the company for the first quarter and answer any questions that you may have.</p>
          <p>The following information discussed on today's call may include forward-looking statements regarding the company's results and prospects, which are subject to risks and uncertainties. Actual results may differ materially and the company cautions not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Southern Copper Corporation undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statement, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. All results are expressed in full U.S. GAAP.</p>
          <p>Now, I will pass the call over to Mr. Raul Jacob. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Michelle and good morning everyone and welcome to Southern Copper first quarter 2011 earnings conference call. Participating in today's conference is Mr. Oscar Gonz&#xE1;lez Rocha, Southern Copper's CEO. On today's conference call, we will begin with an update of our view on metal markets. We will then talk about Southern Copper's key results related to production, sales, operating cost, financial results and capital spending. After that we will open the session for questions.</p>
          <p>Let me focus first on the copper market. We maintained our positive outlook for the market fundamentals of these metals. On the demand side, a worldwide growth in the range of 4% to 5% for 2011 is expected. These will not be matched by new copper production estimated to grow by 3% in 2011.</p>
          <p>At the end of last year, several analysts believe the market was heading towards a deficit of 400,000 to 600,000 tons that should sustain copper prices in the range of $4.50 to $5 per tons. As reported to market then we believe that those prices &#x2013; price levels will imply an acute scarcity of physical materials that we were not seeing at the end of the fourth quarter of 2010 and we still don't see.</p>
          <p>At this point, we believe the market is adequately supplied, considering inventory levels of the Shanghai, London Metal Exchange and COMEX warehouses, of warehouse material and the contribution of the scrap copper, a product that appears when prices are attractive. Scrap copper is estimated by CRU to grow by 200,000 tons in 2011 to a total of 3.1 million tons in the current year with China being its main consumer. For the remainder of 2011, we believe copper prices will average $4.50 for the year.</p>
          <p>As you know, SCC's main by-product is molybdenum. In the first quarter of this year these metal represented 9% of company sales. We're currently seeing a soft recovery in the molybdenum consumption. For the year 2011, we're expecting a relatively balanced market for this metal with prices at about $16 per ton.</p>
          <p>Let me go now into copper production. Before we begin the analysis of this quarter's production, let me remind you that last year the company changed the name of the Cananea operating unit to Buenavista recovery. So please keep in mind that when we mention the Buenavista operation, we referred to the unit formerly known as Cananea.</p>
          <p>The company's copper mine production in the first quarter of 2011 increased by 13.7% to 124,000 tons when compared to 109,000 tons we produced in the first quarter of 2010. This increase was mainly the result of 27,600 tons of copper production at our Buenavista mine that was partially offset by expected lower production at our Peruvian and La Caridad operations. Should we point it out that, I mentioned the Cananea production of 27,600 tons and at full capacity Buenavista should produce about 45,000 tons per quarter.</p>
          <p>As previously reported, the SXEW average production of Buenavista reached full capacity in the last quarter, in the fourth quarter of 2010. Currently, besides the SXEW plant all crushing, milling and flotation circuits of the concentrator are running at full capacity at the Buenavista operation and we are now optimizing the copper recovery circuit to reach full production.</p>
          <p>We expect to finish this process during April and increase the Buenavista concentrator recovery to full production since the second quarter of this year. For the second half of 2011 we expect significant increase in ore grade at the Cuajone mine which will offset the lower production of the first quarter of this year, which was due to expected lower grades.</p>
          <p>Our prior guidance for 2011 was a total production of 630,000 tons of copper with 3% being copper from third-party for purchase copper. Current plants maintain this forecast that consider an increase in their purchase copper to 5.7% for the year.</p>
          <p>Regarding the ramping up of Buenavista and the cost of the repairs, through March 31, 2011 we have to spend $112.6 million from repairs. Of these, $54.4 million were capitalized and $58.2 million were charged to operating cost, both in 2010 and 2011. During the first quarter of this year, we charged $22.3 million to operating cost. We are maintaining the estimated cost of the repairs at approximately $114 million.</p>
          <p>Regarding molybdenum production, in the first quarter molybdenum production decreased by 10.1% to 4,274 tons, compared to 4,753 tons in the first quarter of last year to expected lower ore grades primarily at the Cuajone operation.</p>
          <p>Focusing on Southern Copper financial performance, the first quarter 2011 sales were $1.6 billion, 31% higher than the $1.2 billion we had in the first quarter of last year. This increase was mainly result of higher metal prices, as well as higher copper sales volumes, which increased 12%. When compared to the first quarter of last year, molybdenum volume sold decreased by 10%, silver volume sold decreased by 10%, the zinc volume sold decreased by 4%.</p>
          <p>Swap contracts are hedging approximately 32% of the remaining 2011 copper production at an average price of $4.08 per pound; and zero cost collars are hedging approximately 30% of 2011 copper production with an average floor price of $3.02 per pound and an average cap price of $4.84 per pound. The remaining 38% is unhedged and prices will continue to fluctuate with the market copper price. With these hedges company is benefiting from the current copper prices up 68% of its volume, while obtaining insurance for the remainder of its production at $4.08 per pound in average.</p>
          <p>For 2011 (sic) [2012], the company hedged approximately 13% of copper production through zero-cost collars with an average floor price of $3.50 per pound and an average cap price of $5.18 per pound.</p>
          <p>Focusing on operating cost, our total operating cost and expenses has increased 29.7% or $192.4 million when compared to the fourth quarter of 2010. The most important additional cost was $215 million in purchase copper concentrate. These higher cost is sold from approximately 30,000 tons of purchase concentrate charged to cost balance our smelting capacity with our current production rates, and to replace purchase copper in process by Buenavista material at our Mexican smelting operations. Purchase copper should decrease its weight in the future as we increased copper production from the Buenavista and Cuajone mines. Beside these cost we have some cost inflation during the past....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, it will be just one moment well, we are having some technical difficulties, please hold the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My excuses that we were cut from the line. I am returning to where I was in operating cost. As I said, most of the cost increase in the first quarter of the year has been related to purchased copper concentrate that was &#x2013; we had variance of $215 million in that matter, mainly to balance our production with smelting grade with our production, with our current production. Beside these costs, we had some cost inflation during the past quarter, particularly in fuel and power and cost related to the Buenavista ramping up that I indicated was $22.3 million.</p>
          <p>As a result of the previously mentioned sales and operating cost, EBITDA for the first quarter was $842 million, this figure was 22% higher than the $692 million of EBITDA for the first quarter of 2000 (sic) [2010].</p>
          <p>Speaking about cash costs, Southern Copper operating cash cost including the benefit of by-product credits was $0.243 per pound in the first quarter of this year. This cash cost was slightly higher than the $0.231 of cash cost for the fourth quarter of 2010. The company first quarter operating cash cost per pound of copper produced before by-product credits was $1.67 per pound, $0.14 higher than the operating cash cost $1.53 per pound that we have in the fourth quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>The cash cost increase of $0.14 before credits is mainly attributable to the repair cost of Buenavista that represent about $0.08 per pound of copper and cost inflation expense. Considering the lower production cost of the Buenavista operation we expect cash cost before by-product credits to increase in the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>Regarding by-products, we had a total credit per pound of $1.42 per pound of copper in the first quarter. This year compares to a credit of $1.30 per pound in the fourth quarter of 2010. A $0.12 of higher credit was mainly due to higher prices of sulfuric acid, zinc, silver and third-party purchased copper net contribution.</p>
          <p>Net earnings as a result of the better market prices and higher copper volume from Buenavista, our net income attributable &#x2013; our net income was $478 million or diluted earnings per share of $0.563. This figure compares with net earnings for the first quarter of 2010 of $383 million or diluted earnings per share of $0.451, a 25% increase.</p>
          <p>Expansion and capital projects. Since we have some recent developments affecting the Tia Maria project, let me start by explaining the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (15:27) and the company's position regarding certain <mark type="indiscernible" /> (15:30). Starting on March 23, a small group opposing mining activities in the Islay region, conducted violent acts with groundless and completely false allegations that the Tia Maria project would use agricultural water and would cause pollution in the region.</p>
          <p>These activists have been conducting disruptions, which included national highway blockages, damage to public and private property and attacks on police forces. Specifically, the activists blocked the high traffic highway between the port of Matarani and Arequipa, located 50 kilometers away from the Tia Maria project; these blockages have nothing to do in any way with the construction of our project. In essence, the activists are using the Tia Maria project as an excuse to impede investment and to cause problems to the State, companies and local communities.</p>
          <p>The company has repeatedly stated that the water to be used in the project will be transported from the ocean through a 30-kilometer long pipeline, after its desalinization. All tests and analysis for the operation of the project has been conducted with seawater, which makes the falseness of the activist arguments all the more apparent. With respect to the activist pollution argument, the company has also repeatedly provided evidence that the project complies with the most strict and cumbersome environmental standards.</p>
          <p>In light of the activists disruptions, the Peruvian Government has suspended the Tia Maria project. Company will let a prudent time elapse because of the current political situation in Peru, although in the near future we will provide the authorities with every single piece of information requested by the Ministry of Energy and Mines with respect to Environmental Impact Assessment. The company is confident that with this information any concerns the authorities might have, will be answered as the company has always complied with the highest environmental standards.</p>
          <p>This type of SXEW leaching facility has been widely developed in Peru and other countries and it has been proven that they comply 100% with environmental regulations and do not pollute the air, the soil or the water or of the nearby banks.</p>
          <p>The Tia Maria project comprises an investment of approximately $1 billion, generating 4,000 jobs during the construction phase and 4,100 direct and indirect permanent jobs. The estimated annual production of the project is 120,000 tons of copper cathodes, all obtained through a leaching process, which is considered worldwide as the most environmental-friendly production method. The project would significantly increase Peruvian exports and generate important contributions to the Peruvian economy through income taxes and mining royalties, as well as payroll taxes, custom duties, mining rights and other levies.</p>
          <p>In addition, the company plans to invest in social responsibility programs in the Arequipa region similar to those established in the communities nearby the current Peruvian operations of Toquepala, Cuajone and Ilo. The company is confident that the Peruvian authorities will provide the legal stability that allows for economic development of mining investments and favorable legal and economic conditions for the growth and development of Peru.</p>
          <p>As of March 31, 2011, the company had to spend $434.7 million in Tia Maria. The total budget to complete the project is $500 million &#x2013; $601 million, of which $324 million were budgeted for.</p>
          <p>Moving toward our capital investment, the company capital expenditures for the first quarter of 2011 were $73 million. Regarding our expansion projects in Buenavista, we are working at full speed to deliver the planned 88,000 tons of additional copper through our leaching plants number III and number IV, which will come into production during the second half of 2013.</p>
          <p>We are also constructing their corresponding crushing and conveying systems. Additionally, we are working on the molybdenum recovery plant, with a capacity of 2,000 tons per year, which we anticipate will begin production in the fourth quarter of 2012. We are also concluding the detailed engineering studies for the Buenavista's new concentrator, which will allow us to increase an additional 188,000 tons of copper by the end of 2015. Currently there are more than 4,200 employees and contractors working in Cananea in Sonora for the development of these projects. The estimated investment for these projects is $2.6 billion over the following four years.</p>
          <p>The social programs for the Buenavista community are also underway. The company reconstructed the state of Sonora medical clinic, two new water wells and a street paving program that has been completed and the town library which &#x2013; the most modern technology to improve reference search capabilities at the clinic. In 2011, the company continues investing for the benefit of local communities. The Pilares mine site, close to the La Caridad mine, is being evaluated. As of March of this year 13,700 meters of drilling has been performed, access roads were developed and</p>
          <p>metallurgical testing and preliminary mine planning has begun.</p>
          <p>Regarding the Toquepala expansion, through March 31, 2011, we have spent $124 million on this project, mainly in mine equipment. The use of high pressure grinding rolls and wet screening at the tertiary crushing stage is expected to reduce operating cost. The scope of the project is currently under review as we are evaluating an increase in milling capacity to 60,000 tons per year &#x2013; per day from 40,000 tons per day originally planned.</p>
          <p>The Cuajone expansion project has a total capital budget of $301 million, of which we have spent $43.1 million through March of this year. Increased production from this expansion project will begin in the second half of 2011.</p>
          <p>The Tantahuatay project is located in Cajamarca in northern Peru. In 2010, we began development of this project to exploit the gold "cap". Tantahuatay contains estimated resources of 20.1 (sic) [27.1] million tons of mineralized material, with an average silver content of 13 grams per ton and 0.89 grams of gold per ton. We expect to start dore gold production by July 2011. The project is expected to have an average annual production of 90,000 ounces of gold and 425,000 ounces of silver for five years. The company has a 44.25% participation in this project.</p>
          <p>Regarding the AMC's proposal to effect on all-stock business combination, as we reported previously on the licensing fee of last year, the company received a non-binding proposal from its parent company, Americas Mining Corporation, offering to effect on all-stock business combination of Southern Copper and AMC, a parent company of Asarco. As proposed, all stockholders of Southern Copper will receive 1.237 common share of AMC in exchange for each share of SCC.</p>
          <p>As part of this process, the stock of AMC will be registered and listed on the New York, Mexico and Lima Stock Exchanges. Once completed, SCC shares will be de-listed from the exchanges.</p>
          <p>On August 10 of last year, the company formed a special committee of independent directors to evaluate the AMC's proposal. The special committee has engaged independent legal, financial and mining advisors to assist in this transaction and help in the evaluation of the proposal. There is no specific deadline for this process.</p>
          <p>Dividend payments, regarding dividends, as you know it is the company's policy to review at each Board Meeting, the capital investment plan, cash resources, and expected future cash flow generation from operations in order to determine the appropriate quarterly dividend. Accordingly, as disclosed to the market on April 13, 2011, the Board of Directors authorized a dividend of $0.56</p>
          <p>per share. This dividend will be paid on May 18, 2011 to shareholders of record at the close of business on May 04.</p>
          <p>Well, with this ladies and gentlemen, we finish the presentation for the conference call. Thank you very much for joining here today. And I like open up the phone for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from Leonardo Correa from Barclays Capital. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning. Thank you very much for the call. My first question is regarding the political environment in Peru. What are your expectations on the potential changes for the mining industry going forward under a more lefist regime, if that really occurs?</p>
          <p>And my second question would be regarding also the other expansion plans that you have in Peru, Toquepala and Cuajone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Leonardo, Leonardo, Leonardo....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can't copy you. I'm sorry, could you speak a little bit louder, because we cannot copy you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure, I'll try. The line was very bad all around, but let me try. So first of all my question is regarding the political environment in Peru. What are your expectations on the changes for the mining industry under potentially a leftist regime in Peru? So just highlight maybe some of your updated expectations over the political environment in Peru. That is my first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is also regarding Peru. On your Toquepala and Cuajone projects, if you have changed any of your plans regarding those projects. And how do you expect these projects evolving going forward, especially in an environment with a new government potentially, and also with all the social unrest caused by the mining industry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The first question is regarding future mining taxation in Peru, and the second one refers to the expansions of Toquepala and Cuajone in Peru and the current plans regarding current political environment. Is that a fair summary of your questions, Leonardo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right, that's correct. Perfect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Well, regarding taxation, we are currently &#x2013; and this is related to the political campaign that is going on right now in Peru. What we have seen is that, at the time of the campaign, several statements are made regarding mining taxation, that are &#x2013; when the winner takes office, usually its revised and different position comes out.</p>
          <p>At this point, we have two candidates that are mentioning some increases in taxation for mining activities are likely in the future. But where we will wait to see what happens with the election and what the candidates are doing running offices.</p>
          <p>Regarding the company plans for the Toquepala and Cuajone expansions, I'll ask Mr. Oscar Gonz&#xE1;lez to comment on those two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, about the Toquepala project, we are going to continue doing the retail engineering and the preparation of the environmental impact history to be presented at the end of May.</p>
          <p>In the Cuajone, we already buy the mining equipment in order to start doing the extra stripping that we will need in order to prepare the mineral to double the capacity of the Toquepala project that is going from 60,000 that we are milling today to 120,000, it will be a new plan of 60,000 tons per day.</p>
          <p>And in the Cuajone expansion, we already spent $43 million in equipment for the mine too, although in the stripping that we need to do a change in the variable cut-off grade in order that we will have better grades in the second part of the year, because like was explained we have low grades in Cuajone in the order of 0.5 and then we will need to return to 0.6 or 0.7 in the last four months of this year in order to recover the production that we have incurred this first quarter.</p>
          <p>And we hope that the government or the company's confidence and the government will provide the legal stability and the economic conditions in order that we can continue with that two projects and, of course, we are going to present a reconsideration of this decision about the rejecting of the environmental impact study of Tia Maria as soon as we are ready next week.</p>
          <p>I hope that will answer your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it does. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Victoria Santaella from Santander. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, gentlemen. And Raul, can you elaborate a little bit more in what are the risk of revising your expansion plans if Humala wins the election? I know it sounds a little bit repetitive, but it was not clear if Southern Copper will be revising the growth. And if it is possible to talk about it at this point in time. I'm talking about the operation of the company. Is there any risk that for next year, 2012, we might see delays on the other projects' expansion? I'm not talking about Tia Maria, but the other projects that you previously have been discussing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Victoria, regarding your first question, as has been indicated by our CEO, we are expecting the next government to provide the proper conditions to develop our projects and to develop mining industry through at our current position. On these we are not making any more comments about the political circumstances, we think that Peru should promote economic growth as well as mining industry as part of &#x2013; as an important contributor of this growth.</p>
          <p>About the expansion for next year, we are always reviewing our mining &#x2013; our expansion plans in light of different circumstances. And that is an ongoing task; we are not changing our plans at this point. So we are &#x2013; basically, our project pipeline had been closed to the market and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:17).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from David Radclyffe from BMO. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you. Just another question, sorry, on Tia Maria. Just from a different angle here, if you eventually had to abandon the project if the political landscape, as you were talking about, didn't improve, maybe could you just recap for us how much of the $435 million that you invested so far you could actually potentially recoup?</p>
          <p>And then a second question would be on the Asarco combination. I know you said that you can't provide an update in terms of a deadline, but I do understand that Grupo Mexico was actually targeting completion by, sort of, midyear. So I was just wondering if there is any update or if there's anything new that has emerged that is holding the process up? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, David. And let me address your first question regarding the Tia Maria project. Of the amount invested most of it is equipment, either mining equipment or plant equipment for leaching as well as electrolytic refinery that can be eventually transferred to other projects that the company has. So, on that matter, most of the $435 million that has been invested in Tia Maria would be easily reallocated to other company projects.</p>
          <p>And your second question was regarding transaction with Asarco. For that matter, the group led by independent directors was conformed as I mentioned and they are doing their work. They already hired legal as well as financial and mining advisors. At the end of this year, moving forward to amending their review, but they have no specific deadline to finish their work, so that's what we can report at this point on this matter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Raul, let me add little bit about the equipment of Tia Maria. Yes, we have about $400 million investment and that is mainly about $90 million in equipment for the mine and we are already using part of that equipment in Toquepala and Cuajone for the stripping. And we hope that in case that we cannot get the Tia Maria project undergoing, we are going to insist with the government and the new government in August as soon as he will take place, then we have the opportunity to use part of the equipment that belongs to the SXEW plant that are about $84 million in our two projects of the SXEW plants in Buenavista, because they are two, the SXEW III and the SXEW IV that will be 88,000 tons and the plant in Tia Maria is for 120,000 will be a little higher, we have a lot of solutions in Buenavista in order to reach the 120,000 in the near future.</p>
          <p>And in the case of the equipment for crushing and conveying, we can use in Toquepala expansion the primary crusher part of the conveyor and the secondary tertiary equipment in order to be used there. Then, of course, we are going to have pending in that case about $40 million of engineering that are almost complete and some other small amounts, but mainly we will have about $350 million of equipment used in different areas of Mexico and Peru.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Felipe Hirai from Merrill Lynch. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you, but my question has been answered already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Felipe, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:06)? Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your next question then comes from Jamie Nicholson from Credit Suisse. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for the call. What is your CapEx budget this year by quarter? Given that you spent only $73 million in the first quarter, I'm wondering when you will be ramping up your CapEx, and if you adjusted the budget downward, given the Tia Maria delay? That's my first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, for the second &#x2013; this is our budget for expansions, okay? For the second quarter, we have budget about $121 million. For the third quarter &#x2013; sorry, I made a mistake. This is related to the Peruvian operations. For the whole year, our total budget is $808 million for the Peruvian operations and $867 million for the Mexican operations.</p>
          <p>We usually don't spend this on an even basis. On the first quarter of the year, as I explained, we spent $73 million in total. We will be increasing our expenditures as we move on into the year.</p>
          <p>For the full year, we have a budget of $324 million for Tia Maria. That budget will probably change, since we are expecting some delay on the project at this point. For the rest of the year, we will be spending, increasing our expenditures at the Mexican operations as well as the Peruvian operations in the third and fourth quarter of the year. At this point, I don't have a revised forecast of our CapEx per quarter for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so it sounds like you're keeping the same CapEx budget that you mentioned last quarter for this year, but that it may be revised over the course of the year if Tia Maria continues to be delayed, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a fair statement, Jamie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you still plan to fund this CapEx out of cash flow or do you have any financing plans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this point, we don't have specific financial plans for increasing our debt. Last year, if you recall, we issued $1.5 billion <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:09) basically waiting to be spent for the projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then &#x2013; thank you. I notice that around 37% of your EBITDA last year came from Mexico. And given the growth that you're seeing in Buenavista, and given the comment that you made about it being a very low-cost mine, do you have a forecast or an expectation for what your EBITDA contribution from Mexico will be this year and next? It looks like it could get close to 45% of your total EBITDA, given the production growth out of Buenavista. Is that somewhere in the range of what you're seeing for the breakdown between Mexico and Peru?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think that it's always &#x2013; it is not only copper that we are talking about <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:08) at this point, we're expecting a relatively balance between the contribution of Mexico and Peru for 2011. As Buenavista recovers, we will have more contribution from the Mexican operations into our EBITDA. At this point, for the forecast for the year it's a relatively balanced contribution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then one final question. Going forward just on this point about the uncertainties in the tax regime in Peru, do you expect that should those uncertainties remain or you're unsatisfied with the tax that you would allocate more of your investment into Peru and focus &#x2013; excuse me into Mexico and focus your growth in Mexico rather than Peru, given the uncertainties regarding the political and tax regime there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think this is something that we'll be defining very quickly, as soon as we have the new administration in Peru. And on that day, we will have a review on our plans if necessary, if not we will continue with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Alfonso Salazar from Morgan Stanley. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much for the call. My question is regarding color on cost increases in the quarter. I think it is going to be very useful if you can give us a breakdown on what is due to Buenaventura, maybe something is due to lower ore grades or cost inflation. I don't know if you can share with us that information. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat your question, Alfonso, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. My question is regarding if you can give us some color on cost increases during the quarter? It would be very useful if you can give us a breakdown on what is due to Buenaventura or some preparation expenses or some lower ore grades affecting your costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Let me &#x2013; thank you very much for the question, because it allow us to explain what has happened in the first quarter. I'm sure that many <mark type="indiscernible" /> (44:41) concern about increasing cost of &#x2013; operating cost and expenses, as I reported, it increased 29.7% or about $192 million in the first quarter when we compare that to the prior one, to the fourth quarter 2010.</p>
          <p>And the most important additional cost was about $215 million of our purchase copper concentrate. When we explained you, why we have these additional costs, and the reason for these is two fold. One is that we had a smelting capacity that is much higher than our production rate in the first quarter. We had a much more capacity to smelt copper concentrate than what we had in total production.</p>
          <p>And in this case, the production that we require or the additional production that we require is the Buenavista production and the Cuajone production. We indicated already that Cuajone will pass in the first half of this year, lower ore grade than it's trending ore grade long-term, due to a change in or to the delay on the investment for the HPGR and the Cuajone <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:16) kind of grade. So that's one of the things. We have to buy some copper concentrate to filling the copper level our smelter could fill, which by the way has been operating at very good rate during the first quarter in both Mexico and Peru.</p>
          <p>The second reason is that we have replaced purchased copper concentrates as part of our coppering process in our operations due to the new production of our ore copper concentrate. So this second effect has also affected our cost in the first quarter of 2011. Beside these we have some cost inflation. Fuel cost increased by $7 million in the quarter when compared to the fourth quarter, so quarter to the prior quarter. Power cost increased $10 million and costs related to the Buenavista ramping up the repairs and everything that &#x2013; what we have charged, cost was $22.3 million.</p>
          <p>So when you add all of these, you have a cost increase in total, as I said, of $192 million. We have some positive variances, obviously and a cash cost increase before credit of $0.14 as was reported.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Rodrigo Barros from Deutsche Bank. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Raul, thanks for the call. Thanks for the call. I have a couple of questions. First, if you could give us more color on how much copper concentrate you should buy in 2011 and in 2012, if possible, for your extra smelting capacity.</p>
          <p>And my second question is on the ore grades budget for Cuajone. Since &#x2013; I mean, we are running at 0.5 and then by the end of the year we should be 0.7, as you mentioned in the call. What should we expect for 2012 in terms of ore grades? Is the deteriorating grades also a trend or maybe you have some stabilization? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much for the question, Rodrigo. On the &#x2013; let me start by the last one. The Cuajone operation ore grade will increase because of the project that it &#x2013; which most important benefits will show up on the second half or will start to show up to be precise on the second half this year. That's a variable cost &#x2013; a variable ore grade project that we have been implementing in Cuajone.</p>
          <p>And that will increase the ore grades as was mentioned from 0.5 to 0.7 for the rest of the year, and in total for the next 10-years, the Cuajone operation will increase by this project and another one <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:55) HPGR or high pressure grinding rolls and the operation will increase its production by about 22,000 tons per year. That's something that will certainly flow into 2012 as well.</p>
          <p>Sorry, what's your first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you could give us some guidance on how much copper concentrate you should buy in 2011 and 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, concentrate purchases, thank you. For the first quarter, we bought about 30,000 tons of copper from third parties, copper concentrate from third parties. That's the copper <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:41). For the rest of the year, we're expecting to buy another 8,000 tons, most of them in the second quarter of this year as Buenavista is ramping up, this is still not at full capacity until May.</p>
          <p>From there on, we believe that we will be balanced between our smelting and concentrate productions and capacity. I'd like also to mention that this is not only the result of lower production, it's actually the result of higher smelting capacity at the Peruvian operations. That year, we finished bi-annual maintenance of our Ilo smelter that increased its smelting capacity by about 10% and that's why we are having much more demand from third-party concentrate.</p>
          <p>As we have more normal production coming from Buenavista and Cuajone that will fill-in in replacing purchase copper and certainly the cost of that material of our own material is much lower than the cost of purchased copper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. So I will call you later to get more details on this. But thank you very much for the answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sergio Matsumoto from Santander Investment. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I want to ask a question about tax stabilization agreements that you have with the Peruvian government. On this are they still current? And if so, when do they expire. That is the question.</p>
          <p>And what types of taxes are covered in this agreement? Are they both for corporate tax and royalties? And lastly, would the government need to revoke them if they want to introduce new taxes and royalties?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Regarding taxes stability agreement, we can. One, related to our Toquepala SXEW plant that expired already. So, at this point, we have no any &#x2013; no tax stability contracts that are holding.</p>
          <p>And your second question was, Sergio, I am sorry that I...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:20) very sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about what type of taxes are covered in those agreements, whether they are both taxes and royalties?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, they are not &#x2013; we're paying the useful Peruvian taxes, which are royalty taxes about &#x2013; that goes from 1% to 3% of sales the company average to give you an idea, because there are certain deductions that we can apply to that, the company average. It's about 2% of sales after we've taken the effect of the deductions.</p>
          <p>Corporate tax in Peru is 30% and we have a dividend tax on top of that, which is 3% of profit before taxes. And there is profit sharing, which is 8% of profit before taxes, that's basically what we pay in taxes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the last question is I just want to get an idea of how much protection you may have with these agreements, if the new government wants to introduce a new tax or royalty?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have any current agreements, Sergio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are complying with laws that has to be approved by Congress. And let me mention this, because it's important for all of you to know, the next Congress, which has already been elected will not have a majority. They will have several minorities, none of the candidates that are on the runoff are having more than 30% of Congress. Actually, they have less than 30%.</p>
          <p>And in order to change taxes, you have to pass a law. So if you want to have say a new income tax that has to be approved by Congress and Congress has been very reluctant to approve taxes, the new taxes in the past, we have to see how this the new Congress will react to that, but at this point that's our view of the tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from Rodrigo Heredia from Ixe. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everyone. Thank you for the call. Taking into account that all that you said about the increase in the cost of sales in this quarter, can we expect that EBITDA margin will increase for the end of this year because in the first quarter the margin is something around 52.6% versus an average of the last year of 56.1%? So, I think that if you reduce the third-parties copper concentrate purchases and the rate of the fixed cost in Buenavista could be lower, you can &#x2013; you could show an increase in the margin &#x2013; in the EBITDA margin, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; thank you very much for your question Rodrigo. And let me mention that at these prices if we keep replacing copper concentrates from third parties by our own concentrate production which has a much lower cost that will certainly increase our EBITDA margin looking forward or moving into the second half of this year. So I basically confer with what you just said in the sense that we will increase &#x2013; we could increase our EBITDA margin as long as we have these prices and we have much more of our own production coming into the market.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned our guidance for the year, it's maintained at this point. We are not buying as much &#x2013; as many copper concentrates in the rest of the year because we had one-time effect which was replacing the copper in process at our operations that was purchase copper in the first quarter, that will not happen again in this year, that's our plan, that we don't expect it to happen in the rest of the year. So we will be using much more of our own copper concentrate and rest of the purchase copper. As I mentioned we are expecting to buy about 8,000 tons of additional copper concentrates from third-party concentrates, that's the much lower number that what we processed on the first quarter which was 30,000 tons of copper concentrates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you and one more. You just said that in the case that Tia Maria couldn't go farther, the equipment could be used in other projects, Toquepala, Cuajone or even Buenavista. My question is if this is the scenario, and you use the SXEW plants that you already bought, if you use it in Buenavista this could generate on a faster starting operations in Buenavista for this &#x2013; for these projects or the outlook would remain at the same time in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that at this point we're indicating that the outlook is for 2013, we have to change or we have to pull out from Tia Maria new equipment, we will have to review how it fit in our plans and it is possible that it will accelerate a little bit our project, but it is very speculative at this point, Rodrigo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Jacob, I have no further questions at this time. I turn the call back over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you very much to all of you for attending our conference call and we expect to see you on the next conference quarter conference call for the second quarter 2011 result. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>