<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1205610" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>579</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Mariel von Drathen, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Peter L&#xF6;scher, President and Chief Executive Officer of Siemens AG</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Joe Kaeser, Head of Corporate Finance and Controlling</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Barbara Kux, Head of Supply Chain Management</participant>
      <participant id="4">Mariel von Drathen</participant>
      <participant id="5">Peter L&#xF6;scher</participant>
      <participant id="6">Barbara Kux</participant>
      <participant id="7">Joe Kaeser</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Good morning and good afternoon to those watching our webcast. I'm Mariel von Drathen, Head of Investor Relations, and it is my pleasure to welcome you this afternoon to our Second Quarter 2009 Results.</p>
          <p>The earnings release, the flashlight, and other documents were published this morning at 7:30, and they can be downloaded from our IR webpage. This afternoon's presentation is available on our website and is being webcast.</p>
          <p>I would also refer to the Safe Harbor statement on Slide #2. Our President and CEO Peter L&#xF6;scher and our Chief Financial Officer, Joe Kaeser are here this afternoon to present Q2 results. They are joined by Barbara Kux, Member of the Managing Board, who will review the supply chain initiative with you. After the presentation, we will have time for Q&amp;A where Joe, Barbara, and Peter will answer your questions.</p>
          <p>So with that, I would like to hand it over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mariel. Good afternoon to everybody. Welcome to everybody around the world. I will quickly start with providing you with the highlights of the quarter, and Joe will then give you a detailed update on the financials as well as the SG&amp;A program. And Barbara will then reveal her long-awaited supply chain initiative and the key elements of it.</p>
          <p>Let me start giving you some of the highlights. I said this morning at the press conference, the crisis has arrived at Siemens, but Siemens is not in the crisis. I think we are handling, particularly relative to the performance of a number of our competitors, the crisis at this point in time better. We have also improved significantly since we have announced to all of you the TAP program roughly 18 months ago.</p>
          <p>We have focused our portfolio. I think we now see the strength of the three sector organizations in terms of having the balance between short-cycle and long-cycle business. We have proactively sharpened our portfolio approach. In this quarter, the most recent example is we have completed the sale of our stake in Fujitsu Siemens Computers, which is just one of example of our proactive approach towards it.</p>
          <p>We have also streamlined and empowered new management teams. We have set rigorous performance goal. And I'm very pleased to share with you today that we are making an extremely good progress on our announced SG&amp;A program. The SG&amp;A expenses are significantly lower compared to prior quarter.</p>
          <p>So we have moved with an increased transparency with accountability and also with having now two clean quarters with performance. But there is no doubt that the challenges are real and the current economic crisis has also an impact on our portfolio particularly in the short cycle businesses in industrial, like Industry Automation, Drive Technology and like Osram. I will cover them in a minute.</p>
          <p>Overall our results show strong relative performance in the quarter with an excellent contribution from the Energy sector. And I think quite an impressive performance from the Healthcare sector, bearing in mind that the current economic environment for the Healthcare sector in the United States is as challenging as it probably has been for a long time.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet remains one of the best in this sector. We have remained our high investment grade credit rating. We continue to focus on lowering our cost base and increasing our flexibility. We have already aligned our German workforce to the new demand levels, and we are particularly rapidly deploying the short work week concept in our German factories. We are increasing the immediate fixed cost flexibility, while we also allow our skilled workforce to be ready when the economy will recover.</p>
          <p>The SG&amp;A program with a run rate of &#x20AC;1 billion has already delivered concrete results in the second quarter, and it's fully on track to meet our targets for 2010. And I particularly believe that in today's environment there is nothing wrong with overachieving some of our targets, and we definitely expect this for the SG&amp;A program.</p>
          <p>Let me quickly run through some of the financial highlights of the quarter. Our backlog is at an impressive level and continues to grow with no material cancellations and a few push-outs, which validates our conservative booking process. Our book-to-bill in the second quarter remained at 1.1 robust, which is impressive given the economic backdrop. And back of our backlog, revenue growth was 5% and total sector profit was with 1.844 billion, quite a good achievement.</p>
          <p>Orders tracked largely as we expected, sequentially down 6% compared with Q1. Of particular note was the excellent order development in mobility, where we have booked this quarter a major order in China for components of 100 high-speed trains, and renewables, where we also booked three very important customer orders.</p>
          <p>Cash flow at the sector level was at 1.9 billion in the quarter, essentially flat from last year but significantly higher than Q1, and as a result of continued strict networking capital management.</p>
          <p>Excellent execution against the backlog growth revenue performance in the quarter, and this despite the headwinds which the different sectors are facing right now.</p>
          <p>From a geographic perspective, in emerging markets like China and Brazil, which the Management Board has visited last week, Siemens is exceptionally positioned and received more orders than in the second quarter of last year. I have already mentioned the major order what we have received in transportation.</p>
          <p>And as I already mentioned we had significant order wins in Renewables and Mobility, and as expected these wins were more than offset by market fall in orders in Industry Automation, Drive Technology, and Osram. The remaining divisions in Industry and Energy sectors also had weaker order intake. For the Healthcare, organic growth in orders and revenue, as I mentioned, was impressive given the challenging Healthcare environment what we see in the United States.</p>
          <p>It's important to highlight that our backlog on the left-hand side, as you can see, has increased by 2 billion and stands now at the record level of 87 billion, which gives us good visibility as we go into the second half of the year and beyond. We expect roughly 23 billion of our backlog to be converted into revenue in the second half of fiscal '09, and overall the energy sector accounts for the lion's share of this backlog, accounting for about 48 billion. The Mobility division and to a lesser extent Industry Solutions accounts for a backlog of 32 billion within the Industry sector.</p>
          <p>The solid foundation provided by our backlog is further strengthened by the growing installed customer base across Siemens. It's worth noting that some 20% of the world's installed power generation fleet carries a Siemens label, and this drives the Energy sector's growing service business, our increase in service revenues improving our resiliency in a downturn. And this is further supported by our recurring revenue businesses such as the Industry sector, PLM software businesses, or the Healthcare sector's, IT business.</p>
          <p>Let's now take a look at the performance at the sector-by-sector level. Starting with Industry, as expected overall revenues were down 6% with new orders down 12. The market continues to be weak, and the channel has continued destocking. This has put sector margins under pressure in Q2. As I mentioned before, we took early and decisive action at the Industry Automation, Drive Technology, and Osram. Even the inventories are down as production levels have been reduced.</p>
          <p>We have reduced discretionary spending and we have increased labor flexibility in Germany and, as I mentioned before, we have particularly expanded the short time work week. We are currently standing at 12,000 employees in Germany, going to roughly 19 by June this year. The particular focus is on the Industry segment. So if you compare as a base phase where the majority is actually the production environment in Industry, the 12 compares to roughly 25% of our industrial labor force in Industry going to almost 40% by end of Q3.</p>
          <p>As you know, Osram is restructuring, and you will see those charges in the third and fourth quarters. In Building Technologies, revenue remained largely stable, but orders softened as anticipated given the slowdown in commercial construction, which will impact revenue in later quarters. Industry Solution is seeing the effect of weakening metals market in its orders, but the revenue still remains stable.</p>
          <p>Mobility is on track, actually ahead of track, with continued strong execution in the quarter. The order book and the backlog have never been better in this division. Recently, we have also completed our second review in terms of looking into the broader quality of this business, and we are extremely happy to report the margin perspective of this business has improved significantly versus a year ago.</p>
          <p>Moving to the Energy sector, where performance was very strong, the book-to-bill remained robust in the quarter at 1.3. Strong execution helped revenues to increase at 28% year-on-year, and all divisions remained in the target ranges with all project issues fully resolved what we have shared with you last year. As a result, the underlying margin increased to 12.9% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>New orders were lower, but this is set against the record quarter in the prior year, making particularly the comparable for this quarter challenging. It is again worth noting that at the end of the quarter, the Energy sector's backlog increased to 48 billion. Again we have no material order cancellations. The Energy sector also booked a significant order in the quarter from Iraq for power generation and transmission worth approximately &#x20AC;1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Renewables continues to see high activity levels with revenue increasing by 88%. They won two major long-term high-margin orders in the quarter. In Denmark we won a very significant order with DONG Energy to supply 500 offshore turbines with 1,800 megawatts. And in England, we secured a major contract for the Sheringham Shoal Offshore Wind Farm from StatoilHydro and Statkraft to provide 88 wind turbines, 350 megawatt with a contract volume of more than &#x20AC;450 million. As a result, total order growth was 75% year-on-year, and margins increased to 13.1%. The Oil and Gas division increased profits to 121 million in the quarter, although the pace of new orders slowed.</p>
          <p>Turning to Power Transmission, revenue solidly increased in the quarter by 21% to &#x20AC;168 million, while new orders fell by 19% and Power Distribution's performance mirrored Transmission for the quarter. Revenue rose by 23% to 106 million with a margin of 12.5%.</p>
          <p>And finally turning to Healthcare, the overall situation continues to evolve. While Healthcare demand remains a constant, the funding situation particularly in the United States is under increased pressure. And in this environment our Healthcare sector performed solidly with a 4% increase in revenues.</p>
          <p>Global equipment sales eased slightly, but our Imaging &amp; IT business delivered a strong performance relative to peers and throughout the overall sector performance in the quarter. It's for the first time that our Healthcare business is growth leader, volume leader, and margin leader in healthcare. We are the number one healthcare business for the first time in Q2, surpassing our major competitor of the United States. Although the U.S. equipment market continues to be weak, growth elsewhere helped us to offset this.</p>
          <p>The Healthcare sector also continues to grow its high-margin service revenue streams. Additional resilience comes from the consumable business in diagnostics and IT software licenses, which helps to offset the challenges in the equipment market. In Diagnostics, orders and revenues were level with the prior year. Margins for the quarter were impacted mainly due to product launch costs, which will be launched in Q3.</p>
          <p>Overall Healthcare's underlying margin fell in the quarter to 40%, driven by negative foreign exchange effects, although this was somewhat mitigated by the strong cost management focus.</p>
          <p>That was a brief review of the quarter, and in a few moments I will come back with details on how we expect the rest of the year to unfold. And now over to you, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much, Peter. Very warm welcome also from my side to discuss the results and the valuation of our Q2 numbers. Let me first start with the key performance indicators for our Fit4 2010 program. With the upper left side, which is growth, you all know that we actually have committed to grow 2X GDP going forward, which probably needs some explanations on how we will be intending to achieve that with pluses and negative. So our commitment is that we will only have to suffer from half of the deterioration of the global GDP. So that's the translation in times when GDP is negative. And that, ladies and gentlemen, we believe is quite a challenge because of this cyclicity and the nature of our businesses.</p>
          <p>Profitability for the sectors shows that Energy has been solidly &#x2013; was in the target margins of 11 to 15%. We would not expect this one to deteriorate in the foreseeable future. Healthcare, we believe provided a solid profitability given the environment we see, particularly in some regions. And if we compare the underlying margin of Healthcare, which obviously excludes the PPA impact, then we are at 14%, which is the lower end also of the target margin. Industry certainly will continue to have its challenges in profitability, and I think we all agree that we have not seen the bottom in that particular sector.</p>
          <p>On our cash conversion, we believe the organization has done a decent job in fiscal Q2. There was something to catch up for out of Q1. And you remember we said that we would not be particularly satisfied with the Q1 performance on asset management, that has changed. And I'll come to later in my presentation.</p>
          <p>The cash conversion rate of 1.19 is a solid cash conversion given the fact that we also still have a significant number of cash outflow from the charges we have been taking during fiscal 2008. And the fact that the cash conversion rate deteriorates from 2.87 to 1.19 is obviously due to the fact that we had a significant number of charges in Q2 2008, which at that time were non-cash item and will lead to cash out over the following quarters.</p>
          <p>Now in the capital efficiency, which is ROCE, in our case we significantly increased the ROCE numbers predominantly through the growth in profits across most of the divisions. And that one also we believe will go up also in the next couple of quarters.</p>
          <p>Now let me come to the third part of our key performance indicators from the Fit4 2010 indicators, and that basically is the capital structure. Capital structure we defined as net debt over EBITDA. And we did adjust the net debt number to our so-called adjusted industrial net debt. And I'll come to that in a minute. This one we basically and, I have to admit, unintentionally overachieved with 1.12, and I quickly show you the reason how come.</p>
          <p>If you just follow me now in the third column from the left, you see the 14.2 billion. That's our reported net debt in Q1 2009, and that number of 14.2 basically increased by 700 million in Q2 to 14.9. And that's the column, fifth one, the sixth one from the right, of 14.9. So the permanent impacts from that development, you see, came from key financing activities mostly through the dividend payment of 1.4 billion, and also of course currency impact stemming from the fact that, as you know, we also do have very, a significant amount of U.S. dollar- based bonds out in the market.</p>
          <p>If you now translate the 14.9 reported net debt from Q2 into the so-called industrial adjusted net debt, then you see that obviously a major impact has come from the underfunding of the pension plan, which is 5.3 on the deficit and 0.6 negative on the OPEB, and then some other minor topics and of course also to adjust the Siemens Financial Services net debt to financial standards. So basically what we do here is we follow the formula rating agencies are also applying. And so we arrive at 10.6 billion adjusted industrial net debt, and that translates to 1.12 net debt over EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Obviously it's pretty hard to tell how the pension funding will develop over time due to the volatility in the equity market. We believe we have done the right things, especially due to the fact that we also have replaced the majority of government bonds in favor of A-rated bonds from corporations. So we believe that this is the right thing going forward.</p>
          <p>To give you maybe some more light on the pension deficit and how that transforms, this is the next page what you see here. We have some information here on assets that are DBO. You also see that the discount rate has come down significantly compared to 2008, and it's been going up a little bit as regard to Q2. So I think the slide itself is a self-explanatory. And it remains to be seen whether the low point of equity in March will recover sustainably going forward.</p>
          <p>Now let me maybe come to the next one and that's cash conversion. We did significantly improve our quarter-on-quarter performance in free cash flow. And we also would expect cash inflow to continue not necessarily in Q3, which is usually a somewhat difficult quarter. But we also will see cash inflow coming from outside free cash flow items, for example, from the sale of real estate, as well as the proceeds from our divestiture from Siemens Fujitsu, which has closed April 1, 2009.</p>
          <p>Major differences between the reported income from continued operations on the right-hand side of the slide as compared to free cash flow in Q2 2009 obviously are the CapEx, which are 654 million, the amortization depreciation of plus 709. And the networking capital still accounts for about 165 million as a comparison to the reported income.</p>
          <p>Now, ladies and gentlemen, I do know that there have been time and again some concerns on how companies will be doing in terms of liquidity. You can be rest assured we have a very clear focus on cash and liquidity. You'll see we have about 11.2 billion free liquidity. We have a very strong cash position at 7.7 billion, about &#x20AC;6.5 billion, which translates to about $8 billion, on undrawn credit facility at what I believe are attractive merchants. So there is headroom here in order to cover whatever comes as negative and as adverse impacts going forward.</p>
          <p>One element to achieve cash focus and of course also liquidity are two items. First is a very stringent management of the CapEx, and you know that for many, many quarters now we have put a special emphasis on that topic. And the other one obviously is also how to manage a networking capital in an efficient manner.</p>
          <p>On the working capital turns, we had some setback in fiscal Q1, which was not exactly satisfactory. We've been changing course again. We improved our networking capital turns from 7.8 to 8.2 quarter-on-quarter, and that was predominantly queued to the accounts receivables. And accounts receivables, as you know, have gone up for quite a period of time. We've put a lot of emphasis on managing those accounts receivables in both ways &#x2013; bring the outstanding number down, and secondly also make sure that the quality in terms of overdues remain intact and make sure that we collect the money as we have invoiced. There is still way to go in the inventory piece where we cannot yet be satisfied with the development of the turns, and that certainly will be a particularly focus going forward.</p>
          <p>On the CapEx spending, I think the right-hand side on the slide pretty much shows on how tightly we have been managing CapEx. We mentioned earlier that we have basically released about 50% of the budget. And with our performance here, you'll see that currently we are about just 88% CapEx of depreciation. So the current forecast will probably get us in the neighborhood of the lower end of our target margins, which we has installed between 95 and 150%. So tight capital is definitely something we have a very clear focus on. And if you compare the order growth with the CapEX rate, you clearly see how quickly the company has been acting on those matters.</p>
          <p>Now obviously I do realize that there has been a lot of questions and sometimes even concerns about Treasury Siemens Financial Services in light of the financial crisis and, let's say, other enterprises' deterioration of profitability in those aspects. Here is a description on how we manage money in Siemens in Treasury, and I'll come to <mark type="inaudible" /> in a little while.</p>
          <p>First of all the Treasury management in Siemens is very successful. We have actually managed to have a profit of 125 million in fiscal Q2 2009. Treasury in Siemens is predominantly risk-based, but obviously also increasingly a P&amp;L-driven aspect. You see here how we manage bonds, how we do the financial business, and how we also manage the operating Treasury business. Those are the key terms and the fundamental rules on how Siemens manages Treasury. I think it's pretty much self-explanatory. So if there are any questions, I'd be happy to go into more detail.</p>
          <p>But I would rather now prefer to continue on to Siemens Financial Services, which is on the next page. On the upper left you see that, as I said, contrary to many other <mark type="inaudible" /> very, very well. We are at record quarters. That's true for IBIT as well as for return on equity. Not suggesting that the 39.8% of return on equity or the 117 IBIT is, let's say, the starting point for further forecast. That certainly had also a couple of favorable items in it. But the key message here, ladies and gentlemen, we do have a stable business.</p>
          <p>So why is that? Basically it's the case because Siemens Financial Services has to follow very, very strict rules on how that division is doing business, and a subset of those rules is now displayed here on the lower left of the slide. First of all, SFS continues on areas where we do have the main know how. The main know how means that we do have know-how in those industrial sectors Siemens is also doing business in like energy, like industry, and of course to a material extent in healthcare. And that's what SFS is going to focus on. This is our home turf. This is where we understand the business and where we do understand the value of quality of our customers. We do when/run the financing, and we do have the ability to make very deliberate make-or-buy decisions, and we do it in our own balance sheet.</p>
          <p> The only you hold to maturity investing. There is no credit rating. There is no &#x2013; no &#x2013; loan maturity mismatch, not a single one. That's a very iron rule and very, very keen on focusing on. And we are obviously not invested in neither real estate nor subprime mortgage nor consumer lending, and certainly not in structured credit products. The right-hand side on the slide gives you an overview on what the exposure is by product and also on how we have invested and put our money to work by country.</p>
          <p>So we have SFS, and I will make that very clear again. We do have SFS to provide financial know-how, provide financial platforms, provide domain competency on financial management, and also of course provide economical scale for Treasury, as well as for Financial Services to support the industrial business of the company.</p>
          <p>That much to Treasury and Siemens Financial Services, let me now give you an update on how we are doing on our SG&amp;A program, which is the next slide. As you have heard already from Peter, the good news is we've made very good progress &#x2013; very good progress &#x2013; already in Q2. And best probably is that it all just shows in the numbers in the P&amp;L. if you look at our financial statements, which we have distributed this morning together with the earnings release, you'll see that the Q2 numbers of SG&amp;A came down from 3.243 billion in 2008 to 2.520 in 2009. And the year-to-date number has been come down from 6.3 billion year-to-date 2008 to 5.4 billion in 2009. So it works, it shows, and we continue to have our focus on SG&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Maybe the not-so-good news is that it would be a little premature to just multiply the 5.4 billion by two and then arrive at a number, which would be considered a forecast for 2009, reason being that there are a few favorable one-offs in the Q2 numbers, which may not return again in Q3 and Q4. But it can be rest assured that the direction remains in place. And as Peter already said, there is nothing wrong with exceeding margins. There's certainly a lot wrong in not meeting the targets at all.</p>
          <p>So that much to the SG&amp;A. If we want to take a closer look into, let's say, the key drivers on those topics, you'll see that in terms of the consultancy cost. And please mind the footnote here. It's important in terms of how it splits between SG&amp;A-related consultancy cost and cost of goods sold.</p>
          <p>So we've come over a 600-million starting point over 217 in 2008. We arrived at 210 million consulting cost in the first half, and those 210 are supposed to arrive at 380 for the course of fiscal year 2008. IT costs also have come down from 1.3 billion in 2007, 2008 run rate, now down at 500. And here I think it's fair to just multiply them by two to arrive at the ballpark number for IT of about a billion for the fiscal year 2009.</p>
          <p>Now complexity drivers such as legal entities and number of reporting units you'll see, we working our way through here. They may not necessarily drive down the cost directly, but they certainly are an enabler to get complicity out of the system and make sure that we identify additional potential for G&amp;A savings as we go along.</p>
          <p>While we have not materially reduced the workforce in production in the reported head count numbers nor in R&amp;D because we still do believe innovation is a key element for sustainable competitiveness going forward, the SG&amp;A number of head count has come down 9% in marketing and selling, and 12% in G&amp;A. So you can see it also was there. I still want to make sure this is a cost-efficiency program, not necessarily a head count reduction program, but the improvement of our competitiveness initiative shows in all the different aspects of cost efficiency.</p>
          <p>Now if we have look at the sector achievements so far, you can see that we are very much on track in the three big sectors. The corporation and other operation performance, I think this has to reasonably well. And it's not going to go back, so this is an achieved level.</p>
          <p>And here you can clearly see that the cleanup of the other operation had a significant positive impact also in SG&amp;A. So we're working our way through, and we continue to be very close to the numbers and make sure that we make good on our promises as the SG&amp;A is concerned.</p>
          <p>There is some delay on the so-called cost sector divisions, which is predominantly SIS, reason being that SIS had to benchmark itself and its IT deliveries into the sectors. And this has been achieved now. The IT costs, as you have seen also in the IT cost slide here, have been lower by 20%. So SIS needs to make sure that it works at benchmark levels also to support the sectors. And now the next goal will be to catch up in the SG&amp;A area.</p>
          <p>So that much, ladies and gentlemen, to the update on later drivers of SG&amp;A and also on financials, predominantly liquidity and debt. So that concludes my presentation, and I hand it over to Barbara. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Joe. And a very warm welcome to all of you. As many of you may know, I've spent many years in the supply chain area. It's really an exciting place to be, and from what I have read recently it appears that you are as excited as I am.</p>
          <p>Since joining Siemens, I visited many sites and many suppliers to develop plans to make Siemens a world leader in supply chain management. There is a tremendous energy in the company around this topic and the opportunity we have. We are aiming to deliver solid results to Siemens performance, both in the short term and sustainably going forward.</p>
          <p>Today I will tell you how far we have come and where we are focusing our activities. Let's start with some facts. Siemens is one of the largest industrial purchasers in the world. In fiscal 2008, Siemens purchased materials, services, and finished goods worth about 50% of our total revenue. This corresponds to a total external spend of about 40 billion last year.</p>
          <p>The savings opportunities for Siemens broadly reflect the split in external spend. 53% of spend is direct material at the sector level, with the remainder split between pooled direct material and indirect material spend. These are big numbers. And reducing material costs is obviously a significant part of the supply chain initiative.</p>
          <p>It is also equally important to manage supply risks during the downturn. Now is the perfect time for Siemens to optimize its supply chain. Raw material costs are down. Suppliers with spare capacity are listening a lot more intently to us. At the same time the value of Siemens as a partner has never been higher. We have the brand, the scale, and the stability that suppliers want.</p>
          <p>So what we are driving towards is a structural change in supply chain management within Siemens, not just a short-term initiative. The initial phase is to optimize our supply base. Then we will focus on our strategic suppliers, those who combine competitive pricing with excellent quality and ongoing innovation. If executed well, this will improve Siemens' performance permanently with a significant financial impact.</p>
          <p>In short, this is a game-changing effort. Our targets are ambitious. The savings potential is real. We will be world-class. We are in an active dialogue with our customers and suppliers today. And Siemens will be at world-class levels at the end of 2010.</p>
          <p>We hit the ground running in January and the pace is accelerating. The structure, responsibilities, and targets for the supply chain initiative are embraced at the sector level, in the divisions and regions. The whole company is fully engaged. In just three month, we've achieved a lot. We've renegotiated terms and pricing with about 1,000 of our suppliers. We've already reviewed and redesigned our approach to indirect spend. We've already increased pooled spending &#x2013; that's the dollar spend or the euro spend &#x2013; at the total Siemens level.</p>
          <p>In addition, we've held over 30 workshops with more than 300 suppliers and reviewed the relevant categories for spend, ranging from temporary labor to iron costing.</p>
          <p>In total, more than 1,000 measures have been identified to further optimize our supply chain. No stone will go unturned. For example, one obvious area that will become increasingly important is the role of technology. Other measures include increased standardization and less complex specification or less over-engineered products.</p>
          <p>There is also significant complexity in the large number of suppliers we have &#x2013; over 100,000 to date. And optimizing the existing supplier base is the first step of our program. Many suppliers are only used on an occasional basis, adding costs and limiting the potential for cross-sector purchasing. In essence it's all about bundling, leveraging the buying power of Siemens, and concentration &#x2013; focusing on those select suppliers who add the most value and deliver the optimum total cost of ownership to Siemens.</p>
          <p>We have made good progress so far and are on track with all our short-term initiatives. The longer-term strategic roadmap is progressing well, and we will update you on this as things develop. Going forward, we have defined clear metrics to measure the impact of the program.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, leveraging the purchasing power across the sectors is a key lever to increase cost savings. Today just 29% of total purchasing volume is managed at the Siemens level. Our target is to increase our pooled volume by 60% in 2010. This means about &#x20AC;19 billion of spend will be driven through cross-sector purchasing by the end of next year. One of the key differentiators of our program is global value sourcing. This goes way beyond basic pricing and low-cost country sourcing, but includes co-development and product innovation with our key suppliers. Our target here is to increase our share of global value sourcing from 20% in 2008 to at least 25% mid-term.</p>
          <p>Global value sourcing is about creating long-term strategic value for Siemens, so developing the most competitive network of suppliers. This will enable us to leverage technology from our suppliers and to accelerate innovation at the right price. Our goal is clear. We will establish Siemens as a global leader in supply chain management. Our supplier reduction program will prepare the way for this. In the mid-term, we are planning to cut the number of suppliers from over 100,000 by 20%.</p>
          <p>In summary, we will substantially increase the value that supply chain management delivers to Siemens. It is obvious that I love supply chain management. It is exciting, it is real-world, and it delivers. I look forward to updating all of you on our progress, the deliverables we achieve, and how it is impacting our overall performance.</p>
          <p>And now let me hand back to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Barbara. Let me sum up, and how do we manage and plan for the remainder of 2009. Our second quarter performance showed the underlying strength of our Siemens businesses. Our shorter-cycle businesses have felt the economic slowdown most acutely, and other divisions will feel these effects in quarters to come. Other divisions which benefit from fundamentally longer-cycle trends like Transportation, Energy, and Healthcare are doing relatively well.</p>
          <p>We as a leadership team are intensely focus on improving the operational efficiencies across Siemens. We have improved our conversion into profit and cash flow from the last quarter, Q1. As Joe has shown, we have a powerful balance sheet and a conservative financing structure. Siemens is ready and prepared to deliver solid performance also in this very tough times.</p>
          <p>As I said in my opening remarks, the global economy is probably experiencing one of the most turbulent periods it has seen in the decades. The current macro and financing environment show no signs of near-term improvement, and it's our view that we are still some way off from a real economic recovery.</p>
          <p>I know you are all very familiar with the various macroeconomic indicators, but let me make two observations that are pertinent to Siemens. First, the world has changed since July 2008, when we have set our guidance. Then the GDP forecast for 2009 was plus 2.9%. Today we're talking about minus 5%, and no one could have imagined over nine months a 5-percentage point decline in global GDP forecasts. And the vast majority of our indicators remain negative, implying a continued contraction in the real economy for some time to come.</p>
          <p>Today out of Germany we have received the latest forecast by the government, being planned for minus 6% for 2009. If we look at the VDMA data, the Machine Tool Manufacturers Association's data for Germany, which is a critical data point for Siemens, you can see that orders fell 49% year-on-year in February. And this was after a 40% fall in January. The latest number for March are pointing towards 39%. This survey covers the middelstand, our core customer base in Germany and correlates with what we have experienced in the quarter.</p>
          <p>It's in this context that I'd like to now to turn outlook for Siemens for the year of 2009. When we have set our 2009 guidance last summer, the environment then looked dramatically different to the one we are facing today. Indeed some of you thought actually at that time Siemens is going for a very conservative number. But we have performed well overall in the first half of the year, arguably better than a number of our competitors, and fought hard for every dollar out there.</p>
          <p>We are also very realistic about what is ahead of us. And as you know, the indicators what are still currently in front of us are indicating that we have not yet seen the bottom of the global economy. We have therefore decided to share with you that every year &#x2013; every quarter we would continuously review our assumptions which are underlying our plans.</p>
          <p>For this reason we have decided against the backdrop of the current economic environment to deliver a sector profit exceeding our last year number of 6.6 billion. And I can assure you that the Siemens organization and their totally leadership is fully committed to achieve this.</p>
          <p>For the second half of the year, we expect the Industry sector, with the exception of Mobility, to continue facing headwinds from the slowdown. The Healthcare sector despite a very challenging U.S. market environment will continue to drive an overall solid performance, as we saw in the last two quarters. And finally, the Energy sector will continue to drive strong revenue performance, although we continue to expect a slowdown in product orders and further customer deferrals through the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>We are driving the business hard. We have a key strategy and a relentless focus on optimizing the business and reducing our cost base. You can clearly see what we are making progress. When we look at the execution of our SG&amp;A program just being one example, we have had a good start with the supply chain initiative, and we are fully committed to delivering the forecast of 6-point &#x2013; exceeding 6.6 billion operating profit at sector level for 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With this, thank you, Peter. With this we would start our Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And let me start here, the front with Peter. And I will continue with Mark over there and Colin here in the second row. So we start with Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. It's Peter Reilly from Deutsche Bank. Three questions please. Firstly, on Industry Automation, orders are down or rather revenues are down 19%. You've highlighted the very weak data from the VDMA. The cost reduction measures you're putting in place all so seen very temporary in terms of short-term working. And we're coming off a very high boom last year. Does that imply that you think we're going to back to a strong recovery in sort of the next few years? Or are you considering further measures on the basis that maybe the boom is unrepeatable, and you have to resize the business down to a structurally lower level of activity?</p>
          <p>Secondly on supply chain, I know you don't want to give us any numbers about the scope of the savings. But the thing I thought was missing today is you haven't really given us any flavor of what you think Siemens is like, how far of world-class Siemens is. I know you <mark type="inaudible" /> about Siemens in your new position. Can you give us some feel for what you found versus where you think it should be in terms of world-class?</p>
          <p>And then lastly on Diagnostics, the margin I think was quite disappointing on an underlying basis. If I recall rightly, the margin always for Diagnostics were on a post PPA amortization basis. Are they now unobtainable? Are you now moving to margin targets that are clean? So you can just let us know what's happening with your outlook on the Diagnostics margin please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You start, Barbara, and then over to you, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. What can I say? I think Siemens has a good practice of supply chain management in the businesses and in the divisions and in the sectors. But so far we haven't really tapped the opportunities to look at this topic from an overall perspective, from an overall Siemens perspective. Therefore there are opportunities. Yes, they are substantial, and they are exactly in the areas that I have mentioned to increase the pooling. And let me give you some examples. We buy 1.3 million tons of steel. We do that now on the Siemens level. We didn't use to that. We are one of the largest leaser of fleets, 40,000 units. So also to do these kind of things on a total company level does make a difference.</p>
          <p>Secondly, of course as I mentioned, the reduction of the supply base, we cannot go into the future with that many suppliers. We need to focus on the strategic ones, and we also need bundle more.</p>
          <p>And thirdly the global value sourcing. So these 65, 25, 20 target that I have mentioned, Peter, are clearly the opportunities that we have, together with the sectors and the teams identified, and that we are in the process to realize at this moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me then take, Peter, the Diagnostics piece first. Fiscal Q2 definitely has been disappointing at face value. The underlying margin is about 13.7%, ex-PPA integration. So that's way out of the corridor, which we have said. This has been predominantly due to the fact that we had some new product introductions and also some write-offs of accounts receivables. So that actually should not be continued in the quarters to come. So at this point in time, there is no reason for the division not to be back in the target margin range in Q3. And that's been a clear commitment also by the division, so new product introduction and some write-offs of bad debt.</p>
          <p>Now on the Industrial Automation, clearly the current margin is way off from the peak levels which we have seen not too far ago. And it remains to be seen on how long it will take us till we are going to be through, let's say, trough quarters. There is no reason to believe that this is going to recover anytime soon, so we are more into a, I'd probably would call it, a bathtub shape rather than a V shape if anyone asks me about what shape I would be seeing there.</p>
          <p>The fact however that we are not structurally going into resource cuts is that we have learned from the last downturn that we must not miss the upturn. We must not miss the upturn. Currently more than $0.60 on the euro are fixed cost of some sort. Some are to be tackled quicker; others take time because their depreciation, as you notice, is pretty hard to do.</p>
          <p>So our working hypothesis right now is that we do see a slowdown of this slow energy cycle in the first half of our fiscal 2010 &#x2013; slowdown in order robustness, not suggesting on revenues &#x2013; and that in the second half of fiscal 2010, there will be a rebound of the short-cycle industry business such as Industrial Automation. So the target ranges which we are currently experiencing may accompany us for awhile. And we do believe that there is significant upside if and when the end markets are coming back and the distribution channel will be stocking inventories again. So that's the current view we take on Industrial automation and the short-cycle businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just come back on Diagnostics? I think initially you were saying, if I'm correct, that the margin is supposed to be post all PPA expenses to get inside the target range. You're now saying that you can only get into the target range with a clean margin if you strip out the PPA amortization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I was saying is that the target margin of 16 to 19% on Diagnostics, that's before PPA, definitely. And the comparable number in Q2 was 13.7%. And we do expect that the ratio to rebound in Q3 into the target margin range might not be the upper range, but certainly within the range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we'll continue with Mark in the last row.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Mark Troman, Merrill Lynch. Again three questions, please. Just extending the theme of Industrial Automation and the short-cycle businesses, I guess, putting Osram in there too. You mentioned VDMA, I think their CEO was quoted saying, look, Q1 was very bad, but there are signs of stabilization; i.e., things aren't deteriorating at the same rate going into Q2. I wonder if you could comment on the short-cycle trends though Q1 January/February/March, and whether do you think Q2 can indeed deliver sort of stable performance on Q1, or should we expect further absolute deterioration?</p>
          <p>Second question on the longer-cycle businesses, are you seeing any change in behavior from utilities either positively or negatively? I guess we see better financing conditions for the utilities themselves, which perhaps makes people more comfortable about the backlogs. I wondered what the propensity for utilities to, let's say, put through tenders. Does that look better than it did or not?</p>
          <p>And finally cash flow, Joe, I wonder if you could comment on what you think, whether you think the cash flow performance in the second half can be significantly improved, if indeed we continue to see year-on-year declines in the short-cycle businesses. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, let me start with the utilities. What we don't see is any move in terms of in our current order backlog. But what we certainly see is the propensity to delay or look into opportunities to look at time scales of new projects, which are currently in the funnel. So the funnel is actually to convince customers to zero in. And closing orders in our funnel is certainly more challenging than we have seen in the past, also from the utilities.</p>
          <p>There are some areas where the utilities are actually upside for us. And if you look into wind for example, wind today. The only business which is left, which is a serious business, is actually wind parts, which are owned by utilities either 100% or in partnership with other partners. And that's for us &#x2013; I'm talking about the offshore wind environment. And the two example are just two of them which we have closed in this quarter, and we have several others which we are currently negotiating. So overall I would say getting new orders is more difficult also out of utilities, but we don't see yet the propensity in terms of renegotiating the current order backlog, what we have with them. And, Joe, it's over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, Peter. Hi, Mark. Let me maybe start with the free cash flow development in the second half. Our plan is calling for a positive free cash flow for the whole fiscal 2009. So since we are at currently minus 436, we expect positive free cash flow in the second half of fiscal 2009.</p>
          <p>The big unknown which we are very, very focused on trying to understand the implications &#x2013; or really the implications are clear, but the triggering points &#x2013; is is there going to be a material deterioration of the customers' prepayment if and when the long-cycle businesses come down? And how much would that be? Since early 2007, we have seen a continued increase of our customers' prepayments as compared to development of the order intake.</p>
          <p>So that is a big unknown, and I would feel to be not prudent to speculate about that. But we certainly have been taking actions in terms of financial flexibility and liquidity to make sure if they came quickly, that we would be well prepared. Now that certainly remains a big unknown.</p>
          <p>On working capital, we definitely have a massive focus on it, especially on inventories where we still do believe we can do better. And that will have a material potential to release liquidity and free cash flow. But the customer prepayment impact means that billings exist versus the speed we can adapt our working capital levels to a lower order intake. That certainly is a challenge because it usually takes three to five quarters till working capital is at the level which adequately reflects a different order intake scenario.</p>
          <p>But that's a big unknown and <mark type="inaudible" /> speculation to pick any number here. But we do know this is coming at some point, and we make preparations that this would not pose any liquidity crunch of some sort. And everything else, as I said, we'll take from there. But generally, positive free cash flow is certainly the goal for 2009.</p>
          <p>Remember, we do have significant cash outflow from charges we had been taking in 2008. So the total number expected as cash outflow from the charges 2008 and prior years is 2.5 billion. And out of the 2.5 billion, we currently have about 1.5 already in the free cash flow of the first half of 2009. That's 1.2 in Q1, and it's another 350 &#x2013; it's in the handout &#x2013; in Q2.</p>
          <p>So Industrial Automation, I think short-cycle has that been covered?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the short-cycle trends you saw in Q1 perhaps through the months and whether there are not recovery, but signs of stabilization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think recovery is asking for too much, and I think we can all agree to that one. We expect the speed of deterioration to slow down in Industrial Automation on the top line and obviously then also in the bottom line.</p>
          <p>In terms of Osram, we probably have a few quarters which are going to be challenging in the neighborhood of just about breakeven. They are acting well. They've shed about 4,000 jobs relatively quickly. But they also have been caught into a fixed-cost production factory environment such as for example of the semiconductors.</p>
          <p>Now there is some hope I think from comment from others that the semiconductor cycle will recover sooner than most others &#x2013; remains to be seen. So Osram's certainly something which needs more focus of restructuring also in factories. This is actually what Peter already said, trying for Q3 and 4 in fiscal 2009.</p>
          <p>Now the speed of deterioration certainly would accelerate at Drive Technology. This is usually a one-to-two-quarter delay from Industrial Automation, and this is also something we obviously have a very close look at it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's continue with Colin in second row. <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Three questions, please. First of all, given the group's reliance on <mark type="inaudible" /> schemes, can you give us something approaching a schedule as to how quickly people start to come off those schemes again? So for example between now and the end of your fiscal year, how many people would be coming off <mark type="inaudible" /> schemes? And in the first half of the next fiscal year, how many people would be coming off <mark type="inaudible" /> schemes? That was question number one.</p>
          <p>Questing number two, which is to Barbara again, and of course I'm trying to do the same thing that Peter just did, which is try to get you to comment on something you probably don't want to comment on. In terms of targets, you've clearly given us some quantitative targets, but not any indication of savings potential. So let me ask the question this way. Your success at your former employer, Philips, was quite well documented. Do you see similar scale for potential at Siemens versus Philips? And also I see in the calendar at the end of this presentation, we're down for an update on SCM in December. Would you be presenting savings target at that stage?</p>
          <p>And then last question, a straightforward one for Joe just on restructuring and charges and tax charges. Certainly versus my expectation, these have come in below what I was looking for in the first half of the year, which is nice. Will I be similarly positively surprised in the second half of the year? Or do you think restructuring charges or tax charges will go up in the second half of the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Calling you five-star in this movie, if I may, Barbara. She doesn't see any similarities, and there will be no targets. Guys, I mean, it's very easy. We are in testy times. And as soon as we would announce a target, you can rest be assured &#x2013; and I already received the phone calls &#x2013; I would get the phone calls and we would get the phone calls from our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are for sure targets, but you also have to be wise in your actions, and Barbara is a wise businesswoman with tremendous experience. So there are no similarities, and there will be no target. But what we will do with you, I mean, of course we will share with you the progress in terms of the actions what we are taking, the levers what we have identified them. And that's for sure. But I just tried to give you a little bit of a flavor why particularly in the current environment, I mean, you can be rest assured it's &#x2013; these are testy times.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />, and we are very actually &#x2013; this is something which really helps us. According to the program laid out by the German government, people are allowed to stay in [[inaudible] or in short work weeks for 18 months. There are current discussions ongoing actually to expand this even further. There are deliberations going up to 24 months, and the takeover of social contributions by the government, even the increase in a further scheme to come.</p>
          <p>So what I tried to convey to you, that actually that there is a dialogue at the ministerial levels between industry and the respective ministry to even expand this, which allows us to actually implement this rapidly and to use it in a broader scale and as I shared with you, actually going from 12,000 to 19,000. Where the majority is actually in the industrial working environment, we are going from 25 to 40%, and we can use this in a flexible manner.</p>
          <p>It's also flexible that you can go back because it's targeted at the factory level. And so when you get a big order and you are in and all of a sudden you have to quickly work on an order, you're flexibly enough to move the other way. So this is a flexible instrument, which I think the government is very much supporting and we can use to help us, as Joe has highlighted, to come out of this depressed environment and taking advantage of the upscale. And, I mean if you have over 60% of the dollar as a profit, if the upswing comes, you're better prepared for it. So that's a very flexible one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe on the restructuring of tax rate, I think the current tax rate is a fair number to also calculate the second half with.</p>
          <p>And on restructuring, we do not expect material restructuring to the company. And there are going to be charges in Osram in Q3, Q4. This is important because Osram also sees structural changes from the general lighting to energy saving bulbs and the like. So there's got to be work here, which because there is not going to be any recovery on general lighting for light bulbs could very well be gone for good since there is also legislation out on that matter. So this is structural, and that's why we are doing it in a timely manner. So Q3, Q4 not material to the company, but it will, let say, impact Osram in a way that there is not going to be much about breakeven including restructuring for the addition in the second half of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would there be any charges at BT as well? I think you made some comment in the handout about BT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Building Technology usually has a few quarters delay as compared to Industrial Automation and of course also Osram due to the fact that buildings which were built 12 months ago are now being equipped. And since we have seen major commercial buildings being built less these months, we can be unfortunately rest assured that 2010 for BT will pose a major challenge.</p>
          <p>So now that one being a very much solution- and regional-related business, we might see restructuring charges coming in the fourth quarter of 2009 in order to make sure that we are being properly aligned to the demand of 2010 and going forward. But then again no material charges which would basically materially affect the company's numbers. But there might be a deterioration of the BT margin in the second half due to restructuring efforts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andreas Willi, and then Scott Babka.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Andreas Willi from JPMorgan. Two questions, one for Peter, one for Joe. First on motivation of division sector heads, with the reduced guidance, which you already have achieved 60% of the minimum after the half year and you're ahead of plan on SG&amp;A, how do you make sure the pressure stays up? And have you changed any internal projects following the change in the guidance?</p>
          <p>And for Joe, you mentioned some special benefits into the SG&amp;A in the first half of the year. Where have these special benefits shown up in the divisions? And also as corporate expansion keeps going up despite you having good progress on SG&amp;A overall, so kind of what's that driver there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andreas, to your first question, I think everybody is highly focused on the new targets equally as to the old ones because for internal reasons we have not changed incentive systems. So the managers are highly incentives to achieve the new target. And we have currently monthly operating reviews with all the divisions, so there is an intense focus to really make sure that we are absolutely aligned at all times. And if we have to take corrective actions or supporting the businesses on anything that there is a complete alignment between Board, sector CEOs, and divisional CEOs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, let me maybe, Andreas, come to the corporate items. I think we pretty much disclosed the impact of cost to the central items and the corporate items on page 12 of our earnings release. And if you <mark type="inaudible" /> there have been a series of one-offs which we covered under corporate items in Q2, negative one-offs, which somewhat compensated the relief of compliance-related consultancy cost. So if you just compare the central cost, the corporate costs, they actually have gone down for a little less of &#x2013; from 290 million to about 250.</p>
          <p>So the corporate costs are going down materially, but as I said, there have been several items which went against that, which had some one-off character. So there was some regulatory matter which was in a mid-double-digit number, which we hope/thought there was a negative difference of corporate restructuring of I think 33 million. And obviously the pension costs are going up. So it was a negative 83 as compared to positive four the same quarter a year ago.</p>
          <p>So those are significant impacts. And then again page number 12, they should actually give a comprehensive view on the major impacts there. But then again corporate cost from less than 290 to about 250. And that's probably just about the full-time number. Those 250 you may want to use in let's say in forward-looking prospects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the SG&amp;A benefits you mentioned in the first half <mark type="inaudible" /> one-offs so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about a 50, 60 million number which spreads across a few items. So they are not really material to the general development of the margins in the divisions. I just want to make sure that no one thinks it's 5.4 times two and maybe 10% less and theoretically miss the number. So we probably are well advised to take a more conservative approach. But we are well underway and that looks actually really good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Scott Babka.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. It's Scott Babka with Morgan Stanley. So you've been vocal in the past about the risk of pricing going forward in the cycle. Could you just talk a little bit about what you're seeing now? I'm particularly interested in Automation and Drives, looking at Imaging and Diagnostics and then at Power in T&amp;D, more product businesses. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Scott, the risk of pricing, I mean, that certainly is an aspect which one always comes up with as a possibility if and when factories are not being utilized over time, or if they're over capacities globally such as in Imaging because demand went down, particularly in the United States. So that's why we have always been mentioning that as a probability which will happen at some point in time.</p>
          <p>By the same token, honestly as market leaders, which we nowadays are in imaging as well as in automation and drive, the last thing you want to do, be the one who starts with pricing. We may have lost a few points of market share due to the fact that we've been staying firm on pricing in what used to be A&amp;D. In imaging, at this point in time we're doing very well because still innovation is key there especially the MRI sector, we believe that Siemens has made a very, very strong inroad. And the maturity of the positive development on imaging comes from the MRI business <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one quick follow-up. If you could elaborate a bit on Healthcare performance, obviously it's much better than your peers, not just in pricing in terms of order intake. Is that gaining share in North America, or is that just a better presence in the rest of the world?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is actually what &#x2013; I mean this is a multiple affect us. Number one, we are gaining share in the United States. We are holding up as leader of this industry in terms of pricing. We still see price discipline. I think the companies probably well remember the last major downturn where price was used in an extensive way. So we see overall price is definitely holding up. And we are particularly gaining share also in Europe and in Asia.</p>
          <p>And as Joe has highlighted, when you go into the modalities, I mean, the key thing at this point in time is that over &#x2013; and this goes back several years &#x2013; we have I think in several of the key modalities, NMI being one of them, key innovation leadership positions. And with the products what we have launched in the last 24 months, for example the sensor, which is the high-quality, but value cost-based MRI 1.5 Tesla coming out of China is now for example a product which is perfectly fitted in the current environment. The Somatom, the CT, the Somatom what we have launched is exactly going towards the same type of -</p>
          <p>So we have a good range of products. We are recognized as an innovation leader. We are gaining share, and we are obviously extremely disciplined in terms of the pricing environment. So it's a mix, but I think it demonstrates how the division has, or the sector has over last several years still a very, very, very solid leadership positions, and that's now just the fruit of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we'll have Martin here Crystal afterwards. Martin, second row in front, just in the front here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I've got Martin Prozesky from Sanford Bernstein. Two questions, please. And within the Energy sector, I think the performance of the Power Transmission business was a bit surprising. I think volumes were up strongly but margins were slightly down. Could you comment on whether that was a pricing effect or whether other elements were at play?</p>
          <p>And the second thing, in terms of payables, the strong reversal on the balance sheet, is that purely lower production volumes or were there other elements at play there in the strong payables reversal on the working capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, let's maybe start with Power Transmission. I think this kind of seems to divide into two worlds. It's the high-voltage transformers. That's holding up well mostly due to the fact that this is also being related to the big power plant energy project. The mid-voltage and lower aspects of the division are getting into pricing challenges, definitely are. And what we also see now is that &#x2013; and I referred to that about a year ago &#x2013; if you continue to invest, at a certain point in time you feel the depreciation, so the earnings conversion slows. And I mean, this is not rocket science. And those patterns we are seeing now. This is why we are extremely cautious about investing into more capacities at this time. I'd rather lose an order or two and to maintain profitability. So there is some weakness in the lower end of the transformer area. And we remain cautious about spending a lot of people, paper, and pencils to make sure that capacity is right.</p>
          <p>And so doing well, I believe. The division is doing a fantastic job. We are looking into the possibilities and opportunities in the Middle East predominantly. Also in Asia there are still good potential. But the market has become tighter, definitely has.</p>
          <p>And then the payables, I think that's an area where, also thanks to a new focus on power and supply chain, it's something which we should feel confident about if this continues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Crystal <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, it's Crystal from UBS. I have quick questions, please. The first one is on the inventories. I mean, you said that that was visible from the financial statement. So there has been some inventory buildup in the second quarter. Can you comment a bit in which division that was particularly evident? And how do you think it's going to impact Q3, meaning that if you need to reduce inventories, it might have any negative impact on the margins of the related division?</p>
          <p>My second question is on Industrial Automation margin. The margin was very weak in Q2 at a bit less than 6%. How do you think it's going to be in Q3, Q4? Should we expect the margin to be actually lower again in the next following quarters?</p>
          <p>And my last question is on the impact from <mark type="inaudible" />. It's likely that <mark type="inaudible" /> is going to take momentum, or the positive impact is likely to increase going forward. Have you actually made some estimates of what kind of positive impact we could see on the sector profit in Q3, Q4? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so let me maybe start with inventories. And obviously the divisions which have increased their inventories are in the Energy sector, as one could expect because volume is very strong. It's due to the renewables, as well as the cost in excess on fossil. So those are the growth areas. So we are going with the growth. We still, as I said, I believe have room here to increase returns and the efficiency. But the predominant aspect was in Energy, obviously.</p>
          <p>Now on the Industrial Automation margin, I mean, those are 5.8% which we have reported, certainly a massive deterioration to year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter. I think I said earlier that the speed of deterioration will be significantly less in Industrial Automation as compared to, for example, Drive Technologies. Whether or not we have seen the bottom yet, it seems, but I would not trust it too much because the nature of speed here and the fact that we do predominantly use distribution channels I think is something we'd be better cautious about.</p>
          <p>And impact of <mark type="inaudible" /> definitely has an impact because it goes along with the capacity utilization since people in the factory, there is some quarterly delay on those matters. But the impact of <mark type="inaudible" /> suddenly will help us stabilizing the margins and making sure they would not deteriorate further in a material manner. So there is impact.</p>
          <p>As Peter has already explained, there's currently activity going on in the German government to make good on what, let's say, some expectations were in the industry, that the government would not only expand the duration to 24 months but also cover the so-called social costs which are related to direct labor in the factories.</p>
          <p>We also just recently in the latter part of April have also introduced the so-called <mark type="inaudible" /> into the white collar environment in order to make sure that we also see some benefits along the quarters in that aspect. So we're using that extensively in order to make sure that innovation still goes forward, yet that we cut cost out in a temporary manner in order to make sure that we don't have excess reserves of some product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we'll continue with Tim over there <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. Two very quick questions. First for Barbara, what kind of investment do you expect to have to make to extract your supply chain savings?</p>
          <p>And then secondly for Joe, you talked about order deferral activity, push-out activity. Can you just talk about how big in terms of euro value that was, and whether it now has a new delivery date or whether it's kind of just been pushed out sort of beyond 2010? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the question on the investment is quite easy to answer of course. They are not big. They are very, very minor. Why? Because we work here on material costs, so there is not link to restructuring expenses and things like that. And also as I said at the beginning, we work very much with the sectors to drive this approach. 4,000 purchasing managers or purchasing team members are now on the way. They have clear targets, and they are really going to for the savings. So the investment is rather limited for this activity, and the upsides of course are there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so you expect very limited IT investments because I'm assuming you have quite a number of internal IT systems and that's really kind of the investment I was thinking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that is true. But there is for instance issue to build some business data warehouse and things like that, but they are not very, very major investments that we need to do. We need to bundle it better et cetera. And we are doing that already now. But it's not a big investment in new systems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so see that there should be some room for additional investment in supply chain in the guidance, not to multiply 5.4 times two in SG&amp;A. So you shouldn't worry about it, the performance-related impact from supply chain. We must <mark type="inaudible" /> materially higher than the cost you need to spend for that. So there shouldn't be should be any worry there.</p>
          <p>On the order deferral, we discussed it this morning too when we were meeting with the media. We said we would not have material cancellations. So for a company like us, numbers of, let's say, 3, 400 million would be considered to be material.</p>
          <p>Now on the deferral, that certainly looks different by the numbers. At the same token though, one should consider that we have 87 billion backlog, 87 billion backlog. So if there is a order deferral all the way on that backlog, all the way about <mark type="inaudible" />, that number would be a billion. That definitely is not material. So therefore this is important to understand, that we are currently still reasonably comfortable about our backlog and the discussions on how far to move those <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>The single biggest division which is being effected by deferrals is actually Industrial Solutions obviously due to the fact that those guys are materially involved in the metals business and the steel business. And everyone talks about something that definitely is not about increasing the factory capacities in steel. So therefore there is deferral there in a material way, also in let's say the commodity environment, which we also deliver, the process industries. So there discussions about moving those orders out to later times.</p>
          <p>Many of those long-cycle-related orders also to carry customer prepayments. So customers are very, very sensitive about the fact that they would lose millions by canceling their orders. So that gives us, let's say, some leverage also to make sure that this is a commitment.</p>
          <p>And since we have 59% of semiconductor business and at year end we are actually feel we're going to be comfortable with our backlog. You never know, but at this point in time I think we go for the second half of the fiscal year. And 23 billion of the 87 billion are scheduled to turn into revenues in 2009 second half. Those are important. If there was any material impact, adverse impact of that, there would be cultivation in Siemens elsewhere to cover up for that loss in revenues. So those is the focus. This is what we concentrate on, and everything else deserves the attention it deserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will continue with James Moore here now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Moore, Redburn Partners. A question on FBG and Mobility and then one on the supply chain program. Some questions on FBG and Mobility, and then on the supply chain program. You had two quarters now of improving margins with FBG up at the 13 level and Mobility returning to the top end of your target. Could you talk a little bit about the mix within both of those businesses and where we are on the zero margin contracts relating that to last year? Have they all run out?</p>
          <p>You talked last year in the fourth quarter about Signaling having some problems. Has that come back? And just more on mix there please.</p>
          <p>And I know you don't want to give a target for supply chain, but are there any of the sectors where we will see more impacts than others, or is it across the board, or will it be in the corporate central line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, let's say we'll start with Mobility. I'm not sure about the FBG, whether I understand that correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You had two...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fossil power, you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, fossil...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry. Okay, Fossil Power. All right, that's okay. So there is a customer, which is called &#x2013; similarly so I wasn't sure whether this one would be the motivation of the question. Let's start with Mobility and Fossil Power Generation, division Energy. We are very much through those orders. And as you have seen the last two quarters, we executed well on both Fossil, as well as the Mobility. So in Fossil there is still zero margin backlog which needs to be worked out. The majority of that will go away during the course of 2009. And there is about a billion-plus out of those 16 billion at that time which we still need to go through in 2010. But the majority will be covered during the of course fiscal 2009. And as the matter of fact we do see a materially improved order backlog quality in terms of margins in the mid-term, not suggesting 2010, but 2010 and out. So that actually is positive we need to execute well.</p>
          <p>Now Mobility, this definitely is something where a new management team brought systematic approach through a division that's got big potential but never used it. And potential is always being used, but by the way, how much we try it, that will be delivered in results. The general business model of Mobility is such that there are only a few divisions in Siemens which deliver such a premium return on capital employed as Mobility could be delivering. But that actually requires seamless execution on the platforms. With the new management, I think we have reached the confidence level which makes us confident that we are going to be in the target margin range definitely in 2010, but there is some potential here also for 2009.</p>
          <p>It seems that we have solved the execution issues in the trains area and in the metro area. We also do have hope that we are back to solid margins in rail automation, but it's too early to tell on the software or the regulation fees, whether this is a sustainable situation going forward or maybe just a quick recovery from a extremely unsatisfactory situation. So maybe next quarter, we have a more solid update on rail automation, but definitely the execution of projects has become a whole new quality with the new team in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now on the question of how it touches the sectors, the supply chain management initiative is a massive and compressive program. The focus of it is the total spend of 40 billion obviously. And the plan goes throughout all the sectors. And as I said, there is not one stone that remains untouched.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I go back for one second to the Fossil one, because it's another great story of how we are executing and how the business team is executing, if you remember one aspect was in terms of how do we execute now this so called problem project, which Joe was highlighting. The other aspect was also that at time we had decided to have a significantly different mix between turnkey programs, products, and services, the third what we have mentioned. And we are a year ahead on this one as well. So the mix is actually changing fundamentally towards products and services. And we are actually a year ahead of execution. The target was in 2010, and we have all reason to believe that we will be there by 2009, which again will help us to drive the quality of the business from a margin quality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we'll take two more questions. Gentleman over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. It's Andrew Carter from Macquarie. I just had a three questions on the Energy division, if I could. Firstly, I think the Q2 margin came in ahead of the Q1, and I think that's despite &#x2013; Joe, perhaps at a broker conference you talked about maybe the Q1 margin I think benefited from mix. So I wondered if you can just sort of make a comment on that.</p>
          <p>The second was really just talking about the performance going forward. Business obviously seems to have been performing very well, despite the clear deterioration in the environment for your customers. And I was wondering if there's any risk that the difficulties that some of those customers are having could derail profitability at Energy regardless of the solid backlog. And what I was thinking now was things like commissioning delays or maintenance deferral or spare parts destocking or those kind of things.</p>
          <p>And finally, just a shorter one. I just wondered on Areva NP, what the losses where there and where exactly they were booked in the P&amp;L.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so last time when we met in the broader scheme of things, I was cautioning that <mark type="inaudible" /> in Fossil. The Fossil division was somewhat favorably impacted by a good product mix. And with the good product mix I mean the combination between newer orders and those so-called zero margin orders. And the current fiscal quarter in Fossil showed that we actually have a continued favorable development in the mix between lower-margin-rich new orders as compared to the other ones.</p>
          <p>So therefore not going to get much better in the foreseeable future for the next couple of quarters, but it would not suggest that it gets materially worse either. So this is the ballpark level we are able to achieve in Energy in Q2. Maybe a little bit of downside, but that's just about the level a well functioning organization executing well on projects is able to achieve in the short term. And then we'll take it from there. So mix topics can always be, let's say, a margin fluctuations, let's say, not much than 100 basis points, but this is a possibility.</p>
          <p>On Areva NP, since we basically this year irrevocable production and placed it to Areva. , that asset is held for sale. It still is in the Energy sector and will remain in the Energy sector till the matter is resolved, and obviously it goes away because the shares are being transferred. So due to the fact that is being asset held for sale, what people look is a fair market value as compared to the long-lived assets. So there is not going to be any charges as long as the company believes that there is a fair market value which represents what we can expect as a purchasing price. So there were not any P&amp;L-related charges of any sort stemming from our Areva shares. And it will likely remain that way till the matter is eventually resolved. But then again there will be quarterly updates on the matter and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Martin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Martin Wilkie from Deutsche Bank. A couple of questions on infrastructure. First of all, are you still seeing potential projects coming from government stimulus-led investments in China? Obviously you had a big win in the current quarter, but are you seeing increased tendering from the government for infrastructure projects led by stimulus over the next couple of quarters?</p>
          <p>And then the second question was we've seen lot of moves from governments over the past couple of months on carbon-free energy, a lot of movement here in the U.K. and also in the U.S. Do you think the Fossil Power portfolio is well geared to a carbon-free Fossil generation upsurge over next two or three years? Is Siemens as well benefiting from that, or are there investments to be made either organically or through bolt-on acquisitions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Martin on the global stimulus programs, I think we have to be extremely realistic on this one. I mean, they were just announced. We're probably talking a range between 1.5 and 2 trillion, a major part going into infrastructure. So there's a certain part of it which is geared towards our business, which is quite substantial. It will happen, but it will not happen in terms of being order-relevant before 2010 through our businesses. As you have rightfully said, it must be cascaded; there must be tenders.</p>
          <p>But there are some projects which government used to accelerate. I mean, the Chinese was one of them. We have been last week in Brazil where there's another 250 billion government stimulus program. Again there are some programs which they are now considering to accelerate, what they initially already had in their plan. But they tried to accelerate, and this would obviously be in our area as well. So there are one-offs, but when you really talk about what is the real impact to our business, it's probably between 2010 and beyond.</p>
          <p>On carbon capture in terms of Fossil, indeed we are extremely well positioned because we're working on carbon capture technologies. It's a part of our research of our R&amp;D activities, pre-combustion and post-combustion. So we are working on the technologies. But the issue is here really that we need some pilot plants, and this has to be financed somewhere. And I think this can only be in the combination of government plus private industry. So the critical thing will be their part for example of the European energy plan. But we now must see when and where there will be some private plans that we'd really learn in terms how feasible the whole approach is in terms of &#x2013; in a real scale environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, with that I'd like to close the Q&amp;A. I would like to refer you to the financial calendar for next three months, and that you will find in the package on slide 27. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much for your attendance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>