<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1333123" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-10-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>462</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Malcolm Theobald, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Simon Ayat, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Andrew Gould, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Brad Handler</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Daniel Boyd</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Kurt Hallead</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">J. David Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Bill Herbert</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">James Crandell</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Alan Laws</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">William Sanchez</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Michael LaMotte</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Michael Urban</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Robin Shoemaker</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Geoffrey Kieburtz</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Douglas Becker</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Ole Slorer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Schlumberger Limited third quarter 2010 results conference call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question-and-answer session. Instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded. I would now like to turn the conference over to your host, Malcolm Theobald, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Greg. Good morning and welcome to the Schlumberger Limited third quarter 2010 results conference call. Joining me for today's call are Andrew Gould, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, and Simon Ayat, Chief Financial Officer. Prior to Andrew's overview of the results and his comments, Simon will first review the quarter's financial results. After the prepared statements, we will welcome your questions.</p>
          <p>Before we begin with the opening remarks, I'd like to remind the participants that some of the information in today's call may include forward-looking statements, as well as non-GAAP financial measures. A detailed disclaimer and other important information are included in the FAQ document, which is available on our website or upon request.</p>
          <p>And now, I'll turn the call over to Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Malcolm. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for participating in this conference call. Third quarter earning per share, excluding charges and credits, was $0.70 per share. This is an increase of $0.02 sequentially and $0.05 compared to the same quarter of last year. During the quarter, we recorded $0.30 of restructuring and merger-related charges and a $0.98 gain on our investment in M-I SWACO. These items are more fully described in our earnings press release. As a reminder, we will continue to incur merger and integration related charges during the next few quarters.</p>
          <p>The third quarter results include one month of activity relating to the merger with Smith. This transaction was dilutive to our Q3 results by just under $0.02 per share and it's estimated to be dilutive to our Q4 earnings by approximately $0.05 per share. We issued 176 million shares in the Smith transaction and, due to the timing of the close, only one-third of these shares are included in our weighted average diluted shares outstanding for Q3. The full 176 million shares will be reflected in our Q4 EPS calculation.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we continue to feel the effect of the deepwater drilling moratorium in the U.S. Gulf of Mexico. We estimate that the moratorium resulted in a reduction of our Q3 earnings of approximately $0.02 to $0.03 per share. The earnings effect of the moratorium in Q4 is estimated to be approximately $0.04 to $0.05 per share.</p>
          <p>Turning to the business segments, Oilfield Services third quarter revenue increased 2% sequentially while WesternGeco revenue increased 1%. The legacy Smith businesses contributed $810 million in revenue to the quarter. The growth in Oilfield Services revenue was largely attributable to the continued strong activity and increased pricing in U.S. land as well as the impact of three months of Geoservices activity in Q3 as compared to one month in the prior quarter. These increases were partially offset by reduced IPM activity in the Mexico/Central America GeoMarket and a full quarter's effect of the deepwater drilling moratorium in the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
          <p>Oilfield Services pre-tax operating income of $1.1 billion increased 3% compared to the prior quarter while pre-tax operating margin increased 15 basis points, to 19.9%. The increase in margin was primarily driven by the strong performance in North America. International margins were down slightly to 21.4%, primarily due to the decline in activity in Mexico/Central America.</p>
          <p>By area, Oilfield Services sequential pre-tax operating margin highlights were as follows. North America pre-tax operating margin improved 704 basis points to 17.4%. U.S. land margin improved significantly by almost 9 percentage points as a result of higher activity and better pricing. However, this strong performance was tempered by the effect of the deepwater drilling moratorium. Latin America margin declined 302 basis points to 14.9%, due to the decreased activity in Mexico/ Central America. Europe/CIS/Africa margin was essentially flat at 18.3%, while the Middle East/Asia margin declined slightly by 84 basis points to 30.3%. Sequentially, WesternGeco pre-tax operating income decreased 14% to $40 million, and pre-tax operating margins slipped 145 basis points to 8.3%. The three Smith segments contributed $84 million of pre-tax operating income to the quarter's results.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Schlumberger as a whole, the effective tax rate excluding charges and credits was 21%, representing an increase of over 3 percentage points compared to last quarter. This increase was primarily driven by the fact that we generated a significantly larger portion of our earnings in North America in Q3, as well as the impact of the Smith merger. As you know, Smith is a U.S. company and, as such, has a higher effective tax rate than Schlumberger. The ETR is expected to experience at least a similar crease again in Q4, due to the inclusion of Smith for an entire quarter, combined with the effects of the continued positive momentum in North America.</p>
          <p>We ended the quarter with $3.2 billion of cash and investments on hand and short-term debt of $1.9 billion. Net debt was $3.5 billion at the end of the quarter, as compared to $766 million at the end of Q2. This increase reflects the assumption of $1.8 billion of net debt from the Smith merger.</p>
          <p>Other significant liquidity events during the quarter included $824 million of CapEx and $463 million of pension plan contributions, and $396 million of stock repurchases. Although we were blacked out for one month during the quarter pending the Smith shareholder vote, we repurchased 6.8 million shares at an average price of $57.91.</p>
          <p>We expect to be aggressive and opportunistic with our buyback program going forward. During the quarter, we launched a program to buy back certain notes of both Schlumberger and Smith. The program continues, as you may have seen yesterday in a separate press release. This ongoing initiative will help us to realign our capital structure following the merger.</p>
          <p>Oilfield Services CapEx is now expected to reach approximately $2.5 billion in 2010, while WesternGeco CapEx is expected to be approximately $315 million. CapEx for the legacy Smith businesses from the acquisition date through the end of the year is estimated to be approximately $260 million.</p>
          <p>And now I turn the conference over to Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Simon. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. I have a few comments to add on the quarter's results before turning to the outlook for the rest of the year. As Simon has said, the sequential revenue increase was largely driven by strong improvements in U.S. land and Canada which more than offset a sharp decline in the U.S. Gulf of Mexico, as the deepwater drilling moratorium took full effect.</p>
          <p>Favorable activity coupled with robust pricing power for pressure pumping and the effects of our restructuring efforts lead to a major improvement in our margins. Our North American team under Paul Kibsgaard's guidance has made major improvements in efficiency and utilization across the country. The sequential margin improvement was very satisfactory and we exited the quarter at a high point for both revenue growth and margins.</p>
          <p>Outside North America, activity was mixed. Solid improvements were recorded in Asia, Russia, the North Sea, West and Southern Africa, which offset continued weakness in North Africa and the Gulf of Guinea. Latin America performed well in all GeoMarkets except Mexico where budget constraints, weather and security concerns led to major reductions in IPM activities. Higher exploration activity is beginning to result in better technology sales. New technologies continued to underpin our results as the quarter's highlights clearly show. While a number of these have already seen growing market penetration, such as the ACTive family of real time coiled tubing services, others, such as the unique PowerDrive Archer high build rate rotary steerable system, are just entering field service.</p>
          <p>This particular technology can eliminate the need for a pilot hole in horizontal well drilling by building angle much more sharply than other rotary steerable systems. Other new technologies were unveiled at the Society of Petroleum Engineers technology conference in September. These included the unique Wireline Dielectric Scanner multifrequency dispersion service which has already run 250 jobs in 20 countries during its introductory phase. This technology enables the determination of residual oil saturation in carbonate reservoirs, hydrocarbon volume in low resistivity or low contrast shaly and laminated sand formations and hydrocarbon volume and mobility in heavy oil reservoirs.</p>
          <p>In Testing Services we announced the Quartet high-performance downhole reservoir testing system, that allowed clients to isolate, control, measure and sample, reservoir tests in a single run, using a downhole assembly, only one quarter of the length of conventional technology configurations. In software solutions we announced the release of the Merak Peep 2010, the cornerstone of the Merak suite of economics, planning and reserves management software. This new release which delivers a complete refresh of the application, allowing customers to proactively respond to complex operational conditions and rapidly answer business challenges, was developed in collaboration with 15 oil and gas companies majors, nationals, and independents.</p>
          <p>We also reported a significant number of new contracts in regions across the world, including China, Brazil, Libya, France and Russia. Many of these were based on previous strong performance of certain technologies is in the field, while others were supported by the growing capacity for integration across the Schlumberger technology portfolio. The recent realignment of our portfolio within the three product groups following the acquisitions of the both Smith and Geoservices is already supporting further integration, particularly in drilling services.</p>
          <p>In addition, to these contract wins and new technology introductions, I would also like to mention that we have successfully begun operations in the Red Sea for wide azimuth seismic acquisition. Wide and multi-azimuth has now been contracted in five large basins outside the Gulf of Mexico. First, it was the North Sea, and this year we have shot in West Africa, and are now starting in both the Red Sea and Brazil. We will soon shoot in the Mediterranean. The spread of wide or multi-azimuth is helping to absorb the extra capacity coming out of the Gulf of Mexico and the new build boats entering the market. In the majority of these regions, the industry is looking for reservoirs in complex geometry in deepwater.</p>
          <p>In other areas, we announced the signing of a letter of intent to swap certain assets in Russia to build critical mass in drilling services. Under the terms of the agreement, Eurasia will acquire a number of Schlumberger-owned drilling rigs while Schlumberger will acquire a range of Eurasia service assets, including directional drilling, measurement-while-drilling, well cementing, and drilling fluids. Further, both companies have agreed to enter into a strategic alliance upon completion of the transaction whereby Schlumberger will become the preferred supplier of drilling services to Eurasia Drilling for up to 200 rigs for a five-year period. This agreement not only increases the market for our services across the rig fleet of the largest Russian drilling company, it sets the development for fit-for-purpose, bottomhole assembly technology as drilling intensity increases in Russia in order to sustain hydrocarbon production.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the future. We expect the fourth quarter to show continued strong activity in North America on land, but we do not expect any rapid return to deepwater drilling in the U.S. Gulf of Mexico despite the lifting of the moratorium. Further clarification of the new rules and liabilities under which activity will be conducted will be necessary before any major increase in activity takes place.</p>
          <p>Our restructuring efforts will continue to deliver margin improvement in U.S. land. Outside North America, the delays induced by the knock-on effect of the Macondo well are now being reabsorbed. This and the recent strength in oil prices gives us some optimism that the rate of recovery overseas will accelerate slightly. The normal seasonal declines in Russia will be present in the fourth quarter, and the future of Mexico operations will remain uncertain until next year.</p>
          <p>WesternGeco will show improvement in the fourth quarter, due to increased Gulf of Mexico multi-client sales. We are very pleased with the rapid progress that is being made on the integration of Smith and M-I SWACO. The integration teams and the area coordinators are rapidly identifying both revenue and cost synergy opportunities that augur well for 2011. The enthusiasm among the employees of all companies is obvious and constructive. The integration of Geoservices has also progressed and we have increased market focus of Geoservices technologies by the separation of their mud logging and slick line businesses within the Schlumberger technology portfolio.</p>
          <p>Recent robust demand increases, as well as predictions of higher demand in 2011, will continue to support oil prices and activity absent any further deterioration in the world economy. Further demand increases for natural gas will be necessary to sustain the current level of North American gas drilling activity beyond a certain point in time.</p>
          <p>And I will now turn the call back to Greg. Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from the line of Brad Handler from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Brad.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I could ask for a couple of comments on WesternGeco. Couple of things in your comments, Andrew, sounded encouraging including both soaking up assets, the wide and multi-azimuth comment as well as your comments on the fourth quarter and multi-client sales. Could you elaborate on those, please? Do you have a better view for pricing improvements now in 2011 as a function of better asset utilization and, again, on the data side as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me answer the data question first. I mean nothing is ever sure on Gulf of Mexico multi-clients until the quarter ends, but the level of inquiries is encouraging. And, as we have mentioned before, I think that some of our customers are going to spend a little bit of the money they didn't spend on drilling in improving their data portfolio. So that deals with Q4 multi-client, Brad.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I'm trying to communicate is that the spread of wide or multi-azimuth outside the Gulf of Mexico is going to soak up capacity. I don't think -- or I don't know whether that's going to be sufficient to move pricing in 2011, but it -- I think it is going to be sufficient to absorb capacity, which seems to be becoming a fear that you hear around the community. I actually think that there will be enough work to absorb most of the boat capacity. If, of course, work starts again in the Gulf of Mexico, then it would have an almost immediate effect, I think, on pricing. But I'm not going to predict that at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Okay. Maybe just as a simple follow-up, obviously the fourth quarter is seasonally a little softer in marine acquisition. But the contract announcements in Brazil, Egypt, et cetera, and your new vessel, are those enough, perhaps, to offset it? Might you have more of a flattish quarter in marine in fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just hang on a second and we'll try and help you there. No, there will be a seasonal dip. There will be a seasonal dip, perhaps not as bad as it's been in some times in the past but there will be a seasonal dip in Q4 which you know is essentially the North Sea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Right. Okay. Well, very helpful. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Dan Boyd from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, can you just give us a little more color on the charge that you took in Mexico? Was it due to just purely a restructuring down there or is it a write-down of prior profit essentially due to some project-based accounting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't use project based accounting, Dan. We only recognize revenue when PEMEX accepts the stages of the wells that we've drilled. And, therefore, there's no element of profit in the charge we took. Simon, would you like to describe what the charge was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of the charge relates to the early termination fees to the drilling contractors. We don't own the drilling rigs. We do have a joint venture, as you know, for some of the rigs, but this is all mostly the early termination fees for the rigs. So we don't recognize revenue on a percentage of completion or any of that nature. It's mainly early termination fees, as I said, and some restructuring associated with the severance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful, given some of the other stuff we've seen. As a follow-up, unrelated, Andrew, you mentioned Russia quite a bit in the press release. You recently did the deal with Eurasia. At the same time, there's a number of NOCs talking about spinning out their service divisions. Can you talk about Schlumberger's strategy there, the growth outlook in general but then also what do you see as the opportunity through all this for Schlumberger to potentially take some share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, the Eurasia transaction is very much what -- a phrase I don't like, but I'm going to use it, a win/win transaction, because we could never build a 200 rig fleet in Russia of the quality of Eurasia's. And, as you know, following the Smith transaction, our objective is to sell more drilling services.</p>
          <p>And Eurasia's objective, as often the rig owner is the general contractor, is to improve their performance. So what it does for us is to give us access to 200 rigs whereas before, including the side track and workover, we had about 30. And what it gives to Eurasia is access to our expertise in drilling services and, on certain of the wells they drill, access to the high-end services.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the divestitures in Russia, we will, I think, participate but extremely selectively, because after 15 years, there is willingness and there is capital in Russia to grow a domestic service industry. And part of that is the -- consequence of that is companies like Eurasia and Integra. We will participate where we can draw technology advantage through the participation. But I doubt we will go any more into acquisitions to acquire market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a follow-up on that, did I hear that correctly, that you feel the offering that Smith has, has a large role in Russia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The offering that Smith has and the offering that Schlumberger has and the offering that we have through certain companies we acquired previously in Russia, in the drilling services business has application, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. I'll turn it back over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Kurt Hallead from RBC Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question I had for you, Andrew, is on the North American and international front, you clearly made some significant headway on the restructuring process, maybe to a greater degree than most may have anticipated. In your mind, and in your business plan here, is the rate of change on North America now just bound to slow, given the magnitude of ramp up that we've seen? Or do you still expect substantial improvement in your operating margin performance over the course of the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; I don't think we can do that sort of improvement every quarter because this is the first quarter that they got the full effect of the restructuring. But we do anticipate that we will have further improvements in the margin performance in Q4. I think that we will probably see them through the first quarter and beyond that, I don't know. And -- because it will not only be a question of our restructuring, it will be a question of what happens in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then I was just curious on the revenue synergy front, there really hasn't been much discussion on that recently, and I'm sure you guys are kind of working through all your opportunities at this point. I was just wondering if you might be able to give us some glimpse as to where a starting point could be for revenue synergies and, if not, when you think you might be able to give us some elements of quantification on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had revenue synergies in September. But they were &#x2013; obviously, one month they were very small. Now, we have named area coordinators. So each of the Schlumberger geographical area has a coordinator who reports back on a weekly basis, and the identified opportunities for revenue synergies make us extremely optimistic that this is going to be -- go a little -- quite quickly, Kurt. So I don't -- I don't have a good -- I can't announce a number, but when you look at the quantity of opportunities that they're sifting through, it's -- it looks pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Anderson from JPMorgan, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On the North American side, is the restructuring complete now? Is this simply just about execution from here on out? And basically what do you need to do now? Is this about building up your presence in certain regions? And I guess a follow-up, how are you viewing this market now as you did last cycle? How are you going to be approaching this over the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are talking about North America?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, look, on the restructuring we're not complete but the bulk of it's done. I mean, we still have certain facilities that we're closing, certain consolidations that are going on between areas, certain procedures in equipment utilization, but the bulk of it is over. But it still will contribute a bit in the fourth quarter to margin improvement.</p>
          <p>And how am I viewing this cycle? So, I think that this cycle -- obviously the volatility of gas prices is being dampened by the liquid rich shales, where the activity has been migrating over the last few months. There's a ceiling to that. I'm not quite sure where it is. And the ceiling is governed by the fact that however much liquid you have in it, you still need to get some money for the gas. So &#x2013; and that means that the shales that are going to be drilled are going to be not all the shales, they're going to be the liquid rich ones. So I think the volatility will be dampened but fundamental economic principles have not gone away, and at some stage, activity will moderate. But please don't ask me when it is, because I don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't do that. One other follow-up question on your -- on the WesternGeco side. I just wondered if you could just expand a little bit on the multi-client seismic activity in the Gulf. You mentioned you get a lot of inquiries. But I'm just wondering, are operators preparing for a lease sale in the spring? I believe a majority of that business comes from the E&amp;Ps, so I'm just wondering how concerned are you about their future in the Gulf and what that means to the WesternGeco business model as it pertains to the Gulf?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So when we look at the multi-client inquiries that we're getting today, they are coming from companies who I'm pretty sure -- I'm almost certain will be drilling again in the Gulf, which gives you an indication of their size.</p>
          <p>I think that the E&amp;P presence in the Gulf going forward, and you are quite right to point out that the independents played a large role in multiclient, is undecided at this stage because I don't think it's the rules and regulations surrounding the drilling practices that are going to be important. It's what is the final solution to the liability that companies have to assume going -- in future lease commitments that they make or drilling commitments that they make.</p>
          <p>So we don't know today what the ultimate size of the multi-client market is going to be. What is true is a lot of our multi-client traction is coming through technology. The prefunding we're getting from multi-client at the moment is very healthy, but it's based as much on technology as it is on the fact that we're shooting certain areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Along those lines, are you moving vessels out of the Gulf?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are down to where we are. You know, we have permits for the vessels that are shooting and we don't anticipate moving any more out at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bill Herbert from Simmons &amp; Company. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. Andrew, I'm going to ask you a question that I asked you on the first quarter call and that relates to the roadmap for international margins, if you will, between now and over the course of next year. And keeping in mind price activity and mix. So give us a roadmap as to how you see international margins unfolding, assuming that oil prices stay above $80 a barrel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's important to analyze a little bit why margins have not improved significantly this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think that the first thing you can say is that Mexico has dampened margins for Latin America, but virtually everywhere else in Latin America margins have progressed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You look at ECA, Europe/CIS/Africa. The North Sea had healthy improvements. West and Southern Africa, a lot of projects were delayed by Macondo but they started towards the end of the third quarter, so that will improve. The Gulf of Guinea, by which I mean everything from Ghana through Nigeria down to Equatorial Guinea, is being dampened by Nigeria and then, of course, North Africa has not been good. And so the slight decrease in margins in ECA is really large due to the weakness in North Africa and the Gulf of Guinea which was too much to offset the improvement in the North Sea, Russia and West and Southern Africa. It's sort of clear.</p>
          <p>If you look at MEA, the only reason our margin declined is because we took all the mobilization costs for the BP Rumaila project in Q3. If we had not had that cost, the margins would have been flat with Q2. So I -- if you go forward into next year, I think that the deepwater activity improvement next year, because of the rigs coming on and because of the Macondo -- there will hopefully not be a second Macondo effect, deepwater will improve more than it did this year. We are already seeing, to some extent, a renewal of exploration programs in areas other than the traditional areas in Africa. And that is helping.</p>
          <p>And in the Middle East, if you leave aside Iraq, there are a number of other projects that have very healthy margins going forward. So overall, we've got delayed this year by some extraneous events and some activities that didn't happen, but if oil prices stay where they are, I don't see why margins shouldn't progress next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with regards to what drives margins next year, do you see any prospect of pricing improvement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Internationally</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Technology mix pricing improvement, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And last one for me, we didn't mention anything about Russia and I'm just curious as to your outlook for Russia next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Western Siberia will be a lot stronger and Sakhalin will have a bit of a pause because some shift in operator activity. So overall, I don't think you can -- you may get the same margins but it would be difficult to get improvement, I think, because -- just because of our mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jim Crandell from Barclays, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question, Andrew, is about Iraq. How do you expect Iraq now to unfold over 2011 and 2012 and do you think it's important to have a significant presence in the country on the ground floor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the first part of that question is that everyone has a significant presence now. Everyone has equipment there. Everyone is doing call-out work. It's not necessarily in big contracts. And I think that the real question is really how much of the project activity -- how much of an appetite you have for the project activity.</p>
          <p>And frankly, based on our experiences in South America, we are being quite cautious, because the terms and the conditions that the operators signed, as you know, are quite tight. And, therefore, they're trying to reflect on to the contractors the same tight conditions in the form of performance which they are through very tight terms and conditions asking for high levels of liquidated damages. And in a country where you don't have a great deal of control over the logistics or the security, high levels of liquidated damages linked to performance are not necessarily a good idea. So on big projects, we will be cautious; for everything else, we will be aggressive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and the follow-up, Andrew. Brazil seems like it will be your number one business opportunity in the world over the next two, three, four years. Can you give me a sense of magnitude on the increases in business you expect there? And have you noticed any change in the types of bidding that's gone on there in your major product lines over the last six to 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really. There are one or two IPM-type opportunities with -- not with Petrobas but with the others. The activity with Petrobas I don't have to describe to you, and the internationals has been very strong. But, of course, they're waiting to see what the final form of the new hydrocarbon law is going to be before they invest a lot more. But overall, it's probably one -- it's probably this year, our highest growth rate, I think, Brazil, of any part of the company, except North America. And I don't see any reason why that won't continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. Good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alan Laws from BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Alan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to ask you about the share repurchase, I guess. The share repurchase was down in 3Q. You've mentioned a number of times that you'd look to be aggressive and opportunistic in their repo, following the acquisition or whenever actually during the process that you're allowed to be active. I know you had a blackout there for about a month. But two things really, is there an amount of the 11 odd billion that you paid for Smith that you would want to repurchase. And two, your share price is sort of in the same range as when the Smith transaction was announced. You have the cash, the debt markets seem accommodating. Is there any consideration or appetite for a mini tender offer here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just say we're examining all of the above. Everything you mentioned we're looking at. It is true that in Q3 we were blacked out for a month because we couldn't purchase while the Smith -- what was it, the reason?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The shareholder vote.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For a month in advance of the Smith shareholder vote. And I don't think I have a fixed portion of the Smith purchase price that we should repurchase. I think it's to the extent that all the different methods that you mentioned produce an accretive result, Alan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. That's what I like to hear. My second question, which is clearly not a follow-up, is that Smith was kind of hoping to move down its D&amp;E suite of services into the international arena. When you look at the combination of what have you today, does this still make sense as a growth strategy? I guess did you have that aspect of the market already covered or are the Smith tools adding to your capabilities to service a broader range of the market? Essentially, are you becoming a D&amp;E category killer now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So firstly remember that we were somewhat surprised that we were able to keep the PathFinder, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But actually the issue that we've had in our own drilling and measurements over the last five years is coping with the growth, and the addition of PathFinder allows us to deal with parts of the growth that we absolutely probably couldn't address through our own drilling and measurements.</p>
          <p>So, yes, the Smith strategy of expanding the PathFinder offering overseas is not dead. It's the markets we're going to address with it that may have changed and please don't ask me what they are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. That's good. Thank you very much for the answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bill Sanchez from Howard Weil. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My first question, Simon, is for you. I know you outline here this morning the dilutive impact of Gulf of Mexico, roughly $0.04 to $0.05, and also you gave us the Smith impact of about a nickel. I'm just curious, we appreciate it on a stand-alone basis but isn't there some overlap, if you will, in those two numbers? In other words, the Gulf of Mexico dilution includes also dilution from the Smith acquisition as well or should those truly just be two independent numbers as we think about the fourth quarter estimate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a good point you're raising. Actually, it is two independent numbers except for the number of shares that are now issued, right? So the earning per share or the cents per share is a bit higher, right? But it is two independent numbers. The dilution from the Smith activity includes the impact of the Gulf of Mexico on Smith, which is the M-I SWACO and some in the tools. So it is two independent numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and I guess just looking at the SWACO margin as a whole for the quarter, when you consider that most of the North American exposure that SWACO has is offshore, so you really don't have the U.S. land offset there, if you will, the fact that you were able to do flat sequential margins in that business, Andrew, was there something in the international arena that kicked in that we should be aware of going forward as we think about SWACO's contribution, especially to 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm afraid I can't think of any individual event. There was a much stronger North Sea in Q3. But actually SWACO has done an excellent job on land in the U.S. I know their traditional exposure was very much offshore, but they have taken a considerable position in U.S. land over the last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I could just ask one more here, as we think about fourth quarter and the impact of direct sales, Andrew, anything there we should be aware of, especially in the Eastern Hemisphere market and a potential positive effect on margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there will be the traditional year-end completions, artificial lift, the biggest margin effect we will get is through the SIS software sales, but we do not sell -- remember, we don't sell Wireline or D&amp;M equipment, so we won't have any of those sort of sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, thank you for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Michael LaMotte from Guggenheim Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions on strategy, if I may. First on technology. You've talked the last few quarters about the commercialization pipeline and new products and you identified a few of the technologies in your release and in your comments. Can you talk about where we are with respect to the rollout? And secondly, what -- what's driving the uptake of the technologies in a market characterized by a lack of general inflation? Which can often be an accelerant to uptake.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So actually in the pipeline, when I look at our pipeline now, Michael, the true acceleration is the back half of next year. So we have a normal number of products filtering into the market now. The true acceleration is the back half of next year.</p>
          <p>There are a number of things driving the uptake. So first is, Q3 we saw more exploration and, therefore, a higher quality mix in what we sold. Oil -- at $80 a barrel, oil companies are a little less stringent with their engineers in allowing them to buy some extra technology. And some of the technology, particularly things like PowerDrive Archer, fairly dramatically reduces the operator's cost. So there's no one reason, Michael, but those are the three that I would identify.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I think about the Archer in particular, in a -- having come through the downturn, and the appetite for just absolute costs versus performance tends to shift. We're definitely -- it sounds like we are seeing a shift back in terms of willingness to spend more to get more productivity as opposed to a focus on absolute cost. Is that a fair characterization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's fair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, second question, if I look at the comment on the OGX arrangement, I think that sort of this business model approach that you have in projects like this is truly unique and different. If I think about what growth in that market -- or that opportunity set looks like over the next few years, is the constraint more Schlumberger's appetite for risk and finding the right type of projects or is it really in educating the client in terms of the value proposition of what you're doing in that kind of arrangement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So firstly, obviously, post Macondo the assessment of risk has become a much more important criteria before going into the execution of those types of projects. So, I mean, we actually have had an ongoing program since Macondo to not only review all the &#x2013; the products and services of Schlumberger that provide barriers to influx, but also reviewing, obviously, all the IPM projects where we have responsibility for it. So risk is a consideration but not something that's going to stop us doing it. It's more a question of the type of customer, educating the customer, and getting the customer to accept that we have all the competence necessary.</p>
          <p>So the OGX arrangement is probably the most advanced one of those that we have. We have others where we provide probably the same degree of supervision, but we don't take the same degree of responsibility or risk. And so, actually, I think that the extent to which that market grows, Michael, is going to be a function of the type of operators that spring up. And we have a similar project in Middle East/Asia, which is basically where we're acting for a consortium of local companies who've decided they want to be in the E&amp;P business. But I really think it's going to depend on how the client base evolves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could just ask one follow-up on that. If I look at the portfolio of some of the -- BP, for example, in terms of the review, post Macondo, of &#x2013; call it the proliferation of potential daughter companies, I would imagine that that would invite a pretty interesting opportunity set?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, we are seeing private equity look at this. But the risk profile for private equity is difficult to manage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mike Urban from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wanted to dig in a little bit on the reorganization you're undertaking along product lines. And I was just wondering if that -- one, what's driving that? And two, is that something that you were looking at prior to the Smith deal or is there something unique about the portfolio of assets that you have acquired that's pushing you in that direction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, look, you -- this is a slightly structural question. When we set up the GeoMarket system 12 years ago, we actually had about seven product lines at the time. And therefore, to shift responsibility for management from product line to geography was not -- it was not impossible to shift a large part of the responsibility. We now have 15 product lines, and therefore, no human being is capable of intelligently managing 15 product lines. And we've learned a lot about how the geographical organization works. And whereas it works extremely well for bidding of services, it is not so strong for the bidding of products, because when you sell products, you need to base your pricing off the manufacturing costs.</p>
          <p>And therefore, the shift back to groups and segments represents the recognition that this is a much larger company, and it needs a different management style if we are going to carry it forward intelligently. It does not in any way detract from the ability of the GeoMarket system to provide a sound, intelligent customer interface locally around the world and, secondly, to run the lowest cost support operation possible for those 15 different product lines. That's the basic underlying theory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Makes sense. Along those lines, how are you balancing the two? In other words, there are some risks in going too far down that path and thinking in kind of a -- somewhat of a silo mentality. And one of the advantages that Schlumberger has always brought is the whole is more than the parts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The GeoMarket managers bring that together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's still very much intact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's all for me, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Robin Shoemaker from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andrew. I wonder if -- going back to North America for a moment, we have seen tremendous activity in the shale plays, as you indicated, in the liquids rich. In the dry gas areas, we're seeing some decline in activity. What is your view of the potential for pricing to be weaker going forward in the dry gas shale plays versus the liquid rich?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, at some point sufficient capacity will come on to bring down pricing across the hydrocarbons spectrum. It doesn't matter whether it's dry gas or liquids. It's a question of at what point, in my opinion, the capacity in the market overtakes the demand --total demand. And I don't -- I mean, I'm going to stick my neck out now and say I don't think that's going to happen till in the second quarter or third quarter of next year, but there is a risk it will eventually happen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Another question I had was you've mentioned this year that a great deal of your time has been devoted to the Smith acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wonder if you could share with us, going forward, what would be your highest priorities for your time and attention across all the challenges you face?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that Smith will continue to be a priority for at least another year or 18 months. We've kept the integration team well staffed. We are managing closely the relationship between the Smith companies and the Schlumberger companies, and progressing quite rapidly across the integration, but it -- like any problem that is basically a human one, it requires a great deal of attention and a lot of communication. So I will continue to watch that. And then the obvious other one is ensuring that the passage from me to my successor goes smoothly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Geoff Kieburtz from Weeden. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. A couple of small questions for Simon. When you talked about the tax rate in the fourth quarter, are you saying that there's going to be another 300 basis point increase in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, Geoff, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would that then be the reasonable run rate for 2011, obviously subject to mix profit contribution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, subject to mix and some restructuring that we will start undertaking in 2011, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Could you elaborate a little bit on that, what restructuring -- is this a continuation of what you've got underway, or is there additional restructuring?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I didn't mean a &#x2013; well it's more the restructuring for the Smith companies that we acquired, and this ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It takes some time, Geoff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. The -- in the charges, I was I guess a little bit surprised at the magnitude of the WesternGeco charges, can you elaborate at all on your..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so firstly the Q charges, first generation Q, which now we have unique in the field, it's very obvious that that is going to be obsolete very quickly. So we're biting the bullet on what remains of the net book value and spare parts for first generation Q. And electromagnetics, we downmanned our vessels. So the essential of that charge is the termination of the lease on the vessel, as well as an equity investment we had in another technology that we don't want to continue.</p>
          <p>That does not mean we have exited the electromagnetics market. We can still bid and we can reman a vessel as necessary. And we have stayed very much in the land acquisition market for electromagnetics, as well as the processing and interpretation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And in terms of technologies, you highlight this Wireline Dielectric Scanner, I may be making this a bigger thing than it is, but is this part of your thoughts, Andrew, about the development of gas shales in particular, moving out of brute force and ignorance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No, this is not gas shale. This is a technology that has been around for a long time, but until fairly recently, it was almost impossible to build the antenna and the electronics to put it into service.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we're highlighting it, it's because probably it is likely to be the most successful wireline tool we've introduced for a long time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Could I ask you to elaborate a little bit on the brute force and ignorance topic? Do you see changes going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that, actually, I was a little premature with that remark. I think that as completion technology improves, the economic effectiveness of brute force is still there -- in the U.S. -- not overseas, but in the U.S. And probably a technology change is going to be dependent on other things. I mean it's going to be dependent on water usage. It's going to be dependent on somebody coming with a really good sweet spot identifying suite of logging-while-drilling, but it's still somewhere away, Geoff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Doug Becker from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It looks like you guys are going to have a modest decline in oil service CapEx relative to previous expectations. Is this a function of reallocating some capital post the Smith acquisition or is there another driver there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you referring to fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Essentially just the 2.8 billion for Schlumberger oil services going down to 2.5.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think -- has it gone down, Simon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, as a matter of fact, in the Q4 we don't &#x2013; maybe as compared to what we previously announced we did go a little bit down, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, just relative to what was previously announced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's nothing to do with Smith. It may be to do with the Macondo effect and it may be due to the fact that some of the restructuring we've been doing is leading to much greater operating efficiency of our equipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not a significant shift in terms of our outlook or anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's what I was leading to. And then in terms of the international rate of recovery accelerating, just want to better calibrate that. Is that a -- you mentioned it by rig count, is it revenue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say it's projects starting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one last quick one, you mentioned the North Sea and the healthy improvements there. Others have specifically mentioned Norway as an area of weakness. Any thoughts on what might be the cause of the divergence?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I -- I mean, you know, we -- I don't know. We're very much a drilling company, drilling and evaluation company. Other companies are more completion companies, but we didn't see any notable decline. On the contrary, in our production business in the North Sea -- in Norway, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your final question today comes from the even of Ole Slorer with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Couple of questions. One is on the deepwater completion and the second one will be on the deepwater exploration in 2011. First, one of your competitors have argued that they are introducing a deepwater completion tool that's cutting rig time by 60%, 70%. Do you see this as a major threat to your deepwater position? Or -- or how do you intend to respond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually, I'm quite surprised that it's seen as such cutting edge because I think BJ, through the OSCA acquisition, has a very similar system and so do we. So, they may have -- there may be something I just don't know about this, but we don't see any reason for it to be a huge competitive threat to us or others at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question is on deepwater exploration outside the Gulf of Mexico and outside Brazil. There seems to be quite a lot of initiatives kicking off next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you share with us your view on 2011 as a deepwater exploration year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't ask me to quantify it, Ole, but every indication would be that it's going to be a much stronger year. And as you say, there already projects opening up in new provinces around the world which are really quite, quite ambitious.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's going to be a better year, but don't ask me to say by how much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but it just appears they'll be going after some world-class initiatives in several basins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I agree with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>On behalf of the Schlumberger management team, I would like to thank you for participating in today's call. Greg will now provide the closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, this conference will be available for replay after 10:30 Central Time today, through November 22nd . You may access the AT&amp;T teleconference replay system at any time by dialing 1-800-475-6701 and entering the access code 166349. International participants dial 320-365-3844. Those numbers once again are 1-800-475-6701 or 320-365-3844 with the access code 166349. That does conclude your conference for today. Thank you for your participation and for using AT&amp;T Executive Teleconference. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>