<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1142883" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>462</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Malcolm Theobald, Vice President of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Simon Ayat, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Andrew Gould, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michael LaMotte</participant>
      <participant id="5">Andrew Gould</participant>
      <participant id="6">Bill Herbert</participant>
      <participant id="7">Dan Pickering</participant>
      <participant id="8">Charles Minervino</participant>
      <participant id="9">Simon Ayat</participant>
      <participant id="10">J. David Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="11">Geoff Kieburtz</participant>
      <participant id="12">James Crandell</participant>
      <participant id="13">Brad Handler</participant>
      <participant id="14">Ken Sill</participant>
      <participant id="15">Kevin Simpson</participant>
      <participant id="16">Benjamin Dell</participant>
      <participant id="17">Pierre Conner</participant>
      <participant id="18">Kurt Hallead</participant>
      <participant id="19">Robin Shoemaker</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the Schlumberger Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all phone participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, there will be an opportunity for questions. Instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And as a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Vice President of Investor Relations for Schlumberger Limited, Malcolm Theobald. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gayle. Welcome to today's first quarter 2008 results conference call for Schlumberger Limited. Before we begin, I'd like to review the logistics and format of today's call. Some of the information in today's call may include forward-looking statements as well as non-GAAP financial measures. A detailed disclaimer and other information are included in the FAQ document which is available on our website or on request.</p>
          <p>And now for the call participants and format. Joining the call from New Delhi, India are both Andrew Gould, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; and Simon Ayat, our Chief Financial Officer. Prior to Andrew's overview of the first quarter and his comments on the outlook, Simon will first review the quarter's financial results.</p>
          <p>And now I'll turn the call over to Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Malcolm. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for participating in this conference call. First quarter income from continuing operations was $1.06 per share down $0.05 sequentially and $0.10 above the same quarter of last year. An additional $0.03 gain was reported in discontinued operations.</p>
          <p>Oilfield Services' first quarter revenue grew 3% sequentially reflecting growth in North America and Europe/CIS/Africa areas. The seasonal year-end strength in Artificial Lift and completions equipment sales as well as SIS software sales reverted to normal levels in Q1, while traditional service segments such as Wireline, Drilling and Measurements and Well Services showed sequential growth. WesternGeco reported weak multi-client sales, only partly offset by an improvement in marine activity.</p>
          <p>Oilfield Services generated 1.5 billion in pre-tax operating income, down $33 million from the fourth quarter of last year, but margins declined by 140 basis points to 26.8%. By area, Oilfield Services' highlights were as follows. My comments are on a sequential basis. North America pre-tax margin improved 21 basis points to 25.6% with strong seasonal activity in Canada and Alaska, augmented by a full recovery in the Gulf Coast with the return of deep water rigs. More than offsetting land access operational restriction in the Rockies, winter weather in U.S. north and pricing deterioration for well stimulation-related services in the U.S. central market.</p>
          <p>Latin America pre-tax margin declined by 203 basis points to 20.1%.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, IPM projects' rig count continue to grow with more activity but increased levels of projects startup costs and a high proportion of third party managed services impacted our margins negatively.</p>
          <p>Reduced activity and the less favorable revenue mix due to project delays in Peru, Colombia, Ecuador, and Brazil GeoMarkets also reduced margins.</p>
          <p>For ECA &#x2013; the Europe, CIS and Africa area &#x2013; the pre-tax margin declined 163 basis points to 26.3%. As Russia exhibited the seasonal slowdown of shore cycling and incurred the startup cost for several new projects while operational delays in the North Sea hampered drilling and measurement activity.</p>
          <p>Strong activity was reported in the West Africa, Caspian and Continental Europe GeoMarkets. The area included the consolidation of FRAMO for the first time.</p>
          <p>Middle East Asia pre-tax margin declined by 10 basis points to 34.9%. While the year-end high level of Artificial Lift and completions equipment sale, particularly in the Arabian GeoMarket was not repeated, exploration driven improvements in the Australia, Thailand, Vietnam, East Mediterranean and Gulf GeoMarkets more than offset seasonal weather slowdown in the China, Japan, Korea GeoMarket.</p>
          <p>WesternGeco pre-tax income of $196 million was a sequential drop in margin by 502 basis points to 29.1%. The reduction in multi-client sales and margins following the record sale in the previous quarter more than offset the modest recovery in Marine performance.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Schlumberger as a whole. The effective tax rate was 19.1%, which was lower than last quarter. The decrease was primarily attributable to the favorable resolution of tax examination in a number of countries. The ETR is expected to be in the low 20s for the total year 2008.</p>
          <p>The earnings for the quarter included $41 million of expenses relating to stock based compensation costs. Net debt of $2.2 billion at the end of the quarter. Significant liquidity events during the quarter included $564 million for a stock buyback program and $873 million for CapEx, including multi-client. CapEx excluding $81 million of multi-client surveyed capitalized was $772 million for the quarter.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we bought back 7 million shares for $564 million at an average price of $81.16 per share. As we are approaching the completion of the 40 million share buyback, the Board of Directors approved a new repurchase program for $8 billion to be completed before the end of 2011.</p>
          <p>And now I turn the conference over to Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Simon and good morning everybody. Seasonal factors, weather-related events as well as lower product and software sales following the exceptional levels in the fourth quarter had a general dampening effect on sequential revenue gains with a consequent effect on margins.</p>
          <p>Oilfield Services revenue growth was strongest in the Canada, U.S. Gulf Coast, South Russia, Australia, Papua New Guinea, West &amp; South Africa and Alaska GeoMarkets. Sequential revenue also grew through consolidation of FRAMO into the Europe, CIS, Africa Area. Among the technologies, demand was strongest for Wireline, Drilling and Measurements, Well Services and Well Testing activities.</p>
          <p>In terms of geography, North America recorded the strongest growth as activity increased in the Gulf of Mexico with the return of deepwater rigs, together with stronger demand for Wireline and Drilling and Measurements exploration related-services. Canada saw a robust winter drilling season with high demand for Wireline services in a renewed exploration market as well as for Well Services technologies. Alaska benefited from exploration-related growth. The combination of these factors which largely outweighed seasonal and weather events as well as lower product flow translated into stronger margins although pricing weakness continued to be seen in U.S. Central for well stimulation related activities.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, growth was strongest in the Venezuela, Trinidad and Tobago GeoMarket from higher demand for Drilling &amp; Measurements, Wireline and Well Services as well as from higher SIS product sales. However, this was more than offset by project transitions and delays in Peru, Colombia, Ecuador and in Mexico and Central America. Lower Artificial Lift and SIS product sales also offset overall growth.</p>
          <p>Against the slight decline in revenue, margins lowered more significantly as the Integrated Project Management activity in Mexico continued its rapid ramp up of new projects with an additional seven drilling rigs being deployed in the quarter resulting in heavy initial startup costs being incurred. The majority of these new projects are in areas where wells are much deeper and hotter and as a result take longer to drill.</p>
          <p>Growth in the Europe, CIS and Africa was driven by a variety of positive factors. These included the higher Artificial Lift Systems sales and increased Well Services market penetration in South Russia, strong demand for Well Services technologies in Continental Europe, increased demand for Drilling &amp; Measurements technologies in West and Southern Africa and the Caspian and higher IPM and Drilling &amp; Measurements activity in North Africa. Area sequential growth also benefited from the consolidation of FRAMO revenue. These positive factors were, however, mitigated by operational delays in the North Sea, winter weather in East Russia, and lower SIS product sale.</p>
          <p>Sequential revenue in Middle East and Asia area declined slightly as exploration-driven growth for Wireline and Well Testing services in the Australia, Papua New Guinea GeoMarket together with strong demand for Wireline, Well Testing and Well Services in the Gulf, East Mediterranean and Thailand, Vietnam GeoMarkets were offset by the impact of winter weather in the China, Japan, Korea and lower completions in Artificial Lift Systems product sales also contributed to this performance.</p>
          <p>At WesternGeco, first quarter results fell sequentially as Multiclient revenue declined steeply from the record levels of the fourth quarter. The Gulf of Mexico lease sale late in the first quarter, coupled with the increased cost of wide-azimuthal data sets that are fast becoming the norm for new Multiclient purchases, delayed new sales activity until customers absorb the results of the March leasing round. In contrast, however, Marine revenue increased as both vessel utilization and productivity improved following the vessel dry-docks and the seasonal transits of the prior quarter. Data processing recorded a sequential increase in revenue while land declined as a result of project completions in North Africa and lower demand in the Middle East.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead in the short to medium term we expect a number of scheduled dry-dock expense and vessel transit in the second quarter as activity switches from winter to summer seasons. While the uneven pattern in Multiclient activity is likely to persist throughout the year.</p>
          <p>WesternGeco technology applications saw growth during the quarter with a conformation of a further set of Q-Marine time-lapse service in the Norwegian sector of the North Sea for StatoilHydro on the Norne and Heidrun fields. These surveys represent the fifth successive survey at Norne and the third at Heidrun. Both form part of the ongoing efforts to maximize recovery from both fields through the identification of unswept and partially swept areas.</p>
          <p>Q-Technology has also been selected for deployment of Q-Seabed surveys on the Oseberg Sor and Gullfaks fields, where the technology's low-frequency capability is considered to be of particular value.</p>
          <p>And in the sub-salt environment of the U.S. Gulf of Mexico, processing has begun of integrated Q-Marine gravity and magnetotelluric electromagnetic data sets that form part of the E-Octopus Multiclient wide-azimuth acquisition program.</p>
          <p>Other new technology applications include well services FUTUR active set-cement which provides long-term zonal isolation through self-healing properties upon contact with any hydrocarbon based formation fluid. In Canada, this unique technology was used in an active geological area where maintaining cement integrity has been problematic. And in Italy, its use began on a 50-well natural gas storage field to prevent leakage of storage gas where wells are subject to alternating injection and production, in line with storage gas use.</p>
          <p>Another new Well Services technology unique to Schlumberger, ACTive coiled-tubing, was deployed in Western Canada and Malaysia. The ACTive family of services uses fiber-optic cable in a downhole sensor package to monitor progress from a range of coiled-tubing enabled operations in real time.</p>
          <p>In addition to these technology deployments, we passed a significant milestone in recruiting and training during the quarter with the opening of the Siberian Training Center in the Russian Federation in March. This new center includes all the facilities needed to train and develop our Russian languages employees in artificial lift, directional drilling, well cementing and stimulation, data services and information solutions, as well as integrated project management. The current training capacity is expected to double over the next year to reach 350 students.</p>
          <p>In closing, I would like to reiterate some comments that I made at the Howard Weil conference in New Orleans earlier this month. In the absence of severe global recession leading to a steep drop in demand, the thin cushion of excess oil supply and the failure to stem decline rates in many countries, coupled with a higher-than-expected drawdown of U.S. natural gas storage, are all factors that lead us to conclude the growth will strengthen as the year progresses. We remain convinced that current investment levels are insufficient to both stem decline and to explore and develop new reserves. As a result, we anticipate that the current cycle of exploration and production spending will remain stronger for a longer period than we originally anticipated.</p>
          <p>I am now going to hand the call back to Gayle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And our first question will come from Michael LaMotte with JPMorgan.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess first question has to do with the question or the comment that you made on the fourth quarter conference call regarding '08 being a transition year.  Particularly listening to the some of the Geco commentary for Q2 and second half, I'm wondering if you wanted to perhaps revisit that and within the context of is 2008 going to be a transition year or is it a first half transition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, I think that when I made the comment in December, Michael, I was thinking it was a transition year.  I would say that what has happened in North America coupled with as I am sure you've noticed some fairly dramatic declines in oil production in a number of places around the world leads me to believe that absent this global recession, its more and more a year in which growth is going to strengthen significantly in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We've been &#x2013; I guess all eyes have been on Russia and Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Here in first quarter, second quarter timeframe. Anywhere else, I understand seismic activity in India is very robust right now. Anything in the Eastern Hemisphere that we should be keeping an eye on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well India, I mean, we had just held our Board of Directors here because its &#x2013; firstly its our 75th anniversary in India, but secondly because as you say there is a dramatic increase in the willingness of India to find out whether it has any chance of domestic energy security and therefore huge investment in seismic, and hopefully following that exploration drilling; and as you know, they have 1 or 2 very large development programs that are underway.  So, I think that perhaps for us the really interesting thing in Indian seismic is the fact that we have our second largest processing center worldwide in India.  And we work very closely with the Indian industry on how to interpret Q to the maximum advantage.  But it's symptomatic of perhaps the willingness of developing countries to find out what chance they have at energy security.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, should we think about India as seismic for '08, '09 and then exploration drilling in 2010 perhaps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think &#x2013; I don't know their rig &#x2013; I don't think their rig program is fixed yet, but certainly I think that as soon they can get rigs they will start exploration drilling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thank you, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Bill Herbert with Simmons &amp; Company.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Good morning, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to seismic, I'm trying to reconcile on the one hand, the very favorable demand outlook that &#x2013; not only hearing from you but from others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With the fact the backlog has evolved rather slowly over the past 3 to 6 months, were down 20% quarter-on-quarter, walk us through with respect to the intermediate outlook with respect to contracting your vessels, and what we should expect with regard to backlog build as the year unfolds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that some of the significant drop in the backlog is due to the fact that we have some very long-term commitments that have not yet been renewed, but I would say are currently in the state of being bid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I would suspect as &#x2013; just as I said to Michael, now that &#x2013; to look for a significant increase in the backlog, you're probably looking into the second half year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But there is no lack of bids out there.  There is no lack of tendering, believe me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I figured.  Secondly, I was struck with the fact that there was no mention of what's going on with respect to Saudi Arabia and your rumored new contract there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or Manifa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not a rumor.  I mean, but what strikes you Bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there was no mention of it, no detail, no information provided on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you probably realized, we don't make announcements of any individual contract wins that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just more plainly, could you enlighten us as to the parameters of that engagement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so Manifa is, have we started to mobilize equipment?  Yes.  Is it eventually big?  Yes.  Do we &#x2013; when will it start producing incremental revenues?  A little bit in Q2, but the rest of the year, but really ramping up in '09, not '08.  That's about what I would tell you Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all I have.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Dan Pickering with Tudor, Pickering, Holt.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, for the last couple of quarters, you've talked about expectations around the revenue growth in your business. We did not hear that commentary at least this quarter at it relates to kind of where Wall Street is at, but we assume that silence means that expectations are now in generally the right spot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am very comfortable with Wall Street's assumptions on the full year 2008 Dan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fantastic.  Second question, back to the seismic business, last year, end of the year, we sort of saw marine take a fairly significant downtick with some dry dockings and utilization.  It didn't feel like it bounced up much here in the Q1, Andrew, and now we're looking for some more dry docks in Q2.  I guess, were I am going with this, is there a change in the profitability of the marine business or is this just a fairly lengthy period of getting all the assets in the right place?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, I think I would say two things, Dan.  Firstly, there is a considerable pricing difference between winter season and summer season.  And they &#x2013; there is more and more a shift that takes place every winter and summer.  So, the actual number of transits that we do is increasing.  So, I don't think that we feel that that is going to affect the overall profitability of marine if you take it on an annual basis.  But, I've been trying to convey the message that seismic is going to be lumpy, and it's lumpy in both marine and multi-client.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll now go to Chuck Minervino with Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just wanted to touch on Russia a little bit. You saw that oil production was down in 1Q in several companies here obviously, moving aggressively in Russia in the services market.  Can you just talk a little bit about how you're positioned there right now, and really, how you're going to grow? Will it be predominantly organic growth or will it be &#x2013; would you be looking at M&amp;A in Russia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think our feeling is that M&amp;A is &#x2013; Russia is now overpriced.  We've made our big moves and therefore I suspect that going forward, it's going to be organic.  And a lot of it will be IPM. So, I don't &#x2013; we will do some M&amp;A, but nothing like the scale of what we did in the past four or five years.  And, if you look at our business then, the well services market, the fracing market is oversupplied.  The big growth element these days are services around drilling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just another question with regards to the offshore business.  How &#x2013; can you talk a little bit about how your margins are in the offshore business?  And then, as we go forward here with the new-built rigs coming, what that can mean for margins, I guess one, two or maybe three years down the road?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think our offshore margins are fine.  I mean, really &#x2013; there's no significant shift in our offshore margins.  And going forward, the quality of our revenue will improve and the extent to which our quality of revenue improves, really depends on the number of the new rigs that are on exploration, and then the exploration success that they have.  We have huge margin variation between a successful exploration well and an unsuccessful exploration well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's really helpful.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to David Anderson with UBS.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning.  You mentioned just a few minutes ago the growth is going to significantly increase in the second half of the year.  I was wondering if you could expand on that a little bit further. Was that just primarily centered on North America or are those some other regions, because it seems to me that the offshore, the impact of the offshore new build is more of a 2009 event. So just wondering if you could just kind of expand on that a bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that &#x2013; so firstly, you're quite right to point out that the most significant change, compared to what I said in December, because the remarks I made a few minutes ago, were in function of what I said in the December call. A bigger shift is North America, and that's true for revenue as well.  And overseas, I think that firstly, we are &#x2013; I am personally still astonished at the demand for IPM. And I think that the &#x2013; if you like the &#x2013; perhaps we &#x2013; I had underestimated the extent to which land drilling might expand, but I would caution you that this is very much a second-half event.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then just to touch back on Russia, we did notice there were some changes in the upstream tax regime and it didn't &#x2013; doesn't look it's had too much of an impact. Are you feeling a little bit more optimistic that some more material changes could be coming about and is that kind of the next leg as to what's going to spur IPM mark and is this is a 2009 event for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the Russian government will do what is necessary to release the money that is required to increase &#x2013; to sustain or to increase production. In function, their 2% a year objective and I agree with you that what they have announced so far is not sufficient. But I'm pretty sure that they'll get it right in the end.  So, it could &#x2013; you're quite right that largely, it will be a 2009 event.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one last question on Mexico it's on that proposed energy bill. There are some more performance based service contracts that are mentioned in that, in the bill. I was just wondering how does that impact your view on that market, and does &#x2013; once again, getting back to IPM, I guess, does that imply there's more IPM work on the horizon or is it just you're not going to go through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not so much that I think it'll change our IPM programs, but what it will allow us to do, which is going to be a very nice change, is it will allow us to be incentivized on the basis of the performance of technology, which is something very difficult to achieve at &#x2013; under the current contractual regime.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you get pretty optimistic that goes through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's opposed &#x2013; well, I don't know. I'm not speculating on the past ticks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But if it does go through, it's probably a positive for everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to Geoff Kieburtz with Citi.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  I guess, good evening is more appropriate.  The more positive outlook for North America in the prepared comments, there were several references to the continued weakening trend of North American stimulation prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How do you see that playing out? Is your outlook for the North American market sufficiently more positive that you think that will turn around?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we've seen the bottom &#x2013; or we're seeing the bottom right now. Now obviously, contractually, most of what we're going to do in 2008 is tied up.  There is obviously some capacity that is not tied up and, depending on the size of the rig count increase, there might be a little bit of pricing levers towards the end of the year, but, that's not clear yet.  What I can say fairly definitively, is we see in stimulation services pricing is bottoming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you see pricing leverage in any other product lines in...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that drilling and measurements &#x2013; anything to do with directional drilling in the North American market, as in most other markets, still has some pricing leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And shifting to Latin America, could you maybe give us a little bit more historical context?  I mean, we heard in the fourth quarter, we're hearing again in the first quarter about startup costs on IPM projects, principally in Mexico.  That's been a very big business for you for some time. What's going on? Are the projects shifting to different locations or what kind of is going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the answer is both.  In other words, the projects are shifting to different locations, so the two large projects we've been mobilizing in the last six months, are both in Villa Hermosa Basin which is deep and hot. And at the same time, we've been mobilizing again rigs to Chicontepec and we will, in the second quarter, be mobilizing Burgos seven.  So, Burgos seven and Chicontepec, if you like, is the traditional IPM activity in Mexico, the stuff in the south is the new IPM activity in Mexico</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Both volume and mixed, Andy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Both volume and mix.  But the whole number of contracts, our IPM tenders have changed scale in the last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And your comment about IPM more broadly, because you've mentioned it in the context of other regions as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we hear or interpret those comments to mean that we are going to see more of this where projects startup margin effects become more common?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think we'll have many projects that start on the scale of what we're starting in Mexico.  So to that extent, no.  There will, I think, be a project startup effect in every quarter, but probably at a decreasing level, at least for the balance of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A decreasing level per quarter Geoff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now go to Jim Crandell with Lehman Brothers.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As a follow up on that question Andrew on the IPM business, do you see the IPM business getting more price competitive today?  And if it is going to spread, will more and more NOCs be looking for increased price concessions on IPM work in the future if it's competitively bid?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean firstly we don't, I don't, I know what you've been hearing Jim.  We don't see IPM as being any more price competitive today than it was two or three years ago.  What is true is that every time we go to a new basin, there is a learning curve, and going up that learning curve takes a little time, but once you're up it, you actually have a huge competitive advantage.  And we just celebrated drilling our one thousandth well in the Burgos field.  When you've drilled a thousand wells you probably have a pretty good knowledge of how to do it.  And actually the levels of return we make out of those projects have improved over time, whatever's happened to the pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And I have a question also about sort of E&amp;P spending Andrew.  Our work suggests that we've added upwards of $10 billion now the E&amp;P spends since our survey was published in December, and maybe 40% of that is in North America.  Do you think as you look at the U.S. today that we could be looking at additions of somewhere in the range of 200 to 250 rigs over the course of this year?  And internationally I guess would you think that the recovery is stronger than what you'd thought previously given budget announcements and the higher oil prices and that you could with some confidence now look at least a 20% revenue growth in your international oil service businesses in '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I mean I feel quite confident that the international spending is going to increase, and we weren't that far from the number you mentioned.  So it's not in any way impossible.  I think in terms of North America, I don't really have a good enough read to know whether it's 100 or 200 rigs yet.  I don't know.  I think it'll depend a little bit on the economy and a little bit on the capacity of the industry to follow.  But it's not impossible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You said 200 and 250, I don't feel confident yet of that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  But you will -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was just U.S..  That was just U.S., Jim, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just U.S. Andrew.  And one other quick question, Andrew how many in total seismic vessels between Eastern Echo and what you are building, you were intending to build anyway, do you have on, either on order or in the plan, and can you give me a rough idea on the timing of delivery of those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have 8 vessels on order.  We will get one more this year which is not an Eastern Echo one, it's a Blue Arrow, which will come in the third quarter.  We will start taking delivery of Eastern Echo in Q1 next year, and substantially most of Eastern Echo should be in the course of '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you.  Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question is from Brad Handler with Wachovia.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Hello guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you please speak some more to the buying behavior related to wide and rich azimuth multiclient?  I guess, I'm just, I'm a little confused about whether or not there is some sacrifice of sales that gets made if you sell things after a specific oil company has the lease sale, as opposed to before when you might have had more bidders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that your point is a valid point.  But actually what it does is to add an additional risk, which is that you shot your seismic in the right place for that particular client to buy it, as he's buying it when he knows what lease he has.  Whereas before he was buying much cheaper seismic, but on the basis that he would be, he might be bidding any number of blocks.  So it does add an additional risk, but I'm not uncomfortable with the coverage that we have in view of the last lease sale.  I think there are three things in the multi-client for 2008.  The first is there was some buying in Q4 in anticipation of the lease sale.  The second is the lease sale was extremely late in the quarter and has all the implications of wide azimuth data.  And the third is that we have three phases of E-Octopus to deliver during the second half of the year, which will add a considerable volume of new product to our library.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  If I could stay with this just for a couple of other follow-ups, I just want to sort of make sure I get it.  So assuming the risk variable, and I appreciate you telling us about that, assuming that that works itself out favorably, do you have any reason to think that your wide azimuth prospects have lessened relative to what you may have thought about a year or two ago when you first sort of ventured into the Gulf of Mexico region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wide azimuth?  No, I don't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so the pricing dynamic is -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There may be timing differences, but I don't think it's lessened overall volume prospects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's helpful.  Is it fair for us to think about 2Q as having a pretty healthy snap-back in multi-client based on the fact that we've gotten through this lease sale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think more in terms of the second half year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because as I said we have new product to deliver and I don't think we'll deliver a lot of it in Q2, and there is another lease sale coming up in October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then is pre-funding levels changing at all as it relates to wide-azimuth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are not as healthy as they were I think perhaps two or three years ago when we were pre-funding normal, reprocessing projects and normal 3D, but they're still pretty healthy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I guess getting back to that risk point you made.  Okay.  One sort of side, I'm not sure if it's important at all, but there was a press release by Electromagnetic Geoservices about a patent case in Netherlands.  Again forgive me if this is completely trivial, but is that at all relevant to your business, does it at all hamper any of your efforts for the wreck  specific to ian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  I think, the press release I felt was somewhat disingenuous.  The Dutch Court did not rule, it deferred the decision to the European Patent Office.  So, no patents were validated or invalidated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Ken Sill with Credit Suisse.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Andrew, I wanted to ask a question something that's kind of popped up in the comments as an area of weakness was Schlumberger Information Systems. It was, is weak in North America and a lot of other regions.  I wonder if you could give us a little bit of insight into &#x2013; is this another business that's going to be seasonal or was this just a year-on-year rollover?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's traditionally SIS Information Systems.  It's a bit like seismic in as much as customers use up their budgets at year end to purchase software.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In a year when our growth rate is a bit slower than it was in the past two years, that shows up in Q1 as opposed to Q4.  So we had very, very high sales in Q4 and lower sales in Q1, but it's not new, it's just showing up more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I knew it had been there.  My next question was kind of, is this something that, are the margins in Information System Solution very different from what you're getting in your kind of core oilfield service businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if this would be a high-margin business, would--</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a software business, yeah, this is a software business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so and then in terms of the seasonal recovery, kind of expect something gradual building to a year-end crescendo again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  So just, and then to kind of close the gap here, so you are very happy with where Wall Street is for the year.  Obviously, we have the pattern wrong, pretty clearly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What is your outlook now for 2009?  I know it's awful early, but if you are going to have the deepwater rigs on, North America will be growing fairly substantially, I mean does tightening up North America help pricing power globally in the outlook for '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it would need quite a lot of tightening to &#x2013; basically you are talking about pressure pumping, the segments where Schlumberger participates, you are talking about pressure pumping.  And I think that it would take quite a lot of tightening to really affect overseas markets, and I was warned by Malcolm that somebody would ask me about '09.  So, my gut feeling, and it's no more than a gut feeling, is that '09 will be better than '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of growth, overall growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In overall growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know that doesn't help you very much, but really it is awfully early.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, and yeah, you don't want to get too excited about things, but just wanted to kind of get your feel for that early in the year.  Okay, thank you, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to Kevin Simpson with Miller Tabak.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Andrew, I'm wondering about profit margins.  They came in a little bit below my expectations for oilfield in a couple markets.  Latin America obviously I guess is a function of, to some degree, Mexico and other issues and then the Europe/CIS.  Do you expect that &#x2013; I mean I'm wondering if margins have peaked for the cycle or are these just, kind of short-term factors and there's still margin upside particularly in the Eastern Hemisphere markets where you're so strong?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think you can make a judgment on the basis of Q1.  So, Latin America is very definitely a function of Mexico, but also the project disruption that I pointed out in Peru, Colombia and Ecuador, and a little bit in the south where we had an activity stoppage.  And in Europe/Africa/CIS, I would say that there is no reason to suppose that is gone down permanently.  It's largely seasonal, plus the inclusion of Framo as a consolidated item for the first time, before it was an equity pickup.  And Framo's margins while very healthy, are not at the same level as OFS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So, there's a little bit of an apples-to-oranges comp there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then, you've talked about the tight global supplies and one of the issues that I have is that governments around the world seem to be with collective greed conspiring to slow things down.  Is that a significant concern of yours?  I mean Russia being one place that's pretty obvious, but other places as well, for instance, Venezuela?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alaska?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>U.S. I suppose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're quite correct, it is a concern, Kevin.  It is a concern that our governments think they can tax $100 oil with impunity and that's not the case.  And it's not so much the amount of the tax, it's the fact that it produces a degree of uncertainty into our customers' investment decision and therefore they have to presume a certain degree of risk which makes them shy.  So, you're quite right to point out it's a concern.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, to some degree, in a way, it's baked into your thinking that high-comfort level that the '09 growth is going to be--</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll say comfortably in excess of-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>'09 growth is more dependent on offshore which as you know is very long-term.  Therefore, governments tend to behave more rationally, if you like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>They have less leverage there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.  That's it for me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll now go to Ben Dell with Bernstein.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I know you've had a lot of questions around the seismic business, but maybe I could just ask one on 2009.  We obviously have a big stream of capacity expansion which actually accelerates into 2009.  How do you see that impacting margins in this business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If there is an erosion in marine margins, it's going to be towards the end of 2009, it's not going to be at the beginning.  And in fact, capacity is so solidly absorbed for 2008 that any erosion in 2009 is going to be minor. I would worry more about 2010 if I were you, because 2009, there is a clear demand to date.  And you can match that demand to the capacity that's coming on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and when you look at the application of multi-azimuth seismic outside of the Gulf of Mexico.  Obviously, the Gulf's got pretty unique geology in terms of its salt diapirs, which other basins do you see that being applied to it because it appears that only really Angola has the potential for sub-salt salt diapirs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>West Africa, I mean Nigeria, some of the deepwater in Nigeria, some of Brazil, there's certainly applications in India where I am now, but it's actually more basalt than salt, which is a slightly different problem.  There are applications in the northern parts of the North Sea again it's largely, it's basalt rather than salt.  But you're quite right to point out that the two large markets are the Gulf of Mexico and West Africa, but I wouldn't rule out Nigeria.  I wouldn't say just Angola.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And just lastly, you mentioned your seismic vessel additions. Did you cancel the options on the 5th and 6th Eastern Echo boats or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we didn't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go to Pierre Conner with Capital One Southcoast.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was close, but good morning gentlemen.  Most of the questions have been answered, but maybe a little bit more on marine, and the pre-funding. Andrew could you, would you care to speculate a little bit, you did mention that it was, I think down sequentially from where it had been, but could you tell us where you might expect pre-funding to end up on some of your large multi-client Gulf of Mexico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, probably, I should have been more explicit Pierre. One of the things that is happening is, we were pre-funding reprocessing projects, where the actual investment on our part was much smaller than in multi-client acquisition, and therefore we had very, very high pre-funding ratios and they were very often way over 100%.  So, our pre-funding ratios in function of the acquisition programs have dropped below a 100%, but I would still describe them as healthy and we tend not to commit unless we feel we have an adequate pre-funding ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on an, I think that is helpful color, because your point isn't on an absolute basis.  Is that what your commentary is about the library sales, that basically the budgets are such people are spending it on the pre-funding of enhanced azimuth information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but there is still an after-sales market beyond the pre-funding in wide azimuth.  It's just that, that's why I mentioned this additional risk factor that your wide azimuth is in the right place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  The other one where &#x2013; just a little bit more color again had to do with IPM startups and I appreciate that you have addressed a number of the issues related to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, to the extent we could get a feel for how much are we through the start-up cost and maybe some &#x2013; how many rigs we have on IPM and where do you expect that to be at the end of '08?  Is that in terms of increases and if it gives us a color.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But, I mean, in the last year we've started about 35 rigs.  We're going to start another six, but they're the Burgos ones in Q2.  And Burgos ones I really don't think there'll be start-up issue.  And so that leaves another 10 around the world for the balance of the year.  So, I think, it's safe to assume that the start-up cost element in the quarterly results will decrease from now going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's the color I was looking for.  The rest has been answered.  Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will go to Kurt Hallead with RBC Capital Markets.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just going to hit you all right with this one.  So, when do you think the peak is, Andrew, 2013 or 2015?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you're going to have to make so many assumptions on the economy and all the rest of it, that that's a very, very difficult one to call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But let's say predicated on the decline rates you see in Mexico and Canterell and some issues in Russia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think this cycle is going to peak without a drop in demand.  And a drop in demand can come two ways, it can come violently through a global economic recession or it can come gradually, which is through the gradual substitution of hydrocarbons with other sources of energy.  And if that's the case, it's a long &#x2013; any transition to meaningful volumes of another source of energy is a decade or longer.  So, take your pick which way it's going to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in that period from 1970 to 1980, according to kind of stats I've pulled together, E&amp;P spending grew like 25% year on average over that decade.  Do you think there's a possibility that the next five years or so could replicate that 25% a year on E&amp;P spend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You see, I think this cycle is very different from 1970 to 1980 and it's different in two senses.  One is that in 1970 to 1980, I think that there was some physical shortage, but really it was a political shortage.  And the other thing is that the developments that took place in the 1970s, which were basically added six or seven million barrels or even more a day, where Alaska, Mexico and North Sea and those discoveries were made in the 1960s.  So, there was no exploration to be done.  So, this time I think it's much more difficult, if you like, to see where the development is going to come that is going to produce significant volumes except for the Middle East, Central Asia and Russia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, And how do we -how can we &#x2013; how should, do you think we consider your growth rate opportunity in Brazil, follow on with the 2P and now some of this chatter around the Carioca field? Where's your opportunity set down there? Maybe you could discuss it by product line importance?  And then how should we think about the growth rates in Brazil in general?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that I would characterize 2008 is good and 2009 is excellent. Basically because the large addition of floaters is going to be in 2009 not 2008.  And actually we're very &#x2013; we're mostly very pleased with what we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's for Brazil, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brazil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  And how about in terms of product line importance for you in Brazil, how would you rank it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's very important for wireline, it's extremely important for testing.  It's important for D&amp;M but not as important as it should be.  And well services and the others have a presence, but we have a very satisfactory position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I may just close out here, is there any, is the opportunity set on land in Brazil, is there any good possibilities there or is it mostly just going to be the offshore as we've heard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is some opportunity on land, but it's not going to be anything on the same scale as offshore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our final question today comes from Robin Shoemaker with Bear Stearns.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andrew.  In your Q&amp;A, you have the statement that you're 33% third-party content in IPM and that that will be increasing to mid-40s.  Is this increasing content of third-party services in any way related to the delays you are experiencing?  And what should we think about in terms of overall integrated project margins as third-party content increases from 33% to the mid-40s?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I don't think it's a question of delay; it's more a question of different work scopes.  Simon, would you like to comment on the margin evolution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, you're raising a very valid question here about the third-party element of our services provided under the IPM contracts.  These don't attract the same type of margin we generate on our services.  Our services are at least the same type of margin, we generate or even better.  Now the third-party we do cover our costs associated with them, but they are lower margin.  Now what you've seen the 33 versus the 40% through the year, I don't think it's going to affect the overall margins of the projects, because the efficiency on the rest of the activity will be more than compensating the small deterioration that a 7% increase will cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then the only other question I had was Andrew you commented on a little bit on the acquisitions market, the M&amp;A market in Russia, as somewhat overpriced.  Can you comment overall on Schlumberger's acquisition strategy?  We see recently a lot of M&amp;A activity and also private equity getting involved in purchasing oil field service assets and companies.  Can we read into this enhanced &#x2013; expanded share buyback program that there is perhaps a little less attractive acquisition opportunities for Schlumberger?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, in the calculation of the amount of cash available for buyback we have assumed the same level of acquisitions as we've generally been practicing over the last three or four years.  Now, I don't think you will see us as I've said on many occasions make a major acquisition particularly at these valuations.  However, increasingly we will make niche acquisitions largely for parts of our service line that we don't have all four technology opportunities that we identify.  But, it doesn't, the programme in itself does not signal any reduction in our acquisition strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>On behalf of the Schlumberger management team, I would like to thank you for participating in today's call.  Gayle will now provide the closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, today's conference is being made available for replay after 11:30 AM. Eastern Time today through May 18th at midnight.  You may access the AT&amp;T replay system at any time by dialing 800-475-6701 and entering the access code 915-451. International participants may dial 320-365-3844.  Those numbers again are 800-475-6701, international participants dial 320-365-3844 entering the access code 915-451.  That does conclude your conference for today.  Thank you for your participation and for using the AT&amp;T executive teleconference service.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>