<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1171214" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>469</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David M. Ratcliffe, Chairman, President, and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">W. Paul Bowers, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Leslie Rich</participant>
      <participant id="4">David Ratcliffe</participant>
      <participant id="5">W. Paul Bowers</participant>
      <participant id="6">Nathan Judge</participant>
      <participant id="7">Angie Storozynski</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jeff Coviello</participant>
      <participant id="9">Steve Gambuzza</participant>
      <participant id="10">Timothy Yee</participant>
      <participant id="11">Andrew Levi</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. My name is Kimberly and I will be your conference operator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the Southern Company Second Quarter 2008 Earnings Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. David Ratcliffe, President and Chairman and Chief Executive Officer. Please go ahead, Sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kimberly. Good afternoon and thank you for joining us. I am pleased to be with you for our second quarter earnings call. Joining me today is Paul Bowers, our Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Let me remind you that we will make forward-looking statements today in addition to providing historical information. There are various important factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from those indicated in the forward-looking statements including those discussed in our Form 10-K and subsequent SEC filings.</p>
          <p>The materials we released this morning show our continued strong performance and that we're on track to meet our earnings target for the year. Our business model as you know is not tied to spark spreads or to volatility in the price of natural gas, and ours is not a merchant energy business. Nearly all of our earnings are produced from our franchise business and from long term wholesale power agreements. Our strategy is very straight forward and has produced positive concrete results for both customers and shareholders.</p>
          <p>In an environment of increasing cost from environmental expenditures, new generation to meet increased load, and rising fuel cost, our retail prices remain below the average price in the Southeast region and approximately 15% below the actual average. As a result of lower prices, high reliability, superior customer service, and a regulatory environment that has been constructive and stable, we should find ourselves in a period of relative stability for the next 2.5 years.</p>
          <p>The capital expenditures we have committed for our retail business some $13.3 billion through the end of 2010 either are or are expected to be included in rates. The transparency in cost recovery and in our overall financial profile for the next 2.5 years, I believe distinguishes Southern Company and has contributed to our ability to produce consistent results in challenging economic conditions.</p>
          <p>Our focus will continue to be on delivering reliability, low prices, and superior customer service while at the same time providing our shareholders with attractive risk-adjusted returns. I am confident that we have the team in place to deliver these goals.</p>
          <p>At this point I'll now turn the call over to Paul Bowers, our Chief Financial Officer, for a discussion of our financial highlights for the second quarter and our earnings guidance for the remainder of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David. Our second-quarter results were consistent with our business plan. In the second quarter of 2008 we reported $0.54 a share, which compares to $0.57 a share or $0.03 a share below the second quarter of 2007. This includes a nonrecurring after-tax charge of $67 million, due to changes in our assessment of the tax position associated with our leveraged lease transactions and also includes our earnings from synthetic fuel investments in 2007. Excluding these two nonrecurring items, our earnings were $0.63 a share or $0.08 a share above our earnings from the second quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to the major factors that drove our second-quarter numbers. This discussion will exclude our synthetic fuel business and the one-time charge for leveraged leases. First the negative factors. Increased depreciation and amortization due primarily to increasing environmental investment reduced our earnings by $0.04 a share compared to the second quarter of 2007. Nonfuel O&amp;M for our traditional operating companies had a negative impact of $0.03 a share on our earnings for the second quarter of 2008 compared with the prior period in 2007. This was primarily due to an increase in the number of planned outages.</p>
          <p>Weather reduced our earnings by $0.01 a share in the second quarter of 2008. Weather was $0.02 above normal in the second quarter, but was $0.03 above normal in the same period in 2007. So overall, weather effect was a negative $0.01 a share.</p>
          <p>Taxes other than income taxes primarily related to franchise fees which track revenues reduced our earnings by $0.01 a share compared to second quarter of 2007. Increased expenses at Southern Power Company primarily due to maintenance outages at several of our plants reduced our earnings by $0.01 a share in the second quarter of 2008 compared with the second quarter of 2007. Finally, an increase in the number of shares outstanding reduced our earnings by $0.01 a share in the second quarter of 2008 compared to second quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the positive factors, the impact of positive revenue effects in our traditional business including customer growth, changes in retail rates, plus additional revenue attributable to variable market response rate added $0.17 a share to our earnings in the second quarter compared to second quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Increased AFUDC attributable to our construction program added $0.01 per share to our earnings in the second quarter of 2008 compared with the second quarter of 2007. Lower expenses at the parent company added $0.01 a share to our earnings in the second quarter of 2008 compared to the prior period.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, we had $0.19 of positive items offset by $0.11 of negative factors, so overall our quarter came in at $0.63 per share or $0.08 per share better than the second quarter of 2007, excluding both syn fuel and charges related to our leasing businesses.</p>
          <p>Before we turn to guidance for the remainder of 2008, and our estimate for the third quarter, I'd like to update you on a couple of items that impact our performance. First, it's clear that customer growth has slowed, particularly in the residential market, in response to the downward trend in construction activity caused by excess inventory. Customer growth while still positive is now 0.9% compared with the second quarter of 2007. Customer growth in the second quarter of 2007 was 1.6% compared with the second quarter of 2006.</p>
          <p>Building permits declined at a slower rate in the second quarter indicating that we may be nearing the bottom of the slowdown in new home construction. Installation of new meter sets may have also bottomed out in the second quarter at 5700 per month compared with 5000 meter sets in the month of February. Alabama Power actually reported an increase in meter sets in June suggesting that housing in Alabama may not be as over built as the housing market in Georgia.</p>
          <p>In the commercial sector, non-manufacturing employment growth continues to exceed national trends at 1.2% compared with a 0.4% nationally. The over-supplied office market in Atlanta saw a small increase in vacancy rate in the second quarter while gaming revenues in coastal Mississippi dropped in April but rebounded in May.</p>
          <p>In the industrial sector, the lowering of demand for new housing has impacted industrial sales in the stone, wood products, and carpet manufacturing sectors. Overall we have seen a decline in sales of 1.8% as compared to the second quarter of 2007. The majority of the reductions in industrial sales in the second quarter occurred in the month of May, with significant reductions in operations over the Memorial Day period. However sales to the pulp and paper, primary metals and the fabricated metal sectors which represent approximately 25% of our industrial sales continues to produce at high levels of activity.</p>
          <p>In addition to above average job growth, we have seen an increase in economic development activity in both Alabama and Georgia which supports our contention that the Southeast should emerge more quickly from this economic slowdown than the U.S as a whole. Finally, we expect that the States of Alabama and Georgia will add nearly 280,000 new jobs by the year 2010.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Southern Power; I'd like to update you on some recent developments at our competitive generation subsidiary. Yesterday we signed an extension of our existing contracts with 10 Georgia Electric Membership Corporations or EMCs. Eight contracts were extended beginning in 2010 through 2031. And two contracts were extended beginning in 2013 through 2034.</p>
          <p>The EMCs are currently projected to purchase 500 megawatts of power in 2008 under the existing agreement. Their purchases are projected to grow to more than 1400 megawatts during this extension.</p>
          <p>In another development, in June our Franklin 3 unit went into commercial operations. Although the contract with Constellation Energy does not begin until January, we have sold forward the output of this unit and will contribute to our earnings for Southern Power this year.</p>
          <p>Finally we project that over 30,000 megawatts of new generating capacity will be needed in the Super Southeast between now and 2017. Our ability to bring new generation online at very competitive prices as well as our relationship with wholesale customers should enable us to be a successful participant in new bid opportunities.</p>
          <p>Turning now to guidance for 2008; it is clear that we are executing our strategy and that our businesses are performing well. As you know, we exceeded our second quarter estimate by $0.08 a share. However, given the variability of weather, continued uncertainty surrounding the economy and the fact that we generally derive approximately 45% of our earnings in the third quarter, when we also see the most weather variability, we are maintaining our current earnings guidance range of $2.28 to $2.36 per share. Finally, our estimate for the third quarter is $1.01 per share.</p>
          <p>At this point I'll turn the call back over to David for his closing remarks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>As you can from see our report this afternoon, despite a challenging environment, we've had good first half of the year. And we are on target to meet our operational and financial goals for 2008.</p>
          <p>Speaking on a personal note, I was very pleased and honored to become Chairman of The Edison Electric Institute at our annual convention last month. As an industry we have a number of challenges in front of us. Reducing emissions of carbon, building new infrastructure and pressures from rising commodity and fuel costs, just to name a few.</p>
          <p>I look forward to working with my colleagues in the industry as well policy makers, regulators, members of the financial community and other stakeholders to achieve positive outcomes on these issues. Also our industry through EEI will be involved in the formulation of energy and environmental policies by a new Presidential Administration, and a new congress seeking to meet the expectations of the American people. We look forward to our role in this important national debate.</p>
          <p>At this point Paul and I would be happy to take any questions you might have. Kimberly we'll now take first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Leslie Rich of Columbia Management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Leslie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Leslie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wondered if you could spend some time talking about your wholesale sales. Your volumes were up in the quarter as well as year-to-date, but yet your net income for Southern Power is down quarter-over-quarter and also year-to-date. So I wondered if you could just talk about why your margins are compressing in that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Leslie. One other things that we'll add is that, with the advent of Franklin 3 coming online, also Oleander 5 in Florida coming online which has contracts attached to it, plus Southern Power has a contract with Hog Bayou, a Calpine asset that they're selling out of as well, the volumes are up.</p>
          <p>We also had increased O&amp;M expense in Southern Power, significant increase because most of the plants went through a outage under the long-term service agreements that they have with GE. As you know, we have to take those out for maintenance every so often, and these are tied to the number of starts that they have for those units. And this year we took most of our units out for maintenance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then separately, could you talk about hydro conditions? Last summer hydro was a big issue, and the drought and all that. How are things looking this summer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Leslie, we began this year in better shape than we did last year. Most of our reservoirs were at full, especially in Georgia and Alabama. But as we got into June, we had below-normal weather, in terms of rainfall for specifically in Alabama. Georgia still is maintaining a full pool position, but Alabama is a little bit receding in terms of its pool status. We're up a little bit on our hydro production year-over-year compared to last year's extreme drought, but still being very cautious as we go to this summer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Leslie, I'd just add we've budget about 50% of normal last year and this year. And we're pretty much on budget at a 50% below our normal expectations. That's what we've got baked into our forecast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So last year you saw hydro production down, gas production up. This year you'd expected it to be sort of a more normal balance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it'll still below what we would consider to be normal, but not as bad as last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Nathan Judge of Atlantic Equities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Nathan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just wanted to ask a couple of questions. First, could you give us an update on any developments with your trig technologies, your IGCC? Any new developments there, and how are they -- how is that going as we speak today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nathan, as you know we've been working on the project that we call Kemper County over in Mississippi. Basically we continue to work with the leadership in the state of Mississippi and Department of Energy to try to move the project forward. The next event will be Mississippi Power's filing of a certification of need for the capacity with the Mississippi Public Service Commission which will occur next month. That will begin their review of the project and its economics. We also have other regulatory proceedings associated with some of the tax benefits that will move in parallel with that. So we're continuing to step through the process that's required to get approval for that project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Has there been any other interest in that technology or everybody is still waiting or companies waiting on the sidelines until there is some clarity in the efficiency of that plant up and running?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think people are still sort of standing on the sidelines, waiting to see if we're actually going to move to a commercial demonstration. And I'm sure some people will wait until it's up and running to begin to consider that as a technology choice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lastly, I'd like to hear your thoughts on the recent ruling to &#x2013; about CAIR [Coalition for Affordable and Reliable Energy] and the federal appeals courts and as you've noticed SOx and NOx credits have fallen significantly in price. Can you just give us how that would ultimately play out with the customer in the Southeast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me make sure I am understanding your question, Nathan. Are you saying you want understand how the financial impact on the price of the allowances would impact customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There are two parts to it. I guess two parts to the question; ultimately what do you see is the resolution to the SOx NOx CAIR issue, under a new president and timing, etcetera. If you have any insight there that would be appreciated. And also the financial implications for Southern Company/customers in the region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me talk about the rule, and then I'll let Paul talk about the financial consequences to us. I don't have a particularly good crystal ball here, certainly not better than anybody else's. I think the decision was not a good one, because it creates more uncertainty at a time when we're all trying to get some certainty around what are the requirements going to be.</p>
          <p>I think there's going to be significant effort to try to either legislatively re-implement the CAIR  rule which my expectation is that that will be difficult to do because there will be a lot of effort to create what's typically termed a 4P bill which would include carbon dioxide legislation. That just makes two very complex legislative efforts with regard to CAIR and climate change, put together to be extraordinarily complex. So I think we are going to muddle along here and hope that the Congress would take the lead and simply pass a simple piece of legislation that would re-implement the CAIR rule and we have to deal with climate change in another legislative initiative. But I really don't &#x2013; I am not sure that I am very optimistic about that</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nathan, associated with the financial implications of buck tour of CARE, the thing that we have to remember is that we still have to comply with national air -- ambient air quality standards, the state implementation plans, so those are driving our compliance strategy. When you look at our SO2 allowances that we have purchased, we purchased those under a compliant strategy focus and go through the regulatory bodies to recover those costs for compliance. So when we look at our intermediate needs, they have now been elongated because we have some extra allowances that CAIR would have reduced the numbers of because of that two-for-one ratio. But right now when we look at it, we are having to look at what does it mean to have intermediate group of plants, do we have more allowances now to cover some of those. So that could have an effect on our capital spend for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Steve Fleishman of Catapult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Steve .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi; can you guys hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Steve .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, hi, guys. Just to clarify, I think through the first half of the year you have beaten your own guidance by about $0.16 a share, so from the standpoint of maintaining your guidance for the year, I know you tend to be pretty conservative and you don't know what things can come up in the third quarter and the like, but is there anything fundamentally that would be holding you back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve , when we look at third quarter of last year you have remember that that was one of the record-setting heat waves for us. Matter of fact, it was additional $0.06 last year relative to the weather. Then you have increased depreciation increase and O&amp;M for this year, so we're holding firm with the range that we have. As you know, when I opened up these comments this is 45% of our revenue in this quarter so we need to get to this quarter first before we make any assessment for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, secondly on the market response sales, could you just talk a little bit more about what's been happening with those and maybe you can even breakout within this quarter, that revenue of, I think you said $0.17, how that broke out between market response growth and rate relief? And then just what to expect with the market response sales going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me give a little background on the market response, market base response rates and then Paul can talk about the financial consequences for the quarter and then going forward. I just remind everybody that may not be familiar with it, these rates have been in place for over 15 years and is primarily about 2000 customers mostly in the State of Georgia and Georgia Power's customer base that have the opportunity to choose based on an hour ahead or a day ahead price. And the price is determined as function of the marginal cost of producing the energy. So, the customer has the right to choose or to buy price protection products to cover their choices. So their choices functionally &#x2013; is basically a function of their economic reality and their production capability and their ability to move their production around during off-peak periods. So it really gives them a lot of flexibility to choose what to do. On average this has been a very attractive rate for these customers over its history.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve , one other thing I will add to the description, it is an optional rate. Customers that like to be on this rate and it is approved by the commission in terms of the structure. The marginal portion that David described is just that; that those customers if they can manage their loads they buy on the margin. As we start checking out our resource requirements, that marginal piece is not taken in to consideration because it's a variable load that comes and goes, based on those customers.</p>
          <p>From a financial standpoint I will break it down, primarily for this quarter $0.07 of our earnings per share were attributable to the market response rates. Now for the third quarter going forward we have projected higher rates for these customers, given the norm that we always see higher cost in the summers. So, that is in our estimates going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve , I hope you have a sense that it is pretty hard to project much of that because it's such a function of the customer situation. the economic activity with regards to their particular industry, higher generation availability in stack, and that's why it is a real time rate. It's pretty hard to project much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I have one last question which is just to get an update on the new nuclear proposal in Georgia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's much like the comment that I made about the Kemper County project, the IGCC in Mississippi. It's simply stepping through the regulatory process. We made the EFP filing and the COL filing with NRC. Good news about the COL filing, the NRC response was that it was complete meaning we don't have to go back and add anything else. They will begin to evaluate it. So it should be on a good track. We will present the certification process to the Georgia Public Service Commission in next month, in August as a part of the future needs for the plant. They have until March of next year to decide. They can decide earlier but they have until March to decided, whether or not to certify that capacity if they give us a green light and agree that we should build Vogtle 3 and 4, well then we'll move quickly to move forward with the construction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Angie Storozynski of Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have a question. Given the recent slowdown in the power demand growth in your territory and the fact that you're not going to have any substantial rate cases over the next three years, should we assume that you realized ROEs will simply drop or in other words, how the recent growth in the kilowatt hour sales, differ from your projection of sales that you have in recent rate cases or settlements?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go back and maybe make sure we're on the same wavelength, because I made the comments about the relatively stable regulatory environment. We have mechanisms in place in both Alabama and Mississippi and to some degree in Georgia to make periodic filings for both base rate increases and rate increases necessary to recover capital cost associated with either new capacity in some cases and/or environmental costs. So, there are rate mechanisms that are in place. What I was saying was because those are in place; we expect a relatively stable period of time from a regulatory standpoint. That does not mean that prices will not go up during that period of time.</p>
          <p>The only place where that's not true for base rates is at Georgia Power where we are on a basically three year cycle and we would expect to file again in 2010 in Georgia, we have go under that agreement with the Georgia Public Service Commission. I don't believe at this time we have any plans in the Gulf jurisdiction to make a filing but we could during this period of time.</p>
          <p>We don't expect and I think we said in the economic data that we've produced, we don't expect any continued erosion of revenues. In fact our revenue growth still remains positive overall. We continue to have significant in-migration of new customers into our territory. We have pretty strong economic expansion in some of the primary industrial sectors that Paul mentioned, the primary metals and metal fabrication, the automotive industry continues to expand. So we think we are getting to the bottom of the housing crisis situation with our new meter sets. That's a residential level sort of bottoming out. At least we hope so. So, I think we believe that we are in pretty good shape for the next two and half years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ashar Khan of SAC Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I was trying to get a sense the residential and industrial sales decline. Is that all Georgia and Alabama? I'm trying to track that down to the subs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ashar, from a residential standpoint I would say that majority would be in Georgia, primarily, when you look at the decline because of the inventory and the number of vacancies. Alabama had a slight decline, Gulf had a moderate decline. But it's primarily Georgia that is driving some of the residential sales. When you look at the vacancy rates our normal is about 2.5%. We are running around 3.5% home vacancy rates. That means we have roughly 130,000 residential structures without people in them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then--</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add something to that Ashar, I think because it's &#x2013; we need to make sure we understand &#x2013; we are trying to make sure we understand what we're reporting here, too. We don't &#x2013; when a person leaves a residence for some reason whether it's foreclosure or whatever and the meter is still connected, we don't count that as a lost customer. That's still a customer. But there is nobody using energy on the other side of the meter.</p>
          <p>So what we are seeing we think, it's Paul's point about the increased houses available in the marketplace are houses where nobody is using electricity. So usage is down. I suspect we're also seeing some simple economic reality of people deciding to turning some things off and use less. So I think it's a grand combination of both of those things on the residential side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Paul, what have you assumed for 2008 versus 2007 for growth. Could you remind us in your budgeting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now for growth around 2% energy sales wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>2% growth in energy sales wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So right now if I look at -- we are at zero point year-to-date, am I right? So the total retail sales are up 0.2%, am I right? So that you have &#x2013; you planned at &#x2013; you're initial planning was 2%, am I looking apples-to-apples to that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you look at our overall sales, total for retail, we are roughly at a 0.1% increase over last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And you were predicting 2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so if it was 2% versus the 0.1 what would be the additional earnings? Could you just tell us the variance, what the higher earnings would have been if your were running at 2%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ashar, I think I'm going to have to go offline with you on that, and ask our guys to give you a call back to get into that level of detail. If that's all right with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay fine. Okay, thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ashar, obviously you have to make some assumptions about the mix of customers and the margin associated with the different customer rates. So it need a little bit of work to give you a good a good number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tom O'Neill with Highbridge</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, just curious if you could give an update on your coal inventory situation and any upcoming fuel filings we should expect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yesterday we received approval of a fuel case at Gulf Powers. So that was the last fuel case that we had filed in the system. So that's moving forward, and I think those rates come into effect September 1. We have a targeted inventory of 40 days. Right now we are at 36 days as we sit here. We've had some interruptions in some supplies due to the flooding in the Midwest. And as gas prices were higher, we had increased burn. So we are &#x2013; from an inventory standpoint, we are in good shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jeff Coviello of Duquesne Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Jeff</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a follow-up question on CAIR, you mentioned that the probably the most hopeful thing that could happen was that the U.S. Congress passed some sort of simple enabling legislation that let CAIR be re-instated. And it seems like you are optimistic about that. But I was wondering if there was any &#x2013; should be watching the House or the Senate for that? And if it was going to happen when do you think it would be the most likely?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, Jeff that's great question. But I can't tell you where to look or when to expect it. I know that there are &#x2013; there were hearings yesterday in the Senate, I think on Senate energy and commerce or maybe environment public works. But there were people testifying about the need for some certainty. So, it's getting some play. But when you get to the practicality of moving legislation in this Congress, knowing that they are out of town tomorrow, I mean on Friday, not back 'til Labor Day and then you got to get through the election. I just don't give as much hope for moving this thing forward. I wouldn't say it's impossible. But I'd just &#x2013; I'm not sure it can get done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again like I've said, I think when it begins to move, there is a very good likelihood that there'll be a lot of folks trying to tack a bunch of different things on, as they always do. Remember that the Court actually remanded the decision to EPA to adopt a rule that was consistent with the opinion. So there is some chance that EPA could try to move forward to do something. But it's also difficult for EPA to adopt a ruling in this environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It sounds like if then the Congress isn't going to be able to do anything then after the Labor Day at the earliest, and the politics of the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I think that is a certain. Certain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, got it. Okay that's helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Steve Gambuzza of Longbow Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I was just wondering, if you could explain how it is that you're kind of on-plan in terms of earnings guidance, when sales have been so far below expectations from a retail standpoint. Is it that the market base response rates, do those essentially benefit from lower &#x2013; the sales that you sell under market base response rates, do they essentially benefit from lower retailer load growth, so that the earnings there are offsetting what normally would have been retail revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, they're -- I think there are two things going on here. One is that market base rates benefit from higher gas prices and higher marginal fuel prices. And that's one of the things that drove the second quarter contribution.</p>
          <p>The other thing is and we talked about this earlier is that in &#x2013; going into January we saw the implementation of rate increases, in Alabama and Georgia and Mississippi that had been approved by the Public Service Commissions. So the prices were actually higher going into this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess but didn't those rate increases, didn't they take into account an expected level of load growth that didn't actual transpire?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct. And the market base rate contribution helped make up some of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And &#x2013; but I guess do you &#x2013; all things being equal, do you &#x2013; are you able to sell more power at market based rates when retail load is lower than normal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>your next question comes from the line of Timothy Yee of KeyBanc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you talk just a little bit more about Franklin 3, you had mentioned that it come into service. How much capacity is that? And you had sold some of the output. What's your earnings impact contribution for the year? And was that contemplated in guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you look at -- I'll go to the last point of your question first. There was some contemplation of Southern Power having Franklin 3 on early. So when we project out Southern Power's earnings, we had assumed certain portion of Franklin 3 in that number. Now Franklin 3 is a 640 megawatt combined cycled gas unit that was mothballed back in 2003, 2004 timeframe. This unit was originally sold to Dynegy and that contract was bought out of from Dynegy in that 2004 period.</p>
          <p>We mothballed the unit to search for additional capacity contracts for it. Ended up selling the capacity to Progress Ventures who in turn sold it to Constellation Energy and that contract comes in to place in January of 2009. When we go to a mothballed or a stored plant, there are some anticipated issues with shaking out the construction, shaking out the unit, for the unit. And what we try to do is bring it on early to see if we have any shakedown if you will and the unit right now is doing quite well. And our folks in Southern Power went forward to the market and sold some of the capacity out. And it has some contributions to margin but it is also contemplated in the $135 million net income target for that company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Andrew Levi of Brencourt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I'm all set, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Dan Jenkins of State of Wisconsin Investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Dan .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to clarify little bit on I think you said earlier on the $0.17 benefit from retail non-fuel, that $0.07 of that was the market response rate affect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct Dan .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so I was curious then of the remaining $0.10 how much of that is due to the rate increases that went into effect and how much is say from customer growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, $0.01 is from customer growth and the remaining part of that is just rate increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then I was also wondering if you could give us an update on where you are at on your CapEx spending and if the budgets are the same as you projected at the beginning of the year for CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're pretty much right on budget Dan as it relates to our CapEx spend. As you know we have a three year CapEx spend for our operating company, that $13.3 billion. We are basically right on target with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then as far as any debt that you might need to issue, I know you have about 700 million that comes due in the second half of the year end. I was wondering if you could give us some guidance on your debt plans for the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to finance a spot between 1.2 billion through the remaining part of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. That's all I have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks Dan</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your next question is a follow up from Leslie Rich of Columbia Management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wondered if I could circle back to the leveraged lease charge, and have you walk through an explanation of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure you can. What do you want to understand about it Leslie, can you narrow it a little bit. What it was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are these tax benefits that you took that you had to reverse or --?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's basically correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is this related to SILO/LILO lease accounting or is this something different?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was 3 silos that were retained by a Southern Company as part of the spin out of Mirant in 2001.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that the extent of it, the issue is now over?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we did was decide to go ahead and take a charge because of the IRS success in certain other cases and the accounting recommendation that we go ahead and book what we did. We still are in litigation with the IRS over the issue with regard to our leases and may effect some settlement with them in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but the charge that you took covers 100% of the amount up for debate or there's potentially more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Potentially what we expect our exposure to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And just secondly separately on your call, David it would be interesting to hear your thoughts on the coal markets since you're such a large consumer of coal and if the coal markets --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I am really disappointed Leslie to have to be paying 130 bucks for Central Appalachian coal. You remember part of my background was managing that back in the 80s for Southern Company and that's a long way from where we were then. I think our hope is that some of the supply out of Australia and other parts of the world comes back and by this time next year we are back at something closer to what I would consider to be a normal price which maybe in the 50 to $60 a ton for Central App.</p>
          <p>The Colombian sources that we draw on are also extraordinarily expensive; they are at $135 or have been. So we are seeing significant increased cost like everybody else. Powder River Basin is not quite as volatile so there is some good news and we rely on a good bit of that for our supply.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And have you indicated publicly how &#x2013; are you fully contracted for 2009? And I know you tend to do lots of very long-term contracts and layered in from multiple different supply basins with multiple different contract lengths, but do I need to worry about '09 or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No more than I do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Leslie, as you know our contract strategy for the current year is usually try to be at 95 to 99% covered, and second year out if you will for next year, it would be 60 to 70%, third year out it will be around 40 to 50%. Right now we have taken that strategy up in terms of locking in reliability supply, and for next year we are right at 99% committed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you have fuel pass-through in all your jurisdictions, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, Leslie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from the line of Annie Stile of Alliance Funds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon; can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just a question going back to your kilowatt sales, when you see the commercial and also industrials down about 2% and more than 2% as well, can you break it down in terms of is it from Georgia or Alabama and what's the trend that you see going forward for your kilowatt sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We talked a good bit about the residential situation. So I think that is pretty clear. The commercial business is slowing but still positive year-to-date. The industrial business was down in the quarter and we talked about the fact that we think that most of that occurred in May when some of our major industrial customers decided to take their annual maintenance cycle which is around Memorial Day, where they take a week. I think what we got to do is get into this quarter and see if the industrial production is back to a normal level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Annie we have also had the Chevron refinery in Mississippi out for an extensive time, associated with an expansion at that facility, so we anticipate it to come back online during this quarter, maybe the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you think for the rest of the year it might be a little bit better, or you see the trend will continue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our expectation is that we still have the weaknesses in those industry segments that are attached to the housing market and we still see growth coming out of the primary metals, transportation, fabricated metals where we have had growth in the past. Our anticipation is that these on target if you will as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, last question has to do with the economy &#x2013; with the economy slowdown, can you comment on your uncollectables?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Annie we keep close eye on that at any time when you are in a uncertain economic time but we have not seen a discernible increase in any of our charge-offs and our arrears in fact got better from March '08 to June '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a follow-up question from Steve Gambuzza of Longbow Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, a quick question on the coal, where it sounded like you have actually gone a little bit ahead of your &#x2013; is it fair to say, you are a little bit ahead of where you would normally be for 2009 in terms of your hedge profile?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just didn't -- I guess when listening to your comments about you being hopeful that supply &#x2013; the supply situation would work itself out and that we would see something approaching more normal prices by 2009. I take it from your hedge position that you don't put a lot of &#x2013; you're not necessarily sure that that hope is going to be met? Is that a fair inference?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go back to that &#x2013; who it was that wrote the book that said hope is not a strategy; we decided to go ahead and make sure we were covered for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of that too, of those contracts have a market opener so gives us the visibility to the market for the prices of coal; so we wanted to purchase based on reliability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, there are no further questions. I will turn the call back over to Mr. Ratcliffe for any closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Kimberly, don't have anything except thanks to everybody for joining us today. Look forward to seeing you on the third quarter call. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>