<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1144532" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>706</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Shelly J. Doran, Vice President of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David Simon, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Jay Habermann</participant>
      <participant id="4">David Simon</participant>
      <participant id="5">Paul Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="6">Craig Schmidt</participant>
      <participant id="7">Stephen Sterrett</participant>
      <participant id="8">Michael Billerman</participant>
      <participant id="9">Michael Mueller</participant>
      <participant id="10">Christine McElroy</participant>
      <participant id="11">David Toti</participant>
      <participant id="12">Louis Taylor</participant>
      <participant id="13">Benjamin Yang</participant>
      <participant id="14">Jeff Donnelly</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jeffrey Spector</participant>
      <participant id="16">Nate Isby</participant>
      <participant id="17">Rich Moore</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="corprep">Stephen E. Sterrett, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the First Quarter 2008 Simon Property Group Earnings Concerns Call. My name is Sean and I'll be your coordinator for today. At this time all participants are in a listen only mode. <mark type="Operator instructions" /> I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Ms. Shelly Doran, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Simon Property Group First Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. Please be aware that statements made during this call that are not historical may be deemed forward-looking statements. Actual results may differ materially from those indicated by forward-looking statements due to a variety of risks and uncertainties. Please refer to our filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission for a detailed discussion of these risks and uncertainties. Acknowledging the fact that this call may be webcast for some time to come, we believe it is important to note that today's call includes time-sensitive information that may be accurate only as of today's date, April 29th, 2008. The company's quarterly supplemental information package was filed earlier this morning as a Form 8-K. This filing is available via mail or e-mail, and it is posted on the Simon website in the Investor Relations section, under financial information &#x2013; quarterly supplemental packages. Participating in today's call will be David Simon, chairman and chief executive officer, and Steve Sterrett, chief financial officer. Rick Sokolov, our president and chief operating officer, is unable to be here with us today as he is recuperating from unexpected shoulder surgery. And now I will turn the call over to Mr. Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone. I will just take a few moments at this time to provide comments on the quarter, and then we'll open the call up for your questions.</p>
          <p>We are pleased to report first quarter FFO of $1.46 per share, which is up 6.6% over the prior year. Positive factors contributing to the quarter include solid operating results for all five of our property platforms and decreasing LIBOR rates. You should note that this growth in FFO was achieved despite the fact our share of lease termination settlements was more than 9 million lower in the first quarter of 2008 than in 2007. You may recall that we received some large department store termination income in 2007. FFO was also negatively impacted as a result of a $12 million decrease in fee and interest income, primarily related to an SPG-provided mezzanine loan to the Mills. These two items together impacted our FFO growth from 2007 to 2008 by over $0.07 per share.</p>
          <p>Occupancy was essentially flat, and our mall portfolio square footage lost to bankruptcy during the most recent quarter totaled 133,000 square feet, as compared to 24,000 square feet during the first quarter of 2007. Even with this, our occupancy at the end of the first quarter is still higher than Q1 of 2006. The decline in the premium outlet occupancy is primarily due to lease terminations or bankruptcy of four tenants comprising about a dozen spaces and the late March 2008 openings of Houston premium outlets, which was 86% leased at 3/31/08, and phase two of Rio Grande premium outlets, which had total center occupancy of 85% at quarter-end. Today at Houston and Rio Grande, we are 92% and 94% leased, respectively, and we expect the occupancy in the premium outlet portfolio to return to previous levels by year-end due to lease-up.</p>
          <p>We experienced a continued moderation of sales growth in the mall portfolio. Comparable sales were $491 per square foot, up nearly 1% as compared to the year earlier period. Sales have been impacted by the general economic weakening of the U.S. economy, as well as our portfolio's higher exposure to Florida, which has obviously been impacted by the residential market there. Excluding our Florida portfolio, sales would have been up 2% on a comp basis.</p>
          <p>Going to the premium outlet portfolio, sales increased 5.4% to $511 per square foot, driven by our centers with substantial international tourist exposure that continue to see double digit sales growth. Comparable regional mall NOI was up 2.8% for the quarter, which was negatively impacted by the higher debt expenses compared to last year. Comparable NOI growth for our premium outlet portfolio is 4.1%.</p>
          <p>The re-leasing spread of our mall portfolio was above historical levels for the quarter due to the mix of leases involved. We expect the spread to return to a more historical normalized level by year-end. And the re-leasing spread for the premium outlet portfolio was $7.06 for the quarter, representing a strong 29% increase. Effective cost control in the field and the continued conversion of tenants to fixed cam resulted in higher recovery of common area maintenance expenses during the period, and currently approximately 70% of our regional mall tenants have been converted to the fixed cam billing methodology.</p>
          <p>Our development and redevelopment pipeline remains intact. We will deliver significant value in the upcoming years. We are primarily focused on the redevelopment and expansion of franchise assets in the U.S. and new premium outlet development in the U.S. and in Asia. Capital is a precious resource. We remain very diligent in the allocation of that capital &#x2013; only those projects that meet our return requirements.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet continues to be one of the strongest in the real estate industry, as evidenced by our A- and AAA ratings and the recent affirmation of such ratings. We build our balance sheet to be positioned at all times to access capital in multiple forms. And I believe that this balance sheet strength was evidenced by a financing transaction that we completed during the first quarter, which was a $705 million secured recourse term loan on six existing lowly level / high-quality SPG assets, tapping into their significant embedded equity value of these assets. The facility, which will be or can be increased to $850 million during its term, will mature in March of 2010, contains two one-year extensions at the company's sole option, and base rate on this facility is at a very favorable LIBOR plus 70 basis points.</p>
          <p>The remaining 2008 debt maturities consist of $350 million of corporate bonds and approximately 660 million of mortgage debt, excluding the Mills. We are in the process of refinancing the existing $660 million of mortgage debt at amounts equal to or greater than our existing mortgages, and we currently have over 1.7 billion of available capacity on our corporate credit facility as well as $400 million of cash in the bank.</p>
          <p>It has now been one year since the acquisition of the Mills. The transaction is exceeding our expectations. I believe that the portfolio is significantly benefiting from leasing and operational synergies with our other real estate platforms. We are now ready to take advantage of several redevelopment projects within this portfolio and the retenting &#x2013; retenanting of certain anchors.</p>
          <p>Based upon our solid first quarter results, projected activity for the rest of the year, and our view of market conditions, today we gave 2008 FFO guidance of $6.35 to $6.45 per share. Which is approximately $1.9 billion of earnings, which is very significant in today's environment. And which also increases the lower end of our previously provided range by $0.10.</p>
          <p>We are the largest landlord to most national mall-based retailers. Many tenants generate 10 to 20% of their total sales from stores located in our malls. We are also the largest owner of high-quality outlet centers, and retailers highly value this very profitable distribution channel. The depth of these relations, coupled with our high quality mall and outlet portfolio and below-market leases, should also allow us to lessen the negative impact in a time when retailers are closing stores and reducing their growth plans.</p>
          <p>This concludes our prepared comments today, and we are ready to open the call up for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Jay Habermann with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning. Question for David, or maybe for Rick if he's on the call. With regard to banks pulling back credit lines to major retailers &#x2013; we saw it recently with one of the largest department stores, as well with a women's retailer. Please give us some thoughts as to, will this impact store closings throughout the year, in your assumptions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we've heard is that there is one lender in particular that is not renewing certain lines of credit. The retailers that have been involved, we have talked to them and it has had absolutely no impact on their view or their focus on store closings or store expansions. So at this point we have not had any impact and we have been told that it will not impact what they are doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and David, you mentioned the four tenants closing stores, obviously in the Chelsea division. Can you mention those specifically? And also, I think The Gap closed a bunch of stores as well. Any further thoughts there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, The Gap has closed no stores in the outlet centers. And the store closings in the outlet side have been Mi Casa and Bombay, and it's all been very &#x2013; that's very beneficial for us. Those leases are under-market, and essentially they have all been re-leased. As you know, it does take, once a store closes it takes time to re-lease it. We are fully confident we will get the outlet center back up to the north of 99%. That also included some Springmaid and Westpoint closings as well. So, most of that is, we view as a positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I think Tom has a question as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys. On the Houston and Rio Grande outlet openings, did those open a little bit below pro forma in terms of occupancy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No, they're &#x2013; in fact, Houston is ending up being about a 17% return on cost. Again, we &#x2013; you have to understand it opened literally ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>March 28.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>... March 28, and we are good, but we can't get 100% of every tenant open. And, as I said, the &#x2013; I think Houston is now at 94%. There's some stragglers coming in that are opening. Houston is going gangbusters. Rio Grande is phase two. The opening of that. And again, that opened basically at the end of the quarter and we are actually doing phase three now. So, no issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Paul Morgan with FBR [Friedman Billings Ramsey]. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. On the international side, you have talked about your intentions to grow that share of your portfolio. I'm wondering, mostly that has been through development so far. Are you looking harder at any acquisition opportunities, given the difference between the health of the U.S. economy right now and some of the other markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are looking at a few deals. I'm still of the belief that the U.S. economy will have an impact on the global economy, and I don't think that that has permeated yet. So, the last thing we want to do is jump in there and not have that impacted on how people might view the valuation of that. So, I think our &#x2013; we have looked at a few more deals. There's one with &#x2013; through Simon Ivanhoe that looks maybe a little bit more opportunistic than we have been in the past. But at this point I don't expect any material change to our strategy there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>OK. And, when you look at the environment for construction lending in the U.S., are you seeing a lot of fallout from the lifestyle and mixed-use projects that were percolating everywhere over the past couple of years? Do you either see anything that is interesting from a kind of opportunistic investment perspective, or alternatively do you see a lot of projects either not happening or getting pushed back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me &#x2013; let me add &#x2013; I think it is actually &#x2013; there's a trend here that is actually very interesting, that I think will be extremely beneficial to us. If you think about the recent development, if you go back to the real estate recession in the, the late &#x2013; beginning in the late 80's to the early 90's, it took &#x2013; there was a lot of development that occurred during that period of time that took a long time to stabilize. And the decade of the 90's obviously was not a decade of new development. New development really only began to occur, at least in retail, in earnest in the early &#x2013; after we kind of suffered through the ramifications of 9/11. New development in retail, again, only really picked up its pace in kind of the mid-2000 decade. So, frankly, I see a decade &#x2013; you think about retail development as basically until 2003, 4, 5, 6, I see a decade &#x2013; I do think in the current economy and environment &#x2013; I see a decade, perhaps, that retail development is going to be very slow. And I think that is obviously fabulous for us.</p>
          <p>That is not to say there won't be certain developments. But we could be talking, if you look at the historical trend, it was 15 years essentially before development picked its pace up again. So, I don't think it will be that long, because I do think things happen faster &#x2013; things get worse faster and things get better faster. But I do think we could have a decade of little retail development, which in the long run is great for us.</p>
          <p>The second point I would make, I have heard others talk about talking to developers. I think there's enough carnage out there that I'm questioning why they would talk to the developers. They ought to be talking to the lenders. The answer is, there's a lot of broken projects out there. I don't think a lot has been recognized. That may present some opportunity for us. There's a reason why, on the other hand, that they are broken. But net-net, if we are looking, we are bypassing the developer. We are going to go straight to the lender. And I think the bottom line is that we could have a decade of slow retail development, which I think bodes very well for us and other major owners of retail real estate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that include redevelopment? You've obviously had a lot of that yourself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think redevelopment really hasn't changed that much. And if you &#x2013; and I don't think it will change from the big stable companies. So our view on that is, it is not going to change at all. Now, demand on a few projects may get a little squishy. But from that standpoint I still think franchise assets are so much easier to underwrite, so much easier for the tenant to understand. And to the that extent financing is an issue it is so much easier for the financing sources to understand. So I don't sense currently that that is really going to have a material impact. There may be a couple of projects here and there that that get delayed or reconfigured, but I would think that that would be a big push for us and our peer group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Craig Schmidt with Merrill Lynch. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. The operating metrics that we are looking at, I guess for the first quarter, were probably negotiated months ago. I'm wondering what your leasing team is telling you, what the environment right now is for deals they are negotiating?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, it is interesting. I think the &#x2013; there has been little serious retrenchment on commitments or new stores. There's been again, on the margin, a few people not wanting to do a few deals. I think the big issue for us the rest of this year and into early '09 is going to be with store closings. And so, the focus on us is not so much on oh, boy, the guy committed a store and he is not going to do that. That's been on the margin. We are going to get more space back because there are tenants that are closing stores or either through Chapter 11 or an out of Chapter 11 reorg. So that's going to put some space on the table for us that we're going to be in the process of re-leasing. And that's, again I wouldn't over &#x2013; I wouldn't be overdramatic. We have seen it before. But that's the bigger issue, to me, than a guy going from store openings of 35 down to 30.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would that explain the provision for credit losses kind of ramping up in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean &#x2013; Craig, it's Steve. I think that partially explains it. We are not really seeing a significant tick-up in receivables themselves, but the composition of it has changed a little bit as we have tenants who have either filed or have announced restructurings. There is probably a little more receivables that we would view at risk. Having said that, I think the amount of provision you saw in the first quarter, and certainly the year-over-year change, is not reflective of what we'd expect to see the rest of the year. I think we have probably taken most of the pain on that line item in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, great. And do you have a sense of where same store NOI might be for the outlet sector by the year-end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it would be very similar &#x2013; I mean, look. That is a little bit more dependent upon sales than, say, the mall portfolio. So it is a little harder to predict with accuracy. But I think we feel confident that we will be able to maintain that kind of range. And same thing with the mall portfolio. Even with &#x2013; we still &#x2013; even though we're somewhat under three, we gave guidance in the three to four range &#x2013; still feel we will be able to hit that. We will end up having a little bit more unexpected stores coming back, but I think we will make that up through other means, including temporary tenants and the like. So we still stand by our comp NOI for both portfolios. It's just going to be a little harder to get there, a little more work, a little more elbow grease.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Amica Goelle with Citigroup. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Mike Billerman here with Envica. David, you talked a little bit about, at our conference, going out and buying some debt, whether it be CMBS or &#x2013; excuse me &#x2013; some unsecured.  And then, you talked now about maybe going out and buying some of these broken development deals, and going to the lenders. Where are you on that today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not a lot is trading on the CMBS side. It is very interesting. The, at this point, it is just very hard to find the paper. We do expect that logjam to loosen up. And I think the construction loan side &#x2013; let's see, I was going to be more graphic than I should be, so let's see how I can word this. I think the beginning on &#x2013; I think we are going to see the beginning of the recent development starting to hit the fan. Because if you think about it, a lot of these were built, they are going to have harder lease-ups because of the economy. They are, have a harder takeout because of where the secured market is. And so, the combination of those &#x2013; they are going to be harder to sell because people aren't being that aggressive in valuations. So, as those mature, or they tell the lender exactly what the story is, there's going to be a lot of pressure. I think that part of the game is just beginning. The question is, do we like the real estate. There's more lifestyle centers, as an example, going back to an earlier question, there's more lifestyle centers out there for sale than we have seen in the past. I think the floodgates of that is just going to begin to open. The question is, do we like the real estate, the productivity. And some of these are going to &#x2013; we are going to end up dealing with the construction loaner &#x2013; lender.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how far are you in those discussions already?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's early. Early. Because they may have interest carry for a year, lower LIBOR rates help them somewhat. But judgment day is coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, you talked about not liking where your sort of unsecured debt is trading. North of 300 over, and not wanting to issue into this environment. Are you actively trying to buy back some of your own debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have not seen any of our unsecured debt to speak of in the market, Michael. We actually saw a couple of D pieces of some of our malls that we were very interested in, but the seller opted not to sell. Having said that, we have seen a fair bit of improvement in bond spreads over the course of the last two or three weeks. And our bonds are probably trading 75 basis points inside of where they were, as the market has opened up a little bit. So, over the long term, I view that as a pretty good sign.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you an issuer at these levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think at these levels, Michael, but I would tell you that we like the trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Envica has a couple of questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How does store closures being more pushed back later in the year, in 2008, impact the 4Q seasonality ramp that the business usually experiences?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It could make the fourth quarter, actually, a tad bit more seasonal, Ambika, but that would just be at the margin. You may have a little bit of pressure on occupancy here in the second and in the third quarter, as David mentioned, as we get more space back, and it just may mean that we've got larger occupancy gains in Q4 as we re-lease that space and get people open for Christmas. But I think it would be, very much be at the margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, is there any specific reason that you are seeing that the closures are more pushed back later in the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's really, it's really dependent upon the status of the retailer and what is going on there. There are a handful of retailers that are basically in workout mode, and not knowing exactly what is going to happen with that workout. Are they going to go Chapter 11? Are they going to reorganize out of the proceedings basis? Or are they going to liquidate? We don't control the space so there are some, again, on the margin there's going to be some variability out there depending on &#x2013; again, and this is two, three, four kind of &#x2013; two or three or four tenants that are out there that are in the midst of that process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then some of the retailers that have announced closures this year, they have announced closures that are occurring in 2009. Do you have visibility on which locations those will be in 2009? Or have you yet to get to this point in your discussions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty much we know it, and we are pretty much negotiating. I mean, it would depend &#x2013; we're pretty &#x2013; We have a pretty good handle of the companies that are, have either retrenched or announced some store closings, like the Talbotts, the Anne Taylors, the Gaps of the world. We have a pretty good handle. The ones that create a certain amount of uncertainty are the ones that are not, they don't have that kind of financial wherewithal, so we are trying to weigh that. So, I think generally I would say we have pretty good clarity other than, like I said, two or three or four that are in the midst of thinking about whether or not they can do a reorg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Michael Mueller with JP Morgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. A couple of questions. First of all, looking at the new and redevelopment delivery schedule, a lot of projects there are '08 obviously. I was just wondering if you can give us a sense as to what the pipeline looks like as you move into 2009 and 2010 for deliveries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It really hasn't &#x2013; we really haven't backed off anything material in terms of 9 and 10. We are still very close to announcing a new outlet center in, I would say in the next 30 days, that we will be able to deliver in '09. We are delivering a New Jersey premium outlet at the end of '08. We are going to deliver Merrimack in 10. And we will deliver one more, this one that I talked about, at the end of 9. International pipeline is pretty status, status quo, moving along as expected. We think there's a couple more south Korean opportunities, and even a couple more in Japan that we are working toward. Those could be added to the pipeline.</p>
          <p>And on the redevelopment side of the equation, the big projects are moving. Ross Park, South Shore, North Shore, Burlington just opened with that. So, most of the '08, 9 stuff, North Shore is 9, South Shore is 10. We've got some big expansions with Orlando premium, which is 9. So, it's pretty much status quo just jumping at it. Obviously we are looking to add that. The big one that we are going through approvals, which will take about a year, is the Copley, and we are still all systems go trying to get the approvals there. But that's going to take a year process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then switching gears for a second, you said Mills was running ahead of expectations. Can you give us a little more color, maybe talk about occupancy trends at the regional mall portfolio, the Mills portfolio, and just how closing The Gap is trending, and just remerchandising?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would say that the actual Mills side is &#x2013; we have got a lot of redevelopment that we are focused on. We have some real interest on kind of retenanting some of the anchors. So that's &#x2013; And we are actually making a significant amount of deals in the Mills with the likes of Nike and Adidas and those kinds of players. So I &#x2013; the Mills side is actually, we are very, very positive in terms of what is going on there. Part of that is because the demand on the outlet side from specialty retailer and the Nieman Marcus and the Saks of the world continues to be very, very strong and unabated, and that's what is obviously having a positive impact on the premium outlet side as well.</p>
          <p>With respect to the malls, we have a couple &#x2013; I would say by and large, they are doing as expected. There are a couple that are in major redevelopment mode that we're holding on to space. As an example, Southdale in St. Paul is a great example of that, where we are still waiting in terms of &#x2013; So we are not making as much progress there as we would like, and primarily because we are still sorting through development there. Delama, we are making progress there, but again we want to create some optionality with future redevelopment opportunities. So the bigger ones are kind of in a holding pattern as we sort through the development. The stable malls are kind of all producing what we thought they'd do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Christine McElroy with Bank of America. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I'm just following up on leasing. Have you seen a difference in leasing trends in store closings at your class A versus your class B malls? And just going into ICSC in Vegas, what does your retailer meeting schedule look like, versus last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is still very strong, so we haven't seen a real change in that. I would say I don't know that it is so much A and B. I would say it really depends upon the retailer and where that retailer is focused. Again, I think the teen sector by and large is very strong, and that's in A, B, and C centers. Then you have retailers that are not &#x2013; more broad based but &#x2013; like, for instance, the Disney stores is going through a process now where they're going to be sold or reorganized, and that is across the board. So it really depends on the retailer. It is obviously easier to lease up an A mall than it is a B mall, but I would say the demand isn't all that different, between an A and a B. It just depends on where the retailer situation is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about new concepts? What kind of trends are you seeing leasing there? And are there any that you are particularly worried about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean, I think we have a very strong group of new concepts or new retailers expanding, including, there's probably 30, Abercrombie with Gilly Hicks, Hollister, Adidas, aerie of American Eagle. Apple continues to expand. Back Racks, Bare Essentials, Charlotte Russe, Clark's, Coach, Express, Forever 21, H&amp;M. We're making a lot of deals with H&amp;M. GEOX, Godiva, Justice, Nike. I mean, so there are &#x2013; Puma. Faconnable. So there is plenty of new demand out there that are, we think, are going to help deal with some of the guys that are retrenching. So it's actually, in that sense a lot of deals are being made.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, sorry if I missed this, but Steve, could you walk through what kind of gave you the comfort to raise the bottom end of your guidance range at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Christie, it's a couple of things. One, we are obviously one quarter into the year, so we've got three months of actual results behind us. We've got more visibility into the leasing activity for the rest of the year, even though, as David mentioned, there is still a bit of uncertainty with respect to store closings in the second quarter. And then maybe most importantly, you've got a LIBOR curve that looks very different than it did when we published our initial guidance. So, put all those three together and I think that is where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Toti with Lehman Brothers. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I like your new name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ah, yeah, there's lots of pronunciations there. Can you guys speak a little bit about what you are seeing internationally? Are you seeing retailers track the U.S.? Are you seeing increased concerns about store closings? Just a little bit on that climate there would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The international business is, we don't have a huge subset to make general, big general statements. I will tell you Italy is very stable, even though the economy there is not certainly that strong. So it is very stable. Occupancies and sales are pretty steady. Our new product there has been virtually 100% leased. That is very stable. Poland, we are down to two assets in Poland, but the sales there have been remarkable. So, the economy there continues to be very strong. Japan, even though Japan's economy is slowing, the outlet sector has an unusual niche there in terms of being able to produce sales growth. And so I think that's well &#x2013; very, very well positioned. As the Japanese economy slows, which we are seeing certainly, globally or domestically in Japan. And we expect that to continue. But the outlet position there is very strong and the consumer really likes that value proposition.</p>
          <p>So I would say generally we haven't seen kind of the downdraft but it is a very specific asset base that we have. We are not in the U.K., so I would imagine sales there are probably tracking the U.S. But that gives you a sense. And in France, we have assets there but I would characterize them as very stable as well, both occupancy and sales. So, it's not the kind of volatility that you might expect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Does this strength increase your appetite at all for future investment, from where you are now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I missed the first part of your question. You broke up there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Given your sort of limited exposure overseas right now, does the sustainability of those &#x2013; the market strength increase your appetite for further investment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, sure. There's less retail there and that always makes the supply and demand equation interesting. Certainly from a risk-adjusted basis. The biggest issue is the dollar and how you put capital out and finding the right opportunity where we could add value. And we have been working on it. We will continue to work on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do think Asia, certainly the new developing countries in Asia do pose a risk for some interesting bubble-like characteristics. So, not Japan necessarily, but I do think there are Asian markets that have had a lot of new supply. And that is why we have been very cautious in those kinds of markets, because there are bubble characteristics out there in certain parts of Asia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lou Taylor with Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. David, you had mentioned just some regional differences earlier in the call with regard to the comparable store sales with Florida being weak. What were some of the other regional differences of note?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say the Northeast generally, Boston, pretty strong, no real issues there. Midwest is, God love the Midwest ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We never had the boom so we are not having the bust.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we are pretty well positioned in the Midwest, so we're &#x2013; like Indianapolis is a decent market for us. The other area that is interesting is southern California, is it is not quite like Florida, but any markets that are really &#x2013; northern California seems to be very fine, and again our exposure there has increased somewhat through the Mills deal. But that seems to have a lot more stability than southern California, where there was a lot more of the residential infrastructure in place. And so I would say that area is soft. Texas actually is holding up well. We are seeing softness in Nevada, Las Vegas, for the first time in quite some time. So, we expect that softness to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the second question just pertains to your lease expirations in '08. Your average rent there is pretty high at around $44 a foot versus low to mid $30's for most other years. Is that going to impact your leasing spreads this year, in terms of what you are ultimately going to get, just due to mix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lou, it's Steve. It is a bit of an aberration, just that we dealt with 75 or 80% of our expirations already. So the stuff that is left shows at a higher base rent. Dave mentioned in his prepared remarks we expect the leasing spread to return to historical levels, which for us has been plus or minus 20%. That is about where we would expect to see it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Carol Kimbel with Hilliard Lyons. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. On your income statement, I noticed that the other income line item was down. Is that &#x2013; can you tell me why, is that something we should...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is the Mills.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the Mills?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And lease terminations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And lease terminations. We had a lower level of lease terminations in '08 versus '07.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>OK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ben Yang with Green Street Advisors. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, David. Your outlet business is doing very well and you had previously talked about bringing some of your outlet tenants into the Mills portfolio. Have any retailers actually made this move or indicated plans to do so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there are &#x2013; a great example is Nike, which is a big client of the Chelsea product. We have Katy, Arendell, Colorado, Discover, Franklin, and the Block all moving toward either opened or moving toward deals. Just as an example. Tommy Hilfiger, the same thing, and then we are actually getting some of the mall tenants like Ann Taylor, Victoria's Secret, Gymboree, all moving toward either doing &#x2013; in Vickie's case, they don't have an outlet concept, doing Vickie's full-price &#x2013; or with Ann Taylor doing their outlet stores. So &#x2013; and that is what is good about the Mills right now in this environment. The outlet side of the equation is very interesting to a number of retailers. The Neiman Marcus Last Call, the Saks Fifth Avenue Off 5TH, lots of new deals are in works there as well. So, we are seeing what we thought would be there. Now, what we are also working on, which we are very close to bringing a full-line department store in one property and then even, maybe even building a whole lifestyle component to another property that is full-line anchored. So, on the Mills, I would say generally all are moving pretty positively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, is it fair to say that the Mills assets are somewhat defensive in a tough economy? Similar to what we are seeing for the outlet centers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It appears to be. There is a more interesting value proposition for the consumer. But I want to be a little cautious because I think we are just, we are still at the beginning of a down economy or &#x2013; I'm not smart enough to know what inning we are in. But it appears to be a little bit more defensive. And most importantly, the demand seems to be &#x2013; the demand on the outlet side is high and it seems to be, we seem to be seeing the benefit of that with the Mills portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally, you previously also mentioned that you were still refining some of the Mills data. Have you guys found any more surprises, either good or bad, in the past few months or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty much that is behind us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is?  Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jeff Donnelly with Wachovia. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Just building on, I guess it was one of Christy's earlier questions regarding ICSC &#x2013; David, what is the tenor of your meeting schedule there, versus prior years? I mean, are you seeing more meetings on the books, addressing things like store closings or just renewals versus, say, filling vacancies, or new projects? Or is it just more of the same?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would say it is more of the same. I did look through &#x2013; and Rick is not on the call to commiserate with this &#x2013; but we did, there were several years where &#x2013; '93, 4, 5, et cetera, where all we did is essential workouts. I don't sense that at all in this upcoming convention. There will be a few, I'm sure, but I don't sense anywhere near what we had to deal with in the mid '90's.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Steve, if I heard you correctly in an earlier response, is it fair to say you will see the most significant level of lease expirations in Q2 '08, for you guys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we &#x2013; most of the leases expire &#x2013; a good proportion of leases expire in the first quarter, Jeff. What I did say, I think, is that we still have some variability with potential store closings, and we will see probably more space come back to us in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Well, I guess I'm curious though, if mall occupancy was down, I think 10 basis points in Q1, and I think initially you guys projected flat to a 100 basis point decline in guidance for 2008, at least at the start of the year. I'm guess I'm wondering, if you have a positive experience say by the end of Q2, do you think you might reconsider the magnitude of the occupancy decline you gave at the start of the year for your full-year guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think this, Jeff.  I do think there's another 50-plus basis points of risk on the down side to occupancy, Q2, from stores that are &#x2013; as David mentioned, are people who are either in workout mode or we would expect to get space back. Demand for space is still decent. We are pushing very hard and the visibility would be, can we get back to flat by year-end? That would certainly be the objective. If we miss it, I don't think we miss it by 100 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'm just curious, one last question on occupancy. Is it also &#x2013; so, I guess, am I stretching too far to say maybe any further declines in occupancy will probably come more from expirations and terminations, as opposed to bankruptcies? And I guess for that reason, do you think your termination revenues could actually be above normal in the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well again, the guys that are &#x2013; we are hedging here because there are a couple of guys that are somewhat on this, on the &#x2013; deciding what they are going to do in terms of how they want to restructure. And I would say the variability is really with that sector of two, three, four tenants, as opposed to the guys that we kind of know what is happening with. So, some of that may produce lease termination income, but it is still in process. So, the bottom line for us is, we still think we are going to grow our NOI 3 or 4%. Composition my change somewhat because of the variability of, again, these, the handful of tenants I talked about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>David, are they more like in the home goods area, or is there a particular theme to what area they operate in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is really across the board. Disney is a great example, the Disney Store situation. We are negotiating with them right now. As you know they were owned by Children's Place. There's a movement toward Disney buying them back, which is actually very positive for us. But they don't want to operate the 350-store chain that they had. They want to operate a smaller chain. We are going to have some closings associated with that. And we are negotiating. So it would be great to say, here is what is exactly going to happen, but we are still in the process of working through that. And that's really, it's a couple of those guys that are like that, like a Disney, like a Wilson's, that we are still trying to get a handle on, that &#x2013; we are working obviously closely with the tenants, but that is creating the variability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jeff Specter with UBS. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Does your guidance still assume a soft landing in the economy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The guidance makes no &#x2013; I would tell you that our guidance is really not dependent upon the economy. I don't know that we can sit there and say, forecast GDP growth and that's going to spit out exactly what comp NOI is going to be. It is a judgment call. We know kind of what our lease-up is. We know, we have variability in sales. We have variability in interest rates. You put it all in, we make some judgment calls. That's how it gets &#x2013; that is how we get to our numbers. And that's why we have a range. That's also why I would love not to give guidance, OK? But we are fine. And if it does become less &#x2013; or more severe, then I think there will be more opportunities for us. So I'm good with that, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And with the year-to-date rebound in REIT stock prices, if they remain level for a period of time, do you think we will see a pickup in M&amp;A, public-to-public?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, I don't know. I guess, maybe. M&amp;A is such a emotional framework that I do think &#x2013; let me put it this way. I do think running a company in a tough economic environment is, is very difficult and I think it will wear down a lot of people. Not us. But it's going to wear down a lot. And usually when you are worn out is when you want to get out. So, I guess &#x2013; I don't know if it's stock price so much, but more of, kind of where the mindset is. And I think it is tougher, and it's tough running any company in a tougher environment. And that could lead to more M&amp;A, more than stock price charts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Nate Isby with Stieffel Nicolaus. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I'm here with David as well. What are the leasing spreads you're generating in the traditional Mills portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say they are consistent with the mall business, the specialty stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And could you just touch briefly ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are very anxious to see David when he tours the portfolio. We are going to want an escorted tour, though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How is Alamalada looking these days, David?  No, I'm sorry.</p>
          <p>A &#x2013; David Simon&gt;: That's the wrong company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry.  The Delamo, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Delamo? Well, that is not a Mills. Delamo is still in lease-up phase. A unique asset with lots of opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any movement there on a fashion anchor? The fashion anchor has been discussed five years. I know it wasn't you, but any progress there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have only discussed it for a few months, so we still have some time there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're hopeful, or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It may be harder to achieve than what Mills &#x2013; I still think there's a possibility but it may be harder to achieve, and the time period may be longer than what the market was originally told by the earlier group. We are still working on it, in other words. But it's not ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" /> Your next call comes from the line of Rich Moore with RBC Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys. What are you seeing on the concession front? Are you offering more concessions in this environment, being that it is a bit tougher for tenants?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. The only thing I would say is to the extent that we have a tenant in the workout mode, we do a thorough &#x2013; and I mean, that is really when they have leverage on, we are going to &#x2013; If you don't make a deal we are going to put it in chapter 11. And I put that aside, because in that case we have to decide, we do a pretty thorough analysis of whether we're better off recouping our lease value through what the estate would get, versus what kind retailer they are, what kind of company it is, and whether it is in our best interests to keep them going. Put that aside, I would say generally, if it is just a straight-up deal there's not &#x2013; there hasn't been a big change in much higher TEA or much lower rents. I mean, everything is on the margin so I would say that trend is pretty consistent. We are giving some rent relief to tenants that are in this workout phase that I've described.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good, thank you. And then, on the specialty retailing side, that is an area you may think would run into difficulty in a weaker environment. Is there any &#x2013; do you have any thoughts on specialty retailing at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well again, it depends on the tenant and the sector. Lots of teen retailers are doing very fine. The H&amp;M's and the Other World and the Forever 21's are doing extremely well. So, it really depends on the retailer. I would tell you that it is not &#x2013; you know, it is tough, but it is not a disaster in a lot of cases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then how about like the carts and kiosks, Dave? Is that an area that's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Surprisingly, we are OK there. I would think that &#x2013; I would tell you that I would have thought that that business would obviously be impacted by the economy, but we're -- happened to ride up with the guy that runs it today in the elevator, and I grilled him to make sure, because I knew I was going to get this question. No, I'm kidding. But he seemed to be fine. There may be a little bit of receivable issues on some of them. But demand is holding up and he thinks we will be OK for what we are thinking about this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. And then the last thing, Steve, what are you thinking for LIBOR? How did you come about a LIBOR assumption, I guess, when you were working on your guidance for 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rich, whether it was the original guidance or the updated guidance, all we do is take the forward curve. I don't pretend to be any smarter than what the forward curve is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm disappointed. I thought you were going to tell me where LIBOR is going. All right, thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But if you know, let us know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I certainly will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes our Q&amp;A session. I'd like to turn the call back over to management for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, everybody. We are disappointed we didn't get a question about Rick's shoulder. But he is recuperating fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18">
        <plist>
          <p>He is listening in and we wish him well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We wish him well. So, in any event, thank you. I'm sure we will see some of you in the next month. But we appreciate your support. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect. Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>