<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1369727" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2911</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Sock Koong Chua, Group Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Allen Lew</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Paul O'Sullivan</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Michael Smith</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Luis Hilado</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Weng Cheong Hui</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Bradley Clibborn</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Murray King</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Richard Eary</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Arthur Pineda</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Quah Kung Yang</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep">Jeann Low</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Chris Vagg</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Mark Blackwell</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Sachin Mittal</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Kelvin Goh</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Ramakrishna Maruvada</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Christian Guerra</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Somesh Agarwal</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Ashwin Sanketh</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. A warm welcome to all investors and analysts. You are listening to SingTel's Earnings Conference Call for the quarter ended 30th September, 2010. My name is Yang Fong, and let me introduce panel members on the call.</p>
          <p>Ms. Chua Sock Koong, Group CEO; Mr. Allen Lew, CEO Singapore; Mr. Paul O'Sullivan, CEO, Optus; Mr. Hui Weng Cheong, CEO International (designate); Ms. Jeann Low, Group CFO.</p>
          <p>They are also assisted by other members of the management team from Australia and</p>
          <p>Singapore. Before we start taking questions, I would like to invite Sock Koong to share some highlights from this set of results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yang Fong, thank you and thanks for joining us today for SingTel's results for the quarter and half year ended 30th September, 2010 that we announced this morning. Let me just give you a number of &#x2013; just give you some key financial highlights.</p>
          <p>If you look at the group numbers, revenues were up a strong 8%. Both Singapore and Australia operations continued their revenue momentum and, of course, at the group level that was further lifted by the stronger Australian dollar.</p>
          <p>Group EBITDA was stable and, however, group net profit was down 6% with higher depreciation, finance, and tax expenses. Excluding the impact of Bharti Africa's losses and financing costs, group net profit would have been down 3%. In Singapore, revenues rose 10% on strong growth in mobile and IT and engineering. EBITDA fell 6%, reflecting mobile customer acquisition cost and continued investments in multimedia initiatives such as our mio TV content and rollout.</p>
          <p>Australia, Optus revenue grew 5%. That's driven by continued strong performance in mobile. EBITDA was up 9% with higher EBITDA across all three business segments. The group and associates continue to generate strong customer growth. We now have 368 million mobile customers. Earnings from Regional Mobile Associates declined 6% with lower operating profits from Telkomsel and Bharti.</p>
          <p>Overseas operations now contribute 76% of proportionate EBITDA with Optus accounting for about 31% and the Regional Mobile Associates 43%. The group has also announced an increase in dividend payout to between 55% to 70% of underlying net profit and the board has approved an interim dividend payment of S$0.068 a share is up 10% year-on-year and represents a payout ratio of 59% of the half year's underlying net profit.</p>
          <p>So with that, let me hand over to Yang Fong to handle the Q&amp;A. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sock Koong. I would like to remind participants that this call will last for about an hour. To help us achieve that, if your question has already been asked and you would like to deregister from the queue press zero, two. Our operator will now assist you to put through your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ma'am. First question, Sachin Gupta, over to you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. I've got a few questions. Firstly, maybe for Sock Koong or Jeann. It's good to see you have increased the payout ratio but was wondering, is it possible to talk about &#x2013; what are your thoughts on different forms of capital management because you've still got a fair bit of cash sitting on the balance sheet and it's predominantly sitting in the Singapore business and you're not getting a lot of interest on that. So just wondering any thoughts on other deployment options?</p>
          <p>That's my first one. Secondly, Allen, you've had about S$70 odd million revenue from OpenNet and that's largely &#x2013; is that largely construction or there is some revenue in there from wholesale, as part of your 30% ownership in OpenNet as well? That's my second question and, thirdly, Paul, the consumer business, it's good to see the margin has gone up to 17% odd but most of your customers are actually on-net now, so was just wondering what's the strategy for the broadband business going forward and also in the Mobile business, trends have been phenomenal but are you noticing any pickup in the competitive intensity in the past few months? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sachin, thanks for your questions and I'm glad that you approved of our increase in dividend payout ratio. I think clearly the group is committed to working towards getting to optimum capital structure and making sure that we still have enough financial capacity and flexibility to pursue the various growth initiatives. We will still, at the end of the financial year, continue with our reviews of our overall capital structure, taking into consideration the plans for the next financial year, CapEx management plan, growth initiatives, et cetera, and review this. More needs to be done.</p>
          <p>On this half year or quarterly numbers, sometimes you see higher cash balances for various reasons. Some of it are actually foreign currency deposits held for hedging foreign currency payable. So some of this are just because of timing reasons that you see higher than usual cash level. We are quite conscious of wanting to reduce the negative carry from low yielding deposits and having to pay interest on our various borrowings. So it is a bit of a timing issue. I will pass over to Allen to talk about OpenNet and, then, maybe Paul can pick up on the consumer business in Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sachin, Allen here. Basically the S$70 million that you see is mainly our fibre rollout revenue which is basically the contract that OpenNet have given us to lay the fibre. This has increased from S$31 million one year ago and reflects the speeding up of the fibre rollout as part of the National Broadband Network. As you know, OpenNet is only an associate. It's 30% owned by SingTel so whatever revenue they get from wholesaling the fibre, we do not consolidate in our books, we only take a percentage of their EBITDA because they are a associate.</p>
          <p>I think you also know that SingTel has a lease agreement, duct lease agreement with OpenNet where they use our ducts to run their fibre and, as a result of this duct-lease agreement, we do get a revenue share and that revenue will go in under our Data and Internet line because it's part of our wholesale revenue. I hope that answers your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then we might pick up, it's Paul here and what I was going to do was ask Michael Smith, who's the Managing Director of our consumer business to talk about the broadband market and then I'll come back and talk about mobile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Sachin. In relation to broadband, yeah, our focus is, has been for some time to drive the on-net business. As you'd be aware, we deployed DOCSIS 3, which enables capability up to 100 megabit. It's been a focus for us to drive that into our customer base and will continue to be a focus for us to make sure that we drive ARPUs in our on-net business.</p>
          <p>And probably the second phase would be to make sure that we drive maximum utilization of our investments in ULL. We've been running strongly on that and we continue to focus on driving full utilization of those exchanges and, then, as we look at probably a little bit forward we'll be, as Allen has had a great success in Singapore, contemplate our future in sort of digital media services and the opportunities that they may bring us to take our med businesses to the next level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mike. And just closing off on the mobile point, in the first part of the question Sachin, you say absolutely we see Telstra spending more heavily in the market with obviously their sacrifice of profits now becoming more visible and we've seen that also in a repricing of their plans and their aggressive push behind caps for the first time.</p>
          <p>However, I think these numbers also show you that even in a more competitive market Optus continues to execute well. We have 180,000 plus net adds for the quarter, 140,000 plus of those are post paid and I think that demonstrates that we are still executing strongly on our core strategy. Talking about that our strategy is not about merely responding to our competitors in a quarter, it's a long term plan. It's about extending our network footprint both geographically but also in terms of depth and capacity with backhaul and extra spectrum and extra sites.</p>
          <p>It's about leveraging smartphones and wireless broadband to help win higher value customers and it's also about increasingly moving forward, leveraging convergence on broadband across fixed and across mobile. You'll see us continue to execute those strategies. We believe there's still significant fixed traffic to be cannibalized across under mobile networks. We believe there are still a lot of people looking for the sort of choice and competition we offer and you'll see us continue to execute on that strategy even in a market that sounds like it's going to be a lot more competitive in the next half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thanks. Can I just quickly follow up on the first question, Sock Koong? Obviously, you talk about regional opportunities. Vodafone has been &#x2013; Vodafone PLT, they've been divesting some of the regional minority shareholdings and they do have a stake in Bharti as well. Is that something that's appealing to you guys and, secondly, I guess that the shareholding structure is a bit confusing at times. Can you increase the shareholding further in Bharti Airtel without breaching the foreign shareholding cap?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, firstly to address Vodafone's stake in Bharti Enterprises, you have seen in Vittorio's own interview that he's concluded that there's only one buyer for its shares, because this is a holding company two levels up that holds a lot of other investments other than in addition to the telco business. We will leave Vodafone to sort out their shareholding. Sorry, what was your other question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I was just wondering given the shareholding structure is at different levels, are shareholding is in different levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the Indian rules &#x2013; the rules in India as to how telco shareholders, the foreign shareholding level is being calculated has now been changed, so there is actually foreign shareholding rule for SingTel, but obviously, as you are aware, the security rules in India are fairly complicated. You've got limits as to the maximum amount of shares you can acquire in the year, et cetera, so you've seen us buy shares periodically in the market but we are very mindful about the various constraints and we make sure that we deal within those security rules in India.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Luis Hilado, HSBC Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, thanks for the call. I just have a few questions, two on the Singapore business and one on international. On the Singapore side, I'm just wondering if it's correct that the bulk of the selling and admin Q on Q increase is due to EPL content costs or is there some F1 related costs in there and, therefore, we could see it coming off in the next quarter?</p>
          <p>And, second, is on the staff costs. Should we expect further increases going forward in terms of head count and, therefore, the cost?</p>
          <p>And the last question is in terms of Warid. Any rough guideline when you think it will become breakeven in terms of profit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me answer the questions on Singapore. In terms of the selling and admin costs, it is not just the mio TV content costs that has led to the increase, there's also a big increase in higher SACs and that's primarily because of two effects. Number one, we've had a very strong quarter in terms of acquisition. As you can see we acquired 39,000 mobile postpaid customers compared to our competitors who have a significantly lower number.</p>
          <p>The second also reflects the shift of our base and the new customers towards smartphones where because we have a higher ARPU our subsidy is a little bit higher. So, I think the increase is primarily due to the two effects of content costs plus our SAC costs.</p>
          <p>In terms of the staff cost, a reasonable percentage of the increase is because of job credits. If you take out job credits actually staff costs only grew 2.8% and in terms of whether headcounts were increased, actually the head count in the telco business are stable; we are trying to hold that flat. The main increase in head count comes from our IT services subsidiary called NCS, and the bulk of that head count increase is actually because we acquired IT services company in the Philippines, that account for about 211 and that won't be repeated in subsequent quarters.</p>
          <p>Subsequent quarter staff increase in IT services will be dependent on projects that they secure and the need to man up these projects, so they are supported by topline growth in revenue.</p>
          <p>I'll hand over to Hui to talk about Warid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Hui here. Regards to Warid, the situation in Pakistan is still very tough for the operators there due actually to the country <mark type="inaudible" /> as well as the strong competition over there. Warid has recently done well in terms of EBITDA, whole of last year is EBITDA positive; this quarter is also higher than the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving forward, Warid will be reviewing their competitive offer, as I understand, in Pakistan, opportunity there is more on the multi-SIM. And most operators are banking on the creative bundling to up-sell to the customers. Likewise, Warid is reviewing our packaging and moving forward we do see a lot stronger competition, but cost-wise Warid is taking a lot of measures to improve the bottom line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just one follow up I guess on terms of the SAC costs during the quarter. One of your competitors said there's some supply constraints there for the iPhone during the quarter, which sort of held back sales. Did you experience the same and are you seeing &#x2013; if that's the case whether the situation has improved and we should see even better revenues and but higher SAC going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, my apologies, but we're not allowed to talk about whatever stock situation we have with our particular handset provider. I think the only point I want to add to that is that unlike some of our competitors, we have a little bit more diversified portfolio of smartphones. So I think you know whilst the predominant one is still very much the one that everybody is talking about today, we also have a significant range of other smartphones which can be used as and when required to meet the needs of different customers.</p>
          <p>We also have a very strong business market share in the business segment. And of course for them, a significant number of them are looking at BlackBerry type devices. So I think we're somewhat a little bit more diversified in terms of our ability to meet customers' mobile device needs than perhaps some of our competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Bradley Clibborn, Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just two questions for Paul on Optus. Firstly, just looking at CapEx down to 10% of sales. Paul, if you could just give us some indication on where you expect that to trend kind of in the next 12 to 24 months? Whether that dip is just a one off for this quarter?</p>
          <p>And, secondly, just looking at the fixed business, if we look at your broadband ARPU up 8.5% year-on-year. If you could give us some indication just on what's driving that. And particularly when you look at voice, which is voice ARPU which is growing as well. Just what's driving your overall on-net consumer yields there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for that. I'm going to ask Murray to talk on the CapEx to revenue ratios and then I'll get Michael to talk about the fixed business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul. In relation to sort of the CapEx number to revenue in respect of the quarter at 10%, it's really a consequence of phasing. If you look at our half year CapEx to revenue ratio's around 12%. We have guided the market that for the full year that our CapEx would be around A$1.2 billion of expenditure. And as you can see in our overall MD&amp;A, we continue to weight our CapEx into our Mobile business, given that's where predominantly our growth is coming from. And as the NBN decisions are pending, we'll look to minimise our capital investments into our fixed business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the fixed business with broadband, I guess a few key drivers of that; we did launch a DOCSIS service in the Australian market during the last quarter and we spent a lot of time with our existing base encouraging them about the benefits of that service. So that's helped us drive ARPU into the base. We've also encouraged, as we have in the mobility business, much more value into our plans. We've also had some good and encouraging results in relation to up-sell. And then as it relates to new business, it's prima facie a mixed question about the quality of customers we're bringing in to the business. So they'd be the three key drivers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you're saying that there's a trend towards increasing usage within your broadband base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as services changed significantly over the last 12 months, the amount of included value or included data that's available to customers. Customers are finding ways to avail themselves to that, whether it be through video or other services. So yes, there is increasing usage coupling the increasing provisions that we're providing customers in our plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Richard [Richard Eary], UBS, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, morning guys. Just really &#x2013; just one question actually for Paul and the Optus guys. Just with a lot of noise that's been sort of like talked about in terms of the POI locations under the NBN rollout. I don't know whether you can sort of give us your thoughts in terms of the 14 POI model versus obviously the larger model, which was the 200 to 300 model and what that means to you in terms of stranded assets or competitive advantages down the track?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, Richard. I think you'll see us fairly public on this in some of the media as well over the next 24 hours. We're very much of the view that the NBN debate is really fundamentally about competition, not necessarily about a technology or about costs. And over the last five years, what's been proven and is now endorsed by both major political parties is that there's a strong need to reform the fixed sector to allow a level playing field for competition. And, that's the only way we're going to get breakthroughs in technology and pricing and quality. Just as we have in mobile.</p>
          <p>We're opposed to the idea of having only 14 POI, because it basically breaks four important rules that are all about good competition. First of all, having accepted that we may have to live with a monopoly for last mile access to most Australian homes because it is the only economic way to fund fibre to the home, it would not be good sense to extend that monopoly further and to move it into backhaul. Monopolies of their very nature are not good things.</p>
          <p>Secondly, by having a monopoly back into the backhaul market, we will see &#x2013; we believe a recreation of an environment in which there will be no incentive to invest in upgrading technology or any competing forces seeking to drive greater efficiencies.</p>
          <p>The third major reason we'd be opposed to the proposed 14 POIs is the impact it will have on other markets. Over time, all of us have built up business with state governments, with large corporate Australia, with households who buy our services. As well as in the Mobile business, which have allowed us to fund and build backhaul infrastructure, which is shared with other services. If you take a lot of traffic off those networks, then you're going to leave the residual economics having to be carried by the other private sectors. So it will create distortions into other markets.</p>
          <p>And the fourth reason we think it makes bad sense for Australia is the sovereign risk issue. It's been government policy since deregulation to encourage infrastructure based competition in the Australian telecoms market. SingTel-Optus has made a large investment of over A$ 1 billion a year in Australia on the understanding that facilities based competition was the name of the game. To change the rules now and strand those investments, is actually a very bad thing for the investment environment. So we are &#x2013; we think it makes bad sense for Australia and bad sense for competition. There are approximately 200 points of interconnect in Australia where there will be at least two competitive carriers vying for wholesale traffic. We think it makes sense to allow the market to take hold for competition to again be the dominant force in the industry and to provide interconnect at least at 200 POI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, can I just follow up there. If the government does go down the route of just doing 14 rather than 200, what does that actually mean for your business in terms of CapEx and particularly to the fibre within the mobile backhaul. Does that increase your costs and strand your assets further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'd need to see a little bit more detail on the final shape of it to be able to give you a more qualified answer. At this stage it's not clear what the pricing regime would be or what the access regime would be for those parties. Or whether indeed it would be still possible to access lower down the network and that the difference in economics would be borne by someone who chose either to take at a lower point, or at the more aggregated point. So too early to make a definitive comment on that.</p>
          <p>All I would say is that regard as what's good for us, if you just look at the four points I just outlined, they're actually all about what's good for the industry and what's good for Australia. And I think it will be a very negative development for Australia if we chose to create such a market distortion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Arthur Pineda, Citigroup, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi thanks for the call. I have two questions, both of which are on Singapore. Firstly, what do you think will change in succeeding quarters to allow you to average 35% EBITDA margin domestically, given that costs have probably permanently escalated to payTV and smartphone sales. And just for clarification, are the EPL charges recognized throughout the year or is it only during the broadcast season on that issue?</p>
          <p>Second question I had is with NGNBN. Now that it's fully functional, how do you see your Data and Internet revenue and market share being affected? Are you seeing corporate customer movements or price negotiation now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay I think you've got three questions. One on the &#x2013; what will allow us to hit our guidance of 35% EBITDA in Singapore. The second question is on the EPL, whether you're amortizing during the season or throughout the whole year. And the third one, NGNBN, let me ask my CFO for Singapore, Kung Yang, who's here to answer your question on EPL first then I'll come back on the first and third question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes on the content cost for EPL, we actually amortize it over the season. So we &#x2013; in this quarter, the EPL season started in August. So you see it's like two months of a typical quarter of amortization cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat when is the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the cost recognition will only be seen in 2Q and 3Q?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. We will amortize it over the period of the whole season. So you start doing it this quarter but you would see a higher cost next quarter, because this quarter it only started in August. The next quarter, you will still see -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think we &#x2013; this is Jeann, we are amortizing it with effect from August to 2010 over the life of the contract.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the EBITDA guidance that we've given for Singapore, I think the market would have seen what is our performance in Q1 and in Q2. I'm afraid I can't give you further forecasts with regard to Q3 and Q4 because of competitive reasons. I think the EPL content cost is going to be a constant, but I think at the end of the day there are also things like subscriber acquisition costs. And these will flex depending on different levels of competitive activity out there.</p>
          <p>Also our EBITDA is also influenced a lot by our revenue. And our revenue also will go through different seasonal peaks depending on usage in Q3 and Q4. So I'm afraid, I can't give too much more light on that. But I think as emphasized in our press announcement this morning or in our results announcement this morning, the Singapore business still reaffirms its guidance with regard to our EBITDA margins.</p>
          <p>With regard to NGNBN, it's early days. We've only covered only 40% of Singapore. In fact if you look at the offers that are out there and you look at what's happening as a result of the NGNBN launch, the primary objective of most of the RSPs out there has been to target the consumer market. If you look at above the line, certainly nothing is happening with the business market except for a few positioning ads. And actually if you look at the take-up rate of fibre in Singapore, the bulk of it is at the consumer end; and the business end by and large there is some take-up rate, but mainly amongst SME customers. So I think it's early days, but I'm very optimistic, in terms of what's happening, in our ability to compete with our competitors in the business market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Chris Vagg, Citigroup, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for the question. It was just on the fixed broadband market in Australia, again. I didn't hear, but you made some comments about new media assets, or new media services. Is that in specific reference to maybe some sort of IPTV product or being an unmetered partner for an existing IPTV player like we've seen a lot of here in Australia?</p>
          <p>And then just, also, on mobile SACs in Australia. Obviously, they were up significantly this quarter, but have you seen any impact from the stronger Aussie dollar? Any positive impact from the stronger Aussie dollar in terms of handset prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. It's Paul here. I'll start on the broadband, and I'll let Murray talk a bit about the mobile SACs. I think on the broadband, to clarify, the comments we're making are about selling services, which are value-adding services, on top of the carriage there. Not about any specific service or anything to do with TV per se. So the thrust of our developments over the next couple of years will be very much to leverage the convergence of consumer behaviors and broadband across mobile and fixed, and to provide them with products and services that allow them to have pretty much ubiquitous access and agnostic access. In other words, not to have to worry about whether they're coming in on the mobile or the fixed in order to be able to access the same preferences, or content, or messaging that they've traditionally had. I think that's a consistent direction you're seeing across the industry. I'll pass over to Murray to talk about SACs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, as you rightly pointed out, you've seen our SAC costs up for this quarter, predominantly as a result of the greater weighting into smartphones. So, that's driven the overall growth in mobile SACs. In relation to your question about the appreciation of the Australian dollar on the impact to SACs, clearly, the majority of manufacturers manufacture the units offshore, and with the stronger Australia dollar, there's the opportunity for us to get lower unit pricing and where we have that opportunity we do take advantage of it, but it hasn't really had a significant impact in relation to our overall SAC movements for this respective quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Mark Blackwell, Morgan Stanley, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. Sorry to keep harping on about Australia, but I've got a couple of questions on Australia. Firstly, just to follow up on Brad's question earlier about broadband ARPUs, you're highlighting that you're putting customers onto higher value plans. I'm presuming that means more gigabytes. Are you seeing much cost impact of that yet?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on the mobile market, I noticed that Telstra has just released, for the first time, an unlimited use plan, which, I guess is, to some degree, crossing the Rubicon for them, given the potential impact on fixed. Are you seeing that as a significant event, or is that just part of the overall competitive intensity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay I'll take the mobile question first, and then I'll let Michael talk on the broadband ARPU issue. I think on mobile, it's not just the unlimited plan, although I'll remind listeners that we were the first to bring a truly unlimited plan to the market about two years ago with our initial unlimited launch. So, it's always flattering to see a competitor copy a good idea. But more generally, it's their decision to embrace caps, which I think is crossing the Rubicon as you would describe it.</p>
          <p>What we saw when we first launched caps, now, back about five or six years ago, is that it has two dramatic effects. The first one is it cannibalizes fixed quite aggressively. Customers who now know they can make a call without having to pay a charge on a mobile, shifted pretty aggressively off the fixed network.</p>
          <p>The second thing we also saw at that stage was that we had to reprice our base because people were coming off non-capped plans and onto capped plans. So, I would say the decision to get aggressive behind caps and launch them into the market by Telstra does represent recognition on their part that they have had to reprice in order to meet competition.</p>
          <p>Speaking for us, again, bring you back to our strategy, which is all about building greater footprint and capacity on our network, which we're doing with expanding the footprint towards 98%. It will be at 97% at the end of this year.</p>
          <p>We have also bought spectrum on Qualcomm, which we are now busy rolling out in the capital cities. It doubled our 3G spectrum allocation. We were first in winning a whole series, over 1000 regional licenses, for 3G spectrum, which we're also deploying. We have upgraded our backhaul network very extensively to carry more broadband capacity, and we are also engaged, at the moment, in our first metro build of new sites for many years.</p>
          <p>All of that's about building our network capability so that we can continue to drive very aggressively in the mobile market and to continue to grow our business. That's the strategy we'll keep executing. I have no doubt Telstra's repricing and the sacrifice of margin is going to have an impact in the mobile market. I think, as you can see from our results, we continue to focus on executing our strategies and on driving growth. And with that, I'll pass over to Mike to talk about the broadband market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, mobile is a good segue into the broadband. As the mobile caps have come into our business, we've seen customers enjoy utilization within those products, and what's happening in broadband will be the same.</p>
          <p>So, Mark, to your specific question, yes, usage is increasing. As we launched much higher bandwidth broadband products into the market, I think there was a concern industry-wide, that had been seen in some other markets, where customers traded down their spend to stay at the same level.</p>
          <p>We've always positioned our plans as about being utility for the customer and, out of that process, we've managed to convince customers to stay at or increase some of their spend on their rate plans. And then that will result, in the end, in further utilization. So they're not using all of their limits, but it is increasing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's interesting. I was particularly interested, though, on the cost side of that. Are you seeing that costs &#x2013; given you're allowing so much more bandwidth now, are you seeing that your costs are going up to reflect that, or is that cost more or less contained or fixed within your business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll talk about that in a couple of important respects, Mark. The first one would be &#x2013; and I'll let Murray talk about it a bit more. But the first one is that there would obviously be your local access costs where you're riding infrastructure. And the second one is that a lot of Australian Internet traffic does end up going overseas to the U.S. So, in that case, we're looking at capacity we'd have on Southern Cross, which goes across the Pacific.</p>
          <p>Stealing a bit of Murray's thunder, I guess in both cases, what you don't have is a great degree of variable costs because in many cases we bought the capacity, and it is a really a question of &#x2013; or we built it, it's a question of how quickly we use that up.</p>
          <p>So, it doesn't drive a lot of short-term costs. For us the bigger issue therefore is can we drive incremental ARPU out of it and get a better value from the customer. Murray, anything you want to add to that? In that case &#x2013; sorry, I did steal his thunder. But I just thought maybe it was easier to try and give you an overview of the way we look at the profitability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks guys. Good result. Well done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Sachin Mittal, DBS Vickers, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for the call. I have two questions on associates. First is on Bharti. I mean the tax rate of 25% which we saw for Bharti this quarter was quite high. In fact, they're paying more than the pre-tax earnings as tax for the Bharti Africa. Could you explain, is that something we should factor in our model going forward, the high tax rate, or is this like one-time event?</p>
          <p>And secondly, could you throw some light on the competitive environment in the Philippines, and how is Globe doing over there? Because the profit seems to have declined and then stabilized there. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Bharti has also on their calls advised that clearly the increase in the tax rate is that out of the 16 OpCos that they have in Africa, those which are profit-making at the profit after tax level have an effective tax rate of around 30%, whereas for the loss making entities, because of the absence of reasonable uncertainties for accounting purposes, the deferred tax assets, or the deferred tax credit, are not recognized for the majority of those OpCos that are still loss-making.</p>
          <p>So, you do see a higher effective tax rate when you look at the overall net results of Bharti. So I hope that explains it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Globe <mark type="inaudible" /> in Philippine peso terms, the pre-tax operating profit contribution for the group declined 22% year on year. Operating revenue increased 2% despite continued aggressive competition and proliferation of multi-SIM.</p>
          <p>The popularity of bulk and unlimited voice and SMS also exerted the pressure on mobile revenue. Group momentum for broadband continues to be strong with revenue up 77%. Operating expenses increased 13% due to higher provisions, outsourced services, and network-driven costs.</p>
          <p>On the competitive front, Globe has introduced the unlimited plan in response to the stiff competition over there. More recently, in June they have implemented the daily unlimited plan. This has resulted in an increase in the customer base, which is a good sign for us. In regards to the network itself, for these unlimited plans, software has been put in to ensure that the regular paying customers have priority over the unlimited plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So more or less, I mean, Philippines is not through the bad patch which they have seen in the last one year? Can we draw the conclusion from there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the Philippines market has been very competitive. And in fact, you've seen it also in the other operators' number, where you know the revenue growth has been flat &#x2013; has been relatively flat. I suppose what is more pleasing this quarter is that Globe has added on postpaid net adds ahead of the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Kelvin Goh, CIMB, Malaysia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for the opportunity. And I'm not sure if this question's been asked, but I'd like to know what the rationale is behind you raising your dividend payout policy to where it is. I'm wondering if it's probably some sort of recognition that there is potentially limited acquisition opportunities out there, or is there something &#x2013; or do you think that your cash flows will improve going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The last time that we, I suppose, indicated a change in dividend policy was in December '08 &#x2013; May '08, and this policy, frankly, takes into account our commitment.</p>
          <p>This policy of increasing the dividend payout ratio to 55% to 70% of our underlying net profit versus the earlier payout of 45% to 60%, indicate our commitment to an optimal capital structure. So I think this is part of our capital management exercise where we review our dividend policy on a very regular basis, and also of course in response to our shareholders' expectations.</p>
          <p>But I think what is important is that in revising our dividend policy and in wanting to be committed to an optimal capital structure, we also want to &#x2013; we also desire a certain level of flexibility to pursue our growth initiative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have any targets for gearing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think if you look at our current gearing, it is under one time debt to EBITDA. We are committed to investment grade credit rating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with investment grade rating, what would that require you to have in terms of your gearing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would be &#x2013; I think if you look at the credit rating that we are at, the typical ratio should be between 1.5 to 2.0 times.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Rama Maruvada, Daiwa, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good day, everyone. I have two questions, firstly, with regards to the NBN AssetCo creation by April 2011. Just wondering, given that most of the assets are probably fully depreciated, does the creation of this company have any implication from a balance sheet or a P&amp;L perspective?</p>
          <p>And the second one has to do with the timing of withholding taxes, if you could just provide some color on what is the policy here and, in particular, when the withholding taxes for AIS special dividend will be accrued?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The timing of withholding tax, the withholding tax would be recognized in the period that dividends are being remitted, so that is basically aligned with the dividend payment.</p>
          <p>On the AssetCo, I think you are aware that we are committed with the IDA as part of the implementation of the national broadband network in Singapore that we would transfer certain assets to AssetCo by April 2011, and then we have a commitment that by April 2014, we will divest a significant part of our stake in AssetCo. We will basically hold no more than 25% and of course that will be subject to relevant approvals including shareholders' approval.</p>
          <p>I think as we transfer the assets to AssetCo into an AssetCo business trust, in the initial years it would still be fully owned by the group. So in terms of the economic ownership it will still be 100% owned by the group and whichever value that we put on AssetCo when we do the transfer will be eliminated at a group level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, understood. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Christian Guerra, Goldman Sachs, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thanks for your time. I've three questions, the first one Singapore and then two on Optus. Firstly on Singapore, now that NGNBN is operational and you're now almost at 50% coverage of Singapore, just wondering, Allen, whether you could please talk about how the product margins look versus your existing standalone business and especially data and internet?</p>
          <p>Secondly, a question for Paul on mobiles. Paul, just a few questions there. Firstly in terms of the mobiles market, if you could maybe talk about your average wireless broadband usage per month and how that's been tracking over the last six months?</p>
          <p>Secondly, in terms of backhaul, I know that you're moving from E1s to GigE. Just wondering if you could tell us please how you're tracking in terms of the percentage of base stations now covered by gigabit Ethernet?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, you talked earlier about making some changes to the network footprint and continuing to expand the network. Just wondering what you're thinking in terms of LTE and specifically whether Optus will be going it alone on network build or whether you're still open to a network sharing agreement?</p>
          <p>And just my final question on Optus is again in relation to the competitive environment down here in terms of the changes we've seen over the last six months, great performance as many on the call have talked about. Just wondering whether you see yourselves having to maybe spend a little bit more to keep that momentum up over the next couple of quarters? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian, Allen here in Singapore. Regarding your NGNBN question, NGNBN today covers about 40% odd of the homes and businesses, but I think from SingTel's perspective we take a much longer term approach towards NGNBN.</p>
          <p>NGNBN is the future fixed network. It allows us to not just provide broadband Internet access and the traditional voice, but it allows us to change our entire revenue profile to providing software as a service for businesses, to providing a whole host of other entertainment, information and lifestyle services for our residential customers.</p>
          <p>So I think if you look at just the pure carriage play, obviously NGNBN uses fibre, it's a much newer technology, it hasn't gone down the experience curve. The people that we have to put to look after it, to install it and to maintain it are a little bit more than we have to do for our corporate base network.</p>
          <p>I think in the short term it's probably we get less margins from NGNBN customers, but I think our potential to up sell the customer, both the business and the consumer customer, as well as our ability to get cost reductions or economies of scale as we get more customers coming into the fibre network and to cut better deals with our equipment suppliers as the technology matures is something that's very important that'll help us drive the margins closer to what we're getting with our legacy copper network.</p>
          <p>The other important thing to also remember is that as part of the NGNBN view, SingTel has leased its ducts to the NetCo, the company providing the fibres, and we get a 70% to 75% revenue share for every dollar that they get. So if you factor that in, then that helps improve our margin even more on the fibre business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul here, Christian. Sorry, Christian, did you have a follow up on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm happy for you to keep going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. So just kicking on to pick up on your issues, just looking at the mobile there's a mixture of things we have and have not disclosed on that. So let me try and find a way of talking about it that is helpful without getting into new disclosures.</p>
          <p>I think we'd say on the wireless broadband usage it has always been the case that customers use less than their allowance, often significantly less. The trend over the last 12 months has undoubtedly been to see people use more, but they are still generally well within their allowances. So there's a tendency in the marketplace for people who want to buy security or safety when they buy wireless broadband allowances. I don't think we've disclosed actuals and to some extent we probably see it as competitive, but it goes to the heart of the economics of each of the products.</p>
          <p>On backhaul, again, we haven't given detailed disclosures on that over time. I think what we have talked about is the fact that we were aggressively upgrading our network and building faster speeds and there's been a significant amount of work done on that. But I'll have another look and talk to the IR team and see is there anything we should be doing in terms of matching the market disclosure on those sort of issues.</p>
          <p>On the last one then, we do see LTE as important. In fact right across the group SingTel's been driving aggressively on LTE. And we're part of a group of affiliates that are all collaborating on trailing different LTE vendors and on getting what we believe to be the best of breed approach. We've actually done an LTE trial and operation here in Sydney and have gained significant learnings from that.</p>
          <p>We do think it's going to be important and necessary in order to carry the volumes of traffic we believe Australians will want to carry sometime in the next few years, but beyond that in terms of giving timing of rollout or anything else, at this stage, we haven't chosen to make any announcements or any statements.</p>
          <p>I'm sorry that's all a bit general, but I'm just trying to respect some of the disclosures we give and not give selective disclosure.</p>
          <p>In terms of moving forward in the competitive environment, I'd probably echo some of the earlier comments but build on those. I think undoubtedly it's a more competitive environment today. You have Telstra who clearly indicated their intention to downgrade their earnings in order to try and get some more traction in the mobile market. We've seen the repricing I talked about. We've seen the very aggressive advertising that I talked about.</p>
          <p>But I think it's also important to characterize the differences in where we're all starting from. We're starting from a position of having embraced caps much earlier and having built a set of products that quite willingly and aggressively give people the chances to forward traffic across from fixed and that's both in terms of broadband as well as in terms of voice.</p>
          <p>I think we showed at our recent repricing, which we called Project Sonic, a willingness to also get back out there and make sure that there is a clear difference in competitive offering between us and Telstra, and those of you living in Australia will have seen us advertise that quite assertively in the press.</p>
          <p>So I think the message is we are about profitably growing and expanding our scale position in mobile. That is a core objective of the company. And although, the market is undoubtedly going to be more competitive, we're still very focused on growing and expanding our scale position and that will be built on the strategy that I outlined earlier.</p>
          <p>Hopefully, Christian, those comments have been helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's great. I guess in terms of the backhaul, I guess, the context of the question is that Telstra's now up to around 90% to 95% gigabit Ethernet connectivity to their base stations and obviously we also saw the announcement from VHA about three weeks ago in terms of their $1.5 billion investment. So if you could provide some color going forward that would be much appreciated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we'll have a look at that. Telstra actually discloses a stat on that, <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, up to 90% to 95%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Somesh Agarwal, Macquarie, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Just wanted to gain some more clarity on your OpenNet revenues. I understand that there are three possible revenue streams from OpenNet; the first is the revenue from fibre rollout which you're already including, about $25 million per quarter. The second is OpenNet earnings in which you have 30% share and the third is revenue from lease and maintenance.</p>
          <p>So I just wanted to ask revenue from fibre rollout will cease to exist after 2012, am I correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me explain very clearly. As far as SingTel is concerned, we have a contract, as a key subcontractor from OpenNet to rollout the fibre network for them. And for that we received in Q2 $72 million of revenue. This revenue will stop after Q2 of 2012-2013 year because that's when the fibre rollout essentially gets completed and covers 95% of homes and businesses.</p>
          <p>So I think that is the easiest way for me to explain this fibre rollout revenue and the relationship that we have with OpenNet and the revenues that we have booked this quarter in the SingTel revenue line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But you will continue to get revenues from &#x2013; you'll continue to consolidate 30% of OpenNet earnings and continue to get revenue from lease and maintenance of passive infrastructure until you monetize the assets by April 2014. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me explain that to you carefully. OpenNet is only 30% owned by SingTel and we're not allowed to control the entity, so we don't consolidate anything with OpenNet.</p>
          <p>We only do equity accounting, so we equity account the EBITDA and the profits, our share of the EBITDA profits; 30% of whatever they report. So that is one important thing.</p>
          <p>The other thing related to OpenNet is basically we have another contract with them to maintain the fibre network and for them to lease our ducts in which the fibre runs. For that we get a revenue share of 75% of whatever they book as revenue, but this is because of the contract we have. It's nothing to do with our ownership of OpenNet. So that will be booked in SingTel's revenue under data and Internet because it is for us a wholesale revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And this lease and maintenance revenue will continue irrespective of the fact that you will monetize your assets or not by 2014?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Jeann. The revenue, the lease revenue will be booked by SingTel through AssetCo and when we sell down AssetCo obviously that revenue stream will be reflected in whatever divestment value that we'll be looking at.</p>
          <p>So post 2014, when AssetCo is divested to 25% that revenue stream will no longer be consolidated into SingTel, but it is part of the AssetCo value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Ashwin, CLSA Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Just a question for Paul on the Optus side of things. One of the reasons why we've seen profitability improve has been very good cost management and that, at current levels, it would seem that that isn't going to incrementally contribute much to profitability. Would you be able to talk about that a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ashwin, maybe just give us a little bit more background on your thinking there or your views on that, so a focus of delivering more on-net clearly has driven our margin expansion in fixed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess what you're asking is maybe whether there's much more scope for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's Murray here. I would tell you in relation to costs there's a number of initiatives we'll continue to pursue consistent with our existing strategies, driving more of our traffic in our fixed business on-net and exiting resale or legacy products will improve our cost structure, particularly around our traffic costs. We've undertaken a number of transformation programs, firstly upgrade of our IT systems to allow greater online capability and will continue to drive online take up for various functions around self service and acquiring of our products through the web portal.</p>
          <p>We are in the midst of a customer experience transformation program which is about primarily improving customer experience, but making our processes far more efficient, and we do believe there's more opportunity through process efficiency to drive a better cost structure.</p>
          <p>So we'll continue to pursue those particular initiatives to drive our costs to the optimal level to make sure that we retain a competitive cost structure in this marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fantastic, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, sir. We have a follow up question. Richard, UBS, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. One question I meant to ask earlier was just about in terms of a sort of a TV or a media bundle going forward within the Australian context. And I'm just trying to get an understanding in terms of where you are in terms of discussions with either Foxtel or Fetch. And I wonder whether you can talk about the attributes of whether you'd look at Fetch or whether you'd look at Foxtel as a bundle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't think we've really got a lot to say on that, Richard. I mean we have a Foxtel offering today that's in the marketplace. We know quite a lot about the TV industry because of our direct involvement and more recently retail involvement. Yeah, but I don't think we've got any additional news or information to add to that today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you likely to have any news in the short-term or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, we'll be considering guesting you on the media section of the call at this rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've got nothing to disclose on that today and obviously if we had, I think we'd take the disclosure duties very seriously and we'd make sure we would announce. But you know I think to reflect the seriousness in your questions, we are seeing video plays not only in Australia, but in other markets. Clearly there's a desire by our customers to have them.</p>
          <p>For us the question that we think needs to be answered is, is there a profit enhancing or an economic argument to be made for doing it, and is it something that really does drive your business? And to the extent that we answer those questions will drive our strategy. I think that depending on the different models you look at, there are some people have been able to make that successful, but there are other people who have not.</p>
          <p>So we're very, very focused on the company and always having sustainable profitability and sustainable scale. We would want to answer those questions before we make any final decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, are there any more questions on the queue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have one follow up question from Mr. Ashwin, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please put that through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. This is just a much bigger picture question and perhaps more directed at Sock Koong. When you look at options such as potentially increasing your stake in Bharti, maybe perhaps via the Vodafone sell down, or when you look at possible opportunities in Africa, how do you think about the relative economics? Because on the one hand, clearly you've stated that one of the desired goals is to increase your stake in existing associates. But the incremental dollar investment in the existing associates is always going to be at the lower rate of return than what you've already made. So how would you weigh that versus the potential opportunity in a growth market such as Africa?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me just talk about this Vodafone stake in Bharti. I mentioned this earlier. The shares are in Bharti Enterprises, a holding company that is two levels up. And I understand that in addition to the telecom business, it also holds Sunil's other businesses. So frankly, we would have very little interest in that. I thought I'd just clear the air on that.</p>
          <p>When we look at each investment, each investment actually is looked at as if it is a fresh investment. You know looking at it &#x2013; I'm sure you understand what I mean. The historic cost of investment is actually irrelevant. When we evaluate investments we look at what the current price is and what our assessment of potential returns are in making a whether go or no-go decision on the investment. So whether we look at topping up stakes at Bharti and at holdings holdco level, which includes both India or Africa, versus buying shares at Africa level, we would look at you know, what the reasons are going forward, and of course take into consideration the different levels of risks and what the appropriate risk premium should be as a result. And we hopefully will be able to come to a right decision. I think the advantage of being an existing investor is that you know how the company executes. When you have a set of projection, you know how to look at them knowing what their past track record with us has been like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understand, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Before we end the call, I'd just like to make a correction. Earlier we had a question about the accounting for withholding taxes. For accounting purpose, the withholding taxes on the dividends declared by the associates, they are actually accrued as and when the associate declare the dividend. Earlier we had talked about recognizing it during payments, but that's not correct, so it's upon declaration by the associates.</p>
          <p>So we'll stop the call here. And for callers who still may have questions, we have your names.</p>
          <p>We will contact you. A transcript of today's call will be posted on to our website by end of tomorrow. We thank you for your interest in our results. If you have further questions, please don't hesitate to contact the IR team. On behalf of everyone in SingTel and in Optus, thank you and goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference call. Thank you for your participation. Goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>