<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1237278" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2911</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Sin Yang Fong, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Chua Sock Koong, Group Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3">Sachin Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="4">Paul O'Sullivan</participant>
      <participant id="5">Allen Lew</participant>
      <participant id="6">Anand Ramachandran</participant>
      <participant id="7">Lim Chuan Poh</participant>
      <participant id="8">Raymond Tong</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jeann Low</participant>
      <participant id="10">Murray King</participant>
      <participant id="11">Luis Hilado</participant>
      <participant id="12">Navin Killa</participant>
      <participant id="13">Lee Hsien Yang</participant>
      <participant id="14">Colin McCallum</participant>
      <participant id="15">Sachin Mittal</participant>
      <participant id="16">Kelvin Goh</participant>
      <participant id="17">Laurent Horrut</participant>
      <participant id="18">Richard Eary</participant>
      <participant id="19">Michael Smith</participant>
      <participant id="20">Arthur Pineda</participant>
      <participant id="21">Mark McDonnell</participant>
      <participant id="22">Ramakrishna Maruvada</participant>
      <participant id="23">Khoo Chen Hsung</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to all investors and analysts, you are listening to SingTel's Earnings Conference Call for the Quarter and Financial Year Ended 31 March, 2009. My name is Yang Fong and let me introduce the members on the call. Ms. Chua Sock Koong, Group CEO; Ms. Jeann Low, Group CFO; Mr. Allen Lew, CEO Singapore; Mr. Lim Chuan Poh, CEO International; and Mr. Paul O'Sullivan, CEO, Optus. Also assisting them are representatives from the management team.</p>
          <p>Before we start rolling in the questions, I would like to invite Sock Koong to share some highlights from this set of results. Sock Koong, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Yang Fong. Thanks for joining us today. This morning we announced our results for the quarter and the full year ended 31 March 2009. And you will see from the numbers that we actually have very strong performances from the Singapore and Australian businesses, and that is despite the economic downturn that we saw in the second half of the year, as the Group's earnings were adversely impacted by lower contributions from certain associates and also adverse currency movement.</p>
          <p>What we did see for both the businesses in Singapore and Australia was actually very tight cost control, and as a result you see that underlying net profit was only lower by 1% and would have grown by 11% if not for the adverse currency movement.</p>
          <p>Looking at Singapore, revenues were up 13%. We gained profitable market share, and revenue was also boosted by the acquisition of Singapore Computer Systems. We completed the acquisition in December last year. Margin improvements helped lift EBITDA by 20% to $578 million and in Australia both revenue and EBITDA grew 9%. That reflects strong momentum that we have in the mobile business and we also had stable overall margins despite the much higher number of customers acquired and also higher related costs.</p>
          <p>The Group and its associates continued to register healthy subscriber growth. We now have 249 million mobile customers. Earnings from the regional mobile associates, however, declined by 22% and that is due to lower contribution from Telkomsel and AIS. The Group's results this quarter also included an exceptional impairment charge of 300 million on Warid and $30 million on PBTL in Bangladesh.</p>
          <p>Moving to dividends, the Board is recommending to the shareholders for approval a final ordinary dividend of $0.069 and together with the interim dividend of $0.056 a share that was paid in the interim, at the half year, the total ordinary dividend would amount to $0.125 per share and that is unchanged from last year. This would represent a payout ratio of 58%, which is within our dividend payout range guided of 45 to 60%. So including the proposed final dividend, the cumulative payout in the last 10 years would be $24 billion or 79% of our net profit after tax.</p>
          <p>Maybe I will just take a minute to take you through the outlook very quickly. For the three different parts of businesses, we have actually provided separate guidance and I should say that we are operating in the context where the slowdown continues and Singapore GDP forecast is a six to 9% contraction. Australia, the government had indicated a 1% decline in GDP and in the regional mobile businesses in the markets that we operate in, we are still seeing growth, although slower growth, and in the range of two to 5% GDP growth. Thailand is a two to 3% GDP contraction that has been forecasted.</p>
          <p>Singapore guidance is for revenue to grow at single-digit level from increased contribution from IT engineering as well as first-time revenue from fiber rollout under the National Broadband Network. EBITDA margins will decline to roughly 36 to 38% although EBITDA will be stable, reflecting a change in the business mix.</p>
          <p>Optus, we have guided both revenue and EBITDA to grow at low single-digit level. And for the associates, our two largest associates Bharti and Telkomsel, we expect their earnings in local currency terms to grow this year.</p>
          <p>So I think with that, maybe I will hand over to Yang Fong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you, Sock Koong. I would like to remind participants that this call will last for about an hour. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our operator will now assist you to put through your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator: Thank you, Yang Fong <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. First on line, we have Mr. Sachin Gupta from Nomura, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I have four questions; two for Paul, one for Allen, and one for Sock Koong. Paul, firstly, I guess one of the positive surprises in the last few quarters in Australia has been, apart from mobiles has been business in the wholesale segment, the revenue growth has been modest but the margin increase has been quite significant. Just want to understand what's driving this margin uplift?</p>
          <p>Secondly I guess, Paul, just your thoughts on the strategy for the next 12 months in mobile and in broadband, given the recent merger of Vodafone and Hutch and plus the fiber announcement, just wondering how you intend to position yourself over the coming 12 months please?</p>
          <p>And Allen, I guess for the Singapore business, the mobile net adds of 34,000 they just looked relatively weak, especially the slowdown in the prepaid segment. Just want to get your thoughts on that, is it more macro driven or is it more the impact of competition please?</p>
          <p>And lastly, Sock Koong, just on the guidance, look given the recent trends in the Australian business, I was just wondering why is the management looking for low-single digit revenue and earnings guidance for Australia. And I guess also your gearing is quite low, balance sheet is relatively strong, and there appear to be limited CapEx risks both in Australia and Singapore. Just wondering what's management's or the Board's thinking on capital management please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Sock Koong, if you like I will start off and take the first two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so Sachin just on your first question about Optus business and wholesale, you are quite correct. Over the last couple of years we have lifted margins quite considerably in that segment. If you go back about two to three years ago the margins were down in the high teens and we have lifted them successively. It is important to say that there are a couple of one-offs in both this quarter's number and in the equivalent quarter last year, which if you adjust for, they won an interconnect settlement which is in this year's numbers, and last year we actually depressed the quarter's numbers by putting in some write-offs associated with Broadband Connect, but if you adjust for those, you still get a significant improvement in margins. The underlying margin for this quarter would be 25.6% compared to 27% as we reported, so it is a significant lift.</p>
          <p>It's been driven really by two main trends. The first one was a decision we made three years ago to aggressively get out of legacy technology and move out product offerings over to the new IP-based technologies and that allows us to phase out platforms and to rationalize both management overhead and some of the technical costs associated with those platforms. At the same time, as we get some economic benefit by being able to offer new product sets off the new platforms, which are designed to be less bespoke and less customized.</p>
          <p>The second big trend that was associated with that was a refocus on areas where we have network. So we now profile customers and we only bid and we will only invest in bidding where we know we can carry a certain percentage of the traffic on our own network and it meets certain tests. And we've rewritten our sales rules and our pipeline management around that.</p>
          <p>The combination of the two has allowed us to significantly change the margin profile of the business. On top of that, sort of an unexpected fringe benefit was that as we focused on the IP based technologies, we found that we were often at the vanguard of introducing them to CIOs and we discovered that in many cases, some of those companies had been left on legacy technology because there wasn't an economic incentive for their former supplier to persuade them to make a migration or a switch. So, that's really what's underpinning the business.</p>
          <p>We continue to focus on transformation in the business area. There is further rationalization of product set going on as we move further into the period where more and more Australian corporates are moving to IP, and on top of that we are also looking to integrate the Uecomm infrastructure which we acquired four years ago into Optus business to replace some of Optus business' existing operations and we think that will also assist us. So we would look to be able to maintain the profitability we've had and maybe even improve it.</p>
          <p>The one risk of course that always is price pressure which does manifest itself in the corporate market and as you can see from the latest set of numbers, we are also seeing a slowdown in corporate Australia. More so than in previous quarters, we've seen a slowdown affecting us in the business revenue area, mainly driven by a slowdown in the decisions by corporations on ICT and managed services products, but also the underlying slowdown we've seen in voice because of its being retired, was accelerated this quarter by what we saw and some rationalization by corporates of staff, et cetera. So those are two factors, which will obviously be present in the year ahead.</p>
          <p>On your second question as to how we see ourselves preparing for the merger of Vodafone and Hutch, there is no doubt that we are going to see a much larger and more competitive scale player in Australia when those two companies get together. We recognize that and we are very alert to it. I think there are some things that we can nonetheless leverage on our own merits when that merger happens. First of all, we do have the advantage of having significantly more scale and a significantly more profitable business in terms of margin than either of those two players today. In order to be able to match our margins there would have to be a significant amount of rationalization and retooling of those players in order to be competitive. So we see ourselves obviously leveraging our strength and we will either see it play out in terms of our ability to play in the market or with them needing to spend a lot of time on their internal transformation.</p>
          <p>The second area where we think we have some significant lead is just in our scale and coverage. We've a much larger network footprint, certainly on 3G we are much more extensive, and we are currently extending that lead by moving from 96 to 97% population coverage. So, as the new player comes to market we see ourselves continuing to focus on driving new and innovative tariffs like we have over the last 12 months, which have fuelled our growth, expanding our physical footprint with coverage, and expanding our distribution to match.</p>
          <p>I will stop there and pass over to Singapore to answer the third of your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sachin in terms of question about the mobile net adds, I think as you look at it in context, over the whole year we added more than 400,000 customers. So I think there are different seasonalities and ups and downs, and also you will find that in Q4 the number of foreign workers in Singapore has declined. I think if you look overall at the mobile business, you will see that very clearly in post-paid we have 22,000 net adds for the quarter; if you look at our competitors they had significantly less. So clearly mobile post-paid, which is 85% of the mobile market, we clearly took the leadership there.</p>
          <p>I wouldn't look too much at the prepaid customer numbers because basically at the end of the day the different operators have different disconnection periods for non-tooling customers and you see different times our competitors having huge clear-outs of their existing base. I think the important thing at the end of the day is to look at mobile revenue market share and mobile growth, and you can see in SingTel's case we've grown our mobile revenue 9% and our two other competitors both had declines in mobile revenue. So it's a clearly a case of SingTel continuing to take market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on your question on capital management, I think if you look at the financial markets post Lehman's collapse in September, we were certainly glad that we had kept our financial position in such a strong condition so that as we did our refinancing, we actually received very good support. Our objective, as we have stated consistently, is we will make sure that we pay a dividend in line with the payout ratio that we have guided and we have talked about 45 to 60% of our profit after tax. This year we pay out 58% and what we strive to do is to try and maintain an optimum balance sheet but at the same time retain some financial flexibility so that we can continue to invest in growth opportunities as and when they arrive. I think trying to overstretch your balance sheet and financial position under current conditions where there is still probably still a fair amount of volatility is probably not the most prudent thing to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Sock Koong just a question on the Optus guidance, the low-single digits given the recent run rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think certainly &#x2013; I think the stimulation that the government had put in place had certainly kept consumer spending quite high, but you would have seen that the PM's recent comments that recession is almost inevitable and then moving the GDP forecast down to minus 1% tells you that we would expect some slowdown and the guidance that has been provided indicates our taking a more cautious view, but certainly I think that the management team is well geared up. If growth momentum continues, we will be there to pick up the necessary market share, but of course if things are to deteriorate significantly we would work on our cost structure to make sure that we remain viable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next on line we have Mr. Anand Ramachandran, Citigroup, Hong Kong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good morning, thank you for the call and congratulations on a very good set of numbers. I had three questions. First, if we just look at the Singapore guidance and I look at the quarterly run rate and the fact that you have SCS contributing EBITDA next year, I'm just trying to understand what are the drivers behind the flat EBITDA guidance, I mean are there any specific cost items that you are thinking about? I understand revenues, you have given a guidance, so that's fair. Just on the cost side is there is something specific which you expect to impact EBITDA, given that you are guiding for flat EBITDA?</p>
          <p>Second question, staying on Singapore, if I look at the CapEx number, even ex the satellite you are guiding for S$620 million. I just want to understand how this correlates with NBN; I mean what are you going to spend the money on if -- because NBN and the NetCo has a pretty aggressive rollout schedule. So if you can help us understand what this CapEx is going into given the NetCo rollout schedule being so aggressive here?</p>
          <p>And my third question is on Telkomsel, I mean on yesterday's call I think there was a lot debate but no real answer on why Telkomsel's SMS revenues declined so much in the first quarter. I was wondering if you had any color to provide on that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay I'm going to get Allen to take the first two questions on Singapore, both the guidance and CapEx, et cetera, and then Chuan Poh will take the Telkomsel question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the guidance on Singapore for a flat EBITDA, it's primarily related to where the MTI, Ministry of Trade and Industry is guiding in terms of the Singapore economy. It's still talking about minus 6 to 9%. So we are taking a little bit of that view into consideration. There is also some increased content cost in there. You know next year we take on the Champions League content on an exclusive basis here in Singapore, so that does factor into our EBITDA guidance.</p>
          <p>In terms of CapEx in Singapore, other than the satellite, we have increased our broadband base. We are also -- hence we have to increase our connectivity and investment in submarine cables. That accounts for a significant part of that. Our mobile customers have also increased quite a lot so we want to ensure that we maintain a high quality of service and also cater to the change in behavior as more and more of them use mobile data.</p>
          <p>And then finally our IT subsidiary, SCS; as you know, with it NCS -- with the acquisition of SCS, we now have a major government contract that requires us to put in some capital investment. So if you put those three together that accounts for why we are guiding CapEx at those levels.</p>
          <p>I will hand over to Chuan Poh to answer the Telkomsel question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Telkomsel is still in the process of readjusting some of the tariffs, both in the voice as well as SMS with some degree of caution because we just came off a very aggressive price war in that market and I think if you look at the results of all the other operators concerned, the major ones at least, everybody has fared pretty badly in terms of the fact that despite that growth still occurs in the subscriber area, the revenue hasn't yet in a sense caught up with it. So some of the adjustments in pricing has in fact resulted in a change in some of the usage patterns, and that could account for some of the reason why at this point in time the revenue relative to the usage hasn't yet quite come into relativity, but we are seeing the fact that the price war action has abated.</p>
          <p>Pricing are now slowly being adjusted back to some form of norm, and I think given the current set of results in the industry in Indonesia, we can expect that there will be more price adjustments upwards to ensure that financials will look good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next on line, we have Mr. Raymond Tong from Goldman Sachs, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, just three questions. Firstly, just in Singapore, you nearly lost 5% broadband market share in the past year. Can you just maybe provide some commentary on just the overall broadband market and what is driving these market share losses?</p>
          <p>Secondly, can you provide an update on the process and timeline for the transfer of the passive infrastructure assets into AssetCo, and do you still expect to get about $2 billion for that?</p>
          <p>And just really on Optus, the margins have improved substantially, can you maybe describe what's actually driving this please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Raymond, could you kindly repeat your last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just with Optus mobile margins and they have improved to about 31% in the fourth quarter. Can you may be what's actually driving this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we will take the Singapore questions here first before I pass it on to Paul. Allen, maybe you are the appropriate to take the first question and then maybe <mark type="inaudible" /> can help you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will answer the first question on broadband market share. The reason our market share dropped was because our competitor has been giving away free broadband, one meg speed, with everybody that picks up the enhanced set-top boxes called a Hub Station set-top box. I think at the end of the day, if you look at broadband revenue market share, our broadband revenue market share actually has increased by 0.8 percentage points to 59%. If you look at SingTel's Internet broadband revenue, we grew -- that was stable, but our competitors went backwards. So, overall, if you look at value we are certainly increasing where it counts.</p>
          <p>I will pass over to my CFO AssetCo -- answer your question on AssetCo and the timeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of AssetCo, what we have agreed with the IDA is that we have undertaken to transfer the relevant infrastructure to a business trust structure within the 24 months. Within that 24 months SingTel will remain as a 100% shareholder of the AssetCo, and we have about 60 months from April 2009 to divest our investment in AssetCo to less than 25%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you still -- just on that, are you still sort of sticking with your guidance, I think you mentioned about six months ago that getting around about $2 billion for those assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We never guided the -- the $2 billion I think -- I believe you are talking about the fixed income that we will receive over the 25 years. So we said that we have guided the market and we will receive about 50 to 60 million when it is stable over the 25-years period. This is not regarding the divestment of the AssetCo., it's the income, the revenue share that we have with OpenNet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online we have Mr. Luis Hilado from JPMorgan. <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have a question on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So, I'm going to ask Murray King, our CFO, to just talk briefly on the third question, which is talking about our EBITDA margin profile, and Murray of course is going to point out the importance of seasonality in looking at our numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Raymond, if I understand your question correctly, you are asking the question about our mobile margins increasing in quarter four from around 26% in quarter three to 31% in quarter two. As Paul indicated, there is a seasonality impact and particularly if you look at our revenue mix, there is a lot lower equipment revenue in quarter four coming off the seasonal peak in the Christmas trading period in quarter three. We've seen equipment revenue decline from about $268 million in quarter three to 202 million. So that as a consequence improved our overall margins and that's consistent with prior quarter four periods.</p>
          <p>At the same time, you've also seen us look to manage our cost base aggressively. And so apart from selling costs and traffic costs, which are a consequence of the revenue growth, you've seen our overall cost being maintained well under our revenue growth numbers, so those two factors are the primary reasons why you've seen sequentially quarter-on-quarter an improvement in our mobile margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I suppose just going forward, I mean what kind of margins do you expect over the next year or so, just given &#x2013; I mean are you still looking to be pretty aggressive in terms of acquiring those postpaid customers going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's important when we talk about a going forward period, we are very cautious and we stick strictly to guidance. So if you have a look at what we've released today, we've been quite clear in our view of guidance in Australia and I don't think we want to qualify that in any way. We're basically seeing revenue growing at single-digit level, EBITDA growing at single-digit level, and our free cash flow being stable, and I think you can sort of derive a view based on that.</p>
          <p>&lt;Q &#x2013; Raymond Tong: Sure. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online is Mr. Luis Hilado from JPMorgan, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Thanks for the call and congratulations on the results. I have three questions, two on Singapore business, and one on Telkomsel. For Singapore, I just wanted to ask if with the pressure on IDD revenues in this quarter are you going to adjust your strategy in any way or it's -- you have to just really weather the storm?</p>
          <p>Second question is in regards to the broadband business with the penetration at 83%, is the general view do you think that when the NBN is on stream, is it going to result in penetration so high? Is it going to keep competition away or is it going to result in pressure in terms of the retail prices of broadband today?</p>
          <p>And third question on Telkomsel is there's been a lot of emphasis during the Telkom call about</p>
          <p>subscriber market share, but what do you feel is the outlook for revenue market share for Telkomsel this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Allen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In terms of international calls and whether we will be adjusting rates, I think the reason why international tariff-only revenue declined in Q4 is primarily because of drop in volumes and that's a function of the economy. So, I think today we do not see any reason to adjust our rates we are right through the financial crisis because we think we have reached the optimum point in terms of where our pricing is and where the volumes are likely to be.</p>
          <p>In terms of what is going to happen with NBN with 83% penetration, I think we need to understand that NBN will roll out over the next three to four years and basically that product providing fiber to the home will be a product that people with higher speeds will migrate to. It's not an entry-level product. So, I think at the end of day I think increased penetration will come more from wireless broadband or from basically people coming in as first-time broadband users. So, I think the end result of NBN remains to be seen at this stage because we felt we know what is the wholesale price of the fiber and the wholesale price of the OpCo. It remains to be seen what is the retail price from the RSP. So I think it is too premature for me to contemplate whether there will be a price increase at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just follow-up on that. If I understand correctly that the capacity will be purely for the high speed, so you won't be offering anything on the NBN, which will be for low speed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think yes, this -- the NBN will offer a price for fiber plus electronics to light up the fiber. We expect that it will be bundled with some content, entertainment or application service. So I think it's going to be difficult to say at the end of the day what sort of speed people will use. It will vary depending on the application and the content.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On Telkomsel, I think the focus is not just on customer base addition, but also on revenue market share. What is happening right now is that although the subscriber base net adds is still very healthy because of the price action, it hasn't really caused us to reflect in the revenue growth, but it's the outlook that I think has been given is that you actually do grow at mid-single digit level. That I think is possible because of the fact that the price being adjusted not just at regional level, but also at segmented level will see an increase in the months ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online Mr. Navin Killa, Morgan Stanley, Hong Kong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for the conference call and congratulations on the results. I had two questions actually. One is on the NBN in Singapore I mean how should we look at the impact of this on SingTel let's say not only over the next 12 months but over the next three years in terms of your margins, CapEx, et cetera, et cetera, if you could at least directionally help us understand that that would be appreciated.</p>
          <p>Second, Telkomsel earnings, I'm not sure whether there are exceptionals but I noticed that from your numbers there was a sequential increase in Telkomsel's earnings whereas they had reported a decline and on top of that the rupiah actually depreciated. So just trying to understand whether there is an exceptional element because I understand you do actually take out the exceptionals so it should normally be adjusted for that.</p>
          <p>And the last question I had was with regards to Far EasTone, obviously given the announcement regarding China Mobile's interest there, does your 4-5% stake in that business stay or do you think this is a good exit option for you now that you potentially have a buyer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the question on NBN. I think the impact on SingTel over the next three years &#x2013; I think the important thing is that NBN has got two implications on SingTel. The first is on the wholesale side and then the other is on the retail side. Let me talk about the wholesale side first. Basically, SingTel has an agreement with OpenNet for them to use our ducts and OpenNet has contracted SingTel to lay the fiber and to maintain that fiber for us. So there will be a revenue stream that's associated with that and that's very much at the wholesale level.</p>
          <p>And on the retail level it is too early for me to talk right now because the OpCo part of NBN is still going through the completion process and as things become clearer in terms of when the fiber product will be launched then I can talk a little bit more about what is the implications of that on margins, what's the type of product and what's the type of CapEx associated with that. So I think at the retail level we will definitely be participating in NBN as an RSP. As I indicated in the answer to my last question, we will be bundling content, we will be bundling a lot of other applications and services that will use the high bandwidth of that fiber and at the right time we will reveal the details of that product and the CapEx implications of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the question on Telkomsel, it's really more an accounting issue, so I'm going to get Hsien Yang to answer that. Hsien Yang is our regional financial controller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Telkomsel is really a timing difference because there was some audit adjustments that were done which Telkomsel took into their quarter ending December results whereas from a SingTel perspective we are reporting it in this quarter so that's why you see that kind of timing difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, what was the &#x2013; there was a question on Far EasTone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The question was given that China Mobile Far EasTone deal, I mean do you see any strategic value in being of the three kind of so called strategic partners in that company or would you like to consider cashing out of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you recall the genesis of how we came about with this investment, it was really as a result of restructuring our fixed line investment in Taiwan through NCIC and we swapped that into the FET share. We are still evaluating our position there. We have a small stake but we do have a board seat and I think we are still keeping our options open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online, we have Mr. Colin McCallum from Credit Suisse, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for the call. Three questions from me, the first two regarding Singapore perhaps for Allen. First of all, would you consider building your own OpCo since StarHub has actually won that layer? Is it worthwhile for you to do so even though you wouldn't get the $250 million subsidy?</p>
          <p>Second question is you've alluded to content being quite important. Does that mean that you are going to be very aggressive about bidding for any content that becomes unlocked over the next year or two, thinking obviously about the EPL, et cetera, is that an important part of your strategy going forward?</p>
          <p>Third question is more for Sock Koong. The balance sheet is strong. Even Bharti is now giving you a dividend. Are you thinking more about acquisitions now perhaps in market consolidation and if you are looking outside of existing markets, is Africa something that is of interest or do you view that as being sort of too far away in terms of being able to manage effectively? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me answer the first two questions, firstly on building our own OpCo. I think right now the OpCo tender results have just been announced. The government is going through the completion process with StarHub, which will take all the way until August, September. So once that is completed and things are a bit clearer, we will then make a decision and an announcement to the public about whether we will use the NBN OpCo or we will build our own.</p>
          <p>Secondly, with regard to content, you know within SingTel our pay TV business is a very important part of our transformation to become a multimedia Company. But financial governance and our ability to acquire value accretive content is also very important. We put our content in three buckets &#x2013; must have, good to have, and some we can live without. So EPL certainly falls in the case of Singapore in the must have bracket. But at the end of the day we will look at it in a very financially responsible way. It's the best thing I can say right now. Because of the competitive nature I can't say very much more other than that at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Makes sense. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your questions on acquisition strategy I think we have always been disciplined in our investments and our focus has primarily been in Asia, which we have indicated earlier that we will be prepared to look at some adjacent markets including Middle East and Africa and we would take this opportunity to try and understand these markets better. Obviously, M&amp;A would always be opportunistic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online, Mr. Sachin Mittal, DBS, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you for the call. I have two questions on Singapore and one on Australia. I want to understand a bit on the tax rate in Singapore because normalized tax for the whole year for this year was close to 10%, so what is actually the factor that it is lower than 17%?</p>
          <p>Second thing which I observed is on the cost of sales. There is a significant reduction in cost of sales sequentially in this quarter. On the other hand, acquisition costs have gone up and cost of sale has come down, so what makes this cost of sales?</p>
          <p>Third question is on Australia that I mean when you gave guidance of single-digit growth in EBITDA, have you factored rationalization of tariffs in Australia? Yes. These are three questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think maybe Jeann can help to take the question on taxes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The tax rate is about -- the effective tax rate if you look at in on page 36 of our MD&amp; A for Singapore is actually 17.2%. You know, we have shown the adjustments there. The Singapore statutory tax rate is now 17%. We have booked some adjustments. Clearly, because of the &#x2013; on our deferred tax liability, because of the reduction in the tax rate that benefits lower deferred tax liability to be carried forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So going forward what is the tax rate we should be using?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The tax rate for Singapore is 17% and the tax rate for Australia is 30%, and I suppose you have seen some tax reduction in Indonesia as well as in the Philippines this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. So will not -- if your tax rate is less than 17%, will not that be considered as exceptional income, I mean For FY09, the gone by year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, If we take the tax adjustment, for different tax has been treated as exceptional, so if you look at the <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again if you look at page 36, we have said that of the 61 million tax savings, 49 million was recorded as an exceptional tax credit. And if you cross reference back to page three of the MD&amp;A, we have actually given you the items that we've adjusted out of net profits to get to underlying net profits, and we've adjusted out $49 million of exceptional tax credit because this relates to prior year deferred tax liabilities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very common.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, if I add 49 million tax credit to the tax of -- how much is that, 933 for the whole year, right? Currently, I'm talking about the Singapore level, I'm talking about the Singapore market now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Singapore market taxes. For the year &#x2013; 234, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, 2009. If I add the deferred tax credit of 49 to 112, right; 112 is the tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you take that offline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think why don't you give the detail working to Yang Fong, and I think maybe this question -- it's easier for us to take offline...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Sure. Sure. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> different items.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you have a question on cost of sales, do you mind repeating that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you have a question on cost of sales, you mind repeating that? Sachin, you had a question on cost of sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, like my question is we have seen a significant reduction in cost of sales sequentially in this quarter, so what makes up this cost of sales? If it was equipment sales, I have seen that acquisition costs have gone up, so why are they moving in different directions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The cost of sales has gone down primarily because of equipment sales that we had done into the region. That has dropped significantly because of the financial crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it is not the just mobile phones. You're talking about probably other equipments, is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mobile phones -- primarily mobile phones, mobile phones that we sell on an export basis to other countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online we have Mr. Kelvin Goh from CIMB, Malaysia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for the call. I have two questions. The first one is on Optus where you are pretty much guiding for the EBITDA margin to be unchanged year-on-year. But I'm trying to understand why it is so and when the effects of the iPhone subsidies will probably wash out in the current year.</p>
          <p>And the second question is for Allen, I'd just like to know what other content would you add to your must have list and if any of that is already currently owned by your competitor? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Paul here. I'm actually going to pick up as well on Sachin's last question, which was about a similar issue. And actually in a way it will help me also answer your first question. In giving guidance in Australia we are faced with quite a challenge. As you can see from our results, our business has been relatively unscathed by the economic crisis which has hit over the last 12 months. In fact, our performance has accelerated through that period particularly driven by the strength of our mobile performance.</p>
          <p>But the economic environment is worsening and in fact as late as 48 hours ago the federal government highlighted that we will see a contraction in the economy in the year ahead. There are in fact more pessimistic forecasts than the federal government's, which have been put out there by very credible commentators.</p>
          <p>So our guidance for the year ahead is heavily driven by the uncertainty in the economic environment and that's the primary influence on our guidance. We are not really trying to pick individual market trends or product lines. What we are trying to caution is that all the advice we are getting and all the information flying in Australia is that there will be a significant contraction in the economy and for that reason we think this is prudent guidance to give. If the growth is out there, if we see that actually some of those forecasts either don't impact the communications industry or indeed that they are too pessimistic overall, but if there is growth out there we will absolutely be there to chase it as we have been over the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>But internally, we are reflecting that approach in ruthlessly controlling and managing our fixed cost, but willingly embracing variable costs where they allow us to profitably gain customers and grow our share. And so that's really the driver of our guidance. I think it's important that we do clarify that that you don't think that we're trying to necessarily signal any change in direction or strategy. I will pass over there to allow your second question to be answered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay with regards to the content and what are the other must have content that we will be acquiring this year, I think firstly content is a key differentiator in this pay TV business and is a driver of customer take-up rates. So, we will always review our content line-up in line with the changing preferences and needs of our customers. It is not -- I probably can't share with you the details of what are the must have content we are going to acquire for two reasons. Other than EPL, I don't want to cause the price of other content to go up significantly because once SingTel says it's must have, the content providers will automatically raise their price. So we do have a list of content that we are going to bring up this year, but I will announce it when we do secure the contract. I hope you understand where I am coming from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online, we have Laurent from JPMorgan, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you I had three questions and the first one is one for the Group. I noted that the ROIC was down 2% mostly on a lower EBIT which was again driven by currency fluctuations and I was just wondering if in light of that you could remind us what your currency hedging arrangements currently are, and the break down also between Singapore and Optus on the ROIC. That was my first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is actually -- be my last. Question for Paul, since the government announcement, I was wondering if you've been in touch with the government since the April announcements? And just maybe if you could share some thoughts in terms of what you think -- what's your understanding of what they are actually trying to drive here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Jeann will take the question on the ROIC and hedging arrangement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the hedging arrangements we have -- if you refer to the MD&amp;A on appendix three, we talk about our hedging policy. We have a policy of hedging all known foreign currency exposures related to commitments or transactions. What we do not hedge would be the translation risk of our net investments unless it's specifically approved by the Board. So I think that the appendix three sets out the Group hedging policy.</p>
          <p>In terms of foreign currency debt we clearly try and match it to the cash flow of the Group's underlying operation. So, on the ROIC we would disclose the ROIC on an aggregate basis, so you have seen that in terms of the -- because of the lower EBIT.</p>
          <p>In terms of Australia and Singapore operations ROIC we have not disclosed that. You would be able to get some sense of it in terms of the year-on-year trends when you look at the statutory financial statements. But you know it is really -- there are some eliminations that we take care of, so it's not very meaningful. We would disclose it on an aggregate basis which we have done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I ask you what's the constant currency ROIC in that case? If you normalize for the currency fluctuations what would have been the like-for-like ROIC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you look at constant currency, clearly the currency has an impact. When you look at our earnings, our earnings in constant currency would have been &#x2013; has been affected by about eight to 10% on currency. So if you look &#x2013; if you adjust, if you assume it's constant currency, the ROIC would be closer to 18.5%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so stable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is consistent with the FX movement if you were to look at it on an underlying basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Laurent on your question on Australia &#x2013; It's Paul here &#x2013; yes, absolutely. And as you can imagine we are in regular contact with the government. It's such an important issue and of course we are very pleased that after several years of advocacy and of organizing the industry to provide a credible alternative to the federal government that has facilitated things like getting to the point where the government feels its options allow us to drive real reform in the industry.</p>
          <p>We see -- from our standings with government we see that they are pretty committed really to two important things. One is to creating a separation of the new broadband network from any of the retail carriers, and, secondly, to what you could describe as microeconomic reform across the telecoms industry.</p>
          <p>That's principally got three big areas of activity for them. The first one is taking standings with the industry on their short-term regulatory review. The second one is the $250 million that they are looking to put into regional backhaul in order to break the monopoly that the incumbent has on backhaul into regional towns and cities. And thirdly the work to establish an NBN and a new separated model.</p>
          <p>Our sense is that they are very committed to getting the outcomes that they've talked about and any carrier who wants to seek to negotiate or participate is going to have to work within the parameters of their goals of separation and microeconomic reform. Obviously, there is now going to be an interesting period ahead whilst they finalize their plans in those areas and whilst they talk with the carriers about what assets they might put in or what ways the carriers might participate, but certainly our standings indicate that they are fundamentally fixed on making sure that they drive reform in the sector.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Paul, would you be open conceptually about vending in some assets into this NBN vehicle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. We would definitely be open to putting in assets into the NBN vehicle. Obviously, that's a piece of work that has to be taken through with government over the next few months. There's a lot of devil in the detail. But we think the creation of a separated NBN network in which no retail carrier can have more than a 30% stake which has been set up to provide open and equal access to all carriers is a good thing. We took that view three years ago where instead of merely advocating an Optus based alternative to what Telstra was advocating, we advocated an industry structurally separated alternative. And we would be supportive of that. And if there is a way in which we can deploy our assets to assist that and still get a good return for our shareholders we would be willing to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And have your conversation with the government sort of advanced to a point where you've started to talk specifically about what assets might be vended in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>: We generally -- we break with the practice of one of our other competitors in generally not having our discussions with government in public for what used to be referred to by Margaret Thatcher as megaphone diplomacy. I think we'd prefer to keep them in private and do the consultation. I think you'd have to say that the track record of the last two to three years shows that our advocacy has generally been reasonably influential and led to some sensible and good outcomes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next on line we have Mr. Richard Eary, UBS, Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning everyone. A lot of the questions I had have been answered, but just one specific with regard to just the take-up of wireless broadband in Australia. Now that the numbers are of a reasonable size, I don't know whether Paul or Murray whether you can give us a feel of how much substitution, if any, is happening between fixed and mobile, i.e., are you actually seeing people churn off your fixed subscriptions to take up a wireless-only subscription or is it too soon in terms of the numbers to try and ascertain a trend yet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'm going to ask Murray to comment initially on that and then we also have Michael Smith who is our new Managing Director of Consumer here and Consumer is probably at the fore front of some of these trends, so I will let him provide a little bit of color on what we are seeing at the retail end. But, Murray, do you want to talk a bit about the numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Richard, in relation to the question as to how much of wireless broadband is supplemental over fixed versus how much is complementary, we don't have definitive numbers because it's very hard to get a breakout across the industry. But I think if you reference you've seen across the industry our fixed broadband penetration starts to slow, so I think that gives you a sense that there is some substitutional impact in relation to wireless broadband versus fixed broadband. But at this stage we would think that -- our view is the majority of the wireless broadband is predominantly complementary to fixed so that the households are looking to both have a fixed service, which obviously has the speed and data advantage as opposed -- and to -- but also having a wireless broadband service as well that is -- provides the mobility side for data services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Michael here. Hi Richard. I think the only thing I would add would be there is a strong consumer advertising for both variations of wireless broadband products, the postpaid and prepaid which further substantiates the supplemental nature of people traveling, holiday homes, and the like, and it's also been quite complementary for our strategy around focus on fixed net in relation to our fixed broadband. There's been quite a lot of interest in that product, but -- off-net areas but also on on-net as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to follow up, I mean just out of those numbers, I mean, how much -- I don't know whether you can comment or want to comment in terms of how much is residential, how much is business, and how of those subscribers are actually bundled in with existing broadband plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's a very competitive area, Richard, so we generally don't disclose that, naturally. We actually spent a lot of money as carriers trying to discover one another's numbers and segments. But I think, I mean, I would say it's fair -- what you are seeing in Australia is the take-up across the market place and certainly there is an equal appetite that we can see for users from all the different segments for this product but the shares that a carriers do differ by segment and clearly that reflects the natures of the offerings and the pricing. But I think beyond that we probably wouldn't want to comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks both, thanks Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next on line we have Mr. Arthur Pineda, RBS, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for the call. I have three questions all of which are on the local business. Firstly, if you can please give us a little bit more color in what's driving your gains in the domestic data and IT segments? Do you see room for this decline given the sharper contraction in the economy in 2009-2010 as well as the NGN becoming -- next generation broadband becoming available impacting data?</p>
          <p>Secondly, I'm curious with regard to your margin guidance for Singapore, what will push margin downwards for 2010? You've mentioned that the government is looking at a weaker economy, but you're also saying that revenues will be up around single -digit levels. Presumably the margin weakness will be a result of some specific cost item outside of just content which was mentioned a while ago.</p>
          <p>Third question I have is with regard to broadband. Could you please provide a little bit more color on how your broadband subs are distributed among the various price points and speeds and what percent of them are locked up in contracts? I'm just wondering what percent of your sub space would actually be interested in upgrading to high-speed broadband. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Allen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You have three questions, the first one what is driving data and IT growth? Data and IT growth is basically our Business Communications Group and if you talk about the product, the main product in there is international lease circuits, the local lease circuits, and then something called managed services, which is basically us looking after not just the carriage part of it, but looking after the devices for our customers. The one that's really growing very rapidly is managed services and it's growing by double digit percentages and in excess of 30%, and the other one is growing very quickly is international lease circuits, which is growing about 16%. And local lease circuits is still growing about 6%. So, I think basically despite the global financial crisis we are still seeing our corporate business growing very well. We see basically people moving more, still moving more circuits, putting more data onto these circuits and upgrading the speeds of these circuits.</p>
          <p>The second question in terms of our margin, our percentage EBITDA margin decline, that's primarily a mix. As we get more IT revenue, the IT revenue has lower margin than our telco revenue and that affects our EBITDA margin percentage and so that will decline as we've guided about 36 to 38%.</p>
          <p>The last question you had was regarding broadband and are we seeing people migrating to faster broadband speeds. In fact we are seeing quite a significant movement of our customers from the lower speeds, one to two meg speeds up to the higher speeds, about three and even six, and eight megs. Basically that's been driven by the fact that people now spend in Singapore a lot of time on the Internet. Our latest survey seem to indicate that people aged 18 to 44 spend at least an hour, an hour and a half a day and they are going onto sites, which are data heavy, they are going onto video streaming sites. And that requires them to have high speed to have a better experience. Did I answer your questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, if I can just follow up with the first question I had, are you gaining in terms of market share, is that what's driving your business, or you are seeing just an overall improvement across the board and on data and IT?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we are definitely gaining market share. We are also seeing some of our customers increasing to faster speed circuits, so it's a mixture of both. So, if they go to faster speeds, they pay us a little bit more for this circuit. So &#x2013; and some of them are also upgrading from the older technology to the newer technology, moving from the frame relay to the IT circuits as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next on line, we have Mr. Mark McDonnell, BBY, Sydney.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. I just have one fairly detailed small issue with Optus if I could ask Paul. It's to do with the billing integration, particularly in the business segment. I've been hearing anecdotally of protracted disputes involving different arms of Optus, the Alphawest business and the Optus services business where there isn't in fact an integrated billing system and that a number of customers receive bills in spreadsheets that are involving high levels of human intervention. I think it's mainly through your facility at Fortitude Valley. And I'm just wondering if you could comment on the extent to which these anecdotal reports point to systemic issues and the scope you see for operational improvements?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark. I suppose the fact that I'm not aware of the issues more widely is probably the best way I can answer the fact that I don't believe there is a systemic issue. There will be customers from time-to-time who we will have misunderstandings with. Even the best run organization will occasionally get things wrong. So I'm more than happy offline to follow up on the customers you mentioned and to give you and them a little bit more detail, but generally speaking, we've had very good growth around our data and IP offerings and the work of Alphawest in the area that you mentioned is generally to support the growth of our new products in Optus business and you can see that we managed to get 7% growth in this quarter. So I'm surprised to hear the comment, but I'm also very focused on giving a good customer experience. So I will work with Erica to get you a feedback and to make sure we resolve whatever issues there are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online we have Mr. Rama Maruvada from Macquarie, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everyone. Three questions from me. Firstly, Allen, if you could comment on -- a little bit more on the corporate market, in particular there seems to be some pressure on the business telephone line losses, but this doesn't correlate with basically the LLC and IPLC revenues, which continue to be quite strong. So what exactly is going on in the local corporate market here?</p>
          <p>Second one has to do with the NBN/OpCo CapEx. Is this a part of your CapEx guidance for this year, if not what is the range that we are probably looking at?</p>
          <p>The third one has to do with the Warid and PBTL impairments, what is the percentage of goodwill that's been impaired at the moment and what is the strategy here going forward in terms of future capital injections?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regards to your question on the corporate market, you know, and the possible declines of tying up with our data revenue, I think what we are seeing in the business market is primarily in terms of DEL line disconnections and that's primarily related to the economy and the fact that there are a lot of small businesses that are adversely affected and they are going out of business and that has affected our number of DEL lines and you can see the details of the DEL line reductions under national telephony.</p>
          <p>The second question with regards to NBN and how much we've catered for in terms of CapEx for the OpCo, as I mentioned earlier answering one of the questions, we have not decided what to do in terms of whether we will have our own OpCo or use the OpCo for NBN, that is a decision that we will make once everything is settled with the government. And I think right now I can't talk further details about what our capital plans for this year beyond what I've talked about earlier. I will hand over to Jeann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the Warid question, we do an annual impairment review if there are triggering events each quarter. I think you are aware that we made the investment in September '07 and we have obviously been affected by the risk in Pakistan and the increased uncertainty and of course that would then be reflected in increased funding cost for Pakistan risk. So the impairment is really an outcome of the higher discount rate that's been applied on the future cash flows of the investment that we have, so that has resulted in the 300 million impairment adjustment and you know on a going forward basis we will of course continue to review the investment as with any other investment that we would have, and apply the necessary -- the applicable factors, whether it is discount rate or whether it is operating margins and the business drivers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just quickly follow-up on the answers. Firstly, Allen with regards to the DEL line disconnections, you said it's limited to the SME market, so is there a little bit of divergence here in terms of SME market feeling the impact a bit more strongly than the larger MNC market, which presumably will be using the LLC and IPLC services? Is it a fair assessment to say in terms of how the impact has been felt in your business at the moment?</p>
          <p>The second thing with regard to OpCo CapEx, could you just confirm -- is there some amount of CapEx that's been baked into your guidance or is there something that is not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. To answer your first question, yes, in any recession it is normally this means they are more aversely affected and disproportionately compared to the MNC. So I think what you said just now is absolutely correct. The second is that we do not disclose the details of our CapEx, so I can't comment on whether we have an OpCo CapEx in our current CapEx plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next online with Mr. Khoo from Merrill Lynch, Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, thanks for the call. Just one question in order to get more clarity on the guidance for Singapore revenues. I just wanted to get a sense, if we were to exclude the SCS impact as well as potential NBN revenues, I mean where would we have a reasonable expectation of revenue growth for Singapore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our business right now is very much integrated with our telco, our media business, and our IT services business. So I'm sorry I cannot give you a detailed breakdown for each of the different categories. So I think we look at our Singapore business as an integrated company. So the best we can do is give you the number that we have, which is a single-digit revenue growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Allen, if I could just pose another follow-up question. As you look out into the year given what you are seeing right now, I mean what has surprised you so far in terms of resilience on the revenue side among all your different business lines and what are your expectations, or which revenue line would continue to have the biggest risk going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think we've given you the guidance, and it's difficult for me and I'm not going to comment on the individual revenue lines. I think in terms of what has surprised us in Q4, I think basically we have seen some declines in usage of mobile, we've seen some declines in usage of roaming as well, and we've seen some people taking more bundles from us. I think if you look at our result compared to our competitors the declines that we are seeing are significantly less than theirs. So I think in that sense it has surprised us a little on the upside.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the corporate market side, Allen...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I know our competitors talk a lot about the fact that SingTel has a large share of corporate market, our revenues would be adversely affected. I think other than a couple of companies coming to talk to us to renegotiate a few contracts, I think by and large we are seeing our corporate revenues being very robust and you can see that a large part -- our data revenue is still growing very strongly and that is a reflection that we are not adversely affected or the global financial crisis has not affected our corporate revenue significantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Allen, if I could just -- based on your experience, I mean seeing -- I mean a lot people pointed at corporate market as a major area of risk and they pointed at previous recession and seeing -- I mean what could be different, how would you advise people to say this time what is different from the previous downturns as you would see developments in the corporate market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the downturn has been there for six months. I don't think I will make a detailed prediction about how robust it's going to be for us. I think at the end of the day I think telecommunications is a very key part of any corporate market's functioning. So I think that has sort of made our corporate revenues a little bit more robust and resilient in this downturn. You know the telecommunications is -- mobile telecommunications, data communications is all very much a basic infrastructure and a basic way that corporates function. So unlike in the past perhaps where there was some discretionary expenses on telecoms, right now, we've cut down in travel expenses. That is no longer the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Allen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay in the interests of time we do have to stop the call here. For callers who still have questions, we do have your names, we will contact you soon. A transcript of this call will be posted onto our website by tomorrow. Should you have further questions don't hesitate to contact either the Sydney or Singapore team to clarify. On behalf of everyone at SingTel, thank you and good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>