<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1211897" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2911</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Chua Sock Koong, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for joining us today for SingTel's Results for the Quarter ended 31 December, 2008.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, the Singapore and Australian businesses recorded good growth despite a slowdown in the global economy. However the Group's earnings were adversely impacted by the weaker Australian dollar and regional currencies.</p>
          <p>The Singapore and Australian operations turned in strong performances during the quarter. In local currency terms, both businesses reported growth in revenues and EBITDA.</p>
          <p>However, due to the significant depreciation in the Australian dollar, Group revenues, of which approximately 60% is derived from Australia, fell 3%. Reflecting the weaker regional currencies and the decline in the earnings of certain associates, underlying net profit fell 10%.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of currency translation losses, underlying net profit would have been stable.</p>
          <p>In Singapore, revenue grew 21%, with the first time inclusion of Singapore Computer Systems' results.</p>
          <p>Coupled with the benefit of margin expansion in the telco business, EBITDA rose 14%.</p>
          <p>In Australia, Optus revenue grew 10% on the back of strong mobile customer acquisition. EBITDA rose 1% to A$510 million. The Group and its associates continue to register healthy subscriber growth and now have 232 million mobile customers.</p>
          <p>Earnings from the regional mobile associates declined by 27% due to lower contribution from Telkomsel and currency weaknesses.</p>
          <p>Overseas operations contributed 70% of proportionate EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Now let me run through highlights for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In Singapore, we completed the acquisition of Singapore Computer Systems in December '08.</p>
          <p>SingTel was ranked first in international IP VPN solutions in the Asia-Pac ex-Japan region. In Australia, Optus had another consecutive quarter of strong mobile customer growth with 213,000 customers added, including a significant number of iPhone activations.</p>
          <p>In the fixed line business, the strong focus on on-net business has improved the on-net revenue mix and margins. Our regional mobile associates registered another quarter of strong subscriber growth adding 15 million mobile customers.</p>
          <p>In January, Bharti launched its mobile services in Sri Lanka.</p>
          <p>Let me run through the third quarter results. Despite strong performances in Singapore and Australia, Group revenues declined 3% and operational EBITDA declined 7%, due to a 23% depreciation in the Australian dollars.</p>
          <p>AIS and Bharti continued to deliver impressive growth and strengthen their market leadership. Overall, earnings for the associates fell 26% due to lower contributions from Telkomsel and Globe, and the weaker regional currencies.</p>
          <p>In the quarter; AIS recorded an exceptional non-cash impairment charge on the goodwill of a subsidiary, of which the Group's share amounted to S$44 million. Group underlying net profit declined 10% year-on-year and grew 5% on the sequential quarter basis with improvements in associates' performance.</p>
          <p>For the nine months ended December 2008, the Group's revenue grew 3%, underlying net profit was down 8%.</p>
          <p>In January; the Singapore government announced a reduction in the corporate tax rate from 18% to 17% from 2010 year of assessment. This will reduce the Group's current and deferred tax charge for the nine months ended 31 December, 2008 by approximately $30 million, and the adjustment will be recorded in the next quarter ending March 2009.</p>
          <p>Here is a quick overview of how the Australian dollar and the regional currencies fared against the Singapore dollars during the quarter.</p>
          <p>The Australian dollar and the regional currencies have weakened against the Singapore dollars. In particular, the Australian dollar, the Indian rupee and the Indonesian rupiah declined 23%, 21%, and 14% respectively.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the trends in revenue and underlying net profit assuming exchange rates remain unchanged from a year ago.</p>
          <p>For the quarter ended December '08, Group revenues would have risen 14% and underlying net profit after tax would have increased 1%. For the nine months period, Group revenues would have grown 9% and underlying net profit stable.</p>
          <p>Now let me focus on our Singapore operations. Revenues grew 21% with IT now making up 24% of total Singapore revenues. Excluding SCS, revenue grew a healthy 7% due to continued growth in the Data and Internet and Mobile businesses.</p>
          <p>Expenses increased 5%, slower than revenue growth, and EBITDA grew 10%, the highest in recent years. This reflects continued strength in the underlying business and the effectiveness of our cost initiatives. With the inclusion of SCS, EBITDA margin was low at 37.2% reflecting the higher proportion of lower margin IT revenues.</p>
          <p>Telco margins improved by almost 2 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Data and Internet revenues was up 11% due to strong uptick in data services. Mobile revenue increased 8% as SingTel continued to register strong customer growth. The combined IT and Engineering revenues was $361 million. This includes contributions from SCS.</p>
          <p>Excluding SCS, IT revenues grew 9% due to the higher sales of systems and network integration projects in the domestic market. International telephone revenue grew 6% due to higher outgoing traffic.</p>
          <p>SingTel had another quarter of strong mobile growth adding 68,000 customers as we extended our lead in both the prepaid and postpaid segments. In addition, our wireless broadband service continued to see good take-up.</p>
          <p>We added 28,000 wireless broadband customers this quarter to reach 144,000 subscribers. Fixed broadband customers grew slightly by 1,000 this quarter due to a lower share of gross adds.</p>
          <p>International telephone revenue was up 6% including some one-off credits for inpayment revenue reflecting the economic slowdown though the outgoing minutes declined compared to the September quarter.</p>
          <p>National telephone revenue declined 5% reflecting fix to mobile substitution. As at end December, there were 95,000 customers on the mio plan. We also added 13,000 mio TV subscribers in the quarter to reach 59,000 subscribers.</p>
          <p>In November '08, we launched our innovative mio Home bundle with fixed line, broadband and mio TV for residential customers.</p>
          <p>SingTel is committed to managing our cost and closely aligning it with revenue growth. In the past year, we have invested to increase our market share, resulting in higher selling and admin expenses and cost of sales. This was most evident in the quarters, when SingTel was preparing for mobile number portability and iPhone launch.</p>
          <p>In the light of economic slowdown, we have taken additional steps to manage our cost structure. This includes tightening discretionary expenditure and implementing a head count freeze.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, total operating expenses rose 5% below the revenue growth rate. Selling and admin expenses rose 10% due to higher mio TV content cost and higher utility expenses. Traffic expenses rose 6% in line with higher international call volumes and corporate data revenue.</p>
          <p>Staff cost increased 7% due to head count increase in growth areas, but it has stabilized from the preceding quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving forward, we are focused on cost transformation initiatives to improve our cost base including automating systems and processes and increasing productivity.</p>
          <p>Now let me focus on our Australian operations.</p>
          <p>Optus revenue grew by 10%, driven by accelerated top line performance in mobile. Overall, mobile revenues grew by 17% and service revenue grew 12%. Customer net adds were spurred by the strong take-up of wireless broadband, iPhone, and high value unlimited plans such as the 'yes' Timeless plans.</p>
          <p>In Business and Wholesale Fixed, Optus grew its on-net traffic, particularly in Data and IP as well as ICT and Managed Services.</p>
          <p>In Consumer and SMB, we continue to focus on yield and on-net growth, while managing the exit from resale.</p>
          <p>Mobile revenue grew 17% with 12% growth in service revenue. This was driven by strong customer acquisition, in particular wireless broadband and iPhone, as well as, unlimited plans targeted at high value customer segments.</p>
          <p>213,000 mobile customers were added this quarter, including 104,000 in postpaid. At the end of December, Optus had 388,000 wireless broadband customers with 102,000 net additions across its post and prepaid services during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Mobile EBITDA margin was 26%, lower by 6 percentage points from last year, due to higher acquisition and retention costs supporting customer growth.</p>
          <p>Excluding the A$44 million incremental impact of the iPhone 3G initiative and associated equipment revenue mix, underlying Mobile EBITDA margin would have been 31% and EBITDA would have increased by 7%.</p>
          <p>Optus Business and Wholesale Fixed revenue grew 9% underpinned by Optus' strategy to drive traffic on-net, leverage IP to grow share, and expand ICT and Managed Services' business.</p>
          <p>In Optus business, Data and IP revenues grew 9%, driven by customer growth. ICT and Managed Services' revenues grew 32% with seasonally higher project revenues.</p>
          <p>Fixed voice declined 11% with lower telephony volumes and price erosion.</p>
          <p>Wholesale revenues grew a solid 10%, driven by domestic on-net voice traffic and strong demand for Internet bandwidth and access. Overall, EBITDA grew 21% with margin improvement of 2 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Consumer Fixed on-net revenues increased by 14%, partly mitigating the decline in off-net revenues. In line with the strategy to maximize on-net yield, Optus' focus has been to migrate customers on-net and to manage the exit from unprofitable resale services.</p>
          <p>With its transition to an entirely on-net business close to completion, customers within the on-net footprint have largely been migrated. Optus' on-net broadband subscribers increased 25% to 815,000, representing 87% of the total broadband customer base.</p>
          <p>Wireless broadband also complements our fixed line on-net strategy. At the end of December, Optus had 938,000 on-net telephony subscribers, of which 414,000 are ULL customers, up 14,000 subscribers from a quarter ago.</p>
          <p>Consumer and SMB Fixed delivered a margin expansion of 1 percentage point to 13% this quarter.</p>
          <p>We watch our cost structure in Australia closely with resources being allocated to key growth areas.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, operating expenses grew 15%. Selling cost increased 22% with strong customer acquisition particularly for iPhone 3G, wireless broadband and unlimited plans.</p>
          <p>Excluding selling expenses, other costs grew 5%, managed below revenue growth rate. Primarily, traffic expenses increased 7%, due to higher traffic volumes and further affected by a weaker Australian dollar.</p>
          <p>Staff cost growth moderated to 2%, reflecting the head count freeze in place.</p>
          <p>Let us move on to the regional associates. Now, let me give you a quick overview of each of our six regional mobile associates.</p>
          <p>Bharti is the number one cellular operator in India with 86 million customers. Telkomsel is the leading wireless operator in Indonesia; subscribers grew 36% to 65 million.</p>
          <p>Globe is the second largest mobile player in the Philippines with 25 million customers.</p>
          <p>AIS leads the Thai market with 27 million customers.</p>
          <p>PBTL is a CDMA operator in Bangladesh, a market with a large population and under-penetrated in telecom services.</p>
          <p>Warid is a key challenger in Pakistan with 17 million subscribers. Together with our partners in Warid, we are committed to the investment and have recently made a cash injection to help fund its network rollout.</p>
          <p>Contribution from the regional mobile associates fell 27%. This set of results were also affected by the decline in profits from Telkomsel and fair value losses incurred by Telkomsel and Bharti on their foreign currency denominated liabilities.</p>
          <p>Bharti continue its strong momentum. Operating profit grew 41% as it posted record net adds of 8.2 million, and further improved its market share in India. Bharti recognized fair value losses on its U.S. dollar and yen denominated borrowings as the Indian rupee weakened.</p>
          <p>Pre-tax contribution rose 29% in local currency and 7% in Singapore dollar terms. Telkomsel's operating earnings fell 32% due to price pressures and higher network related expenses.</p>
          <p>During the year, Telkomsel's market share declined by 6 percentage points to 46%, but has stabilized since the last quarter as competitive intensity eases. Including fair value losses from foreign currency denominated vendor payables, pre-tax earnings fell 42%.</p>
          <p>Telkomsel recently announced senior management changes, including the appointment of a new CEO. Globe's operating results fell 17% year-on-year due to the weaker economy and consumer sentiments, coupled with higher network costs from its broadband expansion. Pre-tax earnings dropped 22% on lower fair value gains versus last year.</p>
          <p>AIS reported a 17% increase in pre-tax profits on strong revenue growth from prepaid, data and international calls.</p>
          <p>Warid posted a $29 million loss due to higher network costs and fair value losses on its U.S. dollars liabilities.</p>
          <p>The Group continues to generate significant free cash flows across its businesses. Free cash flow from the Singapore operations for the nine months period was lower due to higher capital expenditure.</p>
          <p>Optus' free cash flow in A dollar terms grew 7%, but declined in Sing dollar terms. Likewise, dividends from the associates grew 5% in constant currency terms, but declined in Singapore dollar terms, due to the weaker regional currencies.</p>
          <p>In November, the Group successfully obtained bank facilities totaling S$1.1 billion, confirming the financial strength of the SingTel Group. The Group's net debt was 6.6 billion as at end December.</p>
          <p>Leverage ratios remained comfortably within our targets. The average maturity of our borrowings is 4.7 years. We have a strong balance sheet which provides the Group significant financial flexibility. We affirm the Group's guidance for financial year '08-'09. Notwithstanding the challenging economic conditions, the Group delivered one of its best quarterly performance in Singapore and Australia this quarter.</p>
          <p>However the global economic slowdown has started to impact the Group. With the current uncertain economic outlook, the Group would be vigilant and disciplined in its business decisions and leverage on its vast experience to improve business performance.</p>
          <p>The Group has a strong financial position and will further strengthen its market position by delivering customer focused products and driving greater efficiencies in its cost structure.</p>
          <p>That concludes my presentation. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>