<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1537365" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2013 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2911</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for joining us today for SingTel's Results for the Quarter Ended 31 December, 2012. The group continues to invest in transformational initiatives to drive long-term growth, while operations remain stable across Singapore, Optus and the associates.</p>
          <p>Net profit declined 8%, due to higher depreciation on network investments, exceptional charges and adverse foreign currency impact. Excluding exceptional and one-off items, underlying net profit fell 2%.</p>
          <p>In Singapore, revenue and EBITDA increased 1% on contributions from new digital services and continued strength in mobile and ICT operations respectively. In Australia, despite a decline in revenue, cost efficiencies drove a 3% growth in Optus EBITDA.</p>
          <p>The regional mobile associates continued to deliver strong customer growth. Key regional associates Telkomsel and AIS recorded strong performances, mitigating lower earnings from Airtel and weaker regional currencies. In constant currency, earnings from the regional mobile associates would have grown 11%.</p>
          <p>Group revenue fell 5%, while EBITDA remained steady as margins increased with strong cost management. Depreciation and amortization rose 5%, reflecting continued mobile network investments. The group recorded exceptional charges, including ex-gratia payment for Optus for restructuring and Globe's accelerated depreciation. Excluding exceptionals, underlying net profit fell 2%. For the nine months to December, revenue and underlying net profit fell 2%, affected by adverse currency movements.</p>
          <p>Now let me share some highlights of the business units during the quarter. In Group Consumer, we made substantial progress in our 4G or LTE rollout. Optus achieved coverage in major capital cities in Australia, while Singapore will receive island-wide coverage by end of March. In December, the listing of Bharti-Infratel raised more than $750 million, making it India's largest IPO in the last two years. We divested our entire Sydney Warid for $150 million.</p>
          <p>In November, SingTel hosted i.luminate, Singapore's largest ICT forum, which was attended by a global audience and industry experts. We unveiled 200 innovative ICT solutions targeted at different customer spend. We boosted mio TV content's suite with the introduction of new genres of TV entertainment; including kids, music and comedy with Viacom International Media Networks. The addition of Nickelodeon and Nick Junior channels in particular, will enhance mio TV appeal to many young families.</p>
          <p>Singapore operations performed well. Revenue rose 1% due to contribution from digital, mobile, and ICT services. Excluding revenue from mass fiber roll-out project, Singapore revenue would have grown 3%. Mobile revenue grew 3% as strong postpaid customer growth offsets lower roaming revenue. Data and Internet revenue was stable as growth in managed services was offset by planned price adjustments on local leased lines. NCS revenue grew 6% on higher revenue from delivery of the MOE project and other contracts. Sale of equipment rose 5% on strong demand for new smartphones. With the inclusion of Amobee, digital business grew to $21 million from $2 million a year ago.</p>
          <p>EBITDA rose 1% on strong cost management. Excluding digital business, EBITDA would have increased by 3%. Total operating expenses rose slightly by 1%, and would have declined by 2% if excluding digital business costs. Selling and admin expenses increased 6% due to higher customer connection costs in fiber broadband, increased maintenance and service cost and inclusion of digital business expenses. Staff costs were up 10% due to annual salary increments, write-back of accruals last year, and inclusion of staff costs from acquisitions. Cost of sales declined 2% with lower fiber roll-out revenue.</p>
          <p>SMS roll-out reached 95% of premises in Singapore. Traffic expenses fell 12% largely due to lower roaming of payments.</p>
          <p>The group momentum of our mobile business continue. We added 63,000 mobile customers, including 50,000 postpaid customers, reflecting demand for new smartphones. In the Prepaid segment, customers grew 13,000 and continued demand for data services. Since our introduction of tiered data plans in July, 17% of our customers are now on this plan with 9% of them exceeding data allowances.</p>
          <p>We're focused on driving growth in mobile data services through sustainable investments in our infrastructure, attractive tiered data plans, and delivering relevant content to customers. Postpaid ARPU declined due to lower roaming revenue and increased mix of data-only SIMs. Acquisition cost per postpaid subscriber declined 12% to $322 due to changes in smartphone mix.</p>
          <p>Data and Internet revenue was stable, with growth in managed service offset by the impact of price competition from NBN. Internet-related revenue rose 5% driven by increased adoption of fiber-based services, as well as higher tiered plans.</p>
          <p>NCS revenue grew 6% on various contracts and delivery of the MOE contract, a program of managed desktops, network and ICT support, which was fully deployed across all schools in the preceding quarter. NCS order book remained strong at $2 billion as at end of December with key wins from both government and commercial customers.</p>
          <p>With our strategy to differentiate through bundling and migrating customers onto fiber, home fixed line services revenue increased 6% to $118 million and household ARPU rose 10% to $50 per month. 338,000 or approximately 29% of Singapore households are on our bundled plans.</p>
          <p>mio TV recorded revenue of $33 million as we continue to enhance and expand our content suite. mio TV customers grew to 398,000 in December, and as of now crossed the 400,000 milestone. The mio TV mobile application, mio TV Go is Singapore's first pay-TV mobile application that allows customers to assess the TV program guide, record programs and control set-top boxes directly with more than 37,000 downloads. We had strong growth of the 32,000 fiber customers and led the market with approximately 60% share.</p>
          <p>Now let me move on to our Australian operations. Optus is restructuring its business to drive profitable growth and position itself to capitalize on future detailed revenue growth. Optus is undertaking a transformation program by enhancing network performance to improve customer experience, reshaping its workforce, and distribution capability, and reducing device subsidies.</p>
          <p>Cost efficiencies have led to improved margin and 3% growth in EBITDA, despite a 6% decline in revenue. In Mobile, EBITDA increased 4% on lower selling and admin costs. In Business and Wholesale fixed, EBITDA fell on the back of declines in voice and Data and IP services, partially compensated by growth in lower margin satellite revenue. In Consumer and SNB fixed, reduced termination rates helped lift EBITDA by 5%.</p>
          <p>Optus Mobile revenue declined 7% mainly impacted by mobile termination rate decline and lower equipment shipments. However, lower revenues did not impact EBITDA as the mobile termination rate decline reduced traffic costs and equipment sales margins are not significant. EBITDA increased 4% on lower selling costs as the result of reduced subsidies and lower advertising expenses. Postpaid customers increased by 58,000. However, postpaid ARPU declined 12%. Excluding the impact of mobile termination rates and device repayment plans, ARPU decreased 7% due to lower roaming and higher churn. Non-SMS data accounted for 26% of service revenue, up from 21% a year ago.</p>
          <p>Business and Wholesale Fixed revenue declined 3%, with growth in satellite partially offsetting declines in business, voice, and data and IP revenues. EBITDA declined 2%, while margin was stable.</p>
          <p>Consumer and SMB Fixed revenue declined 4% on lower broadband ARPU from earlier discounted bundle plans. Price revisions were implemented in November 2012. EBITDA increased 5% and margin improved to 19%. Capital expenditure during the quarter rose 11% to A$273 million. Investment in mobile accounted for 64% of CapEx, reflecting Optus' commitment to enhance coverage, quality, and performance of the Optus network.</p>
          <p>We've largely completed the spectrum migration program, delivering improved 3G indoor coverage. We continue to expand our 4G network, with coverage achieved in major capital cities. Through aggressive cost management, operating expenses fell 8% for the quarter. Selling and admin costs declined 8%, while staff cost decreased 4%.</p>
          <p>Now let me move on to the associates. We now have 473 million customers across 26 countries. The associates continue to register robust customer growth. In particular, Airtel Africa customers rose 21%, and customers for Telkomsel in Indonesia increased 17% year-on-year. Contributions from the regional mobile associates rose 1%, as strong operating performances from Telkomsel and AIS offset Airtel's weaker results. Earnings growth would have been up 11%, if not for the depreciations of the Indian rupee and the Indonesian rupiah.</p>
          <p>Telkomsel's revenue rose 16%, with strong growth across voice, SMS and data. With lower financing expenses, pre-tax profit rose strong 25% in Indonesian rupiah terms and 11% in Singapore dollar terms. AIS pre-tax contribution rose 24% in Singapore dollar terms on strong demand for mobile data services. AIS also recorded lower depreciation, amortization and finance costs on reduced CapEx.</p>
          <p>In the next three years, AIS expects CapEx to increase with a 3G roll-out. Bharti Airtel's results fell 46% impacted by higher depreciation and amortization, financing costs, as well as fair value losses. For South Asia, revenue rose 8% on strong voice traffic growth. However, EBITDA was stable due to higher costs from an expanded network and investments in 3G and LTE. Airtel Africa registered 6% EBITDA growth on the back of robust growth in mobile voice traffic.</p>
          <p>Globe service revenues increased 7% on continued mobile growth momentum. However, EBITDA declined 3% due to higher marketing and subsidy costs and pre-tax contributions declined 17% in Singapore dollar terms.</p>
          <p>Now let me move on to the financial position. The group continues to generate strong free cash flows. For the nine months ended December, group free cash flow rose 1% to $2.5 billion. Cash flow from Singapore rose 28% due to improved working capital and lower tax payments. Cash flows for Optus declined 30% in A dollar terms, reflecting higher CapEx and higher working capital due to handset receivables. Associates dividends rose 15%, mainly due to higher dividends from Telkomsel and AIS.</p>
          <p>Group net debt was $7.6 billion as at end December. The average maturity of our borrowings is seven years. Our credit ratings remained one of the strongest amongst telco's.</p>
          <p>That concludes my presentation. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>