<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1409294" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7788</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Executive Officer">Peter Alexander Sands</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Director &amp; Group Finance Director">Richard Henry Meddings</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Royal Bank of Scotland Plc (Broker)">Ian A. Smillie</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Steven A. Hayne</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Canaccord Genuity Ltd.">Cormac P. Leech</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="McBurney &amp; Partners">Ian Arthur Gordon</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Michael F. Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Tom A. Rayner</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Robert B. Law</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Alex M. Potter</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Rohith Chandra-Rajan</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Chris R. Manners</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Peter H. Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="F&amp;C Investments">George Dallas</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and good afternoon to those of you in Hong Kong and India. Welcome to Standard Chartered's 2011 Half-Year Results Presentation. In a moment, Richard will talk through the numbers and I'll follow with comments on our strategy in some of our markets. We will then take questions in each of our locations separately. This time, John and Jaspal have joined Ben and Julian in Hong Kong, and Neeraj and Anurag are in charge in India.</p>
          <p>So Richard, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Peter. Good afternoon, Hong Kong and Mumbai, and good morning to everybody in London. Our track record of consistent delivery has continued with another strong set of results, diverse income growth across multiple geographies and products as activity levels increase. Cost control has been excellent, and we have invested selectively to underpin future growth. Overall, asset quality remains very good. The balance sheet is robust, diversified with low leverage and conservatively positioned. We remain strongly liquid and very well capitalized.</p>
          <p>Let me do our several key highlights. The group has delivered double-digit income growth and double-digit profit growth, both before and after loan impairment. This is the ninth consecutive record first-half year profit for the group. Double-digit income growth up 11% over the first half of 2010, reflecting the high levels of activity across our two businesses. Costs up only 8% against the first half and actually flat on the second half, as we managed both the pace of hiring and BAU cost total. Jaws are 3% positive on a reported basis. If we include the impact of the UK bank levy estimated at $95 million for the first half, which to be clear, has not been included in these numbers, jaws would still have been slightly positive. Pre-impairment profit up an excellent 14% year-on-year and up 18% on the second half; profit growth of over $0.5 billion, up strongly at 17% over the first half and up 21% over the second half of 2010; tangible net asset value per share is up 30% year-on-year and up 6% since the year-end; continued capital strength with core tier 1 at 11.9%.</p>
          <p>We purposefully moved above the fray last November with our rights issue. We have managed risk-weighted assets well, growing by 7% since the year-end. Return on equity of 13% has absorbed the impact of the rights issue and we continue to attract deposits with a strong advances-to-deposit ratio of 78.1%. The group remains a substantial net lender to the interbank market, and our liquid asset ratio remains strong at 26.5%. This is an excellent all-around performance.</p>
          <p>Let me take you through the numbers. At a group level, income has grown 11% on the first half of last year. Net interest income is up 19%, reflecting very strong customer loan and customer deposit growth, up 22% and 19%, respectively, and up 9% and 8% since year-end. Liability margins are on recovery, albeit, we are continuing to see some pressure on asset margins. Non-interest income has increased only 1% year-on-year, within this, Consumer Banking non-interest income was up 17%, driven by a strong performance in Wealth Management.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking was down 4%, as the increase in Transaction Banking and Financial Markets fees was insufficient to offset a decline in Corporate Finance fees. The Consumer Banking business has delivered strong growth in the first half of the year, with income up 15% over the comparable period. Wholesale Banking was driven by good client income growth of 9% over the first half of 2010 and 12% on the second half. I will go into more detail about this later.</p>
          <p>Expenses are up 8% year-on-year and flat on the second half, reflecting four factors: strong BAU cost control, continued investment in both businesses, some impacts of inflationary pressures across a number of our markets, and the impact of the appreciating Asian currencies. Loan impairment was down 6% on the first half and down 8% on the second half. Other impairments is higher at $72 million. Operating profit of $3.636 billion is up 17% on the first half and up 21% on the second half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Performance metrics; on this slide we are showing key performance metrics both on a reported basis, which excludes the UK bank levy, and also on a basis including the levy. Excluding the impact of the levy, normalized EPS has risen 4% and normalized ROE was 13%, partly reflecting the higher levels of capital the group is now carrying to meet the emerging regulatory requirements. We expect the full-year impact of the rights issue on ROE to be in the region of 150 basis points.</p>
          <p>The board has declared an interim dividend of $0.2475 per share, up 10% year-on-year. The group's effective tax rate in the first half of the year was 28.4%, and for the full year we expect it to travel up to some 29%. Following a change in UK tax laws in relation to overseas large profits, we currently expect that the group's effective tax rate will be between 27% and 29% from 2012 onwards.</p>
          <p>The balance sheet; the balance sheet is in excellent shape and continues to be highly liquid, conservatively positioned and primarily deposit-funded. The funding base is diverse and is continuing to grow in both businesses despite increasing competition. Current accounts and savings accounts, or CASA, grew by 8%, and time deposits grew 11% since the year-end. CASA comprises 51% of total deposits. We are continuing to attract deposits across the group. Total deposits are up 10% since the year end. Our focus on liabilities and disciplined deployment of the balance sheet has again resulted in a strong A/D ratio, which at the half-year stood at 78.1%.The liquid asset ratio is at 26.5%. We have some $150 billion of liquid assets. This is purposefully a very strong position.</p>
          <p>Turning to assets, our loan book continues to be well diversified by country and by sector, with no material concentrations. Our balance sheet remains, as before, a source of differentiation and strength for the group. We have low loan-to-value ratios on our mortgage book with an average of 49%, short maturity profile on our wholesale loan book with some 67% of the book under one year. Our ABS carrying value has continued to fall, now to some $2.16 billion, 0.4% of total group assets. We have low exposure to commercial real estate to leverage loans into Level 3 assets. We have no sovereign exposure to Portugal, Italy, Ireland, Greece and Spain, and our direct sovereign exposure to the 30 European economic area countries is absolutely immaterial. Our total exposure to these most troubled countries in aggregate is less than 0.5% of our total assets. The balance sheet remains robust and well diversified.</p>
          <p>Capital; the group continues to maintain a strong capital position. The core Tier 1 ratio has improved since the year end, to stand at 11.9%, while still supporting an increase in the six-month period in risk-weighted assets of 7%. In the first half of the year, we generated $2.5 billion of profit attributable to ordinary shareholders and we also benefited from the impacts of foreign exchange. We have limited levels of refinancing obligations over the next few years, some $5 billion through to the end of 2013, and we have pre-funded all our 2011 maturities. Risk-weighted asset growth has been well controlled, having accommodated good nominal loan growth and a formulaic increase in operational risk. Core tier 1 at 11.9% is almost double the level at which we were traveling three years ago. Tier 1 is at 13.9% and total capital is at 17.9%. We are very well capitalized, especially in the light of our diversified asset profile.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking; the repositioning of the Consumer Banking business continues to progress well. Consumer Banking has very good momentum and has grown income by 15% year-on-year and 5% over the second half. The business delivered record half-year operating profits of over $1 billion. A feature of the first half results for Consumer Banking has been a continuing increase in liability margins. As a liquid and primarily CASA-funded business, Consumer Banking is very well positioned to continue to benefit from this trend. Expenses have increased by 7%, resulting in positive jaws that round to 7%. Costs are down 5% on the second half of 2010. BAU costs have been well controlled, up by a low-single digit percentage year-on-year. Headcount is down by over 1,000 since December 2010, as we've proactively managed hiring and we continue to rotate staff from the back to the front line. Despite the net decrease in head count in the first six months of the year, we have continued to invest to underpin future income momentum. Over the last 12 months, we have added 900 Consumer Banking sales staff, of whom 480 are relationship managers.</p>
          <p>We have also continued to invest in optimizing our branch network, adding 18 in the first half. We've invested further in ATMs and better customer data systems, as well as in higher brand and marketing spend. When thinking about the cost base into the second half, you should bear in mind that there was a benefit of $86 million in the first half that arose from recoveries on certain structured note provisions previously made, offset by some $30 million of other equivalent one-off items not expected to repeat in the second half. We're also in the second half accelerating investments, subject to the rate of continuing income momentum.</p>
          <p>In terms of risk, we have continued to focus on secured assets. 84% of the loan book is fully or partially secured and only 16% is unsecured. The Consumer Banking loan impairment charge has decreased to $211 million, down 29% on the first half of 2010. Consumer Banking has, since year-end, seen good balance sheet velocity with customer loans up 7% and growth well spread, and customer deposits up 6%. On an annualized basis, the rate of balance sheet growth has slowed compared to last year as a result of re-pricing actions taken in a number of markets.</p>
          <p>Looking at income in more detail, mortgage income was up 2% against the first half of 2010 but down 4% on the second half, with a 19% increase in balances over the last 12 months, offsetting margin compression of some 36 basis points. Pressure on mortgage margins have been driven by strengthening competition and rising interest rates. Market share has remained strong in our key mortgage geographies, albeit we have given up some share as we have priced the book up across a number of markets. Mortgage is the main and important anchor product for the Consumer Banking business.</p>
          <p>Deposit income is up 21% in the first half of this year, driven by a 16% increase in balances and an improvement in margins of some 6 basis points. CASA deposits, which now constitute 56% of total Consumer Banking deposits, benefited from a margin uplift of some 16 basis points, albeit time deposits fell 6 basis points as competition increased. Wealth management has now delivered five consecutive halves of income growth, up 23% against the comparable period last year. Particularly strong performances were delivered by Singapore and Hong Kong, underpinned by strong volume growth in funds, in equities and in structured products. Compared to the second half, Wealth Management has also shown good momentum with income up 9%.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide, income in Credit Cards and Personal Loans, or CCPL, shows excellent momentum, up 16%, and balance is up 28% compared to the first half of 2010, driven by selective asset growth in markets such as Hong Kong, Singapore and Malaysia. We are enjoying steady market share gains in card outstanding, particularly in Hong Kong and Singapore where market shares now exceed 17%. SME income is up 13% to some $660 million compared to the first half of 2010 and up 7% on the second half, driven by particularly good growth in trade products, associated FX and in cash management. The SME book remains predominantly secured.</p>
          <p>Impairment; loan impairment both in terms of dollars and basis points of loss has shown further improvement against both halves of 2010. Looking by product, you will see that loan loss rates are down across all product categories year-on-year. Overall, the total loss rate was at its historical low of 35 basis points, reflecting proactive credit actions including fundamentals but also a benefit from the sale of a number portfolios which generated a write-back to loan impairments of $51 million. Overall, Consumer Banking loan impairment was $211 million, 29% down on the first half and 24% down on the second half of 2010. Our forward-looking indicators also remain steady at low levels.</p>
          <p>To summarize the Consumer Banking overall, continuing good, steady income momentum built on good footings growth and higher activity levels; unsecured assets are growing, albeit the asset profile remains predominantly secured. Liabilities continue to grow and with strong capital levels. Good cost discipline has allowed for targeted investment. Loan impairment is sharply down, and a robust cover ratio of 86%; excellent profit growth, a very good first half.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking; Wholesale Banking has delivered a good performance during the first half of the year with income growth of 8% year-on-year and 9% on the second half. When you look at the Wholesale Banking performance, there are three underlying themes you should bear in mind. Firstly, the business remains fundamentally client-driven with client income contributing 82% of total Wholesale Banking income. We are continuing to focus on deepening client relationships and we are using our network capabilities as a source of competitive differentiation. In the first half of the year, over 45% of Wholesale Banking client income was generated offshore.</p>
          <p>Secondly, as in prior periods, commercial banking and flow FX continued to be the pivot of Wholesale Banking, contributing over half of total client income in the first half of 2011. The annuity-type businesses, trade and cash, are continuing to grow well, geared off strong economic strong across our footprint. Cash margins are also benefiting from rising local currency interest rates. Thirdly, Wholesale Banking remains a very diverse business. The areas that have had slower performance in the first half such as Corporate Finance were more than offset by others that delivered strong growth such as Transaction Banking and Financial Markets.</p>
          <p>Expenses rose 9%, primarily reflecting the impact of prior-year investments. We added some 900 staff in the second half of last year, which has flowed through to expenses in the first half of 2011. Over the last six months, head count has fallen some 150 as we held investment tightly. However, we look to accelerate investment going into the second half. Loan impairment has increased 46% year-on-year and 20% on the second half of 2010, mainly due to taking incremental provisions on existing accounts. There have been no material provisions on new accounts in the first half of the year. Other impairment has increased from $46 million to $68 million, predominantly because of higher charges against Indian exposures. Profit before tax increased 5% year-on-year, up 13% on the second half. We continue to be disciplined in managing the relationship between risk-weighted assets and client income growth, with client income growth as in prior periods exceeding RWA growth.</p>
          <p>Looking at income in more detail; lending income was down 6% from $465 million to $435 million, reflecting margin compression of some 36 basis points compared to the same period last year, although the rates of margin compression has moderated since December. 18% growth of period-end balances in this business was insufficient to offset margin pressure. In trade income was up 11%, driven by growth in assets and contingents of some 27% year-on-year against a wider market increase of 17%. Activity levels have increased with the number of transactions up 14% year-on-year. Cash management income saw excellent growth of 33%, underpinned both by strong growth in average liabilities, up 26% year-on-year; and an improvement in cash margins of 14 basis points against the first half of last year and up 4 basis points against the second half.</p>
          <p>Within the Transaction Banking business, we closed 20% more deals in the first half of the year than in the first half of 2010. We continued to take market share. Our renminbi capability is an important differentiator, and we now offer renminbi services in 29 markets, up from 16 at the end of 2010. Financial Markets is the largest component of global markets, and I'll talk about this in the next slide. ALM income of $431 million was down, as expected, by 12% year-on-year, as accrual income fell. We are beginning to see a benefit from the expectation of rising rates in a number of our markets, and as a result ALM income is up 2% on the second half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Corporate Finance income of $912 million was down 2% year-on-year, after very strong growth into out periods and has delivered a two-year compound annual growth rates and income of 22%. We are continuing to see good deal flow with the number of deals closed increasing by some 25%. However, income growth in the first half was impacted by pricing pressure and fewer large deals, as competition increased. The deal pipeline however remains robust. Principal Finance income of $146 million is up 9% year-on-year despite difficult market conditions. We finished the half strongly, closing a number of deals and also benefiting from favorable valuations on several holdings. This is an excellent business, which we continue to grow selectively and where reinvestments exceed realizations. Clients income was at record levels in the first half of 2011, growing at 9% year-on-year, and 12% on the second half of 2010. Own account income was up 4% when compared to the first half of 2010 and down 1% against the second half.</p>
          <p>Financial Markets; income in Financial Markets of $1.95 billion was up 14% on the first half and up 23% on the second half of 2010. Within Financial Markets, our FICC business was up 14%. This is a business that has a strong link to our Transaction Banking product set, giving it resilience even when market conditions are difficult. Foreign Exchange income of $769 million, up 19% year-on-year, was underpinned by volume growth of 26%. FX benefited from strong Transaction Banking volumes, but also from the continued emergence of the renminbi as a functional currency.</p>
          <p>The Rates business was down 12% despite volumes up some 17% year-on-year, having been impacted by regulatory changes, and in the Middle East deal deferral, given ongoing political turmoil. Commodities and Equities income grew 93%, with Commodities performing particularly well as clients hedged volatile commodity prices. This is a business where we have invested for a number of years, and its strong performance is evidenced in an number of excellent lead table standings. Growth in capital markets where income increased 16% to $271 million was driven by good levels of origination with volumes up 71%. Credit income was down 8% to $142 million, with difficult market conditions reducing transaction volumes. 76% of Financial Markets income is client-driven, with client income up 10% on the first half.</p>
          <p>Loan impairment; Wholesale Banking loan impairment was $201 million, up 46% on the first half of 2010. We remain disciplined and proactive in our approach to risk management and have benefited from a conservative, diverse, predominantly short-dated loan book. Early alerts have increased since December 2010 as we increased vigilance, particularly around our India book. Although we remain comfortable with our exposure to Indian counterparties, we have taken an additional portfolio impairment provision against the India book, reflecting the higher level of stress in the broader economy. We also continue to carry a portfolio impairment provision against the Middle East, albeit at a lower level than at December 2010. The weighted average profitability default improved by 3 basis points to 85 basis points in the first half of the year. This was partly driven by the improving economic environment in some of our core markets and some mix shift towards Asian sovereigns and highly-rated banks. The Wholesale Banking cover ratio is at 53%, or 66% including collateral. The uncovered net at risk is well within our historical recovery levels.</p>
          <p>Let me summarize the overall Wholesale Banking picture. Wholesale Banking has delivered another good set of results, with record levels of client income, a firm grip on costs and focused management of risk. Primary and secondary distribution levels remain strong. The business enters the second half of 2011 with robust transaction pipelines and high levels of client activity. The annuity-type Transaction Banking businesses are growing well, as economic growth across our footprint remains strong, which in turn drives volumes to our Financial Markets business. So Corporate Finance remains a critical factor, and here the second-quarter performance was ahead of the first quarter and the pipeline remains robust.</p>
          <p>Turning to geographic performance, Hong Kong has delivered a very strong set of results with record levels of operating profit of $790 million, up 55%; and record levels of income, up 29% on the comparable period last year. Both businesses have delivered an excellent performance, and Peter will talk to you about this in more detail. Profit in Singapore have seen an 11% increase to $465 million. Income growth of 20% is truly broad-based with the investments we made in the second half of 2010 delivering good income productivity. Expense growth of 22%, or 10% on a constant currency basis, reflects in part the flow-through of these investments. Transaction Banking and Financial Market sales were both excellent, each up over 30%. Wealth Management grew 43%. In CCPL, we built market share, partly through the acquisition of the portfolio of assets, with income up 30% on the first half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Korea's profit was up 30% year-on-year to $193 million, despite a challenging external environment. Consumer Banking income was up 14%, or 9% on a constant currency basis, and Wholesale Banking income fell 10% in a difficult operating environment. Costs were well controlled and loan impairment fell 37%. In other APR, profit is up 46% to $846 million, with particularly strong performances in China, Indonesia and Malaysia, with income growth of 16%, 20% and 14% respectively. These are all markets we invested in at pace during 2010. India has had a challenging six months with operating profit down by 39% on income that was down 12% year-on-year. This performance reflects a difficult operating environment during the first half. We remained committed but watchful in this market, and Peter will talk about this in more detail.</p>
          <p>MESA income of $1.1 billion is up 6% year-on-year and well spread across both businesses. Costs are well controlled and impairment decreased 17% against the second half of last year. Africa's operating profit fell 6% to $291 million, with income up 5%. Against the second half of 2010, profit was up 17% and income was up 13%. We saw greater competition, and in particular, slower Corporate Finance income. Overall however, we remain confident that Africa will continue to grow income at a double-digit rate on an ongoing basis. The Americas, UK and Europe region almost doubled its profit to $244 million in the first half of the year, driven by strong performances in cash, in Corporate Finance and in commodities, and an improvement in loan impairment due to lower ABS charges. This segment remains a key origination center for the Wholesale Banking business as an entry point to our geographies in Asia, Africa and the Middle East.</p>
          <p>Turning then to outlook, we have started the second half of the year well. July has seen good income momentum in the Consumer Bank, and in the Wholesale Bank client income remains strong. Costs remain tightly managed. Both businesses continue to benefit from ongoing increases in volumes, off the back of strong economic activity. For the group as a whole, we expect to deliver double-digit income growth for the full year with flat jaws, excluding the impacts of the UK bank levy. We are maintaining our tight grip on expenses in both businesses, whilst beginning to accelerate investment to underpin growth in 2012. Overall, credit indicators remain good. Our biggest risk by far remains regulatory risk. We continue to benefit from the disciplined execution of our strategy. We remain committed to and focused on delivering our financial objectives, and we remain well positioned in growth markets. Momentum is very good and we are continuing to take market share across a number of products and geographies.</p>
          <p>Thank you, and now I'll hand over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. As Richard has already laid out, Standard Chartered continues to deliver strong, broad-based results. Our businesses have great momentum. We continue to see significant opportunities for profitable organic growth across our franchise, in some of the most exciting economies in the world. We have stuck to our strategy, a strategy that is familiar to you all; a focus on Asia, Africa and the Middle East, markets in which we have a long history and which we know intimately; a focus on building long-term, deep relationships with our customers and clients rather than on transactions and products; a bias towards organic growth as the most sure way of creating shareholder value; a conservative balance sheet approach, emphasizing liquidity, capital strength and a highly diversified asset portfolio; and an obsession with all the basic disciplines of good banking. It's a strategy that delivered before the crisis, during the crisis and is delivering now. We see no reason to change.</p>
          <p>One consequence of our consistent pursuit of this strategy is that we have built a much broader base, a much stronger bank. Our breadth and diversity across geographies, products and client segments gives us extraordinary resilience. Areas of weaker performance are balanced by others doing well. We have multiple engines of growth. Ten years ago, Hong Kong, Singapore and Malaysia together accounted for nearly 50% of the group's income. Today, they contribute just over 30%, even though they all had an outstanding first half.</p>
          <p>We have also increased diversification through significant investment in new capabilities. Ten years ago, we had no private bank, no Corporate Finance expertise and very limited SME products and commodities capabilities. Today, these are all very substantial growth businesses. Together, they account for almost a quarter of group income. This breadth and resilience is particularly important, given the very real risks in the global economy. All of you will be familiar with the trials and tribulations of the Eurozone and the brinkmanship around US federal borrowing. We are not directly affected by either of these issues, but the ripple effects across the global economy and financial system are profound. What both reveal is the depth and scale of the issues afflicting the West, unwinding the legacy of far too much borrowing for far too long will take time, will be painful and won't be smooth.</p>
          <p>Whilst all markets across Asia, Africa and the Middle East are in much better shape, they cannot entirely escape the effects. The monetary stimulus in the West exacerbates asset inflation in Asia and commodity prices worldwide. Weaker demand for Asian exports reinforces the imperative for a structural shift in Asian economies. We are in a world economy where the patterns of growth are extraordinarily divergent and where the problems of the weak create challenges for the strong. We're in a world where economics and politics collide continually and uncomfortably, fueling uncertainty in Financial Markets and stridency in political debate. The cacophony of regulatory change creates its own systemic risks and endangers economic recovery and job creation.</p>
          <p>But we're also in world of opportunity, take China alone. I visited Chongqing in May and last month, Shenzhen, Guangzhou and Beijing. There may be asset bubbles in China, but China itself is not a bubble. The drivers of growth, urbanization, demographics, education and infrastructure, are incredibly strong. Across Asia, more people are experiencing the joys of becoming middleclass consumers than at any time in history. And there's a buzz of confidence in Africa, underpinned by commodity demand, improvements in governance and demographics. We are in the right markets with the right strategy investing for growth, but alert to the risks and capable of taking the bumps in our stride; for there will always be bumps. Our markets will not develop smoothly without turbulence or dislocations. Our progress as a business will not be linear without slowdowns or setbacks.</p>
          <p>Given the strength of these numbers and the opportunities we see ahead, I could just be talking about our achievements, the good stuff. But before I do that, I want to focus on a couple of markets which have proved more challenging; first India. After sustaining very strong growth over a number of years, it's been a challenging first six months for the team in India. We anticipated a slowdown, but in truth it has come faster and deeper than we thought. Both businesses are down year-on-year.</p>
          <p>There are four reasons for this slowdown. First, the Reserve Bank of India has increased rates 11 times in the past 17 months, including a 50-basis point rise last week, an assertive response to inflation concerns. This has slowed domestic demand and impacted equity market sentiment, affecting Wealth Management sales. It has also put pressure on asset margins and credit quality. Second, we have seen some increase in competition, from both local and foreign banks. This has put further pressure on margins. Third, the furor about governance in business and politics has also affected business sentiment, slowing the flow of deals and projects. Enhancing governance and transparency and cleaning out corruption are undoubtedly good things, but the immediate impact on business activity and confidence is negative. Finally, there have been a number of product-specific rule changes that have had negative impact on both Wholesale and Consumer Banking, including greater restrictions on derivatives. As a result of these factors, income in India has fallen by 12% and profit by 39%.</p>
          <p>The immediate outlook remains somewhat challenging and we maintain a rather cautious stance on risk. At this stage, given the headwinds and uncertainty, we're not counting on a strong rebound in the second half. Yet it's important to put this in perspective. Counterbalancing the reduction in Wholesale Banking's onshore client income, offshore client income from the Indian franchise more than doubled to $185 million, in large parts, classic Commercial Banking, Trade, Finance, Cash Management, FX, working capital and so on.</p>
          <p>Looking further out, we remain very confident about the longer-term prospects for the business and we're not changing our strategy. We'll continue to invest for growth. Indeed, the 13% increase in costs over the last year reflects in part the investments we've been making, such as Express Banking centers and online distribution in Consumer Banking and the build-out of the equities platform in Wholesale Banking.</p>
          <p>The balance sheet continues to show good momentum, with customer loans growing by 10% and deposits by 9% since the year-end. India will remain a key engine of income and earnings growth for the group, given the strength of our competitive position and the fundamental dynamism of the market.</p>
          <p>Korea; as you know, Korea is another market in which we have faced challenges, with costs that are too high and an inefficiently structured balance sheet. Yet despite these facts, our Korean business had a relatively good first half, with profits up 30%. Unfortunately, however, the local labor union has been on strike since the 27th of June in a dispute that focuses on our proposals to implement performance-related pay. The framework we are trying to introduce is fair to individuals and teams and enables disciplined cost management. It mirrors our practice in other markets and is consistent with practice in sectors other than banking in Korea. This is purely a local matter and affects less than half our staff in Korea. We've been continuing to operate the bank with almost full capability and the dispute has had very limited impact on financial performance. We are in ongoing negotiations with the union and hope to be able to reach an agreement soon.</p>
          <p>India and Korea were two of our more challenging markets in the first six months of 2011. But one of the strengths of Standard Chartered is the fact that we have multiple growth engines. If one or two runs slow, others will be running fast. Hong Kong, for example, delivered a superb performance with both record income, up 29%, and record profit, up 55%. We've seen strong performances in both Consumer and Wholesale Banking.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking income grew 23%, with particularly strong performance in the high-value segments where we have focused investments. For example, SME income was up 27%, and in the Private Bank income rose 63% and revenue per client, 29%. In Wholesale Banking, income was up 33% with client income up 39%. Our focus on the rapidly expanding trade and investment links between Hong Kong and Mainland China has been hugely successful. We are a leader in cross-border trade settlement in renminbi and in the issuance of dim sum bonds. We have an exceptionally strong balance sheet in Hong Kong and continue to take market share in deposits, which were up 9% since year-end. With an advances-to-deposit ratio of under 60%, we've benefited from the widening of liability NIMs in the first half and are well placed to benefit from further re-pricing.</p>
          <p>China; in the Mainland itself we have continued to invest in rapid expansion of the business. We have opened nine branches and sub-branches so far this year, taking the total to 71. Our latest is in Xi'an, the city of terracotta warriors and, perhaps more to the point, of 8 million people. We now have more than 5,500 staff in Mainland China. First-half income in China grew year-on-year by 16% to $404 million. Including Bohai Bank where we have a 20% stake, profits in China are up 76% to $137 million. However, this significantly understates the impact of China on the group as a whole. Quite apart from Hong Kong, where the business is increasingly intertwined with the mainland, China generates income across the network. Domestically, China has been taking action to moderate the pace of economic growth and squeeze inflation. This is having some effect on our growth momentum, but the impact is limited. The underlying drivers of growth are so strong and our current market share so small that we remain confident that we can continue to invest and grow rapidly.</p>
          <p>But China is far from our only growth story. One of the particularly pleasing features of this first half is the strength of growth in a number of our somewhat smaller markets. For example, in Bangladesh, our first-half income is up 22% and has topped a $100 million for the first time. In Indonesia, income is up 20% to $350 million. Income in Nigeria is up 13% to more than $120 million. And Thailand has bounced back strongly from the political impasse, with income up 24% to $177 million. We have 15 markets which generated income over $100 million in a six-month period, of which 10 contributed profits of over $100 million, a powerful demonstration of the diversity of the group.</p>
          <p>Ensuring we can continue to invest for growth in markets like China while controlling cost growth for the group as a whole is a key priority. In March, we promised that excluding the impact of the UK bank levy, our jaws would be flat for 2011 as a whole, i.e., cost would grow in line with income. In fact, we have more than achieved this in the first half through tight discipline, continued efficiency gains and careful pacing of investment. In the second half we anticipate stepping up the pace of investment somewhat but still expect to deliver flat jaws excluding the UK bank levy for 2011 as a whole.</p>
          <p>In Consumer Banking, we will continue to invest in driving the transformation of the business, increasing our distribution reach, enhancing customer service, launching new products and increasing our brand and marketing spend. We'll be opening more branches, particularly in China, and are rolling out innovative mobile and internet platforms such as Breeze. In Wholesale Banking, we'll continue to invest in hiring relationship managers and product specialists, building out our capabilities in areas like commodities and equities, strengthening our expertise in sectors such as mining and transportation.</p>
          <p>Across the group, we continue to invest in our underlying technology infrastructure. It may not be glamorous or even visible, but we believe that the fundamental data structure, messaging layers, technology security and systems resilience, these things are absolutely key building blocks we need to keep enhancing. And of course, there's a never-ending need to invest to meet new regulatory demands, whether related to reporting, resolution, recovery, anti-money laundering and so on. As always, we'll be flexing the pace of investment to reflect overall business performance and our perception of the risks.</p>
          <p>We enter the second half with our risk radar turned full on. The global economy faces significant risks to the Eurozone, US borrowing, inflation regressions. We continue to grow throughout the crisis supporting our clients and customers. Loans to customers are now 75% higher than they were in mid-2007, which is when it all began to crumble. We've managed to do that by taking a very holistic approach to risk, dynamically adjusting the shape of the balance sheet to anticipate and respond to events. We don't think of risks as sitting in neat silos; credit, market, operational. Risks more than hit you when you're not looking. We're not slaves to our mathematical models. We use them but question them. We don't equate compliance with regulations, with managing the underlying risk.</p>
          <p>We do think culture is the foundation of good risk management, an open questioning culture, which escalates issues, learns lessons, admits mistakes. We are in a risk business, we're investing for growth, and the world is very uncertain. That means we have to be very alert and adaptive. And that's an organizational capability, infrastructure, culture, skills processes that we are continuingly investing in, continually seeking to improve.</p>
          <p>Perhaps the most difficult category of risks to manage is that which emerges from the regulatory and political arena. We are deeply concerned about the unintended consequences of the avalanche of regulatory change engulfing the industry. Despite what some might claim, there is no reform agenda as such; there are too many actors, too many initiatives, and no one working out what it all adds up to. The unintended consequences of this frankly chaotic process pose the greatest risks we face as an institution, and one of the greatest risks to financial stability, economic recovery and job creation.</p>
          <p>We've made our views of all of these very clear, so I won't bore you with more detail. We are supportive of many of the changes. It is in our interest to work within a much better regulated industry, but we need far more prioritization, much better coordination and much clearer thinking about the tradeoffs. As shareholders, you have an important role to play in these debates. Put bluntly, banks that cannot deliver returns to their shareholders will not attract your capital and consequently will not be able to play their role in supporting the rest of the economy.</p>
          <p>So, what can you expect from us? Richard has already given you some thoughts on the outlook for the balance of the year. More generally, we remain committed to delivering against the financial metrics we have used for several years now. Over the medium term, you should expect from us, first, double-digit income growth; given the markets we're in and the momentum of our businesses, we expect to deliver double-digit income growth in 2011 and beyond. Second, broadly flat jaws; we have achieved this over many years and we'll pace our investments to ensure costs grow broadly in line with income. Third, double-digit growth in earnings per share; the recent equity raisings have deflected us on this metric as has the introduction of the UK bank levy, but the underlying dynamics of the business should get us back on track next year and beyond. Fourth, mid-teens ROE; this is the metric we're most questioned on. And the reality is that it is impossible to be definitive about return expectations when so much is in flux around capital and liquidity regulation and when it is unclear how much of these incremental costs will get passed on through pricing.</p>
          <p>This year, ROE has undoubtedly been dampened by the equity we raised last year, the UK bank levy and by the continuing drag of a low interest rate environment on a deposit-rich bank. But when we scrutinize the underlying dynamics of our business, mid-teens ROEs still look achievable. Much depends on what more the regulators throw at us. There are some critical trade-offs embedded in these metrics. Perhaps the most crucial is striking the right balance between ROE and growth. It's possible to get it wrong either way, by delivering growth at too low a return or by squeezing growth to defend returns. The Board is acutely aware that getting this right drives shareholder value creation.</p>
          <p>The first half of 2011 has been challenging with economic uncertainty, regulatory change and political upheaval. It's a huge tribute to my colleagues that they've been able to deliver another record set of results. I'd like to thank them for their commitment, professionalism and team work and also to thank you, our shareholders, for your support. July has been a good month and the bank enters the second half of the year in great shape, with good momentum, costs under tight control, a disciplined and anticipatory approach to risk management and with an exceptionally strong balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Thank you for listening to our presentations. We'll now break the video link and take your questions in each location separately. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, it's the usual format. If you could put your hand up where you are to ask a question and state your name and your institution. So, in the front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Ian Smillie from RBS; two questions, please. The first one, the core Tier 1 ratio was surprisingly strong in the half, and could I invite you to comment on the pace of RWA growth please? So up 7% in the half versus your loan book at 9%, and obviously non-mortgage is growing meaningfully faster than mortgages. So, should we think about the non-mortgage loan growth being more secure than it has been historically, or what else is allowing the RWAs to grow less quickly than loans? And perhaps as part of that answer, if you could give us any guidance in the BIS 2.5 that may come in December please, that'd be very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that was just the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we take the second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question is on check deposit, the CASA performance which was again very strong in the half. Looking at some of the swings and roundabout geographically, it looks like UK and Americas made something like 10 of the 14 incrementals, so by &#x2013; far and away the biggest contributor. Just some color as to what's happening in there, please. And on the other side of that, it looks like Korea and other Asia Pacific went backwards slightly, so just some commentary as to what might be happening on the ground there. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to start with the Core Tier 1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On Core Tier 1, the first point clearly is generating RWA growth of 7%. Our capital position improved. If you annualize that 7%, it demonstrates that we can underpin that to clear our RWA growth whilst maintaining or even slightly improving the core Tier 1 ratio. Within the RWA growth, we did see very good control of RWA and manage of RWA in the Wholesale business first of all, which as I said in my presentation, was growing and I think at about 6% and 8%, i.e., lower than the client income growth growing at 7% and 12%. And the RWA efficiency that comes through Wholesale predominantly comes through collateralization benefit.</p>
          <p>If you take the Consumer side and between the mortgage or non-mortgage growth, yes, we saw quite a high growth in credit risk-weighted assets in the Consumer Bank; that's predominantly attaching to the unsecured portfolios of personal loans and credit cards. If you look at the SME business, we're around 63% secured on SME overall. So again, when you think about what's driving the RWA, it will move in the Consumer Bank as we grow the unsecured, but actually it's not moving at such a rate that needs the RWA for the whole group. On BIS 2.5, yes, there's still lots of things that are potentially moving. I'd have thought that the potential impact on us is overall balance sheet for 30 basis points or so. On CASA performance --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I can see you're on a roll.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I seem to be on a roll. I'm sure your time maybe will come. The CASA performance in &#x2013; that's the hint for a regulatory question, that's a good one actually. The CASA performance in UK, Europe and Americas is predominantly is actually just very Cash Management business, Corporate Deposit business coming through to us in Korea at another APR. Other APR less certain of that, I'd have to think about it quite hard. In Korea, it's simply a mix shift against competitive pressures and, also, as we seek to change profile in the overall balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Generally speaking, when you see rises in local currency interest rates, do you see a substitution effect as of CASA into savings accounts, time deposits and so on? When interest rates are near zero, there's not much incentive for people to tie up their money. When they start rising, you do see that coming through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, another influence is Taiwan. So, the issue in Taiwan is actually what we did see was a change in the regulations around particular regulation on mortgage A/D ratios and the Taiwanese business is predominantly a Consumer Banking business. It's got a mortgage book of about $8.5 billion and the regulators ask for higher levels of deposits held against that. In order to meet that regulatory change at pace, you saw us increase time deposits at, frankly, a margin drag and a change to the CASA TD mix within other APR.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pass it back to Steven, yes. I'll come over to you in a minute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you. It's Steve Hayne from Morgan Stanley. So, Peter, just to make sure you've got your time in the sun as well, I just wanted to come back to your comment about balancing between ROE and growth. In particular, you raised just over $5 billion in the fourth quarter of last year and from what I understand, you're still sitting on most of it and it's just in very low-yielding guilds. So, you've had a structural step-down in the ROE.</p>
          <p>And then, people buy your stock because they want growth. So they want typically it's been wholesale growth and typically it's been India for the last decade. And at the moment, it doesn't feel like you've got that investment to put in in India because of the difficult economic environment there. So, I'm wondering if you can give some more guidance on what you plan to do with the $5 billion and where it's going to be invested over time, because again, it feels to me like the regulatory issues are so overwhelming at the moment that you probably do want to hang on to a lot of it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, you're right on the sort of depiction. We raised equity to take us above the fray on the basis that we could self-fund growth, and that just gave us a step-change in our capital position. That took us out of the noise around what's happening around capital levels. And as the discussion about RWA growth in capital ratio, core Tier 1 has just demonstrated we can self-fund growth. But your point is correct in that at the moment it is a bit of a drag on our ROE, we're not deploying it as much as ideally we would like. But, I suspect that until the regulatory picture becomes a bit clearer, we're not going to rush to deploy it. We're going to be doing it in a very sort of gradual manner because we want to keep in this position of using this phrase, again, above the fray, not sort of sucked into every twist and turn of the regulatory debate.</p>
          <p>But the only point I'd make is, yes, it is true that much of our growth in the past has been Wholesale and much of it has been around India. But if you actually look at the dynamics of the balance sheet, I mean, it's not that we're short of growth. We're growing both sides of the balance sheet strongly. We're growing in places, in multiple different places, certainly in Greater China but also much more broadly. And what I think is particularly pleasing is you're now seeing real momentum coming through on the Consumer side. We've been through really a massive transformation there and it was sort of hard to see what was actually going on there for a while because there were so many moving parts. But now, I think you're beginning to see the real fruits of what we've been putting in place coming through to the balance and to the P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>I'll do one more over here, just straight behind. It seems to work quite well, this technique; and then I'll --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's <mark type="ph" /> Gary Greenwood at Shore Capital (58:28). Got three brief questions. The first one is just on business mix. We saw a very strong growth in the Consumer Bank in the first half of this year, much less so in the Wholesale Bank. As you look forward sort of three, four, five years, do you expect to see the balance of the group materially shifting back towards the Consumer Bank? Second question is just on the dividend growth, 10% growth in the first half of the year. I think consensus is looking for something slightly less than that for the full year. Is 10% the pace of growth that we can expect to see going forward? And then the final question, just on Korea, where you mentioned the impact of the strikes wasn't that significant to financial performance. I just wondered if actually you've got too many staff there in the first place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Business mix, yeah, Consumer Bank is now 28%, up from 21%-ish?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And look, we don't think there is a sort of perfect mix, optimal mix for the group between the two. We like having two strong growth engines that complement each other in many ways. I anticipate that Consumer Banking will probably be a larger part of the group than it's been in previous years, but the Wholesale Banking will still be the bigger part of the group. In terms of dividend growth, well we kept it pretty simple this first half. It's premature to say what we will do for the full year. I only suggest you look at our history in terms of we do understand the importance of dividends to shareholders.</p>
          <p>In terms of Korea, you'll understand that we are in the middle of negotiations at the moment. We do see significant opportunities to improve the productivity of Korea. The negotiations were embarked on in this whole thing are very much about making it a more efficient place. We see opportunities, both in terms of cost productivity and in terms of capital and balance sheet productivity. And so, that is what we are embarked on at the moment. As I said, the near-term, the immediate effect on the strike has been absolutely de minimis. Depending on how long it goes on for and how it unfolds, there may be some effect in the second half, but it's hard to be specific and it's not going to be very big anyway. It's not going to be very significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we just in fairness to take over the side here. There's a mic coming and then we'll come back to you. Yes, we'll --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. It's Cormac Leech from Canaccord. Just your medium-term guidance for ROE is mid-teens, so presumably, say, for simplicity 15%.You're at 12.5% ex-levy in the first half. It kind of strikes me simplistically there's maybe three drivers: risk-adjusted revenues, RWA, cost efficiency and gearing. And I think just touching on Steve's question, there's probably some scope to kind of increase the gearing for the business gradually over time. But I suppose the question is, what do you see as the most likely way for you to get to your mid-teen ROE? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to get this or --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll go first and then you can fill in the gaps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, if there are any I'll try, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, there is this point about where we end up to on the capital and the deployment of money that is essentially being held to give us flexibility. Second is, we are in an unusually low interest rate environment, and for a bank is very long deposit, that's a drag on our returns, and the key to that is US dollar rates. Third, we do see opportunities around things like cross-selling, operational efficiency and so on, where we think it's good for us to put ourselves under the pressure to deliver more return, to squeeze our capital harder. So, there are a number of different dimensions. Do you want to add anything to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd add the income businesses, that if you look at the investment we've made in Wealth Management then you'd see that it's been 23% this first half, the fifth consecutive period of that. We're investing hard in our Private Banking business. Again, we've seen a 31% increase in income, 30% increase in AUM in our Private Banking business. We're investing in equities platform that drags around $100 million trading profit in these numbers in terms of the excessive cost and investment over revenues earned. So, as we turn that business around, it starts to generate &#x2013; I think we'll see that starting to drive further returns on a strategic basis. Absolutely, there is a growing potential.</p>
          <p>But I would be nervous of going at that. At the moment, our current leverage ratio is about 6.3%. It's way, way, way ahead of &#x2013; and still to be settled definitions into Basel III, but we are way ahead of that. And on liquidity, we are debating. We have slightly edged our A/D ratio up. We did move as the crisis sort of grew across the world into a very conservative position. You could see us over the next two or three years moving our A/D ratio up. It potentially is asset growth but more likely to be the pricing away of currently margin dragging, expensive deposits, which again would be <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:04:30) return. I don't think we need to sit under 80%. Currently at the moment, we are a very strong bank. So, there are lots of different areas which underpin a confidence in the growth of returns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But there are couple of questions that I think is worth sort of uncontrollable external variables. One is, the regulatory game isn't over and that, obviously, has quite a big effect on returns. And the second, frankly, is the rationality of the industry. We think that a number of players still haven't really factored in how to price for the new levels of capital and the current sort of liquidity constraints. And that isn't helped by the fact that all the regulatory stuff is in flux and people haven't grappled with it yet. But there's an unknown question as to how fast that will actually get factored in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Do you want to sort of go further back on the same side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (65:42)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the short answer to that is yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly for the immediate &#x2013; certainly into the second half, probably at the beginning of next year, we are going to maintain a very firm view on pricing. We have given up some share. So, in Hong Kong, for instance, we were a touch over 15%, we're now a touch under 15%. In Singapore, we were over 12%, we're now about 11.8%. So, we're given up small amounts of share and I think we feel pretty comfortable with that starts for the pricing benefit we can get. So, that would continue on investments. We invested over $200 million in the first half, slightly weighted towards the Consumer Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China was the single biggest geography.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China was the single biggest geography where we added nine branches, for instance, and we intend to double the rate of branch openings in China and in the second half over the first half. But the overall investment spend is broadly spread across most of the markets, obviously at predominantly in Asia. We're extending investments in the second half in Africa a little bit, so further distribution reach in our African markets. We're investing in online, in mobile, in further branding and marketing expenditure. But it's a pretty broad-based pickup in the level of investments during the first half. We are already making those decisions to accelerate in the second half to underpin 2012, to make sure we go into 2012 with the same degree of momentum that we have currently in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China is the single biggest geography, certainly for the consumer bank, but along the Wholesale Banking it's kind of hard to attach to a particular geography because it seems like product expertise in transportation and mining or something like that which has application across a whole range of our geographies. Okay, it's going to be one more over here, yeah? Put the mic on, and then --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Michael Helsby from Merrill Lynch. I've just got three questions. Firstly, on Hong Kong. You have clearly very strong operational trends in Hong Kong. NIMs were up about 30 bps half-on-half, costs were down half-on-half and loan growth was very strong, up 30% year-on-year, 49% in Wholesale. I was just wondering if you could give us a comment on what you expect for the second half because, you know, clearly the &#x2013; or just some comments on sustainability of those trends. And as an aside, if you could give us a view on the duration of the Wholesale loan book, so, that's question one.</p>
          <p>Question two is just very quickly, within Wealth Management, I was wondering if you could give us a feel for what percentage of the revenue is annuity-driven versus flow-driven. I'm just conscious it has gone up a lot and clearly unit trust sales have gone up hell of a lot, so that would very useful. And then, just as a broader question on Wholesale Banking revenues. Clearly, client income has slowed down a lot relative to what you've done in the past. I think it's the first time really it's dropped below the 15% medium term for quite a while actually. So, I was just wondering, given the competition, given the irrationality that you mentioned, is that something that we should now expect for maybe the next couple of years or is it, sort of, 2012 straight back to 15%? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I take the last one first and then --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll try and do the others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- I'll give you the others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Taking the last one first, yes, Wholesale Banking client income has grown more slowly this last six months than it has in previous times, but this is against the backdrop of &#x2013; well, you know better than I what the results of many of the other banks have been. But actually, given the nature of what's going on in our markets and given the opportunities we see, we think that kind of mid-teens type of client income growth is the sustainable pattern that you should be expecting over the medium term. It's not necessarily going to happen every single year or every single period, but we don't see any reason why the demand and the opportunity isn't there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'll endorse that mid to high-teens for client income growth in the medium term. As we look out to our plans, we have a relatively high degree of confidence on that. On Hong Kong, Hong Kong did benefit, as you say, in margins. We saw a good pickup, particularly in liability margins. If I think about the Cash Management margins since they've doubled in this period from what we were seeing a year ago, and we were getting a very strong growth in overall volumes. Actually, therefore, our Cash Management Business in Hong Kong generated an income uplift of over 80%. 80%. So, you have a doubling of margins and very, very good volumes coming through.</p>
          <p>In the Consumer side, again, we're seeing a slight pickup, again, in the liability margins, which is more than outweighing the asset margin pressure. The asset margin pressure which you see predominantly see is in mortgages, which are down from about just over 110 basis points to below 80 basis points. And I think the other area of pressures is in credit card margins, which are down to just under 9% from 12%. That is in part also a segmentation choice that we are making as we are changing the risk profile of our credit card book and customers. So, how should you think about margins going forward? I think pretty resilient, potentially still improving as liability margins continue to flow through.</p>
          <p>On costs, there are a couple of items within the cost base you need to watch for that we've disclosed in the past. But if you think about we had some Lehman structured note costs going through last year. If you remember that $95 million, $50 million first half, $45 million second, and we only have $10 million of those finishing that particular issue in the first half of this year.</p>
          <p>So, you have to adjust for that as you look at the Hong Kong cost base. Other than that, we have very good BAU cost disciplines and we're starting now to accelerate investment, but there is that one-off to adjust for in loan growth. And we did take the opportunity to book further in Wholesale commercial assets over into the surface liquidity engine, which is our Hong Kong bank. Thus, the Hong Kong business is capable of generating very good levels of liquidity and has done so. We have also therefore taken the opportunity to book in some assets.</p>
          <p>That's partly a contribution to the growth in loans. But mainly, it's a function of just the level of commercial activity that we're seeing partly coming out of very strongly growing trade finance. Corporate Finance was up 90% in that period. Transaction Banking was up 28%, Global Markets up 45%. So, you look at first Hong Kong and its broad range of growth, which I have high confidence, is continuing into the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know, Michael. You put your hand up, right side so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the percentage of fees, are they well...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The majority of the income is fee-based. I don't know but I can come back &#x2013; I don't know that answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hand the microphone, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Thanks a lot. It's Tom Rayner, Exane BNP. Just on the mid-teens sustainable sort of growth rate in Wholesale Banking income, I mean should we assume that mid-teens growth in Wholesale Banking RWAs will be something else that we should assume or are there other trends in there? I mean, I'm particularly interested in the level of provisions. Currently, they do seem low and I hear what you're saying about the short duration of the book and the trade-driven nature of the book. But if interest rates are starting to pickup in one or two geographies, I'm wondering if that low interest rates might also have been part of the very good credit quality trends you've seen so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we're starting out very comfortable with where we are in terms of our provisioning. Obviously, we are very watchful about the external environment. As I've said, our sort of risk radar is turned full-on because it's quite hard to predict the impact on our markets of all the stuff that is happening in the West. I don't think you should draw a straight line between our expectations of client income growth in wholesale with RWA growth, partly because the Cash Management side of the business is a very improvement driver of the growth as is the whole Financial Markets, FX and trade derivatives, all that sort of stuff. So, it isn't sort of an asset-led growth pattern. The uncertainty in that question, of course, comes back again to the regulatory mix and to the degree to which the equations around how we get some assets &#x2013; RWA get changed in the sort of next wave of regulatory change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I might as well ask you for an ROE target, but I don't suppose you're going to give me one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It seems good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we've said is mid-teens, yes, but we've also...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But in Wholesale...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...tried to be very straightforward and say to you, there are a number of uncertainties out there, of which probably the two most clear are what the regulators are going to do as what &#x2013; more than what they've done already, and also the way the industry reacts to that and the way it prices its products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is a very good question, but it does open up a whole series of all the uncertainty and noise that exists around the industry at the moment predominantly coming...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But mid-teens is group target, I'm just thinking Wholesale versus Consumer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we just set a target for the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the loan percentage, I mean I do, too, re-affirm, reemphasize what Peter says, you look at the Wholesale Bank and we're absolutely not complacent about it, but to reiterate, we have minimal exposures to Level 3 leverage loans, ADS, commercial real estate. We have about $9 billion with an LTV of 56%. 70% almost of the book is under one year and predominantly under six months, so it turns out &#x2013; and it has relatively high levels of collateral attaching to it. The largest concentrator in the industry across our book is 12%, as well the largest industry exposure that we have. So, you look around and you say, absolutely we can get hit and we're not complacent and of course we can get hit, but we're not mono-asset focused. We're not in one market &#x2013; stuck in that one market. We're not major to one industry. We spend a lot of time looking for hidden correlations and working out those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm very conscious I need to get back over here, but I know &#x2013; just give it to Robert and then I'll come back to this side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Robert Law of Nomura. Could I explore three areas briefly, please? Firstly, thanks for the commentary on the margins in Hong Kong. Could I ask you to give us some more broader margin outlook for the group commentary, please? Secondly, could I ask you to talk about the prospects for Wealth in a tougher market environment? I know that's been a strong feature in the first half. Obviously, markets in the Far East aren't as tough as they are here. But can you give us some thoughts around that? And thirdly, on the Consumer Bank, you mentioned there was a recovery <mark type="audio gap" /> (01:18:09).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- but it's not just the net loss, people have less confidence in equity markets. Do you want to take on the general --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's the things we've explained, Robert. We see &#x2013; and we've also announced it over many years about asset margin, and asset margins tend to come by a slight pressure year-on-year and I think you've seen that continue across the blend of Standard Chartered's businesses. And so, I expect that continues in the liability margins. I don't see why we would not continue to see resilience, if not slight continued uptick on the liability margins. So, liability margin at Consumer Bank were up 6 basis points; on second half, up 4 basis points &#x2013; sorry, up on &#x2013; 6 basis points on the first half level; up 4 basis points on the second half level; so some progression there. And EMEA Wholesale Bank, they're up 14 basis points and a bit slower increase since the second half before but there's still uptick coming. So, I think that that trend continues. Overall picture, broadly stable; it all nets to I think broadly stable on a sensible planning view.</p>
          <p>On loan impairment, the loan sales was $51 million. It arises predominantly in Taiwan of about $28 million and Malaysia about $21 million I think. I don't anticipate there being material loan sales, you never quite know but in the second half, perhaps single digit millions coming through. If you split those back out where we're traveling, that's worth 8 basis points on the loan impairment and loss rate. It takes us to about 43 basis points. Why would it move? It moves for mix. And you can see us increase our unsecured. Again, a lot of unsecured is by salary transfers, salary payroll-linked. But I would expect the delinquencies to move up as we change mix. I don't anticipate material change this year, starting to come through probably <mark type="audio gap" /> (01:20:53)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>84% secured or partially secured.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Alex Potter from Berenberg. Can I direct you back towards slide 15, the couple of comments you made about Wholesale Bank revenues? Firstly on ALM, you talked about a sequential sort of a linked half uptick relative to some rising yield curves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us any sense of a geographic split, i.e., where that's coming through and give us any sense of outlook into the second half of the year? And the second question you alluded to Corporate Finance revenues. I think you said deal numbers are up but pricing is under pressure. And there's more competition for bigger deals. Can you again give us any sort of sense of where that competition is falling by geography and whether you'd characterize that as new entrants coming into the market or, should we say, incumbents getting back on their feet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. Just on ALM, I think what I'm signaling is that we'll begin to see some resilience in the local interest rate &#x2013; the ever-present local interest rates that perhaps suggest that the recent history of a level of decline second half on first half is easing a little bit. My expectations for ALM second half is still some single-digit-percentage decline, but fundamentally the yield curves are becoming more helpful.</p>
          <p>As to ALM, it's pretty broad actually. I often say we're essentially managing ALM across about 30 different yield curves, so it's a pretty broad geographic picture. On Corporate Finance, I mean Peter will add to that. India and Africa are the two markets where Corporate Finance income is lower. Africa is predominantly a large ticket deals point, although there is some pressure on margins but it's a lot &#x2013; we simply didn't win the same number of large ticket deals as we did last year &#x2013; I think the first half last year in South Africa and Nigeria where we did very well. In India, it's a mixture of margin pressure, it's a mixture of international banks heading for those deals.</p>
          <p>It's also interestingly the local banks, that we've seen local banks come and price away from us transactions and financing for transactions at very aggressive pricing levels. It partly I think goes to Peter's comment earlier about &#x2013; and this is not those banks, it's the banking sector generally, a differential pace of banks reacting to changing regulations, who's pricing in stressed liquidity equivalently across the industry now and has a very different footprint of competitor reaction to increased regulatory cost and how they're pricing for business. So India was local competition, some international competition. Africa was capital markets...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was also in India there hasn't been a reduction in the volume in the market of bigger deals. But actually &#x2013; and at one level I think the Corporate Finance income is in a sense a higher quality income simply because it's more deals at a smaller average ticket size, which in terms of sort of diversity and resilience is a good thing.</p>
          <p>So, we'll just go one in front, yes, and then we'll come across. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks. It's Rohith Chandra-Rajan, Barclays Capital; a couple of questions please. First on loan growth; so in terms of momentum, Wholesale Bank seems to be maintaining momentum half-on-half; Consumer seems to have slowed to about the half the pace than it did in the second half of last year, as you'd indicated. I'm just wondering what you're &#x2013; and that is across most geographies by the looks of things.</p>
          <p>I was wondering what your expectations are going forward and for both businesses in terms of loan expansion. And then secondly, just on the impairments, you touched on some concerns around India. Looking at the NPL ratios, they're pretty much flat in Consumer and they're actually down half-on-half in Wholesale Bank. Just wondering if you could provide a bit more color about your concerns there and also on the specific bond exposure and how much is your overall exposure you've taken a $53 million write-down against?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to take that &#x2013; you'll take the loan impairments &#x2013; I'll start on the loan growth, the first question. I mean, on Consumer Banking, think you should continue to expect the loan growth to be not dissimilar to the kind of pattern you've seen in the first half because of the approach we've taken on mortgages, which is more about yield than it is about volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the emphasis we're putting on growing unsecured and our SME book, which in terms of actual absolute numbers of loan growth, is less intensive in terms of balance sheet growth. On Wholesale Banking, I mean broadly speaking, you should expect similar kinds of things although I'd repeat what I said before, which is the business isn't lending-driven. So in a sense, the loan growth is a product of what else we're doing for our client and what we're helping them do rather than something we target as an outcome in and on itself.</p>
          <p>Do you want to pick on...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On India; yes, first of all, on the &#x2013; actually from when we were &#x2013; when I was talking to you at the pre-close, one of the areas that has changed from my expectation that we had &#x2013; clearly had capacity as we were thinking forward to the outcome was the impairment line in Wholesale, and in particular it was attached to India in both &#x2013; in two areas. One is a particular bond exposure where relatively late-breaking information we've reacted to quickly and I think very conservatively. So, I think we've taken a prudent provision against a particular counterparty bond exposure and attached to our India business. But we also took the opportunity to think about just the macro slowdown, but where &#x2013; macro pressures and potential slowdown in India and we have chosen to add to a special PIP for India and that was sort of $35 million, which takes the PIP for India to $50 million on a special PIP basis. And that's against a broader slowdown, so from the pre-close to final we actually took an incremental $85 million of impairment attaching to India from what I would be seeing at that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we move across further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's two of you in front; one in front of the other. Okay, do you want to go? And then Peter you can go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. It's Chris Manners from Morgan Stanley. I just had a quick question for you on interbank lending. Looking at page 27, it looks like you've increased your exposure to US, UK and European banks by about a third in the last 12 months from $15 billion to $21 billion, and just wondering how do you see that interbank lending moving and how much exposure do you have to Europe and &#x2013; presuming the cost of ensuring that debt is going up? How are you looking at this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the short answer is we've actually reduced our exposure to Europe and particularly to Eurozone banks. We have shifted more of our interbank placement in two ways; one, we've shifted it more to Asia; and secondly, we've shifted it more to &#x2013; on a secured basis, through repurchase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Substantially, since the end of August last year we have been moving away from &#x2013; we've taken down unsecured European bank exposures by about two-thirds of what they were at the end of August last year to where they were at the end of May. And we've shifted that over to Asian banks, super-nationals and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:29:05), which I think is a very sensible position to be in, given what we're seeing in the USA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So, the increase in that line is basically a shift from European banks, you're actually lending to UK and US banks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you look at overall picture of where we are, you'll see that we're shifting again in the overall mix predominantly out from the Western over towards Asian risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Toeman from HSBC. Just coming back to the client income growth within the Wholesale Bank, which is, as I'm sure you'll recall every year, it's grown at about 20%. A consequence of that is the business has been probably doubled over the last three or four years. And I wondered if some of the slowdown we're seeing is actually a size effect that &#x2013; going back three or four years that you're providing new services that hadn't been provided before. Now the business is on size that growth is going to be pretty much linked to the size of growth in the overall market, and your sort of double-digit expectation might actually prove optimistic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we have completed the build-out of our capabilities. The unfortunate truth is that our clients still have needs that we feel we ought to be able to provide and respond to, but we don't yet have al the capabilities. Somewhere in the world we typically have everything. We don't yet have the full set of capabilities across all of our network. And so, if you think about things like equities or commodities or some of the deep sectoral expertise like in mining, transportation I mentioned, these are things where we, or anchor business, where we have -- parts of the world where we have a fully comprehensive offer but we have other path where we're not quite there yet.</p>
          <p>So, I think there is an opportunity to do significantly more. I also think there is a significant opportunity to penetrate our client franchise more effectively. I think we've done a very, very good job with the top 100 or so clients around the world in terms of becoming more relevant to them and being able to meet a broader set of their needs. But if I look at the next 500 or so, there's still a lot of opportunity. And that's a really sort of important thing about what's happened in the Wholesale Bank. It hasn't been primarily about winning lots of new clients. It's been about deepening our relationship with the existing client franchise. We're not finished with that yet. I would also say that if you look at the sort of history of how Wholesale Banking income pools grow in rapidly growing economies, they typically grow at something of the order of a couple of times GDP growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you don't have to be &#x2013; even if you were assuming, we only grew with economic growth or at least the income pool, if we only grew with the market, these markets are going to grow pretty rapidly. Yes?</p>
          <p>I'm going to try and bring this to an end quite soon but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. George Dallas, F&amp;C Investments. Small simple finance question; how are you calculating your cost of equity and how does that mesh with your returns on equity? And more strategically, you really haven't said much about the Middle East. You've had a single-digit growth there, but in the context of the Arab spring and the fact that all sorts of businesses that deal with that part of the world are getting scrutinized for the direct or indirect linkage to somewhat dubious regimes, how are you managing financial and operational reputational risks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I do the Middle East in person, then you do the cost and equity. We have a good business in the Middle East. As you said, we grew operating profit there in the MESA region 7% on the back of income up 6%. And it's been a difficult &#x2013; it's been a quite challenging period for many of the markets in the Middle East. But actually, if you look at our biggest market, the UAE, the UAE has actually done pretty well and it had double-digit income growth in the first six months of the year. We continue to see opportunities for growth in the Middle East.</p>
          <p>And although the political justifications and all the stuff around Arab spring &#x2013; and it's important to point out that at the moment we have virtually nothing at all in North Africa, which is where most of the Arab spring stuff has happened. So, it hasn't really had that much direct impact on us at all. But although the political turbulence and the impact on business confidence and things like that I think is disruptive in the short term, in the longer term having that part of the world dabble in some political arrangement that allow for more sustainable, equitable growth is as far as we're concerned a good thing. And so, we look at that as being a messy and difficult and obviously quite painful transition, but one which actually offers the prospect of some opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On cost of equity, we have a pretty regular process of reviewing cost of equity. We bring it alongside of a view of weighted average cost of capitals due to our GALCO, and we understand that for a blended basis, what our cost of equity is doing and also what our WAC is doing. We then take that, if we're looking at whether it's small acquisitions or investment opportunities in our portfolio investment processes, and we assess the returns. We go against each of those. To that extent, if we look at a cost of equity or weighted average cost for a particular geographic concentration of any size, we clearly adjust the cost of equity for the idiosyncratic risks for that geography, but it's a pretty regular part of management disciplines to test our investments against cost of equity and weighted average capital cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have an aggregate number as well, but I don't know if we disclose it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. Do we disclose it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know if we disclose it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we disclose it? No, we don't disclose it. It's lower than 13 now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Unless anybody else has a burning desire to ask another question, thank you all for attending this session. I hope you take away, this is another good set of results, ninth record profits and consecutively very broad-based growth across a number of different markets, growth and balance sheet; very robust balance sheet. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>