<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1217655" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-03-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7788</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">John Peace, Acting Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Richard Meddings, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Peter Sands, Group Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="3">Peter Sands</participant>
      <participant id="4">John Peace</participant>
      <participant id="5">Richard Meddings</participant>
      <participant id="6">Ian Smillie</participant>
      <participant id="7">Rohith Chandra-Rajan</participant>
      <participant id="8">Irfan Younus</participant>
      <participant id="9">Robert Sage</participant>
      <participant id="10">Peter Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="11">Leigh Goodwin</participant>
      <participant id="12">John Kirk</participant>
      <participant id="13">Michael Helsby</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, London, and good afternoon Hong Kong. For everyone here in London, it's my pleasure to welcome you to our first results presentation from our new head office in Basinghall Avenue.</p>
          <p>As usual, I will introduce today's presentation and talk about the dividend. Richard will talk through the numbers, and Peter will then discuss how he and the management team are running the bank, the current operating environment and our strategic priorities for 2009. We will then take questions.</p>
          <p>During 2008, we have focused on building balance sheet strength and on our liquidity. We've also continued to invest in the business and to grow, whilst remaining focused on our strategy.</p>
          <p>I can report that Standard Chartered has delivered another year of good income and profit growth in 2008, showing continued progress as a Group across our key markets.</p>
          <p>Operating profit rose 13% to $4.57 billion, income increased 26% to $13.97 billion, and normalized earnings per share were up by 1% to $1.749. The Tier 1 capital ratio has increased from 8.8% to 10.1% and core Tier 1 has increased from 6.6% to 7.6%.</p>
          <p>The events of last year were truly extraordinary, testing to the extreme our industry, regulators, governments and the global economy alike. The uncertainty and the contraction of economies will continue this year, and the situation may even worsen. Our markets are now seeing the effects of the crisis.</p>
          <p>As we outlined in the rights issue prospectus, we are proposing to pay a final dividend which is in line with statements made at the time of the rights issue.</p>
          <p>To deliver record results in this exceptional environment is a great achievement. We believe the best way to continue to deliver shareholder value is through our rigorous focus on Asia, Africa and the Middle East, our prudent approach to liquidity and capital, and our continued discipline in costs and risk management.</p>
          <p>The Board fully supports the prudent approach to balance sheet management taken in 2008 and this will continue in 2009. Do not expect us to deviate from this path as the global economy slows in 2009.</p>
          <p>I've now been a director for a year and a half, first as Deputy Chairman and now as Acting Chairman, and it's been a pleasure to work closely with Peter and the management team. I've been impressed by the depth and quality of our management; and that gives me confidence in this uncertain and fragile environment.</p>
          <p>Since the half year, two Non-Executive Directors have stepped down from the Board. The first of these was Mervyn Davies, now Lord Davies of Abersoch, who led the Group during a period of strong strategic and financial progress. He stepped down as Chairman in January to join the U.K.'s Government as Minister for Trade and Investment after 15 years with the bank, and 11 of these on the Group's Board. We're extremely grateful to Mervyn for the immense contribution he made to the bank's success.</p>
          <p>The second Board member was, of course, Adair, Lord Turner, who was a Non-Executive Director for two years and made an excellent contribution to the Board. Adair left in September upon his appointment as Chair of the Financial Services Authority.</p>
          <p>We wish both of them well in their demanding new roles.</p>
          <p>Before moving on, I would like to reiterate that 2008 was another good year of performance. We have been consistent in our strategy, doing business in markets we know and with products we understand. We have focused on the basics of banking and we have kept true to our values and culture. We are on firm footing for the challenges and opportunities that will come during 2009.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Richard to tell you more about the results; Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Good afternoon, Hong Kong; good morning, London.</p>
          <p>Standard Chartered has had another good year. We are in good shape. Today we will be showing you more detail on key areas, because in this environment we believe it is important to demonstrate a firm grip of the basic foundations of banking; liquidity, capital, risk and costs.</p>
          <p>For Consumer Banking, in particular, I will share with you details of our performance in the fourth quarter of 2008 and the steps we have taken to position the business for 2009. We've also increased disclosure around the Wholesale Banking income stream.</p>
          <p>As a result, the running order of my presentation will be slightly different than usual. I would like to focus on three key things. Firstly, 2008 has been another year of delivery despite the difficulties we are seeing in the external environment. The Group has delivered good double-digit income growth and an increase in earnings per share. Profits are up to $4.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Secondly, the foundations of the Group remain in excellent shape. Our capital position is strong and has been strengthened further by our rights issue. The bank is very liquid, the balance sheet is in excellent shape, conservatively positioned and we have a firm grip of risk and costs.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we believe these strong foundations, coupled with the diversity of the business, both by geography and product, will position us well to face the continuing challenges of economic turbulence in 2009.</p>
          <p>Turning to performance; at a Group level, income has grown 26% during 2008, driven by excellent momentum in Wholesale Banking with income growth of 43%. Consumer Banking income grew 3% and was impacted in the second half by the slowdown in Wealth Management income.</p>
          <p>On an underlying basis, by which I mean excluding the impact of American Express Bank, Group income grew by 21%. Organic growth was again the driver of year-on-year income growth, delivering $2.3 billion out of the total $2.9 billion increase in income.</p>
          <p>Expenses have grown 22%, resulting in positive jaws of 4%. On an underlying basis, expenses have grown by 13%, again resulting in strongly positive jaws of 8%. On an underlying basis, the monthly run rate for expenses in the second half of 2008 was 7% lower than in the first half of 2008, as a result of both FX but also a strong focus on costs.</p>
          <p>Also included on the face of the P&amp;L is a gain of $233 million in relation to a derivative that was created at the time of our rights issue. This accounting peculiarity, driven by IAS 32 is normalized from earnings per share and does not impact capital or distributable reserves. For the purpose of performance, none of my metrics presented today will include it, just ignore it; a full explanation is given in note seven of the accounts.</p>
          <p>Operating profit of $4.6 billion was up 13% on 2007.</p>
          <p>Following the rights issue, there are some mechanistic changes required to earnings and dividends per share. For the purposes of clarity, we have shown here the pre and post rights numbers for these metrics to reflect the change in the number of shares. Normalized EPS grew 1%. Normalized return on equity is within our target range of mid to high teens.</p>
          <p>As you look at the performance, there are several themes to identify which, to some extent, compensate for each other. Firstly, there are some one-off items.</p>
          <p>Income in 2008 have benefited from the buyback of upper Tier 2 floating rate notes totally $384 million, as well as the profit on the sale of the asset management company in India, totally $146 million. These items are normalized from earnings per share. There are also some performance-related items that you should listen out for, which I will identify as I move through the presentation.</p>
          <p>In Korea, there is the impact of the hedging asymmetry and also some expense provision release. Secondly, charges we have taken against derivatives contracts across the Group, but again mainly in Korea. Thirdly, the level of equity write-downs included in other impairment. And finally, lower realizations to income from Principal Finance.</p>
          <p>Now the balance sheet; the balance sheet is conservatively positioned. The capital and liquidity profile reflects the financial health of the Group and is a source of competitive strength. We remain a flight to quality institution and have continued to see substantial deposit growth in both businesses, up 30% year on year or 9% since the half year.</p>
          <p>We continue to gather deposits and view them, particularly in these times, as a core strength of the Group.</p>
          <p>Our focus on liabilities and disciplined deployment of the balance sheet has again resulted in the ratio of customer loans to customer deposits, the A/D ratio, improving, moving from 86% last year to 75%. A/D ratios in all of our major geographies are under 100%. The Group remains a very strong net interbank lender and the liquidity ratio is strong at 23%.</p>
          <p>Our loan book is well diversified; by country and by sector. The Group's balance sheet has limited exposure to problem asset classes.</p>
          <p>Capital; the Group's strong capital position continues to improve. Core equity is a comfortable 7.6%, Tier 1 at 10.1% and total capital at 15.6% are well above our stated targets.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of the rights issue, the Group's core equity ratio increased by about 20 basis points in the second half of the year, driven in part by the disciplined management of risk weighted assets, which grew only 2% year on year.</p>
          <p>In summary, the Group enters 2009 well capitalized and with the liquidity necessary to deploy that capital. We have the capacity to do business and we are open for the right business.</p>
          <p>Turning to geographic performance; trading conditions in the Group's main operating markets are increasingly challenging. The macroeconomic backdrop has deteriorated, with a sharp slowdown in actual and forecast GDP growth rates and markedly lower trade volumes over the year-end period. However, the number of banks providing finance in our markets has fallen, providing us with increased opportunities to deepen relationships with existing clients, to increase our market share and to improve margins.</p>
          <p>Against this challenging economic backdrop, income and profit performance for the Group has been broad based and strong. Hong Kong has again delivered double-digit income growth, but profits fell 15% as impairment increased and Wealth Management fell sharply in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Singapore had an outstanding year with income up 60% year on year, with Wholesale excellent, and Consumer very strong across a broad spread of products, and profits were up 67%.</p>
          <p>In Korea, we continue to reshape the business to good effect. Although income grew by 1% on a headline basis, momentum is good and profit before tax grew 10% as expenses fell and we'll come back to this later.</p>
          <p>Other APR, which includes geographies such as Taiwan, Thailand, Indonesia and China, saw income growing 16%. Income in China grew rapidly, up 27% to $632 million. We continue to invest in products and channel distribution, expanding outlets from 38 to 54 in 2008. However, operating profit in China fell 62% to $70 million, with a contribution from Principal Finance in Wholesale Banking significantly lower and Consumer Banking making a sizeable loss given the impact of our investment program. As a result in other APR, profit before tax fell 19%.</p>
          <p>In India, the business continues to thrive. Operating profit was up 37% driven by very strong income growth of 33%. This includes the gain on the sale of our asset management company, which is not allocated to either business. Consumer Banking has delivered double-digit income growth of 19%, whilst Wholesale Banking in India has delivered another strong performance with income up 24%.</p>
          <p>Middle East and other South Asia, or MESA, had strong income growth of 21%, both UAE and Bahrain saw income growth of over 35%. Pakistan's income, however, fell as we reduced our risk appetite in the Consumer Banking business.</p>
          <p>In Africa, profit grew 5% on income, up 14% with Nigeria performing particularly well with income up 30%.</p>
          <p>You will notice again that the Americas, U.K. and Europe region is showing a substantial loss. You should bear in mind that a charge to profit of $41 million, relating to the asset backed securities portfolio and a charge of $220 million predominately arising from the strategic investment portfolio have been taken here. Expenses in this region have grown by over 70%, reflecting the inclusion of AEB, increased levels of head count, as well as new investment.</p>
          <p>Now Consumer Banking performance; in the course of 2008, the Consumer Banking business changed its focus to become more customer centric and to increase its productivity. It has focused on building its resilience to meet the rising economic challenges by driving efficiencies through attacking its cost base, repositioning its books more on its secured business, increasing collections capacity and building further liquidity with significant success.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking delivered income growth of 3% and expense growth of 13%, with operating profit before tax down 33% to just over $1.1 billion. Underlying income fell by 2%. Wealth Management income, which grew 6% year on year, slowed sharply in the second half as investors became more risk averse.</p>
          <p>SME has performed well with income growing by 8%. In difficult market conditions, we have repositioned the book increasing the proportion of secured lending and adjusting pricing to reflect the risk environment. Around 60% of the SME book is secured. SME remains a liability-led business with deposits almost twice the level of loan balances.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking margins have fallen. Asset margins have reduced in key markets. In Hong Kong, this reflected lower prime HIBOR spread, as well as competition. In Korea and other markets, it reflects the de-risking of our unsecured portfolios. Although overall liability margins remain constant, they fluctuated throughout the year and fell in the final quarter.</p>
          <p>Expenses grew 13%, with significant majority of this related to AEB. As a result, Consumer Banking produced negative jaws of 10%. Underlying jaws, however, are tighter at negative 5%.</p>
          <p>In light of the softening revenue horizon, we have taken firm action on expenses. Deposit gathering has been an area of focus for the Consumer Banking business, and through a series of initiatives this has resulted in strong growth in liabilities. Liabilities grew 16% or $18 billion since December 2007, driven by a series of successful deposit campaigns, as well as an expansion of our Internet and mobile phone banking offering.</p>
          <p>Turning to Wealth Management; Wealth Management has seen contrasting performances in the two halves of 2008. Although income grew 6% year on year, in the first half of the year Wealth Management income grew 23% or $278 million, whereas in the second half of the year income fell 14% or $211 million on the first half.</p>
          <p>At the end of the third quarter, customers moved into cash deposits sacrificing yield for greater security. This is shown on the slide, which, for clarity, excludes the impact of deposit income.</p>
          <p>It is our view that in the medium term, there remains a strong demand for wealth management products given the naturally high savings levels, limited social security net, and, in some cases, capped savings rates. Wealth Management remains an important income stream for the Consumer Banking business, contributing 47% of total Consumer Banking income for the full year.</p>
          <p>Moving on to expenses; as the revenue horizon softened in the first half, we initiated a series of cost reduction initiatives with first half expenses held broadly flat on the second half of 2007.</p>
          <p>With the outlook for the Wealth Management business deteriorating in the second half, we have accelerated these cost-efficiency measures, resulting in a decrease of costs in the second half of the year over the first half of 6%. Around half of this decrease results with the impact of the depreciation in the Korean won.</p>
          <p>Even though underlying expenses have grown only $99 million in 2008, the strong cost discipline has allowed us to absorb over $270 million of investment for future growth. We have continued to invest selectively across the franchise. New investment in 2008, which halved in the second half of the year over the first, has focused on distribution with over 80 new branches and over 1,200 new ATMs, primarily in Korea, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia and Africa.</p>
          <p>Importantly, we enter 2009 with our BAU costs, including AEB expenses, running lower than the level at which we entered 2008.</p>
          <p>Turning to impairment; the Consumer Banking loan impairment charge has increased from $736 million to $937 million, with an increase of 27% in the second half of the year over the first half. We have been for some time repositioning our book, tightening our underwriting standards, significantly increasing collection resources and collateral requirements. Just over 20% of the Consumer Banking balance sheet is now in unsecured products.</p>
          <p>On the mortgage book, the average LTV is at just over 50%, with some two-thirds of assets concentrated in Hong Kong and Korea, where the maximum LTV is restricted at 70% and 60% respectively, providing a significant cushion to cope with declines in property values.</p>
          <p>As result of the impact that the deteriorating environment in some of our markets has had on portfolio indicators, the charge for portfolio impairment provision, or PIP, has increased significantly. Now, let me share with you a little more detail.</p>
          <p>There are some simple themes that come from this complex slide and, as I talk, we will highlight some numbers on the screen to draw out the key points.</p>
          <p>The first three quarters show stable loan impairment across the three main asset categories. This remains true in mortgages in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>In SME, there are two features; the decreasing size of the portfolio as we rein in risk appetite. And the second feature is the sharp rise in Q4 impairment, which amounts to some $40 million in total, arising mainly in Korea, Hong Kong and a small increase in the UAE. The increase was primarily driven by the business installment loans unsecured portfolio due to the deterioration in the external environment.</p>
          <p>In other loans, there is a doubling of impairment in the fourth quarter. Of this, there are some individual items in AEB, which contribute around half of the increase, as well as some specific operational issues rather than impairment flow in the UAE.</p>
          <p>So looking at the increase of some $200 million year on year, around a third comes from AEB and the remainder results from the deteriorating credit environment with 40% of the $200 million movement coming from the increased portfolio impairment provision and some $50 million as a result of specific provisions.</p>
          <p>When thinking about the trend into 2009, you should consider that the fourth quarter charge in 2008 included a number of one-off items. You should also bear in mind the consumer will continue its mix shift towards secured products. We are currently tracking towards a quarter one loan impairment charge some 80 to $100 million lower than the $355 million seen in quarter four.</p>
          <p>To summarize for Consumer Banking overall; slowing income in a difficult environment, but met with strong cost discipline; sound asset quality with enhanced risk positioning and collections capability. Consumer Banking is more resilient and its balance sheet is in better shape to face the challenges of 2009.</p>
          <p>Turning to Wholesale Banking; 2008 was an exceptional year for Wholesale Banking with broad based top line growth driven by strong momentum in client revenues and this is in the context of a very difficult economic environment. Tight management of capital, liquidity and risk have been key enablers of growth and a differentiating competitive factor.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking operating profit grew 28% on income that grew 43% headline, or 37% excluding AEB. Expenses rose 34% or 25% underlying, given profit-related remuneration and selective investment in key product capability. But growth has remained below income growth, delivering strongly positive jaws.</p>
          <p>In the second half, expenses fell 6%, or 9% underlying over the first half of the year, reflecting disciplined and selective investment, a firm control of the BAU expense base, and reduced performance-related pay.</p>
          <p>Impairment has increased, reflecting the deteriorating external environment. We continue to be disciplined in managing the relationship between risk weighted assets and income growth with an ongoing focus on origination and distribution of assets. Our markets are very much open for business and we enter 2009 with good momentum. The external environment is becoming more difficult, but the breadth of our income streams and the depth of our relationships position us well.</p>
          <p>Income; client income growth remained robust at 25% excluding AEB and is driven by strong growth across all client segments. Client income contributes some 75% of total Wholesale Banking income.</p>
          <p>To the client lend, the Global Corporates segment grew income at 25%, Financial Institutions at 40%, Local Corporates at 31% and our Commodity segment at 69%. These are good deltas.</p>
          <p>Looking through the product lend, Lending and Portfolio Management income grew 3%, Transaction Banking grew 31% and Global Markets achieved 60% growth with strong growth across a broad range of products.</p>
          <p>Let me show you some new disclosure, which reflects the way we run the business. Now this slide shows the breadth of income growth across all income streams. As in previous periods, client income continues to be the predominate driver of total Wholesale Banking income. Effective collaboration across our network has again proved to be a powerful competitive advantage. We've also taken the opportunity to price up across multiple geographies and across multiple products.</p>
          <p>Trade and cash, which are core to the Wholesale Bank product offering, grew strongly year on year, but also importantly, second half of 2008 on the first half reflecting strong client demand.</p>
          <p>Although trade volumes have fallen globally, Trade Finance capacity across the industry has fallen more rapidly and we have been well positioned to take market share as the number of participants in our market decreases. As a result, trade NIMs have increased and volumes were up over 40%.</p>
          <p>Global Markets had another strong year, and we've taken the opportunity to provide additional disclosure this year to demonstrate the breadth of this business. Global Markets is a predominately client driven business, with proprietary position taking forming a relatively small proportion of Group income.</p>
          <p>Within Global Markets, there are four main product streams. Financial Markets provide end to end financial services for clients such as FX and interest rate risk management and capital markets, and I'll talk about this on the next slide.</p>
          <p>As expected, ALM income has softened in the second half of the year following an extremely strong first half.</p>
          <p>Corporate Finance includes corporate advisory, structured trade finance, project and export finance, and structured finance, and we have built this business from scratch over the past six years, and enjoyed a strong year with the income up over 60% to just under $750 million and pipelines remain good.</p>
          <p>Our Principal Finance business has a strong track record of creating value through its investments. Realizations have been slower in 2008, with income down 37% to $253 million and we have also taken impairment of some $171 million against this book. We remain confident in the underlying quality of the portfolio.</p>
          <p>Looking at financial markets further; income in Financial Markets increased 79% to over $2.3 billion with 77% of this being client income. Our traditional Trade and Cash businesses, which have seen significant volume increases during 2008, provide significant flow to the Rates and FX business, and clients have been more proactive in hedging their risks. Overall, FX income grew 17% with rates increasing almost five fold.</p>
          <p>Commodity and Equities are relatively new businesses in which we have been investing over the past two years; income was up 188% growing from $49 million to $141 million.</p>
          <p>Capital Markets saw good levels of origination in Asia Pacific syndicated loans and Asian local currency bonds, where we consistently rank in the top three of the league tables.</p>
          <p>Moving into 2009, we see opportunities to increase volumes and market share, with the ability to improve margins further as the competitive landscaped has significantly contracted, hence the loan impairment.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking loan impairment was a net charge of $384 million to the income statement, up from $25 million in 2007. This includes derivative-related impairments of some $140 million, the largest of these being in Korea. As anticipated, recoveries reduced marginally year on year.</p>
          <p>We remain vigilant and have benefited from pro-active and robust risk management. We are increasingly looking to use collateral to improve the risk position whilst we regularly stress test our books for a variety of scenarios.</p>
          <p>Early alert, our early warning system has, however, risen strongly from the previously very low levels, reflecting the difficult macroeconomic conditions although they remain without any particular geographic or industry concentration. Only a small proportion of these early alerts represent genuine credit concerns.</p>
          <p>The cover ratio has fallen to 61%, but including collateral is just under 75%, and reflects the impairment of a number of accounts against which we are confident of a high level of recovery. The risk profile is well diversified with no material exposures to those asset classes that have caused such mayhem to the Western banks. Overall, Wholesale Banking has delivered another strong set of results with record levels of income growth, a strong grip on costs, and focused management of risk.</p>
          <p>Turning to other impairment. Other impairment has increased significantly year-on-year primarily due to a number of equity investments where as a result of dislocation in the financial markets the market value has fallen significantly below the investment cost for some time.</p>
          <p>We had at the end of October indicated an anticipated charge of some $300 million. The impairment charge associated with these assets was $357 million for the full year of which 171 million was taken against the private equity portfolio and 186 million was taken against the strategic investment portfolio.</p>
          <p>The majority of this charge is a revaluation rather than permanent impairment and we remain confident that these portfolios continue to be attractive on fundamentals. Other impairment also includes $41 million of impairment on asset-backed securities and a $60 million provision in respect of exposure to an individual Western financial institution.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to Korea. Korea has been an area of considerable focus during 2008 Korea's change program is on track and we are making good progress. The business is increasingly well balanced and is performing well despite the impact of a significant depreciation of the Korean won.</p>
          <p>On a headline basis, income grew 1% and operating profit by 10%. Consumer Banking income fell 11% year-on-year, whilst Wholesale Banking income grew 34%. Consumer Banking income was affected by falling demand for Wealth Management products as well as the impact of de-risking of the SME book. As we'd said it would, the hedging asymmetry has partially unwound resulting in a net gain to income of $56 million in 2008 against a net charge of $155 million in 2007.</p>
          <p>On a constant currency basis, income grew by 18% overall, 4% in Consumer Banking, and 55% in Wholesale Banking. On a reported basis, expenses fell 17%, although adjusting for the impact of currency expenses were broadly flat. We have invested in productivity and efficiency saves, refurbished, and relocated branches, and broadened the Wholesale Banking product suite.</p>
          <p>Existing head count has been reduced by approximately 5% over the course of the year amounting to some 300 individuals. And this has been funded by a release of a provision in the second half of the year of some $65 million. A larger number of individuals have been redeployed from the head office into sales roles.</p>
          <p>Loan impairment has increased from $94 million in 2007 to $263 million in 2008. Half of the increase relates to impairments taken on knock-in knock-out, or KIKO options, an industry-wide issue related to FX hedging products. Loan impairment for KIKOs was some $79 million, with an additional $121 million taken as contract income. There has also been some increase in impairment primarily relating to the SME sector.</p>
          <p>Taiwan, in Taiwan profits fell by 7%. We have invested further in people and systems and expanded our branch footprint both through the acquisition of AEB and particularly Asia Trust. We are disappointed, however, that we have not met the financial objectives we set at the time of the acquisition of Hsinchu even though this is for understandable reasons. Costs and loan impairment remain under good control, but the turmoil in the Wealth Management market, which represents some 33% of Hsinchu's income, has meant that Hsinchu is not yet either EPS accretive nor has it yet delivered double-digit return on investment.</p>
          <p>Strategically, expanding our presence in Taiwan, given its importance in northeast Asia and its growing links with mainland China, is absolutely the right thing to do. And we remain confident of the long-term growth prospects of both Hsinchu and Taiwan.</p>
          <p>Turning to American Express Bank. We have made good progress in the integration of AEB, and have amalgamated in 47 of the 48 countries in which AEB operates. In terms of performance, AEB delivered $552 million of income during the 10 months of ownership in 2008, and profit before integration expense was $33 million. Revenue slowed in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>In Wholesale Banking, we saw pressure on cash NIMs and falling volumes in the last quarter of the year. In Consumer Banking, Wealth Management had a difficult second half as customers moved from investment products into lower yielding cash deposits.</p>
          <p>Integration expenses were $157 million in 2008 as projected, resulting in a loss of $124 million for the full year, slightly more than the $100 million indicated in the pre-close. We are now increasingly confident that we will be able to realize cost synergies of over $130 million in 2009. In addition, 2009 will see a substantial fall in integration expenses to some $70 million.</p>
          <p>Now we acquired a lending portfolio of some $5 billion and it's perhaps unsurprising that in these stressful times some clients end up in difficulties, and we suffered some individual credit related impairment charges. We remain confident of EPS accretion and double-digit return on investment in 2009, and expect a strong delta in 2009 profit before tax of over $200 million.</p>
          <p>Balance sheet. The Group remains strongly liquid both in part and as a whole with a diverse and growing funding base. Current accounts and savings accounts, or CASA, grew by some $17 billion, with time deposits growing $40 billion. Total deposits grew 30%. This strong liquidity position enables us to continue to deepen relationships with existing customers as liquidity from their other lenders dries up.</p>
          <p>Assets. Our balance sheet remains a source of strength for the Group. We have low loan to values on our mortgage book with an average LTV of just over 50%. Our charge-off rate on this portfolio in 2008 was some four basis points for the year. A short maturity profile on our wholesale loan book with over 70% of the book under one year. We have low concentrations to problematic classes such as ABS, commercial real estate, level three assets, and leveraged loans. Overall exposures are well spread over geography and sector, with no material concentrations. The balance sheet remains robust and well diversified.</p>
          <p>Now ABS. The first two columns are gross exposures and do not reflect the impact of either impairments or marks. The third column shows the carrying value on the balance sheet including the effect of asset redesignation after adjusting for both marks and impairment as at the end of 2008. We're also showing the average marks at the end of Q3 and Q4.</p>
          <p>In the year, we have seen redemptions approaching $1.2 billion, resulting in a write-back to income of around $11 million reflecting the recovery of earlier lower marks. In addition, we have sold around $500 million of ABS for a loss of 34 million.</p>
          <p>As we have previously stated, the Group has no direct exposure to U.S. sub-prime and extremely limited indirect exposure. We remain confident of the overall quality of this book. Only approximately 5% of the portfolio or $208 million gross exposure is in ABS CDOs, and this portfolio is marked at $0.14 in the dollar.</p>
          <p>Net exposure of some $3.8 billion shown in the third column is less than 1% of Group assets. During the year, we reclassified some $8 billion of assets, of which $4 billion related to the ABS portfolio. If this redesignation had not occurred, Group profit before tax would have been lower by some $381 million, of which 102 million relates to ABS and AFS reserves would have been lower by $410 million all of which relates to ABS. Full details are shown in note 11 of the accounts.</p>
          <p>Turning now to 2009 and outlook. Whilst the world is uncertain, we are in good shape managing tightly and very vigilant. 2009 has started well. Wholesale Banking has had a very strong January with income broad based and well above the levels seen in the same month last year. Trade finance had a record month and trading benefited from wider spreads. Wholesale Banking continues to benefit from increasing market share February is also strong.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking has had a steady start to the year with income running slightly, but not materially, below the average run rate of the second half of 2008. The outlook for Consumer Banking depends in part on the timing of the recovery in Wealth Management and general levels of consumer confidence.</p>
          <p>We will continue to gather deposits and focus on liquidity strength, and we will maintain a strong capital position. We have taken a proactive approach to risk and positioned our loan books defensively into the economic downturn. We are keeping a very firm grip on the costs.</p>
          <p>Disciplined execution of our strategy, our diverse income streams, and deep client relationships and effective management of capital, liquidity, and risk remain key to success in 2009.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And now I'll hand over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. Good morning all of you in London and good afternoon to all of you in Hong Kong. Richard has given you, I think, a good sense of the numbers. It's quite a complex picture, but what should come through is the underlying strength of our businesses and the overall resilience of the bank.</p>
          <p>I'm going to talk about just three things. First, how we've been running the bank, i.e., what underpins the results that Richard has explained. Second what we see going on in our markets as the crisis unfolds. And finally, our strategic priorities for 2009.</p>
          <p>We've been running the bank according to four fundamental tenets. First, we've stuck to our strategy. We want to be the world's best international bank leading the way in Asia, Africa and the Middle East. As you can imagine, we've been offered all sorts of opportunities but we believe our focused strategy is critical to our success, and it will take a lot to tempt us to change it.</p>
          <p>We do business in markets we understand intimately with customers with whom we have longstanding relationships, selling products we understand fully. That way we know the risks we take. It doesn't mean they'll all play our way, but we know what were doing. Second, we have been and will remain very focused on the basics of banking; on liquidity, capital, risks, operational control, and costs. Perhaps because we've always operated in volatile markets, we have never lost sight of such disciplines.</p>
          <p>Third, we're open for business. We want to support our clients as they navigate the economic turmoil. We want to seize the opportunities arising from the turbulence. Whilst we have taken action in response to the crisis, we've not just hunkered down. We continue to invest for growth.</p>
          <p>And finally, we've stayed true to our values and culture. Standard Chartered is a rather different bank and we want to keep it like that. We run as one bank across geographies and businesses. We're focused on customers, not transactions. We're playing the long game. Our values and culture are key to our competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>I said we're focused on the basics. Let me talk a bit more about what I mean by this and what we've been doing differently.</p>
          <p>First, liquidity. Since banks borrow short and lend long, liquidity risk is inherent to the business. We take a conservative approach to liquidity keeping our asset to deposit ratio well below 100% and regularly stress testing for different scenarios. Since the crisis started in August 2007, we've put even more focus on liquidity gathering sticky customer deposits and keeping a relatively short asset profile.</p>
          <p>American Express Bank, AEB, made a useful contribution adding net $14 billion in customer and bank deposits. As the markets continued to deteriorate during 2008, we put even more emphasis on reinforcing our liquidity profile benefiting from customers' flight to quality. To give one example, we grew customer deposits in Hong Kong by 31% last year to $64 billion.</p>
          <p>Of course, it's not just the quantum of deposits that count, but the pricing and behavioral maturity, the stickiness. Consumer Banking savings and Transaction Banking capabilities with innovative products and extensive network of branches and ATMs, and Internet and mobile banking are powerful drivers of local and foreign currency deposit gathering. In fact, Consumer Banking overall contributes over $40 billion in net liabilities.</p>
          <p>But Wholesale Banking isn't just a user of liquidity. It too has powerful deposit generating capabilities, such as our Cash Management and Custody businesses, which grew balances by 24% to $64 billion in 2008.</p>
          <p>Deposits are just one side of the liquidity equation. The other is what you do with them. Over 70% of our Wholesale Banking assets are under one year in tenure. We continue to be a net lender to the interbank markets. The strength of our liquid assets ratio at 23% demonstrates the resilience and flexibility of our balance sheet. Today, we have over $100 billion of liquid assets.</p>
          <p>We've taken a similarly proactive approach to managing our capital position. In the second half of 2008, we faced a complex situation with rapid changes in investor and regulatory expectations about capital levels, particularly core equity, severe stress across the banking sector, unprecedented volatility in financial markets, and a deteriorating economic outlook.</p>
          <p>We did not rush to raise new equity. Diluting our shareholders or asking them for new money is not a step we'd take lightly. But at the end of November, we decided to launch a preemptive rights issue. As we explained at the time, we did this for three reasons. To respond to the change in investor sentiment about required levels of capital, to give us a buffer in a deteriorating environment, and to give us greater room to take advantage of the potential opportunities we see.</p>
          <p>We are very appreciative of the high level of support we received for the rights issue, 97%. And given the way the world has turned since then, it was clearly the right decision. We entered 2009 very well capitalized. And it's perhaps worth pointing out that this is not just because of the rights issue. Even without it and despite the negative impact of the depreciation of the Korean won and Indian rupee, our Tier 1 and core equity capital ratios would have been stronger at the end of December than at the half year.</p>
          <p>This is partly due to retained earnings and partly due to how we use risk capital, which we reduced by 7% in the second half. In fact, during 2008, Wholesale Banking grew client income by 31% and risk weighted assets by only 4%, evidence of an extremely disciplined approach to capital deployment and utilization.</p>
          <p>Richard has already given you a flavor of our asset quality; conservative, diverse, well collateralized, and mainly of short tenure. But we remain vigilant. Throughout 2007 and 2008, we have continued to tighten underwriting standards and reduce unsecured exposures.</p>
          <p>We've taken tough decisions on customers, for example, preemptively exiting over 900 middle market clients. We've taken tough decisions on products, for example, halving the rate of new booking for business installment loans, our unsecured products for SMEs. These decisions have an immediate negative impact on income, but they are the right thing to do.</p>
          <p>In Consumer Banking, we've been tilting the mix from unsecured to secured. Around some 60% of the portfolio is in mortgages with an average LTV of just over 50%, and even in Q4 an annualized loss rate of only five basis points.</p>
          <p>In Wholesale Banking, we've been very active in repricing and restructuring transactions as they refinance. Given the economic deterioration, it's hardly surprising that the average probability of default for the Wholesale Banking portfolio increased from 57 to 68 basis points. Yet because of the way we've restructured transactions and strengthened collateral, the weighted average loss given default has improved from 37 to 30%. Risk pricing has improved markedly.</p>
          <p>We've also been very focused on the management of operational risk. This is about avoiding losses from system or process failures, documentation errors, fraud, compliance issues and so on. Run a bank through a financial crisis and every operational weakness gets exposed. So we've been very active in identifying potential loose rivets and tightening up every aspect of how we run the bank.</p>
          <p>The obvious gaps or flaws are easy to spot and fix. What's harder are things that work well in a relatively benign environment, but prove inadequate under stress or extreme volatility.</p>
          <p>This is painstaking granular work. Like so much in banking, the devil is in the detail. I am not seeking to avoid risk. Banking is a risk-taking business. But we need to ensure we are consistently taking the right risks, that we understand them fully and that we are managing them as effectively as we can.</p>
          <p>We're taking a similarly disciplined approach to cost management. Reflecting our dynamic approach to costs, both businesses reduced costs in the second half. Flexing costs in response to slowing income and rising impairment does not mean we've stopped or will stop investing. On the contrary, we are determined to continue to invest in growing our businesses so that we can really turn this turmoil to our advantage. But to be able to do this, we have to be extremely disciplined, cutting out waste and nice-to-haves.</p>
          <p>We can't the dodge the tough decisions on investment priorities, on underperforming businesses and on people. This disciplined approach to the basics of banking is essential, given the continued uncertainties in the economic environment.</p>
          <p>Looking at the world economy as a whole, perhaps the central fact is that no one really knows what's going on and what's going to happen next. The crisis continues to unfold at extraordinary pace and in unpredictable ways.</p>
          <p>For example, we anticipated the impact on Asia from the decline in demand for exports, but we were surprised by the speed and extent of the downturn. And now, when you look at forecasters' predictions for economic growth across the region, they're all over the place.</p>
          <p>Yet some things are clear. Our markets in Asia, Africa, and the Middle East are experiencing a sharp cyclical slowdown. But they don't face the structural deleveraging afflicting Western markets. As a result, the Asian downturn should be much shorter.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, while Asian banks are feeling the stress, as dollar liquidity has dried up and the credit environment has deteriorated, they are on the whole, in much better shape than many counterparts in the West. The ingredients of the banking crisis in the U.K. and the U.S., the over leverage, the over complexity, the opacity, simply aren't present to nearly the same extent.</p>
          <p>It's also unwise to draw too many analogies to the Asian crisis of the late '90s. In fact, the resilience of Asia owes much to lessons learnt from that experience. This time most countries have substantial FX reserves and strong fiscal positions. This time most corporates have relatively conservative balance sheets.</p>
          <p>Asian governments have also responded much more quickly to stimulate their economies and ease liquidity pressures. These actions will take time to have an impact and some measures will undoubtedly be more effective than others, but the sheer scale of the policy response is impressive.</p>
          <p>Moreover, it's important to look beyond the immediate crisis. Whilst the near-term economic conditions have deteriorated sharply across virtually all our markets, they remain fundamentally attractive. With young, increasingly well-educated populations, a growing middle class, rapid urbanization, and continuing industrialization, our markets in Asia, Africa, and the Middle East still offer enormous potential for the long term.</p>
          <p>In fact, the crisis will almost certainly accelerate the shift in economic power from West to East. We're in the right markets and we'll stay focused on them. Given the uncertainties, we need to be flexible and adaptive, anticipating and responding to the extraordinary changes around us.</p>
          <p>However, some things will not change. We have a clear and consistent strategy to become the world's best international bank, leading the way in Asia, Africa, and the Middle East. It's well understood by customers, by staff, by regulators and policymakers and by you, our investors. It works. We'll stick with it.</p>
          <p>We'll also keep the focus on the basics of banking, on the way we manage capital, liquidity, risks, operational, control, and costs. And we'll stay open for business. In fact, we see many opportunities to deepen our relationships with clients, take market share and improve margins. Many of our competitors are distracted by problems or withdrawing to focus on their home markets. That's how we will turn the turmoil to our advantage.</p>
          <p>Our two businesses do start the year with very different priorities. In Wholesale Banking, it's all about sustaining the momentum after such a strong performance in 2008. In Consumer Banking, it's about reshaping the business to rekindle income and profit growth. Mike Rees and the Wholesale Banking team had a very successful 2008. Almost every business put in a strong performance.</p>
          <p>Our strategy of deepening client relationships continued to deliver results. Income from the top 50 clients grew 45% and the number of clients with annual income over $10 million increased by 88%. Building bigger, deeper relationships with our clients will continue to be the key driver of growth in 2009.</p>
          <p>Despite the success we've had in building new, more sophisticated businesses, almost 60% of Wholesale Banking's income arises from what might be described as Classic Commercial Banking, trade finance, lending, cash management, plus directly related FX and hedging transactions. This is the core of our franchise. And while overall market volumes will be under pressure as economies slow, we are winning market share and increasing margins significantly.</p>
          <p>The balance of Wholesale Banking's business is split pretty evenly between what we described as value added and strategic client business, such as corporate finance, capital markets, structured and project finance, and own account.</p>
          <p>Despite the slowdown in economic activity, the pipeline for value added and strategic activity remains resilient.</p>
          <p>Competition is disappearing faster than demand.</p>
          <p>Roughly, half of own account income is ALM with the remainder a mixture of trading off customer flows and private equity. While the individual components are quite volatile, in 2008, ALM increased by over 80% and private equities fell sharply. Aggregate own account income has been fairly constant between 20 to 25% of overall Wholesale Banking income over the last few years.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking. Steve Bertamini took over Consumer Banking at the beginning of June, and he and his team have now embarked on a radical reshaping of the business. We are accelerating the shift from a very product focused model to a much more customer-oriented approach. Our current cost sell ratio is only 1.4 products per customers. That's not good enough. So we're putting much greater focus on product bundles tailored to specific segment needs, to relationship pricing and to relationship management rather than simply sales.</p>
          <p>We are also improving productivity and customer service through a series of reengineering projects, including call center consolidation, and by standardizing system platforms, processes, and products. Too much local variation has got in the way of efficiency where cutting costs while still investing.</p>
          <p>We are taking a much more proactive stance towards the balance sheet, attracting current and savings accounts with improved transactional services, reinforcing Consumer Banking's ability to be a powerful liability gathering engine for the bank as a whole.</p>
          <p>We're taking a more defensive stance on risk, shifting the asset mix towards more secured products enhancing our scorecards and collection capabilities. We are reconfiguring the Wealth Management business. Whilst demand for wealth products will come back at some point as consumers regain confidence, it's not going to be the same. We are shifting to more of a portfolio management approach.</p>
          <p>And finally, we're implementing a new participation model that puts more discipline on what business we do in each market and aligns the cost structure and risk approach accordingly. The change agenda in Consumer Banking is ambitious and far reaching and we have to execute it in a very difficult market environment. I don't underestimate the scale of the task, but I am confident that we are doing the right things and that we will reshape the business for sustainable growth and competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>While it's important to talk about the individual businesses, it's also important to recognize that we run Standard Chartered as one bank. The two businesses depend on each other for balance sheet, products, client referrals, and shared infrastructure. We need both to succeed.</p>
          <p>In this context, I often get asked about the balance between our businesses; am I concerned about the increasing strengths of Wholesale Banking relative to Consumer Banking? The short answer is, not really. We do want the bank to be broadly balanced with two strong engines of growth, but we're not going to get there by making Wholesale slow down. The trick is to get Consumer to speed up. And there were many parallels between what we are doing to reshape Consumer Banking now and what we did in Wholesale Banking some years ago.</p>
          <p>Our emphasis on balance between Wholesale and Consumer Banking, between short-term and long-term, between profit and loss and the balance sheet is perhaps why we have been able to weather the storm so well, why we are still around after 150 years. We think banking is a long game. It's about relationships, trust, and commitment. That's why we are proud of our history, why we celebrate our anniversaries.</p>
          <p>It's at times like these that our commitment to customers is a powerful differentiator, something that will stand us in good stead as the cycle turns. It's at times like these that our commitment to our markets distinguishes us from other international banks in the eyes of regulators and policymakers. It's also at times like these that our continued commitment to the communities in which we live and work is recognized. Banks and bankers are far from popular in most parts of the world. We can't change that alone, yet by supporting our clients as they navigate the crisis, by committing to our markets and working with policymakers and regulators as they devise responses, and by being a force for good in our communities, we can show what Standard Chartered stands for, what we can contribute.</p>
          <p>Amidst the chaos of the industry, our brand stands prouder than ever before. Ultimately, it's about our people and our performance. Ultimately, it's about the values and culture of the bank. These aren't things we take for granted. In fact, I'd like to take this opportunity to thank the staff of Standard Chartered for the commitment, teamwork, and professionalism they showed in 2008. We'll need all of it again in 2009. For 2009, will undoubtedly be a very challenging year.</p>
          <p>We have started the year performing strongly and with confidence and clarity about our priorities. We will stick to our strategy of leading the way in Asia, Africa, and the Middle East. We will keep focused on the basics; maintaining the quality of the balance sheet, anticipating risk, managing costs tightly, keeping a firm grip on operational control. We will stay open for business, supporting our clients and taking the opportunities we see emerging from the turmoil. And we will stay true to our values and culture to what Standard Chartered stands for.</p>
          <p>Jaspal, Ben, and Julian will take your questions in Hong Kong. John, Rich, and I will take them in London. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, there are some microphones on either side available to take your questions. Please put your hand in the air if you want to ask questions and please remember to state your name and the institution prior to asking your question. Why don't I take one from the right over here first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Mike Trippett at Oriel. Just a couple of questions, actually. The exercise of building liquidity and switching more to the secured book, which is obviously totally understandable, I just wondered what impact that is having on the margin overall, which at the Group level looks like it's incredibly resilient. But I just wondered how that's sort of moving through the fourth quarter and what the offset is of that pressure from the repricing of the Wholesale book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to handle that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think you've got a balance going on between the two businesses in terms of asset margins. So if I took Consumer Bank asset margins across most of the product categories, perhaps with the exception of SME, which has been more stable as you probably thought, you see a compression of margins.</p>
          <p>So if you looked at Hong Kong in particular, actually, second half Hong Kong saw mortgage margins fall from 0.5 to 0.1. Singapore was falling again by about 30 basis points in the second half. India was falling about 30 basis points, but still remains over 2% in mortgages. So you see an asset compression. You get the same type of picture in the other asset categories of Consumer.</p>
          <p>On the other side, Wholesale asset margins were pricing up. Clearly, with reference -- actually in January, a record month for Trade Finance, so in spite of the fact that our volumes were falling, not as much as market volumes were falling, the fact that we've been able to reprice those margins up, actually gave us, one, a very good month. But two, I think is illustrative of the balance between the two businesses.</p>
          <p>In terms of gathering deposits, again, as we've said, we think that gathering deposits is an absolute -- it's a core and essential strength of the Group. We will continue to do that. And certainly in the fourth quarter, last two months of the fourth quarter of '08, we did see a liability compression attaching to the deposit gathering campaign. We saw it move very strongly to gather in liquidity in anticipation of the year end and making sure we have the firepower to support our clients. That did cause some compression in liability margins, particularly in the Consumer Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just add. I mean at a very high level, I'd say that in this kind of environment, if you are offered a choice between near-term P&amp;L benefit and balance sheet strength, you take the balance sheet strength. So we have taken some drag, both in terms of choosing higher asset quality and in terms of just managing the liquidity position. And it's probably had a bit more of a drag for the Consumer Bank than for the Wholesale Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the revenue fall in the Consumer Bank in the second half, probably 30 to $40 million of that revenue fall attaches to liability margin pressure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Ian Smillie from RBS. I have four short questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a theme. Firstly, in the Wholesale Bank, could you give us some sense as to your appetite to grow the loan book? Because you presented to us you've got the liquidity in the capital. But I am just wondering in terms of your appetite to actually grow that business in terms of assets in this year.</p>
          <p>The second question is the improvement in the RWA to loan ratio, which you explained for '08. Is that now baked in and will RWAs grow roughly in line with <mark type="inaudible" /> or is there more to go on that front?</p>
          <p>The third question in Wholesale Bank is, it looks like the uncovered NPLs went from 250 million to something over 600 million. Could you give us some perhaps more detail in the collateral that you've got behind that and why you were comfortable to reduce the coverage ratio and why we shouldn't just think that that's a lead indicator for a rising P&amp;L charge this year?</p>
          <p>And then the final question, sorry, when you are running your stress scenarios, what's a reasonable stress scenario P&amp;L bad debt charge for the Wholesale Bank this year, because the order of magnitude could be anything, and any color on that would be very much appreciated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I do the first one and then you do?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes. <mark type="inaudible" />, I do one and you get three, very fair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's why he is the CEO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that is the four questions, you see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is, then Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. Fine. We continue to have an appetite for growth in the Wholesale Bank. But you've got to remember this is not a lending led business. The lending business is not the driver of growth here. But we continue to have an appetite to deepen our relationships with clients. I would draw a sharp distinction that we are not focusing much on expanding our customer base. We are primarily focusing on deepening relationships with existing clients, which we know already very well. Now, you get the other three.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the RWA to loan growth trends going forward, I think if you look at -- to give you the clue actually, the trajectory on 2008 was impacted by a number of factors. One, exchange. So if you actually take exchange rate, I think you'll find that Wholesale's RWA growth, which I think was 4%, was actually 10 to 11% if you take the impact of exchange.</p>
          <p>We also benefited from a model adjustment, which came through. You may have seen the FSA finally determined. We'd lobbied for nine months with many other banks around how to model, what we call, the minimum maturity claw attaching to Trade Finance assets, which they were holding at a year. Obviously, Trade Finance assets are a much shorter duration than that. So now we model them to actually the relevant duration. That gave us 3 to $4 billion of risk weighted asset benefit.</p>
          <p>And then actually we have had some benefit, I think, as we have entered AIRB status through 2008. So as we have increasingly gone after collateral, particularly on local corporate segments, and we have discussed this before, we are able to improve the risk weight whilst actually pricing up and by actually attaching further collateral and better collateral, which counts with Basel II, but didn't used to count for Basel I in the same way. And that's given us, if you like, some step benefit.</p>
          <p>On the third point, we can continue to get that. I wouldn't believe we'll get it in the same degree going forward into 2009. That, I think, will be the element that will change. Within the numbers we've had PD migration. Wholesale has seen about 6 billion of PD migration negative. We'd expect that to move up in any sensible modeling going forward into '09 by some degree. But that's the picture for the Wholesale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are some benefits, not so much for Wholesale, but on the SME side when we've seen very quick policy action in countries like Korea, Hong Kong, and Singapore in introducing guarantee schemes for the SME. And a significant proportion of our lending activities in SMEs now is being covered by these guarantees, which are -- I can't remember the precise numbers, but they are sort of 80, 90% --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>70% Hong Kong, 80% Singapore, 90 to 95% Korea guaranteed elements of SME lending, which has been introduced in a very cogent way by those governments in support of their SME sectors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And immediately changes the risk dynamics of that lending quite significantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the uncovered NPLs, the main feature here attached to the derivatives position is coming through where we have, as we've indicated, taken -- in Korea, for instance, we've taken $200 million, of which 79 million was loan impairment and 121 was contra-income. The impact of that contra-income is not showing through these lines. You've got a small amount, not anything like the same amount outside Korea and three or four other markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So essentially the contra-income is like a provision, which isn't included in the cover ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be the main driver or the main differentiating driver. On the bad debt charge, Ian, who knows? What I would say, though, if you think about where the Wholesale Bank '08 numbers have come from, 384 was a loan repayment on credit, up from 25; 140 of that attaches to derivatives. We feel very conservatively positioned, who knows, but very conservatively positioned with regard to that.</p>
          <p>50 or so was PIP build coming through into the Wholesale Bank. We increased our judgmental factor within portfolio impairment provisioning.</p>
          <p>And then the rest is across three or four markets where we have local corporate business. The one I think, which is the most significant increase you will see is Hong Kong, which increased by about $80 million and that attaches to local corporate business, where there is assembly or supply in mainland China, but head-officed effectively in Hong Kong. So we would keep a close watch on that. And then actually it's Taiwan 20 to 30 million up, Korea 20 million up outside the derivatives point, and India up about 20 million, but attaching to local corporate business. None of them moving particularly materially, but that's the world we're in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This side of the room is so much more active than that side of the room. Why don't we go right over to the left hand side? Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Steve Hayne from Morgan Stanley. Just wondering if you can just provide any form of guidance on dividend policy. I mean, as you've commented, 2009 is going to be a lot more challenging. Unlike many banks you actually increased your dividend, albeit slightly, but you did in '08. I am wondering if you can offer any guidance for '09. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sounds an appropriate question for the Chairman that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I thought.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, first we'll do with 2008, I mean what we've done for 2008 is set the dividend policy, the final dividend policy very much in line with the policy set out in the prospectus, the rights issue prospectus. And for the investors that took up the rights issue that represents a modest increase in dividend for 2008.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we clearly are very mindful of balancing all the time issues of the capital, making sure that we have adequate levels of capital from a balance sheet point of view, but at the same time, mindful from a shareholder point of view, dividend is very important. So as we move through 2009, we will obviously look at what dividend we can afford to pay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we go to the front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. It's Rohith Chandra-Rajan from Citi. I just had a couple of follow-up questions really on the impairment provisions. And just firstly, on the Consumer Banking business, if you could just clarify the 80 to 100 million reduction in the quarterly run rate that you are expecting this year? Is that primarily due to the dropout of the one-off style AEB related impairments in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, predominantly, yes. Actually, if you look to what happened, we had about, just over $20 million biting us in the UAE on things which I would call -- actually what Peter was talking about in terms of loose rabbit type issues. And we had coming out from the AEB portfolios about $60 million coming through. So if you take those away from the 130 increase, and it's all in that other element -- and our forward projections are simply based, actually we've now done January, February, we can see what's actually happening. As you know, loan impairment and working through the buckets and the flow rates, one has a pretty good view out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And one of the geographies that doesn't really feature in terms of the increased impairments is Singapore, despite a very weak third and fourth quarter and a deterioration expected in the economic outlook for this year. I am just wondering what you are seeing in terms of impairment trends there this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not seeing any particularly material increases, either across Consumer or Wholesale. If you look at Singapore's assets in the Consumer Bank, a very substantial proportion of those are mortgages and they have a loan to value of 48%. So when you're seeing property price compression in Singapore, we have a significant cushion to deal with that.</p>
          <p>In terms of Singapore's policy responses, that's been very helpful. They're at the 80% of SME guarantees. They've dropped property taxes. They've dropped taxes 1%. They've guaranteed retail deposits. They've taken a whole series of quite cogent actions, essentially to buttress their economy in the teeth of the economic slowdown. We are not seeing any material movement in the impairments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And then, just finally a detail -- a point of detail on the Wholesale. I noticed that you've increased probability of default in terms of your assumptions as you'd expect in this time in the cycle, but lost given default decreasing. Is that because of a change in the structure of the portfolio, increased collateralization, just wondering what <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's exactly it. What's happening -- I mean it would be surprising given what's happened in the economy if probability of defaults hadn't increased, right, you would expect any corporate loan portfolio to have an increased probability of default. But what we have been doing is proactively restructuring the transactions to have greater security, to have greater collateral. And that's -- and so we've been deliberate. And that has allowed us to offset some of the impact of the greater probability of default on, say, risk weighted assets. So if you are looking at the dynamics of risk weighted assets in the year, that's one -- it's that combination. It's quite a powerful driver of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Shall we just shift one row back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Sandy Chen from Panmure Gordon. Yeah. If I can have just three quick questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. I'll compress it then. The -- tie that in -- I was just looking at the coverage ratios, and on pages 29 and 31, Consumer coverage ratio has dropped from 81% to 72%, Wholesale has dropped from 75% to 61%. So in terms of guidance, I guess, given the responses to the previous questions, should we just be expecting to carry those forward, even despite the rising impairment environment and potentially falling asset prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't expect a material shift in the Consumer Banking picture. In the Wholesale Banking it goes, again, I think to the nature of this issue attaching to derivative positions, attaching predominantly to Korea. So I think -- that I think is the item that will work through and --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It works through relatively fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will work through relatively fast the whole of the book we stopped writing that business in April of '08. It will work its way through predominantly by end of first half, certainly by August. In that regard, if our judgment is right, actually you may see some pickup back in terms of coverage ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the second question is kind of related to that derivatives. We've talked about this a bit -- on page 56. It looks like your net exposure on derivatives has gone up by about $1.9 billion, as you kind of narrowed assets liabilities year-on-year. Tying that into what you just said about the Korea sort of netting out on impairments, is that how we should interpret that net exposure movement or -- and how sustainable would that be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think the -- first of all, the point I think, is quite right point. The derivative positions had grown. So actually give an increase, but that's predominantly -- more of that's increased volatility. Our actual positions have actually reduced. So volatility is driving the wider mark-to-market, which you see coming through on the assets and the liabilities. The derivative positions are as you see still broadly matched. There is a slight mismatch and much of that just goes to differential cash settlement timings according to different product flows. It doesn't particularly relate to the Korean issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one on this side. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Irfan Younus from NCB. I have a quick -- one quick question on the bank's exposure to the Asian currencies. And there is a relevant sense that it has started to decline again in recent weeks. And how it's likely to affect the capital going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The bank's exposure to Asian currencies and the impact on capital, well, obviously, we are exposed to Asian currencies, because most of our business is in Asia and we have capital denominated in Asian currencies. However, the most significant one which is Korean --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- our structural position in Korea is largely hedged.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's different to what initially was flagged last year? You've tried to hedge it now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We are not completely hedged, but it's much more muted, the impact on the Group's capital position than it was in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We changed our approach to it, given the volatility very late last year and started actually to take hedging against the structural FX position of Korea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are welcome. Shall we, Robert?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks. It's Robert Sage from Macquarie. Two questions. First of all, on costs. I seem to recall at the IMS stage, you were talking about broadly flat jaws and you've come on obviously with very impressive numbers. I was wondering whether you could just sort of talk through in terms of what changed towards the end of the year. And possibly, I mean, you've been good enough to sort of give us some guidance in the past on costs or jaws. I was just wondering, I hear what you say about the various run rates on different sort of parts of the business, but if you could give us an overall Group feel on that.</p>
          <p>The second question was really sort of following Ian's Smillie's question --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought that was two. [laughter]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well, I'll say it in two parts, that first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's part A and B. Your second question, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The second question was in terms of sort of being open business, your name is being sort of speculated about in terms of various acquisitions at the moment. And I was just sort of wondering how you felt relative to your sort of capital ratios, not talking individual transactions, but just in terms of your appetite to buy cheap businesses as well as cheap assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I give the cost one to Richard, because Richard loves talking about cost. And then John and I can talk about the acquisition side of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the jaws, I think the other way you could also look at it is, if you looked at it on a normalized basis. If you looked at it on a normalized basis, you would still see we had positive jaws of 3% underlying, but minus 1% -- just under minus 1% headline.</p>
          <p>So, if you adjust for those normalized items, you will still see the jaws coming -- you will still see a good jaws picture, particularly on the underlying basis, given that AEB is the difference and that had very significant integration expenditure, as you know, which is now falling away.</p>
          <p>But in general, there's been an increasing underlying, so an increasing focus on our costs in terms of where we are investing, the pace of our investing, the BAU cost disciplines, moves on decisions around head count. And that, if anything, was accelerating through the second half, as we saw the revenues slow. Remember the pace of the slowdown attaching to Wealth management Income. So, the Group was pulling cost levers harder as it saw that revenue horizon impacted.</p>
          <p>As to guidance, I don't think we see any reason to move away from the drumbeat that we march to, which is cost growth broadly in line with income growth. So, as long as we can read the revenue horizon with a degree of confidence. That cost growth in line with revenue growth would have a positive bias, i.e., we are more likely to come in with cost growth below revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Given the world's much more uncertain at the moment, it doesn't surprise you that we are holding costs very tight --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- in going into 09, very tight indeed, to give us run rate benefit, to take decisions around investment rollout.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on acquisition, I'll make a couple of comments, I don't know if you want to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just wondering, how many opportunities in 2008, Peter, came to us as slam-dunks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had some very interesting, quite unexpected esoteric opportunities offered to us, many of which had very little to do with Asia, Africa, and the Middle East, as you can imagine. The primary driver of our strategy remains organic growth and we do see many opportunities in this market to continue to take market share and to improve margins and to deepen relationships with clients, and that is going to be the core of the strategy.</p>
          <p>However, obviously, there are going to be opportunities emerging and we will look at them, but we have to be convinced that they really add to what we can do organically. And I do think there's a little bit of added caution that we would have in this environment relative to sort of more benign times. There is always a degree of sort of execution risk and just difficulty in integrating any acquisition. If you are doing it in extremely volatile markets, it's just harder to get right. So, it would be an added degree of caution.</p>
          <p>I don't think we have &#x2013; we are in a position where small little things, bolt-on things, we could take without coming to shareholders for money, anything material. We would have to be sufficiently convinced of the story to believe that we could stand up in front of our investors, and explain why it was worth them funding a transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the most important thing that shareholders need to know is that the Board, when it looks at any investments, organic investment or indeed acquisition, is that it has to be seen clearly to be creating shareholder value, and not destroying value. We certainly don't believe in just acquiring businesses for bulk. We certainly don't believe in acquiring businesses to widen the geographic footprint outside of those territories that Peter just mentioned, that we intend to focus on.</p>
          <p>And above all, it's very important that any acquisition that we make is able to augment what we are trying to do organically, as Peter said. And I think I'm sure during 2009, opportunities will come along. And there will always be two basic tests; one, strategically does it fit? And secondly, financially does it make sense? And if we can't tick all of those boxes, we shouldn't touch them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next to Robert, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Toeman from HSBC. Two questions, first rather train-spotterish. I wanted to thank you for giving us more information on the Financial Markets division, but I wondered why the numbers on page 20 of the presentation don't tie up with the note three, I sure we can learn something very useful from that.</p>
          <p>And again, your comments on the probability of default and loss given default on the Wholesale Banking, you give the impression that the PD times the loss given defaults suggests a charge of 20 basis points on the portfolio, and that's setting your <mark type="inaudible" /> capital requirements. So why isn't it right to look for 20 basis points as a forecast for Wholesale impairments going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to deal with the note three one first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think the important thing about note three, we've had this debate, actually some &#x2013; I've done these results &#x2013; we've had this debate about what is note three. And actually, I think, the earlier disclosure is a better disclosure, because of how we manage the business.</p>
          <p>So if you look at the foreign currency line, which is the main one and it includes all FX income regardless of how or where it arises. So it includes Consumer Bank, it includes the Korean and SPV FX asymmetry, it includes all translation gains and losses on balance sheet positions, as well as underlying Wholesale Bank FX instruments. And many of those actually will be traded as part of a different portfolio, or dealt, or managed as part of a different desk.</p>
          <p>So if you think about a transaction where we would have a local currency bond -- and we've done this before -- local currency bond, you have an interest rate swap attaching to it, cross-currency swap attaching to it. If that were booked through the rates desk, all of the income is on the better note, which is how we manage the business. What this note does, it just simply captures on an accounting basis, and sweeps up all sort of foreign currency, foreign exchange income.</p>
          <p>To that extent, actually, whilst with apologies to my auditors, who are sitting there, it's a very important note in terms of financial disclosure in the accounts. It's not a very helpful note at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your other question, Peter, what you will enjoy if you like the wholesome PD, LGD stuff, is when we publish our Pillar 3 disclosures, which are coming up -- when are they coming up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>April, the --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Early April.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Early April. Well, they will be coming out in early April, and you will have a blizzard of PD and LGD and all sorts of fun numbers -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which we are engaged on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- which we can talk about. I mean the thing you are missing, well, you're missing a few things to be able to turn that into any sort of model based forecast; one is EAD, exposure at default, and the other is the impact of FX. And in any case, because your -- these are mathematical models predicting low probability events, they are, by their nature, only that. And so, I would be careful in using them too adventurously in terms of making predictions.</p>
          <p>But the reason for talking about the PD and LGD was to give you a sense of the magnitude of what we were doing in terms of restructuring the collateral and security element of the book, and to show that it is of the same magnitude, roughly speaking, as the degree of probability of default deterioration in the book. This is not a thing we are doing on the margin. This is a substantial shifting in terms of the quality of the book.</p>
          <p> Tom,, shall we get Tom? Well, you're right there, so why don't you -- sorry, Tom, we'll come to you in a minute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good morning, it's Leigh Goodwin, Fox-Pitt Kelton. Just a couple of questions, following up on slides 19 and 20, which give us the breakdown on the financial -- well, the Wholesale income, and with a breakdown of Financial Markets as well.</p>
          <p>So, the question comes back to one which we were all asking six months ago about the sustainability of Wholesale revenues. And you've answered that very well in the second half of the year, I have to say. But just two of those items, the growth in ALM and the growth in rates, account for about a billion of the increase. And I'm just looking at the commentary around rates, and you're suggesting that some of that is due to sort of favorable positioning against certain rate movements, well done. But I wonder how sustainable we should think about that as being. And also changes in government bond values on your own book.</p>
          <p>And then, against ALM, clearly, we've had a steeper yield curve. That's helped to offset some of the margin compression. But as yield curves perhaps flatten, or -- '09 on '08 -- I wonder whether what sort of ALM income we can expect for 2009. So really I'm driving at sustainability in Wholesale and those two items in particular?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, why don't you have a go at that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, ALM, we are very well positioned. Yes, it slowed in the second half, but actually we are now positioned well. I think we're maximizing accrual run rate, essentially from a steepening curve, but the short end's dropped, long end is up, and we are short. So we are actually positioning well and taking lots of steps forward with good accrual run rate. So ALM actually in '09 has had a very good start.</p>
          <p>Would I expect it to continue? We'll see what happens with rates, but it's certainly got momentum going through for the next, at least, immediate short-term horizon.</p>
          <p>With regard to the rates, it is actually the business in 2008. I think, where we saw -- actually, had a phenomenal -- it had a phenomenal performance. I mean the team did a superb job. And within the numbers you see, about 300 or so -- 330 million or so, actually I would call own account trading position, where picking up the language -- it had very good opportunities to trade, good volatility. Again, lots of rate movement. Again, staying short was a &#x2013; it was a phenomenal performance, but I'd like to say, staying short in that type of environment, it was possible to make good money. It has done that.</p>
          <p>So about 300 million to 330 million of that rates business I would put down to position and trading. And it predominantly drives this thing -- it is part of the reason for Singapore's very good performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But on the other hand, I mean, of course, another large chunk of our own account, which is Private Equity, saw a pretty significant movement in the other direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also &#x2013; sorry -- the majority of it clearly is also sales. So when you look at this Financial Markets income, it's very important, 77% of this income is client income as you look at this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks very much. I was also going to ask on the sustainability of the Wholesale revenues. I think it is pretty crucial, and I mean I'm sad that you're rubbishing note three because it's been my favorite note for a long time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know it has, Tom. Move on, Tom, move on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I am. I'm moving on to slide 20 disclosure. I mean is there anyway you can give us a feel for how the quarterly trends played out in the second half on some of the big items, because it's really back to the same point, because we want to understand how much of the second half revenue was really just fantastic performance or driven by --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't give you quarter actually because I haven't got it in my head.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But what I can tell you is, with regard to Wholesale Bank's income in January, which we said was very strong, it was broader based than it was in the January of 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And can I just lead that on just to your overall strategy because -- I don't want to put words in your mouth, but just summarizing. It feels as if there is a bit more focus on cost control in consumer possibly because the Wealth Management opportunity is not there with what's happening economically. But in Wholesale, you feel, because lots of maybe big sort of U.S. investment banks are not in a position to compete with you any more, you might be able to push on aggressively and take their market share away. Is that a fair summary of how you see things in the next year or two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say that there's an even greater focus on costs and costs discipline than there has been in the past in both businesses. When you are in an environment as volatile as this, and you look at the P&amp;L, we can't predict with any precision quite how the income trajectory is going to go. We can't predict with any precision quite how the loan impairment is going to play out. So the lever over which we have most control in both businesses is costs. And so, we are keeping a very, very tight grip on it.</p>
          <p>Obviously, the dynamic is different in Wholesale. Wholesale has had a very strong performance, and the opportunities to invest and take market share are very, very evident.</p>
          <p>In Consumer, we are investing to build distribution and strengthen our franchise, but we've also had to respond to a very sharp reduction in Wealth Management income. And the challenge here has been that Wealth Management itself has a very low cost income ratio. So, when you lose the income, a very high proportion of it goes straight through to the bottom line. And so, we've reacted to that quite assertively in the terms of managing the cost base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, can I just add something to that, because I think it's very important when you look at these market conditions, which are clearly very difficult, and most people agree that 2009 market conditions are going to be difficult as well. But Richard referred -- used the expression flight to quality, and you cannot underestimate enough the quality of this brand and the loyalty and indeed respect the bank has in some of these key markets.</p>
          <p>And that is why, I think, over the course of the next 12 months, in very difficult market conditions, there is a very good chance that the bank will continue to gain market share. And I think that goes both for Wholesale and Consumer bank.</p>
          <p>And that's why, I think, what Peter tried to do was set out in his presentation, how important sticking to our knitting, getting down, focus on the basics of banking and the services we provide with our customers. So just simply looking at the numbers and trying to extrapolate forward based on perhaps just on 2008, you've got to look at the dynamic of what's really happening in the market too. There is an exciting opportunity here for Standard Chartered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm conscious you've had your hand up a long time. You're right in the middle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's John Kirk of Redburn. I've got a capital question please. It strikes me that there is a fantastic opportunity for Standard Chartered across the board really at the moment, but at the same time there are reasons to think that perhaps you don't have enough capital to take full advantage of them.</p>
          <p>And the first is that your capital ratios are not quite as pristine relative to your peers as they perhaps were. And also, as you yourself point out, there is an enormous amount of uncertainty regarding the economic outlook and so on and how the business will perform in '09 in revenues and impairments and so on.</p>
          <p>So I guess I'm trying to put this question as optimistically as possible, do you feel you have enough capital there to be able to take all the opportunities that are out there? Or are there other constricting factors such as the operational capabilities of the Group, the capability of the Group to actually take on all this market share opportunity operationally rather than through a capital constraint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we're very comfortable with our capital position. And I think you have to look at the ratios, the capital ratios in the context of a couple of things. One is the rest of the quality of the balance sheet, in terms of the liquidity position and the asset quality, where the assets are, what kind of assets they are, the fact that we have such a low relative to the competition AD ratio.</p>
          <p>The second thing is you have to look at the capital ratios in the context of profit generation; are you making money, and thereby are you replenishing your capital? And, I think, both of those support the strength of our capital position?</p>
          <p>You can paint a scenario in which we had loads more capital and we rushed off and did loads more stuff. I actually think that that would be a kind of risky scenario because this is an environment where you want to be very disciplined and very deliberate in what opportunities you take. We are turning down opportunities both inorganically and organically practically every day, because we just reinforced right across the business that if it's off strategy, you don't even think about it. And if it's on strategy, you double check the way it works, because in this kind of environment, it's so easy to get things wrong.</p>
          <p>So, to your point, this whole focus on operational control and the way we run the business and the discipline we run the business is absolutely important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm very comfortable with the level of capital to be able to take advantage of organic opportunities and to the extent we see them and they are attractive and create value, small bolt-on acquisitions. If we saw a compelling case for a bigger acquisition, we wouldn't have the capital resource and we would have to come to shareholders. But frankly, I think that's a good discipline. If we can't tell a convincing story about a potential large acquisition to convince the shareholders to back it, then we shouldn't really be doing it anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely right. Always be mindful of what's in the best interest of your shareholders, never forget that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Michael Helsby from Morgan Stanley. I've just got two questions. And just following up from the capital points and I think a key thing that you mention is profitability. At 2008, you have got about 350 bps of pre-provision profit to loans, which I think is very high. I was wondering, under what economic circumstances that you put up on your slide 38, you can envisage actually burning through any book value given that high-end provision coverage.</p>
          <p>And second point is in the Americas and U.K. loan book, I know AEB is playing around in there, but it's been growing extremely strongly in the last couple of years. I know anecdotally that you've been involved in a lot of the expansion of Indian corporates outside of India. So, I was just wondering if you could comment on the quality of that book, and that would be cool?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to do both those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On the first one, I am not going to try and paint you a picture actually what would burn through it. I think in terms of where we run stresses, and we run deep stresses, we run deep recession stresses, and so on. I think its difficult for us to see more than 150, 160 basis points coming off effectively capital ratios, as we remain well above our target ranges on those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's running stresses worse than the Asia crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's worse than the Asia crisis because actually the Asia crisis doesn't pick up how difficult it was for, in many ways, consumer bank attaching to SARS. Do you remember SARS in Hong Kong bankruptcies basically combining. So, if you actually add that that was worse than Asia crisis. You have to run --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much worse?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Significantly worse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Significantly worse, yes. Good question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The high level point, if you run a scenario that says Asia crisis plus even worse experiences for certain portfolios, you still have a resilient capital position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now, I have completely forgotten -- U.K. you've got U.K., Europe and Americas. Quite rightly you've got AEB coming in, which is 5, 6 billion or so. You've also got -- we run offshore booking units. So we have offshore booking units in London, Singapore, Bahrain. An element of that growth actually several billion, attaches to offshore bookings in the London OBU. A substantial proportion of that will emerge and will come out from India.</p>
          <p>You have also seen in there a growth of exposures attaching to Pembroke, which we acquired recently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Aviation --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Aviation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>--finance and leasing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, sort of a whole series of broad range of business attached to commodities and structured trade actually booked in London. The quality of the book is good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I am conscious of time, if there's another question, I am happy to take it. Otherwise, we can wrap up. Any final questions?</p>
          <p>Thank you all for joining us. I think we are pleased to have delivered, what I think, are resilient results in a tough environment, and we've started the year well. So, thank you for joining us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>