<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1490001" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-08-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7788</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Non-Executive Chairman">John Wilfred Peace</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Director &amp; Group Finance Director">Richard Henry Meddings</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Peter Alexander Sands</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Tom A. Rayner</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Rohith Chandra-Rajan</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Jason C. Napier</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Chirantan Barua</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Chintan Joshi</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Cenkos Securities Plc (Broker)">Sandy W. Chen</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well good morning, London, and good afternoon to those of you in Hong Kong and in Mumbai. I'm pleased to report that the bank has again performed strongly in the first six months of 2012, our tenth consecutive first half of record profits. Set against a macroeconomic environment that is increasingly challenged, these results are very strong results. And let me emphasize, this is a story of continued and consistent delivery from an institution in the tenth year of unbroken growth.</p>
          <p>Once again, it seems that the world is becoming more uncertain by the day. Nonetheless, our focus will remain, as always, resolutely on the interests of our shareholders. And I would like to reiterate that we have a firm grip on the business, with the ability to turn adversity to our advantage. And we will keep investing as we see long-term opportunities for growth.</p>
          <p>In recent weeks, issues have surfaced around governance and behavior in banking. At Standard Chartered, we believe it's not just about what we do, but how we do it. Our culture and our values continue to be a source of strength and competitive advantage. Strong corporate governance and an obsession with the basics of banking remain key areas of focus for our board. Now in a moment, Richard will walk you through the numbers, and then Peter will talk about our strategy and outlook.</p>
          <p>But first, let me comment on a few highlights of our performance. Income rose 9% to $9.51 billion with profits before taxation up 9% to $3.95 billion and normalized earnings per share up 11% to 116.6 cents. With return on equity at 13.8%, we remain on target to reach our key financial objective of mid-teens return on equity over the medium-term.</p>
          <p>We are again increasing the total amount of dividend paid to shareholders. The board has declared an interim dividend of $0.273 per share, which is up 10%.</p>
          <p>Standard Chartered is in the right markets with the right strategy and we have the right leadership in place. That is why we remain confident in the bank's ability to deliver sustained good returns and we thank our shareholders for their continued support. Now, with all the noise going on around us, we are determined not to become distracted and to remain our focus on doing good business.</p>
          <p>We continue to support our customers and clients, deepening our long-term relationships with them. I'd like to take this opportunity to thank our customers and our clients for their trust and commitment to banking with Standard Chartered.</p>
          <p>Let me now ask Richard to walk you through the results in more detail. Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Good morning, London, and good afternoon, Hong Kong and Mumbai. What I'm presenting today is another strong set of results. Our track record of consistent delivery has continued despite the challenges in the external environment. And these results are in line with previous guidance. There are no surprises.</p>
          <p>We have a firm grip on the management levers of costs and investment and of risk. We continue to manage the business conservatively. Our balance sheet strength, strong capital and liquidity position and our ability to access unsecured funding are key competitive advantages, enabling us to support our clients through turbulent times.</p>
          <p>Economic growth, while slowing, still remains strong because our footprint markets of Asia, Africa, and the Middle East. As we continue to manage the business tightly, we are further stepping up investment spend to position us strongly for the long-term growth opportunities we see across our markets.</p>
          <p>Let me draw out several key highlights. The group has delivered strong income and profit growth over the first half of 2011 (sic) [2012] (5:36), both up 9% and this against a background of a slowing global economy and currency headwinds. On a constant currency basis, both income and profit were up by a double-digit rate, showing the strong underlying beat of our business.</p>
          <p>Costs have been tightly controlled and we have delivered positive cost income jaws, which round to 2%, providing the additional capacity to accelerate investment in both businesses. Our balance sheet remains in excellent shape, with an A-D ratio and liquid asset ratio of 77.6% and 27.9%, respectively.</p>
          <p>Customer loans and advances and total deposits have each grown 4% on the year-end position and risk-weighted assets have grown 6%. Continued capital strength with core Tier 1 at 11.6% and total capital at 16.9%. Normalized earnings per share has risen 11% to 116.6 cents.</p>
          <p>We've declared an interim dividend of $0.2723 per share, up 10%, and we continue to make good progress on improving returns, for our shareholders' return-on-equity is 13.8%, or 13.3% after adjusting for an estimated deduction for the UK bank levy. Let me take you through the numbers.</p>
          <p>At a group level, income has grown strongly, up 9% on the first half of 2011 and within this, consumer banking income was up 5%, while wholesale banking income increased 10%, with broad growth was up in multiple products and customer segments. The growth has been impacted by just under 3% as an income level by local currency weakness, particularly the Indian rupee, which alone accounts for a 1.6% drag on income.</p>
          <p>Expenses are up 6% year-on-year and 9% on a constant currency basis. We look to increase investments in the second half of the year, particularly in our systems and our distribution network and we will focus on enhancing customer experience and service.</p>
          <p>While loan impairment has increased, it remains low and reflects the gradual and planned mix shift in consumer banking assets towards unsecured and also, provisions taken against a very small number of wholesale banking exposures.</p>
          <p>Operating profit of $3.948 billion increased 9% on the first half of 2011. The group's effective tax rate in the first half of the year was 26.5%, and this is lower than the 2011 full year effective tax rate as a result of geographic profit mix and the impact of the branch profits exemption election made last year. And overall, the group has had a record first half, with the performance underpinned by the diversity of our business and the continued economic growth across our markets.</p>
          <p>The diversity of the group give us real resilience. Our multiple engines of growth enable us to grow at pace, even when some geographies or products have weaker years. Despite the macroeconomic environment, 20 markets grew at a double-digit pace. Our largest market, Hong Kong, which grew income at 10%, contributed just 18% to the group's income in the first half of 2012.</p>
          <p>By product, we've seen double-digit income growth in credit cards, in personal loans, in deposits, in rates, and in the heart of our wholesale banking business, trade and cash management. And we continue to invest in our product capabilities. For example, we are the market leader in renminbi, and we are pioneering areas of automation for the benefit of our clients in trade finance.</p>
          <p>Moving to the balance sheet. The balance sheet is in excellent shape and continues to be highly liquid, well diversified, strongly capitalized, and a source of real competitive advantage. We remain firmly open for business, actively deploying our balance sheet strength to support our customers and clients.</p>
          <p>The group remains primarily deposit-funded, growing deposits in both business despite strong market competition in some of our key geographies. Total deposits are up 4% on the year-end position, as we benefit from being the only major international bank to be upgraded by all three rating agencies since the onset of the financial crisis. We have limited refinancing requirements over the next few years and only some $3 billion through to the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>We have continued to see good support from the capital markets, with two subordinated Tier 2 and one senior unsecured transaction closed so far in 2012. And all three transactions were heavily over-subscribed, reflecting the strong and continuing demand in the market for our name.</p>
          <p>Our liquid asset ratio was at 27.9% and we already meet the minimum Basel III requirement for both the net stable funding ratio and the liquidity coverage ratio. We have some $174 billion of liquid assets.</p>
          <p>Turning to assets, we continue to see good growth momentum, with our customer loans and advances up 4% since the year-end. We have in consumer banking a continuing bias to secured lending, with 82% of the book being either fully or partially secured. We have a low loan-to-value ratio on our mortgage book of 48%; a short maturity profile on our wholesale banking customer loan book, with 63% of the book under one year in tenure, reflecting the continued trade bias of our business.</p>
          <p>And we have no direct sovereign exposure to Portugal, Italy, Ireland, Greece or Spain, and our total gross exposure to these countries remains immaterial at around 0.5% of total assets. Our loan portfolio remains well-diversified, both by geography and by sector, and conservatively positioned.</p>
          <p>Moving to capital. The group remains well-capitalized, with a core Tier 1 of 11.6%, a Tier 1 ratio of 13.4%, and total capital of 16.9%. In the first half, we have generated $2.8 billion of profit attributable to ordinary shareholders. The capital ratios have been affected by a number of factors, including the final dividend, where there was a lower scrip take-up than we have historically seen. Growth in risk-weighted assets of 6% including the impact of some negative credit migration, an element of drag from structural foreign exchange, and the acquisition of shares to support long-term staff incentive schemes. In July, we issued $1.25 billion of lower Tier 2 capital and including this issuance, our total capital ratio would be above 17%, at 17.3%.</p>
          <p>Looking now at performance by business and starting with consumer banking. The consumer banking transformation program continues to make good progress and we are investing in the business in order to grow both our customer base and customer service capabilities. Consumer banking customer footings have grown over the year-end level, with customer deposits up 3% and loans and advances up 1%. Loans and advances growth was impacted by a decline in mortgage balances in Korea, in particular.</p>
          <p>Income grew 5% year-on-year to $3.5 billion. There's slightly lower momentum than in the past. Income growth has been impacted by muted performances in India, Korea and Taiwan. However, China and Indonesia, but also Africa, and the Americas, UK and Europe region are all growing income at a good double-digit rate.</p>
          <p>Expenses increased 9%, although the comparative period included $86 million of non-recurring cost recoveries made against structured net provisions. Excluding this, expenses grew 5% year-on-year. As we see opportunities to grow, we are investing in marketing, in infrastructure and building out our network, in particular, in Africa and in China. We have completed 56 branch projects in the first half, including new branches, branch relocations, refurbishments and some closures. And we've also continued to invest in enhancing our mobile and Internet banking capabilities.</p>
          <p>The consumer banking loan impairment charge has increased in line with expectations and I will go into this in detail later. As a result of the lower overall performance momentum, one-off expense recoveries in the comparable period of 2011, and higher loan impairments, consumer banking operating profit has fallen 11%.</p>
          <p>Turning to product. Mortgage income was down 13% against the first half of 2011, with balances down 1% on the year-end position and compression in margins. Overall margins have fallen some 19 basis points year-on-year and are rising particularly in Hong Kong, Korea, Africa and China. Mortgage income has been impacted by regulatory cooling measures in several key markets.</p>
          <p>Deposit income is up strongly, 14% year-on-year, driven by an improvement in margins of some 10 basis points and an increase in balances of 3% on the year-end position and despite increasing competition for liabilities across many of our markets.</p>
          <p>Wealth management the income was down 3% year-on-year, due to weaker investor sentiment given the slowing global economy and market volatility, and the geographies most affected here were Taiwan and Korea.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide. Income in credit cards and personal loans shows excellent momentum, up 13% year-on-year, as we continue to grow balances, up 7% since the year-end. We are enjoying steady market share gains in credit card spend, particularly in Hong Kong and in personal loans in Hong Kong and in Korea.</p>
          <p>SME continues to perform well, with 7% income growth year-on-year driven by lending, trade, and cash management. The SME book remains predominantly secured. We continue to increase our lending to SMEs with loans and advances up 3% on the year-end position.</p>
          <p>Moving to impairment. Loan impairment has increased year-on-year, in line with expectations, reflecting growth in the portfolio and mix change. Loan impairment increased 42% on the first half of 2011 to $300 million, but is down marginally on the level seen in the second half.</p>
          <p>Loan impairments benefited in the first half by some $43 million from sales of previously written down portfolios, in line with the average level seen in 2011. We remain comfortable with our exposures and continue to proactively manage our book. Our forward-looking indicators have actually marginally improved on the level seen in the second half of 2011.</p>
          <p>So, to summarize for consumer banking, balance sheet momentum has slowed and we are seeing pressures in wealth management and in mortgages. However, deposits and unsecured are growing well. Costs and risk are under tight control and loan impairment is growing in line with our expectations. We have identified accelerated investment opportunities to underpin continued growth in the future.</p>
          <p>Looking at wholesale banking. Wholesale banking has delivered another outstanding performance, reflecting the resilience of the business model, the continued business activity of our client base, and underlying growth within our footprint. Income was up 10% and client income up 8% on the first half of 2011, which was itself a very strong period. Client income contributes 80% of total wholesale banking income, with over 70% generated from our corporate client base and the balance from financial institutions.</p>
          <p>Our sustained performance is built on our traditional foundation of commercial banking, which contributes over 50% of wholesale banking client income and provides us with a strong platform to engage with our clients, often on a daily basis. As well as giving us an unparalleled view of the client's business, it gives us real opportunities to expand our relationship across other product lines.</p>
          <p>As we sit at both ends of the major global trade and investment flows, our network and the interconnectivity of our markets remain sources of competitive differentiation, with 51% of client income in the first half of 2012 being network revenue.</p>
          <p>The strength of our client relationships, often built over decades, gives us real competitive advantage. We continue to invest in client service capabilities, including a new but significant and multi-year upgrade of our cash management system and a standardized relationship management platform, and we will further accelerate investment in the second half of 2012.</p>
          <p>Own account income increased 21% year-on-year. This is driven by principal finance, which was up 59%, mainly on valuation gains and by ALM income, up 14%. ALM income growth reflects a larger balance sheet and an improving yield opportunity. As a client-focused bank, our trading activities are centered on executing the high levels of client flows we generate. We have no proprietary trading desks.</p>
          <p>Expenses rose 3%, primarily reflecting strong control on business-as-usual costs, creating investment capacity for the second half. And operating profit increased an excellent 16% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Looking at income in more detail. Our core transaction banking business has had a strong first half, with income up 19%, accounting for over three-quarters of total wholesale banking client income growth. We have deepened further our focus on transaction banking as our core business, a pivot from which other products are sold.</p>
          <p>In trade, income was up an excellent 25%, driven by growth in average assets and contingents of 13% year-on-year and an increase in margins of some 17 basis points. Intra-Asia trade continues to grow at a faster rate than global trade, which is expected to be lower in 2012 than in 2011. We continue to take market share as our network capability differentiates us.</p>
          <p>Cash management income saw strong growth of 13%, underpinned both by growth in average balances, up 11%, and an improvement in cash margins of seven basis points against the first half of last year.</p>
          <p>Corporate finance income was up 9% on the first half of 2011. This business is increasingly diversified, with an increase in the number of transactions closed year-on-year. The deal pipeline remains very strong, indeed, a record by both number and value, although there is clearly execution risk, given the challenging external environment.</p>
          <p>Financial markets. Income in financial markets was up 2% on the first half of 2011. This is a strong performance in light of difficult market conditions impacting the industry and FICC, in particular. Our FICC income was up 1% year-on-year and 15% on the second half of 2011, further highlighting our core banking strategy and commercial banking foundation, albeit quarter two was down on quarter one.</p>
          <p>Foreign exchange income of $743 million fell 3% as a result of muted volumes, reduced volatility and a higher proportion of business transacted with financial institutions.</p>
          <p>The rates business grew income by 20% year-on-year to $539 million, due to the increased appetite of our corporate clients to hedge their positions and as a result of higher levels of interest rate volatility. Commodities and equities income fell 13% when compared to a strong first half of 2011, impacted by low volatility and the non-repeat of several large client transactions completed in that comparable period.</p>
          <p>Capital markets income increased 7% year-on-year to $290 million. The uncertain macro environment narrowed the window for issuers to access the market, resulting in lower syndicated loan volumes, somewhat offset by an increase in bond volumes. Credit and other income was up 1% on the first half of 2011, again, on the back of lower volatility.</p>
          <p>Moving to loan impairment, overall, net loan impairment remains low at 36 basis points of loans and advances to customers. Loan impairment has, however, increased 41% year-on-year, owing to provisions made on a very small number of exposures. More than 80% of these provisions are from a very small number of accounts in the UAE related to general macroeconomic factors and in India, relating to both macroeconomic and more specific political factors. We are not currently seeing any signs of stress and we remain comfortable with our cover ratios in particular, reflecting the quality of underlying collateral and our historic recovery rates.</p>
          <p>Though the alerts have increased on the year-end position, given our proactive starts on managing risks in a more uncertain environment. In addition to our normal monitoring, we have conducted deep dives in a number of geographies and sectors and credit quality across the wholesale banking book as a whole remains strong.</p>
          <p>Our wholesale banking loan book is conservative, diverse by geography and by sector and predominantly short-dated, where 63% of loans and advances have a tenure of less than one year. We have low exposure to problematic clauses, ABS, leveraged loans and Level 3 assets, and our commercial real estate portfolio of $10.4 billion has an average loan-to-value of 46%.</p>
          <p>To summarize, wholesale banking has delivered another strong set of results and there is very good underlying business momentum, with record deal pipelines and continued strong growth in our core businesses of trade and cash.</p>
          <p>We continue to have a firm grip on costs, enabling further accelerated investment in the second half, and we remain proactive in the management of risk. We are positioned in the growth markets of the world. We have strong core banking relationships and we are offering support to our clients and customers as they grow.</p>
          <p>Turning to geographic performance. Peter will talk to you about Africa, about China and the Americas, UK and Europe region. However, let me highlight some of our other geographies. Hong Kong has continued to deliver and has finished the first half strongly, achieving double-digit income growth. The performance is broad-based. Wholesale banking delivered a strong performance, particularly in transaction banking and corporate finance. And we continued to benefit the mere emergence of the renminbi and from Hong Kong's role as the gateway to mainland China. Consumer banking income in Hong Kong was up 5%, impacted by a fall in mortgage income, given margin compression. However, we have seen double-digit income growth in credit cards and personal loans and also deposits.</p>
          <p>Singapore has delivered 6% income growth on a very strong comparative period, in particular in wholesale banking. We have seen strong income growth in credit cards and personal loans and in transaction banking. Given this continued income momentum, strong cost control and a fall in loan impairment, operating profit in Singapore increased 17% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Korea's income grew $110 million or 13%. However, this includes $74 million from a one-off property sale. We continue to see strong growth in network revenue, up 10%, as we build on our position as the international bank for Korean global corporates. Expenses in Korea are down on the levels seen in the first half of 2011, with the benefits in the early retirement program more than offsetting inflationary increases. We continue to reshape the consumer banking balance sheet in Korea. Indeed, we have recently signed an agreement with the Korea Housing Finance Corporation to transfer to them fixed rate mortgages that we originate.</p>
          <p>Looking at India, the rupee depreciation against U.S. dollar has had a significant impact on performance, with a 14% drag on income. On a reported basis, India income was down 12% as the difficult operating environment continued onshore. Although consumer banking represents only a small part of the business, income here is up 8% on a constant currency basis, with a particularly good performance in deposits.</p>
          <p>Within wholesale banking, we saw a strong performance from our core trade and cash businesses. The network revenue, which is reported in other geographic areas, continues to deliver good growth, up 20% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>We maintain a cautious view on credit risk in India, given the uncertain environment, and we have stress-tested our portfolio and tightened underwriting standards. We remain optimistic with the medium term prospects and continue to invest in the business.</p>
          <p>Within MESA, consumer banking income was up 3%, driven by good performances in SME and credit cards and personal loans. In wholesale banking, client income increased 5% with good performances in both transaction banking and corporate finance. But this was more than offset by a fall in own account income. And as a result, wholesale banking income fell 1% over the comparable period.</p>
          <p>Costs here have been tightly controlled, up 5%. Loan impairment has increased 13%, driven by provisions taken on a very small number of accounts within wholesale banking. And as a result, operating profit for the MESA region was down 12% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Turning then to outlook. As we consider the outlook for the full year, it is important to bear in mind the growing turbulence and uncertainty in the global economy, particularly in the Eurozone. The material and increasing drag from an ever more complex set of regulatory requirements, and the continued strength of the U.S. dollar against Asian currencies.</p>
          <p>So the world is increasingly difficult to forecast. However, for the group as a whole, we currently remain on course to deliver on our full year financial objectives. So double-digit revenue growth, neutral jaws, but with a positive bias, double-digit earnings per share growth and we made good progress towards our medium-term target of mid-teens return on equity, with a pre-levy return on equity at 13.8% in this first half.</p>
          <p>We have a firm grip on the levers of risk, costs and investment, and we remain open for business. Indeed, we are proactively reaching out to support our customers and clients even more, growing our business as they grow theirs. As a result, we enter the second half with confidence. We've had a strong July, but we are watchful of the significant and growing challenges in the external world, and we are managing risk tightly.</p>
          <p>We continue to focus on the basics of banking. We continue to invest in order to underpin future income momentum and we continue to take market share in multiple markets and across multiple products. Thank you, and now, I'll hand over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. Good morning, and good afternoon to those of you in Hong Kong and Mumbai. These results represent a very positive start to the year. Amidst all the turbulence in the global economy and the apparently never-ending turmoil in the world of banking, we remain consistent in continuing to deliver strong performance.</p>
          <p>I appreciate it may seem a bit boring in contrast to what's going on elsewhere. But we see some virtue in being boring. We've stuck to our strategy, staying focused on our markets in Asia, Africa and the Middle East, supporting our customers and clients, maintaining a tight grip on the business. We've held true to our values, to the spirit of here for good, taking a long-term view, always trying to do the right thing.</p>
          <p>Our record of consistent delivery is testament to the resilience of the bank's business model and underscores the sheer diversity of the income engines we have. These results are not a bank's bank nor flattered by big one-off items. They are just our tenth consecutive first half of record profits.</p>
          <p>Such consistency is all the more important, and all the more remarkable, given the scale and unpredictability of the external events and trends affecting us. The avalanche of regulations shows no sign of abating and given the seemingly endless flow of bad news about the industry, the calls for yet more regulation have predictably intensified.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile and more fundamentally, the global economy continues to weaken. The Eurozone faces profound challenges, a political and economic morass that has defied every attempt at resolution. We don't see the Eurozone's problems getting solved any time soon and every failed plan makes it more difficult to win market credibility for the next.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., ultra low interest rates and continued fiscal largesse have undoubtedly been a tonic, but neither is sustainable. Concern is already rising about the prospect of a post-election fiscal cliff. Indeed, across the West, central banks have had to deploy an unprecedented array of tools and initiatives in an attempt to offset the effects of fiscal austerity and bank deleveraging.</p>
          <p>But quantitative easing and the like appear to have less effect with every hit. Think how quickly the LTRO wore off. It was absolutely needed, but for &#x20AC;1 trillion, you would have hoped to have got more than a couple of months of feel-good factor. For too many years, the West boosted growth and at least the illusion of prosperity through ever more private debt and ever more public spending and thus, public debt.</p>
          <p>We're now in the painful process of weaning ourselves from that addiction. But the risk is that we swap one set of drugs for another and become overly dependent on what central banks can do. Some action is undoubtedly desirable, but we are already in uncharted territory, so must be extremely thoughtful.</p>
          <p>As we've often said before, Asia is not immune to the woes of Europe and the fragility of economic recovery in the U.S. The West is some two-thirds of the global economy and if it slows, no one is unscathed.</p>
          <p>Yet although Asia is slowing, we remain reasonably confident about the outlook. The underlying structural drivers of growth remain robust. Urbanization, demographics, industrialization, the growth of intra-regional trade and investment. We see no dimming of Asia's longer-term growth prospects.</p>
          <p>And while some degree of near-term slowdown appears inevitable, policymakers in many of our markets have far more room for maneuver than their counterparts in the West. Of course, the scope for policy errors in every market has its own specific issues. But at this stage, we're not expecting a sharp departure from the growth trajectory; more, some bumps in the road.</p>
          <p>We're not complacent, but with demand for financial services growing at around twice GDP growth at this level of per capita income, and with ample room to win market share, we still see exciting prospects for growth across our markets.</p>
          <p>It should therefore be no surprise that we're not changing our strategy. We will continue to focus on Asia, Africa and the Middle East. We will continue to invest for growth and we will continue to be obsessed with the basics of banking, balancing the pursuit of growth with disciplined management of costs and risks, keeping a firm grip on liquidity and capital.</p>
          <p>The strength of our balance sheet remains a powerful source of competitive advantage. We're well capitalized, already exceeding Basel III requirements, and highly liquid, both in local currencies and in U.S. dollars. We're a leader in the internationalization of the renminbi.</p>
          <p>To give you more of a sense of how we're running the bank, I thought I'd highlight a few themes that run through our strategy. First, continued investment for growth. Whilst we've delivered positive jaws of over 2% in the first half of 2012 and maintaining our guidance for flat to positive jaws for the year as a whole, we are continuing to invest at pace in both businesses. Indeed, given the opportunities we see arising from the turbulence and the disarray of our competitor, we're stepping up the pace of investment. Most of this is to fuel organic growth.</p>
          <p>Whilst we do look out for acquisitions to build scale, gain market access or gain critical capabilities, the primary driver of growth is organic investment in our businesses. For example, we continue to invest in building out our distribution networks in key markets. To give you a sense of the pace of the expansion in China, this slide, which shows 87 branches as at the end of June, is already out of date. Last week, we opened our 90th branch in Dalian, having opened our 88th and 89th in Changsha and Tianjin a couple of weeks ago. In fact, I was there for the opening of the Changsha branch. We expect to reach 100 branches in China by the time we announce the full year results early next year.</p>
          <p>In India, we now have 94 branches, considerably more than any other international bank. And we also expect to hit 100 mark there by the same time. At this point, we will be present in 43 cities across India.</p>
          <p>In Africa, where we currently have 183 branches across 14 markets, we're also significantly stepping up the pace of network expansion and anticipate that we will have some 250 branches or so within the next couple of years.</p>
          <p>Expanding our distribution is not just the bank branches. We've been increasing investment in mobile and Internet channels. For example, Breeze, our suite of award-winning retail banking apps, is now available in seven markets. In fact, in consumer banking, we now offer mobile banking in 33 markets, Internet banking in 29, and are rolling out new products and services at pace.</p>
          <p>But technology-driven innovation isn't just about electronic channels. We're also investing in standardized platforms across our markets and in both businesses. This is crucial to achieving continuous improvements in productivity, high levels of system stability, better risk management and rapid rollout of innovation.</p>
          <p>The benefits for clients and customers are very tangible. In consumer banking, customer complaints have halved from 2009. We've also seen significant improvements in our Net Promoter Score, the measure of those customers who would positively recommend us.</p>
          <p>The benefits for productivity are equally impressive. Through automation, hubbing and process reengineering, we are driving continuous improvement in cost efficiency. For example, in trade finance, the number of transactions processed per employee have increased by 35% since 2008, while over 95% of cash payments are now electronically initiated.</p>
          <p>By making ourselves more productive, we maximize headroom to keep investing in innovation. Again, using trade finance as an example, we've rolled out a standardized state-of-the-art platform we call Trade Port, maximizing straight-through processing rates and providing better risk management through centralized management trade limits and utilizations.</p>
          <p>In May, we executed the world's first end-to-end automated trade finance transaction using SWIFT's Bank Payment Obligation concept through our Straight2Bank platform. This electronically matches documentation between banks on either end of the trade flow, enabling faster payment for goods and quicker shipping. This kind of innovation is critical, since trade finance is at the core of Standard Chartered. From the outset of the financial crisis, our trade finance income has more than doubled from $470 million in the first half of 2008 to $958 million at the end of June, a compound annual growth rate of 19%.</p>
          <p>International commercial banking, trade, cash, lending, FX is the heart of our wholesale banking franchise. Our strength in facilitating cross-border trade and investment explain our continued success in our Americas, UK and Europe region. Indeed, it might seem a bit odd that we've delivered such rapid income growth in the West, both in this first half, up 26% year-on-year and by a compound annual growth rate of 28% over the last five years.</p>
          <p>This is not about us drifting into doing domestic business in such markets. It's purely about winning market share and facilitating trade and investment between Europe and the Americas and our core markets. We're helping German companies sell cars in China, Indian companies make acquisitions in the UK, U.S. or French companies raise capital from Asian investors.</p>
          <p>A good example is BP's renminbi bond in September 2011, a first for BP and actually the first ever renminbi bond lifted in London. We acted as joint lead manager and book runner and also assisted BP in remitting the proceeds onshore to mainland China.</p>
          <p>We manage wholesale banking as a network, not as a collection of individual geographies, identifying key trade and investment corridors and deploying resources to capture the opportunities. For example, we are uniquely placed to facilitate the explosive growth in trade and investment between China and Africa. No other bank has both a large network and deep relationships in China and a large network and deep relationships in sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
          <p>Over the last decade, China's trade with Kenya has grown 30 times, with Nigeria, 18 times, with Ghana, 19 times. In fact, trade between China and sub-Saharan Africa has risen 20-fold in the same period, from just under $6 billion to nearly $110 billion.</p>
          <p>In July, we brought the leadership of our African businesses to Beijing to meet senior leaders, media and clients. In fact, of the 300 business leaders from Africa attending the recent forum on China-Africa Cooperation, hosted by Premier Wen Jiabao, 20 were from Standard Chartered, the single-largest group by some margin.</p>
          <p>This is a good example of how we're building our business in China. We're sticking to what we know and where we can add value. In wholesale banking, we are focusing on assisting the state-owned enterprises as they reach out overseas, such as to Africa, and supporting multinational corporate as they exploit the opportunities of China's growth and above all, on working with China's new and rapidly growing private sector companies, since these are often undeserved by the local banks and represent the future of China's economy.</p>
          <p>We have no exposure to local government investment vehicles, don't try to compete for vanilla local currency business for the big state-owned enterprises and our commercial real estate exposure is minimal.</p>
          <p>Likewise, in consumer banking, we focus on SMEs and more affluent individuals, what we call the high-value segments. We are not yet making profits in consumer banking in China as we invest in building out the business at pace, but the number of active customers in the high value segments grew 31% in the first half of 2012.</p>
          <p>We're also leveraging the trade investment links across Greater China, exploiting our presence across the Mainland, Hong Kong and Taiwan. Whilst wholesale banking income in China grew by 25% in the first half of 2012, China network income, booked elsewhere, much of it in the rest of Greater China, grew by 56%.</p>
          <p>As the business develops, so too does the way we manage risk. We are continually investing to enhance our risk management infrastructure and capabilities. But our fundamental approach to risk has stayed consistent over many years. We remain cautious and on the lookout for trouble. We haven't changed our risk appetite and don't plan to. We're extremely watchful about the current environment, about the way our markets and clients are responding to the global macro developments, about the potential second or third order consequences of possible stress events like further strains in the Eurozone.</p>
          <p>We have seen some increase in loan impairments in both businesses, but from very low levels and we remain very comfortable with the shape and quality of our loan book. In fact, it's at times like these when the relationships between a bank and its clients really gets tested. We know our clients very well. Many of our relationships go back decades or generations. We stand by them through good times and bad. That's what we did in the Asia crisis in the late '90s, through the SARS epidemic in 2002, throughout the global financial crisis in 2008-2009 and it's what we're doing now.</p>
          <p>That doesn't mean we're passive or simply agree to everything. On the contrary, we engage intensively with our clients as partners, actively helping them navigate the challenges they face and grab the opportunities they see. In our view, that's what banks should do and what they're for.</p>
          <p>The bank is in good shape and our businesses have good momentum, but we are not at all complacent about the external challenges. The global economy is fragile, with the risks to the downside. Politics and regulatory change continue to pose huge challenges, eroding our economics, creating obstacles to growth.</p>
          <p>We are certainly not immune to such factors. For example, the economic and political paralysis in India has slowed the business and the decline in the rupee has resulted in considerable FX drag. But our enthusiasm for India and our commitment to investing in the market remains undiminished, given the strength of the longer term growth story.</p>
          <p>In India, as elsewhere, we need to strike the right balance between tactically responding to immediate developments and keeping a view on the longer-term prize. This is a critical challenge for us as management, something we're continuously focused on dynamically fine-tuning.</p>
          <p>Taking a longer-term view of our business is one of the underlying tenets of our strategy and culture. We build long-standing relationships. We don't grab transactions. We build sustainably profitable franchises. We don't have proprietary trading desks. We build businesses that deliver a wider social and economic benefit. We're selective and turn things down that we don't understand or don't like the look of.</p>
          <p>Our culture and values have never been more important. As a source of competitive advantage, as the ultimate protection against risk, our culture and values are our first and last line of defense. Doing the right thing, supporting our clients through good times and bad, being here for good. These may sound like glib phrases, but they underpin why Standard Chartered stand on, underscore why we're on track for 10 years of record profits.</p>
          <p>For me, as Chief Executive, our culture and values are a top priority. Something we can never take for granted. Something we embed in our systems of measurement and reward.</p>
          <p>We start the second half extraordinarily well positioned in an extraordinarily turbulent world. We have multiple engines of income growth, the balance sheet strength to support our customers and clients, the capability to step up investment spend while maintaining a tight grip on expenses, and a robust approach to risk borne of long experience of managing through economic crises.</p>
          <p>I'd like to take this opportunity to thank you, our shareholders, for your support, and to thank our staff for their unwavering professionalism and commitment. They are what make Standard Chartered here for good.</p>
          <p>We start the second half acutely alert to the risks, but also, excited by the opportunities. Our businesses have good momentum and we are stepping up investment. We know what you expect from us: double-digit income and earnings per share growth, cost growing in line with income, mid-teens ROE over the medium term. And we remain very focused on achieving these objectives.</p>
          <p>Thank you. John, Richard and I will now take your questions in London. Jaspal, <mark type="ph" /> Ben and Julian (54:45) will take your questions in Hong Kong. And <mark type="ph" /> Sunil and Anurag (54:48) will take questions in Mumbai. So as the usual format, if you could raise your hands, and then when the mic comes to you, if you could say who you are and the institution you're from. So where do we start? Here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning. It's Tom Rayner from Exane BNP Paribas. Could I have two questions, please? Maybe the first for Richard and then one on strategy for Peter, if that's okay? I'd just like to get a sense of margins in the trade business on a sort of Q1, Q2 basis, because my sense from the Q1 was that you tried to push margins up, but actually lost a bit of share and then, the view was that, that was going to be reserved. So it seems like you've got your market share back. I'm just wondering if subsequently, the margin versus that Q1 has actually come down a little bit? So I've just got a sense of what happened there. And then second one on strategy, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you ask us &#x2013; give me the second one first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I might like to swap the questions around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we'll go through...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the strategy, I mean, it's fairly high level. If you look at slide 35 and all of those risks, and you mentioned yourself that the risk for global growth is to the downside. I just want to get a sense whether you think that shareholders might not be better served rather than accelerating investment, voting on sort of higher risk areas within consumer, whether a slower balance sheet growth strategy a bit more focused on tighter cost management might lead to higher returns and higher dividend payouts at some stage. It's obviously a big question. But that's &#x2013; I'd like you to maybe address that one as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, why don't you take the margins question on trade finance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can take the other one as well, if you like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, look, on the margins, without giving the specific basis points movements, we had clearly a 17-basis-point pick-up in margins. You're quite right in your narrative about what we saw in trade balance. We actually repriced our trade finance businesses in the late part of 2011. And then in the first quarter, we held pricing and we did see lower volumes. We also saw that in part, I think, because we had two particular competitive pressures that were more marked than general competition.</p>
          <p>One was Japanese banks. I think <mark type="ph" /> Tommy (57:36) talked about that before, the Japanese banks, certainly Q1 came in quite assertively and the second was actually also the European banks in the initial burst of enthusiasm post-LTRO1.</p>
          <p>We lost <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:54)we stayed firm on pricing. Actually what then happened as those competitive elements eased is actually, we were able to grow our volumes, grow our market share quite strongly. I think towards the end of &#x2013; towards the latter part of Q2, there's been some slight, but a slight downward, not push, but downward movement on margins but I think the business has got itself positioned really strong. So the net outcome of 13% growth in assets and contingents with a margin picture up 17 basis points and very good build and very good share pickup, I think, has actually &#x2013; the business has played it, I think wholesale has played it absolutely right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on your strategic question, it's a very good question. I mean the &#x2013; we are &#x2013; sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is this a joke?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we know very well that the shareholders want both from us. They want growth from us and they want returns from us. And we are sort of dynamically managing the tradeoffs between those all the time. But we do see an opportunity to take this moment to seize market share and to further build out our businesses in some of our key markets. And although the world has a lot of Lloyds and particularly if you're sitting in London, things can look pretty sort of dire. You referred to one slide, but I'd also refer you back to the slide where I showed you the relative GDP growth rates. Our markets, even when they slow down, are going to slow down to GDP growth rates that the West didn't achieve, even when it was doing really well.</p>
          <p>And if you couple that with where they are in terms of financial penetration, the development of their  bond markets and so on, there are very, very significant opportunities to grow our business. And we want to make sure we are investing to build businesses that are not just sort of nice businesses in these markets, but businesses of real scale and strategic sustainability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't we start on this side and just go &#x2013; why don't we just go right next to you for the moment and then we'll swap over a bit. Rohith?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Rohith Chandra-Rajan from Barclays, if I could have two as well, please? First one on sort of investment spend, I guess you've talked to us, this is probably the fourth time you've talked to us this year and I was just wondering, just in terms of investment spend, you've shown us where you anticipate spending it. Just wondering if you could give some indication as to the step-up in costs you're expecting as a result in the second half and how your thinking on that might have changed over the four times that you've spoken to us this year?</p>
          <p>And then, since you want them both at once, the other's just on credit quality. The India NPLs in the wholesale bank, NPL ratio has more than doubled to 9.5% in the half year and you talked about stress testing the book. I was just wondering if you could give us a little bit more color around where you're seeing that NPL formation and where you draw your comfort in terms of the outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, on the investment spend, what we talked to earlier, we talked about stepping it up a bit and that was in the order of sort of $20 million, $30 million. Now we're stepping it up more than that original to give you bit more flavor about the sort of cost run-through. It's very broad-based and it's not &#x2013; we're not investing in things that we weren't doing anyway. It's a continuation of investment in our systems platforms, in our people, in our branch networks and so on. So, do you want to pick up that, I guess, to touch on the credit quality point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. On the investment spend, the P&amp;L impact, Peter is quite right of our discussions with you in April, it was around a $25 million to $30 million impact to cost P&amp;L in the second half. We've now just released, authorized $75 million to $80 million of incremental to that $25 million spend. So if you had $100 million plus in terms of increased investment spend in the second half over the first half, that would give you an indication of our acceleration. These are accelerations of investment over our original budget demands.</p>
          <p>And they derive really from our view about, one, how well we're holding BAU costs and that's giving clear capacity. But, again in the overall framework of jaws. So we've seen very good, stable growth in revenues. We've taken a forward view on that and we think we've got very good capacity to accelerate investment.</p>
          <p>The other thing to be mindful of is how that flows through into then 2013. One has to be slightly careful as one invests that one fits to the full-year impact of that investment through to the following year and I would anticipate that $100 million will be around $160 million or so to the 2013 annualized costs.</p>
          <p>On credit quality, I mean generally, before I come to India, as we said, the loan impairment and also, the NPLs predominantly are rising in two markets in wholesale banking, we're talking in India and the UAE. As I look at the loan impairments, we said it's a very small number of individual accounts where we've actually provided and which are making the main contribution to the growth in NPLs. We've clearly had a very good chance to &#x2013; more than chance, a very good opportunity to review those and we provide for them, I believe, conservatively. And that's why I think the cover ratios we have in wholesale, particularly to the value of collateral, also maintains a very prudent stance.</p>
          <p>So the formation of NPLs is predominantly matching where you'd expect &#x2013; where you'll see the LI, it's India and it's the UAE and everywhere else, frankly. In wholesale, we see no signs of stress in any of our other geographies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Rich, wouldn't you say loan impairments overall were pretty low anyway in relative terms?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, in wholesale, loan impairments is 36 basis points in relation to loans and advances. And so I think we have to hold this in context. So it's up 42%, but it's 36 basis points. Actually, I think that level of charge is wholly appropriate versus again, without <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:04:51) the shape and diversity and nature of the assets that the wholesale bank has. 63% is under one year, high collateral and limited exposure to problematic clauses there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:05:06).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi guys. I've got two questions, if I can. Firstly on U.S., Europe, I remember at the full year, you made a point of talking about the opportunity and clearly, that's come through in the first half, with client revenues up 27%. So I was wondering if you could just expand on what you said, Peter, in your chat, and maybe talk about the &#x2013; how you see the opportunity longer term and the revenue opportunity longer term and just expand on that a bit?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, more of a bigger picture question, really. But clearly, there's a lot of concern, you talked on the macro slowdown. But there's a lot of concern about the slowing volumes in Asia, clearly trade, et cetera. And I was wondering if you could just talk about and try to wrap it up for us about the outlook? But touching on the drivers of volume, you've mentioned market share repeatedly in terms of what you can do, but also margin, and just try and wrap it out for us in terms of how you see the outlook over the next six to 18 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. On the first point about U.S., UK, Europe, about region, actually, I think it's been a story that we probably haven't talked about a lot, because it's not just a story of this half, but it's actually been a story of the last five years. But it's been a story with a somewhat different shift. If we were going back to 2008, 2009, 2010, a lot of the growth would have been in the Americas. And we were, in a sense, benefiting from the disarray of some of our U.S.-based competitors. And U.S. multinationals doing business in Asia were looking to us increasingly for support in conducting their business.</p>
          <p>Increasingly, Europe has been a stronger story. And again, it's partly a competitive thing. It's just partly a reflection of the disarray of some of our European competitors. But I also think that we, ourselves, have got better at making the linkages work and actually running the business to support these clients who run very sort of complex multinational treasuries and so on.</p>
          <p>And we do see significant further opportunity to continue to build this kind of business in both the Americas and in Europe. We remain very disciplined that we are not interested in doing domestic business in either part in the world. So everything we do is focused on, how is this linked with Asia, Africa and the Middle East? We don't want to sort of get too enthusiastic and drift off strategy. But even taking a very, very focused approach, there is very significant opportunity. I mean, the Eurozone remains China's largest trading partner in the world, despite all its travails.</p>
          <p>On your broader question, which was really quite a broad question, look, there's, no doubt, considerable macro uncertainty in the world and trade flows tend to operate with a beta greater than one, like, they tend to magnify either the positive or negative. And so we entirely expect to see quite a lot of volatility in trade flows. The bit that is secondly growing quite strongly, actually, is intra-regional trade. The traditional trade of sort of Asian exports to Europe and the U.S. is very vulnerable to what's going on with the West. Intra-regional trade is driven by different factors such as the growth in China, Chinese consumers' consumption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You should mention Africa, too, maybe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, and Africa is &#x2013; Africa, I spoke of in the presentation. I mean, and a lot of that has been driven by commodities. But there's also increasing Chinese exports to Africa as you get more of a consuming class developing in China. I mean, it's difficult for us to give a very definitive picture on how this translates into any sort of specific numbers for us. But what I would say is that we wouldn't expect trade growth to be incredibly strong and underlying volumes of trade, because the world economy isn't incredibly strong.</p>
          <p>However, we do see some withdrawal of capacity, particularly from Western banks and that creates a &#x2013; and a change in the shape of the trade in terms of where it's growing and where it's strongest. Both the withdrawal of capacity and the growth of these new corridors in China, Africa is a good example. Plays to our advantage.</p>
          <p>The margin picture that we've already touched on varies from period to period, depending upon, critically, the availability of dollars. And dollar liquidity has become one of the more &#x2013; offshore dollar liquidity, i.e. offshore from the U.S., has become one of the more sort of unpredictable and sort of in flux variables. But we are in a position to take advantage of that, because we are highly liquid in dollars. We have the trade finance infrastructure, we have the relationships, but there will be sort of ups and downs and volatility along the way. I don't know if you wanted to add at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could give you some &#x2013; the trade picture and stats we're seeing in our market, trade finance now growing at around 7%, global trades growing around 5%. And that 7% across our footprint from WGO stats are slower than a year ago, which we were over 20%. But the thing about that 7% means that the rate of growth we're getting in assets and contingents, you get a sense of some of the momentum we have as we win share.</p>
          <p>Interesting in trade, we're seeing a very good growth in our correspondent bank businesses in FI, where that income &#x2013; that business was at growing 50%. It's around a quarter of the business and it's growing at 50% as we got better share, I think, in corresponding bank relationships. Other areas, frankly, where we see very good market share pickup would be corporate finance, we've got an 18% increase in deals transacted.</p>
          <p>In the cash management, mandate it's been around 30% more transactions in the first half this year than in the comparative period. If you look at our rates business, we saw a 63% higher volume in rates, smaller transactions and a 15% growth in our client active rates, client business. So there is a range of areas where I think partly through the technology delivery, partly through by being open for business, liquid. And we also saw a bit of a kick from our ratings upgrade, particularly coming through to rates. I think we're seeing pretty good momentum there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we take one from this side of the &#x2013; yeah? Jason?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning. It's Jason Napier from Deutsche Bank. One for Richard and then one for Peter, both on India, please. As Rohith already highlighted, NPLS have more than doubled half-on-half and the 39% NPL cover is, I think, the lowest geographic coverage that you've got in the group. So I wonder whether you wouldn't mind talking a little about the profile of those NPLs?</p>
          <p>And also just talking, you mentioned being confident about the medium term outlook for that market. But I noticed the loan growth half-on-half in India is actually pretty good in wholesale, despite currency. And so, I wonder whether you could talk about where you are investing in terms of balance sheet growth in India?</p>
          <p>And then, the second question for Peter is really around the distribution investment plan in India. The priority sector lending requirements have got much, much higher agricultural component going forward. You've got five years to adapt, but I just wonder whether where you're putting branches and outlets will need to change as you look to comply with those new rules?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should I &#x2013; if I take the first one, the best for me to answer, I think, is to give you some profile around the underlying growth. And I think where we've seen growth has predominantly been in our transaction banking and trade businesses. When I think about the overall book, you've got a wholesale book onshore and offshore of just over $19 billion and it splits around $6.5 billion, $6.8 billion, but $6.5 billion or so is onshore and just over $12 billion is offshore.</p>
          <p>If I look at the number of borrowing relationships I have within that, there are 3,600 essentially borrowing relationships, and of those, I only have 24 which are over $100 million. So in terms of where I can look really quite closely and hard at the larger numbers, large exposures; there are only 24 of those. 28% of the book is in trade, 55% of the book exits in a year, the average maturity of the book is about 1.8 years.</p>
          <p>We had a more significant concentration to telecoms a year ago, it was 26% or 27% of the book, it's now down at 17%, and our next concentrations would be in infrastructure, which is predominantly ports and roads at 9%. The commercial real estate book in India is, again, it's about $1 billion and the LTV on that is in the mid 40%, so in terms of profile, there's a lot of detail in that. If you step back from it, it's a wholesale book that looks much like many of our books, actually. We don't have significant exposure into things like real estate. It has significant trade within it, it's short tenure. And where we're seeing the growth has predominantly been in the transaction banking, predominantly trade finances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the whole subject of private sector lending and distribution, I think the latest proposals of private sector lending have to be seen in the light of also the thinking going on in the &#x2013; by our Minister of Finance around subsidiarization, because essentially, they are creating an incentive in due course to subsidiarize, and I would expect that by the time you get to the end of your five-year timeframe, in fact, they're kind of irrelevant, because anybody they would apply to is likely to have subsidiarized anyway and thus, have a different priority sector lending type of set of rules applying to them. And in any case, these rules are still, in a sense, subject to some discussion and negotiation.</p>
          <p>In terms of where we're putting branches, well, the reality in India is, you only have very limited influence of where you get your branches. And the branches we have been given licenses to open, we've got six more, are all actually in good Tier 2 cities. So we're very pleased to be able to open branches in them. But it's not like we are following a sort of business-led strategy in selecting precisely where those are. Whether the potential advantage is, and I wouldn't want to sort of get too excited about this or get you too excited about this, because I think there's still a lot of policy stuff to happen of &#x2013; one of the potential benefits of the subsidiarized structure, should that come about, would be that one would have greater freedom to open branches, not just in quantum but in terms of selecting where you put them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, should we go in the middle left?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Chira Barua from Sanford Bernstein. Three questions. One very broad on consumer. Where, Peter, do you see consumer growing from here both in terms of markets and products, because that's definitely a lagging business as of now? The two other specifics, one on market risk on the trading VAR. The trading VAR is up significantly. It would be great if we can understand where that's happening and why is it not transferring into market risk capital? Because that's not up significantly.</p>
          <p>And the second one is cost. So how much of your compensation is actually deferred, especially in the wholesale bank. That again will be? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, okay. On the CB momentum, I mean, there's no doubt that CB has slowed down a bit and the primary reasons for that have been in the mortgage markets where we've seen a combination of margin pressure and also, sort of regulatory policy action directed at concerns around housing bubbles and the like.</p>
          <p>But the second reason of course, is that most of the CB business is in local currency and indeed, if you look at CB income growth on a constant currency basis, it was at 8%, not 5%. We are continuing to invest in the businesses. We do see most of the growth coming in what we call the high value segments, so SME, private banking and priority banking and indeed, these all grew faster than consumer banking as a whole. Private banking had a particularly good first half, with income growing 14%. So you will see continued investment in and focus on those three segments.</p>
          <p>In terms of the market, fundamentally, CB will be growing in the markets in which we're in at the moment. We are continuing &#x2013; we're making a very deliberate decision to continue to invest at pace in China, despite the fact that at the moment, the consumer banking business is losing money in China. Indeed, it lost more money this first half than it did the year before, reflecting the pace of investment. I think you'll see us dial up Africa more than we've done in the past. We're seeing increasing opportunity for consumer there. But I think the way to think about it more and more, because it's the way we're driving the strategy, is very much about these key segments, so the priority banking, SME and private banking.</p>
          <p>Richard, do you want to pick up on the VAR and compensation costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean on the VAR, you'll see both the VAR in both the trading book and the non-trading book are both up by broadly equivalent percentages. The non-traded book, frankly, is about 50% from listed private equity, part of which has increased, and the other 50% is simply from higher liquidity balances coming in through ALM, so it's the size of book, size of investment.</p>
          <p>On the trading VAR, that's predominantly from interest rate risk and interest rate positions in a couple of markets including, in the main, India, is what's driven that. The translation through to market risk capital is partly offset by some model improvements that we've had from regulators. On the deferred comp, it's about &#x2013; of the P&amp;L bonus charge in this first half, about 12.5% is deferred &#x2013; is actually flow through from prior years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chintan Joshi from Nomura. Two questions, please. Firstly, on ALM, Richard, you hinted to ALM opportunities in your comments. Can you help us think about the scale and duration of these opportunities? How the outlook for that is in the second half and what geographies are you thinking about there. And then one on mortgage strategy, another half where margins have been developed and you've hinted to competitive pressures in the past. At what stage do you come in and say, we've got to defend market share in some of these geographies and which geographies would that be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I take the second one first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then you do <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:23:45). I mean, to some extent, we've made that shift &#x2013; we've been making that shift already in that we are trading off a bit of margin to defend share. But that's something we are going to manage very dynamically. We're not going to do business on economic rates. But on the other hand, we want to maintain our presence and strength in mortgages, because for many of our customers, it is very much an anchor product in the relationship. And so that is something that we are, as I said, managing very dynamically.</p>
          <p>The one I would highlight, though, as being a bit different and slightly sort of clouding the aggregate numbers is Korea, where this arrangement we've got in which we can, in a sense, pass off fixed rate mortgages, that is going to somewhat distort the aggregate numbers, particularly because we've put about $0.5 billion for it in the first half, but we've got capacity for more like $4.5 billion. So do you want to pick up the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On ALM, we earned $490 million on ALM in the first half, up 14% on the first half of last year, flat to the second half of last year. I think the fact that it was flat gives you part of a clue, part of the income arises from simply high liquid asset buffers, higher levels of liquidity held and then invested.</p>
          <p>The other thing ALM has done, I think, very effectively is that we've benefited from low short-end rates and a slightly positive yield curve and we have, as investments have matured, we've invested them at slightly longer tenure up the yield curve to pick up some &#x2013; and pick up revenue.</p>
          <p>What would my guidance be? Actually, on geographies, it's quite a difficult call. We invest, of course, about 30 different yield curves, so I don't carry that pattern in my head. In terms of what I would expect in the second half, I'd expect to see $40 million to $60 million of lower income. I could be surprised by that to the upside, but I think it tends to move in that type of direction second half on first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just following up, slightly longer duration, could you &#x2013; would you want to quantify that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The average maturity in our loan book is 277 days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Sandy Chen from Cenkos Securities. I've got two questions. One cheeky one and another one on completely kind of trigger question. The cheeky one is, Richard, would you take the Barclays job bash him up, in the future, would you take the Bank of England job as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm answering that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was that one question or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall we hear the serious question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's hear your serious question, because why you prepare your long-detailed answer to that first one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It won't take long.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. The other question is really related to &#x2013; and I think you partially answered that with the ALM response is, have you seen deposit inflows or capital, all this talk about positive outflows, capital outflows from a troubled Eurozone, you must be seeing some inflows as a result of that, or are you? And secondly, related again to Eurozone, the sort of inverted negative points or repo curves, has that affected the ALM business or your treasury business in any way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the deposit inflows, I mean, the short answer is yes, we have been seeing signs of inflows into us, particularly from more rating sensitive counterparties. And so, it's often things like real money funds or public sector-related institutions and so on. And indeed, what tends to happen when things get worse is that one of our biggest problems tends to be what to do with all the money that flows in. In terms of the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:28:23).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps as material?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's material to us. Any? Oh sorry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no. I forgot about that to the first question and can I say publicly, I think Richard Meddings is an outstanding executive and I'm not at all surprised that the media are speculating about Richard being a candidate or a potential candidate for the Barclays job as indeed for the Lloyds job, as indeed for many other jobs that come along.</p>
          <p>Richard does a fantastic job here at Standard Chartered and he knows that he has a tremendous future with this bank. This bank is still going places. We have got a lot still to do. And I am confident Richard will continue to be a very important and leading player in the future of this bank. Does that answer your question? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your thoughts about <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:29:21) government?</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:29:25).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My answer to that is, the country isn't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Getting this show back on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Move on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions on what we've done? Oh, good. We can now go off to beach volleyball. John, do you want to-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I summarize?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Go ahead, summarize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well first of all, as usual, a very big thank you to you for coming today to these results presentations. In a nutshell, I think you'll agree, a strong set of results. To quote Peter, a boring set of results in many way because it's a consistency of delivering an execution on the strategy which we are confident will continue to deliver value for our shareholders in the future. And the business has momentum although we are still very mindful of market conditions, the turbulence which many of you this morning referred to, nonetheless, we are confident that we are in the right markets. We do have the right strategy. And as I said earlier to you, sir, we have the right people. So, thank you for coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>