<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1295278" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7788</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">John Peace, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Richard Meddings, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Peter Sands, Group Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Raul Sinha</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Leigh Goodwin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Michael Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Mike Trippitt</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Arturo de Frias</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Robert Law</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">John Armitage</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Peter Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Thomas Rayner</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Ian Smillie</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Rohith Chandra-Rajan</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Rohith Chandra Rajan</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Andrew Lim</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Manus Costello</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Steven Hayne</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, London, and good afternoon, Hong Kong. And welcome to the Standard Chartered 2009 Annual Results Presentation. I'm delighted to announce that 2009 was the seventh successive year of record income and profits. The Bank has used its strong capital and liquidity position and its increasingly powerful brand to capture market share from competitors and to deepen relationships with customers and clients.</p>
          <p>Standard Chartered grew income and profit despite the economic downturn across the world and significant interest rate and FX headwinds. Income increased 9% to $15.2 billion. Profit before tax rose to 13% &#x2013; rose by 13% to $5.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Normalized earnings per share were up 2.8% to $1.798. The board is recommending a final dividend of $0.448 per share, making an annual dividend of $0.6603 per share, which is up by 7%.</p>
          <p>Throughout the financial crisis and economic downturn, we've consistently produced strong results. We have achieved this by sticking to our strategy and supporting our customers and clients through these difficult times. Throughout the crisis we stayed open for business.</p>
          <p>We helped many of our customers buy their homes, increasing our mortgage lending by $10 billion to a total of $58 billion. In 2009, our total lending to customers, clients and financial institutions increased by $28 billion, an increase of over 10%. The Bank now lends more than $250 billion.</p>
          <p>Longevity in our markets is something we are very proud of. Not only does it give us the local knowledge to serve our customers well, it also makes us part of their community. We have been working with many of our clients for generations. And the downturn as uniquely helped us to reinforce these valuable relationships.</p>
          <p>We've managed a way through the crisis very well, much to the benefit of clients and shareholders. However, like most bankers, we are conscious that the world has changed, and that we must work together with regulators, governments and the rest of industry to secure a better financial system if we are to support the global recovery, and to focus on the socially useful aspects of banking.</p>
          <p>Peter will be saying more about our views on regulation in a moment, but let me first just touch on the bonus issue, which has been so much in the spotlight in recent weeks. In the geographic footprint in which we operate, competition for talented employees is red hot. Today we employ over 75,000 people, only 2,000 of whom are based in the U.K. We must therefore take a global perspective in setting a remuneration policy.</p>
          <p>We pay for good performance. We do not reward failure. And we have continued to produce record income and profits on a sustained basis. We have increased our capital base, raised our dividend, continue to invest in the business and have generated substantial value for our shareholders over an extended period of time.</p>
          <p>We have not used government liquidity, capital or asset protection support. On balance, the board has therefore concluded that it is in the interests of the business and our shareholders to reward the management team for yet another successful year and to retain top talent in these fiercely competitive markets, but only when it is appropriate to do so.</p>
          <p>We are also satisfied that our remuneration policies encourage long-term performance and do not reward short-term risk-taking. We fully support the FSA code on remuneration, to which we were already broadly aligned last year, and we have gone still further this year. So we will continue to reward performance within that framework. However, in setting this year's bonus pool we did take into account the U.K. bonus tax and we've spread the cost of this across the business globally. Our compensation as a proportion of revenue has fallen in each of the last two years to 32%.</p>
          <p>For all the industry and media discussion on regulation and remuneration, it is crucial that the balance of regulatory reform is right to avoid unintended consequences that could potentially hinder global recovery. The best way to protect against financial stress and ensure an effective, functioning financial system is to have sound, well-managed, well-governed institutions.</p>
          <p>At Standard Chartered we do have a proven strategy and a world-class management team, both of which have withstood the test of the last couple of years. We have also taken steps to further strengthen our corporate governance with new appointments to the board and changes to the board committee structure. Mike Rees and Jaspal Bindra have both been appointed Group Executive Directors. Mike has been CEO of Wholesale Banking since 2002. And Jaspal is our CEO in Asia.</p>
          <p>We have also appointed three new Non-Executive Director. Dr. Han Seung-soo was Prime Minister of the Republic of Korea in 2008 and 2009. Richard Delbridge has had a wide-ranging banking career. And Simon Lowth is currently an Executive Director and Chief Financial Officer of AstraZeneca Plc.</p>
          <p>I would also like to take this opportunity to publicly thank Gareth Bullock, another of our Group Executive Directors, for the significant contribution he has made to the success of the Bank over many years. Gareth will be stepping down from the board on the 30th of April.</p>
          <p>In 2009 the board conducted a review and implemented changes to the board committee structures to reinforce the high standards of corporate governance. This included separating the existing Audit and Risk Committees to accentuate the focus on risk management.</p>
          <p>So in summary, 2009 was another successful year for the Bank. We faced challenges in the global economic and regulatory environment, but the board believes Standard Chartered has the right strategy for sustainable growth and the Bank enters 2010 with real resilience and momentum.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Richard who will take you through the numbers. Peter will then address some of the macro issues across our markets and our strategic priorities. We'll then take questions. Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Good afternoon, Hong Kong. Good morning, London. As John has said, Standard Chartered has delivered another record performance in 2009 and let me draw out several key highlights.</p>
          <p>Record levels of income, over $15 billion, and record levels of profit, over $5.1 billion. 2009 was the seventh consecutive year of record income and profit, delivering compound annual growth rates of 19% in income and 22% in profit over that period.</p>
          <p>Substantial income momentum. The Group has generated in excess of $1 billion of incremental organic income. Income on a reported basis is up 9% year-on-year, or on a constant currency basis, up 14%.</p>
          <p>Demonstrable cost control. Costs are well controlled, up 4% on 2008 delivering positive jaws. A proactive approach to risk. The risk environment is improving as reflected in improvement in leading risk indicators and total impairment has fallen in the second half.</p>
          <p>Strong profit growth of $583 million, up 13%, or on a constant currency basis, up 18%. Ongoing capital strength. We have generated organic Core Tier 1 equity of $3.2 billion and raised $1.7 billion through an equity placing. We have managed risk-weighted assets well, growing by 13%. The Core Tier 1 ratio grew to 8.9%, up from 6.1% only 18 months ago.</p>
          <p>Liquidity. We have further strengthened our robust liquidity position, attracting good levels and an improving mix of high-quality deposits. Our A/D ratio remains very strong at 78.6%. Normalized return on equity of 14.3%.</p>
          <p>These are excellent results and even more so given the low interest rate environment and the impact of foreign exchange headwinds. Now let me take you through the numbers.</p>
          <p>Group performance. At a Group level, income has grown 9% driven by excellent momentum in Wholesale Banking, but also a consistent quarter-on-quarter improvement in performance in Consumer Banking. Expenses are benefiting from strong management discipline and have grown 4%, resulting in positive jaws of 5%.</p>
          <p>Loan impairment, although up 51% year-on-year, was down 16% or some $180 million in the second half over the first half. Operating profit of $5.15 billion was up 13%.</p>
          <p>Turning to performance metrics. Dividend per share has grown 7%. Normalized EPS has risen 3% and includes the impact of the rights issue and the placing but also, as mentioned at the time of the interim results, a higher year-on-year effective tax rate.</p>
          <p>Normalized EPS excludes four main items: the impact of the buyback of Tier 2 notes of $264 million; the provision of $170 million taken against structured notes issued by PEM Group in Taiwan; a one-off tax charge relating to the finalization of prior year U.K. tax computations of $190 million; and $58 million in relation to the U.K. bank bonus tax.</p>
          <p>Balance sheet. The balance sheet continues to be conservatively positioned, well diversified and highly liquid. The Group remains strongly liquid both in parts and as a whole, with a diverse and growing funding base.</p>
          <p>Current accounts and savings accounts, or CASA, grew by 34% or some $40 billion, with time deposits falling $11 billion since 2008. We have focused on improving the mix of our deposit base and the proportion of CASA has increased to 53% of total Group deposits from 43% at the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>Wholesale continues to win significant cash mandates across a variety of markets. And Consumer is a high-quality deposit-gatherer, providing further resilience to the Group. Total Group deposits increased 8%.</p>
          <p>Our focus on liabilities and disciplined deployment of the balance sheet has again resulted in a strong ratio of customer loans to customer deposits, the A/D ratio, which end 2009 stood at 78.6%. The A/D ratio in all of our major geographies is under 100%. The Group remains a strong net interbank lender and the liquidity ratio has strengthened significantly to 26.2%.</p>
          <p>Turning to assets. Our loan book is well diversified by country and by sector. Our balance sheet remains as before a source of differentiation and strength for the Group. We have low loan-to-values on our mortgage book, with an average of just over 50%. Short maturity profile on our Wholesale loan book with around 70% of the book under one year.</p>
          <p>Our ABS carrying value is now just under $3 billion, or some 0.7% of assets, and we remain confident in the quality of the portfolio. We have low exposure to commercial real estate, to level 3 assets and to leveraged loans.</p>
          <p>Overall exposures are diversified over geography and sector with no material concentrations. Our largest individual geography accounts for 18% of total Group loans. Cover ratios have strengthened in both businesses, which positions us well as we enter 2010. The balance sheet remains robust and well diversified.</p>
          <p>Capital. The Group's strong capital position continues to improve as we organically generated some $3.2 billion of Core Tier 1 equity and we are proactively improving both the quantum and quality of capital. As you will recall we also raised $1.7 billion in an equity placing in August. Throughout the year we have had good support from capital markets through our funding and non-equity Tier 1 issuances.</p>
          <p>As a bank, within our funding profile, we have very low levels of refinancing maturing over the next few years, only some $8 billion until the end of 2013. And this will be increasingly important given the massive refinancing needs for the European, and in particular the U.K., banking sector. Core Tier 1 is up at 8.9%, total Tier 1 is at 11.5% and total capital is at 16.5%. We are very well capitalized, especially in light of our conservative balance sheet asset profile.</p>
          <p>Now the Consumer Banking performance. The repositioning of the Consumer Banking business is progressing well, as evidenced by a range of financial and non-financial metrics. The business has good momentum as we exit 2009 and an improving risk picture.</p>
          <p>For the full year Consumer Banking income fell 5% and expenses fell 3% with operating profit before tax down 22% to $867 million. Momentum in the second half of 2009 has, however, been good and profit in the second half of the year was up 49% on the first half.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking has seen good balance sheet velocity for both assets and liabilities. Loans have grown 17%, primarily in secured product as we have taken good market share in a number of key markets. And deposits grew 11%. The percentage of new CASA that comes from payroll accounts has doubled year-on-year. And Consumer Banking is contributing some $35 billion of surplus liquidity to the Group. Looking at Consumer Banking in more detail.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking income has grown by 10% in the second half of the year over the first. Quarterly income has now risen for four quarters in succession. The business has faced two specific structural headwinds in 2009, being liability margin compression of some 60 basis points and also foreign exchange weakness. Together these two factors have impacted income by some $1 billion, in part offset by good volume growth but also by asset margins holding up well.</p>
          <p>Expenses have fallen in Consumer Banking by 3% year-on-year and, excluding the impact of PEM Group, actually fell by 8%. We have maintained cost discipline, reducing head count by around 3,000 since the end of 2008. And we're seeing increasing efficiencies as a result of hubbing, call center rationalization and standardization of processes.</p>
          <p>In the second half of the year, expenses grew 8% over the first half as we accelerated the level of new investment to some $60 million in the fourth quarter, specifically to underpin our 2010 momentum. During the year we added relationship managers in premium banking, private banking, and in SME. We added 79 new branches whilst relocating and refurbishing over 130 branches, invested in Internet and mobile banking and we increased marketing spend.</p>
          <p>The Consumer Banking loan impairment charge has increased to $1,052 million, up 12% on 2008. Loan impairment in the second half of the year fell 13% on the first half as the credit environment stabilized.</p>
          <p>We've continued to focus on secured assets. 76% of the loan book is fully secured, 8% is partially secured, and 60% is unsecured. We've tightened our underwriting standards, reshaped the unsecured business away from high-risk segments, increased collections capacity by 10% and migrated towards government-guaranteed loans in the SME business.</p>
          <p>Looking at income in more detail, wealth management fee income has grown quarter-on-quarter during the year. Fourth quarter fee income was up over 35% on the first quarter, reflecting improving sentiment and increasing sales of fund products in our key markets. Singapore and Taiwan performed particularly well. Wealth management including deposits is down from 47% of total Consumer Banking income in 2008 to 40% in 2009.</p>
          <p>Mortgages have performed well with good margins and market shares up in Hong Kong, in Korea and in Singapore. In Singapore, we captured 15% of new business in the year and in Hong Kong we captured 17%.</p>
          <p>SME income fell 12% year-on-year, although income in the second half of the year was up by 12% on the first half. Deposits in SME are around twice the level of loan balances and grew 21%. Loans grew 14% to $13.3 billion. The SME business has been reshaped and derisked with increasing focus on secured lending and increased use of government-guarantee schemes. Around 60% of the SME book is secured.</p>
          <p>Impairment. Now let me draw out the key points on this slide. Looking at mortgages, loan impartment has fallen in the second half of the year. Delinquency trends in our largest markets remained broadly stable. Within SME, you can see that impairment has decreased significantly since the first half of the year. Almost $2 billion of SME loans are now booked under government-guarantee schemes and we have continued to decrease the size of the unsecured business installment loan portfolio.</p>
          <p>Credit cards and personal loans contribute some $14 billion of the total $24 billion of other loans. The vast majority of the $761 million loan impairment in other loans was driven by this unsecured portfolio, although loss rates have stabilized since the first two quarters of the year and lead indicators are falling. Other loans also includes secured private bank and wealth management lending, where loss rates are negligible.</p>
          <p>As you can see, loan impairment in the fourth quarter of the year fell, as we expected, by some tens of million of dollars on the third quarter. The risk environment in January has continued to improve and we expect the first quarter to continue, if not accelerate, the trend of incremental quarterly improvement.</p>
          <p>To summarize for Consumer Banking overall, steady income momentum quarter-on-quarter built on good footings growth, with assets showing an increased bias towards secured and liability showing an improved mix, strong cost discipline allowing for targeted investment, loan impairment showing clear improvement and a robust cover ratio of 84%.</p>
          <p>Turning to Wholesale Banking. Through whichever lens you look, Wholesale Banking has had another excellent year in 2009, delivering broad-based and diverse top-line growth across multiple products, geographies and segments. The continuing execution of a consistent and clear strategy, increased depth of client relationships, leverage of the network and firm management of capital liquidity and risk have been key enablers of growth and a differentiating competitive factor.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking operating profit grew 36% on income that grew 24%. Expenses rose 11% primarily reflecting increased levels of profit-related remuneration and the flow through of investments. Cost growth remains well below income growth, delivering strongly positive jaws of 13%.</p>
          <p>Impairment has increased year-on-year but has fallen in the second half of the year. We continue to be disciplined in managing the relationship between risk-weighted assets and income growth. Risk-weighted assets grew by 18%, or some $24 billion, during 2009.</p>
          <p>Income. Client income, the major engine of Wholesale Banking revenues, grew strongly, up 22%, and contributes 74% of total Wholesale Banking income. Although client income held up well in the second half of 2009, own-account income fell 47% as spreads returned to more normal levels, volatility decreased and ALM income fell, as we said it would, by some $150 million.</p>
          <p>Three of our four client segments each generated income of over $2 billion in 2009 for the first time, with global corporates in particular performing strongly, up 42%. The fourth segment, commodities, grew 38%.</p>
          <p>Looking through the product lens. Lending and portfolio management income grew 54%. Transaction banking however fell 5%. Within transaction banking, trade income was up 26% with rising margins ahead of falling volumes whilst we still gained market share.</p>
          <p>Cash and custody income was down 24% despite balances increasing 21% to $97 billion. Global markets achieved an excellent 38% growth with strong growth across a broad range of products but in particular in financial markets and in corporate finance.</p>
          <p>Looking at income in more detail. During the course of 2009 client income increased its share of total income from 69% in the first half to 80% in the second half of the year, as own-account income softened and client income remained firm. It is worth reiterating that we do not organize ourselves around proprietary activity and we have no proprietary trading desks.</p>
          <p>We continue to become more important to our clients and to deepen relationships. Effective collaboration across our network is a powerful competitive advantage, with over 35% of Wholesale Banking client income generated offshore. Commercial banking and flow FX continue to be the pivot of Wholesale Banking, contributing 59% of total client income in 2009.</p>
          <p>Lending income was up strongly from $551 million to $849 million, reflecting significantly increased margins, which have largely sustained into the end of the year, and good fee income. Lending volumes increased 3%.</p>
          <p>In trade, margins were up by some 70 basis points during the year and we benefited from increasing market share in many geographies. Cash had a very strong increase in volume, although this was insufficient to compensate for margin compression of some 80 basis points, a material drag of some $600 million to income. This is equivalent in magnitude to the impact of liability margin compression in the consumer banking business.</p>
          <p>Global markets had an excellent year and remains a predominantly client-driven business. Financial markets is the largest component of global markets and I will talk about this on the next slide.</p>
          <p>ALM income was up 6% on 2008. ALM entered the year with strong existing positions, capturing both high fixed interest rates and wide credit spreads, and benefited from lower funding costs as interest rates fell faster than the market expected.</p>
          <p>During the year, relatively steep yield curves offered good reinvestment opportunities, resulting in a good robust year for the ALM business. ALM has started 2010 well, and should remain strong through the first half of the year, although this is dependant on yield curves and rates.</p>
          <p>Corporate finance income of $1,294 million, which includes advisory, project and export finance, structured trade finance and leverage finance, was up 74% and is the result of extensive investment in people, products and geographic coverage. As we enter 2010, pipelines remain very strong.</p>
          <p>Our principal finance business has a strong track record. Income of $337 million was up 33% as investor sentiment improved, especially in the second half. This is a business that we continue to grow selectively. Reinvestments exceed realizations. We have historically exited investments at some three times invested cost.</p>
          <p>Looking at financial markets in more detail. Income in financial markets increased 40% to over $3.3 billion, with 69% of this being client income. During 2009 there was a marked difference in performance between the two halves. In the first half of the year, clients were proactive in hedging their risks, bid-offer spreads widened and volatility increased.</p>
          <p>In the second half of the year, market conditions were less volatile and bid-offer spreads contracted, resulting in income falling 37% half-on-half. In the fourth quarter income fell on the third quarter primarily in own account, but has rebounded strongly in January.</p>
          <p>FX income was up 13% year-on-year as we outperformed the market and took share. Rates increased 18% as we expanded the product suite. And credit income increased significantly on the back of strong client flows and increased volatility.</p>
          <p>Income in commodities and equities increased from $141 million to $389 million, reflecting commodity price volatility, expanded geographic and product coverage, and good equities deal flow. Capital markets, where income increased over 70% from $234 million to $409 million, saw good levels of origination, especially in local currency bonds and loans.</p>
          <p>Turing to loan impairment. Wholesale Banking loan impairment was a net charge of $948 million, up from $384 million, and there are four particular factors. Firstly and materially, significant impairment was taken, mainly in the first half, against certain local corporate exposures in the Middle East region.</p>
          <p>The second factor is specific derivative-related impairments of some $200 million, primarily in Asia. Thirdly, we have increased the portfolio provision by some $150 million of which over 90% was taken in the Middle East and within that, predominantly aimed at the UAE.</p>
          <p>Fourthly, across the book the overall portfolio continues to perform resiliently with early alerts down by some 35% from the peak levels seen in March. We are seeing a series of individual small loan impairments but with no particular geographic or industry concentration.</p>
          <p>The overall quality of the portfolio has improved during the second half. We do continue to watch the Middle East closely, particularly the UAE, given event at the end of 2009. The Wholesale Banking cover ration of 65% is up on both the half year and on the 2008 year end positions and is, after collateral, a prudent reflection of risk. There's been no appreciable increase in non-performing loans in the second half of the year. The uncovered non-performing loans are well within our historical recovery levels.</p>
          <p>Let me summarize the overall Wholesale Banking picture. Wholesale Banking has again delivered another strong set of results with record levels of income from multiple sources, a firm grip on costs and focused management of risk. It enters 2010 with very robust transaction pipelines and strong client income-led momentum with good growth in customer assets and in cash balances.</p>
          <p>Now turning to geographic performance, rather than going through each individual geography, I will focus on three in particular, the Middle East and South Asia business, India and Korea. Firstly MESA. Income in MESA grew strongly, driven by the Wholesale Banking business, to just over $2 billion. Of this, some $1 billion of income is in the UAE, our largest geography in the region.</p>
          <p>The risk environment in the Middle East has been very much in focus during 2009 and loan impairment increased sufficiently to $811 million. Within the $811 million there are three main drivers. Firstly, as I have mentioned, impairment taken mainly in the first half against a couple of local corporate exposures in the Middle East of some $350 million.</p>
          <p>Secondly, $285 million of impairment in the Consumer Banking business, predominantly against the unsecured business. Of this $171 million relates to the UAE. A portfolio provision charge totaling $138 million in the Wholesale Banking business. And we now carry $170 million on the balance sheet, the Wholesale portfolio impairment provision in MESA.</p>
          <p>Turning to the shape of the portfolios. The Wholesale Banking loan portfolio in MESA is $14.6 billion. $10 billion is in the UAE and within this $10 billion, our exposure to those high profile Dubai entities currently perceived as troubled is around $500 million. We are fully engaged in the resolution process relating to these entities, and to the extent that we may ultimately take any losses here, we do not expect them to be material.</p>
          <p>For Consumer Banking total loans in MESA are $4 billion of which just under $2 billion is in the UAE, with around 60% secured. It's been a tough year. We've taken loan impairment of $171 million. Non-performing loans in the UAE have fallen in the second half and our leading indicators are showing improvement.</p>
          <p>India. India has had a truly excellent performance with Wholesale Banking being the primary engine of growth. Total income was $1.8 billion and India became only the second geography to generate in excess of $1 billion of profit. In 2008 income included a $146 million gain on the sale of the asset management company.</p>
          <p>Income in Consumer Banking fell 8% headline, although adjusting for the impact of FX, income grew 1%. Income in Wholesale Banking grew 29% headline, or 43% excluding the impact of foreign exchange. This is a diverse business where we have over 150 clients from each of whom we generate more than $1 million in income. It is also a business that has no substantial own-account element, with over 90% of income being client income.</p>
          <p>In late 2008 and early 2009 we repriced lending and trade business. And at the same time we continued to win good market share. The strong income pick up from trade and lending more than offset the 100 basis point compression in cash management margins. We also saw a very strong growth in corporate finance where income almost doubled year-on-year as we built out our product set and deepened existing relationships.</p>
          <p>Expenses in India as a whole were tightly managed. Loan impairment in India increased by 51%, primarily in Consumer Banking where we saw pressure on unsecured loans. Loss rates have been improving since April and are meaningfully better than the market average.</p>
          <p>Korea. We are making good progress in Korea. Income was flat on a headline basis, although increased 16% excluding the impact of foreign exchange. Wholesale had another good year with further momentum. Income was up 22% on a constant currency basis. Client income was 80% of the total and grew over 40%.</p>
          <p>Offshore income generated by Korea doubled to over $150 million. Investment and cost growth remained tightly managed and loan impairment returned to more normalized levels as the size of the knock-in, knock-out options, or KIKOs issue, decreases.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking had a solid year despite significant headwinds. Income grew 13% on a constant currency basis. In the second half we've realized around $70 million relating to the sale of our stake in BC Cards. Excluding this, and also on a constant currency basis, income was up some 7% in the second half of the year over the first half.</p>
          <p>We've continued to invest in the branch network but expenses have been well controlled and jaws have been neutral. We saw loan impairment pressure on the unsecured loan books in the first half of the year but derisked SME and moved to a more secured footing. We have seen good balance sheet growth in mortgages and the business has steady momentum going into 2010.</p>
          <p>Turning then to outlook. 2010 has started well for both businesses. For the Group as a whole, income and profit are higher than in January 2009, and you will recall that we started very fast in 2009. What is particularly pleasing about the performance in January 2010 is the better balance between the two businesses, with Consumer Banking a larger relative contributor to total income and to profit, and also that client income in Wholesale is up strongly.</p>
          <p>In Consumer Banking income momentum continues and is ahead of the underlying run rate for the second half of 2009. Expenses remain well managed and the loan impairment picture continues to improve.</p>
          <p>The momentum in Wholesale Banking has continued. Client income had a record month in January and was some 80% of total Wholesale Banking income in the month. Own-account income, although lower than in January 2009, was ahead of the run rate for the second half of 2009. And our deal pipelines remain both active and strong.</p>
          <p>This said, we remain watchful on the outlook and we are not complacent as to the risk environment. The world remains very uncertain but we enter the year with good momentum. 2010 has started strongly.</p>
          <p>We will remain focused on the effective management of capital, on maintaining excellent levels of liquidity, on improving our risk profile further, and on the disciplined execution of our strategy. We are well positioned in growth markets. We are taking market share in multiple products across multiple geographies and we are in great shape.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And now I'll hand over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. Good morning, those of you in London, and good morning to &#x2013; good afternoon to those of you in Hong Kong. Richard has explained the numbers and once again they tell a compelling story. Record profits on the back of record income, another stronger balance sheet, a broader, deeper client and customer franchise. The Bank is in very good shape.</p>
          <p>We did not let the crisis interrupt our track record of consistently delivering for our shareholders. We have no intention of allowing the aftermath to deflect us either. Both businesses have begun 2010 with good momentum. And whilst the economic uncertainties remain daunting and the regulatory rules of the game are in a state of total flux, we start the year with a blend of caution and confidence.</p>
          <p>And let's be clear, at no point during the crisis did we take capital from any government or liquidity support from any central bank, nor did we utilize debt-guarantee schemes or asset-protection arrangements. But rather than talk about our achievements in 2009, I want to start by talking about the problems or headwinds we faced and the challenges we see ahead. I'll then lay out our strategic priorities for 2010.</p>
          <p>At the interims I mentioned three specific challenges we faced in the first half: our overall performance in Korea; loan impairment in Middle East South Asia, MESA; and the sharp fall in income in wealth management and deposits in Consumer Banking.</p>
          <p>Richard has already touched on all three issues but to recap, Korea has delivered much better performance in the second half of 2009 and we expect even stronger results in 2010. In MESA, we do anticipate continued challenges, given the political insecurity situation in Pakistan, the well-publicized problems in Dubai, credit issues elsewhere in the region.</p>
          <p>However, it is important to keep these issues in perspective. As Richard pointed out, we are well provisioned, we have limited exposure to commercial real estate and the underlying business is strong. Income in MESA was up 25% in 2009, so while not underestimating the near-term challenges, we remain fully committed to the region and are investing for growth. We plan on opening for business in both Saudi Arabia and Libya this year.</p>
          <p>In wealth management and deposits the picture is mixed. We saw a marked improvement in wealth management income in the last quarter 2009. Deposit margins remain under pressure, although we have continued to be very successful in attracting accounts and balances.</p>
          <p>Now if those were the challenges we saw in the first half, in the second half the biggest challenge to the Bank's overall performance arose from the slowdown in Wholesale Banking's own-account income, which fell 47%. Some of this decline is seasonal since August and December are always slow trading months. But we also felt the effects of reduced bid-offer spreads, lower volatility, reduced ALM opportunities.</p>
          <p>Yet to be frank, we're not that worried about this slowdown as we have always said the real engine of growth in Wholesale Banking is client income. Own-account income will fluctuate between 15 and 30% of total income, depending on external factors. It was at the top end of this spectrum in the first half and has now fallen to more normal levels.</p>
          <p>Client income momentum is the fundamental driver of Wholesale Banking's performance on a sustainable basis and this continued to be resilient through the second half. Furthermore, client income in January was up over 20% compared to January last year.</p>
          <p>So if Korea, MESA, wealth management and deposits and own account in Wholesale Banking posed the biggest challenges in 2009, where do we see the major challenges in 2010? Fundamentally our most significant challenges have less to do with specific markets and more to do with the uncertainties about global economic prospects and the sheer scale and pace of change in banking regulation.</p>
          <p>Let me say a bit about both, starting with the global economy. There's no doubt that the global economy starts 2010 looking better then it did 12 months ago. After a contraction of nearly 2% in 2009, global growth will return in 2010. We expect a modest recovery of perhaps 2% or just over this year. However as these figures show, there is a sharp disparity between the prospects for our markets and those for Western economies.</p>
          <p>But if we've learned anything from this crisis, it's that the global economy is far less predictable, far more turbulent than many thought. I see five risks. First, remarkably little progress appears to have been made in rebalancing the world economy. And while imbalances of such scale exist, so there remains the potential for currency crisis, asset bubbles and trade wars.</p>
          <p>Second, there's a lot of deleveraging still to happen, particularly in the West, both in the private and the public sector and this is never quick or painless. Third, it's far from clear how robust the recovery will be once governments and central banks withdraw their extraordinary stimulus measures.</p>
          <p>Fourth, there's a real risk that persistently high levels of unemployment across many parts of the world will fuel protectionism and other populist policies that'll actually impede resumption of sustainable growth. And finally, there's the risk that the pendulum swings too far in the form of banking regulation, with the result that the real economy is starved of credit just as confidence and the desire to invest begins to return.</p>
          <p>Our markets, and particularly Asia, are better placed than most part of the world to weather these risks. But they are not immune, so we cannot be complacent. Yet thus far policymakers in most parts of Asia have been remarkably effective in responding to the twists and turns of the crisis. The regulatory debate revolves around how to achieve two important objectives. First, making the banking system safer, less prone to crisis. And second, ensuring we have an efficient and effective banking system that can support recovery and job creation in the real economy.</p>
          <p>The challenge is that there are some real trade-offs between these objectives and it's crucial that policymakers strike the right balance. Get it wrong one way and we'll risk another crisis. Get it wrong the other and we'll stifle growth and job creation and risk another sort of crisis.</p>
          <p>The debate around capital levels illustrates the point. There's no doubt that the banking system held too little high-quality capital before the crisis. Most banks, including Standard Chartered, have already improved their capital ratios significantly. The question now is, how much is enough? And the closer a regulator was to the epicenter of the crisis, the higher the answer they tend to give.</p>
          <p>It's all too easy to see how the pendulum could swing too far, with hugely damaging unintended consequences. And when I say damaging, I don't mean to banks, I mean to the real economy and to jobs. That's why it's absolutely critical that we think through the aggregate impact of all these changes on the real economy before we rush to implement them. This is not to say we are against all the proposals or that we're defending the status quo. Better regulation is clearly needed and we are broadly supportive of many of the specific proposals put forward by the Basel Committee.</p>
          <p>Specific measures we do support include: higher capital levels and a greater emphasis on quality of capital, and thus on core equity, with a consistent approach to deductions; a new approach to non-equity capital that allows greater loss absorption in practice; significant increases in the risk-weighting of trading book activities; far more robust liquidity regulation; simplification of resolution approaches, particularly cross-border, to reduce the too-big-to-fail problem; harmonization of accounting approaches; international application of common principles on remuneration; introduction of macro prudential tools such as loan-to-value caps, LTV caps, or liquid asset reserves. Here the West could learn much from Asia, where many of these tools are already well established.</p>
          <p>The point is that there is a lot that we agree it makes sense to change and we are committed to working with policy-makers to ensure these changes are as well thought through and practical as possible. But I would also add that there are some things we think are bad ideas. For example, variants of Glass-Steagall seem to us hugely distracting, costly and unlikely to make anyone or anything safer. Pre-funded resolution funds seem equally unattractive since they institutionalize moral hazard. Contingent capital looks remarkably like some of the overly-complex derivatives that helped cause the crisis in the first place and which didn't work in practice the way they were supposed to in theory.</p>
          <p>So I would argue for action but deliberate, somewhat cautious action, for simplicity, because complexity creates obscurity and diverts attention from the real risks, and for international consistency, because otherwise we'll stimulate arbitrage and generate yet further complexity. We should also accept that, however good the rules, they won't make up for poor management or poor supervision. And to my mind the crisis had less to do with weaknesses in the regulatory framework, although there were flaws and gaps, than with poor management and governance and with inadequate supervision of existing rules.</p>
          <p>Given such economic uncertainties and regulatory flux, it's critically important to be clear on our strategy and priorities. We are. We have a consistent, clear strategy, well understood by staff, customers and investors. Back in 2003 we said we wanted to be the world's best international bank, leading the way in Asia, Africa and the Middle East. Last year we reflected on our strategy, asking ourselves whether or not we should change it in the light of the crisis. Should we expand in the West? Should we be more acquisition-driven?</p>
          <p>But we concluded that the fundamentals of our strategy, organically led, focused on Asia, Africa and the Middle East, with a balance sheet-driven, conservative business model, running ourselves as one bank. But these fundamentals are, if anything, even more compelling today than they were before the crisis.</p>
          <p>One of the strengths of this strategy is that year after year we have been able to take problems or headwinds in our stride and still deliver superior performance. The geographic pattern of our results demonstrates this resilience and diversity. In 2009, India, Singapore and Africa set the pace once again. U.K., Europe and Americas bounced back strongly. Hong Kong and Other APR returned to good profit growth.</p>
          <p>Let me touch on some of the highlights. To start with, India. Hong Kong became the first of our markets to achieve $1 billion in profits in 2007. India achieved this milestone in 2009 and is now just a whisker behind Hong Kong. As you can imagine, there's quite a race for which will be our biggest market by profits this year. We have built a superb franchise in India and this year it is our intention to open a new chapter in our long history by listing in India.</p>
          <p>Africa. Profits up 54% to $482 million, an outstanding performance. We're capitalizing on the rapid growth in trade and investment flows between Africa and Asia. Singapore, up 17%, driven by Wholesale Banking. Within Other APR, China, with profits up more than 200% to $280 million, on the back of income up 17%, China is now becoming a significant business for us.</p>
          <p>U.K., Europe and Americas, this profit delta of $294 million is driven by a number of factors, including the successful integration of American Express Bank, where we have exceeded our synergy targets, and non-recurrence of the write-downs of strategic investments and ABS and derivative losses we experienced in 2008. The breadth of our business across diverse, fast-growing markets gives us enormous resilience in a turbulent world.</p>
          <p>Our near-term strategic priorities are very clear. Our top priority is to maintain our track record of delivering superior financial performance. To do this we need to sustain the momentum in Wholesale Banking and complete the transformation of Consumer Banking. We need to stay absolutely focused on the basics of banking, on the way we manage liquidity, capital, risks and costs. And we also need to grasp the opportunity to reinforce our brand.</p>
          <p>The key to sustaining performance momentum in Wholesale Banking is our client franchise. We turned the crisis into an opportunity by reaching out to our clients, filling the gaps that other banks had left. One decision we took following the collapse of Lehman was to take &#x2013; was to put tight restrictions on taking on new clients. We had prospective clients knocking at every door but we wanted our existing clients to know that at a time of crisis they had first call on our liquidity and capital, that we were there to support them.</p>
          <p>In 2009 income from our top 50 clients increased by 38% and the number of clients from which we generated income in excess of $10 million increased by 88%. We are deepening our relationships by getting closer to our clients. We're also expanding the product capabilities and solutions we provide to them. Indeed, we're constantly enhancing these capabilities, both organically and through what we call capability acquisitions.</p>
          <p>I've mentioned American Express Bank. I could also have talked about Harrison Lovegrove or First Africa. The most recent was Cazenove's Asian equity businesses, which we purchased last January and now call Standard Chartered Securities. This has already exceeded expectations, executing mandates on a range of IPOs, rights issues and placings, predominantly with existing clients of the Bank. This is the beginning of a deliberate strategy to build a relevant equities business across our key markets, extending our capabilities in helping our clients raise capital and grow.</p>
          <p>Whilst Wholesale Banking is constantly refreshing an already highly successful, client-led strategy, Consumer Banking is midway through a strategic transformation. Until recently this was a largely product-led business, but over the last 18 months Steve Bertamini and his team have been reshaping Consumer Banking, so that it too focuses on building deep, longstanding, multi-product relationships with customers. This is a big, complex change program and whilst it is far from complete, we are making good progress.</p>
          <p>As Richard has described, Consumer Banking's performance was hit hard by the crisis. Wealth management income collapsed, liability margins fell sharply, loan impairment increased significantly as unemployment rose and small businesses struggled. We moved swiftly and decisively in response, cutting costs, adjusting risk parameters and rebalancing the product mix. But we did not let such tactical priorities deflect us from the strategic reshaping of the business, hiring relationship managers, opening new branches, extending and enhancing mobile and Internet channels, changing incentives and performance metrics, launching a new customer charter.</p>
          <p>It's early days in this transformation and we're not fully through the margin headwinds from the crisis, but the signs are more than encouraging. Consumer Banking income in the second half was up 10% on the first half. Despite subdued demand in many of our markets, we're growing the most critical elements of the balance sheet, current and savings accounts, or CASA, up 51%, loans up 17%, faster than ever before. We're winning market share in most products and segments in all of our key markets.</p>
          <p>For both businesses, the depth and quality of our client and customer relationships are critical to our strategy and success. And this focus on clients and customers, the obsession with the basics of banking, the emphasis on acting as one bank, on doing the right thing, these are key elements of our culture, key aspects of our brand.</p>
          <p>Standard Chartered is a rather different kind of bank. We've been around for more than 150 years. In fact, in 2009 we marked our 150th anniversary in Hong Kong by issuing the world's first $150 note. We believe in building long-term client and customer relationships and without diluting our focus on delivering for shareholders, we are committed to being a force for good in the communities in which we live and work.</p>
          <p>There's no doubt that our brand has been strengthened by the way we performed during the crisis. But I think it is still the case that it's the performance of the Bank lifting the brand, rather than the brand helping drive the performance of the Bank. We have a brand that means a lot to those who know us. But too few people in our markets know our name. Too few know what we stand for.</p>
          <p>So this year we will be investing to build awareness, not least by putting our name on Liverpool shirts that will be seen on hundreds of millions of television screens around the world. And we will be working harder to tell people what we stand for, what makes us different.</p>
          <p>Our brand is all about commitment. We're here for good, to create value for our shareholders, to support and partner our clients and customers and to make a positive contribution to the broader community. We're here for the long term. We don't run when things get tough. We don't dodge tough decisions and trade-offs. This is the way we do business. It has underpinned our strategy and success for over 150 years across Asia, Africa and the Middle East and it will be the foundation for our future.</p>
          <p>I became CEO, Chief Executive, in late 2006 just before the world of banking went completely pear-shaped. It probably wasn't the best timing in retrospect. But I am immensely proud of the way the people of Standard Chartered responded to the crisis, turning it into a strategic opportunity for the Bank. So I do want to take this opportunity to thank all of our staff.</p>
          <p>I'm also enormously appreciative of the support we received from our clients and customers, from you, our investors, and from our regulators. We look at the crisis as an inflection point. Banking has changed irreversibly. Our role and position in the world of banks has changed dramatically. We didn't just weather the crisis, we turned it to our advantage. Whilst I don't underestimate the challenges and uncertainties before us, I am also excited by the opportunities. We are in the right markets. We have a clear strategy and a strong brand and we've started the year with good momentum.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Jaspal, Ben and Julian to take your questions in Hong Kong. John, Richard and I will answer your questions in London. So thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. We'll now go into questions. Can I just remind you to put your hands up if you want to ask a question and when you get a mic, can you remember to state your name and your institution before you ask your question. Shall we start with one in the middle here? Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Raul Sinha from Nomura here. Without going into the merits of backing Liverpool, can I ask two questions please on India and China? Firstly, it looks like India contributes about 20% of profits but takes up only about 8% of Group out of UAs and you're likely to get some more capital there this year. Can I ask what your plans for deployment of that capital might be? And then secondly on China, could you give us some disclosure on your loan books in China? How much is in mortgages? It looks like your cross-border exposure is about 10 billion there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, it could be worse. I have a finance director who supports Wolves [Wolverhampton Wanderers soccer team]. I'll just respond on India and capital and then, Richard, if you could pick up the question on China. The point of listing in India is not specifically to raise capital for India, or indeed really specifically to raise capital.</p>
          <p>The point of listing in India is to further differentiate ourselves in what is an absolutely key market for the Group and to build our brand and profile and positioning in the country. We will raise enough relatively &#x2013; we'll probably raise somewhere in the region of 500 to 750 million, which will be enough to provide liquidity for the local listing. But the capital won't be specifically for the India business. Do you want to pick up on China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And for the other Wolves fans in the room I'm confident we're going to stay up, so that's all right. The China balance sheet is about $9 billion of Wholesale assets, customer assets, and just under $3 billion of Consumer assets. About 1.7, $1.8 billion of those assets are mortgages in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will the capital be funded?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The capital will be funded.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Any more questions? Right at the back there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. It's Leigh Goodwin from Citi. I've got a couple of sets of questions actually. First is around foreign exchange and second around regulation. Just on FX, it looks like underlying profits were up 18% on a constant currency basis. I wonder if you could just elaborate a little bit on which currencies in particular were the headwind?</p>
          <p>And in light of currency movements in the last couple of months, whether you expect those headwinds to become tailwinds in 2010 please? That's my first set of question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to give us the second question, the regulation...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The second question just around regulation, number one was, any change in your ROE targets as a consequence of increased capital requirements? We heard from HSBC that they may be moderating theirs a little bit. I wondered whether you were following suit? Secondly was where your risk appetite might be if and when the support &#x2013; the &#x2013; sorry, have I lost you there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can still hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry. If and when the state guarantees on SME lending were to be withdrawn, clearly you've taken advantage of that. I wonder whether you'd moderate your risk &#x2013; your risk appetite would cause you to moderate lending on SME, if and when those are withdrawn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I &#x2013; what don't you start with the FX question and then shall I come back on the ROE? Or you can do the ROE one and I'll come back on the SME one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very good. Yeah. On &#x2013; I mean, you can do the maths, essentially there's about $630 million of negative income pressure coming from FX and over $200 million of trading profit. And the main markets where we've seen headwinds on exchange rate are Korea, where the average is &#x2013; the average drag is about 16% at P&amp;L, and India, where the average drag is about 12, 13% or so P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>I earn a fiver if I get to mention the three other currencies, which are actually we've been also impacted by the cedi, the naira and the kwacha, which have each depreciated between 26 and 35%. But the essential ones, the more material ones are India and Korea. As to how we look going out, I think there is clear prospect, but you have your own view on rates, of those headwinds effectively at least calming, if not turning tailwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the ROE, we've had for several years a target of mid-to-high teens ROE. We think it's a bit premature to change that as a target, so we're not changing it as a target. And we'll have to see what happens in terms of all the regulatory debate and the sort of flow out in what people describe as Basal III. I do think it's an important issue because I think in the way the regulators come to the answer, they have to come to an answer which actually provides a reason for shareholders to actually provide capital to the sector. Otherwise they will end up with more deleveraging than they expect.</p>
          <p>On the SME point, I think it's hard to give a generalized answer because a lot of it will depend on the sequencing of the improvement in the economy versus the speed at which governments pull back from their SME guarantee schemes. I think most governments in Asia are very mindful not to withdraw support from the SME sector too early, because the SME sector is so crucial to sustaining job creation. We see the SME business as a strategic business for us, so it's not about us being tactical in this at all. We've actually being very involved in helping design and implement some of these schemes. And so we're not going to sort of cut and run as they get pulled back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I can just remind you of the proportion of that, the amount written under government guarantees are $2 billion out of about a $13.5 billion SME book, and it's predominantly Hong Kong, Singapore, Korea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Other questions? Michael?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Michael Helsby from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. I've got a couple of questions, firstly on the commercial bank and then on the dividend. You gave the split of commercial banking and flow FX at 59% of client revenue. I guess two parts, firstly, why don't you split out the commercial banking P&amp;L from the Wholesale bank like HSBC do? I think that would be quite beneficial for us. And as clearly margins have been very depressed in 2009, so I was wondering if you could talk about the evolution of the margin, both on the liability side and the asset side, as you look at it into 2010?</p>
          <p>And second point on the dividend. I mean, your Core Tier 1 is 8.9 point. I think your Tier 1 target is 7.5 to nine. So clearly you've got a lot of capital, your leverage ratio's down at 19 times. When I look at your dividend, I think the payout ratio this year is 36%. I think looking back over time that would have normally, in a normal year, had a 40% handle on it. So it's just, as we look at both capital and dividend, what should we think about in 2010 and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I suggest is &#x2013; I think there were actually three questions in there. There was the commercial bank reporting question, a margin question and a dividend question. If you could take the commercial bank and margin question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you want to pick up on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the commercial banking question, clearly I would like to be helpful. I think the way we show the numbers though is the way we think about the business. And we think what the Wholesale Bank strategy has been and it's a, forgive me, Mike, it's a very simple strategy which is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Quite well executed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well executed, reasonably well executed. It is to get to be a <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what you get from a Wolves supporter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A top three bank to clients. And the way that the commercial banking works, it's absolutely integral to the rest of the product offering and the way that we run the relationships and the interaction. So we've often talked about the benefit of a cash-management mandate that's one.</p>
          <p>And if you think about the cash-management mandate, so we sit and we offer to 30 countries for Shell and 21 countries for Diageo and so it goes. We offer their cash management across multiple countries. So we sit and run the current account, all the flows, all the payments in, the payments out, for multiple different currencies that come into that central management piece and it gives us the opportunity then to offer them not just FX but other products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hedges and all that sort of stuff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because we engage with them on a daily basis and we interact with them on a daily basis around the fundamental transaction processes that they're managing. And the rest of the product set predominantly feeds off that so we often talk about the pivot of Wholesale is actually the commercial banking business.</p>
          <p>And much of the rest of the power of the income development has been as those other products have been built out, but they've been built out linked to and combined with our strategy about serving the client. So that's why we show it as it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the margin point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Margins are &#x2013; I mean, the main pressure on margins has actually been, if you take the two businesses, has been liability margins. Clearly we stand with resilient liquidity. We take very significant earnings drag by choice for carrying high levels of liquidity. And if you look at what's happened to liability margins, they have very significantly compressed in a low interest rate involvement.</p>
          <p>As we look at the Consumer Bank, we think that the headwind of interest rates will ease through 2010, because essentially there's been a repricing of the back book. So as the book has exited and then been rebooked, so it's rebooked at lower levels. That impact is largely working its way through and probably by March, April will have worked its way through. Therefore we won't face a headwind in the following nine months, it will be sort of calmer water. And then we'll see what interest rates do in terms of whether rates come up.</p>
          <p>Wholesale has the same issue in cash management, that it faces 80 basis points or so of liability margin compression on those cash-management balances, which with custody were $97 billion. So very significant compression, same averaging, working through the year. But as interest rates potentially start to rise and as the averaging has worked its way through, we should see at least calmness if not improvement gearing to a rising interest rate environment.</p>
          <p>Asset margins, very good. I mean the asset margins in Consumer have been excellent. Mortgages have remained resilient, that's been very good. Personalized credit cards have been resilient. So we've seen good asset margins, and they don't look at this stage like they are coming under any material pressure. In Wholesale, again we saw good repricing opportunity. You can see it come through in India, you can see it come through in Africa, you can see it come through in Hong Kong. There's been some slight softening but it's slight softening of those asset margins in the Wholesale bank, which you would expect, but not material.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dividend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, Mike, I think, you ask a very good question on dividend. And we're first of all delighted that in 2009 we're able to pay a dividend and indeed increase it by 7%. So clearly dividend is important to us. But I think Peter's already brought out a very important issue here, which is what are the appropriate levels of capital and what are the appropriate levels of regulation to ensure that, from a shareholder point of view, the returns remain attractive, whether it's returns on equity, whether it's the returns by way of a dividend, I think levels of capital as we look forward are going to be a very important thing to look at, not just from derisking the banking system, but also from the point of view of making it worthwhile for shareholders to invest in banking stocks.</p>
          <p>It is our policy as a company to pay a dividend and clearly that dividend we'll set next year based on the profits that we achieve in that year. But in terms of how that might be affected in the future, I think this is why Peter this morning focused on the importance of getting the regulation and the balance of the regulation right as we look forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we'll take &#x2013; here. Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Trippitt at Oriel. Two questions, one just on risk-asset growth, which was 13% against flat asset growth in the year. I know you do explain it, bit of credit migration and also energy trading risk assets et cetera. But I just wondered if that is &#x2013; you feel that, that has now &#x2013; risk-asset growth versus asset growth should normalize in 2010, putting aside whatever Basel comes up with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want both questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question, could you just talk a bit more about the wealth management business? Because I understand you're talking about bit of a turning point in Q4, but I still can't help but feel that structurally this business is underperforming for you. What are your views two years on after the AmEx Bank acquisition? Is this really giving you what you want? And where do you see wealth going in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you pick up on the risk-weighted asset question and then I'll come onto the portfolio &#x2013; do wealth management...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean essentially what you have is Consumer bank assets grew fast, 17%, but the risk-weight, given that there's a high proportion of secured assets, particularly mortgages, actually grew marginally at just over &#x2013; around 2%. Then you have the other way round actually at Wholesale where essentially assets, loans were growing at around 10% and the risk-weight was growing at about 18%. Now within that therefore it's mainly a focus on Wholesale. Two elements, market risk capital, you see that move up $10 billion.</p>
          <p>We had that conversation at the half year. Half of it comes from a schedule rule change with the FSA around CDO values. And half of it comes from our commodity and equities business, which still trades on the standardized model whilst we await FSA approval to go to Cat 2, go to credit risk RWA. Essentially the credit risk RWA moved up because of PD migration.</p>
          <p>It moved up around $15 billion or so. But we had efficiencies of around $5 billion from better collateral management and so on and from upbeat of about just under two billion. So essentially therefore you had essentially 13, 12 to $13 billion of credit risk risk-weighted asset movement, and it's predominantly PD migration.</p>
          <p>Where do we see it? Our going-in budget assumption was actually that, that PD migration looks like it should be halving in terms of the incremental pick up from what we were seeing going through 2009. Now we'll have to see how that goes, but our forward expectations was for single-digit PD migration come through in risk-weighted asset growth and we'll see if the world continues to improve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On wealth management, I think you're right. The nature of the wealth management businesses, certainly in Asia but I think more broadly, have changed. They'll be less product-driven, probably less complex on the whole. And we have changed &#x2013; this is one aspect of the change in CP strategy that has had quite a profound impact on the way &#x2013; on the kinds of products we sell and the way we sell them. We're taking much more of a sort of portfolio management approach with our clients rather than a product-led approach.</p>
          <p>You mentioned American Express Bank, you remember there were two aspects of the acquisition to American Express Bank. One was the private banking side of it and the second was the FI bit of it in Wholesale bank. I mean, both of them, I think, have been very important contributors. We've had very significant cost synergies in both aspects, both in Consumer Banking and in Wholesale Banking. Strategically the private banking addition gave us a step forward. It wasn't the easiest time to be growing a private banking business and AUM suffered because of changes in investor markets and so on. And on the FI side, that's been integrated very effectively to strengthen our global FI business.</p>
          <p>More questions? Sorry, I will come to you this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Arturo de Frias from Evolution. Two questions please. One again on capital, sorry about that. In fact my impression is the opposite I think. Capital will &#x2013; capital ratios will remain under pressure and not because of regulatory change, just because of the growth in the business. If your ROE's around 14 and 15 and you're paying 40% of that, your internal capital generation is around 10. And your RWA increase is 13 and it's probably going to go higher than that.</p>
          <p>So I think for the next couple of years it is inevitable that you grow risk-weighted assets more than you grow capital and hence the Core Tier 1 ratio is going to fall, unless there are other elements that play in the equation. And so I would like to hear your views on that. Obviously the listing in India being tangible will help, but I don't know if that's going to be enough or &#x2013; well what's your view on that?</p>
          <p>And the second question is on India, the jaws in India are absolutely amazing. Looking at it on constant currency, the revenue growth is very strong but probably reasonable given that we are talking about a strong growth country. I think it's 17%. What I find unbelievable or very, very remarkable is that costs are falling in India. And well if you think &#x2013; how is that possible and is that sustainable in the medium term? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I take the capital point first and then maybe you can comment on the cost performance in India.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, the perspectives illustrate why we have lively debates as a board about dividend policy and our approach to, what is it the regulators call it, capital conservation. On the one hand we are very conscious about supporting growth. On the other hand, am I going to have three hands here, we're very conscious about rewarding shareholders. And on the third hand, if I had one, we're very conscious that the rules of the game are changing all the time in terms of what regulators expect us to attain.</p>
          <p>The one point I'd make is that in 2009 one very capital-efficient bit of the Group was not performing very well. Because of low interest rates, our liability margins were under pressure. And one of the dynamics in terms of our profit generation that is very affected by the external environment will be the impact of rising interest rates on those liability margins.</p>
          <p>But we are very conscious that it's quite a complicated equation around capital. But the thing that makes us very confident is that we are, A, slowly generating equity capital, internal generation of equity capital. We have continued to do so throughout the crisis. We've continued to generate equity capital. Second, we have a lot of control because our book is so short tenor over our risk-weighted assets and so we can manage the equation relatively dynamically.</p>
          <p>Do you want to just comment on the cost performance in India?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On cost performance and also on the overall momentum. It's partly where did a lot of the income performance come from? And essentially we've built out, as we've said before, significant product expertise and coverage into clients. And so if you take corporate finance, corporate finance doubled in India. I also referenced that margins had improved very significantly. We took the opportunity sensibly to reprice money.</p>
          <p>And we repriced in trade and in lending, and those therefore &#x2013; the assets that we were booking were running at much higher levels of income. Going to cost, there's one &#x2013; there is an item in the underlying cost base which is around $50 million of benefit, which was coming from just some service tax rebates that we achieved with the Indian authorities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's a bit flattered by that but it's still a very good performance on cost. More questions? Yeah, Robert?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert Law at Nomura. I have two brief questions please. Firstly, could I invite you to give us some comments on the prospects for jaws in the current year? And secondly in reference to the wealth management business, you have in the past split out the numbers between wealth and deposits, but you did at the interim stage give us a slide which allowed us to make pretty good estimates of that.</p>
          <p>Could I ask you for some kind of update on that? In particular, what was the delta on the wealth revenues, second half on first, so we can see how that's improving? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I leave you that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The jaws outlook message will be very similar to the one we've always given, which is that we anticipate growing cost broadly in line with revenues. And that's because these aren't a &#x2013; this isn't an outcome that we don't manage. We &#x2013; it's an outcome we manage. And one of the debates, it's a bit like the capital debate that we're constantly having as a management team, is, what's the right trade-off, given the nature of our franchise and the growth opportunities, between driving positive jaws, and therefore near-term profits, and investing in the business and franchise? And the stance we've taken is that, as we see the performance of the Bank unfold through the year, and depending of course on the impairment performance as well, we will release investment into further developing business, so broad guidance is broadly in line. On the wealth management deposits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, I think the first thing is just on the income that I gave you the stat that Q4 was 35% up effectively in wealth management income on Q1. It was a relatively steady progression. One of our main markets, clearly Hong Kong. At its low point the daily income was running at just over $200,000, $225,000 or so. By the fourth quarter it was running at about 660 on daily income, if that gives you some sense for income momentum through the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. John, here at the front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Could you just give me a feel...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably say who you are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. John Armitage from Egerton Capital. Could you just give me a feel please for the deposit profits you think you're forgoing across the Group as a result of the fact that interest rates have migrated to these exceptionally low levels, compared to a more normalized environment? And secondly, could you just remind me please, what was the year-on-year income hit you had to absorb in aggregate across the Group from the repricing downwards of deposits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Roughly 600 million a business, isn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's 600 million a business, although the question I think is, where would you &#x2013; we're going to stay strong liquidity, all right. So the question is, what would be the natural A/D rate that we would travel at? And so the surplus liquidity that we carry gives you that type of income level attaching to the Consumer Bank. Your view with our view, when are we going to return to more normal circumstances?</p>
          <p>We're choosing to take the drag at earnings for higher levels of liquidity and a lower A/D ratio than we would otherwise through &#x2013; at a normal point in the cycle wish to carry. So where would we move that to, I think is then a second question, as conditions normalize. But the overall calculation of income drag purely from the liability length that we have is, as Peter says, about $600 million in each business, because Wholesale has that very high quality cash management business, corporate current accounts effectively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean you would obviously get a little bit of an offset elsewhere in margins and so on. So just summing the two 600s is probably exacerbated but you can &#x2013; it's of the order of $1 billion in drag or something from having a very strong liability position in a very low interest rate environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's year-on-year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Toeman from HSBC. The global markets business generated six billion of revenues. That's 40% of Group total. The risk-weighted assets relating to markets, or the market risk-weighted assets are 10% of the Group total. So trading is 40% of revenues but 10% of the capital requirement. You'll have to take my word for it, but that's one of the widest disparities we see in the European banking sector. I wonder, does it mean that actually you've been over trading within global markets per unit of capital employed? Or does it mean when regulators look at how much capital you might require in the future, you're going to be penalized relative to the competition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the short answer is, and Richard can expand on it, is that actually the nature of what we're doing in much of our global markets business is the kind of thing that requires relatively little market-risk capital. If you look at our underlying VaR, you'll see that it's also very low relative to our competitors, particularly our trading VaR. And so what we've got going on is a lot of flow business of various sorts. And that is generating a lot of revenue, as you say, but it's not taking a lot of market risk and therefore it's not requiring a lot of capital to support it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. And which is exactly &#x2013; look at &#x2013; if you look at the shape of our trading book VaR, it's a very small proportion and banking book VaR, it's about 70% of VaR. And if you look at the total VaR we run, it's low, in fact very low, but low compared with many other banks in terms of the positions that they take. And on &#x2013; just on Basel III, to your regulator point, as we look at the impact of Basel III upon trading book capital multiples, we think it is low-single billions of dollars to us in RWA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, obviously I do look at the VaR and it hasn't changed at all over about the last two years which makes me slightly suspicious of the calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a number of different things moving in there. But I can &#x2013; we can take you through the calculation and the underlying thinking of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't we take one from over this side of the room?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Hi. It's Tom Rayner from Barclays Capital. Can I just have two questions please? The first on Wholesale revenues. I think I noted, Peter, in your intro that client income is up 20% January-on-January. I just wondered if you could update us maybe for how February was looking and comment on the overall sustainability of that number? Because I'm trying to get a sense to how much, particularly in financial markets, how much the growth in client income rather than own account benefited from the very favorable conditions in '09. And I have a second on regulation if you want that now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you give me the second as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, it's just again reference to your slide, you mentioned you want to see simpler resolution procedures, particularly for cross-border. I just wondered, with that in mind, if you could update us on your views on the debate of a branch system versus a legal entity where you have your own capital requirements in every geography that you operate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well I'm sure you'd like me to give the first couple of days in March as well. Look, what I said, just to be very clear, is that client revenues in Wholesale banking in January were up over 20% on January 2009. Now we wouldn't be talking about January with such confidence if we'd had a completely disastrous February. So I'm not going to give you the February numbers, but you can read into that as you will. The regulatory debate...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Careful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How many hours have you got? The fundamental issue is that reducing it &#x2013; on the branch versus subsidiary, reducing it to a branches-versus-subsidiary thing kind of misses the point. Because you can have incredible problems in resolving a branch and you can have incredible problems in resolving a subsidiary. And you can have branches which have dedicated capital and intra Group exposure limits which are even more strenuous than subsidiaries, depending on what jurisdiction you're in.</p>
          <p>What we need to evolve to is a situation in which there is just a set of better processes and better understanding between regulators and within banks of how you deal with these sorts of resolution problems. I think that is absolutely important because I don't think we want to be in a situation where there is an assumption that every bank has to get rescued. I think you want to have a situation where you can resolve things in an orderly way.</p>
          <p>That can be simpler with a subsidiary, but it's not necessarily the case. You can also have huge complexities with subsidiaries. Some of this is in the hands of banks. Banks can make is easier. Some of it's in the hands of regulators and some of it goes down to the basics of the interplay between different bankruptcy regimes in different parts of the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Can I just go back onto the first question, because I wasn't really after February's figure, I was really looking for a comment on overall sustainability of client incomes. Because we know that on the own account, spreads have come in and what have you but just on &#x2013; the conditions in '09, certainly first half, must have been favorable to clients' income as well as own account. I just wondered if you could comment on the sustainability of the growth going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think we've given you a fair amount of indication. Richard talked about pipelines being, I think, active and strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we've said that both businesses have good momentum. They do. The businesses have good momentum. On the other hand, I don't want to underestimate the risks in the world economy. We are quintessentially a business that lives off trade and investment flows around the world, so we won't be immune to shocks and changes in confidence. So we are &#x2013; the business is in great shape, we're winning market share but it's a bumpy world out there. Sorry, Ian, I know you've been right over there on the right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ian Smillie from RBS. Two questions, please, the first one on the rise from CASA deposit performance. Could you give us some sense as to your expectation as to how that would perform as and when interest rates start rising, and I guess perhaps to differentiate between the Consumer bank and the Wholesale bank?</p>
          <p>Just trying to capture how much of that is strategic growth and how much of that is more cyclical growth if you like. And the second question is with reference to the Wholesale bank, a couple of businesses that you referred to having invested in quite significantly over the last year or two, being corporate finance and the commodities and equities businesses, could you give us some color or guidance or expectation as to how we should size the revenue opportunity there if they continue to execute successfully over the next year or two? Because the pace of change is pretty aggressive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I &#x2013; I'll have a go at the first one and then Richard can correct me and have a go at the second one. On the CASA point, we took a deliberate decision in a situation where we were a flight-to-quality institution and we were finding deposits coming in at quite a rate, we took a deliberate decision to focus on attracting the most &#x2013; the highest quality deposits. Those that over the long run are the best foundation for a client relationship, i.e. current accounts and savings accounts, and those with the most stable characteristics in terms of balance sheet management. So we were very deliberately moving the &#x2013; particularly the consumer book from being time-deposit heavy to having a much bigger CASA portion.</p>
          <p>How that evolves in terms of what happens when you get more investor confidence and higher interest rates will depend market to market, actually. I don't think you lose the accounts. What you may find is there's substitution in terms of the balances through to investment products and so on. We would certainly be expecting that. But the great thing is, if you have that client relationship, you're in a far better position to capture the opportunity to sell them the wealth management product.</p>
          <p>And to the earlier question from Mike about how the wealth management business is changing, that's the kind of thing we're seeing in the way that it's changing, is that it becomes much more of an integrated approach to managing the relationship with the client and having a discussion with them about, given the way the opportunities and interest rates are changing, how they should manage their own assets.</p>
          <p>On the Wholesale Banking side around CASA, I think it's a somewhat different case. What you've got fundamentally going on there is our cash management business has being winning a lot of mandates. It's being growing volume and winning a lot of business. So far that has not translated through into very strong income growth because of the margin pressure, but we see that as a fundamental platform, both for earnings and for the client relationships.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How to answer your question? I don't think I can give you a number to plug except to say that, if you look at corporate finance, it is advisory, it's project export finance, structured trade, leveraged finance. We initiated Strategic Client Coverage Group, where we have 40 very senior bankers now covering up to five clients each and bringing to bear the full weight of the bank in terms of servicing those clients, and global corporates grew income at 42%.</p>
          <p>We continue to hire good talent. We continue to present our product skills to more of our clients and again, Peter shared with you stats around income progression in our top clients, so 38% income growth in our top 50 clients or so. And a lot of that comes from going up the strategic product &#x2013; the strategic value offering.</p>
          <p>In commodities and equities, this is a relatively new business still. And we are still building out products and coverage and systems, so we have more room to go. And again Peter referenced the CASA Asia business. It's very interesting that the CASA Asia business, which is exceeding expectations, the vast majority of the transactions that we did with them came from original Standard Chartered Bank clients able to gear off the capability that was actually brought in with a really good team. So there's confidence behind I think momentum in both of those business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. One over here. Sorry, right at the back. I'll do right at the back here and then I'll come further forward. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Morning. It's Rohith Chandra-Rajan, Barclays Capital. Another question on the margin, if I could please. Group margin down 20 basis points or so half-on-half and looking at the geographic disclosure, it looks like all geographies were actually up apart from Hong Kong, which was flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You need to &#x2013; can I interrupt because I &#x2013; I suppose caught by form, we didn't show &#x2013; in a full year we weren't showing first half but if you had time, because we got you up early enough in the morning this time, to get to Page 81, you'll see actually that there's a representation which is actually changing essentially the gross assets number to exclude intra regional assets, which then works its way through the margins.</p>
          <p>So your better picture, and I can share with you separately the first half margin numbers, but they're logical against what you should now see as at the restated 2008 year end and the 2009 year end. So your first half picture may have a &#x2013; may be somewhat distorted if you just go to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just looking at the disclosure as was, there seemed to be a mix shift in terms of average loans with a big increase in the Americas and U.K. and Europe business. Just wanted to understand that better, if that is a real movement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure what the &#x2013; I mean unless it's there, lend manager and assets placed back in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well let's pick that up &#x2013; why don't we pick it up online. Just to give you what's happened with the restatement of the assets on the geographic segmentation, it's all to do with the treatment of intra Group placements within a region. It doesn't make any difference to the Group as a whole. I'm sorry, I'm conscious there was a couple of questions here. I'm also conscious a little bit of time. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just &#x2013; it's Andrew Lim at Matrix. Sorry, could you just clarify what your view was on the net interest margin for the Group in terms of half-on-half performance? And what are the main drivers behind that? And secondly, risk-weighted assets under Basel III, could you give us some color on how much the individual components are expected to increase under the new regulations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I think the impact on the margin, as you see our Group margin's essentially 2.5 down to 2.3. It's predominantly a liability margin compression point and it's pretty linear. And much of it's coming through our big holders of liquidity, our strong liquidity centers, so Hong Kong in particular for instance, where you saw very significant cash margin downward pressure on a very strong liability position.</p>
          <p>With regard to Basel III, I mean essentially you can get this from the capital note, but we are, I think, relatively minimally impacted. I mean, there's Peter's point about how long it's going to take to bring all these items through, but assume they all come through and they all come through tomorrow, we think that the maximum impact to us then is around 125 basis points. And predominantly there's 900 to $1 billion of deferred tax, there's 500 million of excess EL, there's 250 of minority interests and there's about 300 million of material holdings and that's sort of the amount. So we think 125 basis points total. If all these measures came in tomorrow, that would be the degree of impact on our capital base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But frankly if they all came into tomorrow, the direct impact on us would be the least of our problems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Manus Costello from Autonomous Research. I just wanted to follow up on questions about Group structure. I wondered specifically if the process of writing your living will, which I presume is going on at the moment, will lead to changes in the Group structure? I wasn't clear from your answer previously. And secondly, if recent limits on intra Group exposures have changed the way that you'll be managing liquidity or capital around the Group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the short answer is, there'll be no immediate rush to change the Group structure. We already have a structure where over half our business is in subsidiaries and the two biggest businesses that aren't in subsidiaries are in branches which have dedicated capital and dedicated liquidity. So actually we already have a structure that either is subsidiarized or quasi subsidiarized in the nature of it. And I've already forgotten your second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Intra Group exposures, whether or not that has any impact on the way you manage liquidity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Intra Group exposures always do. But you've got to remember that it's not just things that are published here or in Europe that matter to us, it's all the things that are published around. And we are constantly managing quite a rapidly changing landscape of rules around intra Group exposures. We run the Group so that we can simultaneously have all the bits of the Group stand up for themselves under stress scenarios and that we can utilize the combined strength of the Group to support our clients.</p>
          <p>And so there's a balancing act of doing both those things. And we &#x2013; I actually see that as a key strategic capability of the Group, our ability to strike that balance and manage what is increasingly complex in terms of the regulatory environment around intra Group exposure. So yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. I'll keep this brief. It's Steve Hayne from Morgan Stanley. Just two quick questions. One, amongst a very strong set of results, financial markets was clearly a bit weak H2 versus H1. And I'm wondering if you can help give us a bit of outlook on that, particularly FX, rates, commodities et cetera, it's stepped down quite a bit?</p>
          <p>And secondly, I'm just interested in what's happening in Hong Kong, because your net interest income was basically flat '09 versus '08, which is actually pretty good result. And I'm wondering if you could just expand on the competitive environment in Hong Kong in key products? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the financial &#x2013; do you want to take the Hong Kong one? On the financial markets one, I think I'll come back to the whole discussion we had about own account, because a large chunk of that is the reduction in own-account income in the second half. The fundamental thing you've got to be thinking about is how strong client revenues are. At any one time, own account will oscillate a bit around that, but the fundamental building of the franchise around the financial markets business continues. In terms of Hong Kong?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Hong Kong, clearly we've already talked about the downward pressure on interest income and margins, very long liabilities, to some extent clearly balanced both by very good market share growth in mortgages and when mortgage margins, if you looked at them in '09 versus '08, are over 100 basis points higher than they were actually in '08, then that's predominantly through the prime HIBOR spread going out in 2009 to around 5%, and it was less than 3% the spread at the end of 2008. And that's helped hugely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm conscious of time so unless there's any other burning questions I was going to suggest we end. John, did you want to say...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Shall I just try and summarize the key messages that we'd really like you to take away from today's presentation. 2009 was again a record year for the Group. A very successful set of results in what has still been a very turbulent set of economic climate, particularly in those Western markets that have been particularly exposed to the banking crisis.</p>
          <p>Increased EPS and we've increased the dividend. Our balance sheet continues to show good strength and we've made a great start to the year. So there's good momentum in the business and we look forward to 2010 with confidence. The best is yet to come.</p>
          <p>On that note, thank you all very much for coming this morning. Thank you for your support and we look forward to seeing you at the half year results. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>