<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1331200" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7788</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Peter Sands, Group Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Richard Meddings, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mike Rees, Group Executive Director and Chief Executive Officer, Wholesale Banking</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Ian Smillie</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Peter Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Arturo de Frias</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Robert Law</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Rohith Chandra-Rajan</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Leigh Goodwin</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Michael Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Raul Sinha</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, London, good afternoon, Hong Kong, and a particularly warm welcome to those in Mumbai for the First Results Presentation since our listing in India in June. I'm joined here in London by Richard Meddings, our CFO; and Mike Rees, CEO of our Wholesale Banking business. John Peace, the Chairman, is hosting our event in Hong Kong and Jaspal Bindra, CEO of our Asia business, is leading in Mumbai.</p>
          <p>As usual, I'll ask Richard to start, by taking you through the numbers. I'll then come back, to talk more about the external environment, the way we are running the business, and our strategic priorities. We'll then take questions in each location separately. Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Peter. Good afternoon, Hong Kong and Mumbai, and good morning, London. The first half of 2010 has been another period of strong performance by the Group. As you listen to the presentations this morning, the themes driving the underlying performance of the Group will be ones with which you are very familiar.</p>
          <p>Multiple income engines, with income well diversified; costs well controlled and investing for future growth; risk under good control, with loan impairment and asset quality showing significant improvement; good growth on both sides of the balance sheet; activity levels higher; market shares up across a range of products and geographies; double-digit profit; and double-digit EPS growth.</p>
          <p>Set against this is the picture of margin compression, particularly across liability products, but more moderately across assets. The results are wholly consistent with our diversified banking model; there are no surprises. We have delivered record levels of profit over previous record levels. This is not a recovery story. Let me draw out several key highlights.</p>
          <p>Income of over $7.9 billion, and record levels of profit, over $3.1 billion. We have continued our record of consistent delivery over the past seven years. First half income has grown at a compound annual growth rate of 19%, and profit at 23%.</p>
          <p>Good income momentum, up 10% over the second half of 2009 reflecting the high levels of activity across our two businesses. Costs up 8%, as we continued to invest, to underpin momentum. A continuing improvement in the risk environment, with loan impairment sharply down in both businesses, and leading indicators not signaling any deterioration.</p>
          <p>Profit growth of $278 million, up 10% on the first half of 2009, and up strongly by 35% on the second half of 2009. Continued capital strength, with Core Tier 1 at 9%. We have generated good levels of equity and managed risk-weighted assets, or RWAs, well, growing by 9% since the year end.</p>
          <p>Liquidity, we continue to attract deposits, strengthening further our robust liquidity position. And our A/D ratio remains very strong, at 76.2%. Our liquid assets ratio is stronger than at the year end, now at 27.2%.</p>
          <p>Let me take you through the numbers. At a Group level, reported income is broadly flat on the first half of last year. Although you should remember that in that first half, income included the gain of $248 million, relating to the buyback of some of our Tier 2 notes.</p>
          <p>Good growth in Consumer Banking income, up 8% and Wholesale Banking client income up 18% has been partly offset by weaker own account income. And I'll go into more detail about this later. Expenses are up 8%, reflecting our investment program in the second half of 2009 and the first half of 2010. Loan impairment was down 60% on the first half of 2009, reflecting the improvement in the risk environment. Operating profit of $3.12 billion is up 10%, and is at almost the same level as for the whole of 2006.</p>
          <p>Performance metrics, normalized EPS has risen 10%, and dividend per share has grown 10%. Normalized return on equity was 14.7%.</p>
          <p>The balance sheet, the balance sheet is in excellent shape, and continues to be both highly liquid and conservatively positioned. The funding base is diverse and is continuing to grow in both businesses, despite increasing competition. Current accounts and savings accounts, or CASA, grew by 2%, or some $4 billion, with time deposits growing $20 billion since the year end. CASA now comprises 50% of total deposits, up from 43% some 18 months ago.</p>
          <p>We are continuing to attract deposits across the Group, rising 8% since the year end. Our focus on liabilities and disciplined deployment of the balance sheet has, again, resulted in a strong ratio of customer loans to customer deposits, the A/D ratio, which at the half year stood at 76.2%. The A/D ratio in all of our major geographies is under 100%.</p>
          <p>Turning to assets. Our loan book continues to be well diversified by country and by sector. Our balance sheet remains, as before, a source of differentiation and strength for the Group. We have low loan to value ratios on our mortgage book, with an average of 49%; short maturity profile on our wholesale loan book, with some 65% of the book under one year.</p>
          <p>Our ABS carrying value is now $2.6 billion, approximately 0.5% of total Group assets. We have low exposure to commercial real estate, to leveraged loans, and to Level 3 assets. We have no direct exposure to sovereign debt in Southern Europe.</p>
          <p>Overall exposures are diversified by geography and sector, with no material concentrations. Our largest individual geography, Hong Kong, accounts for 17% of total Group customer loans. The balance sheet remains robust and well diversified.</p>
          <p>Capital, the Group continues to maintain a strong capital position. In the first half of the year, we generated $2.1 billion of profit attributable to shareholders. And in addition, we raised over $500 million through a listing of Indian depository receipts in Mumbai.</p>
          <p>Throughout the year, we have also had good support from capital markets, having raised over $4 billion of lower Tier 2 and senior funding. And these deals were significantly oversubscribed and priced at levels well within issues executed by entities, with much higher credit rating. This reflects our financial strength and name recognition. We have very low levels of refinancing maturing over the next few years, only some $6 billion until the end of 2013. We have already pre-funded all of our requirements for 2010, and most of our requirements for 2011. RWA growth has been well controlled, having accommodated good nominal loan growth and a formulaic increase in operational risk. Core Tier 1 is at 9%; Tier 1 is at 11.2%; and total capital is at 15.5%. We are well capitalized and especially in light of our conservative asset profile.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking, the repositioning of the Consumer Banking business is progressing well, as evidenced by a range of both financial and non-financial metrics. The business has good momentum, and excluding the impact of the sale of BC Cards in the second half of 2009, income is now at its highest level since the first half of 2008. For the first half, Consumer Banking income increased by 8%, and expenses increased by 10%, with loan impairment falling 47%. Operating profit before tax is up 85%, to $643 million.</p>
          <p>Consumer Banking has seen good balance sheet velocity since the year end, with loans up 9%, primarily in secured products, and deposits up 5%. Through working closely with Wholesale Banking, some 36% of new CASA during the year came from payroll accounts. Consumer Banking contributes some $30 billion of surplus liquidity to the Group.</p>
          <p>Looking at Consumer Banking in more detail. Consumer Banking income has grown by 8% over the first half of last year, and momentum has remained good. The business has faced the ongoing structural headwind in 2010 of continued liability margin compression. Against the first half of 2009, liability margins were down by 27 basis points on average, and since year end were down 7 basis points. In addition, asset margins have come under some moderate pressure in the first half of the year, as competition has increased.</p>
          <p>Expenses have increased by 10%. We have maintained cost discipline, with business as usual costs up only some 4% year-on-year. We continue to drive efficiencies in the cost base, and we are making good progress in hubbing and standardizing the way we work.</p>
          <p>As to risk, we have continued to focus on secured assets. 77% of the loan book is fully secured, and only 15% is unsecured. And this, along with the improving macro-economic backdrop, is reflected in the loan impairment performance. The Consumer Banking loan impairment charge has decreased, to $299 million, down 47% on the first half of last year.</p>
          <p>Looking at income in more detail. Mortgage income was up 36%, against the first half of 2009, with just under a third of the increase coming from foreign exchange, and the remainder from a combination of strong volume increases, up some 21%, and higher margins. Market share has remained strong in our large mortgage market, although margins have fallen from their peak in the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management fee income has grown for six quarters in succession, reflecting a better economic backdrop and improving customer sentiment. Compared to the first half of 2009, fees were up 39%, with income from fund products doubling. Hong Kong, Singapore and Taiwan performed particularly well.</p>
          <p>Compared to the second half, Wealth Management has also shown good momentum, with fees up 10%. In the last few weeks of the first half, and as mentioned in the pre-close trading statement, we saw softer income levels, as turmoil in Europe impacted sentiment. In the first few weeks of July, we are seeing a recovery in Wealth Management fee income. We've seen continued growth in deposits, but the ongoing low interest rate environment and increasing competition, has resulted in significant negative income drag, totaling some $220 million in the first six months of 2010. The impact of low interest rates was far less pronounced when looking at the second half of 2009, resulting in income drag of only some $60 million.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide. Income in credit cards and personal loans, or CCPL, was up 4%, and volumes up 7%, compared to the first half of 2009, driven by selective asset growth in markets such as Hong Kong and Singapore, where we increased market share. We are repositioning our product offering towards customers in our target segments, and where we already have the payroll relationship, thereby improving the risk profile of our book. Against the second half, CCPL income was down 5%, due to the non-recurrence of the gain on the sale of BC Cards.</p>
          <p>SME income is up 20%, to some $580 million, compared to the first half of 2009, and up 7% on the second half, driven by particularly good growth in trade products, associated FX transactions and in mortgages. Both sides of the balance sheet have grown well since the year end, with loans up 7% and deposits up 17% to some $29 billion.</p>
          <p>Impairment, loan impairment, both in terms of dollars and basis points of loss, has shown substantial improvement against both halves of 2009. In the first half of the year, we have seen a portfolio provision release of $52 million, with the potential for more releases in the second half, albeit probably at lower levels.</p>
          <p>Looking by product, you see a consistent picture of rapidly improving loan impairment. In mortgages, loan impairment has continued to fall and was half of the level seen in the second half of 2009. Our loss rate in mortgages for the first half was 5 basis points.</p>
          <p>Within SME, loan impairment has halved on the level seen in the second half of 2009, with loss rates sharply down. We have de-risked the book with the business installment loan book down from $1.8 billion to $1 billion over the past 12 months, and we continue to be active users of government guarantee schemes.</p>
          <p>Credit cards and personal loans contribute some $15 billion of the total $28 billion of other loans, with the balance being secured Private Bank and Wealth Management lending. The vast majority of the $238 million loan impairment in other loans was driven by the CCPL portfolio.</p>
          <p>Loss rates are down by around a third since the second half of 2009, reflecting the repositioning of the book to a stronger risk profile, but also improving macro-economic conditions across our markets. The total loss rate across all products was 58 basis points, the lowest six-monthly loss rate we have seen for a decade. Our forward indicators are continuing to improve with 30 plus days past due down across all products and on average, down by 19 basis points since the year end. However, we expect the current rate of improvement in loan impairment to slow in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>When thinking about the outlook for impairment, there are two factors to bear in mind. Firstly, we intend to continue growing unsecured in a disciplined manner in selected markets, so a mix change. Secondly, we expect to continue to see good overall loan growth.</p>
          <p>So to summarize for Consumer Banking overall, continuing steady income momentum built on good footings growth and higher activity levels. Assets have shown a continuing bias towards secured, and liabilities continue to see strong CASA levels. Good cost discipline, allowing for targeted investment. Loan impairment, sharply down and a robust cover ratio of 83%.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking, Wholesale Banking has delivered a strong performance during the first half of the year and has continued to focus on deepening client relationships using our network capabilities as a source of competitive differentiation, and on maintaining a disciplined approach to its cost base and its balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking operating profit grew 10% on income that was broadly flat. Expenses rose 5%, primarily reflecting the impact of investments, but also foreign exchange. Loan impairment has fallen sharply, down 74% on the first half of 2009. We continue to be disciplined in managing the relationship between RWA and client income growth. Client income grew 19% on the second half, whereas RWA grew by 9% or some $14 billion since the year end.</p>
          <p>Income, client income, which accounted for 81% of Wholesale Banking revenues grew strongly, up 18% year-on-year. Own account income has returned to a more normal, long run proportion of revenue. Own account income fell 40% when compared to the exceptional performance in the first half of 2009, but has recovered well, rising 14% or some $110 million on the second half. Three of our four client segments each generated income of over $1 billion, illustrating the breadth of our client base.</p>
          <p>Looking by product, Lending and Portfolio Management income grew 13%. Transaction Banking income was up 1%. Global Markets was down 2%. Overall, within Global Markets, client income growth of 24% was more than offset by own account falling sharply.</p>
          <p>Looking at income in more detail. Wholesale Banking continues to be a client income led business. Year-on-year client income has increased its share of total income from 69% to 81% and has shown good growth as own account income has softened. It is worth reiterating that we do not organize ourselves around proprietary activity, and we have no proprietary trading desks.</p>
          <p>Effective collaboration across our network is a powerful competitive advantage, with over 35% of Wholesale Banking client income generated offshore. As in prior periods, Commercial Banking and flow FX continue to be the pivot of Wholesale Banking, contributing 52% of total client income in the first half of 2010. Lending income was up strongly from $412 million to $465 million, reflecting increased margins. Lending volumes were up only 6% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>In Trade, income was up 11%, driven by volumes up 26%. Activity levels are sharply higher with the number of trade LCs issued up 20% year-on-year. We benefited from increasing market share in many geographies, despite margins, on average, being down some 31 basis points year-on-year and down some 35 basis points since the year end.</p>
          <p>Cash saw a very strong increase in volume, up 24% as transaction levels rose strongly, although this was insufficient to compensate the significant margin compression of some 43 basis points against the first half of 2009. This equates to some $170 million of income drag in the first half of the year. Cash and custody income was therefore down 9%. Despite this, we have grown our market share in U.S. dollar and euro clearing since December 2009.</p>
          <p>Financial Markets is the largest component of global markets and I'll talk about this on the next slide. ALM income was down 12% year-on-year. In the first half of 2009, ALM captured both high fixed interest rates and wide credit spreads, benefiting from lower funding costs as interest rates fell faster than the market expected. As these positions matured, funds have been reinvested at relatively lower rates, generating much lower levels of accrual income in the first half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Corporate Finance income of $932 million was up 52% and is the result of extensive investment in people, products and geographic coverage. We closed 49% more deals in the first half of 2010 than in the first half of 2009. As we enter the second half of the year, pipelines remain very strong and July has been excellent.</p>
          <p>Principal Finance income of $134 million is down 1% year-on-year, despite difficult market conditions. This is a business that we continue to grow selectively and where reinvestments exceed realizations.</p>
          <p>Looking at financial markets in more detail. Income in financial markets of $1.7 billion was down 16% on the first half of 2009, but up 34% on the second half, with 78% being client income. In the second quarter of this year, income was down only marginally on the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Equities income was down over 45%, but is only a $50 million income business. Capital Markets income was up on the first quarter, and FICC income, by which I mean FX, interest rate, credit and commodities, was only marginally down, reflecting the strength of our client franchise.</p>
          <p>During the first half of 2010, client income in financial markets was up 9%, reflecting much higher volumes, but against the backdrop of tighter spreads.</p>
          <p>FX and Rates both saw good volume growth, but spread compression and persistently low interest rates have resulted in income falling 22% in FX and 11% in Rates from the first half of last year. But both businesses showed very strong increases in income over the second half.</p>
          <p>Income in Commodities and Equities decreased from $236 million to $165 million. Capital Markets, where income increased 3% to $233 million saw good levels of origination and strong league table positions. Credit income was down 9% overall, although client income grew well off the back of good deal flow and increased bond activity.</p>
          <p>Loan impairment. Wholesale Banking loan impairment was $138 million, so less than one third of the $525 million charge in the first half of 2009. This reflects the shape of our exposures, improved market conditions and our disciplined and proactive approach to risk management.</p>
          <p>The overall quality of the portfolio has continued to show steady improvement since the year-end, with early alerts not showing any particular industry or geographic concentration. Early alerts are down 30% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>As mentioned in the pre-close, loan impairment in the first half of 2010 was related mainly to incremental provisioning on a few existing problem accounts, particularly in Korea, and particularly related to the shipbuilding sector. There have been no new material impairments in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>The Wholesale Banking cover ratio is 56% and after collateral, offers coverage of non-performing loans or NPLs of 70%. The uncovered NPLs are well within our historical recovery levels</p>
          <p>Let me summarize the overall Wholesale Banking picture. Wholesale Banking has delivered another strong set of results, with record levels of client income from multiple sources, a firm grip on costs and focused management of risk. It enters the second half of 2010 with very robust transaction pipelines, sharply higher activity levels and strong client income-led momentum, with good growth in customer assets and cash balances.</p>
          <p>Turning to geographic performance, I won't go through each geography individually, but we'll talk about Taiwan, within other APR, and then Korea.</p>
          <p>Taiwan. Other APR is the Group's largest geographic segment in terms of income. The largest geographies in other APR are China, Taiwan, Malaysia, Indonesia and Thailand which, together, account for 86% of income and 84% of profit.</p>
          <p>Within this, Taiwan has shown a strong performance in the first half of the year. Taiwan is a geography that generated $283 million of income in the first half of the year, has a total loan book of some $12 billion and employs just over 4,000 people.</p>
          <p>The business is heavily skewed towards Consumer Banking, which accounts for some 80% of both income and loans to customers. Income for Taiwan is up 5%, despite the impact of considerable margin compression.</p>
          <p>Costs are down significantly, primarily as a result of the non-recurrence of one-offs in the first half of 2009, mainly the provision related to PEM structured notes, but also due to the restructuring we effected in early 2009.</p>
          <p>Loan impairment, as in other geographies, has fallen sharply and profit has increased substantially to $121 million.</p>
          <p>Income in Consumer Banking was $224 million, up 16%, and was broadly spread by product. We saw particularly good growth in mortgages, up 20%, where we picked up market share at higher margin and a lower average LTV. Wealth Management Fee income was up 56% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking income was $59 million, down 23%. This is a very liquid business, and the impact of low liability margins is particularly relevant. Client income was up 3%, with Trade and Global Market sales income up strongly, but cash income was down. Own account fell sharply as in other geographies.</p>
          <p>We have a strong business in Taiwan, which is supported by an improving macroeconomic backdrop and fast increasing economic convergence and cooperation with Mainland China. Deal pipelines are good, and we look to be on track for a very good full year outturn.</p>
          <p>Korea. We continue to make progress in Korea. Against the first half of 2009, income was up 13% on a headline basis, although down 3%, excluding the impact of foreign exchange. When comparing against the first half of 2009, it is important to remember that this was a period where we benefited from spreads widening and delivered an excellent performance in Wholesale Banking.</p>
          <p>Against the second half of 2009, and excluding the impact of BC Cards, income is up 2% and profit is down 14%. Our books are well provisioned as we enter the second half.</p>
          <p>In Wholesale Banking, we have continued to build out our product set and leverage the network. In the first half, offshore income was $80 million, more than in the whole of 2008.</p>
          <p>We have good velocity on both sides of the balance sheet; loans have grown 15% against the first half of 2009; we have held market share in mortgages and personal loans, despite increased competition; and we have built market share in SME.</p>
          <p>Customer deposits have grown 40% since the first half of 2009, significantly outpacing loan growth. Our market share of both CASA and time deposits is up since the year-end.</p>
          <p>The macroeconomic environment in Korea continues to improve. It is a well regulated economy and is continuing an export-led recovery and is forecast to grow GDP by 6% this year. Although interest rates have remained low, compared to liability margins, the cycle looks to have started to turn with a 25 basis point increase in rates on 9th of July.</p>
          <p>Set against all of this is the fact that Korea remains, for us, a high cost income ratio market. Competitors are liquid and are growing their balance sheets strongly and margins are under pressure.</p>
          <p>Overall for Korea, we continue to make progress and we have good balance sheet momentum and good deal pipelines. We are optimistic about the second half in Korea and expect a profit outturn materially in excess of the level we have seen in the first half of this year.</p>
          <p>Turning then to outlook. Whilst the world remains perhaps just as uncertain, July has been encouraging. For the Consumer Bank, income momentum continues and should benefit as we continue to grow footings and selectively rebalance the mix towards unsecured. We are well positioned for the turn in the rate cycle, but now expect this to be more of a 2011 rather than 2010 factor. Wholesale Banking client income remains strong, and our deal pipelines remain both robust and active.</p>
          <p>For the Group as a whole, we would expect to see jaws narrowing from the 8% negative jaws in the first half, but we still anticipate negative jaws at the full year. We are keeping a tight grip on expenses in both businesses, and in both businesses, credit indicators remain good.</p>
          <p>We will remain focused on the fundamentals of the Group, which are in excellent shape. We are well positioned in growth markets. We are taking market share in multiple products across multiple geographies.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And now, I'll hand over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Richard. This is a strong set of results achieved against an uncertain and sometimes difficult external environment. Whilst the global economy is undoubtedly recovering particularly in Asia, this recovery is very uneven, somewhat fragile and there are still many risks.</p>
          <p>You'll recall that in our pre-close trading statement at the end of June, we deliberately used quite cautious language to describe the environment. Through May and June, we had seen softer markets, trade and business volumes falling, investors spooked by sovereign debt and currency issues.</p>
          <p>In recent weeks, we have seen more positive sentiment in the markets and encouraging upticks in some businesses. However, we remain somewhat cautious. There are still big risks to the global economic recovery. The imbalances in the world economy remain acute.</p>
          <p>Deleveraging in the West is now happening in both the public and private sectors, particularly in Europe, and this will inevitably be painful. Central banks have only just begun to unwind liquidity support measures. This too could have a significant impact.</p>
          <p>Unemployment remains the biggest political issue in most countries, creating pressure for populist and protectionist measures. The regulatory change agenda is enormously complex, often fragmented and fraught with unintended consequences.</p>
          <p>With confidence febrile and markets nervous, I would say we are over the worst, but not out of the woods. Our markets, Asia, Africa and the Middle East are bouncing back, but to sustain that momentum, they need the West to grow too.</p>
          <p>Whilst the global financial crisis was actually a western financial crisis, it was big enough to impact everyone. What is clear is that, whatever happens, Asia will grow faster than the West. Indeed, the crisis has accelerated the shift in economic power and influence from those who consume and borrow to those who produce and save. Focused on Asia, Africa and the Middle East, we are in the right markets.</p>
          <p>In fact, the pace of recovery in Asia has been remarkable. Asian exports have grown, on average, over 37% year-on-year. Several of the most trade-dependent economies, such as Taiwan and Singapore, have seen double-digit GDP growth and are now ahead of pre-crisis levels of activity. More domestically-driven economies, such as China and India, continue to grow at pace.</p>
          <p>Underpinning this growth are increasingly diversified trade and investment flows. Everyone talks about the China/Africa trade and investment corridor, but there are a profusion of such non-traditional corridors. Korea and the Middle East, India and Africa, China and Brazil, trade within the ASEAN region now accounts for over a quarter of Indonesia's exports, more than a third of Thailand's, Malaysia's and Singapore's. All these markets now export more to the rest of ASEAN then they do to China.</p>
          <p>Given our networking capabilities, these trends play to our strengths. Let me give you one example. Hyundai Motor, a leading Korean car manufacturer, set up a state-of-the-art production facility in Chennai in India. Building on our long-established relationship with Hyundai Motor, and our on-the-ground capabilities in India, we financed the building of a factory, as well as auto finance, working capital, hedging, cash management, and also provided similar banking services to many of the suppliers, both Korean and local. This example illustrates the power of our network, the breadth of our product offering and how we operate as one Bank.</p>
          <p>As we emerge from the crisis, we have taken stock of our strategy, asking ourselves whether it's still right, still robust in the face of the fundamental shifts in the world economy, the avalanche of regulatory reforms and the changes in competitive dynamics.</p>
          <p>The answer is that we still believe that we have the right strategy. It worked before the crisis; it worked during the worst of the crisis; it's working now. We aspire to be the world's best international bank leading the way in Asia, Africa and the Middle East, parts of the world that offer great prospects for growth that we know intimately and where we have deep roots. These are the right markets for us. We focused on customers and clients, on building deep, long-term relationships, and standing beside them through thick and thin.</p>
          <p>We are obsessive about the fundamentals of the Bank, the balance sheet, our infrastructure, our brand and reputation, our culture. We're equally obsessive about the way we run the Bank, how we manage costs, risks, liquidity, capital and controls. We believe investment in organic growth is the key to driving sustained value creation.</p>
          <p>Acquisitions and investments do play an important part in our strategy, giving us new capabilities, creating new platforms or overcoming obstacles to growth, but organic growth has been, and will be the main driver of our success. Our approach to acquisitions can be summed up simply, we grow what we buy, we don't just buy to grow.</p>
          <p>China is a good example. We continue to make significant investments in our business in China, expanding the branch network to 56 branches, building our franchising capabilities. Although profits are down year-on-year, since in 2009 we benefited from private equity gains, the underlying momentum of the business is robust. Consumer Banking income is up 27% year-on-year, Wholesale Banking client income around 40%.</p>
          <p>Inorganic investments and partnerships complement this organic growth. We have a 20% stake in Bohai Bank that has now grown to over 25 billion in assets and has 42 branches in 11 cities. And most recently, we established a strategic partnership with the Agricultural Bank of China, underpinned by becoming a cornerstone investor in their IPO. With 2.6 million corporate clients, over 320 million personal customers, and nearly 24,000 branches, but virtually no international network, Ag Bank offers plenty of scope for mutually beneficial cooperation. For example, in providing international trade services to their millions of SME clients.</p>
          <p>Building the SME business is a strategic priority across all our core markets, primarily because it's a great source of profit growth, but also because it's one area where we can powerfully demonstrate our distinctive contribution to the broader real economy.</p>
          <p>SMEs are the main source of employment growth in most economies, and in several of our markets they dominate the economy. In Korea for example SMEs account for over half of GDP and 88% of total employment. Helping SMEs grow and prosper is an obvious way in which banks can be socially useful and deliver value for their shareholders.</p>
          <p>This is a business we have been investing in to build. Today, we have SME customers across 30 markets, served by 1,300 relationship managers. We continue to expand lending all through the crisis. SME loans grew 14% in 2009 and a further 7% in the first six months this year to over $14 billion. Meanwhile, SME deposits have grown from 17 billion to 29 billion since the beginning of 2008, with 17% growth in the first six months of 2010.</p>
          <p>This growth has been achieved by investing in product capabilities, in dedicated SME centers, and in recruiting and training relationship managers. However, we are also looking to complement our organic growth through selective acquisitions. For example, last month we acquired GE Capital's factoring and hire purchase business in Singapore. A small, but targeted acquisition that extends our product capabilities for SME customers.</p>
          <p>Our Corporate Finance business represent another good example of where we have combined investment in our organic business with carefully selected acquisitions that expand our capabilities. Mike, given that corporate finance is part of Wholesale Banking, perhaps you could say a few words about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, Peter. The strategic rationale for building our Corporate Finance businesses was very clear. We had great relationships with our clients, but we didn't have the product capabilities to take advantage of the growth in infrastructure, trade and investment flows emerging in our geographies. We needed to deepen our relationship with our core clients and conduct more high-end advisory and finances business in order to take advantage of these growing flows.</p>
          <p>Alongside the process of hiring and building the business, select acquisitions were crucial. Harrison Lovegrove in the Oil and Gas sector, Cazenove Asia, now called Standard Chartered Securities on the equities side, Pembroke for the build out of our aircraft financing offering, and First Africa provided boutique advisory capabilities in Africa.</p>
          <p>The momentum in the business is self-evident. In seven years, we've built a business that's seen income growth $40 million in 2003 to $932 million in first half of this year. First half income is up 52% on the first half of last year, driven by ever larger mandates, and is up 37% on the second half of last year. This is a very strong business performance, and now forms a very significant part contribution to our clients' business.</p>
          <p>Corporate Finance is a business where we had chosen to invest for growth and now we're seeing the benefit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mike. Of course, building businesses like SME or Corporate Finance, or expanding organically in markets like China takes sustained investment. And while some of this can be funded through productivity enhancement, the pace of the investment does drive cost growth.</p>
          <p>We have consistently said that we manage the Bank to deliver broadly neutral jaws, i.e., costs growing broadly in line with income. This first half we have not done that, and this is deliberate. Last year we responded to the global economic turmoil by pulling back sharply, so our jaws ended up being strongly positive. And this year, we decided to accelerate investment spending to ensure we took full advantage of the opportunities emerging from the crisis.</p>
          <p>The margin pressure on deposits and the sharp reduction in own account income year-on-year somewhat disguises the underlying business momentum of the Bank, the pace at which we are winning market share in most segments and products, across most markets and building volumes. We are investing in scalable infrastructure to enable us to continue to grow at pace in a controlled and cost effective manner. If you look at our jaws, or cost income ratio over a multi-year period, we are doing exactly what we said we'd do, increasing costs broadly in line with income.</p>
          <p>We have deliberately stepped up our investment to transform Consumer Banking. Expenses in Consumer Banking climbed 10% during the first half as we added 400 relationship managers, nearly 700 frontline sales and service staff and continued to invest in our branches, Internet and mobile channels.</p>
          <p>We still have much to do in Consumer Banking, and still face downward pressure on margins, but we are getting results. For example, in Hong Kong mortgage volumes have grown 25% year-on-year giving us around 15% market share, our highest ever. Deposits have grown 10%, much faster than the market. As interest rates begin to rise across our markets, which they are just beginning to do, we will see the benefits of what we have done to build the scale and quality of our customer deposits flow through to income.</p>
          <p>Another area in which we have stepped up investment to sustain our long-term growth is in branding and marketing. We have a great brand, but it could be a much more powerful driver of value creation. So far, our brand has been propelled largely by the success of our business, rather than helping drive our success. We want to make the brand far more potent as a source of competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>This is not about throwing money around to achieve nebulous goals, but about controlled investment to achieve specific objectives. First, we want many more people across all our markets to be aware of our brand, who we are. Our brand recognition is just far too low.</p>
          <p>Second, we need them to understand what we stand for and why we are different. Because we really believe we are a different kind of Bank. And finally, investment in the brand must drive incremental business.</p>
          <p>Our sponsorship for Liverpool is all about building basic brand awareness. Given the number of people watching the Premier League across Asia, Africa and the Middle East and the extent of Liverpool's global fan base, this is a cost effective way of putting our name on the TV in all our markets every week.</p>
          <p>With the launch of Here for good, we're telling the world what we stand for and why we're different. Here for good is a simple phrase, but one with multiple meanings. It captures our long-term perspective, the fact that we're committed to clients and customers, to our markets and the communities in which we live and work. We've been around for a long time, and we'll stick around through good times and bad. Here for good also captures our belief in doing the right thing, and being a force for good and making a positive contribution to the economies and societies in which we operate.</p>
          <p>At one level it's about community initiatives, but even more profoundly it's about the way we run our business every day, everywhere. What clients we take on, what products we sell, how we conduct ourselves.</p>
          <p>Before I close I want to talk about India, partly because, for the first time, we have Indian investors and analysts in Mumbai listening to our results presentation and partly because, in the first half, India was our most profitable market.</p>
          <p>Having been beaten by just a whisker by Hong Kong in 2009, India is certainly ahead at the halfway mark in 2010 with profits up 19% to 624 million. Both businesses have great momentum and we're continuing to invest to make the most of the opportunities.</p>
          <p>It's worth reflecting that in 2000, the year before we acquired Grindlays, our profits in India were 45 million, and those of Grindlays 90 million. I was in India last week and it was clear what a difference the listing has made to our brand and profile. For us the IDR listing, and on the slide you can see the Chairman of the listing ceremony, it's a symbol of how we are Here for good in India.</p>
          <p>We've been in India for over 150 years. Our first two branches anywhere in the world were in Kolkata and Shanghai in 1858. We've now become the first, indeed the only, international company to list in Mumbai. We are enormously appreciative of the support of our new investors in India.</p>
          <p>These results demonstrate, once again, our commitment to delivering consistent and sustained performance. This is not a bounce back, a sharp recovery in profits; it is simply another set of record results, continuing a trajectory that now extends over more than seven years.</p>
          <p>I would like to take this opportunity to thank all of our staff for once again ensuring that we deliver for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Both our businesses enter the second half with good momentum. But we remain extremely watchful about the global outlook, and are managing the business very dynamically. We are investing now in order to grasp the huge long-term opportunities across our markets. But we are also ready and able to respond tactically as events unfold. We don't underestimate the scale and unpredictability of the external challenges.</p>
          <p>In this context, we have kept focused on the basics, kept driving the underlying momentum in both our businesses, and have stepped up investment in the brand. The Bank is in great shape, has good momentum and it's superbly positioned for the future.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to John and Jaspal to take your questions in Hong Kong and Mumbai. Mike, Richard and I will take your questions in London. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, if you'd like to ask a question if you could raise your hand, and then if you get given a mic say who you are and where you come from. Ian do you want to get a mic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, it's Ian Smillie from RBS. Two questions please. The first one on the Consumer Bank. Richard, could you talk a bit about the appetite to grow the unsecured book from here, perhaps in the context of should we think about that growing as an increasing proportion of the overall Consumer Bank loan book? Or is that simply just keeping it in line with mortgage?</p>
          <p>And perhaps as a second part to that question, could you talk about the demand for that product, because if I understand you correctly, you're trying to sell it more to the existing payroll customers than you did historically? How much demand do you think there is in that space to sell the unsecured product? So that's question one.</p>
          <p>The second question is for Mike, which is on Wholesale Bank client revenue. For the first time in several years, you're long-term prediction of high teen revenue growth has come through, obviously because it's been falling rather than rising. The question is, from this current base, could you give us a sense as to whether the kind of the north of 20% growth years are now behind us, simply as a function of your size? Or whether as cyclical comes back in your favor, you might see some years again north of 20%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd be interested in the answer to that question but <mark type="inaudible" />.....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But why did we take it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. Why don't we take Richard on unsecured first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think the answer starts from &#x2013; if you look at the shape of the Consumer Bank, we have now 85% of the assets in the Consumer Bank are fully secured or partially secured. So we started with a very robust position of only 15% of the assets are unsecured. If you go across to loan impairment and you see, as I said in the commentary, 58 basis points. It's the lowest level of loan impairment that we've seen for a decade, and our forward indicators are stable, actually to improving.</p>
          <p>Within that mix we have, over this crisis period, de-risked the book in a number of areas, in SME in the BIL book which is installment lending and in unsecured. For the last nine months to a year or so, we've been looking at how we should grow our unsecured business. We clearly have capacity to grow our unsecured business against the framework I just laid out for you. But we intend to do it in a very cogent way.</p>
          <p>So the messages about looking at the customers with whom we have payroll relationships and, therefore, we have richer data is absolutely central to the way we build it. And also we'll do it certain targeted selected markets. So you'd expect to see us do it in Hong Kong, in Singapore, in Korea, in Taiwan and predominantly in those markets.</p>
          <p>As to how much it will grow, I would hope that it will move the dial, that as a proportion of the overall consumer asset picture you should see it move up from the current 15% unsecured. I don't think it's going to move the dial massively, but I would hope to see, and expect to see, that we'll have sufficient appetite to move the dial a small amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Wholesale Bank, I think what I've said in the past is the fact that we believe that Wholesale Bank revenues, typically through the cycle grow at about two, two and a half times the rate of GDP growth. Which is why I got the derivative of a good benchmark for the long-term client revenue growth is somewhere between mid to high teens, is the sort of benchmark I've given you. And I think we still stand by that, and the evidence we're seeing is that we continue to take market share.</p>
          <p>Our volumes are up very significantly. So Richard quoted our Trade volumes being up 26%; we talked about cash volumes being up 24%; we talked about Corporate Finance being up 49%. However, in the first half of the year there was more liquidity in the market from quantitative easing in the West and from financial stimulus packages in Asia, and so banks were more liquid. So we saw a contraction on margins.</p>
          <p>So we think we will emerge from this crisis with additional market share, with additional volumes with our clients and still use internally that rule of thumb I've stood by for the last three or four years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Other questions. Sorry, yes, Peter. Yes, Peter Toeman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Peter Toeman from HSBC. Mortgage spreads seem to have contracted quite a bit in the first half of this year. I wondered &#x2013; well we know that in Hong Kong mortgages being priced off HIBOR as opposed to prime. I wondered if those structural changes are going to continue to depress mortgage spreads going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are actually seeing some mortgage pressure, although actually it's an odd period this because you've actually got a picture where the mortgage margin increased in the second half of last year, and then has fallen in the first half. And the level to which they've fallen is still above the level they were at, at the first half of last year. So mortgage margins are actually up 9 basis points across the Group on the first half margins that we had, and are down 13 basis points on the full year. That's Group.</p>
          <p>For Hong Kong it's the same pattern, it's an up, down pattern. I think we would anticipate still -- further moderate downwards pressure. I think about 85 to 90% of the mortgage market in Hong Kong has now been written on HIBOR. You'll see that impact come through, so I think we've seen some, as I say, small fall. We fell from about 135 basis points, about 115 basis points in Hong Kong over this last 12 months. I think you'll see some further moderate pressure down...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is a question right over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, the question has been answered. Okay. Up here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Arturo de Frias from Evolution. Another question on margins, but from a slightly different angle. You have mentioned margin pressure on several points of your presentation, margin pressure on mortgages, margin pressure on cash, margin pressure on trade, a few times in fact. And when I look at what all the other banks are talking about, they have been able to offset their deposit spreads pressure repricing their assets, and they can do that probably because Europe is re-trenching and deleveraging; obviously that's not your case.</p>
          <p>So you are suffering, at the same time, pressure in deposits and pressure on assets, and well I guess that's a fact of life, that's how your markets work. My question is, is it inevitable that until we see rates going up, you are going to continue to suffer margin pressure, because you are going to have margin pressure on both assets and liabilities side of the balance sheet, or there is something that you can do to try to offset that?</p>
          <p>And a small follow-on on that question, given that revenues in consumer are not growing much because probably of this margin pressure, and given that wholesale is growing very strongly, and we just heard Mike saying that it can continue to grow by high teens for the next two or three years. We are going to see again wholesale gaining ground, probably that's not the way you would like to put it, but gaining ground versus consumer? So is the proportion of wholesale versus consumer profit going to increase again in favor of wholesale versus what we could have expected in the last couple of years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I try the high level one, and then if you want to pick up on more detail on the margin points.</p>
          <p>What you've actually seen in this first half is a shift back towards consumer having a larger share of profits. It's still smaller, considerably smaller than wholesale, but a significantly more share of total profit than it had in 2009.</p>
          <p>I think the fundamental point about the interest rate cycle is that we are very long deposits as a Bank. We have a very good deposit base in the Consumer Bank, and probably sort of under-recognized, we have a very good deposit base in our cash management business in the Wholesale Bank as well. So we are definitely in a position where a rising interest rate environment is one that is advantageous to us.</p>
          <p>And a falling interest rate environment, by extension, is one that is more difficult. And a falling interest rate environment where central banks are throwing liquidity around is probably the most problematic, because you get low interest rates on your deposits, and then you get more competition on the asset side.</p>
          <p>Now as we begin to see interest rates rise, and we are beginning to see them rise in our markets, that will flow through to deposit margins. We don't expect that to actually have much P&amp;L impact, frankly, in 2010 because of the repricing cycle, and how long it takes to feed through. We've still been seeing the downward pressure affecting these results from interest rate falls that happened some time ago. So there's a lagged impact of it, but it is quite powerful.</p>
          <p>I don't know, Richard, did you want to add anything more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've had this discussion before. But I do think there's a fundamental difference between the West and the East. Part of that, don't forget that Asia's going at a different beat.</p>
          <p>So yes there's a different dynamic I think to the way margins might work as the world deleverages very significantly. But in Asia you got strong underlying growth rates.</p>
          <p>So yes, we'll have competition coming through and margin pressure will be there, but it's on a fundamentally different platform. It's a world where we're seeing growth rates in most of our markets in GDP of 5%, Indonesia over 6%, India 8%, China 10%. This is a very different picture that we're seeing.</p>
          <p>As for the margin pressure themselves on liabilities, we saw in the cash management business in the Wholesale Bank a drop of 43 basis points. So it's from the mid 115, 116 and down to the low 70s, and in the Consumer Bank we saw a drop, 96 to 69; easy to remember. But the vast majority of that drop in both of those businesses was actually against the first half, and the rate of the decline is slowing. And I think that gives your clue, your indication as to how you can expect this to play as interest rates stop falling, and in fact start to rise.</p>
          <p>So I'd be pretty confident that, as rates rise, we'll see the benefit of that coming through on our liability margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we shouldn't exaggerate also either the asset margin position. Lending margins in Wholesale haven't done bad before, and although if you look at the Trade to Finance business, margins are down 30 bps year-on-year. But they're still above what they were the year before, because they soared up and now they've come &#x2013; which one would expect; it's a sort of overshoot. And when you combine that with the 26% increase in volume, we've actually delivered 11% increase in income.</p>
          <p>So the pressure on margins is much more acute on the deposit side than it is on the asset side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Proportion of businesses, would you like to take? consumer, wholesale proportion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I said at the beginning it's shifted already towards Consumer. I think it's very difficult to predict precisely the shape of how it's going to evolve, because it depends upon the cycle of both loan impairment of the two businesses and the differential impact of interest rate cycles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Wealth Management income in Consumer. We need to see that continue to come back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert Law, just behind you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Robert Law, Nomura. Can I ask three brief points please? Firstly, on your own account trading, do you think that's bottomed out now after the high base last year?</p>
          <p>Secondly, you've given some guidance on the year-on-year jaws. Could you comment on whether you see flat jaws in the second half, compared with the second half of last year?</p>
          <p>And a bigger topic, you did raise the issue of acquisitions in your presentation. Could you comment on whether you're seeing increased opportunities in that area, and are you looking at expanding the current footprint that you've got?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll take the acquisitions question first, then if you, Mike, can deal with own accounts, and you can deal with the jaws, Richard.</p>
          <p>Acquisitions. We always repeat the same thing, which is that actually we're fundamentally focused on organic growth, and if given the choice we'll always spend a dollar organically rather than through an acquisition. But sometimes acquisitions do make sense as a way of either building scale in particular markets, or getting hold of capabilities of one sort or another.</p>
          <p>I referenced the small acquisition we did in Singapore around meeting and things like hire purchase for SMEs. We've also acquired a Barclays Custody business in Africa. We also acquired another bit of GE Cap's business, a mortgage business, in Hong Kong. So it's all very small bolt-on acquisitions.</p>
          <p>We do see some opportunities around the place, but if anything I would say the scale of the acquisition opportunities emerging from the crisis has turned out to be less than we expected. Partly because the distressed banks have tended to hang onto the things that were any good, and only sold things that weren't very attractive. And we're not a great believer in buying things that aren't very attractive.</p>
          <p>And so while we are constantly on the lookout for things that can support our organic business, filling gaps in our franchise, filling gaps in our product capability, I wouldn't say we're seeing a whole wealth of opportunities in the acquisition space. Own accounts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Own accounts. There's two halves to that; the environment and what we're doing, so let me cover the first. Clearly, in the West, the events around Greece caused a major reaction in terms of risk aversion. And that was also a correction, I think, in that there was a huge amount of liquidity in the market which was actually disconnected from economic reality. So there were a number of things going on around the events around Greece. And I think the market changed, as you've seen in a number of Western banks' results through quarter two, quite dramatically.</p>
          <p>I think we've come through that period now, and I think again perversely, because of the stress tests, we seem to be in an environment now where that correction has happened, and we're trending towards a more market-norm. Now we were relatively unaffected by those in our markets because that was a very Western phenomenon. So from an environment point of view I think we're still going to see crises, we're still going to see ups and downs, but I think we're trending towards more normal investment and trade per cycle. So you'd then assume that we're into a more normal environment.</p>
          <p>From our point of view, I think we are more comfortable now in terms of some of the sustainability of the revenues, largely because we're more diversified. If you go back three years ago, we were very foreign exchange-orientated as an asset class and with some interest rate derivatives on the back. I think now we're more balanced across our asset classes with both, foreign exchange, interest rates, commodities, equities and credit. So I think, as we see a changing environment we feel more comfortable because we've just got that more diversified income flow. And at the end of the day we're still dependent on the external environment, but I think we're better positioned to be able to withstand that than we have been in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another way to put it is that we always tend to say that, roughly speaking, client income to own account is 80-20. In the first half of last year it was 69 on client income and now it's back to its level. So we're more in the realm of normality now than we were in the first half of last year. Jaws, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On jaws; there are two reasons I won't answer your question directly. One is if I do, I think I'd give you quite a good forecast indication. And the second is I'm not sure I can do the math, so &#x2013; more relevant. But I think as we look at --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that mean you can't do your own forecasts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no. I think if you look at what's happening; 5% negative jaws, 2% negative jaws, Wholesale/Consumer. Actually they're narrowing already. But if you look at what's happening, and if you looked at those jaws against the second half performance, Wholesale's down another percent from there at about 4%, just under 4% actually, and Consumer's flat. So the trend is down. And I &#x2013; as we go into the second half we have got good tight control on the cost levers, and I think that's important. Peter used the word tactical. So you've got long run strategic direction here, but we're going to manage quite tactically in what is a world that feels still pretty uncertain, causing some caution.</p>
          <p>So as you look out, expect us to have a good grip. It will remain negative, predominantly because as the mass of the sizeable positive jaws in the first half against the first half of last year works its way through into the full year. But we have very good grip on the cost levers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Morning, it's Rohith Chandra-Rajan from Barclays Capital. A couple of questions, if I could please; one on revenues and one coming back to jaws, so on costs. Just sort of more broadly on revenues, would it be, given the sort of margin and volume dynamic in the Consumer business, is it fair to assume a sort of flattish half-on-half progression in revenues in the Consumer Bank? And more broadly, you commented about a pick-up in activity in July, specifically mentioning Wealth Management. Are there any other areas of business in either Consumer or Wholesale, where you see &#x2013; I guess particularly Wholesale, where you've seen an improvement, particularly, I guess, versus a very strong first four months of the year?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on costs, I guess, just trying to understand better your ability to control costs in the second half. A lot of the investment spend has gone into head count that you've highlighted. So really where would you be looking to rein back on costs in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could start, I'll have a go on some of the revenue dynamics. I think the first thing to say is, you've got to take out some of the noise from own account, and for things like the liability management exercise in the last year which created year-on-year distortion. The second key fact, Q2 income in both businesses was ahead of Q1. So while we talked about a slowdown in May and June, it wasn't a slowdown that put us into negative territory versus Q1. May and June were weaker than we wanted; July we saw pick up. You mentioned Wealth Management; we've also had a pick-up in Trade and Corporate Finance and Tax Audit, across a range of different businesses.</p>
          <p>We don't want to sort of declare victory, because this is a volatile picture, and also August, tends to be &#x2013; in the trading businesses, tends to be a relatively slow month in any case. But we were certainly encouraged by the fact that, across a number of key businesses, July was markedly better than May or June. The other thing I think you do need to look at when you're thinking about second half, and the income momentum in both businesses, is what's going on in the balance sheet. I mean the fact is that customer deposits are up 12% on the end of '09, and customer loans are up 9% on the end of '09. And so both businesses are seeing good balance sheet velocity which ultimately translates through into income.</p>
          <p>Do you want to add anything on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think you've covered it very well. Very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've forgotten what the second question was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On control of costs into the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The reality is, part of the &#x2013; arguably the reason why we had negative jaws in this first half is because we demonstrated very effectively that we can control the costs a year ago, because we pulled back on the cost lever very sharply. We ended up with 10 point something percent positive jaws. Which means that almost whatever you do, you end up with a distortion the following year. We are very mindful of what costs are committed, in terms of head count and projects and things, where we have flex, and where the decision points are that allow us to move our cost base. I wouldn't say that it's completely flexible, but we're very used to managing it dynamically so that we can respond to how we see the income or loan impairment trajectory.</p>
          <p>Richard, do you want add anything on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, on head count we continue to hire. We are building out businesses not just in the front line, but also in the support functions. We'll see what head count growth we get in the second half. It tends to have a natural cycle to it anyway, actually. The remuneration dynamics in the sector tend to make it less easy effectively to hire towards the end of the year, and it's a quieter period, and then it really starts again early the following year. So we still continue to hire, and we've got very grip again, as I say, on the investment programs that we have not yet released and that we have yet to decide to release. So we're watching that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. It's Leigh Goodwin from Citi. I've got three unrelated questions, actually. First two are quite short ones. First one is on FX; could you just tell us whether any FX movements had any impact on the numbers in the first half? I know they have in previous periods, and I just wondered because they've been moving around quite a lot. Secondly, just following up the question on own account, and on asset liability management. I wonder whether you could tell us whether there'd been any pick-up in the second quarter as we saw with one of your counterparts &#x2013; well, it was HSBC actually who found more opportunities to reinvest surplus liquidity profitably in the second quarter. I'm wondering whether that's something that you'd also seen.</p>
          <p>Thirdly is a broader question on regulatory risk, because this was something which I know you've been very concerned about, and you're not making a lot of it today. So does that mean you're less concerned, or whether you're still concerned? And specifically one point &#x2013; one question is on the UK bank levy. Because I'm finding it very difficult to work out what that's going to be for you, and I wonder whether you can <mark type="inaudible" /> enlighten me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I take the last question first, and then if you can pick up the FX risk, and if you can pick up ALM and sort of Q2 dynamics. Regulatory risk; look, we're still concerned about regulatory risk. It's just that we thought you might be bored by us talking about it. We get bored about talking about it all the time. And the funny thing is it's not really the core regulatory agenda of Basel III that causes the real problems. It's all the stuff around the margins; it's the stuff on levies and remuneration and independent commissions and all this sort of stuff. But it's also just a sheer distraction. The amount of time both regulators and people who run banks are spending dealing with all this stuff is a complete distraction.</p>
          <p>In terms of the levy, it's not entirely clear to us either how it's going to work or how much it's going to cost us. If you do a sort of crude back of the envelope thing you can quickly get to a number that says, of the order of 100 million in 2011 and 200 million in 2012. But whether that's right or not, it will depend a lot on precise definitions on how they deal with potential overlap between different schemes in different countries. And I think there's still a lot to be sorted out. Frankly, the implementation complexities of that were not considered thoroughly enough, and I think we're still some way to seeing how that's all going to play out.</p>
          <p>On the FX, that's a pretty <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On a year-on-year basis we've had just over $300 million of revenue benefit, and $89 million of trading profit benefit. Against the second half it's $40 million of profit benefit and just under $100 million of revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's basically Korea and India?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Korea, India --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...and Singapore. Those are the two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>ALM trends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me not maybe give you too much insight in terms of the Q1, Q2 numbers, but absent that I think you've been given the trend about what our overall numbers did quarter one on quarter two, so you can infer from that. But what I would say is, we're seeing a change in the environment. In our markets in Asia particularly, regulators are concerned about asset price inflation, and really since last September have been using macro-prudential tools to try and cool that asset price inflation. And clearly, not trying to push up interest rates in order to choke up fragile growth. What we've seen now is them pushing up interest rates. Now that gives them a real challenge because they want to keep their currencies weak, and push interest rates up to control inflation so they push the inflationary pressures. So they're got a real challenge.</p>
          <p>But we are seeing the trend is changing now. So India, for example, has done three rises now in the last four or five months. Korea, as Richard said, has put a rise in. So &#x2013; and that's good for ALM, because they're not shock rises. The best thing for ALM is just nice steady rises, and you can layer into increasing yields. The worst thing for ALM is when you get shock rises, because you're just the wrong side of that. So the environment is getting more friendly, and then it all depends on the balance between our local currency and G3 balance sheets. But the trend is improving, from that point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Michael Helsby from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. I've just got three questions as well, actually. Firstly, could you tell us what the profit contribution was from China? I know you mentioned it was down, but if you could tell us what it is that would be helpful. Also, just more of a bigger picture question on India. India is clearly your biggest region by profit, but it's very much dominated by Wholesale. So I was wondering if you could just tell us what you're doing to improve the Consumer profitability and grow that business. I know it's quite difficult, regulatory wise, but that would be helpful. And just lastly, I'm just thinking strategically. You mentioned all the trade corridors in your speech, Peter, and one that stands out that you're not in is the China-Brazil link. So I was wondering if &#x2013; at a board level, if you've ever had any discussions about entering Brazil as a region. And I think that would be quite interesting. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Richard, China profits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China profits are $80 million, just under. And of that, Consumer Bank loses some low-10s of millions of dollars and Wholesale Bank therefore makes 120 to $125 million of profit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On India; I mean India is a great business, and the Wholesale Banking business has done superbly well, and will continue, almost under any scenario, it'll continue to be, by far, the biggest business in India. That said, the Consumer Banking business is doing well. You've got income up 18%; you've got profits up 121% to 53 billion. So, if it hadn't been in India this would look like a good performance, but it's just been dwarfed rather by what's going on in the Wholesale Banking business. The reality is that we are more constrained on the Consumer Banking side because of the restrictions on branches and so on. It's harder to build out a Consumer Banking business, and we do see it as an important part of the overall franchise and business in India. What we are doing is we are spending more on non-branch channels, things like off-site ATMs, Internet and mobile channels, so as to find ways of overcoming the constraints we have on the branch side. I think we will &#x2013; we have the potential to drive sustained growth in both businesses, but that's not going to mean that we suddenly shift to having a consumer-led business in India.</p>
          <p>Now, China-Brazil. Funny you should talk about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Funny you should talk about that. Fortunately, we saw that coming, or we recognized the trend. But for us, again, it's a very focused strategy. Brazil is dominated by the four or five big local banks there now, so to think we're going to go into that market and start tromping around the domestic market and compete, is not our strategy. So the strategy we have for Brazil is very similar to the one we have for the rest of the Americas and for Europe, which is, how do we catch the trade and investment flows going from Brazil into, actually, the wider area in --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Latin America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Asia, not just China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so we've been building our business up there, and actually last month we got our domestic banking license. And the aim there is to work, as we do in the rest of the Americas and Europe, with the large corporates who are wanting to do trade and investment flows into Asia, Africa and the Middle East, but also then working very closely with the banks, acting almost as their international arms for those trade flows. So a very focused strategy. But you're absolutely right on the potential of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have you sized potential in terms of revenues, five years down the line when you've been thinking about your investment strategy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes we have. And we've spent quite a lot of time talking about it. We think it is &#x2013; you're right to focus on it; it's a very interesting opportunity, and I think one that, given the depth of our network in Asia &#x2013; but not just that, but also the capabilities we have in the areas of metal and mining, energy and so on, and agriculture, we can play with real knowledge, sectoral knowledge in those flows. And so we do think it's a very exciting opportunity. But the trick is the discipline. It's making sure we don't get distracted and start trying to think that we can build a domestic franchise, because if we do that we'll get nailed. Any other questions? Yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Raul Sinha from Nomura here. Can I perhaps draw you a bit more on Korea, where profits have gone the other way, especially relative to your long-term aspirations there, in that market? Firstly, in loan impairments which have got worse from the second half of last year, it looks like you've taken specific impairments in on shipping; could you quantify for us what the size of that was? And then secondly, could you talk about the outlook for revenues on a constant currency basis for the second half, because you have seen the revenue line going the other way as well in the first half of 2010, even after we adjust for the currency impact which was, I think, 4%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to pick up those, Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me just pick &#x2013; I mean, the thing you also have to normalize out is BC Cards. So you've got to take currency out and BC Cards out I think to get to a much better picture of the first half this year on second half of last year. With regard to the loan impairment, in Wholesale Bank we've a $69 million specific provision, numbered provisions. The lion's share of that attaches to those shipbuilding exposures; we've had no new material provisions, as I said in the presentation. So the lion's share is to shipbuilding. We have pretty much fully provided all of the shipbuilding accounts which are in default.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On revenues, I mean, the progression forward is broad based across both businesses. I think you have to normalize that, as I said earlier, for the second half BC Cards -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question was really around it's a liability style market, so &#x2013; but you are seeing interest rate hikes there. Can you expect the Consumer Bank --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It'll take a little time for that to &#x2013; It'll take a little time for that to feed through. And as Richard said, we are anticipating a materially higher profit performance in Korea in the second half. We are making progress in Korea. I wouldn't pretend it's a quick fix; I mean it's taking time to deliver the kind of productivity performance, both in terms of return on capital and in terms of cost income ratio that we want. But the other part of the Korea story that I think is important not to forget, the example I gave of Hyundai Motor in India, that actually is mainly generating income in India, but it's business that we wouldn't have done if we didn't have our franchise in Korea. We're also increasingly doing a fair amount of business in the Middle East that is linked to major Korean companies.</p>
          <p>And so we've got lots to do in Korea, and the big challenge is really getting the Consumer Bank motoring. But on the Wholesale side, we're already leveraging the relationships with big chambers across the rest of our network quite effectively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry <mark type="inaudible" />. There was no pressure coming on the time deposits, you had a change in regulatory ratios attaching to liquidity in Korea, and all the local banks moved very quickly to adjust to new forward targets. They also changed the funding ratio to something called COFIX which is an average of the local banks' rates. And that has put more pressure on mortgage margins. That again was a feature in the last two to three months or so. But even with those taken into account, we've got very good pipelines and high expectation of a materially better upturn in the second half than on the first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Any other questions? No more questions? Well if there are no more questions, just to sort of pick up some of the quick highlights. Obviously, this is a record set of results, up 10% year-on-year and 35% on our profits in the second half. Actually, we've made it rather simple for you because you've got 10% profit increase; 10% EPS increase; 10% dividend increase. So it's very simple. Group income, yeah, it's flat at a headline level, but if you cut under the skin of that and think about the own account dynamics, the liability management, you've got the CB income up 8%, you've got client income in Wholesale Banking up 18%, and you've got good balance sheet velocity both sides of the balance sheet in both businesses. So while we don't underestimate the uncertainties in the world, we have started the second half with good momentum in both businesses and the Bank as a whole.</p>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for joining us this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>