<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1181282" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-11-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2066</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Lars Troen S&#xF8;rensen, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Eldar S&#xE6;tre, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Lars Troen S&#xF8;rensen</participant>
      <participant id="3">Eldar S&#xE6;tre</participant>
      <participant id="4">Torgrim Reitan</participant>
      <participant id="5">Iain Reid</participant>
      <participant id="6">James Hubbard</participant>
      <participant id="7">Colin Smith</participant>
      <participant id="8">Neill Morton</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jon Rigby</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the StatoilHydro Third Quarter 2008 Earnings Presentation. My name is Lars S&#xF8;rensen, and I'm the Head of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>This morning at 8:00 AM, Central European Time, we put all the presentations and MD&amp;A out on the web, both on our own website statoilhydro.com, but also on the Oslo Stock Exchange website. The presentation that we use today can be downloaded from both the Oslo Stock Exchange page, but also statoilhydro.com, of course. I would like to direct your attention to the disclaimer, and safe harbor statements that we have in the back of the presentation.</p>
          <p>Let's spend 30 seconds on your safety, as usual. This room has three emergency exits, one behind me, two at the sides. When you come out, that's entrance out there, you have to go past the reception, and there's a staircase that will take you downstairs. Or, there's a staircase just behind me here, and that will take you downstairs and out into the open. Assembly point is at the other side of the street. Don't use the lifts of course if the alarm goes off. If the alarm goes, it is real there are no fire drills or anything like that prepared for today.</p>
          <p>Eldar S&#xE6;tre, our StatoilHydro's Chief Financial Officer, will take us through today's earnings presentation. After the presentation, we will have a Gas seminar, or after the presentation we will have a Q&amp;A session first, sorry, where you can ask questions, both from the floor here in London, but also from the Internet. After the earnings presentation, and after the Q&amp;A session of that session, we will have a Gas seminar. We would like to invite you to participate on that of course if you would like to, and the Executive Vice President and Head of Natural Gas, Rune Bj&#xF8;rnson, will be the host of that presentation. I'll come back to presenting the presenters in that presentation later. The seminar will be webcasted as well, so if you would like to follow that presentation on the web, you can do that.</p>
          <p>At this point, I'd like to welcome or send my welcomes to the audience from the web. You can actually send in your questions and I will read them aloud to Mr. S&#xE6;tre or later at the Gas presentations Q&amp;A. And you can do that already now. You can use the submit questions button on your screen.</p>
          <p>So, after these short words of introduction, it's my privilege to welcome our Chief Financial Officer, Eldar S&#xE6;tre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars. Ladies and gentlemen, I would like to welcome you first of all to this third quarter presentation here in London. It should come as no surprise to any of us that both financial markets and commodity markets are volatile. But I have to say that to see the volatility and the power of the financial crises that we have experienced over the last few weeks that has been quite an experience I guess for all of us.</p>
          <p>Being in a business with very long-term horizons, I think it is our duty as management to make our investment decisions and really to plan our operations in such a way that we are able to create shareholder values through the cycles whatever are the situations and the cycles of the economy.</p>
          <p>We expect that the world economy will see a downturn for some time derived from this financial crisis and that this also will have an impact on the demand and supply for our core commodities. Fundamentally however, we maintain the longer term perspective on our industry. There will be growing demand for oil and gas in the years to come and it is our duty and also our competence to accommodate this. So our strategy therefore remains firm. We have a strong portfolio of assets and we maintain our current plans. Although taking into accounts the effects of the current markets and also fully understanding the optionality and the flexibility that we actually have in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>So this is the background for my presentation today and the main message that I will convey today is that, first of all, StatoilHydro has a solid underlying operations and we have made some improvements also during this quarter that I will come back to. Secondly, that our financial position is fundamentally solid and that we have a strong cash flow generation at the current price environment, which is sufficient to serve both our CapEx program and a dividend policy in line with our &#x2013; dividend payout in line with our dividend policy. So I will come back to all of these issues and I will start with the highlights of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Our underlying net operating income increased by almost 60% on a quarter-to-quarter basis. The main driver behind this increase is higher, obviously higher oil and gas prices. However, we also saw a 1% increase in equity oil production on the quarter oil and gas production and on a year-to-date basis a 5% increase in oil and gas production.</p>
          <p>At this point I would also like to highlight our strong performance on the Norwegian continental shelf. We saw a high regularity this quarter, including the successful completion of a very comprehensive, actually the most comprehensive, maintenance turnaround program that we have ever seen. We saw continued good progress on drilling, improving our drilling operations, and also a continued high success rate on our exploration program on the Norwegian continental shelf . In addition, we also strengthened our position in the Goliath discovery in the Barents Sea.</p>
          <p>Then we've also had this quarter a significant non-cash impact on our net financial items and consequently also in our net income. This comes from a 15% weakening of the Norwegian kroner versus U.S. dollar. Then you have to remember fundamentally StatoilHydro benefits from strong U.S. dollar. However, this quarter the foreign exchange accounting adjustments related to our U.S. debt and also some currency swaps, and I'll come back to this, is minus almost NOK 14 billion which is the main explanation for the negative net financials of 9.7 billion this quarter. And I underline that these are unrealized and they are non-cash as such and accounting effects are adjusted (07.33).</p>
          <p>Finally, I repeat that our financial position is strong with a good cash generation from operations and I will revert to all of these topics later in my presentation. But let me first just remind you of some changes, improvements that we have made to our disclosure practice, just to make sure that you understand this and are able to benefit from them.</p>
          <p>First of all, we will now discuss our results more consistently in the financial &#x2013; on the basis of what we call adjusted or underlying net operating income. As we're now reporting according to IFRS, introduces some volatility, we could say, in the profit and loss related to fair valuation of various assets, impairments and reversal also of impairments, derivatives, accounting, et cetera. And also then we have the over, under lift situation from quarter-to-quarter that also changes as the lifting schedule impacts this and so does accounting effects on inventories when oil prices changes, et cetera. So in order for you, investors and analysts to be better able to compare the underlying performance we therefore adjust for these infrequent items.</p>
          <p>With regards to costs, we now also provide a more detailed split of the operating cost developments including a breakdown from the total Group operating costs, down to the upstream cash production costs. So you can see how this is &#x2013; you can reconcile these components which is then relevant when you measure the unit production cost as we present it for the Group as a whole.</p>
          <p>Finally, on this issue within the Natural Gas business segment we now split the net operating income into processing and transportation and marketing and trading. And within processing and transportation what you will find there is the income from our share of the &#x2013; in GasLed, the pipeline system in Norway and also income generated from our Rolla technical service provider related to the gas processing facilities at Koshte and Kolsness. The result from the marketing and trading sub segment then is reflecting the value added from these activities on top of our upstream business. So hopefully you can hear me better now. So we trust these improvements to our reporting is appreciated and that you will soon get acquainted with these and then I will proceed to our most important value driver.</p>
          <p>As already mentioned, we have delivered a 1% equity production growth compared to the same quarter last year, reaching an equity production of 1,733,000 barrels per day. On the Norwegian continental shelf, production has developed more or less as planned, except for the Kvitebj&#xF8;rn pipeline incident that you should be aware of. Production outside of Norway has been slightly lower than expected due to some unplanned shutdowns.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, as I've already mentioned, we had an extensive Turnaround program on the Norwegian continental shelf. The negative impact from this Turnaround program was approximately 70,000 barrels per day in the quarter, compared to approximately 40,000 barrels per day in the same quarter last year. The impact on planned maintenance on the outside of Norway was in the range of 10,000 barrels per day in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Unplanned shutdowns that I mentioned from our international operations outside of Norway accounted for approximately 25,000 barrels per day this quarter and it was mainly related to our activities in Azerbaijan. So in summary, we have delivered a 5% equity production growth on a year to date basis and we've maintained our guiding of 1.9 million barrels per day of equity production for the full year of 2008.</p>
          <p>Entitlement production in the third quarter was 1,550,000 barrels per day compared to 1,596,000 in the third quarter of last year. And the main reasons for this reduction is new tranches in some production sharing agreements and also including the unplanned shutdowns and repairs, as I've already mentioned.</p>
          <p>So, let me now turn to the key financials in more detail. As I've already mentioned, we now focus our discussion on the adjusted or the underlying net operating income. In the third quarter, our underlying net operating income was NOK 52.1 billion compared to 32.8 last year. This increase was due to a 36% increase in the realized liquids prices measured in Norwegian kroner and a 55% increase in gas prices also measured in Norwegian kroner. This was partly offset by a 3% reduction in entitlement production and also somewhat higher operating cost that I will come back to.</p>
          <p>Infrequent items, special items impacting our net operating income was a negative 5.1, which I also will revert to later in the presentation. Net financial items amounted to minus 9.7 billion in the quarter and this was caused by weakening of the Norwegian kroner versus U.S. dollar and I will discuss this actually on my next slide.</p>
          <p>But let me now explain the unusually high tax rate of 83% this quarter. This is mainly related to two factors. First, it has to do with the net financial item, which is quite significant as you have seen and negative this quarter, and they are calculated at a tax rate of around 45% and in this quarter it was more or less exactly 45%. So therefore, about 45% of the net unrealized financial costs, and is cost this time, of 9.7 is deducted while the operating income typically had a tax rate of around 70%. So this impact, 45% on a big cost component that drives up the average tax rate for the quarter.</p>
          <p>The other main component is related to impairments of 3.1 billion which mainly comes from our Gulf of Mexico portfolio. These assets in the Gulf of Mexico, which have been impaired, are without tax protection from an accounting, and I repeat from an accounting perspective. Future income generated from these and some other assets are considered to come too far into the future to be recognized in accounting &#x2013; in an accounting perspective. But these losses, if they are maintained, are still obviously deductible from a tax cash payment perspective when revenues emerge.</p>
          <p>So then to the net financial items. These amounted to a negative 9.7, mainly caused by unrealised currency impacts on long-term debt and short-term liquidity swaps of almost 14 billion that I mentioned. We manage StatoilHydro as a U.S. dollar business. And as I mentioned already, long-term, StatoilHydro will benefit from a strong U.S. dollar. However, our accounts are reported in Norwegian kroner, which is also the basis for the main part of our tax payments and also our dividend payments. And that &#x2013; these facts give some non-cash accounting volatility from quarter-to-quarter and the development this quarter is as expected. The weakening of the Norwegian kroner against the U.S. dollar will result in an unrealized currency loss related to our long-term debt. The weakening of 75 Euro or 15% resulted in an unrealized accounting loss on long-term debt of NOK 5.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Then to the liquidity part. As mentioned, our revenues are mainly in U.S. dollar with tax liabilities and dividend commitments continuously in Norwegian kroner &#x2013; accruing in Norwegian kroner &#x2013; and to manage this currency exposure in Norwegian kroner related to future tax and dividend payments. We therefore, fix the U.S. dollar and NOK relationship on a daily basis and hence remove the currency risk related to these future Norwegian kroner commitments, as I mentioned related to tax and dividends. However, as most of our running OpEx and CapEx are still in U.S. dollar, we therefore, swap these Norwegian kroner hedge position back into U.S. dollar with a maturity matching the future tax and dividends payments. And these swaps are mark-to-market in our accounts and they result therefore, in an unrealized gain or loss every quarter and you have seen that in our accounts for many quarters now. And in this third quarter, these swaps generated as I said an unrealized and still non-cash loss of approximately NOK 8.7 billion.</p>
          <p>Then I will give some comments to each of the business areas. Starting with E&amp;P Norway, the adjusted net operating income for E&amp;P Norway was NOK 43.8 billion compared to 28.3 last year. The increase was mainly, was due to a 38% increase in liquid prices in Norwegian kroner and a 38% increase in the transfer price of natural gas. The realized price for liquids, that is crude, condensate and NGL, was approximately 110 on average, U.S. $10 per barrel, against the Brent average of approximately U.S. $115 per barrel.</p>
          <p>On the NCS, almost 15% of our liquid volumes is NGL, which has been priced at a lower price than the crude oil, and that explains, actually the whole price differential of U.S. $5, compared to Brent Blend. Average daily production of liquids increased from 770,000 barrels per day, last year &#x2013; third quarter last year &#x2013; to 780 this quarter. And average gas production decreased from 537,000 barrels per day to 512 in oil equivalents in the third quarter this year, and it is mainly driven by the Kvitebj&#xF8;rn pipeline incident that I've already mentioned.</p>
          <p>At our Capital Markets Day in January, we also presented some plans for improving our drilling efficiency, both related to drilling on new production wells, to fight the decline on the Norwegian Continental Shelf, and also to improve exploration activities. In 2007, we managed to drill around 70 meters per day, on average, and in 2006, the performance was even worse actually. Year-to-date, in 2008, we have reached approximately 80 meters per day. That is a 15% improvement and in line, actually with what we indicated as an improvement, in January at our Capital Markets Day. So this is really a strong achievement for such a big portfolio within the short timeframe and we will certainly do our utmost to sustain this performance and improve even further. And as mentioned, we have also completed the most extensive turnaround program ever on the Norwegian Continental Shelf, and this, which is really a portfolio of big projects, complex projects, has been delivered on-time and within &#x2013; with the consequences for production that we have guided on earlier.</p>
          <p>Then to the International; outside of Norway business, but again, adjusted for infrequent items, net operating income for our E&amp;P outside Norway was 3.8 billion compared to 3.4 in the same quarter last year. This increase was mainly, due to a 29% increase in realized liquid prices, measured in Norwegian kroner again, which contributed 2.1 billion to the -- and in this context, I should also mention, a particular feature this quarter, that we actually had 63% of our lifted volumes on the Norwegian or on the international side, taking place in September, and this is due to the predefined lifting schedules and procedures that are in place. And with the declining prices through the quarter, this lead to lower average realized prices, again compared to Brent Blend.</p>
          <p>Adjusted exploration expenses was down 0.5 billion, when we adjust for 1.3 billion in impairments, which is allocated to exploration within the international E&amp;P segment. And the reduction of 0.5 is related to increased capitalization of international exploration activities. All of these increases were partly compensated by an 11% decrease in the average daily entitlement production. So, in addition to some unplanned shutdowns, as already mentioned, there was an average PSA effect on entitlement production of 183,000 barrels per day, on a quarterly basis, and 178, on a year-to-date basis, compared to 125,000 barrels per day in the same quarter, last year.</p>
          <p>Finally, in this segment, a comment, start-up of new fields led to an increase of depreciation of 0.4 billion, ordinary depreciations, when we then adjust for 1.8 billion in impairments which is allocated to depreciations.</p>
          <p>Then to the Natural Gas business; the &#x2013; adjusted for the net &#x2013; adjusted for infrequent items, which is basically derivatives in this segment, the income for Natural Gas business was 2.2 compared to 1 billion in the same quarter last year. The adjusted operating income, within the processing and transportation, and we now, as I've said, have split this segment, was 1.6 billion which is at the same level as it was last year while the adjusted net income for the marketing and trading was 0.7 billion, positive, compared to a loss of 0.6 billion last year.</p>
          <p>The volume weighted average sales price was to NOK 2.37 per standard cubic meter in the quarter compared to 1.53 in the same quarter last year and, as I mentioned, that is 55% increase.</p>
          <p>Natural Gas sales volumes was 9.9 billion standard cubic meter in the quarter and that is approximately at the same level as we saw in the same quarter last year. And of the total gas sales in this quarter, 7.9 bcm was entitlement gas from the Norwegian continental shelf and 2 bcm was third-party gas.</p>
          <p>Adjusted operating expenses increased by 0.6 billion compared to third quarter last year, if you adjust these numbers. And this is due to increased transportation activities caused by startup of new pipelines related to the Langeled, startup of the Langeled pipeline and also the Tampen Link pipeline and also higher LNG transportation volumes and costs of these volumes are ramping up.</p>
          <p>I would also mention one small item &#x2013; sales, general and administration costs. You can see in the financial review that these increased by 0.2 billion and these &#x2013; the underlying costs for StatoilHydro is unchanged. So, this increase is entirely related to expenses covered by the SDFI, the state share of marketing activities in the U.S. So, this is a grossing principle that has been applied.</p>
          <p>Finally, to the Manufacturing and Marketing. The adjusted net operating income for this segment was 2.7 billion compared to 0.4 billion in the same quarter last year. And I'll comment this under each of the business sub-segments of this part of our business.</p>
          <p>Oil trading, oil sales, trading and supply had a net operating income of 2.3 compared to a loss of 0.3 billion last year. The increase was due to positive currency impacts which we haven't adjusted for on our commercial storage and also positive development in particular related to our crude trading activities.</p>
          <p>The adjusted net operating income for Manufacturing was 0.2 billion compared to 0.5 billion last year and this reduction is due to the ongoing &#x2013; still ongoing quite comprehensive started early September turnaround at our Mongstad refinery. Quite extensive, leading to both reduced revenues on the refinery side and also higher cost, maintenance cost, related to this turnaround and it's all down in order to improve the operational robustness of this very important refinery for us. Adjusted net operating income for energy and retail was 0.3 compared to 0.2 billion in last year.</p>
          <p>So, let me now summarize the adjustments that we have made in our reported numbers in order to arrive at our underlying net operating income. As already mentioned in my introduction, our income is adjusted for certain items that are not reflective to be precise, our underlying performance in the reporting period. And the following items have been adjusted for in this quarter. First of all, impairments had a negative impact of 3.4, I've said that, before tax and 2.9 after tax for the reasons that I've mentioned to you earlier. This is mostly related to Gulf of Mexico assets and mainly due to changes in forward prices because these are assets that have been impaired earlier and they are following the markets out there every quarter.</p>
          <p>This quarter we also &#x2013; I'll comment on derivatives, sorry. Derivatives had a positive impact of 0.9 before tax and after tax 0.8 this quarter. And this comes from a negative effect on the E&amp;P Norway business segment of 2 billion which is related to the earn-out agreements that some of you have seen following us for many quarters now, and this time because of the forward prices and developments, the valuation is down. While we had positive impacts, both on Natural Gas and in the Manufacturing and Marketing, of approximately 1.5 billion in each of those segments from derivatives.</p>
          <p>Then to the underlift. This quarter, we had an underlift position of approximately 30,000 barrels per day on the Norwegian continental shelf and there was no such position basically outside of Norway. Now, this amounted to 1.3 billion before tax and 0.3 billion after tax.</p>
          <p>Finally, we had a provision related to a take-or-pay contract within our Manufacturing and Marketing segment of 1.3 billion before tax, 0.9 after-tax and also some miscellaneous accruals of minus 0.3. So combined all of these infrequent items represent a negative impact 5.1 before tax, 3.4 after-tax and in the same quarter last year it was a positive impact of 3.1 before tax. Should also mention that you will find more details including how these effects are broken down on each of the business segments in our financial review statements.</p>
          <p>Then I would like to give a few comments also to our operating expenses and as I mentioned we have added a more detailed split of these costs in our review this time and we will continue to do so. The E&amp;P upstream production cost in absolute numbers have &#x2013; show an increasing trend that you can see here to the left. From third quarter last year to the third quarter this year about two-thirds of this increase of 0.7 is related to activities, it's about start-up of new activities, both on the international shelf &#x2013; international operations and on the Norwegian Continental Shelf. And the last third that is the net effect of industry cost inflation of also increased maintenance on the mature field on the Norwegian Continental Shelf and obviously also compensating measures that we are doing to compensate for these.</p>
          <p>Based on equity volumes, the unit production cost was NOK 33.3 for the last 12 months compared to NOK 29 in the last &#x2013; in the same 12 months one year ago. So overall, we had an upstream cost development according to our expectations and our guiding remains the same, a production unit cost of around 33 to NOK 36 per barrel in the period from 2008 to 2012 with an upwards pressure in this period.</p>
          <p>The operating cost within the Natural Gas and Manufacturing and Marketing have also increased compared to the third quarter last year even if we exclude the infrequent items that you can see illustrated here. The higher operating costs was mainly due to &#x2013; compared to the same quarter last year was mainly due to higher transportation cost, as I've already explain, under the Natural Gas segment and also costs related to the comprehensive turnaround at Mongstad.</p>
          <p>Then a few comments also to our financial position. Some of you might be concerned about how cash flows and financials are looking these days. And as already mentioned in my introduction, I can assure you that we are in good shape. Our after-tax cash flow from operation was NOK 113 billion in the first nine months of this year and in addition we had sale of assets generating NOK 5 billion, so that was cash coming in to us. We invested cash wise 46 billion kroner and we paid 27 billion in dividends related to 2007. Now that leaves us with a cash flow of 72 billion if you exclude the dividends which are related to last &#x2013; to 2007.</p>
          <p>As per the end of this quarter, 30th of September, our cash exceeded our debt with NOK 13 billion. So in other words, we are generating a strong cash flow and we also have a strong balance sheet, which gives us financial flexibility and capacity to continue with our high quality CapEx program while staying fully committed to our dividend policy of paying 45 to 50% of our net income of...</p>
          <p>As we said at our Capital Markets Day in January, we are cash flow neutral for this year before dividends at around U.S. $50 per barrel. That excludes acquisitions and nothing at all has changed to this statement. It's still the same. I should also remind you that our &#x2013; all our ongoing projects, project development, that we are developing, in the process of developing now have been sanctioned on the basis of lower oil prices that we currently see and also that our portfolio of producing assets these days have significantly lower break-even prices than you see.</p>
          <p>Our non-sanctioned asset portfolio is also constructed in such a way that we &#x2013; the projects with the highest assumed break-even prices are also the projects with the largest flexibility and optionality in our portfolio when it comes to timing and the strategy of developing these assets.</p>
          <p>Finally, to summarize my presentation, let's have a look at the guiding for the full year of 2008. At the Capital Markets Day in January, we guided an equity production of 1.9 million barrels per day and our production performance during the first nine months of this year have been strong and supports the same guidance of 1.9. Our 2012 guidance is also unchanged at 2.2 million barrels per day.</p>
          <p>At the second quarter presentation in August, we estimated organic capital expenditure for the Group as a whole at the &#x2013; a level of 65 billion for the year and that was based on an estimated 525 that was reasonable at that time, Norwegian kroner per U.S. dollar for the rest of the year. The estimated capital expenditure remains unchanged at these assumptions although the current level of U.S. dollar versus Norwegian kroner will influence the final year-end figure and remember that approximately 7% of our CapEx is exposed to U.S.</p>
          <p>Unit production cost for equity volumes is estimated, as I said, in the range of 33 to NOK 36 per barrel in this period. We expect to continue our high exploration activity level throughout this year and to complete around 75 to 80 wells this year. That is slightly more than we have guided you previously. But we still keep our exploration cost estimate at below 18 bit.</p>
          <p>Finally, I would like to remind you that a potential further strengthening of the U.S. dollar versus Norwegian kroner that we saw in the fourth and third quarter will have, and, as we have seen actually so far in this quarter, will have a negative impact on the net financial items also in this quarter, so that's just to remind you. But then you should also remember that fundamentally we will benefit from a strong U.S. dollar.</p>
          <p>And as my closing comment I will just inform you that we will announce more details when it comes to 2009 at our capital markets update, as we call it, presentation on the 14th of January next year here in London. So I hope to see you then. Thank for the attention and I leave the word back to Lars for some...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thank you, Eldar. I'd now invite you here in London to ask questions and also just to repeat asking questions from the Internet, you can do that by pressing the Submit Questions button and I'll receive them on my PC and ask the questions on your behalf. You can do that already. So please send in your questions now.</p>
          <p>Then I would like to invite Senior Vice President and the Head of Performance Management and Control, Torgrim Reitan to join us here at the panel and also the Head of &#x2013; the Executive Vice President and Head of Natural Gas, Rune Bj&#xF8;rnson, who will also be available here next to me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the first question, I'll take one from the Internet and then I'll leave it back to the floor here. First question is from Jason Kenney, ING and it's about PSA effects or PSE effects. We have a guiding on &#x2013; at page 25 in the presentation with some indications on what the PSE effects are on an annual basis and Jason asks at $40 per barrel, at a $40 per barrel shift, it implies a 4,000 barrels per day impact between 80 and $100 per barrel in oil price. However, in the 2Q results there was a $35 per barrel change between 150 and $115 and there the impact was 15,000 barrels per day, can we assume that StatoilHydro's portfolio is less sensitive at lower prices or is there a S-curve out here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, what you can assume is basically what we guide you on. It's hard to be precise and use the &#x2013; this as a basis for making further assumptions. Basically, we have a PSA effect of US$178 per barrels so far this year and at US$100 that will remain the same. So, I think during the third quarter we have seen no assets coming into new tranches and basically we don't expect to see that in the fourth quarter, but maybe you, Torgrim, could...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you Eldar. I think it's important to recognize that during 2007 we had a large increase in the PSA effect as we saw oil prices increase steadily and we also saw that in the beginning of 2007. We have come through a lot of tranches, so currently it looks stable. There are still a few projects that will end &#x2013; which are in cost recovery phases and will move into tranches later, but not assumed in 2008 as such. So, it is just, we said at the Capital Market Day that at $100 per barrel as an average oil price, the PSA effect could be approximately 180,000 barrels a day and as you see it's the same as it's currently as well, so it's going along as we planned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, another question from Iain Reid from the floor here in London.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Ian Reid from Macquarie, Eldar a couple of questions. Firstly, the discount to Brent you've now got at the moment. I understand your comments about the NGL pricing differentials but about a year ago you had about $1 per barrel differential. Now that oil prices have fallen to approximately where you were about a year ago is it again going to be $1 or is this 6 or $7 locked in now? And the second thing is, you talked about flexibility at some of the higher cost projects, I presume you mean oil sands, et cetera. Can you give a kind of an indication of what you mean by flexibility? Does this mean we should expect a delay for the implementation of the future phases of oil sands?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the flexibility, I think it is &#x2013; what we are talking about is definitely that kind of projects. We have underlined all the time since the acquisition in Canada that one important feature for us was actually the flexibility and the optionality. So far what we have done is to embark on the license of the demonstration plan which is progressing according to plans. So still we have the same flexibility in that portfolio and obviously we are following the cost developments. And what potentially also happen to that in the &#x2013; if this environment continues and obviously we also have other development opportunities in our portfolio, particularly related to the really deepwater stuff, for instance in the Gulf of Mexico. And what I am saying is that there is flexibility also there, if it's proper, to delay some of these projects. So again the average picture is that we have more flexibility on, at the higher end, as you &#x2013; higher end of the cost curve, illustrated, as you said, by the Canadian oil sands. On the first question Torgrim, maybe you would.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the NGL and how that affects the realized price versus Brent Blend, what we saw during the last year is that as oil prices increased steadily and the prices of the NGLs didn't follow as much. So, it didn't -- the contribution from the NGL didn't matter so much in the realized price as it has done the two last quarters. So, I think that is the observation that we also have, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's very hard to predict anything in these days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I could -- if I could add, NGL is going into totally different markets. It goes typically into the petrochemicals, into the refineries. And what we have seen this quarter is pretty much, the spreads coming down but they are still at, I think, something like US$70 per barrel as an average of the NGLs and, while oil prices come down. So, it's depending very much on where that market for NGLs as such is developing and it's not related very strongly to oil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. We'll take one question from the internet is from -- it's about the Canadian oil sands, it's from John Olaisen from Carnegie. Have you done any impairments to the Canadian oil sands or is it still valued at US$2 billion on the balance sheet, or was it considered to make an impairment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No impairments and we consider a lot of stuff but this one was not considered, not as far as I know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James Hubbard, Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, James Hubbard from Morgan Stanley. Just two questions, on development drilling, you talked about a metric of meters per day, 80 meters per day. I think earlier in the year you talked about number of wells and that figure was 60, if I am remembering correctly. Can you put that metric of meters per day in the context of how many of the 60 have been drilled, because obviously this quarter is distorted by all the maintenance, it's hard to see what's really going on in the underlying NCS portfolio.</p>
          <p>And then do you actually think internally of meters per day, because it seems to me that's a metric that is, could incentivize people in the wrong way in the field. And then, secondly, the Gulf of Mexico impairments you mentioned in the presentation, what were they, are they in line with the previous Gulf of Mexico impairments and if so is &#x2013; can we now, is that the end of those impairments or is it something completely different?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I can say when it comes to the impairment is that these are assets that we have impaired earlier. So according to IFRS what happens then is that you get the volatility into these &#x2013; if oil prices increased, we would have to reverse the impairments. And if forward prices goes down, you have to take it down. So once you've started impairing these assets, you are into the elevator, to put it that way. So this is only related, there are no new assets related to the previous assets that we have been impairing for Gulf of Mexico.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the number of wells, you know what we try to do is to present this in a way which is easily understandable and I can assure that we have metrics which is more complicated than the meter per well. And there are various types of wells to be drilled and so on and so it doesn't really say something about the complexity of our programs. So they are just a way of communicating this in a simplistic way. But fundamentally, we have improved by approximately 15%, adjusting for all these factors. And in terms of number of wells I think we have drilled something like 80, 81 wells so far this year and last year we drilled 86 &#x2013; 85, 86 for the full year. So we have pretty much drilled as many wells as we did for the full year last year by the end of the quarter. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Colin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Colin Smith from Dresdner Kleinwort, two questions as well if I may. First one, just in view of the sort of pressure there is in growing volume in the international business, and with the change in equity and asset prices that appears to be going on, can you just make a comment about where you think things stand, in view of your strong balance sheet as well, on -- with regard to further M&amp;A activity?</p>
          <p>And the second question was just on your dividend policy, can you just remind us, when you're thinking about the payout ratio, whether you're focusing on the reported net income or whether you think about it more in terms of the adjusted net income because obviously last year it was a pretty high payout ratio if you relate it back to the reported net income and a little bit more clarity around that will be helpful? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the dividends, I'll take that first, the dividend policy is related to our actual operating income, or net income as it is reported. That being said we obviously will take into considerations the elements creating that operating income. So, all the elements that is being adjusted for in the numbers, the adjusted numbers, will obviously be the things that we'll be taking into considerations when we rule on our actual dividend payment of such, in accordance with this policy. But the starting point, that is the --</p>
          <p>When it comes to M&amp;A activities, I think we have always said -- basically what I said also was that we have to think long-term in this industry and something we do continuously is to evaluate M&amp;A opportunities, both on an asset basis and portfolios of assets, to put it that way. And we will continue to do so. And we have a strong financial position, as I illustrated, and we have access to funds, to put it that way, being rated the way we are. So, we feel to be robust in this situation, it's actually a good place to be. So, we will continue to look at that kind of opportunities and they could even be cheaper than they were sometime ago and, depending very much on the specifics here. So, yes, we will have to think through the cycles also in respect of this. So, I think that's &#x2013; that being said, obviously we are taking into account what is happening around us now in all aspects and, both in terms of our own financials and the impact on commodities and supply and demand of our commodities. So, that's definitely going to be a part of the equation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the dividend question actually also answered &#x2013; or the dividend answer &#x2013; also answered a question from Michele Della Vigna, Goldman Sachs, who asked what the dividend payout would be. So, 45 to 50% is for. Next question from Neill Morton.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. It's Neill Morton from MF Global. I have a question on your accounting policy with the caveat that I'm not an accountant. This might be a very stupid question. I just &#x2013; continually intrigued by the very large currency swings from quarter to quarter, I appreciate them &#x2013; I understand the mechanics, understand that's all non-cash. But I also note that the other large non-dollar reporter European companies with dollar debt, presumably also obviously reporting under IFRS, aren't reporting these big swings quarter to quarter. I guess the question is firstly, how do you benchmark your policy versus your peers? And secondly, are you concerned that these effects are perhaps diluting the transparency of your results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we continuously also have to make sure that we have a good feeling about our policies. When it comes to our, keeping our U.S. dollar &#x2013; our debt in U.S. dollar I think that is a very logical policy in relation to the fact that most of our revenues comes from the same currency. So, I think that's a robust policy and also, in terms of liquidity management, to really make sure that we have the cash in Norwegian kroner available in the amounts that it's reflecting the underlying performing leading to these tax payments and related to that period I think that is a prudent policy as well.</p>
          <p>We have made a lot of money on that when things have gone the other way. Now we see a loss and basically it's not a cash loss as such. It's simply making sure that we have the Norwegian kroner available in the amount that we planned for and in relation to the income supporting it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> have these policies in places as well yet they are not reporting the same quarter to quarter swings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, to my knowledge this is a very common way of operating liquidity management as such, and in particular in our case also to keep the long-term debt in U.S. dollar. So, we have, I think for practical purposes all our long-term debt in U.S. dollar and a significant part of our cash in running, in our expenses, both on operations and on CapEx in U.S. dollar. So, we have to take it back, swap it back into U.S. dollar &#x2013; it's really this swap. It's not the fact that we hedge it. It's this swapping it back into U.S. dollar which technically gives this volatility. But then when we actually pay this Norwegian kroner we get, the Norwegian kroner that we asked for and intended to hedge, so it's just an accounting thing that happens between creating the swap and at the point in time where we'd actually take it back and use the Norwegian kroner for paying tax and dividends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually that explains questions from both Jason Kenney, ING and Michele Della Vigna, Goldman Sachs, but there is another little add-on from Michele. He is from Goldman Sachs. He says can we expect a similar financial loss in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll try to put a sentence about that into my presentation really to warn you. I mean yes, if you look at the long-term debt that's quite mechanical. There is relationship. I mean, we have stable debt position and it's all U.S. dollar, so you can just sort of calculate that and it worked in this quarter as assumed. Then, when it comes to the liquidity management, it's more &#x2013; there is more risk to that. It does not necessarily &#x2013; it has to do with the profile of the earnings and so on, when they do the exchanges and so on, so you cannot sort of say exactly what is going to happen. But typically what we have seen that has been in the same range as the effects from the long-term debt, maybe slightly higher. And that's also what happened this quarter. So, that's what you can see if you look back into our numbers in previous quarters. So, I think that's the best guidance we can give.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I'll just take another one from the Internet before we give the work to Jon. And that is from Argus &#x2013; Adam Porter, Argus Group. Could you give us a decline rate for your Norwegian oil fields and your Norwegian gas fields, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have a good performance on the Norwegian continental shelf. The production has developed more or less exactly as we have planned. That means that we have fundamentally the same decline rate that we actually talked about when we had a &#x2013; back in January, of 4% on average between oil and gas. Then it's slightly higher on gas &#x2013; on oil and typically slightly lower than 4% on oil. So, that's what I can say and I have no more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Jon Rigby from UBS. Two points of clarification on some questions that were brought up earlier. The first on the impairment charges, if it's swinging around depending on prices and we've seen a decline in prices, does that mean you originally impaired against the forward curve rather than a long-term view of prices, because I can't believe your long-term view of prices was above where we are right now? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second is, when you come to look at the special element for any dividend you are going to pay and you talked about 45 to 50% as your aspiration of the payout ratio, what year will be you looking at primarily when you're looking at that, let's say, sometime next year? Will you look back over 2008 or will you be looking at 2009, which presumably at current observation would be worse than 2008, or will you look through and make some kind of &#x2013; take some kind of view where you see medium term oil prices trending, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, when it comes to impairments, what we do is to take &#x2013; to relate this to the market. We have our own assumptions and they could vary and are not as dynamic as the market is, but what we typically do is to use the forward curve for the next five years automatically because we ask the market and they tell us and it's the best answer we can get. And then we have our own assumptions beyond the next five years, which we then give judgment on, when something triggers a new judgment of those. So in this case, it's the forward curve which has impacted the impairments, mainly the forward curve.</p>
          <p>When it comes to dividend, all I can say is that we &#x2013; this is, there are no specific years and what you say is 45 to 50% over time, we have paid something like 51% since the IPO back in 2001 on average, so it's the demonstration that we actually have been able to honor this dividend policy and I think my main message is that is something we will continue to do. I cannot promise any given year that could be &#x2013; things happen in special circumstances, so I cannot guarantee that in any given year but at long term that's the kind of level you should expect and I think we have demonstrated our commitment too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, John Olaisen from Carnegie has got two questions. One is about breakeven cash flow after CapEx, so I think you answered that already with US$50 per barrel. The other one is how much is the remaining value of the Spinnaker acquisition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To be honest, if I &#x2013; I don't have the answer because I haven't summarized it. It's a little bit all over the place in our accounts, in our balance sheet. So, I haven't -- and it's not accounted for as one asset in our portfolio as such, it is all over the place. So, I haven't got that number for you. But obviously it has &#x2013; it was at the time of the acquisition. I cannot say anything more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No questions from the floor. Take another one from &#x2013; yeah, there's one from Neill, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Neill Morton again. At the start of the year, you talked about the reorganization of the NCS into different business units. Aside from Sn&#xF8;hvit, since then you've had leaks at Oseberg, you've had leaks at Statfjord, you probably made a mistake and continued to pump through the Kvitebj&#xF8;rn pipeline, which caused a subsequent leak. You had very damning safety reports from the authorities. Is this simply a function of your dominance on the NCS? Is it simply bad luck, coincidence or is it perhaps merger pains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's not merger things. Because if you look at the underlying, and I've been through all of these reports in detail and it has nothing to do with the merger. This is typically events which has causes that goes a long back in time. And it's complex and it's a lot of causes which pulls together and lead to these incidents. So, I think the Statfjord incidence was very unfortunate, and we have definitely, I can assure you, a comprehensive program to make sure that we will not do that kind of stuff again.</p>
          <p>But it's complex and it goes back in time and it has to do with the -- being extremely cautious and understand the risk when you do operations out there. It's so complex and you have to understand that the whole organization down to the operations have to understand the risk picture and it's also about complying with the procedures that we have in place to do, to do this stuff. So, both in terms of training, in terms of compliance, simplifying documentation and also understanding risk and doing risk assessments in a more efficient way, is part of the improvement program that we're embarking on to move on from these events.</p>
          <p>Then I would like to mention that the Kvitebj&#xF8;rn has nothing to do with this. That does not come in the same category. The pipeline was brought out of its location and that was not done by us and we had a very thorough calculation as to whether we should continue to operate it or not, and we knew that was a risk and that hit us but we knew it. So this was something calculated, we controlled it all the time, and in any case also there was a very minor leakage. And in any case we couldn't have had it back in full operations by now, because the repair system that we planned for didn't fail on some tests. So in any case, we would have to spend more time on that. So I think there is, there isn't much I would have done differently on the Kvitebj&#xF8;rn pipeline as such.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are actually a little bit on over time according to the program but we'll just allow this Q&amp;A session to finish and then we'll go straight to the Gas Seminar. So, if anybody's waiting out there on the internet will just have to give us five more minutes. There's another question from Woodmac/Wood Mackenzie, Johnny Shelton. In January 2008 overall Norwegian production was revised down by some 10%, and I guess he is referring to the official NPD numbers. Do we expect further downward revisions for 2009, 2010 and if so by how much? And how much of this would be proportionionate to StatoilHydro's stakes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what I can show you is basically that when it comes to &#x2013; as shown in the liquids production this quarter was at the same level as, and even higher and even after an extensive turnaround program, gas production was down. We have Kvitebj&#xF8;rn field which is down. And fundamentally, we are increasing our gas production on the NCS. So, and then again, I would just like to repeat our ambition to maintain the current level of production on the Norwegian continental shelf actually for quite a long time. So, the numbers that you refer to that's not something I think that you can apply directly to the spreadsheets for this company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. We've seen decreasing oil production in Norway, at least in 2008. How are you going to maintain the production or even increase it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's a &#x2013; there's a lot of measures and then I could start talking about all the operational improvements that we are now working on. I think one important I already touched upon, improving the drilling efficiency and we've made good progress on that. We are also working very systematically on the regularities issue and make sure that, sort of, we actually produce as efficiently as we can when the fields are in operations. This quarter, we had big turnarounds which impacted the regularities that goes into that factor. But looking away from that we actually saw progress on regularity this quarter. Then, it's about extensive drilling and we have drilled something like 30 wells in Norwegian continental shelf this year. We have 22 discoveries and some of that is discoveries which can be fast tracked and really support our production also short term. Some of that actually also gives us potential for new developments on a standalone basis.</p>
          <p>So, I think it has been a very good exploration year for StatoilHydro so far this year. And so, there is a whole range of measures which I think is supporting both the gas and obviously in our executing the whole development program that we are into on the new projects in our portfolio. So, I think it's &#x2013; we're attacking the whole range of measures that we can work on in order to at least maintain the current level of production on liquids.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, there is a last question from the internet here, Neil McMahon from Bernstein. He has first asked about any color on paying out special dividend in 2008 but I think you already said many times that we'll maintain 45 to 50% of payout. So, I'll just jump to the next one. Please, provide an update on whether you are renegotiating rig contracts, given the fall in commodity prices and with the likelihood of a weakening oil service sector?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, what I can say is that we're a big player in this market and we're following the situation closely and we have an active relationship to all our contracts, to put it that way, and to the extent that includes that kind of possibility I am sure that we will be able to capitalize a benefit from that, but... So, we will follow the situation and see what happens in this part of the market, which typically tends to be the earliest part of the market responding to changes in the activity levels out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, I think we'll just end this Q&amp;A session now. And just to give people a little bit of air here in London, we will resume with the Gas Seminar 15 minutes late, but at 2:45 London Time, so seven minutes from now. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>