<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1308509" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-05-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2066</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Lars Troen S&#xF8;rensen, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Eldar S&#xE6;tre, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to Statoil's First Quarter 2010 Earnings Presentation. My name is Lars S&#xF8;rensen and I am the Head of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>Today's presentation can be found on statoil.com and downloaded from this website. Questions from U.S. on the web can be as usual sent in using the Submit Question button on your screen.</p>
          <p>Without further ado, it's my privilege to welcome today's speaker, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer, Eldar S&#xE6;tre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars and thank you to all of you for joining us at this first quarter earnings presentation. Not surprisingly the first quarter has been like many quarters before, strongly influenced by the macroenvironment. And this is illustrated by the positive signs of recovery that we have seen in the global economy, especially in the United States and in China. Also the issues that we have experienced within the Eurozone and the volatility in the financial markets and last but not least for our industry the rising oil prices and oil demand which is mainly driven from Asia.</p>
          <p>It's a pleasure for me once again to present a quarter with generally good operational performance for Statoil, a solid production, good trading results, which I will revert to, and a continued strict cost discipline. And they are all contributing to good financial performance in actually all of our business areas this quarter.</p>
          <p>On top of this we have also made good industrial progress. We have enforced our value chain, our gas value chain in the U.S. both through increasing the Marcellus acreage and strengthening the market access. The exploration activity continues to deliver high value and we have matured the resource base further by approving and sanctioning six new projects this quarter.</p>
          <p>So let me start by looking at the financial results for the quarter. Statoil delivers a net income of 11.1 billion, which is compared to 4 billion in the same quarter last year and there are three main explanations to this positive development. First of all we have had much higher earnings from our International E&amp;P business segment. Secondly, the losses on net financial items has been lower this quarter compared to last year and finally we have had a significantly lower tax rate &#x2013; reported tax rate in this quarter.</p>
          <p>And the main drivers have been the continued recovery of the oil price of around 50% &#x2013; 48% since the first quarter last year and this is measured in Norwegian kroner. This was partly offset by a decrease in the gas price of 35%. I should also mention that despite the lower gas price that we have seen, we have sustained solid earnings from our gas trading business, which I'll come back to.</p>
          <p>Statoil's first quarter reported net operating income was 39.6 billion, which is compared to 35.5 billion last year. The adjusted earnings were 38.9, which implies adjustments this quarter, of a moderate NOK0.7 billion. Adjusted earnings after tax were 12.1 billion, which is up 14% compared to last year and the effective tax rate on the adjusted earnings that is excluding tax on net financial items were 69%.</p>
          <p>I will revert to the results for each of the business areas later in the presentation. Let me now say a few words about the oil and gas production. Total equity production reached 2.102 million barrels per day in the quarter which is up 28,000 barrels compared to the same quarter last year and this represents actually a record high production for the Group as such on a quarterly basis.</p>
          <p>And this record was driven by a 13% increase in the equity production outside the Norwegian Continental Shelf and offset by a 2% reduction in Norway. The growing production outside Norway was mainly driven by the start-up last year of the Tahiti and the Thunder Hawk fields in the Gulf of Mexico, the ramp-up of Agbami in Nigeria and increased production from ACG in Azerbaijan and also from Marcellus in U.S.</p>
          <p>The decrease in the Norwegian liquid production was explained by the expected decline on the mature fields in Norway. And again this was partly offset by the Kvitebj&#xF8;rn being back in full production last year and also new production from the Alve field and the Tyrihans field since last summer.</p>
          <p>The customer off-take on our long-term gas contracts has been high in the first quarter and this is due to relatively cold weather as you know in most of our core markets. The entitlement production was down 1% at 1.915 million barrels per day. And this implies so called PSA effects of 187,000 barrels per day between the equity and the entitlement volumes, which is slightly above our guiding of 180,000 barrels per day at US$75 oil price, which by the way is unchanged from what we have presented earlier.</p>
          <p>I will now go into the results from each of the business areas briefly. Starting with E&amp;P Norway, which reached adjusted earnings of 29.1 billion this quarter which is 2% down from last year and the main drivers for this change were a 46% increase in the liquids price, which added 9.5 billion to last year's result. And a 41% lower transfer price of gas towards the natural gas business segment which contributed negatively with 9.2 billion. And the oil and gas production &#x2013; the lower oil and gas production had a negative effect of NOK1 billion.</p>
          <p>Operating cost in Norway increased by 4% in nominal terms, mainly due to as I mentioned new capacity from Alve and Tyrihans and also combined with high volume actually maintenance &#x2013; well maintenance, well related activities in this quarter. The reduction in exploration activity from last year also lead to a 0.3 billion reduction in exploration expenses.</p>
          <p>The International E&amp;P segment had adjusted earnings of 4.5 billion which is considerably up from the 0.3 billion last year. Most of this 4 billion of the improvement is caused by the 54% increase in the liquid prices again in Norwegian kroner.</p>
          <p>Entitlement production increased by 5%, while total equity production increased by 13% to 557,000 barrels per day which again is a record high production of our production outside of Norway. The increase in operating expenses of 0.4 billion was driven by the higher production volume as such and again driven by new capacity coming onstream. In addition, we have had more field in preparation phase, preparation for production and this is mainly driven by the high impact activities we have from Leismer in Canada and Peregrino in Brazil.</p>
          <p>I should also mention that royalty payments also increased of relation to our Canadian offshore Canada operations by approximately 200 million this quarter, compared to last year. From the first quarter last year, we have also had a 23% reduction in the SG&amp;A costs within the International segment of which 15% is explained by the currency development and the rest 8% is driven by cost saving &#x2013; ongoing cost saving program.</p>
          <p>Natural gas had adjusted earnings of 4.6 billion this quarter against &#x2013; compared against 5 billion last year. Net operating income from processing and transport that part of the business was 1.7 billion which is down from 2 billion last year. And this was mainly driven by lower tariff revenues from temporarily reduced capacity at K&#xE5;rst&#xF8;, which is by the way now back at full capacity.</p>
          <p>Also in this quarter despite lower gas prices in general, we have been able sustain a high level earnings from our flexible gas marketing and trading, the gas &#x2013; marketing and trading part of the business, which is on par with last year at NOK2.9 billion. We have realized an average gas price in all our markets. Volume rated average during the first quarter of NOK1.64 per standard cubic meter and this equals US$7.3 per million BTU.</p>
          <p>So good results from our gas business are due to the following reasons, first of all, a solid long-term gas contract portfolio with a substantial component of oil indexation intact combined with a high gas off-take in the first quarter from our customers and also the very good opportunities that we have to move gas both in time and in geography from the flexible infrastructure to capture arbitrage opportunities.</p>
          <p>And finally our last business segment Manufacturing &amp; Marketing delivered adjusted earnings of 0.9 billion in the quarter compared to 1.6 last year. The adjusted earnings within our oil trading business were 0.6 billion and this is compared to 1.2 billion last year. And then I should remind you that the first quarter of 2009 had exceptionally steep contango curve ahead of them and while trading resource this quarter are driven by a flattened contango price structure compared with what we saw last year, one year ago.</p>
          <p>Adjusted earnings within the Manufacturing part of this business were zero that is the methanol production and the refineries and this is compared to 0.2 billion in the same quarter last year. And this decrease is mainly due to lower refinery margins in Norwegian kroner which was partly offset by higher methanol prices.</p>
          <p>Adjusted earnings in Energy and Retail were 0.4 billion in the first quarter which is compared to 0.2 billion in the same quarter last year and the increase was largely due to higher volumes and higher fuel margins. So all-in-all our adjusted earnings added up to 38.9 billion as I mentioned, which is 8% higher than we saw in the same quarter last year and the corresponding tax rate was 69%, which is in line I think with the guiding that we have given you earlier.</p>
          <p>Then a few comments also to our cash flow and our financial situation, this illustration shows our cash flow movements during the first quarter. As you can see Statoil generated again strong cash flow from our operations of NOK50 billion approximately. Taxes paid in the quarter amounted to NOK13 billion and then I have to mention that we have paid only one tax payment this quarter and we pay six of them during the year. So next quarter will include two tax payments compared to this quarter's one single tax payment in Norway. In addition the dividend for 2009 of NOK19 billion will be paid on the 2nd of June, obviously subject to AGM approval.</p>
          <p>Our investments are progressing as planned, according to plans with a net spending of around NOK19 billion in the quarter. And as you can see our net debt to capital ratio at the end of the first quarter was at 26 or nearly 26% and we expect this ratio to be slightly reduced towards the end of the year given the current level of oil and gas prices for the rest of 2010.</p>
          <p>And now let me say a few words about how we continue to move new barrels through the value chain and the activities in that context for this quarter. As highlighted at our strategy update in February, in London, we have a substantial resource base of approximately 22 billion barrels and our main focus is now on maturing this portfolio. Improving the overall capital efficiency and reducing breakeven prices through optimal scoping, technical scopes of these projects, leveraging our technology base and also sourcing and organizing the projects in the most cost efficient manner.</p>
          <p>In the first three months of this year, we have sanctioned five new projects on the Norwegian Continental Shelf. Two of these projects, the Kristin Q template and the Njord's north-west flank have been developed through the so-called fast track capital efficiency program which we have talked about on the Norwegian Continental Shelf. Which aims to, reduce the costs and increase the speed of development in relation to our substantial portfolio of small to medium sized projects on the Norwegian Continental Shelf.</p>
          <p>So we have started on this program and these are the two first results that we have delivered and the focus is, as talked about earlier, on standardization and industrialization as the main approach to enhance these developments. In addition we have sanctioned the Gudrun and the Marulk project and as you might have noted we have also now agreed the way forward with our partners on the Valmont project in the North Sea. And these projects are important steps &#x2013; important projects to maintain the production level on the Norwegian Continental Shelf. Outside NCS we have also sanctioned the Chirag Oil Project in Azerbaijan. So that adds up to six projects.</p>
          <p>In 2010 we will maintain a high level of exploration activity although slightly lower than we have seen over the last couple of years. And past year success on exploration continues so far in 2010. So far we have announced seven discoveries, four on the Norwegian Continental Shelf and three outside of Norway and among those the sidetrack of the promising the Vito discovery in Gulf of Mexico, I should mention that. We consider that to be a promising development and also the recent discovery close to Nona field, the so called Talksonold development, which might support a longer life for our Nona field.</p>
          <p>So let me then conclude the presentation by just confirming our guiding for 2009 (sic) [2010] , short version is that there is, no changes to the guiding. Our equity production is expected to be in the range of 1,925,000 to 1,975,000 barrels per day of oil equivalents in that range this year and between to 2.1 to 2.2 billion in 2012.</p>
          <p>Our production in the first quarter has been more or less as expected. However, significant uncertainties about the gas market remain as we head into the summer season where off-take &#x2013; the seasonal off-take is traditionally lower. And on top of the seasonal variations, we also expect to see challenging gas markets in the near-term due to the supply overhang situation that we see. And we're prepared to differ gas volumes to the extent necessary focus on &#x2013; focusing on value creation more than volume targets as such as.</p>
          <p>In addition, second quarter marked the start of a comprehensive turnaround season on the Norwegian Continental Shelf and although the majority by far will be carried out in the third quarter, we expect around 30,000 barrels per day in quarterly effects in relation to maintenance activities in the second quarter. And the quarter full year, we estimated an impact of around 50,000 barrels per day so that there should that &#x2013; there will be a lot of maintenance in the third quarter. There is no change to our guided unit production cost of 35 to NOK36 per barrel for this year. We also maintain our capital guiding of 13 billion. And finally on the exploration, we expect to drill and complete around 50 wells at a cost of US$2.3 billion this year.</p>
          <p>So with these remarks I leave the word back to you Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Eldar. We will now start the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And let me just repeat for the audience on the Internet, you can send a question to me by pressing the submit question button on your screen.</p>
          <p>I'll start with the question from the Internet then you can think about whether you've got any questions from Oslo here. I'll take one &#x2013; or I'll take two questions &#x2013; I'll take one question from two people actually. Jason Kenney [ING] and Iain Reid [Macquarie Securities], both wonder what impact have you seen and what impact do you expect from the Transocean Deepwater Horizon incident in the Gulf of Mexico at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no impact directly into our activities so far. The only impact is basically that we have offered our services and advice to assist in the current situation. In terms of our ongoing drilling activities we are drilling on two wells in Gulf of Mexico, two exploration wells have two rigs in operation. They are drilling as according to plans and we obviously reviewed our activities one more to be sure that we &#x2013; it's safe to proceed with the operations and that's the conclusion. So we are proceeding with the drilling activities and exploration activities as such. So that's the short-term.</p>
          <p>Longer term it's an industry question really and I would be surprised if there were no consequences coming out of an event like this. But I think the main &#x2013; before it's possible to say anything firm about that, I think it's necessary to get deeper into &#x2013; understand the causes that has led to the current situation and see the full consequences of that and I would be surprised if there were no consequences.</p>
          <p>I think our future activities will be scrutinized based on what has happened and I also think that, obviously based on events like this all kind of requirements and will be gone through by the authorities, but that's just speculation. But that's the kind of consequences that you could imagine and potentially also that sort of process of opening up new possibilities for the industry might also be more &#x2013; take more time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are a couple of questions about maintenance, I think, you already told us that the effect was 50,000 barrels on an annual basis and the second quarter effect was 35,000 barrels in the quarter. So this is just a repeat of that. But then there is question from Elaine Dunphy [Deutsche Bank] who asked, can you tell us what volumes were lost in the first quarter to maintenance and I guess that's pretty -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's very low volumes really, so I think we are talking about 8,000 barrels per day and the split is around 50-50 between the Norwegian Continental Shelf and the international maintenance activity. So a very low activity level on relation &#x2013; in relation to maintenance this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Elaine just wants to continue on that subject and wants to be sure that the 50,000 barrels estimated turnaround was included in our production guidance of 1.925 million to 1.975 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's included, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Then there is a question from John Olaisen from Carnegie in Oslo here, on gas. Does the strong first quarter, gas sales give some room for upside in the 2010 production guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think basically it has been a strong demand and strong off-take situation but that's typically also what we see in the first quarter. So basically in the first quarter it's &#x2013; we are producing as much gas as we can, because that's basically what the customers want. So I don't think you should read what has happened in the first quarter as an indication that &#x2013; in terms of where we will sort of come out in the range, it's more or less as expected. Slightly on the strong side but not very much different from what we typically see in the first quarters.</p>
          <p>And I could just John, only repeat the uncertainties that we are facing. We are now moving into a different situation and the supply overhang and the supply and demand balance that we have talked about is still there. We don't see any fundamental changes to that and are prepared to move on volumes and focus on value creation in our gas marketing activities and also repeat what we said about the turnaround activities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There's a question on gas again from Iain Reid [Macquarie Securities]. How much NCS, or gas from the Norwegian Continental Shelf, was sold outside the long-term contracts this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I haven't got that number to be honest. But typically the off-take in relation to our long-term contracts has represented a much higher proportion in the first quarter, but the exact split I haven't got that and I'm not able to give you a number on that at present.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can take the last question from Iain Reid [Macquarie Securities]. Can you update us on the sale of 40% of Peregrino, when should we expect this and how will it affect the 2012 production target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of a potential sale or whatever, I'm not prepared to give any comments. If I started with a practice on that it would take us in the wrong direction I think. So I'm not prepared to give any comments other than to say that typically owning 100% of an asset is not necessarily an ideal situation. So divesting a part of this asset is an option for us. But I'm not prepared to comment anything more specific than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then there is a question from James Hubbard at Morgan Stanley. Can you say what West Qurna 2 contracts are currently out for tender. what other major contracts needs to be tendered and what are the risks that the project delays occur due to ongoing Iraq political uncertainty?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of contracts and specific details on contracts and tendering I think what we have to do in that case is to refer to the operator, which is Lukoil. In terms of implications from sort of the political situation and the election situation in Iraq and implications on the projects and it's impossible for me to be &#x2013; to speculate and I would never start speculating about anything like that. But we're proceeding with the project as fast as we can and are now focusing on setting up the project and putting up the organization that can move this project forward as speedily as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I'll take the last questions from Elaine Dunphy from Deutsche Bank. It's about the Norwegian Continental Shelf and the production volumes there. Oil volumes on the NCS were down 55,000 barrels per day or 7% year-on-year on natural decline, measures to maintain reservoir pressure and operating issues, could you tell us how much was driven by operating issues and how should we be considering oil production on the NCS through the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, the decline represents approximately 6.0, 6.5% year-on-year on the liquid side. We have guided on an average declining rate of around 5% and not splitting between oil and gas but we indicate that oil fields typically will have a higher decline rate than the gas fields as such. And the other component which goes into the portfolio considerations is when new capacity is coming in and in this case we have had two new fields coming in last summer, it was ramping up and they are combined oil and gas production.</p>
          <p>So basically, we have not had sufficient new capacity to compensate for the decline this year. We put a lot of measures into fighting the decline. And both through utilizing the existing infrastructure and that goes back to the fast track approach that I talked about. We have a lot of smaller discoveries in Norway, which now are speeding up, tying into existing infrastructure and is obviously also all the IOR measures that we are putting in to fight the decline.</p>
          <p>So our approach and our ambition is, to maintain the overall oil and gas production on the Norwegian Continental Shelf for the next 10 years at approximately the current levels. There is no change, what we see this quarter has no implication whatsoever. This is expected for that ablation and gradually as we move forward oil production will be replaced by gas production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There is a question about tax rate from Irene Himona at Exane BNP Paribas. The 69% tax rate in the first quarter was unexpectedly low. Could you please provide guidance for the full year 2010 and the likely tax rate? And discuss once again the reasons for the low first quarter level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, basically, its &#x2013; I think our guiding is pretty much around 70%, that's what we have said as an average. We have indicated the Norwegian Continental Shelf at around 74% and that's exactly what it was this quarter. We have indicated the gas business at around 70%, slightly lower this quarter. So there was slightly more revenues on the gas business onshore &#x2013; on onshore taxation this quarter than might be typical, but not significant. So that might explain why they are below 70%. The International tax percent is around 43 and we have guided at 40 to 45. So it's right in the middle. And the downstream is at 30% which is also spot-on according to what we have indicated earlier. So pretty much the tax rate this quarter is maybe slightly lower, but not much compared to what you should expect going forward.</p>
          <p>But there will be significant variances on the tax rate, reported tax rate because of a functional currency that is now in U.S. dollar for the holding company, while the tax is still a Norwegian kroner taxation. So we &#x2013; you will see differences for those reasons, but based on the adjusted number and tax on adjusted numbers this is the kind of tax rate 70, 72% that you should see going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Then we have a question from Oswald Clint at Bernstein. Can you quantify the impact of natural gas earnings in the first quarter 2010 from new long-term contracts and from the new structure incorporating the higher level of spot prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I am not aware of any new contracts actually coming into effect in the first quarter. We have talked earlier about the renegotiations, the discussions we have had with some of our customers regarding the price structures and how we split the volume of some of the long-term contracts between oil indexation and gas indexation. And we have indicated that we have moved a tranche of some of these contracts from oil indexation to the spot market pricing. And that has had effect from this quarter and that effect is included in the average gas price of 1.64 that we have reported.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And basically, I think, Rune Bj&#xF8;rnson, who is the Head of our Natural Gas Division, at the Capital Markets update in February, he was clear and he was actually &#x2013; we basically took out volumes of the existing contracts for &#x2013; as a temporary measure, but the actual contract will not change.</p>
          <p>So the terms and conditions on the contracts are the same. And then we have taken out more volume tranches that we have either let the customer decide, either you can get it at spot prices or we can sell it in the spot market and you won't take the gas then. So it's a matter of restructuring the volume a little bit in this market situation and we've been able to keep up earnings in the gas market &#x2013; or in the gas business quite handsomely this quarter.</p>
          <p>There is question from Hootan Yazhari at the Bank of America-Merrill Lynch. Is the 7% decline in Norwegian oil production indicative of worsening decline rates in the portfolio? Does it make you nervous of your longer term explorations to keep production flat in Norway?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the exact number is 6.5% and as I've said it's as expected. So this has more to do with the decline on gas on oil field is higher than gas fields and higher than the average. So this has more to do with sort of the sequencing and when new capacities coming in, but the decline &#x2013; the underlying decline from the major of the fields that is declining is not behaving and different from what we have expected them to do in this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A question from Rahim Karim at Barclays Capital. Can you help us understand the finance chart? With the net debt of 75.3 after adjustments, that the finance chart is so low &#x2013; finance charge I think it has to be, is so low, any guidance with the full year. You talked about the &#x2013; that's another question. So can you help us understand the finance chart with net debt of 75.3 after adjustments? Why is the finance still so low?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll make a try.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a &#x2013; I think we have a table in the MD&amp;A where we show &#x2013; tried to explain what is happening with the finance chart and I agree if you look at the net debt the interest payments and costs should be higher than what is reported. The reason for this has to do with the interest rate derivatives because we are we are swapping some of our debt, some of our interest exposure into floating interest rates and that means that it's a swap which is accounted for in our accounts market-to-market. And since the interest rate has gone down slightly in this quarter that has given market-to-market benefit of approximately 1.1 billion in the quarter which goes into the interest rate calculation presentation as you see it in the accounts. So if you adjust for that, the interest rate is approximate or the interest cost is approximately NOK1.2 billion and 0.5, 0.6 of that is, interest rates as such and 0.6, 0.7 is accretion which is basically related to the removal cost and the annual sort of appreciation of the removal cost. So it's a good question and &#x2013; but there is an explanation and I think it's given in the MD&amp;A documentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we just take Rahim's next question. You talked about the weather proving the upside to the realizations. Can you talk about how you expect this to evolve assuming a stable Henry Hub price? That must be the temperature on gas price, I guess he is alluding to. You talked about the weather proving upside to the realizations, can you talk about how you expect this to evolve assuming a stable Henry Hub price? Do you understand the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have to ask Rahim to repeat it and then I can take somebody else in the mean -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But basically obviously temperature as heating is an important sort of segment in the gas market. So heating is &#x2013; heating and residential demand represents approximately 50% of the gas demand and so that has obviously a big impact and it's very much depending on the temperature. It has been a cold winter and we're moving into a different season but to state explicitly sort of the effect of that single component on the gas price going forward, I think that's &#x2013; the gas market is something where we have to look at all of components as such and it's hard to single out any.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of more questions from Oswald Clint at Bernstein's. Can you provide some indication whether exploration activity within the disputed zone with Russia could be seen in the near-term after the recent discussion or is it &#x2013; is there still &#x2013; is it still at the political level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all we're very pleased with the settlement that appears to now emerging. So, but we also accept that it will take time. It has to go through a ratification process and there might details for whatever we know that needs to be put in place and the ratification process which we are very optimistic will be dealt with quite soon. And then there is a long process to mature the seismic activities and political processes supporting &#x2013; leading up to sort of more type of drilling and licensing activities.</p>
          <p>So it's a long journey ahead of us in this area but as obviously it's extremely interesting for us to hopefully be given the opportunity to take a closer look at this acreage because everything we see from outside the acreage points in the direction that it's a very interesting and attractive <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Oswald Clint [Bernstein]. Can you update us on the buyback program you talked about in the fourth quarter results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the buyback program is something, which we have said is part of our tool box. It's stated specifically in our dividend policy that buyback is something that we might use. And I think to avoid any speculation as to whether we will intend to use it or not, it's something that we now intend to ask for the AGM and every AGM going forward.</p>
          <p>So it's in place. It's a part of the tool box because we have tipped AGM and can do this only once a year and I think it's prudent to put the mandate in place. So it's an effective part of the tool box that can be activated in the case that situation should emerge. But it should not be seen as that there are specific plans to use buyback programs. It's actually just putting a mandate in place as an integrated part of the dividend policy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to stress we don't have a mandate right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we have applied the AGM for mandate on the 19th of May.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes, that's true, Lars, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the last question is from Oswald [Bernstein]. You talked about the quality of the oil in the Vito discovery. Can you talk about the quality of the reservoir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is operated by Shell and typically in these kind of instances we leave this kind of lot of news flow on Vito to Shell. So all I know &#x2013; express today was that we think it's interesting and we have a 25% stake in Vito and it's something that we hope, can be &#x2013; create the basis for a new development. But it's early to say, but we are optimistic as far as we see. But the more specifics we leave to Shell to provide news on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there is a question from a private shareholder, at least somebody who hasn't put in a company here, <mark type="inaudible" />. Is the future growth to some &#x2013; is it usual for growth to come from internal growth in exploration, both on NCS and its actually asked, is that all aiming more on M&amp;A activities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All the growth that we have talked about going into 2012 is based on organic activities coming from exploration assets. That's in our portfolio for the time being. And we've also in February at our strategy update, we also presented a comprehensive portfolio of assets, which pointed at growth or so beyond 2012 although we did not indicate any more specifics and try to quantify that growth. So all these statements and this strategy, is based on organic developments and the assets that we have and the prospects that we have and exploration opportunities that we have in our portfolio. That does not mean that the company would stop looking at inorganic opportunities. That wouldn't be prudent for a management to do. So we will obviously look at that kind of opportunities, but &#x2013; and to the extent there would &#x2013; we find them attractive for creating shareholder value we would look into it. But the strategy and the main focus is not to mature the strong resource base and all we have said on growth, ambitious going forward is based on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. There is a question from Kim Fustier at Credit Suisse. Can you talk about the recent progress you've made on beefing up your gas trading capabilities in Europe and the U.S.? And can you give us some color on the gas arbitrage opportunities you're seeing currently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have gradually overtime now built &#x2013; strengthened and built our organization on the gas trading site, both in Europe, in Norway, in U.K. but also in the U.S. based on the gas resources from &#x2013; through Cove Point from LNG, from Gulf of Mexico now also shale gas. So we have also built a quite substantial gas trading business in the U.S., build systems, competence, people, knowledge and a more comprehensive trading portfolio with more flexibility tools.</p>
          <p>And we have also strengthened this through adding storage capacity and so on at Aldbrough in the U.K. So gradually we have built, both, infrastructure competence and people resources to this business. And we have also developed it further in terms of what's integrating our long-term business and the short-term trading business. So to optimize the &#x2013; these two parts &#x2013; two legs of our gas marketing business. And the idea is basically to use the flexibility that we have in our trading system. We have several landing points into the Continental and UK gas markets. We have also several sources into the U.S. trading hubs as I've mentioned.</p>
          <p>And to move volumes in time and geography arbitraging through utilizing this whenever we see opportunities and I should also mention that we have on the Norwegian Continental Shelf substantial flexibility in particular on the Troll field and Oseberg field which is actually storage. We can keep the oil &#x2013; the gas, excuse me, in the reservoirs without paying for expensive storage at other places and use that volume flexibility as well. And we also have LNG flexibility in the trading portfolios as we now have Sn&#xF8;hvit into the portfolio. So this is gradually the components and how we have developed this. And I think we have proven over some quarters now that we have been able to sustain a reasonable robust level of earnings. That doesn't mean that it's not going to volatile. You will see ups and downs. But there are no, major component of speculative mandates with regard to in our gas trading, this is base low trading basically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a question from Orlando Finzi at M&amp;G Investments. Does the expected gas market weakness for the rest of 2010 impact the radar on &#x2013; the rate or the level of your CapEx plans in 2010 and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. The CapEx plans for '10 and '12 is going according to plan and our financial planning and capability to go on with the program from a financial perspective is robust in relation to whatever gas price development we might see. So we don't see any developments in the gas markets short-term that might have any impact on our investment program as such.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A question from Christine Tiscareno at Standard &amp; Poor's. Should we expect more deals to deliver natural gas from Marcellus? Are you covered for the moment on your upcoming Marcellus production? How will delay &#x2013; sorry, that was the first question. Should we expect more deals to deliver natural gas from Marcellus? Are you covered for the moment on your upcoming Marcellus production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as I said we have strengthened the system. We have added approximately 10% to the acreage in line with the agreement that we have with Chesapeake. So basically when Chesapeake adds acreage to Marcellus, we are given the opportunity to participate into that acreage. And that's something we do on a regular basis with smaller chunks. And what we did now was to pool some of this together into a bigger bite so representing approximately 10% of the current acreage. And as I said this is an integrated part of the agreement with Chesapeake and we will pursue those kind of opportunities to add high quality acreage to our current position also going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a further question from Christine [Standard &amp; Poor's] which is about Gulf of Mexico. How will delays in Gulf of Mexico drilling affect your production plans?</p>
          <p>And I guess for 2010, the production for 2010 and the production for 2012 that we have guided on will not be affected by this drilling of course because there's no -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't see any effects on the production from at least from what we have seen of the impact so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of more questions left. Barry MacCarthy at Royal Bank of Scotland. What were the reasons for the Board's preference for partial IPO of Energy and Retail over alternatives such as a full exit via sale to a trade buyer or perhaps financial investor which might be less dependent upon marketing conditions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a decision process in the Board and concluding that there is the realistic outcome is the partial IPO that has to do with the capacity &#x2013; likely capacity in the market and the fact that we, in any case, will be tied very much to the E&amp;R through support agreements and supply agreements before we sort of can get &#x2013; cut all the ties. And I think it's also important that Statoil shows support to the new company through that kind of ownership and make sure that sort of we have faith in the new company and are also willing to invest and keep a share in the new company going forward and then we take it from there going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a question Trond Omdal at Arctic Securities in Oslo, about Peregrino. He asks about our considerations regarding maintaining 100%. I think you already said that that we always consider whether only 100% for the life time opportunity is right. But then he asks about project status for Peregrino.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>While Peregrino is moving forward as planned. We had some issues and had to wait for weather &#x2013; right weather conditions. There are two jackets in place and that we have to lift the modules on top of that on both these platforms A and B. And eventually weather conditions turn out positive and nice to us, so now all the modules are in place on the both the Peregrino-A and the Peregrino-B. So now all activities are moving on and there is no change to the time schedules because obviously we waited for some flexibility in this respect. So we expect the Peregrino to be in production early next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Got two more questions left. One from <mark type="inaudible" /> at Fokus Bank in Norway. What is the share of gas sales linked to long-term contracts and what's the average duration of these contracts and what is the remaining average duration of the contracts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first one was on the average on the oil part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all how much gas do we sell oil linked and how much do we sell -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said we &#x2013; the main part of our gas volume is still linked to long-term contracts. And of the long-term contracts the main part is still linked to oil. So approximately 25 to 30% of our total volume, total volume including what goes beyond the long-term contracts and typically on an annual basis is linked to oil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think is linked to gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>25 to gas and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Linked to gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And 75 to oil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so in terms of contracts length obviously some of these contracts have been in place for some time, quite sometime they are getting older. So in this &#x2013; in the next decade we are getting into situations where some of these contracts are running out. But to be specific in terms of averages, I haven't calculated it in that respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, I think Rune Bj&#xF8;rnson, the Head of Natural Gas in February, he said that the first contract &#x2013; the really long-term contracts, they were sort of 25 to 35 years when they were entered into and the first one of those will start expiring in sort of 2017 and the last ones in 2029-ish in that range. But I won't really &#x2013; we haven't really quantified how much is where, but these are long-term contracts really.</p>
          <p>Last question I have here is from Jon Rigby at UBS. Obviously kroner-U.S. dollar was less volatile in the first quarter, but even so the FX/IFRS adjustments look very small. Isn't &#x2013; Is it a net of a few more &#x2013; of many movements, or is it explained by reduced ethics only or have you changed some of your underlying interpretation of the accounting policy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. There is, no changes to the accounting policy. Basically this &#x2013; the main part of this is related to the exchange that &#x2013; we have most of revenues in U.S. dollar, but we pay taxes and dividends in Norwegian kroner, a lot of it. So basically, we swap into or we exchange into Norwegian kroner to the extent necessary and then we swap back into U.S. dollar because we don't need the Norwegian currency on a running basis. So this swap, this market is accounted for on a market-to-market basis and what is in the account is the Norwegian kroner part of that swap compared to the U.S. dollar functional currency that we have. So that represents a loss of 2.5 billion reflecting a currency difference of I think approximately 4%. That's the main part. There might &#x2013; there is also other these kind of other components of functional currency but the main component is related to the swap from U.S. dollar to Norwegian kroner and there is no change to the practices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But then, I don't see any more questions from Oslo and there are no more questions on the Internet. So from me there's only left to say, thank you very much for participating and good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>