<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1190472" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1559</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Rogers, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Rick George, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Ken Alley, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Paul Cheng</participant>
      <participant id="5">John Rogers</participant>
      <participant id="6">Rick George</participant>
      <participant id="7">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="8">William Lacey</participant>
      <participant id="9">Ken Alley</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Suncor Energy Inc. Third Quarter Results Conference Call.  At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode.  Following the presentation we will conduct a question and answer session.  Instructions will be provided at that time for you to queue-up for questions.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  I would like to remind everyone that this conference call is being recorded on Wednesday, October 29, 2008 at 7.30 AM Mountain Time.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the conference over to Mr. John Rogers, Investor Relations.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Cheryl, and good morning everyone and thank you for listening in to our third quarter conference call.  I have Rick George, President and CEO with us; Ken Alley, our CFO; Maureen Cormier, our VP Controller, and Tim Maw, from the Controllers Department.</p>
          <p>I just wanted to remind everyone we are dealing with some forward-looking information and all in this there's necessary caveats around that.  So, we'll follow the normal format, Rick will give you a bit of a overview of the quarter.  Ken will give us bit of an update on finances.  I'll talk very little about the outlook and then we'll open it up to questions.  So, Rick, why don't you take it away?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>John, thank you very much and we will try to make this relatively short, because we did have our conference call last week around our capital budget for 2009.  Obviously, pleased to announce a very clean quarter, a quarter with earnings of about $815 million and cash flow of just below 1.35 billion.</p>
          <p>So, obviously what helped us through the quarter was higher oil prices.  We also -- I can tell you are very focused on the path forward from here in terms of what we talked about last week in terms of prudence around managing our capital expenditures, flexibility, in case oil prices go either direction from here and also still plan for growth over the next two to three years.  I think it's a model that very few companies will be able to emulate through this.  Obviously in this new environment, one of the focuses we have is: how do we deliver both on the operating side and on the capital investment side in a much less expensive way?  I will tell you &#x2013; well, probably on the operating side, it, won't come quickly. It'll be a little stickier coming down than it did coming up, but something that we'll have a lot of focus on as we roll into 2009.</p>
          <p>Our number one priority as a company is operational excellence and we're very well aware that we have disappointed the market in 2008 and we're planning to rectify that here over the coming months, and are actually looking forward to a much better run in 2009 and on into 2010 and beyond.  I am confident that we're making progress in this area.  I was actually up in Fort Murray last week, and although it hasn't necessarily translated to volumes directly, I can tell you from what I know of the operations and having walked the plant at some length, I do like what I see and the operation is beginning to display much better reliability.  In fact, I have absolutely no doubt about our upgrading capacity reaching 350,000 barrels a day over time here.</p>
          <p>I think what we're starting to see now is the bottleneck in our current limitation has started to move from upgrading to bitumen production.  And obviously, the Firebag ramp-up through 2009 as we bring on the latest set of assets in 2010, when we bring on Firebag Stage 3, will both help that overall.  So, overall we do know that is the area of focus.  We do know that we've got to deliver and I can tell you that our employees -- and we have some great employees -- are dedicated to reaching that and obviously have my greatest support.</p>
          <p>So, with our higher levels of production, we're also looking forward to lowering levels of our cash costs.  You'll note from the outlook that, if you go do the math, we're calling for an average of low 30s, I think it's actually 33.75 in terms of operating costs for Oil Sands in the fourth quarter.  Again, we'll have to reach production rates of about 270 on average to do that for the quarter, but are very hopeful we can get to that.</p>
          <p>Now, I did spend a lot of time last week on the capital spending for 2009 and beyond and I don't really have a lot to add to that.  What I can talk about just a moment is our major project work that's currently ongoing.  First of all, the MCU project, which was about $2.3 billion, is done. It's completed, it's behind us.  The Millennium naphtha unit is about 45% complete on construction and expected to be on-stream in the third quarter of 2009.  We'll be glad to have that project done.  The Steepbank extraction plant is about 60% complete and again will come on middle of 2009 and again, another project we're looking forward to having done.  The Firebag sulfur plant is 85% complete on construction and expected to be on-stream in the second quarter of 2009. And one of the other big legs here is Firebag Stage 3, I think I remember, that's 68,000 barrels a day of bitumen production, is 40% complete with first steam in the fourth quarter of 2009.  So, that's what you've got to look forward to.  The Voyageur Upgrader is actually 10% complete, and as you know we're actually delaying that somewhat from the original schedule by about 12 months as we head into 2009.</p>
          <p>So, I will say that good results from the downstream in this quarter -- very solid, the operation there is very solid, and obviously, we are impacted by margins and volumes, but a very good performance by our downstream group. And the Natural Gas, in terms of volumes has been very good in the quarter.  They have more dry holes than they would have expected and that's obviously one of the challenges we have with that business.</p>
          <p>So, I wanted to just spend a moment on two items, because there seemed to be a lot of confusion out in the marketplace about: what is Suncor's real position, and what does lower crude oil prices really mean for Suncor? I -- first of all I want to go to, let's just assume a $60 crude oil price US WTI and assume a kind of exchange rate of $0.78 -- which is kind of today's exchange rate.  So, if you use WTI at $60 you'd have a realized price in Canadian dollars of about $77. Okay?  You would have to discount that by about $4 for the quality of crude on average that we produce.  You would have about $4 worth of royalties. If operating costs -- just roughly use 35, we actually think it should be lower, but use that as the rough number -- and then your DD&amp;A,  i.e. non-cash charges, of about $6 means your earnings net-back would be $28 a barrel, or just below 30.  By the way, your cash flow net-back in that case would be about Can$34.</p>
          <p>So, it isn't often a business that you have where 50% of your revenue is actually a net cash flow. And so, this is not a case of us not being able to make money at $60 -- there seemed to be a lot of misunderstandings and panic out there in the market on that.  Now obviously, you wish it were $140 and you'd have even higher margins, but that's not where we are. And the advantages that we have in our Oil Sands business on that is: no decline curves &#x2013; you're going to see some big decline curves, I believe, worldwide; and no exploration costs.  So, you have certain advantages and your other one is to just watch and make sure we get to reliable production at the lowest costs we can -- that's really the goal line.</p>
          <p>The second thing I wanted to do is to maybe clear up a little confusion around Voyageur, because again, people kind of swap numbers between what today's return is versus what you plan on, on future &#x2013; on future development. And obviously, we have the lowest installed capacity with the assets we have on the ground now.  Now, with Voyageur it does take an $80 WTI number to get a 15% return on capital.  But we still believe that to be very strong economics.  We think we can deliver on it for sure and of course, once that installed capacity is there, it's there for a century or more.  Now, we have already spent about one third of the capital, about $7 billion out of the $21 billion at the end of this year. And as I mentioned at the call last week, I will be stretching the rest of that over '09, '10, '11 and '12.  And so remember, this stuff has been in progress already for over five years, so this is not -- none of this stuff is near-term, and we don't really run future economics based upon today's crude oil price.</p>
          <p>So listen, we think it's still a very strong, very viable project.  You hear people that say: oh -- well, Suncor can't make money at $80. I would say that those people really haven't their homework around what the economics are here.</p>
          <p>So, I think that's kind of where I want to leave it, and I want to turn it over to Ken to talk a little bit <mark type="inaudible" /> in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank, Rick and good morning everyone.  Yeah, we did talk about the strength of the balance sheet on last week's call, but clearly in the current economic environment I think it's worth reiterating just how strong our financial position is today.</p>
          <p>If I look first at liquidity, our liquidity position is excellent.  We've got about $1.4 billion of cash on hand.  We have a syndicated credit facility available to us -- it's un-drawn.  Its $3.75 billion, it does not mature until 2013 and I have complete confidence that that facility is available to us should we wish to draw on it as we go forward.  So, no concerns about being able to use that facility.</p>
          <p>The debt we do have on the balance sheet is long-term.  Our average maturity is 2028.  We have no maturing debt over the next couple of years.  So, overall liquidity position -- very strong; no refinancing exposure in the intermediate term; and feeling very good about the strength of our financial position as we move forward now.</p>
          <p>John, I'm going to pass it back to you after that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'm -- you repeat the outlook with the quarterly release so I'm not going to say too much on it.  Just a commentary, however, on the production that we're predicting for the year, averaging 235.  You can do the math but I'll help you -- it's about 270 for the quarter.  We do have to do a turn around on the vacuum tower on UE-2 during the quarter, so that will reduce a bit of the production for a short period of time.  We still expect -- and that's been our plan the whole year -- we still expect that we'll be exiting this year in the 300,000 barrel a day range.  So, we're pretty happy with the way things are going, as Rick mentioned. We've had our struggles this year but we're starting to see some pretty good progress there.</p>
          <p>Cash costs, which are directly associated for the most part with production levels -- we would predict in the fourth quarter we'd do &#x2013; something in the neighborhood of about $33.75.  And that will give you the full year of 36.50.  So again, as production goes up we do see those costs come down.</p>
          <p>Other than that, I think that's all we were going to talk about before the Q&amp;A.  Again, with the Q&amp;A, if we could keep our questions to the strategic nature.  We'd be happy to deal with your specific modeling questions after the call.  It's a little easier when I want to deal with those questions.  So, Cheryl, why don't we open it up to questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Your first question comes from Paul Cheng from Barclays Capital.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, gentlemen, I actually don't have any strategic question. Maybe that John or someone, that you can just email me after the call -- want to know what is the FIFO impact for this quarter for the Oil Sand in the corporate. You, in your press release, talked about the R&amp;M side.  Also, if you can breakdown for us what is this stock-based compensation; and then, final one is that fourth quarter Oil Sand sales volume, should we assume it's going to be higher than the production given the third quarter is substantially below?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Paul, let me answer the last the last question and Tim if you could e-mail those other two things to Paul that would be great.  We would expect that over time production sales actually equal each other.  We got a little bit behind this quarter in terms of sales because of the inventory of sour product, but as we get -- move more and more of that, we'll find that the sales will probably or should &#x2013; could potentially exceed production in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning gentlemen.  Just a quick question, you talked about the bottlenecks in bitumen production and in order to fill the 350,000 barrel a day upgrading facilities next year, did I &#x2013; I may have just heard incorrectly, but do you need Firebag Stage 3 to get there? Do you think -- can you fill the 350,000 barrels a day before Firebag 3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ryan, its John.  We're actually on a path to move towards the 350, probably very late next year.  To get there we need a number of things: we need Firebag 1 and 2 to be up to full production, which will probably be somewhere in the 80s, where that'll eventually land.  We do need the Petro-Canada volume to come in.  We do need the volume to be working at its full capacity.  Any shortage from any of those three will have to be made up by Firebag 3, which we are going to start steaming late next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.  And then the other &#x2013; the other question, just from a general perspective. I know you've talked some about how costs could potentially come down on the long-term on project development in a lower oil price environment. How much, if we were at $60 oil next year? Could you expect to see very much relief on a cash OpEx basis, or do you still kind of stay in that 33 to $35 barrel range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, you know what, I would leave it there. I do think we're going to see some cost advantages, maybe not earlier in the year. It's probably going to take us sometime to drive that.  And we have a lot of work with new assets coming on, as I mentioned, on the projects side in the first, second or early third &#x2013; by our third quarter. So I think it will come. I just think, Ryan, it'll be a little bit sticker than it was on the way up, which is pretty typical of this industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Brian Singer from Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, how are you?  Actually, just following up on the previous question.  First, on the cash operating costs side, I think &#x2013; Rick, in the margin numbers you went through at a $60 oil price environment, it did imply a meaningfully lower cash operating cost, correct if I am wrong. But can you just talk about the path to -- the path to getting there and maybe a little more color on how long that takes, ultimately?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually Brian, the number that we quoted -- the $35 -- was the cash operating costs, which basically are where they are today.  So, we actually haven't made any projection in terms of lowering those costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And that -- did you not mention, maybe I wasn't writing this down, a $35 net-back in a $60 oil world? Maybe I wasn't taking notes correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, and maybe we didn't say it right.  So, let me make sure that you have it.  We talked about a $77 price in terms of realized, a $4 discount, $4 royalties, $35 operating costs and $6 DD&amp;A, which would give you a $28 net-back.  I think what we did do is say that was the net-back on an earnings basis. If you look at it on a cash basis, of course, you have to add the DD&amp;A of $6 back and that's where you've got a $34 or maybe $35 net-back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again -- in Canadian dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, again, in Canadian dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, got it. And then, on the capital costs side. How long until one should expect the impact of lower steel prices to translate into the ability to buy things more cheaply, from a Suncor perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's a good question.  I think it will take some time, and you've got to remember we're kind of re-jigging in terms of our corporate or capital plans.  Obviously, we've got a number of projects to finish where the steel would've already been purchased, and we've actually stopped buying bulks of things in the current environment and with our capital plans.  We probably won't be back purchasing in a major way until sometime in 2009 and by that time I would expect to see some of these lower prices roll through. And as importunately, the real competition among the suppliers and contractors will help as well.  So, I think you kind of want to wait this out as long as you can through that.</p>
          <p>If there's any saving grace, a lot of the equipment we bought for Firebag, stages 3 in particular, but also the upgrader, at least were purchased back when the Canadian dollar was closer to par. And so, there's a combination here of some of the equipment you bought when the Canadian dollar was very strong -- that's good. And then, we're going to try to wait as late as possible to buy the bulks of things until you see those commodity prices roll back.  Now listen, exactly how the future unfolds is hard to tell here.  So, if &#x2013; but I think we'll build to play that as we see it as 2009 rolls out and we see how the economy around the world kind of responds to the current financial crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from William Lacey from FirstEnergy Capital.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Ken, I was just wondering if you could maybe give a little bit more color -- I know it's flogging a dead horse and John, we've talked about this in the past -- but I'm assuming that you've obviously been talking with your bankers of late regarding the credit lines snag.  Can you just sort of give some more color on those discussions?  What their thoughts are, what have you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can do that, Will.  So, I mean -- just to reconfirm for everyone, it's $3.75 billion and it matures in 2013.  We have had conversations with the banks.  I mean, that credit is available for us to draw on. All of the banks in the syndicate have the capacity to fund their share -- it is a syndicate, it's not one or two banks. It's probably about 10 or 12 banks in this group.  It's lead by a very strong group of banks, really around the world but the core of this is one of the strongest Canadian banks.</p>
          <p>So all in, I feel very confident, and through those discussions and my knowledge of the status of those banks that this facility is available for us to draw as we need it.  It's not like that we're going to be taking it all down at once.  Remember, it's a flexible.  It's a revolving credit facility.  We don't have to draw it all down at once.  We draw on it as we use it.  We repay it.  It's available fully for us, but we don't have to draw it down as a term loan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, and it's just comforting hearing that in this market. I think people just like reaffirmation that those discussions are ongoing and that people have had positive response, so that's good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And thanks for asking the question, Will, because it is top in mind, but I do -- would like to give people comfort on that front, as would our bankers, I'm sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.  Just on Firebag -- obviously, you've been having some pretty good numbers of late.  It looks like you're just over 43,000 in July and just under 44 in August.  As far as sort of the ramp-up profile now, can we expect now that the limitations are off on this facility, that we should see a pretty quick positive response on the production front from this facility going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't know if it's quick but I think it's slow and steady, Will.  I think we did mention back in August when the controller, that came off, it would probably take a couple of months before we saw meaningful changes -- and we're starting to see them.  I would still expect that by the end of the year we'll accept in the 50,000 barrel a day range and we'll be moving up to that 70 to 80 range, maybe you could, incrementally, above 5000 barrels a month.  So, it'll be slow and steady.  The good thing about it is once it gets up to that full rate, it consistently produces at that rate for 10 years or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it is going right direction.  So -- good. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's going in the right direction, you bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir? Hello, Mr. Rogers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, my apologies.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And so, the next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  Are you still hoping to produce an average of 300,000 barrels per day?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, hi, <mark type="inaudible" />. It's John.  We're expecting that we'll exit this year at 300,000, and preliminary look at 2009 would say we'll be producing at 300,000 next year, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and you'd get to about 350 at the end of that year or is that open?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're moving towards that 350 capacity, and as I mentioned earlier, there are three or four things that have to kind of work towards getting up to 350.  We will have upgrading capacity of 350, and now it's a matter of filling that capacity, and that's our, kind of job one during 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you .Mr. Rogers, there are no further questions at this time.  Please continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that's great.  Thank you, Cheryl, and thanks everyone for listening in to our conference call.  I'm actually traveling right now, so if you do have follow-up questions, the best way to get a hold of me, and I think that everybody knows is to get through to me in my email, which is simple: jrogers@suncor.com. If you've got any questions at all just send them by email and as you know, I'll get back to you real quick.  So, that would be great if you could do that. Other than that -- hope everybody has a great day and we'll see you later.  Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen this concludes the conference call for today.  Thank you for participating.  Please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>