<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1164387" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1559</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Rogers, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Rick George, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Ken Alley, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Brian Dutton</participant>
      <participant id="5">Rick George</participant>
      <participant id="6">John Rogers</participant>
      <participant id="7">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="8">Rob Plexman</participant>
      <participant id="9">Ryan Todd</participant>
      <participant id="10">Ken Alley</participant>
      <participant id="11">Paul Cheng</participant>
      <participant id="12">William Lacey</participant>
      <participant id="13">Gordon Gee</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you, for standing by. Welcome to the Suncor Energy Inc. Second Quarter Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Following the presentation, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. Instructions will be provided at that time for you to queue up for questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. I would like to remind everyone that this conference call is being recorded on Thursday, July 24, 2008 at 7:30 AM Mountain Time.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the conference over to John Rogers, Vice President, Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone, and thank you for listening into our second quarter conference call. I have the usual suspects with me today. Actually Ken Alley and Rick George are in remote. They are up in the Fort McMurray location. So Rick and Ken are up there and in the Calgary office with me is Maureen Cormier, our Corporate Controller, Greg Freidin and Tim Mah from our Controllers' Department.</p>
          <p>We are going to follow the normal pattern. Rick will give his introductory comments, Ken also will give you a bit of the insight into the outlook and then we will turn it over to you to ask questions of Rick and Ken. So Rick why don't you kick it off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>John, thank you very much. I'm delighted to be here and Ken and I are obviously in Fort McMurray. We have had a Board meeting here over the last couple of days and got a good chance to get our Board around all of our operations here in Fort McMurray which has been a great trip.</p>
          <p>So, listen, we're on to talk about the second quarter earnings. We obviously knew and the market knew as well that our second-quarter results would be impacted by the turnaround at the upgrader number one. At Oil Sands, it was one of the largest turnarounds that we worked, that we've ever completed. And it did come back a little bit late, it did take us a number of extra days to bring that unit back on. And really, it was around the amount of work that we found once we opened up the unit and also the availability of labor, which is certainly very tight in this region.</p>
          <p>And if you think about it in a two-year context, we had a big turnaround in upgrader number two in the second quarter of last year and so both this year and last year impacted by those turnarounds. They are very important part of this business, it's very important they get done right and they are very important in terms of us being able to operate safely as we go forward.</p>
          <p>The turnaround is now behind us. We are feeling very good about that. We still are bringing the unit up to full production and so the month of July won't look quite as strong as you might expect. But, what I would say the rest of this year looks extremely good as we divide out these facilities. So obviously, we are not very happy with the production in the first six months of this year. We do know we have disappointed and what I would say about it is, listen, this is temporary.</p>
          <p>This is one of the challenges that corporations go through. It is not permanent. We do feel like we have this well under control. We have the right people on the right assets and we will get this lined out and will move forward towards that 350,000 barrels a day, which will come later part of next year. So, we're disappointed on that. Some of the root causes include a very severe winter, we did have the restrictions on Firebag, which you would have noted got listed just two days ago. We are very happy that that got lifted.</p>
          <p>We worked very hard to make sure that happens. And our track record, a sense of the restriction was on has been very, very good. So, I think that all helped us. Production at Firebag this month will be around 42,000 barrels a day. We will start and have already started steaming new wells. It takes you about three months to get communications between the well bores and so then you'll start to see a ramp up after that.</p>
          <p>We are very happy with the production numbers at Firebag. This restriction order we are not happy with, but it did give us a chance to fix a number of things that really kind of steady down on the wells. We had some down-hole problems. We got all of those fixed and so, very happy with that. If you look at Firebag, it's one of the biggest steep production, if not the biggest, in Canada at about 40,000 barrels a day and it will be ramping up from there.</p>
          <p>Really like the reservoir performance. Really like the technology, although, we are still going up the technology curve there. So, if there is any silver lining around the restriction, it's that and we certainly made full use of that cap to the extent that we can. So, the group up here is working very hard. It's not an easy environment, it's very busy up in the Fort McMurray region. Generally, the all of the industry is pushing hard up here to get volumes up. Very proud of the team here in terms of what they're doing and what they are getting accomplished. And so, we feel very solid about where we are on a go forward basis.</p>
          <p>Just, to move onto major projects for a moment. Of course, that's a big part of Suncor work these days. If you'll remember, we did a project, we called the MCU, the Millennium Coker Unit. It was a $2.3 billion project. And virtually, it is complete now and it was on time and on budget. Not something you can say about a lot of these projects. So, very proud of the Major Projects Group and what they've done with that. That's a very tough project, because it's right in the middle of the operating plant. I know, the operations guys are glad to have that work, kind of mostly behind them and those guys out of the essential operational parts of that.</p>
          <p>Our Millennium Naptha unit which is about a $650 million project, it's 30% complete and is targeted for a mid-2009 completion. The $850 million Steepbank Extraction Plant project engineering is essentially complete, construction about 30% complete, and is again targeted for 2009 completion. At Firebag, the sulphur plant that we're putting in that will handle all of the sulphur from all six stages. The engineering is 85% complete, construction about 30 and it's targeted again for 2009 completion. So, a number of these smaller projects other than Voyageur, are going to be done here in the mid to a latter part of 2009, again it will be a great milestone to have those behind us.</p>
          <p>With regard to Voyageur itself, the project is split into two pieces -- the upgrade of the engineering is 70% complete and construction is about 5%. We are in the field doing deep undergrounds, a lot of piling work. We've already done one of the largest concrete pours on the project in terms of the coker structure and so that the Voyageur project is off to a good start, early days but at a good start.</p>
          <p>Firebag Stage 3 and this Voyageur project we have 3,4,5 and 6. Stage 3 is the first one, it is -- the engineering is 90% complete, construction is 30% complete and we're targeted to have first oil at the very end of 2009. And so you'll start to then see those stages ramped out at about a year at a time after that. So we're very proud again of the project work we do in a very tough environment from a labor availability viewpoint, but we're managing this, I think as best we can in this environment. And I'm very proud of that.</p>
          <p>If you think about the other two businesses, Natural Gas, very strong quarter and obviously we increased the outlook in terms of performance for the full year and so very happy with that particular operation. And in the downstream, Refining and Marketing, solid operational results, if you look at refinery utilization that was good. Obviously, we're impacted by refining margins just like everybody else, it can't escape that. Refining margins are down, we are seeing some demand reduction and we're certainly seeing margins on gasoline in particular down. If there is any bright light to any of that side of the business is diesel margins hanging in pretty solid and Suncor is a large diesel producer if you look at Oil Sands and our two refineries together.</p>
          <p>So if you take a look at it, really good results, with one exception and that is the operational results at Oil Sands. I can just tell you there is a big focus of Steve Williams, our Chief Operating Officer and our entire team and I think I'm absolutely convinced, we're turning a corner here and you'll see much better results as we head into the last six months of this year. So that's kind of it on an operational basis. Ken, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Rick, and good morning everyone. Rick covered it pretty well. I mean, clearly the financial results reflect the planned turnaround and the impact on production at Oil Sands. That was offset by very high crude prices, so that continues to be the story here as we go forward. Rick talked about that offset some of the production shortfall from the turnaround. Good performance from the natural gas business, I'm pleased to see that performance. The downstream business, Rick talked about the softening of gasoline demand and margins clearly impacting that business year-over-year, clearly masked to a certain extent by the change in accounting to FIFO.</p>
          <p>So inventory gains are showing stronger results in the downstream than we would see if we were on a LIFO basis. I think that really gives a true picture of what's happening to margins on the downstream. Given that we had the turnaround cash flow was pretty strong at $1.4 billion and capital spending very much in line with our expectations. So overall, the balance sheet is about where we thought we would be at this stage of Voyageur expansion. So we feel very good about our ability to finance that project and all of our capital spending going forward. We did take the opportunity to put some long-term debt on the balance sheet in the second quarter, really to finance Voyageur, but it's really part of building out the overall capital structure of the corporation going forward and that will be a very much larger corporation once we complete project Voyageur. So overall, the balance sheet is about where we expected to be and in good shape.</p>
          <p>John, I think I'll just pass it over to you now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great back to Calgary here. The only thing I was going to comment on was the outlook, it is on page 3 of the release. Obviously we did adjust the production outlook for Oil Sands given our year-to-date production. I think everybody with us publishing monthly production numbers knew or anticipated we were going to change that range, 240 to 250 is the range that we are now predicting, will come in for the year. It will be a build through the year, we would expect that we would exit the year at 300,000. So we're kind of building from July through to the end of December with an exit in the range of about 300. The mix is as it is stated here and the realizations are a little better than I think we had originally anticipated with the WTI pushing off 250 to 350. And cash costs really just fall out of the production numbers in the neighborhood of 35 to 36. So you'll probably see something like 31 to 32 in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Natural gas production in the range of 210 to 220 as Rick mentioned, just up a little higher. We've seen some really good performance out of that group and chose to update the guidance for the year. So really that's all I was going to comment on. What we'd like to do now Joanne is to open the line for questions. Again Maureen and Greg and Tim and I would like to answer your detailed modeling questions after the call when we could give it a little more time, a little more consideration. So if you have any strategic questions you would like to put up for Rick and Ken, we would be happy to entertain them now. So over to you Joanne.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen we will now conduct the question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And your first question comes from Brian Dutton, Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning Rick. I think you've made a pretty clear this year that your key priority is improving the reliability of the base business and operational excellence. Along that line could you remind us of the issues that you've being facing at extraction and with the turnaround now behind you, have those issues now been resolved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, yeah. A lot of our problems at extraction have been around our handling of sand and we've had a couple of instances, particularly early in the year where we actually plugged off one of the major plants there with sand and very heavy production -- oddly enough as a direct result of having very rich ore in one incidence where we carried that rich ore carried over a lot of sand into second part of what we call Plant 4 where we actually plugged it off with sand. So we know a lot of the issues that we had in the first quarter particularly and then the second quarter we feel like we've got a real bead on, whether that's erosion in our tailings lines or whether it's plugging off Plant 4. And so there are lot of terrific work and it's not just one thing, there's about eight different items that the extraction plant has been working on in terms of continuous improvement to make sure that we get that done.</p>
          <p>I feel very good about that. In fact if you look at that, that is not the limiting factor over the last several weeks and so coming out of the turnaround, and they did a lot of work on the extraction plant, the turnaround feel pretty good about where we are with that. Having higher volumes from Firebag going into the plant will help, I will say that. I mean, we're probably 20,000 barrels a bit lower than we would have expected if Firebag would have had full lift off by now maybe a little bit lower in that. And that would have helped you ride through some of the extraction plant problems. So as we ramp Firebag on up continuously that will take a little bit of the pressure off the extraction plant. Also taking in Petro-Can volumes which start later this year into the plant, that means you then have two mines, two extraction plants, Firebag and Petro-Canada all feeding the plant. All that should help steady off in terms of feed into the plant. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello,</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You there, John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm here, are you guys there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh oh. I think we have a technical glitch here. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll just go and check.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And your next question comes from Gil Alexander, Starksky Associates . Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you give us an idea of what your cash operating cost...? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We seem to be having some technical difficulties here. I'm not sure. Operator, you should stay on this line. Gil, go ahead. We can hear you here in Fort McMurray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you. Could you give us an idea of what your cash operating cost per barrel will be, once you get to 300,000 barrels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gil, we would expect it to be somewhere in that $27 a barrel range, when we have sort of steady state production at about 300,000 barrels a day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And good luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Zubeida Mirza, CIBC World Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, can you hear us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We can hear you. And I'm going to have to correct your previous answer. It's probably --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have one more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...27, when we get the 350.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. The next question will come from Brian Singer, Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. Can you guys hear me, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fantastic. I wanted to focus on Firebag. Could you discuss, I guess as you remediated the sulphur issue, if there are any larger takeaways either for Firebag or just more broadly for SAGD in terms of sulphur management and timing of some of these sulphur issues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So, what happened to us was when we did all the core hole drilling across Firebag and did all the sampling as a result of that, we did not see any significant amount of sulphur in that. And so, at one point a decision was made that we didn't actually need sulphur handling. Then, when we started steaming and this shows you, this is a very young technology -- I'm talking about the industry in general, in terms of SAGD. When we started steaming, then we got a completely different kind of reaction underground in terms of producing more sulphur than we ever projected from the reservoir modeling. That's not actually a massive problem, except that we just didn't install the facilities to handle that. Those, and I mentioned those specifics are being installed and will be complete by second quarter of 2009 and again that sulphur plant that we're putting in will handle all six stages.</p>
          <p>So, it's still not a massive amount of sulphur, but it's enough that it will cause an odor problem. So don't think about this is a highly sulphur reservoir. It is just more sulphur than we actually designed in the facilities. But if you look at Firebag overall, listen our average well is over 2,000 barrels a day. So this is a great reservoir, it's got a great cap rock, in the beginning stage there's very little water and if you look at well production rates, compared to any other SAGD projects, we are more than double sometimes quadruple or 10 times with other SAGD produces who are producing per well pair.</p>
          <p>What I would say is every reservoir is different and so you cannot generalize this across all of the industry, because the thicknesses, the amount of water, the over burden you have of pressure of that reservoir is different in absolutely every single case and so you cannot generalize about any of this.</p>
          <p>We are still very happy with our reservoir, we're very happy with our performance, looks very solid. This is just one of those adjustments at very early in the stages of a 9 billion barrel reservoir development. And again, I feel very confident about where we are going with this overall. If you look at Firebag over the last three, four months it has been very solid, very steady operations in terms of production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then secondly on costs, could you give us an update just I guess given higher steel costs and maybe some update on where the labor market stands in terms of labor cost inflation? What that potentially could mean relative to what you have already locked in for Voyageur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's a great question. So we still continue to see -- you're asking really Voyageur on the construction on a go forward basis. And we still are subject to inflationary rates, which far exceed anything that you read on any other industry that I know about. We certainly would be seeing inflationary rates on materials in the 7 to 10% rate. So that is higher than we put in the initial estimates. We are not giving up on it yet, I can tell you that, but and we certainly have quite a bit of equipment order on upgrader, on the Voyageur Upgrader already and certainly on Firebag stages three and four.</p>
          <p>We're probably more impacted in terms of that and in terms of stages five and six on Firebag than anything, because we've so much of the material ordered. So it is still an issue and I am not announcing another number, except to just say listen there's plenty of pressure on the inflationary front. On the manpower front, we were really impacted this year by the turnaround, we put a lot of those resources I mean human basis over onto the turnaround that has been moved back. Again very -- we are obviously pleased with both, where we stand on engineering and the fact we have engineering pretty far ahead of construction, both at Firebag and at the Voyageur Upgrader site. And, very early days, but very pleased with the progress we're making there. So, just know, yeah inflationary pressures, absolutely.</p>
          <p>One way to look at this is of the $20.6 billion project, we already have $4 billion spent. So, you are one fifth of the spending way through. At the end of this year, you'll probably be closer to 7 billion spent of the 20.6. So, we are heading there. I can tell you that. What does help us a little bit is Firebag being staged in four different stages. And the fact that you'll have the first stage and the production from that coming out in 2010. And then, it will come on in stages. So, that's actually helping that somewhat. And, of course the big piece then is of course the Upgrader. But if you walk up on our Upgrader side, which I did recently, you'll be very impressed with the amount of activity going on there already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And your next question comes from Robert Plexman, CIBC World Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I had two Firebag questions. Rick, first of all, just wondering if there is any risk that the government could reimpose the restriction? Between now when the sulphur plant is completed. Also wondering if the restrictions at Firebag have had any impact on your ability to start commissioning the MCU, if there is any relationship there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks Rob. And then, what I say on the second question, none as, no restrictions at all in terms of starting up the MCU at all. No actual tie at all there. On the other, you got to remember what this controller was about was about odor. And so odor &#x2013; so  this is not a safety issue, it's not an environmental issue and it's not an operational issue, save the fact that we had more odor coming out of plant than is allowed.</p>
          <p>And, we have had except for one upset in January, we've had virtually no exceedances since December last year. So, as long as we can keep in that operating mode, then we should be able to keep our license in, I think we've learned our lesson is what I would say to this. We will not be tolerant of exceeding those limits. And the temporary fix we put in has worked extremely well. We do not see why that can't work very well, all the way till we get this sulphur plant done. So, listen it's an operational issue you can always have upsets, but what I would say is we would not sacrifice short-term daily production over that odor issue, the odor issue is one that we feel like we have under control and as long as we are very careful with that we shouldn't have any further restrictions on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Ryan Todd, Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. A question for you. I know the past couple of years have been pretty heavy on the turnaround side and operations have been a bit rough. Going forward I know there will continue to be a certain amount of turnaround in normal operations. What do you think is a reasonable target utilization rate in terms of -- versus total capacity for the Oil Sands operations going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is a good question. I mean, you have the capacity obviously, but you're always going to have various issues catalyst replacements or other issues. I think, because of the fact we have two Upgraders going to three Upgraders we will have the maximum amount of flexibility and you have to remember, every three years potentially four if we can stretch it that far you have to take these things down for between 30 and 60 days to do the correction. Outside of that a normal run rate would be certainly in the 90% of your nameplate value. Now the trouble with this business is that's not a steady state number, but some utilization in that 90% range should be something that you should target for, and that's certainly where our budgeted numbers would look at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One thing we could say too is the production numbers that we do put out are with our anticipated utilization rates. So they are not the maximum production they're our anticipated utilization rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thanks. That's very helpful and then one more I am sure and I know you get at this all the time, but refining valuations very, very cheap out there. Any -- in terms of refining and acquisitions any interest on anything. And specifically on and maybe you can't comment on this, but on Frontiers Refineries would you anticipate any sort of anti-trust issues down on the Rockies regions or you think if you're interested you'd be able to do something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm not going to make a comment on specific companies -- I guess, I've been talking about this sometime we continue to look at downstream assets. It has to really be asset-specific and if you recall we bought the Denver refineries before the big run-up in refinery margins. I think, we got most of that margin and feel great about the timing of that. As I said, and we're right through the middle of the peak of refinery margins that they looked way too high for me and we did not pull the trigger on anything.</p>
          <p>And so for us it's a very patient game and it's about asset fit. So it has to fit with us and production coming out of Oil Sands. We continue look at individual assets, not very interested in companies at the current time. What I would say is, with increased ethanol production and with demand dampening, as I would put it, then I don't know that I see refinery margins roaring back any time. So this may be a game of patience as much as anything. But I'm really happy with the two refineries that we had. I would sure love to have a couple of refineries, which I'm not going to identify on the phone. But it's a price value issue for Suncor and not a real drive to be in the downstream. And so I think that's probably the best way that I can put that. I don't want to talk about specific companies or specific assets for the obvious reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Paul Cheng, Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first, John before I forget. When -- after the call, can you or someone send me, whether email or phone call a stock-based compensation by segment and also the FIFO inventory gain for the downstream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We will be happy to do that, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Rick, I know it's still early, but I think, you had indicated that after Voyageur you're not sure that building Upgrader up in Fort McMurray, or even in Edmonton or anywhere in Alberta that makes sense going forward. So wondering have you guys thought to contemplating beyond Voyageur, what is the growth plan for the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Good question, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or that is still too early?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. It's not too early. No. In fact, we are working very hard on that. We have a number of options in terms of what we're looking at, one is the mining project we call Voyageur South, there is further expansion possibilities in Firebag. We have also a mining opportunity which is located just North of Firebag. And so we've got three or four different projects that have the potential to do that. Probably, the most likely and we're still working on this would be a Voyageur, we'll call it Voyageur South, which is just south of the Voyageur Upgrader. This would not be -- the one thing I would say about that is, we are looking at is a mine using completely new technologies throughout, a lot of which we are developing currently. And so those plans are there.</p>
          <p>One of the reasons it's not too early to start talking about some of that is because we're getting to the point where to get environmental permits to do a project is moving out from probably 36 closer to some other number. I don't know where that number ends. But we are certainly well beyond 36 months just to get environmental permits, not to mention engineering and construction to follow.</p>
          <p>So it's not too early. I do want to keep our organization very focused on the here and now both in terms of operational excellence driven by Steve Williams, but also on the major projects we have. So we have a lot on our plate, but I would say in the background, we are working on this issue of where it is next.</p>
          <p>I think what is different is, if we have 500, 550,000 barrels a day of upgrade capacity, then our ability to take a little bit more risk in terms of producing heavy oil or bitumen and selling that to the market, is a different issue than it was if you are at 250,000 barrels a day and then take bitumen at 100,000 barrels a day. So you have a little more flexibility.</p>
          <p>I think the other thing that's changed in the market is, if you look at supply issues and production drops in Mexico and I think Venezuela will follow. Then, what we are also seeing is a lot more pull on the Canadian crudes terminal coming out of the Gulf of Mexico. And so, I think, if you think about it logically, if you have coking capacity either Pad II, south of Chicago or in the Gulf Coast that is short of heavy and maybe the better option may be to go with the heavy that you get down into those marketplaces rather than build your own Upgrader. And, certainly Suncor is one that has got the flexibility to do both, that's the good news. And you can probably take a little bit more risk about what's happening. We do a lot of work and I know you do too, Paul, around what's going to happen to light heavy differentials as hard &#x2013; it's not an easy call. But I would say, given what I know on a worldwide basis including what's going on in West Africa and the Middle East. I would probably bet on lower light heavy differentials on a go forward basis. It's hard to call five years out but that's certainly something we're looking at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually agree with you. I think, the line of defense is coming down. Rick, I mean, how big is the Voyageur's self mining. Are we talking above 100,000, 200 or what...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we've actually gone public with that. I would just say right now, it is in that 100 to 200 range. We haven't actually set a number and gone public, but you can expect later this year that we will be a little bit more definitive about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Another question you're talking about. I think, the earlier they questioned about acquisition of refining. I think that patience is a virtue, may be a better payoff. But before we even think about acquiring assets, I mean, what's the possibility or the potential that <mark type="inaudible" /> that you can organically to expand your -- to take in even more of the solid crude or they have the oil there? Is it economic at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Heavy oils are a little bit of a problem. Since you'd have to add cokers, that's a big investment in what is a relatively small market. So, I don't really necessarily see we are in a lot more heavy than we do today, we run a little bit of heavy done there now. And, we have an asphalt plant that obviously takes a lot of that heavy. But continuing to look at is there an opportunity to change that refinery into producing more diesel versus gasoline than it does today, it has some flexibility, but not a lot and so I don't think there's a lot of potential for that. We're very happy with that asset, and if you look at its cash flow particularly in the first six months, it shows you are very solid even in the environment we find ourselves in. But I don't see a really big opportunity there to change it to let's say add cokers or something that makes it large on the scale of Suncor</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And also, Rick, you earlier mentioned that the severe cost pressure that you guys are facing in the industry. Any update or changes that you look at in terms of the CapEx for this year as well as the guidance for the next several years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, nothing for this year. In fact our projections of over 7 billion of our capital, we look to be on track with that or maybe slightly under but it's just a timing issue more than anything. So no, not on that. You will see a higher capital budget out of us in 2009 and really that's around Voyageur, and it's an issue of timing. 2009 or early 2010 will be our peak spending years in terms of Voyageur and as you get into late 2010 and '11, that's where you'll have most of the materials bought and you'll actually be finishing up a number of the projects. So, that the peak comes here in 2009 or early 2010 and then after that ramped down, but no real change in terms of the profile that we expect on the next couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think, previously that the guidance is around in the $8 billion for the next two-years. Is that still in the ballpark okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, its John. It's probably more on the 8 to 9 range for the next two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. Final question, I think that when we're looking at the new production guidance, I mean, the fact that when you look at the first six months and then obviously, that you have to revise it downwards. But that appears, that it also means that you're revising the second half of the production guidance down where it's been? I mean, given that you think most of the problems that are facing you in the first half is already behind you. Is there any particular reasons causing the second half revision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Rick, do you want me to answer that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Paul, not really, I think, we had looked at the Firebag restriction and felt that we would be short of bitumen for quite some time and the control order is now behind us. But it's going to take as Rick mentioned three months of steaming before we begin to see some incremental production. So, a lot of this has to do with the shortage of bitumen and as we build that bitumen up we now feel that we're probably 12 months behind where we wanted to be. So we'll be at 350, anticipated 350 sometime in the second half of next year, which backs everything into this year. So we would expect to exit this year at 300, which is probably lower than we thought we'd be 12 months ago. But I think, as our operational experiences has unfolded, this is where we kind of think we are. So we are probably 12 months behind but I think, we had anticipated this a little while ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from William Lacey, FirstEnergy. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentlemen. just two real quick questions. We've seen producers start to get more and more involved in what I'll call the midstream along the pipelines or at least owning equity on the systems. Rick, what is your thought as far as the strategic importance for you guys getting the whole Gulf access, what have you about owning steel in that particular segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think you got to be careful. You know certainly we're looking at all of that and I think the strategic advantage that I see for Suncor involved the size and scale of our operations, the amount of diluents that we have available and the fact that we were in both upstream and downstream. And we certainly are taking positions on pipelines on a go-forward basis.</p>
          <p>Actual ownership is a different issue in the sense that if you look at historically the returns are much lower than we have at other investment opportunities. So you got to be very careful. It will be strategic for us, it will be around having the right storage in the right location, and some other assets that are very important. I'm not saying that we won't take positions on pipelines, but they will have to be something where we think we have a distinct competitive advantage. It won't be a wholesale kind of -- let's take an equity position in a pipeline for a long period of time. Now what I would say is virtually most of the pipelines are being -- we're taking a look at taking throughput rights on those, but actual equity ownership is again if you look at our return on capital numbers, those projects look pretty low. So a better choice for us may be to return cash to shareholders than do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Second question. I know you've dealt with this one before, but just your flexibility on your production output, obviously diesel pricing is pretty strong, how much flexibility do you have in sort of tweaking your output towards more diesel, what have you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And I would say limited. There is some flexibility at Sarnia and Denver but not massive here. It is just keeping that diesel hydrotreater up and running and turning out the diesel. So I did a back of the envelope calculation the other day, because we don't necessarily think about in these segments, but we would produce about 100,000 barrels a day of diesel between Fort McMurray and the two refineries, something close to that. So it is an important part, but our flexibility in terms of massively increasing that is somewhat limited without putting in significant new capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Gordon Gee, RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gordon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, good morning, guys. Sorry I might have missed a bit of your prepared remarks, but is it possible for you to give a number for your LIFO, FIFO adjustment is for the downstream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's actually right in the statements, Gordon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes sorry. I'm just out of the office; I don't have access to the pdf.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>179.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gordon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentlemen, there are no further questions at the time. Please continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thanks Joanna. The one thing I wanted to elaborate on, just for a second was around our cash cost and we certainly do expect to be in the $27 range when we're at the full capacity of 350,000 barrels a day. When we're at 300, we're going to be more like 30 to $31 in terms of cash cost. So again, as we move toward that 350, we think our production base does support about a $27 cash cost. With that, I just wanted to thank everyone for listening in. Again, Maureen, Greg and Tim and I will be available in my office for your detailed modeling questions. And other than that, everybody have a good day. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call for today. Thank you for participating. Please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>