<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1406215" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7870</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Management Board, President &amp; CEO">Jean-Pascal Tricoire</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Co-Chief Financial Officer">Emmanuel Babeau</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Investor Relations Contact">Carina Ho</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Olivier Esnou</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Securities (Paris) SAS">Ga&#xEB;l De Bray</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Ludovic Debailleux</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA">Alfred Glaser</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Andreas Willi</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Martin Prozesky</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Simon J. Smith</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Martin Wilkie</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Daniela Costa</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">James A. Moore</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning and welcome to the session of review of the H1 Business Results of Schneider Electric. I am here with Carina Ho and Emmanuel Babeau and we're going to comment together the first half of this year 2011.</p>
          <p>Very quickly, going to slide five, a reminder of what is Schneider Electric today, a &#x20AC;21 billion sales company over the past 12 months &#x2013; the last 12 months. And you find here the main characteristics of our company, a very global company, strong exposure to emerging countries, 38% of our turnover on the last 12 months, 39%, actually, on the last quarter. Strong investment in research and development, actually an investment that we have beefed up in the first half.</p>
          <p>And a very diversified exposure in two directions, two geographies, a very balanced presence around the world, and around end markets with a very balanced presence on several end markets; on end markets which are infrastructure, industry, data centers, buildings and residential.</p>
          <p>Going to slide six, remind you our commitment to sustainable development. Clean products, clean processes, commitment to ethical business. And the strong commitment to the development of the communities, where we work around our BipBop program for electrification of underprivileged people, on insertion of underprivileged youngsters, with a big commitment in education in our business, particularly the business of energy and electricity.</p>
          <p>Moving onto the H1 results, more specifically, I would say that this first half was characterized by three things. The first point is a strong growth on both top line and the operating results. We confirmed a double-digit organic growth, current growth at 20%, mainly impacted by the adding of Areva Distribution, but also by the other acquisitions that we've done principally last year. And this strong growth on top line has been followed by a strong growth on the operating result with our EBITA growing by 14% in value.</p>
          <p>The second characteristics of this first half, it has been a very strong deployment of our strategy. First element is an accelerated growth in new economies, which are representing, again, 39% of our turnover in Q2, and the total growth in H1 of 17% and we have clearly invested in the first half in a renewed way to make sure that we are present in the secondary cities and the more remote places of the new economies, the West of China, the East of Russia, the secondary cities of India, secondary cities of Brazil. Clearly we'd say that we would invest in 2011 and this has been a significant part of our investment.</p>
          <p>Second transition we had in H1 is a strong surge of solutions in our turnover. Solutions represented 35% of our turnover, a growth of 14%. And this is a place where we have invested in H1. Solutions boosted our growth. The counterpart of it is that that they don't carry the same margin, so they put pressure &#x2013; come back, they put pressure on &#x2013; only if you can come back. Thank you. They put pressure on P&amp;L margin on the first half. Last year was more of a product half, and this year was more of a solutions half.</p>
          <p>Third point that really was a strong implementation of our strategy. It was an intense first half in terms of acquisitions. Many things come at maturity at the same time, with clearly where we executed acquisitions along the profile that we prefer to pursue, which are mid-sized acquisitions, service both new economies and solutions, but I will come back to that.</p>
          <p>Third point that characterizes this first-half is clearly an unusual level of disturbances, which affects &#x2013; that had impact in H1, but that we shall correct in H2. The first one has been a very strong impact of raw material cost inflation, the highest and the fastest we have ever known, actually &#x20AC;200 million plus in H1 and there's going to be more in H2. And actually, we need to be more proactive in pricing both solutions and products. But it took us, it takes some time to react to raw material inflation. Therefore, we see something were driving activity and that will kick in at a higher level in H2.</p>
          <p>The second unusual disturbance was serious Japanese crisis and I have been very clear with that. We had taken the very strong orientation to save our customers and to make sure that we would be able to serve our customers. And therefore, we have taken a number of actions which have impacted our industrial costs, re-engineering of products, making sure we would map completely our supply chain and clearly, it has led us at the end of H1 to driving the inventory up far above the average of what we use to do. And this is something that we are going to be reducing in H2, because the news that we have from our supply chain are rather positive.</p>
          <p>I mean, actually, we probably overestimated six months ago the impact of what was happening in Japan, but it was very difficult in two months ago to understand exactly what would be the impact. Today, we serve our customers, we served our customers. There has been no disruption with our customers, but clearly we have &#x2013; it has provoked a surge in our inventory and therefore, an unusual deterioration of our cash generation.</p>
          <p>So, the unusual fact on H1, it has been the density of acquisition. We have kept you informed of each of them. Most of them are small to medium, but it has incurred some cost, it has incurred some &#x2013; a lot of activity and clearly. As I am going to tell you, the priority of the H2 is integration and will make sure that those acquisitions are coming solidly inside China.</p>
          <p>So, I am going to go into the three engines of growth of this H1. They are also the main directions of our strategies. They are the core elements of our One program and I am going to start by solutions.</p>
          <p>I already said most of it, but again, solutions make up 35% of our business in H1 with services representing 10% and the growth has been 14%, plus 4% respectively to the average of the group. As much as 2010 has been an unusually high level of activity in products, they were the early cycle in the rebound post crisis. The solutions, not surprisingly and we're been very clear on that all over, have taken more time to rebound and the first half has been dense in solutions. But again, positive drives growth, negative dilutes the margin. But anyway, you don't have the same capital employed, I repeat it, on solution.</p>
          <p>What have we done? We are keeping on investing in software technologies, one of the big steps we are in the process of doing is, by the way, Telvent joining Schneider. We are developing architectures by market segments. We are putting into place commercial and execution centers and we are ramping up the services. I've always been very vocal that between the time you recruit somebody for solution and services and the time they produce revenue, you've got 18 months. So, it's an investment that we do gradually, but which is weighing clearly on our margins in solutions.</p>
          <p>Slide &#x2013; next slide, the second element of our strategy is the development of new economies. And when we look at the big picture, we doubled our size in new economies in the past five years. Most of it has been done organically. You would gather it. Actually, we are today doing &#x20AC;8 billion on the last 12 months in new economies. For me, it's a kind of market, because when I took over the operating management or the operations of the Group, the whole of Schneider was around this figure. I mean, we are doing around &#x20AC;8 billion in the whole of world and 80% was in the Western economies.</p>
          <p>So, we've grown in the past seven years a pretty sizable company in the new economies, and what I like and what we're doing in new economies is the balanced aspect of it. We are presenting every new economies with very strong positions not only in Asia, which is the very center of what we do in new economies, but also in Middle East and Africa. In Latin America, we are really &#x2013; we've redressed and grown very significant position particularly in Brazil, and clearly in Russia, where with the acquisition or the joint venture we have with Samara, we've doubled our position very recently. Here, the main axis are the geographical coverage, like many Western companies, we used to be strong in the main cities, in the main urban environments. We are really developing in a more capital way in those countries.</p>
          <p>Commercial presence, which is really present everywhere in those places, very strong presence now in R&amp;D and other development. I'll come back to that, because we start to be very visible. And we start now to develop our solutions and services as new economies as they develop. Now we're finding that it's smart to outsource things to people like us.</p>
          <p>So, very strong element of Schneider, it's clearly a point of investment, both organically and externally by acquisitions in the first half. But it's a story which is developing in a very, very strong manner and which is becoming very central. The growth in Asia, particularly Asia Pac, has been spectacular in the past two or three years. We have reached a new size and one of the objectives that we have in the next years to come is to make sure that we consolidate and support this growth, based on the very solid footprint that we have in new economies.</p>
          <p>Two other things I like in the new economies, well, I am not speaking about very large projects that are export projects. These are rooted activities in the economies of the new economies. And the last thing I like is that those business are as probably as profitable as what we do in major countries. We are not subsidizing new economies from the mature economies. Those new economies are developing in a mature and autonomous way.</p>
          <p>Going to slide 11, you see very clearly that on Q2 &#x2013; on Q1, the new economies have again generated a different sort of growth with respect to the mature countries of 10%. By the way, nothing to be very ashamed of in mature economies, very strong rebound based on the new activities that we developed.</p>
          <p>The things that we develop in new economies are really based on the investment we do, on the new activities we are capturing. It's about services, it's about solutions, it's about energy efficiency, in some cases, it's about renewables. It's really things that we develop on markets which overall, when you take the average of Europe and the U.S., have still not recovered from the crisis. But you see really the strong kicker that new economies represent in our growth.</p>
          <p>So, solutions, new economies, on new economies, just to give you a glimpse of things which are coming on the market, which are offers for new economies developed in new economies. You have got example here in energy. Actually, this is an offer coming from Areva. IT products, which are just developed for the new economies, which are carrying their own characteristics. Industry, we are very successful with products of this series of motion, which is totally adapted to the China market in this specific example, and others which are developed India for India, China for China, Brazil for Brazil and that we are developing, manufacturing locally at different functions on different value price points.</p>
          <p>I am going to the third engine of our growth, which is acquisition. You know it's been always proper for our model at Schneider. We are a &#x20AC;21 billion company in an accessible market, which is above &#x20AC;200 billion, so it's still very fragmented. And there were many things that came to maturity in the first half, and that has taken a lot of our activity, we acknowledge it. But when you look at the past 18 months, fundamentally, we've done a certain number of acquisition. We have acquired for roughly &#x20AC;3 billion of turnover. Half of it is about solutions, half of it is about new economies. And actually when you look at it, there is an overlap of &#x20AC;1 billion of solutions in new economy, so it's &#x20AC;2 billion in new economies, &#x20AC;2 billion in solutions, of which &#x20AC;1 billion is overlapping.</p>
          <p>Now you would say, well, it's a lot. Actually there are large two acquisitions, Areva D and Telvent, which are kind of the exceptions to the typical profile of our acquisitions, but when then you look at rest, it's typically what we are used to do, I mean small, medium acquisition, very often in a private negotiation, very often with private owners and bolt-on companies which are integrating pretty easily, with a lot of work, but which are integrating quite naturally in our company.</p>
          <p>Again, we've got very strict criterias, financial criterias in our acquisitions. They are not the only one, the first one is obviously is the strategic fit, the second one is the cultural fit. But the financial criterias are very strict and every time we don't go with a typical criteria, which is roughly above the &#x20AC;1 billion, we announce it and we tell it very transparently in our communication. So, you are informed of every time where we decide to make an exception, which is not often, by the way.</p>
          <p>Our debt structure is very, very &#x2013; our balance sheet is very solid, but Emmanuel will come back on that.</p>
          <p>So, what strikes me in H1 is that it has been an intense application for implementation of our strategy. What we see today is that energy efficiency is mainstream. And by the way, what &#x2013; the tragedy that happened in Japan, and especially the pressure it puts on nuclear industry, is making the two technology banners, Germany and Japan, have decided to adopt new energy models and to be stronger on energy efficiency.</p>
          <p>We totally support this. We believe that we need all kinds of generation, but anyway, that the world will become &#x2013; will have to become more efficient. And clearly, we have an edge today on the solutions and particularly the, what we call eco-structure, in the field of energy efficiency solutions. So, what you saw in the first half is a development technologically around the eco-structure breaks and in terms of competence with a set-up of competency centers on our solutions for energy efficiency particularly are developing by 14%, growing by 14%.</p>
          <p>Smart grid emerging on the most striking element of the first half, and this time, it's the offer on Telvent, which is bringing &#x2013; which is doubling our software capabilities in the field of the smart grid. Our new economies are driving the world growth, the striking difference between the debt in the mature countries and the capacities of financing in the new economies, where we are well rooted, not because we decided yesterday to go there, but we decided a long time ago, and it's a well-rooted, well &#x2013; I'm very happy at present that we have there, again, 17% in H1.</p>
          <p>I'd like to go to the next slide, slide 15. I'll remind you that we worked on our productivity, on efficiency in the first half. And clearly, we delivered a good productivity, a bit below last year. There was certainly less volume rupture or change in this first half. And also, we have impacted, we could have done better in purchasing and absorption of fixed manufacturing cost, but we had to make some important compromises with electronics, due to what happened in Japan and the ruptures in the supply chain.</p>
          <p>And there was a lot of work also in reengineering &#x2013; there is a series of products that we totally reengineered, because some of the components were not there anymore. I mean, the factories have been wiped out. And we reengineered, which is, in my dialect, a tour de force, they were reengineered in like two months and made available with the customers.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we decided to overstock to cover the crisis. And this is very visible in our cash, which is, for the first time, negative, but this is mainly due to the inventory. And we kept working on our support function cost with respect to our sales, reaching 24.5% of our sales in H1 2011. This been helped this time by Areva D, because this is a place where Areva D is helping a lot for the margin, the integration of Areva D has decreased the average margin of the group, but this is very mechanical and very explainable.</p>
          <p>Now, I am going to hand over to Emmanuel for the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Let's move into some details on numbers and first of all, let's look at the details of the performance of our sales by business.</p>
          <p>In total, our sales amounted to &#x20AC;10,336 million during the first half. It's a 21% growth versus H1 2010. Before looking at the organic performance, let's look at scope and ForEx. ForEx is slightly negative, it's 1% negative. That is marginal, but we expect this ForEx impact to be more negative toward the end of the year, as we see a continued depreciation of the dollar versus the euro. Therefore, we can expect a negative impact which will be stronger at the end of the year at the ForEx level.</p>
          <p>Change in scope, it's mainly what Areva is bringing in terms of sales, but it also includes impact of acquisitions such as Uniflair or Lee Technologies. And I am now moving to organic growth, 10.2% during this first half. It was almost 12% during the first quarter. It's almost 9% during the second quarter. So, we kept a very good momentum on our growth.</p>
          <p>By business now, as you can see, industry is clearly leading the chart here with 18% organic growth. Industry business is growing in each region. So, the dynamism is not limited here to new economy. We really see a nice and strong growth everywhere. The competition for industry player is there. There is a need for more productivity. There is a need for energy efficiency and it is clearly developing very nicely as a business.</p>
          <p>If we look at our product, clearly, there is a very strong demand for motion and drive-related product. And if we look at solutions, we have been developing very well our OEM, the machine builder solution business, during this first half.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the other businesses. Power, 9% growth. Power is developing extremely well in new economies. No need to say that there is a nice construction market, well-oriented in new economy, but there is also strong investment in low voltage for infrastructure, for industry that is driving the growth.</p>
          <p>When we look at the metro country, in the U.S., we have seen a rebound, but which is clearly not driven by what we see in the construction, because here, there is no rebound in the U.S. neither in residential nor in non-residential. So, it is what we sell in term of low voltage through the industry and through the data center and market which is the engine of the growth.</p>
          <p>In Europe, there is some positive situations, such as France or Germany, where we see, notably in France, some positive sign in the construction market, although still limited. But we have a big drag with the Spanish situation, which is extremely difficult and significantly negative.</p>
          <p>Moving to the energy performance, 5% organic growth. Energy has been accelerating between Q1 and Q2. Q1 was only marginally positive. So, indeed, we know that this business is more late cycle than many of our other activity. And we are seeing momentum rising notably in new economy, with the project and infrastructure in oil and gas and that is generating a nice increase of the business, 9% organic growth on the second quarter.</p>
          <p>IT business, almost 10% growth through this first half. We are seeing a very nice development of demand for the big system, big data center project, largely related to the development of the cloud. At the same time and notably in the mature country, because situation is still good in the new economy, we see a slowdown in the growth for small systems. So, that is somewhat slowing down the IT performance, which has been still very solid with this 10% growth.</p>
          <p>Buildings, well, I remind you that today, buildings is, I think, the lowest exposure to new economy. So, of course, that is somewhat a disadvantage for this business. Still, a 7% growth during this period. We've seen very strong demand for services and notably, advanced services, so strong added value to our client in the building industry to manage their energy.</p>
          <p>We see a nice development for solution and project around security and we have seen a nice growth in new economy, which is start to develop well and certainly, we are investing a lot there to achieve that. We are seeing projects around energy efficiency in new economy gathering momentum.</p>
          <p>Moving to the performance by region, in fact, apart from Western Europe, we've been reaching double-digit growth in all the other three region. But let's start with the new economy, that is the most striking performance and Asia Pac, of course, as the first one, 17%. We are experiencing a 20% growth plus rate in China, in India and in Southeast Asia during this first half. So, a very strong performance globally on this region. And we are not reaching globally for Asia Pac, this 20%, because the Pacific region has grown at more moderate pace, but otherwise, it's a very powerful performance from Asia Pac during this first half.</p>
          <p>Rest of the world and I stay therefore on new economy, that is one region which actually accelerated between the first quarter and the second quarter. We see very good situation in Latin America and not only even Brazil, Brazil is, of course, very good, but we see Colombia, Chile, Peru doing extremely well. We've seen very strong performance in Russia as well and Middle East has been developing well. Africa, which was negative and very negative during the first quarter, stabilized during the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Now moving to the mature country, North America is 11%. If I look at the U.S., we have continued to deliver strong performance in industry. We have continued to see this rebound I was mentioning on power. On IT, I did mention the situation of a mixed bag between big system and small system. Mexico and Canada were also extremely good.</p>
          <p>Now finishing with Western Europe, very contrasted situation. You have some markets, which has really been developing well, such as Germany, Italy and France. You have markets which are around stability, such as the U.K. and you have the Spanish market, which is significantly negative.</p>
          <p>Now moving to the detail of the P&amp;L, as you can see, this is another six months where we have been able to significantly improve our EBITA margin and of course, I am looking at comparable data here on the right hand part of the chart. As you can see, we reached an EBITA before acquisition and integration cost of &#x20AC;1,413 million. This is 13% growth compared to last year and we have increased our EBITA margin by 40 basis points. We are therefore one more time able to grow our operating profit quicker than our sales. And here, even though at the level of the gross margin, we have been impacted by a very negative headwind linked to the raw material inflation.</p>
          <p>But precisely, this is what I would like to detail now and the various impacts that we have experienced and that led to this performance and improvement in profitability. Of course, the big negative element of this first six months, let's be clear, is absolutely a record negative impact of raw material for the group. I've been looking to the past number and I think the worst performance &#x2013; the worst number that we experienced in the past was a negative element for the full year in 2007 of &#x20AC;260 million. That was for the 2007 year.</p>
          <p>Just in six months, we've experienced a negative raw material impact of &#x20AC;213 million, so something that we have never seen in the past. If you add some other inflation impact, it's 250 million negative. In front of that, I mean we continued to be extremely efficient in delivering productivity and in fact, we almost matched with the productivity this negative element linked to inflation.</p>
          <p>We also put some price increase, 0.5% overall, certainly below what we should have been doing during this first half. Let's be clear. We have been somewhat caught by surprise by the speed and the volatility on the inflation on raw material. It takes some time to put the price increase, to inform the clients to put that through various channel and we are actually being very ambitious for the second half, we'll do much better than that. But we have this 0.5% performance on the first half and we really, in fact, mainly measure, as Jean- Pascal said, the performance on the product business more than on the solution business.</p>
          <p>Then we have a mix impact, which has been negative, not surprisingly. As we are growing into the solution business, we know that we are having a negative impact at the level of the margin, but we don't see that as an issue, let's be clear. This growth in solution is increasing our top line dynamism. This is extra EBIT generated and this is extra cash generated for the company, so the fact that it is having a negative impact on the EBIT margin mechanically is not a negative element. It's just something mechanical that we have to take into account.</p>
          <p>Now in front of this evolution of the gross margin, we have been able to grow our support function costs at a lower pace than our sales, 7% organic growth for our support function costs, more than 10% for our top line, a differential of three points between top line and our cost, and that shows two things. The first one, of course, is that we've been impacted by inflation. That's around &#x20AC;90 million impact, but that also we took the decision, again very consistently, to keep investing for the future growth of Schneider Electric, and that explains why we have this growth of 7%.</p>
          <p>This is extremely well planned, we know where we are investing in businesses such as IT, in businesses such as building. We know the geographies where we want to invest to be stronger tomorrow, and again, I mean, we are certainly in an adverse environment in some dimension, we are showing that this is something we can do and continue to do efficiently in the future.</p>
          <p>Now looking at the profitability by business, you see that globally, you have three categories of performance. First one and star, Industry, which is increasing very nicely, its profitability 2.3 points. Here, of course you have the growth impact which is playing positively. The fact that probably industry has been less impacted than other by the raw material inflation and that is, of course, playing. And the fact that this is not a business where the solution are the most important and where they are representing the IS share.</p>
          <p>Second category, businesses where we have stable margin as a case of power and energy and here, we have been able to compensate the inflation for raw material. And then two negative evolution of profitability, IT and Building. This is, of course, the weight of solutions for these two businesses. This is the raw material inflation and this is, again, the very conscious decision that we need to invest for the future in these two businesses and that is, of course, having an impact on the profitability at new economies here.</p>
          <p>Now very quickly down to the end of the P&amp;L, &#x20AC;41 million of integration cost. This is mainly not Areva cost, but costs that we have incurred through the various acquisition that we have announced. More specific comment on amortization of intangibles very much in line with last year, with the Areva part in addition.</p>
          <p>Net financial expenses, it's growing compared to last year, but the reality is that cost of our debt, what we have been paying in term of financial interest, is &#x20AC;10 million lower than last year, so we keep reducing the cost of our debt. The reason for this increase is a pure ForEx impact. Last year, we had a &#x20AC;40 million positive impact in the first half, this year, we have a &#x20AC;20 million negative impact, so it's a &#x20AC;60 million difference, which explains the deterioration of the financial expenses line. Income tax, very much stable, we are at 24% and we believe that we should finish the year around the 24% income tax rate for the group.</p>
          <p>Taking into account equity investment, minority interest, that lead us to our net income group share, which reached &#x20AC;802 million. It's almost a 10% growth compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Now moving to the free cash flow and that clearly deserve a significant explanation, because that is something extremely specific that happened during this first half. First of all, a general comment. We build most of our cash flow during the second half of the year. I mean, we have the seasonality on the cash flow generation and if we look in the past, we have been consistently generating between 60% and 80% of our cash flow during the second part of the year. And that will continue to be the case.</p>
          <p>Now on top of that, there is some non-recurring element that has been impacting this first half and that we do intend to correct during the second half of the year. The big drift, in fact, is coming from the working capital, which in total is almost growing by &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>If I look first on our trade working capital, it's a &#x20AC;770 million growth of our need in working capital, with the first reason behind that, of course, is the growth of the activity, 10% growth, very sustained top line and that is having some impact mechanically on the level of our working capital. But on top of it, as Jean-Pascal explained, we consciously took the decision in order to ensure the delivery of our client to increase the level of inventory and we saw that it was something that we could support on the provisional basis in order to make sure that we would not be losing sales.</p>
          <p>And as a matter of fact, I think that first of all, we have not been impacted. But we have seen some clients coming to us and saying that they were facing difficulty with some other supplier. Which means that certainly you know, that's a decision that have been helping us, and in terms of relation with the client, that has been perceived very positively. Probably also some elements that much more marginal on the receivable that will be collected at the end of the year. And that explains the total evolution of the trade working capital.</p>
          <p>Now in addition, we have a &#x20AC;200 million negative impact on the non-trade working capital and here it's, of course, the sum of various elements, very significant bonuses and premiums that have been accrued for at the end of 2010 on the back of a very good year for the employees that we paid during this first half. Some tax element as well that has been playing. Some cost and charges that had been booked and provisioned and that we paid in terms of guarantee and so on during this quarter. So, that explains this amount. We do expect, again, the total impact to be much lower toward the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Last, but it's also a meaningful element, which is that we are increasing our capital expenditure amount. We are growing from &#x20AC;218 million last year to &#x20AC;329 million. We are back to something more normal in terms of CapEx, around 3% of sales. And this is, I think, a &#x20AC;100 million negative impact. So, that is really all these elements together that accounts for this negative free cash flow during the first half. Something again that has to be seen as a one-off and something that will be corrected during the second part of the year.</p>
          <p>Facing the dividend that we have paid, the acquisition, sorry, not finished yet. Thank you. Taking the dividend, acquisition, capital increase and other elements, we have a debt which is slightly below &#x20AC;4.5 billion at the end of June 2011.</p>
          <p>Now this is just to highlight what I have explained, in fact that really, the building up of our working capital during the first half. You have this evolution of inventory and the decision that we have made and this objective, obviously, we have &#x20AC;300 million of excess inventory that will be corrected during the second half of the year. And that is clearly something that we are taking as a top priority during the second half for all the teams.</p>
          <p>We retain a very strong balance sheet. As you can see, our net debt to EBITDA is at a low 1.2 times, so in line with what we had at the end of 2009. The EBITDA reach almost &#x20AC;1.7 billion. And we have more than &#x20AC;2 billion of cash that's included in the balance sheet, so we retain a very healthy balance sheet situation.</p>
          <p>Jean-Pascal, are you ready for the outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. So, while the first thing is to look at our priorities today on &#x2013; I'm going to share an internal document which is where we drive our teams today, we continue to drive organic growth. We've got some very interesting spots of the business with high dynamics. We spoke about the new economies. We spoke about our new activities in major countries. So, we keep capturing new opportunities in energy efficiency, in the smart grid and in the new economies.</p>
          <p>Second point obviously is to ramp up the price actions. And this is about products, which makes 65% of our business. And to as Emmanuel said it, this is principally where we measure the price increases, but it's the control of the margin on the solutions, which are developing faster now. And where we need to make sure and we are working so that we make sure we integrate also the ramp-up of our MI, of raw material inflation, inside the pricing on the delivery of solution.</p>
          <p>Operational efficiency, industrial productivity. SFC on sales, we see something where we've put strong control in H2 as we are now reaching basis of comparison which are bit higher. The fourth point on efficiency would be the reduction of inventories, which we've done last year also to make sure that we drive cash conversion. Now that &#x2013; since now two months, we now understand that the Japanese crisis is not behind us, but that we have mastered the consequences of it on the delivery to our customers.</p>
          <p>And finally, obviously, a lot of focus on the integration of the acquisitions, big or small or medium size and make sure that we deliver synergies.</p>
          <p>So, if you go to slide 28, well, on the top line, most of the Group's end markets expected to continue to develop positively. The markets which are the least favorable are the residential and non-residential markets in the mature markets where we don't expect any much rebound or expect much dynamics. On the other hand, we expect a robust momentum in the new economies, which will continue, but on the basis of higher comps of last year. And we have to integrate globally the higher basis of comparison in H2.</p>
          <p>In terms of profitability, H2 profitability is better than H1 in the typical Schneider profile. We have to go back a long way to find a normal year at Schneider between 2008, 2009, 2010. All those profiles were totally distorted. And but if you come back to the good old years, where the world was, between brackets, normal, we had a far better profit generation and cash generation in H2 and we are kind of back into a more normal year.</p>
          <p>The negative solution product mix on gross margin, but helping on the top line. We are going to accelerate the price actions and we tied the increase, as we said, of 1% of sales to partly offset the raw material headwind that now we estimate at &#x20AC;400 million with the new dynamics of raw material.</p>
          <p>Industrial productivity in excess of &#x20AC;400 million on the basis of good volumes, on the basis of more serenity on the electronics side. And finally, we are going to keep reducing the support function costs to the sales ratio. So, if we have the macro conditions that we have today, we confirm our organic growth target of 6% to 9% and clearly, we would feel comfortable with that guidance with the first half that we have scored.</p>
          <p>Now on the EBITA, we target an EBITA margin this time more around 15%, which is more closer to the bottom of the bracket that we had announced at the beginning of the year and seeing the intensity of what we do in acquisition and the cost incurred, on the inconsistency with what we did last year and it's before acquisition integration cost and related integration of cost of 2011 acquisitions. So, that's about the outlook, good on the top line and on &#x2013; at 15% on the operating margin for the year.</p>
          <p>And now, we are ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we'll now open the Q&amp;A section. And we'll start with questions from the room and after that, we'll take questions, some questions by phone. Olivier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Olivier Esnou, Exane. Maybe two questions. On the growth, if I look at your peer group, they have given a slightly now organic growth. I mean, maybe if you could give us some feeling, having H1 now in the back and some backlog, still even if it's not a future of Schneider, where you feel &#x2013; if you feel a bit more comfortable knowing a little bit that?</p>
          <p>And then on the pricing, the second question. The pricing versus raw mat dynamic, do you think for the year, where you will be in terms of coverage? And this whole material number of &#x20AC;400 million, it is as of when, I mean, using raw material as of when so that we have bit of a feeling if they move from here, where it could go? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the bracket of growth, clearly at the end of H1, we feel, we are well-positioned in this bracket. But we maintain the guidance, because while you seen &#x2013; let's face it, there is some uncertainty in the world of today. There are some debate about the debt in Europe, in the U.S. Although we don't take hypothesis of major ruptures, it's clearly creating some uncertainly. So, we prefer to stay cautious, all right?</p>
          <p>But with 10% in H1 and we have steady backlog actually, probably the highest in terms of amount that we've known. We are entering into H2 with a good momentum. So, that's for the top line. Now if you look at the pricing, Emmanuel said it and I can only confirm. Our ambitious to price up by &#x20AC;200 million. On facing raw material impact of &#x20AC;400 million. And there we have to be quite &#x2013; we &#x2013; it takes some time to pass the price increases through the chain. That's the first thing.</p>
          <p>And probably, we didn't see at the beginning of the year the magnitude of the raw material impact, actually. When we started in February, we were more around &#x20AC;200 million. One month after during the road shows, we almost became about 200, 250 on that. I don't think the operations, our operations, I have to confess, saw it enough. We are not proactive in pushing the price.</p>
          <p>What has been passed on the products, on the transaction is sticking. I think there is so much pressure anyway for everybody that I see the environment as favorable to make the ability. Now we have also to humbly say is that we measure the price increases mostly on the product part of the business, the transactions, while on the 35% of our business which is solution, it's about margin control. And there, what has happened is a surge of the solutions and tangentially, we have taken larger projects in the first half with a lower gross margin. So, that has had most of the impact on the gross margin you've seen in the first half has been coming more on the change of mix on the average margin and solution rather than the price on products.</p>
          <p>So, we work actively on it. It's a question of disparities, it's a question of time to go through the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one follow-up maybe, &#x20AC;200 million coverage out of &#x20AC;400 million, how should we read that? Is it just a timing issue, i.e. next year, normally if raw materials stay flat, we have a &#x20AC;200 million excess. Or is it a fact that it's &#x2013; you don't think you should cover it for some growth competitive strategy decision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, actually, we have a carryover effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you have a carryover.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you refer to the past, this is what has happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Every time we have a price increase, it took us some time to catch up because of time line. And this is probably something we have to learn better in the future is to react faster and in a more productive way. Now face it, it has been brutal. It's been &#x2013; as Emmanuel was saying, probably it's the double and twice faster than what we knew before. So, we didn't see everything. We didn't appreciate it to this magnitude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ga&#xEB;l?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, Ga&#xEB;l De Bray from SocGen. I've got a couple of questions, actually. The first one on the free cash flow, especially on the inventory line, the inventory to sales ratio was 16% last year in H1. It's now 17.8% and even if you include the expected &#x20AC;300 million of reduction in inventories you're targeting in the second half, it seems that the ratio is going to be still above 16%, while I would have expected the ratio to gradually come down, given the move towards solutions. So, can you explain a bit more what's going on there? And if there is I don't know somewhere a plan maybe to go below the 16% mark at some stage?</p>
          <p>The second question is, well, actually, this is about the activity in H2, do you think there could have been some pre-buying in the first half of the year in anticipation of the price actions you're taking for the second half? And whether this could &#x2013; well, there would be a recap of slowdown in the second half?</p>
          <p>And my third question would be about M&amp;A, how do you feel about acquisitions at the moment? I mean, how do you judge your integration capabilities, because you have done so many deals over such a short timeframe. Don't you think it's really time to slow down the pace of acquisitions just to refocus on integration and wait quite a long time before doing something else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll start by the last subject. On acquisitions, we have been as you said, very active in the first half, those operations came at maturity at the same time. So, and we were working on some of those files for some time. I mean, we have been following them, developing the relationship, negotiating them for some time. So, now, is it absolutely outside of the reason, we had for instance in 2007, 2008 to take out Areva D and Telvent? No. We were probably spread on three quarters rather than two quarters, but this is where we are.</p>
          <p>Now, the integration of those companies are really taking place in the local operations and you know that there is a lot that has been done in the new economies and the local management is really in charge with the specific follow-up. Now we've got two cases that need more bandwidth, Areva D, which is still in process and which takes time, because now, the split with Alstom has been very well done and it's been done according to plan.</p>
          <p>Now we are in the very practical things of legal contracts, legal entities, IT systems, the sweaty and complicated work that you have to do in an acquisition and that's going to take some time and we've been very vocal about that. And by the way it was, all this time had been totally integrated in the plan. Now, if you say, what is the focus? The focus is clearly to integration. There has been this concentration of elements coming in the first half. I'm personally very happy that we are going to be spending more time on operations and integration in the second half, because I like it. So, that's very clear.</p>
          <p>Now, on your second question, which is the pre-buy duty to supply chain issues, principally, or the price increases. It has been maybe bit of that, but I don't think too much because everybody has been attentive to the stock levels also. There has been, I think, more stock making around the electronics supply chain issues. There, we have seen a kind of &#x2013; yeah, certainly some strange behaviors at time. We've tried to limit them not to create ourselves to propagate that back to our suppliers who are already struggling, in some cases. But we find that it's not very meaningful. At this stage, we are looking at the stock on the inventory of our distributors and we don't find them out of whack. I mean, just it doesn't seem to be totally unreasonable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just maybe I'll take your first question, Ga&#xEB;l, on the level of inventory. We're not saying that we are going to be back at the end of the year to the kind of ideal situation and certainly, there is still things that we can do on the long-term and it's an ongoing work.</p>
          <p>So, you can be sure that we will keep working on the efficiency of the supply chain and level of inventory. And certainly, as we are entering into a new company program next year, but in due time, we'll come back on that. That will be a very important element to make sure that we keep generating some improvement at that level through simplification, through better organization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to give also some color, we are in the transition of the supply change. We are in the transition from Hal Grant to Annette Clayton, so there was a lot of work of passing the stick over the past three months. And Annette is fully in charge and is totally dedicated towards the topics we are mentioning. Hal has made the good work of maintaining the supply chain during the Japanese crisis and it was sometimes complicated and Annette now is strongly focused on making sure that our inventories is coming down to the level where it should be in regard to the operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please. Okay, Ludovic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Ludovic Debailleux, Natixis. Two quick questions, first of all a follow-up on the free cash flow. Simply, could you help us to quantify the kind of free cash flow for sales that you are focusing for the full year, assuming that the level of inventory is normalizing and taking into account as a seasonal effect? And second question, the growth and momentum in emerging are very robust. Do you see any sign of overheating in any specific country or do you believe that the trend is sustainable in the medium term? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the free cash flow, I suggest that you make a quite simple exercise of taking your assumption of the EBIT on the second part of the year. Of course, you have several dimension that you have to estimate in term of growth of our top line, because it is having some impact on the evolution of the working capital. You take this &#x20AC;300 million reduction, and I guess you can anticipate that we'll also work on the level of receivable.</p>
          <p>I think that we've been clear on the fact that we are back to more normal investment pattern regarding the CapEx and that will give you probably a pretty good idea of the cash flow in the second half and, therefore, for the full year. You should also probably factor in some improvement at the level of the non-operating working capital. We do believe that the impact will be lower than the &#x20AC;200 million negative that we have seen on the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the new economies, we see a strong momentum now comparing to a more demanding basis of comparison. So, that would be the main adjustment. I would expect also some cool-down in China, because you are at the end of the stimulus package or kind of the end of the stimulus package and the restriction of &#x2013; on credit, but we have good dynamics in China. And as we go west, as we go into the secondary cities, as we leveraged fully our capital presence, we find new ways of growth. But again, comparing to a more demanding basis and with probably an expected cool-down to come, that we don't see too much today in our figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alfred?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Alfred Glaser, Cheuvreux. Coming back to that geography you just mentioned, could you be a bit more specific on growth rate in China in Q2? And what could be the growth rate in Q3, Q4 going forward? And geographically, could you also comment on your sales evolution in the Middle East and North Africa. You said that the region was doing pretty well, could you be a bit more specific on this?</p>
          <p>Then two questions on the cost and margins. Could you give us the margin level of Areva Distribution in the first half of 2011? And on cost cuts and productivity gains, given the complex situation you are facing this year, could you extend or amplify the cost reduction and productivity targets of the one program particularly going into 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on China, we are not specific on every zone, but it's above the average of Asia Pac, so very strong and very dynamic today. And for the rest, for the perspective, I was clear enough, I think, in my previous answer. Middle East is doing well with very high contrast between region Dubai, which is still an Emirate, which is still down, Emirates, and other places which are doing far better, Saudi Arabia being one example. What we do in Turkey is also very good. So, but globally, Middle East is doing well.</p>
          <p>Looking at Africa, as Emmanuel said it, this is the only negative place and this is due to what we have in North Africa, which is &#x2013; we had a strong position and we have a strong position in Egypt, which is going through low activity at the moment and traditionally, we see also some strong position in North Africa.</p>
          <p>On South Africa, which at the moment is weak for reasons which are linked to the global macro environment there. But we expect Africa, where we have a strong presence, where we have a capital presence on the peer presence to rebound once the revolutions will be clarified and the new political powers will be in place. Today, we've resized on like in these cases, like it happens in the new economies, we are waiting for the new environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the margin of Areva D, no, in fact, we are no longer able to split that because really, the business is merged, so we are not able to say what was previously Areva and what is now Schneider. We have even the part of the range which has been rebranded Schneider and therefore, it's totally merged now and we are not able to differentiate. So, you have to look at the energy business as a combined thing and as we have seen, the margin has been stable during the first half.</p>
          <p>Regarding the cost reduction and productivity under one program, well, let's be clear, we have the ambition on the long-term and on a very regular basis to generate significant productivity. That means 3% to 5% on a regular basis. So, what you are seeing in during this year is not a one-off. I am not going to guarantee that the amount will be north of &#x20AC;400 million next year as well. But we certainly expect to generate significant productivity in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have been very vocal always and there is still a lot to do in the supply chain, especially on the upstream part with our suppliers. Concentration of our network is happening. Today, it's generating not so much productivity, because by the time you do it, you generate also a lot of cost, but when it's operating and it's really coming, then we should find new ways of simplifying and getting productivity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we'll take one last question from the room and then we will start taking questions by phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, <mark type="indiscernible" />. I am from Natixis, but on the investment banking side, not on the research side. One question, you mentioned on one of your slides as that when monitoring M&amp;A transaction, you want return on capital employed to exceed WACC within three years. So, one question, what is your targeted WACC level? And could you consider divesting businesses if they were to fail to meet your targeted return on capital employed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we have today a WACC which is slightly above 8%, that is WACC of the Group. I think that we can generally certainly consider to sell businesses. I mean, the portfolio of Schneider is the leading portfolio. And what has been relevant at the given moment will lose relevance in the future, be less connected with the evolution, the direction that we are giving to the Group. So, that's an exercise that we are permanently doing. And therefore, we don't discard the possibility that we will be selling businesses in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, we'll start...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not all about working. It's about strategy, customer needs, and a lot of other things which are more managerial. But clearly we are always looking at our portfolio and seeing what is the most fit to keep for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, first question by phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>You have a question from Andreas Willi from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks for taking my question. My first question is on inventory. You had a very good drop through rate on your volume growth in the first half of this year, was this also partly due because you overproduced relative to what you sold, so maybe you could give us the year-on-year increase in production volume relative to the year-on-year increase in your sales volume?</p>
          <p>And the second question, on your IT business in terms of the small systems, which were weaker, is that the reason why the profitability is maybe a bit weaker or are there any changes in the competitive environment in general also in the larger systems?</p>
          <p>And lastly, on guidance, maybe you could tell us what we should expect for restructuring and acquisition costs for the ones already announced for the full year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the inventory level, we have been retreating what we have been producing and not selling, i.e. the productivity that you have here is a net productivity, if I may say, in that respect. So, we don't have a kind of increased productivity, because we would have been overproducing. That is not taken into account and we benefit from that in the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For our IT business, clearly, there has been a change of mix and this is really a story of cycle first. We know that in this business, the early cycle are the small products, the network and the business network products, which are the one-phase products. And then we were building last year and we spoke about that recurrently, we are building the pipeline for data centers.</p>
          <p>And data centers come with a different business model. As you know, you get a project with a low margin and then you make a profit through the services that are from data centers and we are in this phase where we do proportionally less transactional on one-phase products. Taking the projects and generating in the future more services. We have not seen ruptures on the competitive conditions today on the market. We've launched our new products in smart ups in smaller products, where as always, at the ramp up of the products, you've got the ramp, you've got the productivity to install or the right cost to install, but it's been marginal on all things. But we have not seen big changes.</p>
          <p>Last thing that we &#x2013; I have to say that North America, for one phase products, the market has been not as good as last year. Clearly, it has been &#x2013; it's linked to servers and the market of servers has not been as favorable for the one-phase product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, just on your last question, thank you for giving me the opportunity to clarify one more time that the guidance is on the EBITA, so it's a clean EBITA. So, after cost of restructuring with only one caveat, which are these acquisition and integration costs for the very reason that of course, we could not anticipate them at the beginning of the year. But really, the guidance is on the EBITDA after restructuring cost.</p>
          <p>For the restructuring cost, the best assumption I can take at that time is that it will be in line with what we have had last year, roughly speaking. I don't think I can be more precise than that at that stage. And on acquisition cost, as we don't know yet, we have still a number of projects which are expecting approval. There is a number of costs still going on. I'm not able today to clarify what could be the impact for the full year. We'll do that as soon as we have a clear view on them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll now have the second question by phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is by Mr. Martin Prozesky from Bernstein, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a few questions, please. In terms of pricing, I just want to get back to that. Did you take any price increases in H1 at all? Because there was a bit of a price increase on the bridge, but it seemed quite small, and did you have any problems taking prices?</p>
          <p>And on the commodity side of that question, is it copper, steel, plastics where you're seeing the biggest pressure or are there other surprising areas? We've seen some other companies' array of metals, silver, surprising on input costs. Are there are other problems that you see on input costs?</p>
          <p>And the second question on Telvent. How much of the business that you acquired would you need to sell, having now looked at the business in detail, how much of the business do you expect to keep?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin, I have the impression that on the pricing, I think we've already answered several times the questions through several ways. So, in a nutshell, raw material inflation was higher farther than what we were expecting at the beginning of the year. On the products, we are passing prices, we are keeping on passing prices, adjusting now, it takes some time. You get the cost before you get the prices through and we are glad you could &#x2013; we should have been more proactive probably on that thing, on the path. And we say that familiar to pricing, principally on the product side, which is 65% of the business. But I don't want to come back into all the details.</p>
          <p>And the commodities that impacted us, there is a part of plastic but it's certainly not the dominating part. What was the most dominating in H1 was copper and was silver. And some were in other inflations. We had the transportation cost, because we are global company, we transfer products and that goes with oil and oil is not a cheap thing anymore, which by the way, is very good for our energy efficiency activity.</p>
          <p>On Telvent, go back to the acquisition, fine. But we are interested for Telvent for all of Telvent. That is participating to what we do in the smart grid, in the water applications, in the oil and gas application. We are going to deal with the transportation issues in the field of what we do in smart cities. And I remind you that we do numbers of tuners, city infrastructure, especially in the new economies, where the new cities are born, that our customers are asking us operation management with a lot of data aggregation, where the IT capability of Telvent will help us for everything which is real-time IT.</p>
          <p>And even there is one activity there, which is weather forecast, as you say, what Schneider is doing, weather forecast. It just happens that we use this and we use today weather forecast services in our present systems to adapt the management of our renewable of the buildings on certain number of water applications.</p>
          <p>So, what we see in Telvent is a very good fit for the whole business of Schneider. I remind you also that this acquisition is still in process and that we would stick to what we have said at the moment of the acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Simon Smith from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead. Mr. Smith, your line is open. Please go ahead with the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. My first question really relates back to the topic of restructuring charges and how we look at them. I mean, obviously, there has been apart from the change in the numbers of guidance, there has been a modification of the basis of it. And I just wanted to work out exactly what we should include and shouldn't include in the numbers?</p>
          <p>So, I mean, last year we had about &#x20AC;100 million of restructuring charges, this year, we've been looking again for &#x20AC;100 million of restructuring charges, but now, we have a sort of dual definition of a restructuring charge, ones that are related to actual acquisitions and ones that aren't. In terms of the absolute number, either if you could confirm whether that's still the &#x20AC;100 million that we should be looking at? And then obviously in the first half out of restructuring of &#x20AC;43 million, &#x20AC;41 million has actually been related to acquisitions. I wondered if you could give as well a sort of feel for the absolute number, what that split would be for the second half? So, that'd be my first question.</p>
          <p>I think the second question really, just coming back to pricing, I just noted you changed some of your assumptions from the first quarter call. I mean, I understand the raw material and to be honest with you, a move from 350 to 400 is not that surprising, but before you've been talking about doing some circa 1% price increases, and then in Q1, you said that you'd do in excess of that. And the reason that that's now not happening, is that because you tried in some areas and it wasn't possible? Or just you went back and looked at the plan and realize that in the time scales you had and the windows of opportunity, it just wasn't possible to get them in? Just interested to see whether there has been any evidence of price failure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You take back the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, which is very much what I answered to Andreas and there is a clear differentiation, restructuring costs. When we talk about the restructuring cost of &#x20AC;100 million that we had last year, it's what we do within the group to permanently optimize the structure of the group to manage a difficult situation here or there. And to have the group as fit as possible permanently. So, it's really purely internal.</p>
          <p>Again, we are not giving guidance which is before the restructuring costs this year. So, when we are giving this around 15% EBITA margin objective, that is after discussed of restructuring. I am clear on that. And then, we are not changing the guidance, but when you start the year, frankly speaking, you have no idea of what the M&amp;A business is going to be, what the M&amp;A activity is going to be, which kind of cost you are going to incur. And it can be very small at the end of the year or very big if something has emerged as an important acquisition.</p>
          <p>So, by nature, I would say we are simply not able to forecast that as it cannot be included in the guidance. So, that's just what we are clarifying here and I hope that those things are absolutely are crystal clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On pricing, back to pricing, it's really to cut a long story short, it's really more a story of timing so far. And you say that on &#x2013; yeah, but it's really a question of timing. I mean, it takes time to get the pricing through and again, we should have been probably more faster to implement our price increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is by Mr. Martin Wilkie from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey good morning. It's Martin Wilkie at Deutsche Bank. Just a question on your support function costs. You talked about reducing that ratio into the second half of the year. Historically, those costs have grown at roughly two-thirds the label of your revenue growth. But I wondered if you could just talk around how much you think you can reduce that by? And obviously in the first half of the year, you hit both by the growth investment and the inflation side of things and if you could just perhaps split how you are looking to target those two pieces separately? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Martin, well, inflation is above 3.5%, so that is globally what we see as an average and of course, when we look at new economy, we are certainly more in the 4% to 6% range, on average, and it's lower in the mature country. So, that is inflation part, which is there. Now, we've been very active in investing in the first half. Our sense is that we will probably be less active in the second part of the year, so the global growth of the SFC will be closer to the inflation number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And most of the investment, again, was in new economies, developing, building on the IT, the IT business into the new economies. They are bit less strong in those new economies on steel services in mature countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mrs. Daniela Costa from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks for taking the question. I just wanted to clarify something on the outlook on the comment between H2 and H1 profitability seasonality. I think on EPG, you have mentioned that in 2010, if Areva had been fully integrated in the portfolio, the first half margin would have been close to 13% and then the full year, close to 14.5%, which implies around a 300 basis point seasonality for H1 versus H2 in 2010. Why is this &#x2013; why is your expectation that the seasonality profile is now slightly different, is my question, basically. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wasn't at EPG, Jean-Pascal, so I am not able to fully react -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was saying that integrating pro forma Areva, H1 was close to 13%, actually, it's 13.3%. So, now you can have the real figure, it's 13.3%. So, when we reach 13.7%, it makes 40 basis points of improvement. On the full year, the pro forma of last year full year was 14.5%, full year, okay.</p>
          <p>So, traditionally, when you go back to 2007, there was a high seasonality and there is a high seasonality in the profile of Schneider in terms of profitability, where H1 was below the H2, the total year profitability and therefore, H2 profitability by quite a lot. And actually, what I say that Areva was accentuating this profile, because for Areva D, it's even more different. There is even a bigger gap between H1 and H2. H2 is far higher than H1. This is what I was saying. So, this year, we are integrating and you can see it when I said last year that it would have been 13.3% in 2010 in H1 including Areva and 14.5% on the full year. You realize that Areva is making it even more seasonal.</p>
          <p>And the big reason is that there is a part of this business which is linked to utilities and utilities tend to order more and buy more at the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we'll now take the last question and then we'll close today's conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question comes from Mr. James Moore from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning everybody. It's James Moore at Redburn Partners. I've got three questions. Going back to Simon's question on restructuring versus acquisition costs, I have to say I am confused. I think you are saying that there was both &#x20AC;41 billion of acquisition costs and separately, &#x20AC;43 million of restructuring costs in the first half. But what I don't understand is why in your report on page 28, you say you have &#x20AC;1,415 million of EBITDA, but you say you have &#x20AC;1,413 million of EBITA and that seems to be only &#x20AC;2 million difference between the two, so it looks as if the acquisition costs, the &#x20AC;41 million are part of the &#x20AC;43 million and not separate. Could you just clarify on that?</p>
          <p>Secondly, it looks like your margin on acquisitions is about 1% in the half and 5% if you exclude the integration costs. I presume some of that is Areva, but as we go into the second half, is 5% a sensible underlying margin for acquisition contribution?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, could you say what the EBITA margin in the first half was in solution, because the last years, you talked about the margin dilution solution. It's hard to know whether that's got worse or better or roughly where it is today? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James, to clarify, although I am not totally sure to understand what is not clear, I mean, if you should start from the EBITA before acquisition and integration costs the &#x20AC;1,413 million, you decrease if you move to page 22 by &#x20AC;41 million, which is acquisition and integration charges, precisely the majority related to all the cost linked with our acquisition this year.</p>
          <p>Then you have &#x20AC;98 million of amortization of intangibles and that gives you the EBIT number. So, in fact, we don't show here the restructuring cost, which are taken into account to get to the &#x20AC;1,413 million. I hope this clarifies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Does it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am being slow, it doesn't. I'll come back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very happy to take that offline. The other question was on contribution of acquisition, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that on that one, frankly speaking, the biggest one being the Telvent and Leader &amp; Harvest, we don't know when we're going to close this transaction, so we are not able to say what will be the impact. That will be probably the biggest impact on the second half, and therefore, we're not able to say what will be the contribution from the acquisition during the second half. So, again, as soon as we have a certainty for Q3 number, we'll have better idea, we'll clarify that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Finally on solutions, the margin that we do this first half on solution in respect to what we are doing last year is below. The gross margin actually is close to two points below and it's coming from two facts, James. The first one is a typology on the mix of the projects we have addressed. As solutions grew, we are going on &#x2013; it depends year-on-year. But on typically larger projects, which are bit lower in margin, but normally they generate more service in the second phase, and also due to the RMI impact, because a large part of those solutions which is a project related would be around panels, equipments and those equipments has very high density in copper, in raw materials, and we again, and I don't come back on that, we didn't price enough of the cost into the execution of those projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think this was the last question. I'd like to thank you for attention, your questions. And we're going to be back to you very soon with road shows, where we're going to able to give more color and details about all the elements that you raised today and the questions you asked to us. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>