<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1279804" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>FY 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7870</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Jean-Pascal Tricoire, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Emmanuel Babeau, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Carina Ho</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Olivier Esnou</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Ga&#xEB;l de Bray</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Martin Prozesky</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Andreas Willi</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Simon Smith</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">James Moore</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Vidya Adala</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Andrew Carter</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">James Stettler</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Good morning, everybody. Thank you for being here. [French language] So today we are connected through this webcast, which is a new experience at least for this end-of-year conference. I'd like now to start the presentation.</p>
          <p>And we're going to go this morning &#x2013; and I'm in Slide Three for the people following us on the phone. Today what I would like to go through is a quick overview of Schneider, then lead you through a strategy and business update at the end of 2009. Then finance presentation, that will be done by Emmanuel. And then I will come back for the outlook on next year. Carina here will take care of sorting the questions and making sure that the process of questions-and-answers is properly and orderly driven.</p>
          <p>So let's go first to the first part of my presentation, and I'm going to fly over the first four slides because I believe that people who are online this morning are all very knowledgeable of our company. So well, the next slide, Slide Five are explaining that the main characteristics of Schneider. And when you think of Schneider, you should think of a global company of which the first markets are the U.S. and China, a company which has a diversified exposure to end markets.</p>
          <p>And if you go to Slide Six, a company which is very specialized, everything we do is focused on energy management, making energy safe, reliable, efficient, productive and green. Going on to Slide Seven, a company which has an intense commitment to research and development, 5% of our turnover, 8,000 engineers actually across the world.</p>
          <p>On Slide Eight, a company that believes, and I believe, that sustainable development is not only a duty but a key differentiator for our company. Now I move to Slide Nine and actually would like to remind you that our company is uniquely positioned to catch major market opportunities of our generation. And two major opportunities are the energy challenge, and we are the company of energy management and we are particularly the company of energy efficiency.</p>
          <p>And as a second time, we have a very well-rooted capular presence in new economies which are at the end of 2009, 34% of our sales. BRICs, the new economies, will be four among the top five world economies by 2050. You still have in the worldwide 1.6 billion people who don't have access to electricity and to energy. So our strong footprint in new economies, more than 40,000 employees from 18,000 five years ago, is a strong asset for the future.</p>
          <p>Next slide also expresses that if you think of Schneider as the company of energy management and especially of energy efficiency, and the company of new economies, we are also uniquely positioned in the core of the subject of the smart grid. So smart grid is addressing all the aspects of the energy continuum, from generation to consumption.</p>
          <p>And we are very well positioned today to address first, the introduction of renewables on the grid, which we address easily in the centralized manner for solar farms, wind farms, but also on a decentralized station, like for instance addressing the need to put panels on the roof of buildings. We are very well positioned to drive energy efficiency in every segment of consumption, building, industry, infrastructure and homes. This is a place we address today not tomorrow. This is a place that we address nowadays.</p>
          <p>We are working a lot on the infrastructure for electric vehicles, which is a new challenge for the grid. This is a volatile and individual form of consumption, which is coming up and nothing today is equipped to received those new electric vehicles.</p>
          <p>And finally, we are exceptionally well positioned to address real-time grid management and especially the acquisition of Areva Distribution is reinforcing what we do already in this sector. So when you think of the smart grid, Schneider is well positioned not to address a slice of the smart grid but to address all the aspects of the variation of the changes happening in the smart grid.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to move on to the subject of today, which is really 2009. And if I would like to summarize 2009, it's been a year of operational reactivity to the crisis, point one. And an intense year of preparation of the future with the launch and execution of the first year of our plan, One Schneider.</p>
          <p>So if I address &#x2013; I'm going to go through, as called for, certain number of subjects but first I'm going to focus on the results, the operational results of 2009. And again, it has been a reaction and resilience to the crisis. Second I'm going to address the three axis of One, the three transformations of One, one solution provider, our investment in new economies and creating one global company. And finally I'm going to also address subject of research and development, which is a place where we've not reduced our investment. We've maintained our investment in 2009.</p>
          <p>So moving on to Slide 12, what happened in 2009. One year ago when we faced you to launch One and to give the perspective about the market, we said that we had little visibility, which was real, and that our sales would decline by minus five to minus 15. Actually what we faced was a decline of our sales of minus 15.7.</p>
          <p>And in our portfolio of sales what we could see very clearly that solutions, which is a strong strategic axis of development for ourselves for us, has resisted better than the rest of the group. So solutions were only minus 10 and better than the average of the Group. Our new economies went down by 9%, better than the average of the Group. So both solutions and new economies were strong motors of resilience, strong engines of resilience throughout 2009.</p>
          <p>What was our reaction? We gave the total priority to cash management. When I faced my teams at the beginning of the year I said, this year it's going to be cash first, second, profitability, third, volume, but make sure that we manage correctly the cash and we protect the cash. For two reasons, first to make sure in a very unpredictable situation, make sure that we would exit, we would pass through the storms without problems. And second, make sure that we would exit the shock that we were predicting in 2009 in a very strong cash and balance sheet position to make sure that we would manage to out profit the next phase of the crisis.</p>
          <p>So what have we done? We've reduced our cost in terms of support function costs and productivity in a very aggressive manner to make sure that we would reposition ourselves, restructure ourselves, to make sure that we will exist the crisis far leaner and far more efficient than at the beginning of the crisis.</p>
          <p>We've spoken to you about the flexibility on the CapEx from 15 to 20%. Actually we reduced our CapEx by 27% and we've adapted our working trade &#x2013; our trade working capital by 20%, which is beyond the decline of sales. So for that, the teams that we have around the world have shown a great responsibility and reactivity.</p>
          <p>In terms of financial milestones, we committed within a bracket of sales from minus five to minus 15%, a decrease of minus to 15%, to maintain an EBITA margin before restructuring of 12%. Actually what we achieved is to deliver 12.9% at the end of 2009, one point better than our commitment.</p>
          <p>What is striking is the record high cash flow coming from the CapEx and the working capital management, and therefore the conversion of cash on the net adjusted income, which is reaching a record high of 186%. Both cash flow and cash conversion are by far the historical record of our company.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Slide 13 where the cash generation, if you take a view over the decade, has structurally improved a lot. At the beginning of the decade we're producing a cash flow and sales which was between three, let's say, to 6%. Now we're regularly between eight and this time 12% of our sales. And you see that has been really restructural and coming from the improvement of our business model that we've worked on over the past years.</p>
          <p>We &#x2013; it doesn't appear on this slide, but if you look at the EBITAR, EBIT before amortization and restructuring, again its 12.9 in 2009. If you would look at the same parameter in the last crisis, 2003 &#x2013; 2002, 2003, this same EBITAR would have been at 12%, so we have increased or improved our EBIT before restructuring of one point with one difference. Last crisis was a decrease of sales of 7% in two years. In this case it was 16% in one year, so clearly the reactivity and the flexibility or the company has drastically or dramatically improved.</p>
          <p>One thing which is important also due to this fantastic cash generation is that we exit with a debt below three billion. So the debt decreased by 38% and we really come outside of the crisis with a very solid balance sheet, which is good at the time we're making the acquisition of Areva Distribution. And in case as players of our sector are knowing some difficulties, we are in a very good position to keep on consolidating our industry.</p>
          <p>So that's about the results. Now let's look at One. And, I mean, the One seems now so much part of our daily life that we just forget we just launched it one year ago. Three-years program, we're at the end of the first year of the implementation of One. Remind you the key elements of One, I'm in Slide 14, become or grow our solution-provider part of the business, become leader in new economies in our businesses and build a more simple and more global company.</p>
          <p>Well on the side of solution provider, we launched EcoStruxure, which is our integrated system addressing all the segments that we are touching, data center, building, industry, infrastructure and home. This has been launched this year. Well what we've seen in 2009 is that green has become a reality. Copenhagen, people can criticize and spend a lot of time speaking about the pluses and minus of Copenhagen, but you can't go to any company, you can't go to any country which doesn't have the green and energy efficiency at the top if its agenda.</p>
          <p>So the world has returned a corner in 2009 and clearly, apart from very, very marginal people, everybody is working on the carbon footprint and in the energy-efficiency part of the equation. And we've delivered quite a lot of innovation in offers and solution. The most part of the innovation is really coming into the plug-and-play integration of all our systems into a unique and integrated system, EcoStruxure, which doesn't exist anywhere else.</p>
          <p>Second, and as you know we estimate that solutions should grow more than 5% above the world GDP in the next coming years. When we look at a leader in new economies, we've kept on investing and kept on our penetration in the new economies. The first part of what we did in new economies was to transfer production in new economies to be closer to our customers.</p>
          <p>What we are doing here is to invest more into decision centers, R&amp;D, marketing, and we are growing our capabilities in those countries into the white-collar space. We are well on track also to keep on getting more of our production closer to these fast-developing customers and well on track to reach 50% of our production into the new economies.</p>
          <p>Finally, probably the most intense work we did in 2009 is around the one global and simple company. We've worked a lot on the leaner supply chain, on our supplier concentration. We've simplified a lot our G&amp;A functions. We've moved from our 120 brands to be far closer to 10 brands &#x2013; 10 major brands and I tell you that most of it has been done in 2009, so we are more than on-track to reach this objective. And we've put into place our new organization which is not product-driven but customer segment-driven to be able to face the customer and have teams which are totally responsible of putting all the capabilities of Schneider in front of one customer by segment, by building, by industry segment, by infrastructure segment.</p>
          <p>Going a bit more into details for solution providers, as you see, solutions were a model of resilience, plus 6% respect to the average of the group. Solutions are now making 32% of the sales of the group on &#x2013; inside the solution services themselves on the installed base make 11% of our turnover. I remind you that services were pretty much nothing in our sales five or six years ago, that we worked intensively on that &#x2013; on that intensely on that and that the results are coming upon services are profitable.</p>
          <p>To make this solution approach more competitive and to make sure that we are more competitive than our competition in supplying those solutions, we need to have a system which is easier to integrate than any other system in the world, so this is EcoStruxure.</p>
          <p>And I'd like to move you to Slide 16, which explains what is EcoStruxure in a building. We could do exactly the same thing in a plant, we could do exactly the same thing in a piece of infrastructure. But on the left side, you've got what people use to do in the traditional building, where you have got vertical system for power distribution, for air conditioning, for lighting control, for energy control, for access on security control.</p>
          <p>With EcoStruxure, you've got one infrastructure of communication for automation. You've got one repository for all the energy going to the building, one repository for all the processes happening in the building and one repository for security and one repository for video verification.</p>
          <p>We want video to be present in every of our application, because it's a good way not to have many people running across the building or plant to check what is going on. With video, not only you ensure the security but you can use the security infrastructure to check what is going on technically. And therefore, you can reduce your maintenance cost.</p>
          <p>The result of that is that obviously, it is more reliable, because you've got one integrated system. In terms of efficiency, 30% of energy saving on an existing building, on a new building, come to see our headquarter in Paris. You can cut your consumption by a factor of four, so decrease it by 75%. It's less OpEx, minus 30% of OpEx because everything is integrated. It's less CapEx, because everything is integrated, 30% of CapEx reduction.</p>
          <p>And for our customers who are looking for a simple solution, it's one neck to choke. Before on the traditional installation, you had conflicts to resolve between the different providers of the different facilities, while here, they've got one people to speak to on one responsibility, one clear responsibility they can face. That's about solution.</p>
          <p>Next slide is about new economies. If you take a view across the ten past years, the new economies have been growing 9% better than the mature economies. In our portfolio of sales last year, it was 10%. So, new economies are not an engine of growth, but an engine of resilience when times are getting tougher. Well, we've moved, as I said at the end of 2009, 43% of our cost of goods sold into new economies and we are also moving some decision centers to make sure that we understand exactly what's happening there and we are faster in our reaction and reactivity there.</p>
          <p>What we expect is the new economies to grow at GDP, world GDP plus six and we want at the end of our plan 2011 to have transferred 50% of cost of goods sold into the new economies. It is a very, very strong platform that we have in new economies.</p>
          <p>And it's not project sales and it's not export sales, it is sales inside the network. We belong to the network. We, every day, sells thousands of orders or take thousands of orders to thousands of customers through hundreds of intermediaries.</p>
          <p>Slide 18, on moving to one global company, one of the big subjects we had after years of intense growth and intense acquisitions was to make Schneider more simple, more integrated and more global. What we've done &#x2013; we've really used 2009 as we &#x2013; everybody had to get more efficient and to be more efficient on costs this year to change the way we work in Schneider.</p>
          <p>What we learned to do is to specialize by focusing on the end-customer. What we've learned to do is to share a lot, put into place shared services, using globalized functions. What we've learned to do is to collaborate between businesses of Schneider to make sure that we would be able to deliver a full solution for data center, for a building of our plan. That's a real big change.</p>
          <p>What we've kept on doing is to work on the reduction of number of references. You remember we are coming from 1.2 billion. We are now at 466,000 at the end of 2009, big part of it is due to the brand migration. We used to have products labeled under several brands. Now they are all under Schneider Electric and this helps a lot to simplify supply chain. And we've kept on concentrating more of the supply chain purchases into the hands of our key suppliers, who are above 1,000, but it's a strong concentration that we want to bring from 50 to 70% of our purchasing.</p>
          <p>The results are striking. We have achieved 105 million in productivity. That's inside the COGS. That's inside our supply chain and we are on track to achieve 600 million savings target in productivity over the period of three years.</p>
          <p>Now we've also worked on our support function cost without losing efficiency into that, because what we have done is to work in a different manner. This is why we moved really one Schneider into that we call our One organization. Lot of progress done in finance and HR, globalizing the expert functions, working on the mutualization of functions inside geographies, a lot done also in the field of marketing globalization, making sure that there were not too much overlaps into the way we do marketing. We, for instance, merged our many sites on the Web into one site, which is available in multiple languages.</p>
          <p>Worked a lot on foreign sales force effectiveness. We had spoken to you in 2008 of pilots done in the field of sales force effectiveness. We have deployed that now into most of the countries and every time we do that, we gain 10 to 15% in efficiency. On other actions, like we've &#x2013; we are collocating. This is what we did in the west of Paris, concentrated seven offices into one and we are doing that everywhere. We just did that in Delhi. We just did that in Beijing. Every time, it's cost gains and better ability to work together.</p>
          <p>We are globalizing IT. We have globalized IT. We are rationalizing our commercial sites. And again, our brand migration is more than underway. It is well advanced as of today, which means that you remember that at the beginning of the year, we had told you we want to cut our support function costs from 600 million to 1 billion, according to the magnitude of the crisis. After one quarter, we told you our target is to go to 1 billion. In the first year, we did about 541 million of savings, which means 10% of support function costs over the year.</p>
          <p>Again, we've also reengineered our organization to make sure we would focus on our end customers and make sure that we would deliver this capability of one responsibility, dedicated teams in front of one customer need and this is what we've done by the creation, on the alignment of five worldwide divisions, one which is called Power, Industry, IT, Buildings and our Customized Sensors division. These divisions have a double role, serving full solutions for key end-user segments, but also having worldwide responsibility for key lines of products of Schneider.</p>
          <p>When Areva Distribution joins us, we are going to create an energy division that will be made of 1.7 billion of Areva and the 3 billion of Schneider in the field of utilities, oil and gas, and medium voltage and that will create the six pillars of our businesses in Schneider.</p>
          <p>So solution, new economies, one global and simple company for our customers. Now I'd like just to make one slide &#x2013; to go with just one slide about R&amp;D. We've decided, in 2009, to touch every aspect of efficiency and cost in the company but the R&amp;D. We've kept the investment in R&amp;D intact. We've worked on the efficiency, but we've kept the amount of money that we put into the R&amp;D the same, because &#x2013; and we are delivering this year a certain number of innovation. Big part of that R&amp;D spending is into EcoStruxure and the integration of our systems.</p>
          <p>So that for a very busy year, operational reactivity, building the future with the deployment of One and making sure we keep a very strong investment in R&amp;D. And finally, changing the way we work in Schneider. And I would say, at the end of 2009, the company has been putting a different of march with things, at least, are very simple, more simple for our customers. Emmanuel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean-Pascal. Let's now dive into more details regarding the numbers. And let's start with a look at our sales, of course, for the full year and then we'll have a special focus regarding our Q4 numbers.</p>
          <p>Globally, our sales decreased organically by 15.7% in 2009 compared to 2008. That's, of course, a significant drop. If we look by region, there is really two categories of evolution: the Western world, Europe and North America, which experienced really similar decline, around 19% decline organically. Asia-Pacific and rest of the world was better. Asia-Pacific penalized by of course Japan, Korea, and Australia, which were difficult, as all the Western world. And that just means that globally, Asia-Pac has been decreasing by 10% organically. Of course, we'll come back on the Chinese performance, which has been globally helping the region to limit the decrease and rest of the world, which is mainly new economies, which has been very close to stability at minus 2%.</p>
          <p>If you look at Q4, what is interesting to note is that we have significantly limited the rate of decrease for service for ourselves in this last quarter for 2009, with an organic decrease of 10%. Really two reasons behind that. The first one is that ,of course, we start to enter into easier comps. The Q4 of 2008 was not showing the same kind of growth as the one we experienced in the first three quarters of 2008. But, even more important, we have started to see a significant rebound in new economies and notably, in China. And that has meant that new economy, globally, posted during this fourth quarter a growth, organic growth plus 1% and that, of course, is a good news for the Group and for the prospects allowed for growth.</p>
          <p>Europe, North America and the Western world remained relatively difficult, double-digit decrease in this Q4. Asia-Pac was close to stability without Australia and without Japan. This has &#x2013; would have been a growth. China posted a double-digit growth in Q4. India renewed this growth as well during this Q4 and the rest of the world was close to stability.</p>
          <p>Now moving to our business lines and how it moved during the year, you see that we have globally two businesses which performed relatively equally, the Electrical Distribution and Critical Power, 13% decrease. But the trend in Q4 for these two businesses has been different. Electrical distribution continued to experience the same kind of decrease, minus 13%, but it's fair to say that the beginning of the year had been easier for Electrical Power. So they enter into the downturn of the cycle later than Critical Power. Regarding Critical Power, on the contrary, Q4 has been positive, back to growth organically plus 1% for this business.</p>
          <p>Regarding automation and control, largely driven by industry investment. The beginning of the year had been terrible with a severe cut in spending from industry player. We see that from Q4, we are entering into easier comps, but also, we are seeing some new flows of investment and that has limited the growth decrease at 9% for Automation &amp; Control in Q4.</p>
          <p>Let's now have a focus on H1 and H2 to underline the fact that we have significantly improved our performance in H2 compared to H1. If I start looking at our EBITDA margins, this is, of course, before restructuring and one-off gain. We posted a margin of 11.6% in the first half, but we increased this EBIT margin to 14.2% in the second part of the year, which is very close to what we have done on average in 2007 and 2008. That means that we are not totally there, but we are much, much closer to what we are delivering in 2007 and 2008 in the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Looking at the cash generation now, the first half of the year had been already good at 9.4% of sales generated in cash. We have beaten a record in the second half with 15.5% of sales generated in free cash flow.</p>
          <p>Now looking to the left hand part of this chart, let's look little bit to the P&amp;L and let's make a stop on the gross margin; &#x20AC;6.2 billion, it's 39.4% of gross margin rate compared to 14.6% last year, which means that we have defended relatively well our gross margin and really two reasons to that. The first one is the fact that we have been resisting well in terms of price. Globally, we have increased our price by 1% throughout the year 2009, which is a good achievement given the environment; and the second reason has been globally, the manufacturing productivity, I will come back on that. Of course, we have been helped as well by the positive evolution of the raw material cost, which has been positive by more than &#x20AC;140 million and globally helping our margin.</p>
          <p>If I continue to go through the P&amp;L, the R&amp;D expenses which are taken at the level of support function cost, absolutely in line in 2009 compared to 2008, &#x20AC;403 million. And now I get to the SG&amp;A expenses, where we have this big decrease, 8% in the numbers, but organically, we are talking about a decrease of 10%. That means that we have reached an EBITDA before restructuring and one-off gain of &#x20AC;2.044 billion and that is giving us a margin rate of 12.9%, i.e. approximately three points below last year.</p>
          <p>Let's continue to visit our P&amp;L. One-off pension gains, &#x20AC;92 million, which is a curtailment of our pension fund in the U.S. We have frozen the defined benefit plan to move to defined contribution and that means we were with another provision of this fund, that we had to take into an exceptional profit in 2009, so that corresponds to this &#x20AC;92 million.</p>
          <p>Restructuring cost, &#x20AC;313 million. All the saving that we have been generating, whether in manufacturing, productivity or on the support function cost, of course, were achieved through some restructuring and we, roughly speaking, a good &#x20AC;200 million our normative amount of restructuring, which is around &#x20AC;100 million a year.</p>
          <p>Amortization and impairment of purchase accounting intangibles, we normally are amortizing by 100 million our goodwill every year. This year, the difficult situation on our sensor business had led us to book an extra 120 million of impairment of intangibles and that is making this number of 230 million.</p>
          <p>Therefore, we are reaching an EBIT of &#x20AC;1.592 million, net financial expenses of &#x20AC;384 million, but I will detail this number in a few seconds. Income tax, &#x20AC;293 million, significantly below last year, where it was &#x20AC;555 million. Of course, two reasons for that, the first one is that the profit is lower than for the previous year and the second one is that we have improved our underlying tax rate, which moved down to 22.6% compared to around 24% last year.</p>
          <p>Equity investment was a drop of &#x20AC;21 million and we have &#x20AC;42 million of profit that we have to give back to our minority shareholder. That leads us to a net income group share of &#x20AC;852 million, but if we adjust from the non-recurring elements, we reached an adjusted net income of &#x20AC;1.060 billion.</p>
          <p>Analysis of change, rapidly, to understand how we moved from &#x20AC;2.9 billion of EBITA in 2008 to &#x20AC;2.044 billion. Of course, first and foremost, this is because of a very powerful and negative volume impact which cost us &#x20AC;1.3 billion. Then we experienced some positive productivity, manufacturing productivity impact and there, I need to make a reference to two amounts: the minus 146, which is the negative impact of volume going down and therefore, we have an amount of fixed cost which is amortized over lower volumes and this is a negative amount of &#x20AC;146 million. But at the same time, the work that we have made on productivity generated &#x20AC;251 million, which is net of &#x20AC;105 million of net productivity gain.</p>
          <p>The mix was negative &#x20AC;244 million, which is largely due to the fact that some of the most profitable region like Europe experienced the biggest decline, so that has been pretty negatively in terms of margin. Inflation was a positive impact. We experienced some inflation on our cost, around 50 million. But as I described to you, we also experienced a positive impact of a raw material decrease, which brought us &#x20AC;144 million of extra profit.</p>
          <p>The price impact is positive, &#x20AC;152 million, this is, roughly speaking, this 1% price positive impact throughout 2009. Support function costs were reduced by 460 million and then you have some other impact, 65 million and 88 million of negative currency impact.</p>
          <p>If we stop on manufacturing productivity for a second to understand how we managed to generate this 251 million gain in productivity, this came first by improvement in the way we purchase, a saving of &#x20AC;452 million. We've been also better managing our plants, lean manufacturing, &#x20AC;42 million of profit and the rebalancing representing &#x20AC;57 million of profit. We are now only one semester at &#x20AC;105 million of productivity. We know that we have an objective of 600 million. We believe that we are on a very good track to deliver this &#x20AC;600 million in 2011.</p>
          <p>SFC reduction was, of course, another major achievement of the year, &#x20AC;541 million. We are already very close to the minimum structural savings that we will generate of &#x20AC;600 million and we are here again on a good track to deliver our objective of &#x20AC;1 billion. Of course, this objective of &#x20AC;1 billion will be adjusted as time goes by and depending how the economy worldwide is evolving.</p>
          <p>If you look at the margin by region, two really contrasted situation. The first one is a very positive situation, the stability or close to it that we have seen both in Asia-Pac and in the rest of the world. We stayed around a 16% EBIT margin and that, of course, came from a lower reduction in terms of volumes in the Western world, but also from very good management in terms of cost that allowed for this good performance. Europe and North America were, of course, much more impacted and they did experience a significant decrease in their profitability.</p>
          <p>If we look by business line, really special situation. The first one is the most remarkable, Critical Power, that despite a 14% reduction in sales managed to increase the profitability, really very strong and very powerful management of manufacturing but also of the SFC, plus one point of profitability.</p>
          <p>Automation &amp; Control was the worst performer in terms of evolution of the profitability, of course because of the magnitude of the decrease that they suffered in volumes. And Electrical Distribution was very much in line with the average of the Group with 2.8 points decline in profitability.</p>
          <p>Now one new and of course key element for the future, as Jean-Pascal told you, we are going now to change the way we are following our business and the way therefore we report to you. We will be now following the business through our five businesses, which are described there, power, industry, IT, buildings and sensors. And we will be reporting to you both sales, EBITA and profitability for the these various businesses. Of course once we have finalized the acquisition of Areva Distribution, a sixth business will be added to this list and power will be split between power and energy.</p>
          <p>Just note that we have two businesses with profitability which are very similar, power and IT. We are 16, 17% EBITDA margin. Industry and buildings are around 10%. Let's be clear, industry should improve as the business we hope rebound in 2010.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to what has probably been the best achievement of Schneider in 2010, which is cash generation. We have been generating free cash flow of close to &#x20AC;2 billion, an all time high for Schneider Electric. Of course the operating cash flow has been impacted and significantly impacted by the decrease in the EBITA, but we manage to improve the working capital by 813 million and that really has made the difference compared to the previous year. And that enabled the fact that the cash flow of 2009 has been even above the cash flow of 2008.</p>
          <p>A few comments below the line free cash flow, dividend 317 million. A large part of the dividend has been paid in shares. Acquisitions were limited, 100 million of acquisition. Capital increase is the amount of equity increase which is reserved to our employees.</p>
          <p>And on the line other, you have some positive ForEx impact and also the fact that we terminated a liquidity management contract with a bank. In total we decreased our debt by &#x20AC;1.7 billion, moving down from 4.6 billion in 2008 to &#x20AC;2.8 billion at the end of 2009, a 40% decrease. That's a remarkable achievement.</p>
          <p>A word maybe about the working cap management, because not only did we decrease the working cap following the sales, but we went even beyond that with the receivable decreasing by seven days. And I can tell you that in this environment, which of course was a situation where cash was scarce and people were reluctant to pay, we have to pay a tribute to the work which our team have been doing in managing this receivable account. That's certainly one of the great achievement.</p>
          <p>I can also tell you that the stability of inventory was not a given. Given the impact on the supply chain, the huge reduction in volumes, to manage to stabilize inventory one year from another was also great achievement.</p>
          <p>That has led us to a cash conversion &#x2013; historic cash conversion rate of 186%. And despite the decrease of our EBITDA, EBITDA reached &#x20AC;2.4 billion, we managed to improve further our net debt to EBITDA ratio, 1.2 times compared to 1.4 times at the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>I will not say that we were taken by surprise by the strong cash flow generation, but close to it. And that has meant that at the end of 2009 we're in the situation where we have 6.3 million of &#x2013; billion, sorry, of gross debt and at the same time we have a cash-positive situation in the balance sheet of &#x20AC;3.5 billion.</p>
          <p>So negative impact of that is that our gross debt costed us a normal cost, around 5% in 2009. And that is a cost of &#x20AC;323 million in term of financial costs. But at the same time the cash, which is invested as you can imagine at no risk and short-term, has been generating a very low return given the interest rate at short term in Europe and in the U.S., 26 million only.</p>
          <p>For the other element, 56 million is linked to pension and other benefit we have each year to actualize our cost of engagement. And 30 million, which is largely due to the new facility, banking facility that we put in place to have flexibility during the course of the summer. No surprise for you if I tell you that therefore in this condition we have all the liquidity we need to finance the Areva acquisition.</p>
          <p>Moving to the dividend, we have applied the rule of 50% of the net profit being paid to our shareholders with one little adjustment, is that because of the magnitude of the non-recurring element this year, we have retreated our net profit from this element to get to this dividend per share of &#x20AC;2.05 per share, which I think is underlying the strong cash generation and the performance of the company for 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Now very briefly to the outlook, where we were somewhere &#x2013; already we spoke about main elements. What we see today is that the industry market and the data center market have started to rebound, are already in sequential growth. New economies positive from Q4 and are likely to boost Group sales.</p>
          <p>On the negative side, the non-res buildings are slowing down and it's not new, but it keeps slowing down. The business environment in mature economies remain uncertain.</p>
          <p>Now on the side of the productive profitability, industrial productivity and support function cost savings to continue. We are very determined to keep acting on that and we're going to benefit on the productivity side of more stable volumes. Then we have risk on raw material inflation. It was positive last year, it's going to be negative next year. And we are focusing to keep on restructuring and we are going to have restructuring charges expected between 150 to &#x20AC;200 million.</p>
          <p>So this all being taken into account, what we forecast is to have a return to growth, at low single-digit organic growth, and to continue improving the margin from where we are today with an EBITA margin of around 14% pre-restructuring.</p>
          <p>So that's to conclude this presentation, which was pretty complete. Now we are ready to take the questions and answers. And I'll let Carina drive this session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, ladies and gentlemen, good morning. So we'll now start the Q&amp;A session. First of all I think we'll let participants in this room to start question first, then we'll take questions from those of you are connected by phone. To make sure that everyone have a chance to speak, so I will invite all of you to limit your question to one and plus one follow-up question if possible. And please also mention your name when you speak. Thank you very much. So we'll start with the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. It's Olivier Esnou from Exane BNP Paribas. So my question is, what kind of growth rate would make you stop the crisis adaptation savings of 400 million? Is there a way you can share with us the trigger for you? Where is the trigger? And my follow-up question is, in Q4 some companies have commented that there may have been some unusual pattern of, let's say, 2009 budget consumption that made Q4 particularly good. Is it something you have noticed? Or the trend you have in Q4 has basically continued into Q1? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carina is very strict, as you know, even with us. So starting with your last question, so that's the question where you want the guidance for Q1 actually. Well I remind you that January is always very difficult to read. It's a small month for various reasons, impacted by variations of, let's say, Chinese New Year, for instance, which is a bit classical but very much important this year. Anyway, I don't think there was impact in our results of budget consumptions in 2009. I &#x2013; and we didn't force either the trend, wanted 2009 as a breakthrough rupture here to be as pure as possible and we couldn't notice from our customers very unusual behaviors. So take Q4 as a fair reflection as an ongoing business. Is that answer your question?</p>
          <p>The second point about your question about when do we stop the 400 supplementary adaptation. I don't read it with a growth trigger, actually. What we're going to see in 2010 is a very contrasted situation. In the mature countries, the economy won't bring very much except the stimulus packages that will kick in, in some of the geographies. On the other hand, some of our activities, services, solutions, energy efficiency, renewables, launch of innovation in the field of industrial automation, will bring us growth. But it won't be on the fundamentals of the environment, it will be because we dig &#x2013; or we ditch ourselves out of the crisis.</p>
          <p>So according to the way those ventures, those individual projects are gaining momentum, we're going to invest selectively in those things. But fundamentally in mature economies we still have a lot to do in rationalizing and streamlining the company. So I'm expecting &#x2013; we did 540 in the first year, if you take out the inflation and what we had in IT, and so it's gross savings and we want to keep going, not at the same magnitude but at a very significant magnitude. Let's say 150, 200 million at least this year is something that want to work on.</p>
          <p>On the other side in new economies, there you see very strong growth dynamics. And I think it will be absolutely crazy to keep with what we've done last year. So there we are looking country-by-country and situation-by-situation and we can fuel up the growth and keep building on the strong platform that we have. So for me it's not mathematical on an Excel spreadsheet, unfortunately for some of us in the room, but it's going to be business-driven and case-by-case but retain in mature country, nothing changes. We have to keep rationalizing the company and we have the plan to do it. On the new economies it's far more differentiated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to complement your answer, as you have seen we are largely looking at the savings on a kind of consolidated basis, taking into account at the same time the manufacturing productivity and saving on SFC, And globally for 2010 we target an amount which could be between 400 and &#x20AC;500 million of gross savings on these two elements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. What you have to see that, as we always say, that the volume would impact two aspects. One would be the SFC, and it was at 600 to a million. But at the same time the productivity would be impacted by the same volumes, so what you lose on the SFCs you can make it back on productivity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we are still very much in cost reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. This is Ga&#xEB;l de Bray from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. My first question relates to the CST business. I can see you've created a new division here, regrouping your customized-sensors activities. What's the strategy here for that business? And is it a good candidate for disposal maybe in 2010? The second question, or the follow-up question, relates to pricing. Is it fair to assume that pricing conditions were roughly flat for you in Q4, maybe slightly negative? And do you expect to be able to pass on rising raw material cost to your customers through price increases in 2010? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well pricing was positive in the second half of the year so we kept with good dynamics, but not as high pricing as in the first half, but it remained positive. Now if &#x2013; and this going to be the case and the raw materials are starting back to increase, we're going to improve or we're going to increase our prices wherever we can to fit or to compensate for this raw material increase. We've done it in the past. We've probably no choice and we are going to do it if we have to do it now. The business has different dynamics between the diffuse business, where it's more product sale and where the raw material impact is more immediate, and then you've got the growing part of our business, which is solution and service and projects, where the raw material impact is far lesser. So this is some thing that we have to...</p>
          <p>Now back on CST, on the sensors, this is to give visibility of what is happening there. We've said consistently on the past two years that this has been a very difficult business because, I remind you, it's very exposed to automotive and automotive didn't have good dynamics. We want and we're going to readdress and we are readdressing or turning around CST at this stage. And it's our only business which is driven by technology. We take technology that we have from our sensors in the other business and we apply it to new segments, which are more non-repetitive machines, as we call them, aerospace, medical and less and less automotive, because we try to be less exposed to automotive.</p>
          <p>So the priority is first to make sure that this is profitable and well profitable. And then we're going to think about several avenues, one can be to grow that using the same strategy rationale, build on the technology and apply it to a different segment. Otherwise we can partner. But today the priority is really to build CST, turnaround and build.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. First question is, you perceived of course a very strong free cash flow generation in '09. Is it sustainable? And where do you see your free cash flow with sales ratio in 2010 onwards? And housekeeping question, the tax rate stands at 22.6%. It's very low. Is it sustainable or you think you will go back to 25, 26 in '010? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric, on free cash flow generation, of course we won't get in 2010 the great impact that we had on the working cap evolution. So my sense is that we're going to be back to normal working cap evolution with sales. As we said, we are targeting to come back to a moderate growth and therefore I would expect to have marginal negative impact of the working cap based on that evolution on 2010. We may also see some pressure on the supply chain because we could see some shortage. We have seen that already in term of electronic goods. So that could have an impact on the necessity to be a little bit more cautious in the way we are managing our inventories. So I think that we should come back to something more normal in that respect and therefore have something in term of net profit transformation into free cash flow which would be closer to the normal, let's say, 80, 90% transformation rate that we experience usually. Regarding the tax rate, it's true that we have had a particularly good year in 2009. I think that we could be back to something like 23, 24% tax rate, normative tax rate for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on a more global view that what we are doing are still good engines to improve the cash flow. I mean, the move to less capital-intensive activities, services, solutions, software by the way in many cases. The fact that we move our production in new economies, which is less capital intensive. The fact that we rebalance our supply chain closer to our customer diminishes the amount of inventory in transit, and an absolute discipline on receivables. So all of this gradually is bringing us to increase structurally, and this is very visible over a decade, our cash flow generation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Just one question on your guidance. You mentioned that you want to achieve about 14% EBITA margin in 2010. Looking at the fact that you want to reduce costs by 400, &#x20AC;500 million this year and you want to achieve organic top-line growth, this is not a very aggressive guidance. Could you give us some more details about how you calculated that target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You cut us up every year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well when we build the guidance, first of all we did not say 14%, we said around 14%. And I gave that to reflect the significant level of uncertainty that we still have as we start this year. First of all, uncertainty on what will be the growth of our top line. Secondly, uncertainty on the level of saving that we'll be able to generate. We will be in the bottom part of the range that I gave to you or we will be in the upper part of the range?</p>
          <p>In term of price uncertainty, I think that today we would probably target to something which would be around flat in fact in term of price. We will have some inflation back certainly in a significant way in all the new economies so that we'll be impacted globally our cost. We mentioned the fact that raw materials are playing negatively. That could be 100 to 150 million negative impact the raw material this year, so of course playing negatively. And we believe that we could also have a mix playing (46) negatively. I won't give more detail on that, but if you take all that into account, we believe that our guidance is reasonable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question. So if there's no more question from the room then we'll pass on to people who have connected by phone. So first question from &#x2013; by phone and can the person also state his or her name when he or she speaks out, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Martin Prozesky from Sanford Bernstein. You have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions please. The first on the Chinese performance, in Q3 I think you said you saw 15% growth, but you were more cautious on Q4. And then today again you saw a very strong double-digit growth. Could you just expand how broad a base it was where you saw that coming from? And the second, on the pricing strength that you saw in Q &#x2013; in the second half of the year, the 1%, could you give us an indication where there was weakness versus real strength, maybe by product segment, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On China, we've seen a rebound on almost every segment. Take the infrastructure, it has been boosted by the stimulus package, which we see clearly in our sales. I remind you that most of the sales are done with intermediaries, local integrators. They are done by Chinese operators. So, and we are speaking about small and big things, but rather medium size and small things that was happening every day, like the reconstruction of Sichuan is real, and it's a lot of business for our partners and customers and it's happening everyday.</p>
          <p>So infrastructure certainly. In industry, we do a lot with machine manufacturers and they've started to export again and to build machines again. Industrial investment is also taking place in China more than in any other place. In Buildings, we've seen with renewed credit, renewed construction also, and there is a real movement to green in China. And many people in the world are speaking about green, but people in China receive KPI targets on green. So they make it more real than in other places.</p>
          <p>What we do in residential is also developing and what we do in data centers clearly is also developing. So in China, it has been on all segments that we've seen things developing and we've not seen major differences between Q3 and Q4. So it's been a solid trend and a solid rebound. So we take the crisis in China as lasting two quarters concerning Schneider sales and it's good, by the way, for the world economies that we're going to those directions.</p>
          <p>On pricing, pricing has been as much our choice as the market choice. We've been very disciplined and kept, well, enforcing very strict discipline on the market. Now we want to be selectively more aggressive in some segments of the market. And as this is very competitive information, I won't tell you exactly where, but there are few segments when we want to attack a bit more solidly in the next coming quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way to do in Q4, selectively again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So second question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Andreas Willi from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a question on the dividend, which you cut back quite a bit, back to a kind of 2004-'05 level. You had an extraordinary year on cash flow and you again proposed to shareholders that they can take stock instead of cash as well, so the likely outflow from the dividend payment looks quite modest compared to the cash generated. How should we understand this low dividend? Is this just in general a concern on the strength of the recovery and the concerns on the debt market? Or this is a clear signal that you're going to buy &#x2013; that you're going to do more acquisitions over the next 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On a global point of view, it's not a lack of confidence. We are very confident in our business, we are very confident in our company. At the same time, it doesn't mean that it's going to be a flurry of acquisition. But we are exiting a period of crisis, where a certain number of players have been weakened. We have a strong and solid strategic plan for the future. On one side, we want really our shareholders to be treated fairly. This is why we retreated our net from the exceptional elements and it seems fair into the direction of all the stakeholders, employees, shareholders, the environment and our customers. And on the other side, it's clear that we want to exit this period with a very strong balance sheet and the capacity to be mobile strategically.</p>
          <p>And I think we, again, we've been very transparent on our strategy with all of you. We've been very clear on our intention to be one of the major players of energy management. And if we don't find an intelligent use of this cash, we are going to give it back to our shareholders, that's no doubt. But we are in a very interesting period today where the world will become still tight and tense in the mature economies. Some people in the new economies will be wanting to find partners for their development and it's important for us to be ready and strategically agile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was clear. A follow-up question on your exposure. What percentage of your total sales are to public or institutional customers in developed markets? And particularly within your energy management offering where you do the energy audits and all that, what part of the market there is public customers that may be under increasing pressure, even to do sensible things like saving energy because of short-term concerns on funding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that's a difficult &#x2013; actually it's difficult to characterize and it's very variable from one geography to the other one. I would say in the U.S. on what we do, it's probably more than 25%. Probably even more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the buildings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the buildings &#x2013; well, yeah, of the buildings and infrastructure. On the other geographies, it's very variable by country, but we see as much appetite for energy efficiency from private sector, which can do it for their P&amp;L. I see many of others have started to realize that they just don't know how much energy they are consuming. I'm always struck that when I meet a CEO, he's very, very precise on his IT budget, which is normally in the magnitude of two to 4% of his turnover. They never know their energy bill, which is far higher than this. And their potential of gain is far higher than on the IT bill.</p>
          <p>Second, it's also a factor of image, with the big movement to green economy, carbon emission reduction. And you've seen very visible actors like the retail chains going strong into that. So today we see as much movement in energy efficiency from the private actors as from the public actors, which are tendentially very slow to move.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Simon Smith from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you for taking the question. I wanted to just ask about the outlook you have for commercial construction. I know obviously for you, this area is confused with the benefit you see in energy efficiency, but you were talking about continued declines there. I just wondered if you could frame your expectation of those declines in terms of year-over-year change versus, say, sequential change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You said it's confused, so what we see that, we think that most of the decline is behind us, but we don't expect any quick rebound of this kind of activity. And actually we expect it to keep going slowly down in the next coming month. Now our &#x2013; what we do in building is to propose new value to our customers. So it's integration of all of the controls inside the building and the big, big thing about energy efficiency. We start also to install panels, solar panels on the roof of our customers. So the question on revamping also for existing building is another subject. But clearly, we don't expect big dynamics on the building segment in mature economies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You should take into account the fact that we have a powerfully negative carryover impact, which means that, even if we start to see in the coming months some sequential recovery in the non-resi building activity, that doesn't mean that those numbers will be positive for the whole 2010, precisely because we have this negative carryover impact coming from the strong decrease in 2009. We do expect that the residential could be back to modest growth in 2010 in the Western world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I remind you that buildings, non-res buildings, are roughly 30% of our turnover and that with one of the interest what we of &#x2013; one of the things we've worked on is to diversify our end-market exposures. We have a strong end market to IT industries, 17%, which is clearly rebounding, 25% on industry, which after a very low level in 2009, is also sequentially improving and 16 or 17% of exposure to infrastructure, which is supported by public subsidies. So res is 10% and after many years of low res, it's coming back up. And buildings is 30%, but it's still 30% and amongst those buildings, half of them are industrial or government-owned building. So the real exposure to private and commercial building is 15% of our turnover. Just to reset the crux point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I ask a follow-up question on inflation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the &#x2013; your guidance you gave for pricing, so would I be right in thinking that the summary of what you said is that you think pricing will be roughly flat, but raw material cost will be up about 100 to 150 million? And just alongside there, you mentioned that in some areas, inflation will be back and obviously other inflation was pretty good last year. From the 50 million you had last year, where do you think that could go to in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we've already given a lot of detail on our expectation for 2010. And frankly speaking, we didn't come with our crystal ball this morning. So we won't give any number on the inflation impact globally on our cost. We give, regarding the raw material based on the current price of raw material, what could be our impact, between 100 and 150. We cannot be more precise than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We give our best hypothesis at this stage, but one thing we've proven in the past six years is that we knew how to adapt to inflation levels and to adapt our pricing policies in consequence.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. James Moore from Redburn Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, everybody. It's James at Redburn Partners. I wondered if I could ask what your margins were in 2009 in the wider solutions area, and also in the service piece of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a bit of a classical answer, but once again it was a case they were slightly below the average of the Group, okay. Though they were close, were roughly in the average of the Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we've maintained margins of a good level into those activities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on the margin, you said 14% excluding Areva D. What's your expectation on the timing for Areva D? And with that, margins including Areva D?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. This is not including Areva D.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have to restate Areva D when it comes on line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think regarding Areva D, frankly there is too much uncertainty on what would be the date for the closing of the transaction. And therefore, the impact on 2010 will largely depend on when we close this transaction. So we want to be cautious in that respect and we don't want to give any idea of what it could be, because that would be really based on a number of assumptions and that would be unreasonable. So that's the reason why we really wanted to give guidance which is excluding the impact of Areva D. But of course, once we have closed the transaction and that we have a clearer view on the impact, we'll tell you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's clear. Can I just ask your best guess on timing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We said during the spring, which is today our best guess on timing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ms. Vidya Adala from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. A very quick question for you. The fourth quarter did have very strong organic growth. Now my question is, do you think this is really driven by restocking, or is there underlying improvement in demand? And you also cited some sort of investment by customers. Is this really OpEx, or do you see CapEx returning in 2010 from your main customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well there have been several aspects in Q4 of this year. On one aspect, I don't think it was much of restocking. I think it was business as usual. Our distributors have stayed very cautious with their stock. It was really &#x2013; we saw some of the market, which hold their breath from the beginning of the year, started to reorder. And again, we spoke about the industry market, we spoke about the IT market, somewhere in some places about the resi market, some form of rebound happening.</p>
          <p>And is it a return of CapEx? Yes, there is return of CapEx in some industries. We see some of the data centers being built, we see some plants being built in new economies particularly. And we see people probably not much opening of greenfield operation in mature economies, but remember one thing is that the products that used to have a life cycle of 10, 15 years in the past, have now a life cycle of three to five years, if not less. And every time you change a production line, you've got to reinvest. So there is a lot of revamping, retrofit expansion taking place, plus the fact that there is energy efficiency and people are trimming their P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>One of the benefits of the crisis is that people have been back to their costs and they started to realize, and we proselytized that, and we document that, that energy is a part of their competitiveness. And they can reduce their costs by reducing their cost of energy. And on top of that, it will prepare for the next phase of our economies where there will be carbon trading and you're going to be impacted on your carbon impact. So this, we see it very clearly and it enables us not to be on the new part of the business, but on the retrofit and revamping part of the business. And this is clearly one of the major points of resilience we have today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Jean-Pascal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Andrew Carter from Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Andrew from Macquarie. I just had one question just on distributors, if I could. I think the &#x2013; I wondered if the move that we've seen with Rexel looking to reduce the inventory days that the company's holding, do you think that's going to be more widespread among the various distributors? And I guess, either way, is there any reason to believe that Schneider's products wouldn't be affected by this? Because I note that Rexel is actually still talking about sales declining year-on-year in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you say about inventory days declining, is that it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Yes, I think Rexel talked about reducing by one day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We saw a lot of destocking in 2009. There was cautiousness of distributors and there was a lot of work on their side on streamlining their supply chain. Supply chain originally was not totally optimized. And certainly in 2009, Rexel and other distributors did what Schneider do. When the crisis is hitting you, then you &#x2013; there is no resistance to change. All the resistances that you had before are disappearing. So many of actors and players of our industry, of our customers, have worked a lot on their internal process. And this has derived clearly on the decline of inventory, that structural improvement.</p>
          <p>Now I believe they will need, for everybody will need to rebuild some inventory in the next coming period, just to make sure we don't miss sales, or they don't miss sales. That's for sure. But you can't negate that there has been a strong and good work on their supply chain to reduce structurally the inventory. Does it impact us at Schneider? I don't think so, because at the same time a company like Rexel is, like we are doing, concentrating the number of suppliers and we happen to be one of their largest suppliers. I believe we are the largest supplier. And there is a strong partnership, strong trust and confidence between the companies. And every time there is a crisis, bonds between large suppliers and large customers are rather strengthening than anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll have time for just one last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question is from Mr. James Stettler from New Street. You have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. It sounds like very single electrical player wants to move into energy efficiency. Can you talk a bit about the competitive dynamics and if there's any pricing pressure out there? And then the follow-on question, unrelated, how much of your sales does China now represent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Energy efficiency, you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China, correct. Okay. So when &#x2013; energy efficiencies is a market in the making, so we are just at the beginning of the curve. When you look around you, nothing today, nothing is energy efficient. And everything will have to be energy efficient. There is no option, I think. Well just look at the very stupid mechanics of population, which are very predictable. You can predict that the consumption of electricity will double in the next coming 20 years and somebody will say, well why not? But it's a huge pressure on the resources. And if there is anybody that believes that it will stay the same price for electricity, I think you are very na&#xEF;ve. Energy will be very expensive. Carbon emission will be a real focus, pollution will be a focus and the modeling itself will be &#x2013; will have to change dramatically in terms of development.</p>
          <p>So if you take that, there is a huge amount of things, there are few competitors that are trying to position themselves, but when you want to tackle energy, you can't go by bits of it, you have to tackle the full energy equation and there are not many companies in the world that can do it. We are, for the applications we tackle, a unique company to deal with to reduce energy consumption. This is what we've chosen and driven.</p>
          <p>Now China, in terms of percentage of sales, we are slightly below or across &#x2013; no, actually we are above 10% of our sales in China, all compounded. This doesn't include the export sales that we do from China which are internal sales. This is outside Group sales. So it's been a major shift and change in the past coming years and &#x2013; yeah, because China is a competitive market, I think one of the things you have to realize and that you see very clearly, is that our presence in new economies is not only capular where we took the capital from profitable, which enables us to envisage or to deploy investments without reservation in those economies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think there's one last, last, last question from the room here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From the room? All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So &#x2013; and then after that we'll stop today's conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />, Standard Chartered Bank. Quick question on CapEx for this year, 2010. You're starting the year with 3.5 billion, spending 1.1 on Areva approximately. How much CapEx do you plan on spending? And do you expect eight, 9% of sales as cash flow for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding cash flow generation, I won't be more detailed on the answer I made and the fact that you should now expect something being back to normal, and this one-off very positive impact of the working capital evolution not to repeat itself obviously. On the CapEx, that will be another year of discipline, although as we said on a number of occasion today, we know that we'll have to invest in new economies in order to cope with the growth and to be sure that we keep building our shares in these new economies. So that is something that could drive some increase in CapEx in 2010 compared to 2009 but that should remain a limited increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to be back to more normal in CapEx this year. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Just as a conclusion I would like to thank you for your time, your attention, your care for Schneider. We really appreciate it.</p>
          <p>I just want to conclude by telling you that 2009 was a year of intense operational reactivity to the environment but we took the advantage to streamline and reshape the company to be ready for new developments and invest for the future in solutions, in new economies and in innovation. And again, if there is one objective that we want to have is to be back to growth and back to development around our growth engines.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your time, thank you for your attention and see you very soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>