<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1173316" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7870</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jean-Pascal Tricoire, Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Pierre Bouchut, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Christel Monot</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jean-Pascal Tricoire</participant>
      <participant id="5">Pierre Bouchut</participant>
      <participant id="6">Martin Wilkie</participant>
      <participant id="7">Andreas Willi</participant>
      <participant id="8">Scott Babka</participant>
      <participant id="9">Ga&#xEB;l de Bray</participant>
      <participant id="10">Olivier Esnou</participant>
      <participant id="11">James Stettler</participant>
      <participant id="12">Alfred Glaser</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Schneider Electric 2008 Half Year Results and 2008 Second Quarter Sales Conference Call. The conference will be presented by Mr. Jean-Pascal Tricoire, Chief Operating Officer and Mr. Pierre Bouchut, Executive Vice President Finance Control and Legal Affairs. I now hand over to Mr. Tricoire. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Good day, everybody. I am here sitting with &#x2013; I'm Jean-Pascal Tricoire, and actually CEO of the Company, not COO. I'm sitting with our CFO, Pierre Bouchut, and Alexandre Brunet, our IR. I will be speaking today about our strategy and our results.  Our strategy and results both are closely linked. Our results come from the execution of our distinctive and solid strategy.</p>
          <p>Several years ago, I had announced our ambition to reposition Schneider, to reposition Schneider as a global specialist of energy management. Five years later, we are worldwide leader in energy safety with our Power and Control division, we are worldwide leader in energy reliability with our Critical Power &amp; Cooling Services division, and we are worldwide leader in energy savings with our power monitoring and control and building automation division. We are also able to supply connectivity and automation in any end-user segment. We also recently completed our solution with moving to green energy through the key acquisition of the Canadian company called Xantrex this week.</p>
          <p>Our results are the strict product of the execution of our focus strategy, and the results we present today are solid and above guidance. They are solid in financial terms. Our EBITA is, for the first time, over &#x2013; at 15% for the first time ever. Our net earnings grows, again, double-digit by 17%. Our cash flow is more than doubled. It is also a very solid result in terms of growth. We strike an organic growth during this first half at 10.6% organic, excluding any currency from acquisition effect.</p>
          <p>And finally, we are confident in the future. We upgrade our guidance. We feel confident to do it with a growth at a minimum of 8%, and with an EBITA that we forecast at a minimum of 15%. We also commit to our financial structure to FFO on net debt above 35%.</p>
          <p>So I'm moving to slide two. I'm going to go with you through another view of our strategy, then go into the main strategic and business update. Then Pierre Bouchut will detail all the financial results, and then I'm going to be back to give you our outlook for the year.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide four, no change, as before. I have clearly announced our strategy to position Schneider as the global specialist in energy management. Our job is to connect energy production to energy usages. We do not operate in energy production. This is a different business. This is a business of large projects. There are very few and large customers. This is a business which has little synergies with what Schneider Electric is doing.</p>
          <p>We do not operate in energy usages, appliances, lighting, HVAC. But our job is to make sure that we connect energy production to energy usages in the smartest way. Our job is to deliver an active and efficient architecture from plan to plug. Our job is to help people to make the most of their energy.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide five, help people to make the most of their energy, what does it mean? It means we make energy safe, protect people and assets. This is what we have always historically done with our part on control activity. We make energy reliable. That mean we supply ultra secured energy for critical applications. This is where we now hold worldwide leadership through the combination of APC-MGE and the rest of Schneider Electric.</p>
          <p>We make energy productive. We have solutions for automation everywhere, for connectivity everywhere. We offer services at every phase of the lifecycle. We have automation solutions in industry, with industry automation in building, with building automation in home, in home automation in infrastructure, with infrastructure automation. We make energy more efficient. We bring energy efficiency, reduction of consumptions. We bring through open and integrated systems, solution to optimize CapEx and OpEx. And finally, we now have solutions to make energy greener. We offer solutions to connect to renewable sources of energy, and clearly, Xantrex is at the center of this solution.</p>
          <p>I move to slide six. You know that always Schneider has been a very focused Company. We don't want to do many things, but we want to be very focused on what we do. We want to do it well. In the sector of safe energy we are number one in power and control, with a market share which is double of the next follower. In energy reliability, critical power we are also number one through the combination of APC-MGE and the system we are building around that. In connectivity and automation solution, we belong to the top three of the world. Energy efficiency is already 20% of our business, &#x20AC;4 billion, and we estimate we have a leadership position in the technologies for energy efficiency.</p>
          <p>All of those markets are very dynamic and very robust businesses. But the distinctive strategic positioning of Schneider is a capability to combine all of those businesses, all of those capabilities, into unique solutions because our customers don't want to choose between safety, reliability, productivity and efficiency. They want it all. And it's complicated to combine all of those requests together. We are in a unique position to combine them.</p>
          <p>Slide seven, I think it has not been realized enough how we have changed the profile of Schneider Electric in the past years. We have transformed the growth profile of Schneider Electric, we have added new and growing businesses, we have balanced our end market exposure to we more able to capture growth opportunities, but also to be more resilient if a segment would be slowing down.</p>
          <p>So point one, we have radically increased exposure to emerging markets. We are now doing 32% of our sales in emerging countries. And if we take a perspective of the past ten years, the average growth organic in those countries has been certain here, and it has been growing faster in the past years.</p>
          <p>Point two, we have added fast growing activities in our portfolio, and especially activities which are absolutely critical to energy management. 27% of our business is now made in critical power and energy efficiency, and they combine together to deliver energy efficient critical power solutions. Point three, we have diversified quite radically our exposure to end markets, and we have particularly increased our exposure to infrastructure on IT markets, data centers markets, which represent today 33% of our exposure to end markets.</p>
          <p>So very significant changes. I should remind again that we've doubled size in the past four years, and that 50% of the activities we do in Schneider today were not in the Group portfolio at the beginning of the century. And I believe people have not understood enough this change of positioning.</p>
          <p>At the same time, and I am on page eight &#x2013; in slide eight, we have also increased very significantly our flexibility and consistently stepped up our cash generation. How have we done that? We've moved 40% of our cost of goods sold, so our direct costs, cost of products, cost of systems, in low cost countries versus 10% in 2001. It makes us more competitive in cost. It makes us far more flexible, because what we used to do in mature countries was heavily automated and broadly flexible. What we do in emerging countries is manual and much more flexible. And it has displaced our base of production from the euro base, which is very costly today, to a non-euro base.</p>
          <p>Second point is that we've kept on making our production system, our enterprise system more outsourced. So we work more and more with suppliers. 62% of our cost of goods sold is outsourced, and up to 70% of it is variable because we integrated in it some variable costs in the company; transportation, some temporary workers. We've made our direct cost structure far more flexible than it was. If you take the total P&amp;L of Schneider, by the way, more than 50% is both &#x2013; is acquired from external suppliers. So very flexible to be reconfigured.</p>
          <p>Finally, as a result of that, our cash flow generation has improved very, very significantly, and this first half is a very good performance in that sector because we've more than doubled our cash flow generation respect to last year.</p>
          <p>I'm moving now to the part two of my presentation. Moving to the strategy, but mainly business update. I remind you that our strategy is very simple. We want to increase our growth profile and step up the efficiency of our Company. Our principle of management is to keep on delivering robust results, while keeping on transforming the Company and investing in the transformation in the Company. Absolute priority any way is to keep on delivering improvements to our economics. So three major pillars to the increase of our growth profile; emerging countries, energy management and exposure to diversified segments, and particularly fast growing end markets.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide ten, these are results exemplify the robustness of our strategy. What we show here is that we are scoring in the first half an organic growth of 10.6%. That is now our fifth semester with a double-digit growth. We are reaching, for the first time in the history of Schneider Electric, an EBITA of 15%, an improvement of 80 basis point. And actually in absolute value this EBITA growth by 14.6% faster than the current progression of our sales at 8. We are improving again double-digit net income at 17%. What I'm very proud of and pleased of is that we multiplied by more than two our free cash flow thanks to our low capital intensive model.</p>
          <p>We have always committed, after the exceptional acquisition of APC last year, to communicate specifically on it. The EBITA of APC-MGE, the combined entities, is jumping by 60%, reaches an EBITA of 13.3%. Now closer and closer to the average of the Group. And Pelco integration is doing better than said in the acquisition plan, which makes the multiples of both of those acquisitions now very reasonable.</p>
          <p>I have to say I am very pleased with this performance because we keep improving regularly our economics while investing in promising transformation for the future of Schneider. We keep on developing our service and project capabilities, which are today still margin dilutive, but still the global result of Schneider is improving. We are investing in the globalization of our IT to make ourselves more lean and more integrated. We are developing integrated solutions for our customers. All of this represent investment, but we still manage to realize all the investments while improving our profitability.</p>
          <p>I move to slide 11, a deeper look at the growth performance. Well, we have strong dynamics in our regions and in our new businesses. Europe finishes the first half at plus 9%, North America at plus 5.7%. In North America we had issues with our supply chain in June, particularly due to some supply issues and due to some problems of capacity that prevented us to ship everything we would have liked to ship. So business holding at the right &#x2013; at a good level in North America. Asia-Pacific, accelerating from Q1, 16.6%, and Rest of the World strong, above 20%. The Group, as I was saying, is scoring plus 10.6% growth, and the emerging countries are contributing, again, close to 20% at 18%.</p>
          <p>If we look at our activities, critical power accelerated in Q2 to reach for the first half 12%. Building automation, very strong. This is really linked to the demand for more energy efficiency, energy savings; people are really starting to address in the natural world the consumption of their buildings. Wiring accessories, ultra-terminal as we say, which is wiring accessories, cable management, datacom, at 4% really slower because of the residential decrease in Europe particularly, still booming in Asia. On services, still a very strong engine of our growth, at plus 17%. Energy efficiency activities that we do in the sales are growing by 16%.</p>
          <p>So now let's look at the detail of the pillars of our growth. I'm moving to slide 12. Emerging countries, as always, represent today a 32% or 33% over the year. Well, again, a very strong sustained growth. The sales we realized today, as of today in emerging countries reached &#x20AC;6 billion over the year from the best of our forecast. And this acceleration of growth rate is really coming from the solidity, the robustness of the infrastructure that we now have in those countries. So now it's not a project-based presence. It's really a very diverse, very solid, very deeply rooted presence in those countries that we are fully leveraging to grow faster in those countries.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 13, the next pillar of our growth is energy efficiency. It's now a &#x20AC;4 billion business, growing at 15%, 16% to be precise, in the first half. Well, clearly, we have solutions for industrial infrastructure, we have energy efficient solutions. And I remind you that the solutions of the infrastructure, cooled infrastructure for data centers, is very energy efficient and very innovative in that regard. We are worldwide leader in energy efficient data centers.</p>
          <p>Buildings and residential makes up 40% of the worldwide energy consumption. And again, we have a worldwide leadership in those two applications. We are able to bring in any of those application a saving of 30% with a payback now which is below three years in average.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 14, the last pillar of our growth capability is the strategic repositioning we've driven to diversify our end market exposure and position ourselves on fast growing segments. I'm speaking, for instance, of natural resources; oil and gas, mining and minerals. I'm speaking about the electrification of economies, and especially the emerging countries. But it's need for electrification also in the mature countries, and everything we do in data centers where we see no weakness at all, certainly in the next coming year.</p>
          <p>So if we move to page 15, you see that &#x2013; and I've already expressed myself in road shows about this &#x2013; that  we've changed very significantly since '01 our end market exposure. 33% of our business is done in emerging countries, today in '08; 20% of our business is done &#x2013; is driven by energy efficiency, and most of it is not in emerging countries. Most of it is complementary to what we do in emerging countries, in mature countries. At the same time, we benefit from the strong growth of some key market segments; data centers, natural resources, oil and gas, mining and minerals, we are speaking about that, and utilities electrification of countries. All of those activities, all of those segments represent today, as of today, 60% of our turnover, and they are growing faster than 10%.</p>
          <p>On the other side of our activities, we've got 12%, 10% of what we do which is in residential. We've got something like close to 20% of construction, which is not strictly in the emerging market. But this is largely compensated by 60% of our business that we do in fast growing and very dynamic segments.</p>
          <p>I'm moving on to slide 16. The second part of our strategy is to develop the efficiency of the Group, and we have there three very clear priorities. One is rebalancing. Getting closer to the faster developing countries, making sure that we move our cost and move our infrastructure in cost competitive countries. The second one is globalization. We have got a huge reservoir of efficiency there. We've grown a lot by acquisitions. Our culture was very much a culture of local management.</p>
          <p>We are now driving processes across the entities of the companies and leveraging our size to get the full benefits of scale. And finally, simplification. We want to simplify now that we've reached a new size of new critical mass, a new geographical exposure, make sure that we have lean structures, unified processes on cost reduction. We are probably only one-third through the plan of rebalancing globalization and simplification that we have in front of us, and this will be a major axis of our new Company plan that we are going to announce at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>I'm moving to slide 17. Just to exemplify what we are doing in the field, what was done in the field of rebalancing. We've reached at the end of 2007 40% of our COGS, cost of goods sold, that means direct cost in low cost countries. Our ambition for this year is 42%, which has been reduced with respect to last presentation. Not because of the actions we are doing, but there were some restatements done in Pelco and APC, and that we are a bit more negative on that side than originally computed. Anyway, the movement is to keep on rebalancing the Group and pushing the needle in that sector.</p>
          <p>On the other side, in '07 we do already 50% of our sourcing in low cost countries, and we have more than 50%, 55% of our manufacturing head count in low cost countries. The cost rebalancing target that we had fixed for ourselves in the frame of new2, it was 40%, is already achieved in '07, and we want now to go to 42%. The collateral benefit of that is that we've rebalanced, in terms of parity, the Group so that we are not sensitive any more to drift of the euro to the dollar.</p>
          <p>I'd like now, in the next coming slides, to give you another view of the progresses we've accomplished in the three and a half past years in the frame of new2. I believe that at the end of the year we're going to be coming with our new Company plan, and probably won't be very much listening to the achievements of new2. So I think it's a good time now to be speaking about what we've achieved.</p>
          <p>We have committed to things that were not particularly easy 3.5 years ago. We've delivered, we've executed in our priorities, and we've beaten our targets. I believe one of the achievements that we've had in the past four years has been to change the culture of execution at Schneider Electric.</p>
          <p>In customer satisfaction, we've increased the proportion of very satisfied customers by 20%. In customer service, we've increased the on-time delivery rate by 3 points by line, which is very significant when you consider that we are not at bad levels of delivery three and half years ago, but now we are at very good levels of delivery. We've increased our productivity on COGS by 4.5% every year. A growth on average of the plan, over the years of the plan. I said before we've rebalanced our COGS in emerging countries now at the rate of 42% at the end of '08. We've reduced our logistics costs &#x2013; let me tell you that at the time when the oil barrel is at this at the very high price, this has been extremely important &#x2013; by 1.6 point. We've decreased our IT costs by 1 point. We've decreased our support function costs by 2.5 points.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 19, we had fixed ourselves a target of average growth over the period of 5% that we stepped up afterwards to 6%. We've delivered an average of 10%. We have fixed an initial target for the increase of our EBITA between 12.5 to 14.5. We reached today 15%. We had targeted a ROCE increase of 2 to 4 points, and at this stage we are up 2 points, including the acquisitions, from the effects of acquisitions. We had committed to dividend payout forming 50% of the net earnings, and we've consistently delivered that.</p>
          <p>One other thing we speak a little bit less but which is a matter of pride on the criteria of selection for our &#x2013; pride for the employees on the matter of selection for our customers, is that we had fixed for ourselves a barometer of sustainable development and we've doubled our score according to criterias of this barometer reaching close to eight, which was our target, and 10 at the end of June. And we're going to be certainly over eight at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>With that, I've brushed up a complete picture of our strategy on our results, and tried as much as possible to connect the strategy that translates into robust results. I'm handing over the mic to Pierre who will detail our financial presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Well, good morning to everyone. As already stressed, Schneider Electric enjoyed another strong progression of its result in this 2008 first half. Let's review this progression in more details, and we are on slide 21. The following slides are actually under a format which most of you are now familiar with.</p>
          <p>Our reported 8.4% sales growth is made of 10.6% organic growth, a 4.4% positive impact from acquisition and a negative 6.6% impact from foreign exchange rate evolution mainly due, of course, to the drop of the U.S. dollar versus the euro. Our gross margin slightly improved up to 41% owing to price increases and to better gross margin at our critical power and cooling service business units, and because also of our projects and services activities reporting better gross margin.</p>
          <p>Our EBITDA progressed by almost 17% and exceeds &#x20AC;1.6 billion, and our EBITA before &#x20AC;49 million of amortization of purchased accounting intangibles, but after &#x20AC;53 million of restructuring cost, increased by 14.6% up to &#x20AC;1.346 billion while, as already indicated, our EBITA margin reaches an all time high of 15%, improving by 0.8 points.</p>
          <p>Owing to a tight control of our interest expenses limited to &#x20AC;119 million and to a reduction of our effective tax rate from 28% in June 2007 to 26.5% in June 2008, our first half net income increased by 16.7%, up to &#x20AC;851 million, while our first half EPS has reached &#x20AC;3.56.</p>
          <p>The following chart is our, henceforth, traditional analysis of our EBITA change from the &#x20AC;1.175 billion in 2007 first half up to &#x20AC;1.346 billion in 2008 first half. As you can note, out of 14.6 points in EBITA progression, 17 points are explained by organic growth, 1.9 points by acquisition, while FX rate evolution had a negative 4.3 points impact. With &#x20AC;240 million the volume impact remained very significant, while owing to our successful efforts to improve the gross margin of our sales in projects and services, the negative mix effect at &#x20AC;52 million has been drastically reduced.</p>
          <p>During this 2008 first half we succeeded to pass over 166 million of price increases, representing 2% of all sales. It is worth mentioning that we have been able to pass price increases throughout our different geographies and our different business units with, in particular, a 1.7 price increase in Asia-Pacific, a 3.9% in North America and a 2% in critical power and cooling services. This &#x20AC;166 million price increase exceeds the all in &#x20AC;132 million impact of raw materials, transportation and labor manufacturing inflation.</p>
          <p>Our continued efforts to improve productivity have generated &#x20AC;171 million savings, in line with our new2 targets, while our other operating costs, SG&amp;A and R&amp;D, have increased by &#x20AC;152 million following our continuous sales, marketing and R&amp;D investments in emerging countries and in new businesses with high growth potential.</p>
          <p>It is worth noting that the &#x20AC;51 million negative currency effect is broken down into a negative &#x20AC;68 million translation impact, and a positive &#x20AC;17 million transaction impact following our APC and Pelco acquisition. The impact on our EBITA margin is, therefore, slightly positive. And last, the acquisition impact is limited to &#x20AC;22 million when taking into account the negative &#x20AC;24 million impact of the divestiture of MGE Small Systems realized in the second half of last year.</p>
          <p>The objective of the following slide on page 23 is to illustrate our pricing power capacity. As you can see it, over 2008 first half, of &#x20AC;166 million price increase represent a 126% of the &#x20AC;132 million combined inflation impact coming from raw materials, up to &#x20AC;78 million; transportation, up to &#x20AC;10 million; and labor manufacturing, up to &#x20AC;44 million. This 126% compares favorably with the 109% achieved in 2007 and calculated on the same basis.</p>
          <p>As indicated in the following slide, our industrial productivity plans generated &#x20AC;171 million savings, represented 3.8% of our products cost of sales, a better achievement than in 2007 first half, &#x20AC;126 million savings at 3.6% of our sales.</p>
          <p>Such a productivity improvement is exactly in line with our new2 targets, and those &#x20AC;171 million savings are broken down as follows; &#x20AC;85 million savings through improved purchasing conditions owing to better negotiation, more globalization, but also to the value engineering of our products.</p>
          <p>You can note that over the last three years we have transferred about &#x20AC;900 million of industrial purchases from high cost to low cost countries. &#x20AC;26 million savings through lean manufacturing, &#x20AC;34 million gain from manufacturing rebalancing to low cost country. And, at last, &#x20AC;26 million impact generated by industrial rationalization for the closing down and consolidation of four manufacturing plants since the beginning of this year. It is worth indicating again that at the end of 2008 we plan to realize 42% of our cost of goods sold in emerging countries as compared to 34% or so of our sales in emerging countries.</p>
          <p>The following slide represents our profitability across region, and before the allocation of corporate cost. As you can see, Europe represents 46% of all sales, North America 27%, Asia-Pacific 18%, and the Rest of the World 9%. As you can see it as well, all our different geographic operation post a solid and rather homogenous EBITA profitability above 14.3%.</p>
          <p>In Europe, our EBITA margin increases from 17.7 to 19% owing to a more dynamic pricing power, to a significant volume impact, to sustained productivity improvement and to our development on the attractive energy efficiency market. In North America, we succeeded to maintain our EBITA margin as 14.3% owing to a strong pricing power, to the APC turnaround and to all development on attractive segments, such as data centers, water treatment, hospitals and energy efficiency, and despite a more difficult residential and commercial building market environment and a 0.5 point EBITA dilution coming from the integration of Pelco.</p>
          <p>In Asia-Pacific, our margin progression of 3.1%, up to 15.4%, reflects a significant volume impact in construction and infrastructure markets, but also a 1.7% price increase and our productivity improvement. At last, in Middle East, Africa and Latin America, the posted 16.1% EBITA margin is stable and explained by the tight management control of a rapid but solid expansion.</p>
          <p>In the same way, the following chart presents our profitability across our different businesses and before the allocation of our corporate cost. As you can see, electrical distribution accounts for 56% of our sales, automation and control for 30%, and critical power for 14%. It is worth noting that each of our three businesses post a significant improvement of its profitability.</p>
          <p>The improvement of our electrical distribution profitability, up to 18.7%, is largely explained by the volume impact, the productivity gains and the pricing power. The same applies to our automation and control profitability, which also benefits from the ramping up success with our clients of our new unity range of products launched two years ago, while our critical power and cooling services business unit profitability increased by 3.8% up to 13.2%. And this is largely attributable, as you know, to the ongoing turnaround of APC combined with pricing and volume impact.</p>
          <p>In this respect, and as exposed on the following slide, our 2008 first half APC-MGE performances are in line with our announced business plan at the time of the APC acquisition. 2008 first half sales organic growth rate has been up 12%, while the EBITA profitability before restructuring cost has reached 14.1%.</p>
          <p>Our CPCS BU, business unit, benefits from the solid trend on its end market with an 11% growth of its sales in home and distributed, and a 15% increase of its sales in enterprise system and services, but also from a significant improvement in profits in the implemented synergies in purchase, logistic and support function costs. With the ongoing market trend and further operating efficiency, we expect our critical power and cooling service EBITA before restructuring to reach 15% in 2008.</p>
          <p>In the same way, and as indicated on the following slide, the Pelco post-merger integration is going on well, in line with our presented business plan. Actually, despite a slightly softer than expected organic growth, but owing to above target cost and sales synergies, Pelco EBITDA improved very significantly, up to $48 million and 15.5% of sales in 2008 first half, and is expected to reach 122 and 16% of sales in 2008. This make us confident on our 19% EBITDA margin for 2011, and this also qualifies the different comments at the time of our acquisition closing in October 2007, since based on our 2008 EBITDA forecast our acquisition price, adjusted for tax benefit, stands out at 11 times 2008 EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Our sources and uses of funds is now representing for H1 2007, H1 2008 and the last 12 months as of June 2008. Over the last 12 months &#x20AC;2.377 billion operating cash flow and &#x20AC;219 million capital increase have mainly financed &#x20AC;576 million capital expenditures, &#x20AC;796 million dividends, &#x20AC;1.139 billion acquisitions and &#x20AC;438 million reduction of our net debt.</p>
          <p>You will note on this slide our success in controlling our operating working capital needs with a limited &#x20AC;67 million additional working capital needs over the last 12 months, despite our double-digit organic growth. You will also note &#x20AC;1.928 billion generated free cash flow over the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>As expressed in the following chart, this &#x20AC;1.928 billion last 12 month free cash flow as of end of June 2008, represent a notable 176% increase versus the &#x20AC;1.94 billion last 12 month free cash flows as of the end of June 2007. Therefore, our cash conversion rate improved significantly from 41% in June 2007, up to 58% in June 2008 when measured by the ratio of free cash flow over EBITDA, or from 76% in June 2007 up to 113% in June 2008 when measured by the ratio of free cash flow over net income.</p>
          <p>I'm moving to the following slide on page 31. Such an improvement of our free cash flow is explained, to a large extent, by the achieved control over our working capital needs and our capital expenditures. The following slides explain this evolution of the capital employed by our operations over the last 12 month. As you can see, and despite the context of high demand for our products, we have, in particular, succeeded to reduce our inventory by almost nine days and our receivable by almost nine day as well. And therefore, to reduce our working capital needs by 2.2 points down to 21.6% of our sales, while containing our CapEx to 3.2% of our sales.</p>
          <p>As a result, our capital employed at &#x20AC;16.749 billion, only increased by 13.7%. Therefore, and as explained on the following slide 32, as a result of our capital employed increase limited to this 13.7% over the last 12 month, while our EBITDA and EBITA were increasing respectively by 24.3% and 22% over that same period, our return on capital employed post significant improvement.</p>
          <p>Our cash ROCE measured by the ratio of our EBITDA after tax of our capital employed improved from 13.1% as of June 2007 to 14.3% as of June 2008. And naturally, the same factors explain the progression of ROCE measured by after tax EBITDA of capital employed for 10.89% as of June 2007 to 12% as of June 2008.</p>
          <p>As exposed in the following slide 33, owing to our robust results and owing to our strong cash generation, our financial structure as of the end of June 2008 improved significantly with a 13 time interest coverage by our EBITDA, a 53% debt to equity ratio, and above all, a fund from operation to net debt ratio, as per Standard &amp; Poor's rating agency definition, at 39%.</p>
          <p>We are confident in the capacity of our business model to continue to generate strong cash and steady free cash flow in the coming years. Therefore, we are committed to maintain this FFO over net debt ratio above 35% in the coming years, targeting an A- rating.</p>
          <p>I'm leaving now the mic again to Jean-Pascal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pierre. I'm in slide 35. Well, given current economic conditions, our present backlog, present business opportunities, our present portfolio of activities, yield market exposure, we feel confident to upgrade our end of year guidance. And we upgraded to a minimum of 8% in organic sales growth, previously it was between 6 and 8, and we upgraded to a minimum of 15% EBITA margin at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. We are now ready to take any of your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have a question from Mrs. Christel Monot from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hi. Good morning, everyone. Just two quick questions please on the change in EBIT. The first one is on the operational leverage of the volume. When you look at the 240 million you have achieved compared to the volumes, you find that ratio of 30%, which is lower than what you have achieved in previous period. Can you comment on that please? And the second question is on the mix. Obviously, you have improved the profitability in services and projects, and therefore, the mix is much lower than it was in the previous period. How do you think about that? Is that sustainable going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the second part on the mix, yes, we think it is sustainable because clearly, as you know, it is one of our objective to improve the profitability of our project, services and solution. We indicated that our objective was to improve it from a level which is &#x2013; which was last year of about 12% up to a minimum level of 15% over the coming three years. And all what we have been doing in the last six month is going in the right direction. And we are confident that this trend should continue in the coming years, and we are working hard for that. Regarding the volume, well, that's a measure. But please note that the price has been better than before, and we have to dig to give you a more precise answer on this specific point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a follow-up question on this bridge analysis. On the margin, the same question comes on the change in scope. If we look at the margin of the acquisition it looks like it's a 6% margin if we again compare a contribution of EBIT and a contribution of volume &#x2013; of, sorry, revenues. Do you know where that's coming from as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. As indicated during the presentation, we had a negative &#x20AC;24 million coming from the divestiture of APC-MGE Small Systems. As you know, this divestiture was closed in the second half of 2007 and, therefore, were it not for this &#x20AC;24 million the impact from acquisition would be of &#x20AC;46 million positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jean-Pascal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was Pierre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the compliment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Martin Wilkie from Deutsche Bank. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. It's Martin Wilkie from Deutsche Bank. So a couple of questions. First of all, very strong cash flow. Obviously your working capital is improving there. Could you let us know has that been driven by your improvement in the logistics plan and is that now at a sustainable level or should we see further improvement there? And also, I think you mentioned you had some supplier problems in the U.S., or some supplier delays in the U.S., and if you could let us know how that impacted that particular number?</p>
          <p>Secondly, obviously, you made an acquisition earlier this week. Just if you could generally talk about asset prices. What you're seeing with potential further targets? You mentioned your own leverage targets, but do you see some further small deals potentially coming in the pipeline over the next six to 12 months? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Concerning the CapEx, obviously, it's coming from a very structured way that we've been announcing now for more than one year. Well, actually, the simplification of our logistic setup has been started with new2. We've closed close to 60 logistic center in the past four years. So we've closed sub-critical logistic centers. And in the course of that we've increased our deliveries, delivery rate, our service to our customers, and we really now start to see the benefit coming into the inventory.</p>
          <p>The second thing that we are working on is everything into receivables, and we are streamlining and professionalizing our processes and that has been also launched. So that's sustainable and that should, will keep on improving. Now there is a place &#x2013; there is also something in that the places where we are developing fast are probably paying better than some of the original places, and especially Eastern Europe, Latin Eastern &#x2013; West Europe, sorry. On the other side, we see the reverse pressure on the payables, because as we are looking or finding more suppliers into the low cost countries the terms of payment are shorter than what we had in South Europe. So there is a bit of counterweight here, but we are working hard on that and we think we are &#x2013; we can do better there and keep doing better.</p>
          <p>Concerning the U.S., effectively, June and May have been affected by some delivery issues. I didn't refer to it also, but there was some effect of that also in Europe due to the strikes that happened. There were some ports of the Mediterranean, like Marseille, which was blocked. The truckers in Spain didn't help very much for at least one week, and the time to recover the traffic didn't help. In the U.S. we had two elements. We had some suppliers that couldn't deliver, and we had some issues, internal issues, on some key components. But these orders that we've not lost and that we're going to find back in July. So what we've seen in the U.S. is a slow slowdown on our traditional activities. But at the same time, on some other activities back to the data centers, back to energy services, back to energy efficiency, back to what we do in oil and gas, while the dynamics of the market have been very good on making that slowdown a slow slowdown. Okay? All compounded.</p>
          <p>Now, back to Xantrex, the acquisition that we did at the beginning of the week, has been vocal since two years since we did APC acquisition. That there was an obvious segment of application for the technologies where we are world leader with APC-MGE, what we do in drives, which was the inverters, the UPS for solar conversion and wind conversion. To accelerate this development, because we've got everything to connect a renewable source of energy to an energy usage. We've got medium voltage, we've got transformers, we've got power monitoring on control, we've got remote monitoring. We're just lacking those invertors. We've been working for now a year with Xantrex on taking some projects together, especially in Europe, and we knew each other very well. Xantrex was limited in its commercial expansion capability. The synergies there are big and they are double. On one side we have all the commercial network and all the commercial legitimacy with Schneider to propose a full system, a full solution, to connect our customers to renewable source of energy, so make their energy green.</p>
          <p>On the other side, the technologies that Xantrex are using, we have ten times more volumes on the side of APC-MGE. So the cost reduction will be massive, day one. So on the synergies, purchasing synergies are big immediately, day one. Our manufacturing synergies, also they're very good. Now, do we have other plans? We are not extremely active on the field of acquisition, but still there are some firms that we are following regularly. They are mid-sized firms. I would say around a maximum of &#x20AC;300 million of turnover, and really it's a matter of opportunity. But know that the priority after APC and Pelco, the priority is more to integration. Pierre wants to complement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If I may add two points. First of all, regarding the working capital needs, I think that in addition of the specific plans that we have to reduce our inventory level or receivables, we are working hard on those. I think that the customer satisfaction program, which is really one of our driving force within Schneider, has instilled a real discipline within the organization. And with the improvement of customer satisfaction in terms of delivery on time, in terms of quality of services, quality of products, I think it has a really direct impact on our capacity to reduce our working capital needs. And this is a big plus, and I think it explain to a certain extent this improvement.</p>
          <p>As far as acquisition are concerned, as you probably have noticed since the beginning of the year, we have closed some small acquisition, but very significant for us in terms of market share in wiring in devices in Chile, in Russia, in Turkey, for instance. So we are continuing to work hard on acquisition. And the fact of being committed to maintain an FFO over net debt higher than 35% will not at all prevent us from continuing to make acquisition at the same pace than over the last five years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to come back and summarize that working capital point then. So the improvement you've seen in the first half, is it at the very least taking you to a new level of efficiency and actually there's still some further improvement yet to come on that point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to be working on further improvements. Now, as we've always explained, while you improve &#x2013; when you close a logistic center you deteriorate temporarily your working capital. So it's something that we are doing. We keep on investing in the reduction of this CapEx. But it goes with some steps and it will go regular &#x2013; it will be a regular improvement. In &#x2013; as you know, we will be presenting our new Company plan in a few months, and we think that we have a further margin of maneuver to improving our working capital needs, and we provide you at that time with a very clear &#x2013; with very targets regarding those further improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd like to &#x2013; probably to develop on that. We are going to be finishing the Company program new2 at the end of the year. And at the end of the year we are going to be coming back with a new Company program and with new ambitions in every direction; growth, development of activities, positioning and also efficiency. So while there is a lot that would be probably clearer at this time when we are going to come with a full package of positioning of our ambition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Andreas Willi from JP Morgan. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Two questions please. The first one is on the automotive industry and your exposure there. If you could just say what your total sales to the automotive sectors are in your automation sensors business, and what you have seen there in trends in recent months? And the second question is in terms of your margin. Normally we see quite a good improvement in the second half over the first half due to the seasonality. Is there any reason to expect anything different this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. On the automotive sector, Andreas, Alexandre will be able to give you more elements, but in automation we have not chosen particularly automotive as a target segment as some of our key worldwide competitors have made of that their key sector. Naturally, today we just are pretty happy of that choice because, clearly, automotive is not the fastest investing sector in the world. But it's rather limited in our automation segment. What we like to do in automation, where we excel, is the places where you can mix automation systems with power systems because in power systems we've got a very strong leadership and power is getting more and more automated. So all the applications which are power intensive are our preferred applications. We also develop a pretty strong business with the OEMs, with machine manufacturers, who are doing pretty well today.</p>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; so we're going to give you some elements, but it's absolutely not dominant in what we do in automation. The second point is about the margin. Well, normally our second half is higher in margin than the first half. Now we've taken a cautious stand to the second half as some of you, particularly, can be over pessimistic sometimes about the environment. So we've taken a stand which say it will be a 15% plus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no reason why we should not benefit from the same sort of positive seasonality impact in the second half of this year very obviously. And as far as the car industry is concerned, big car manufacturers, if my memory is correct, in automation alone our total sales is around &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's quite limited.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In automation, pure automation, because we do much more with this solution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Scott Babka from Morgan Stanley. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. Obviously, pricing was very strong in the first half. I was just wondering if you could shed some light on whether you expect to see a similar net benefit into '08 &#x2013; the second half of '08 and into '09? And my second question was really just on the balance sheet. Clearly, cash generation's been very strong and you're targeting it as an A- rating. Could you just talk a little bit about the plans you've put in place for the refinancing? And then also how much capital would you see available for acquisitions? I know you're talking about that not being a priority, but how much headroom do you think you have looking forward for the next 12 months? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the pricing, clearly, we want to keep on the same dynamics that we have launched. You have seen our pricing ability increasing by the year in the past four years. I've said many times that we didn't have enough discipline in that sector. Now we have reinstalled this discipline. It took some time to build it up and run it. But we are pricing up, and it's not as simple as kind of prices increases. It is really managing the prices on value you offer to customers. So I'm expecting us to be keeping on pushing the pricing. In 2009 or 2008 we never made forecasts for the year, the following year, at least externally. But I think one of the good signs I see whatever in the environment is that we've been able to price also in places where the demand was weak. So I think we've developed also this know-how of pricing even in slower market conditions. That's for pricing. And now I am going to revert to Pierre for financing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, as far as Schneider liquidity is concerned, we started the year with cash and used available credit facility for total consideration of &#x20AC;3.650 billion. So we had a very comfortable position. During 2008 we have to repay debt of &#x20AC;1.9 billion. And to give you precise figures, as of the end of July we have already refinanced &#x20AC;1.2 billion out of 1.9 billion without going in the Eurobond market. So we are extremely confident that our plan for 2008 is to raise about &#x20AC;2.4 billion, and so we are extremely confident that we will achieve that by the end of the year. And, therefore, that we should end up the 2008 year with a cash and available credit facility higher, most probably higher than at the beginning of this year. And obviously, this will help us to continue to finance acquisition if need be. And here again, I reiterate what I said earlier, the fact that we are targeting FFO over net debt higher than 35% will not, how should I say, cut down our capacity to make acquisitions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Ga&#xEB;l de Bray from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. Ga&#xEB;l de Bray SocGen. Good morning. I've got two questions, please, regarding your North American business. Just looking at the critical power division, overall, for the Group it achieved roughly 16% organic growth in Q2. So if we assume this was roughly the same kind of growth in your North American business for critical power, when I calculate that the rest of the business is probably growing not that much.</p>
          <p>So could you maybe confirm this or maybe just tell us how much exactly the critical power division grew in North America, and what was the implied growth for the rest of the business? And my second question is quite similar, but is now related to the margin development. Because, overall, the margin was quite stable in North America in the first half compared to last year. But APC's margins have, obviously, increased quite significantly over the same period. So what's the implied drop in margins for the rest of the business in North America?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you look at the business in North America, the business of critical power was a bit &#x2013; was not in the average of what critical power has done, it was lower. And it was below 10% in H1 for the reason that we've always said, is that we've terminated unprofitable lines of business last year. And there is still a negative effect of this product cutting in North America, and that will resolve in the next quarters to come. Okay? Which means that the growth that we do in CP, in critical power, is below 10 in North America, and that's not because of growth on our fundamental products. It's becoming -- it's coming from the termination of lines of products. Therefore, the business that we have, let's call it our traditional business, in North America in the first half has been around five.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I may, regarding the EBITA margin, as I mentioned it during the presentation, the <mark type="inaudible" /> Pelco in North American figures has dilutive impact on this EBITA margin of 0.5 points. And if you take that into account you can see that the EBITA margin for North America is about stable. It explains the bulk of the difference between 15.1 and 14.3.</p>
          <p>On the margin stability in North America, we saw activity of services growing pretty fast in H1, especially in the energy services, and this is not as high in margin as it is on the traditional power business. The residential was all-time low, which is normally a good carrier of margin for Schneider. Where probably now we &#x2013; if there is anything to expect in the future that probably it will pick up at one stage next year. But that has put some pressure on the value of the margin now. The ROCE of those activities is excellent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. So there has been no pressure on the margins in North America for your traditional activities then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I just have a follow-up question on your adjusted organic growth in Q2 by division because you gave these figures in Q1? It would be great if you could do the same for Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll do it separately. You can call Alexandre. He will provide you with those figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Olivier Esnou from Exane BNP Paribas. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I have three questions. So, first, a qualitative one. Is it possible to make some qualitative comment for the quarter about if you have seen any change of trend meaningful for the quarter by region you think would be worth pointing out? Secondly, I'd like to come back to the projects and solution business. Can you tell us how big it is a business all together for 2008 roughly, and what end markets are especially targeted here? If it's different or more specific than the one of the Group.</p>
          <p>And I understood you want to go from 12 to 15% margin here, but &#x2013; and maybe you said that, but I may have missed by when you think you can get that business to 15%. And last question, it's on the R&amp;D development. There was a step-up in R&amp;D spending in the first half, especially in the capitalized R&amp;D. And I wanted to know if you could tell us where are you spending this R&amp;D, and how we should think about capitalized R&amp;D going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Olivier, I'm just answering the last question on R&amp;D. The step-up is coming from Pelco. Largely coming from Pelco being consolidated as of, as you know, the 1st of January. Pelco has significant R&amp;D expenses, as you know, and the bulk of it here again is coming &#x2013; or the difference is coming from Pelco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it should be sustainable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It should be sustainable, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Change of trend by region &#x2013; and this is Jean-Pascal speaking &#x2013; if we make it very simple, no sign of weakening whatsoever in the emerging countries, and I'm integrating into that Eastern Europe, which is very dynamic today for us. And we have visibilities on projects. Traditionally, what we do in those emerging countries has quite some visibility. In the U.S., residential down. We take the other segments of our traditional activities, again, I'm mentioning our traditional activities, are slowly slowing down. On construction the industry is holding well. Our less traditional activities, you take energy efficiency, and this includes a very solid component of what we do in building automation, very geared, our building automation is very geared to energy efficiency. What we see in terms of CPCS data centers and the capacity to aggregate full solutions around CPCS, is very dynamic. So that's compensating.</p>
          <p>In North America &#x2013; in Europe, sorry, the segments we've seen really going down have been the U.K., has been Spain, and that's really residential. So that was expected somewhere, but we've seen the residential overall in Europe decreasing, going down. One of the very good things is that we see the business in France accelerating, and that has been quite steady now for several quarters. We had very good growth in France, close to 7%, and a lot of that is coming from the services. We start now to see <mark type="inaudible" /> delivered to our customers.</p>
          <p>So if I would summarize, I would say no sign of change in emerging countries, even with a certain visibility. I would say slowdown in &#x2013; confirm down, not slowdown in residential, because it has bottomed down. Some slowdown in our traditional activities in the field of construction, but very compensated in North America and in Europe by our new activity. Boom on development on the side of energy efficiency on the side of critical power. Does that answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, project service and business, actually, this is a business -- well it depends how much you put into it, because we've got a large part of our business, which is equipment that we -- I don't think they were that in what I call project and services, which I put in the services. What is pure service? And I put in the projects what is engineering of solution to a customer. And those projects can buy 20 equipments into -- and integrate them in their proposal.</p>
          <p>But when I look at projects and services, it's now slightly above 10%. And it's growing between 15 and 20% consistently. And the good news is that the margin has really increased in the past two years. And we are now in a margin, which is close to 12 at this stage, and that we ambition to bring to the whole as a Group in the next coming plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How big is it this if you put it together...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10% of the turnover.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, 10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. 10. 10. And that's different from service?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No. No. I'm talking together the engineering -- to engineering on services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Above 10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But you are excluding the engineering to orders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I'm excluding the engineering to orders, which are power control centers, motor control centers, those kinds of things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And by when you think you can get to 15 there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was telling you that I think it will be one of the ambition that we are going to affirm in our next company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's for '09. Okay. Okay. Great. Thank you guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. James Stettler from Dresdner. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of your guidance for the second half, obviously, a slowdown is forecast. Where do you really see that coming through? And then in terms of the margin, looking out to next six months, where do you see the biggest risk to the margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in the next coming six months, I would say there has to be a slowdown. I would repeat what I said about the changes of trend on the market; that there will be more traditional activities coming through the residential in Europe, and some slowdown in some of the construction activities. But again, compensated largely by the data centers, energy efficiency services, solutions.</p>
          <p>So but probably the weakest -- the weaker point will be on the side of construction in the U.S., and probably some slowdown in some construction in -- or in residential in Europe. Risks on margin, today we are pretty bullish about that. I mean we are working on our margins and pricing, we are working on productivity. You know that we have an outsourced model in China, a lots which is working with external suppliers.</p>
          <p>When the growth is strong, it's probably less efficient in terms of margin than in integrating model, because your suppliers have a lot of work and they impose somewhat higher conditions. When the times are becoming a bit rougher, then it's easier for us to ask for some understanding from our suppliers. So we work on the margin. The other thing that we didn't touch very much here is the support function costs that we are keeping on trimming in the West, I mean, Western Europe and North America. And we've done a pretty good job there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You talk a bit about labor inflation and, obviously, your ability to continue to offset material inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what we want to do, and so far it has been very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But at the same time, James, don't forget, while you have labor inflation, but as you rebalance, also every time you rebalance labor, and you recognize a jump in cost that offset that at the level of your labor costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Alfred Glaser from Cheuvreux. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I also wanted to ask about the cost inflation. You had a good performance in the first half on your manufacturing cost inflation and support function cost. Do you think that you can go on with that type of increased levels? Or do you think that these will be higher or lower going forward and into the following quarters?</p>
          <p>I've had two other questions. One on tax rate. The decrease was very steep in the first half of this year. Do you think that you can go on with such a tax rate decrease in the following half years as well? And finally, one question on pricing, and I think I missed the price increase in Europe. Could you just please give us the figure for Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Cost inflation, first of all, to avoid any misunderstanding, if you are looking at page 23, what is captured is labor manufacturing cost inflation, i.e., the 44 million euro, which is indicated on this chart is the labor manufacturing inflation, the impact of labor manufacturing. And the answer to your question is, yes. As we said it, we are confident that through our price increases will be able to make up for the combination of raw material price increase, labor manufacturing price increases, and oil in transportation.</p>
          <p>And we achieve 126% in the first half of this year. We're confident that we should post a similar ratio in the second half of the year. Regarding tax rate, yes, again, our objective is an effective tax rate for the Group of 26% in the years to come. So we are on good track. We move down from 30% to 26.6 in the first half, and we should be in a position to deliver this target. And regarding the pricing in Europe, if my memory is correct, is 1.7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Martin Wilkie from Deutsche Bank. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Martin again, just with a follow-up question. Can you just tell us what you're seeing in emerging markets in terms of the growth profile? Obviously, it's been a big boost to your sales over the past couple of years. You are seeing some, perhaps, more negative commentary coming out of things like competence indicators in China, these kinds of things. Could you just let us know what you're seeing in the emerging markets in terms of, i.e., the potential growth profile over the next six to 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I repeat what I've said. We see no weakening. I indicate -- I've already developed that, but you have several models of development. One is linked to the local market. I mean, emergence of middle class, which you see, for instance, very strongly in Russia, you see that in China, you see that in India, you see that in Brazil. That's one.</p>
          <p>Second engine for growth is oil price, even if it does slightly decrease, it remains at a very high price and driving investment and driving profits in the countries owning oil. And so that oil benefits to us on the two aspects, investment directly in oil and gas where we operate, petrol dollars, which are recycled in more projects that's good to us. And by the way, the other good news with high oil price for Schneider is that the payback for any energy efficiency investment is reduced. So that is helping a lot on the energy efficiency market.</p>
          <p>The other engine for growth in emerging markets is everything in mining and minerals extraction. A lot of projects there; where we are very well positioned with automation and power; and more and more power monitoring, by the way. So, again the story of energy efficiency and energy consumption coming in. And there is another thing, which is purification. I mean the grids, once you have a generation plant installed, once you have the T&amp;D line installed, very seldom remains it alone in the countryside. I mean, you've got to distribute that energy, and the purification is really driving a lot of our growth there also in those countries.</p>
          <p>So we see very strong markets in emerging today. And don't forget one thing, is that there are many of those countries where we're just a representation only seven years ago. We've invested a lot in those countries to have a real local presence with local partners, with distributors, with local logistics, with local representation. So the platform that we have today is important now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I guess the concern is more from the sort of macro level. You're seeing a lot more in the press about -- for example, this morning some of the conference indicators coming into China are slightly weaker. So it was just more if that's what these sort of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look. There are many macro indicators these days, and it's -- the good thing is that we are close to our customers. So I mean, if you look only the macro indicators, you would have stopped many things a long time ago. But our business is not to be reading only the newspapers, but it's to be doing business. And it's clear that what you see in the field can be quite different from the things that are written in London, Paris or New York, in those countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can take a last question. I think it's 11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The last question is from Mr. Peter Testa from One Investments. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I have three questions. There are certain things that people often cite is concerns in Schneider. You've addressed quite a number today. I just have three left. I was wondering if you could help understand a bit better. One is as your mix shift with low cost countries, which has been, traffic slows down and lower cost country inflation picks up, whether the net benefit will disappear?</p>
          <p>Secondly is on data centers, which has been strongly growing. Why that will sustain itself into a generally slowing business in commercial investment? And the third thing is, is just on the building segment where, obviously, the slowing commercial construction environment, your views and visibility on that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm not -- I didn't understand your first point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As your transition towards low cost countries slows down, and as inflation picks up in low cost countries, what are the benefits that you've seen? Accrued will be less of a positive factor going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have many remedies to that. One of the major remedies is that we are still a net exported to low cost countries. There is still a lot of euro-based cost going into low cost countries for sales. And we keep on rebalancing and relocalizing and every time we increase our margin. So just that is one.</p>
          <p>And the second thing that I'm very pleased with is that we are -- what we are doing today in terms of mastering our prices also in those countries, and learning how to pass the right price at the right moment to the right customer. So I think there is space also for that which is very clear.</p>
          <p>Second element, which is the market for the data centers. The market of data centers is not related to the commercial building at all. A big part of that market is linked to the IT, the digitization of our society. That means every time we do most things on the web, every time we watch video on the web, every time we go more on the networks, every time a company is going from paper documents to digital documents that is generating a lot of demand for data centers. Add to that that many data centers are obsolete in terms of conception, since the time just started at the beginning of the century, and there is a lot of retrofit and revamp going into the data centers anyway because the technology is not up to date.</p>
          <p>If you want to get great servers you can't do it, if you want to be competitive, you can't do it with old technology of data center. You have to add to that that energy. With the change of technology in server electronics, energy has become a big part of the equation of data centers. So data center managers are really keen now on re-looking at their data center to make them more cost efficient, energy efficient. And it's clear that APC and MGE, but APC particularly, has a system called infrastructure, which is incredibly more performing in the field of energy efficiency than any of its competitors.</p>
          <p>Now back to the building and the construction, don't forget that there is a significant part of what we do in buildings, which is second round and retrofit, especially in the mature world. We don't see any issue today in the building, pockets in emerging countries. By the way, we are intentionally less exposed to building in those emerging countries. We do much more in infrastructure. We do more in industrial applications. But in the mature countries, what we do in the buildings there is a lot which is second round and retrofit. And especially what we do in the field of energy savings, on energy consumption, is coming back on existing buildings. So it's not tooling to the new construction. It's more linked to our capacity to come back on the building and property improvements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you very much for those answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, we appreciate your time, especially on 1 of August, and your attention. Thank you for all the questions that were asked to us. We are -- well, we are happy and proud of the results we produced, and confident in what we are going to produce. See you very soon anyway after some of us or some of you take a deserved break during the summer. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you all for attending. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>