<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1450067" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2952</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Jennifer Gough</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Michael T. Mack</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">John Ramsay</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Jeremy M. Redenius</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Neil C. Tyler</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS AG (Broker)">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">Tony G. Jones</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Helvea SA">Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Andrew G. Stott</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Vontobel Equity Research AG">Patrick Rafaisz</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="ING Bank NV (Broker)">Fabian Smeets</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrew G. Benson</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Jaideep Pandya</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Richard Logan</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Virginie Boucher-Ferte</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Syngenta Full Year 2011 Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode until we conduct the question and answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Just to remind you, this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to your Chairperson, Jennifer Gough. Please begin your meeting and I'll be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to the call. Today's presentation will be given by Mike Mack, CEO; and John Ramsay, CFO. The slides to accompany the presentation are available on the Syngenta website.</p>
          <p>Could I first just read the cautionary statement from slide number two? This presentation contains forward-looking statements, which can be identified by terminology such as expect, would, will, on track and similar expressions. Such statements may be subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause the actual results to differ from these statements. We refer you to Syngenta's publicly available filings at the U.S. SEC for information about these and other risks.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll hand you over to Mike, who will begin on slide number three, delivering our performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jennifer. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Syngenta today announced a very strong performance in the first year of implementing our integrated strategy, which we announced one year ago. The increase in volume alone for our combined business represented $1.2 billion in additional sales, and we believe that we've gained market share as a result.</p>
          <p>In addition, pricing across the group was positive with crop protection in the fourth quarter registering a 4% increase. We therefore exceeded our 2011 objective of achieving overall price stability. The target we set for ourselves in 2007 to improve the profitability of the seeds business while simultaneously growing it was also exceeded with an EBITDA margin of 17.1% versus the 15% target.</p>
          <p>Record free cash flow of $1.5 billion is enabling us to increase the proposed cash returned to shareholders with the dividend raised to CHF8 per share and a further share repurchase of $200 million. So overall, we're very pleased with the outcome, which in a year of transition demonstrates our ability to grow the business, as well as increase profitability.</p>
          <p>Slide four gives you some of the industry context. Agriculture remained robust in 2011 despite the prevailing the economic uncertainty. And indeed, many growers realized record incomes. High crop prices encouraged investment, resulting in record global output. But in the important U.S. market, production was lower as both cereals and corn were affected by adverse weather. These differing outcomes contributed to crop price volatility. But overall crop prices remained above historical levels owing to growth in demand. This was highlighted in the case of China where imports of both corn and soy bean increased significantly. At the same time though, emerging markets continued their productivity drive, propelled not only by a desire for self-sufficiency but also by their increasing role in international trade as shown, for example, by the surge in Russian wheat exports.</p>
          <p>Slide five. Our new strategy announced last February is based on three core objectives: integrate, innovate and outperform. Integration of our commercial teams is ahead of schedule, and we're building on our strong platform of products to launch fully integrated offers. A number of these offers are already in the market and their success is a validation of the strategy we are now pursuing.</p>
          <p>On innovation, we're bringing together our R&amp;D scientists to promote the development of new combined chemical and genetic solutions on a global crop basis. We've defined pipelines for each of our eight key crops with a combined value of over $22 billion post-2015. And it's this pipeline that will enable us to outperform for our customers in the field.</p>
          <p>We're also firmly on track for financial outperformance, and let me now hand over to John Ramsay, who will be pleased to tell you more about that. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Mike. Good morning. Our results announced this morning demonstrate a very strong business performance, reflecting continued volume momentum and positive prices.</p>
          <p>Starting on slide seven, you can see that the 2011 sales increased 14% and at constant exchange rates were up 12%. Volume increased 11% and price was 1% higher, reflecting a positive price environment in the second half across all regions. EBITDA increased by 18% at constant exchange rates to $2.9 billion. Net income at $1.6 billion was up 14%, reflecting higher depreciation and amortization together with restructuring and impairment costs.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share increased by 18% to reach $19.36. And record free cash flow of $1.5 billion was driven by a higher EBITDA and our effective management of working capital. And this strong cash position has enabled us to propose a dividend increase of 14% to CHF8 per share. In U.S. dollar, the increase will be 15% at current exchange rates. And finally, our cash flow return on investment at 14% was above our target level.</p>
          <p>Turning now to slide eight, you can see the evolution of reported sales. Volume growth of $1.2 billion was driven by both crop protection and seeds with a notably strong performance in emerging markets. Volume growth in those markets contributed some $800 million, demonstrating the continued level of technology acceleration and the sustained high level of return on our growth investments.</p>
          <p>Price for the full year was positive in both crop protection and seeds with a marked improvement in the second half. And I will come back to crop protection pricing in more detail in a moment. You can also see from the slide a favorable impact of $283 million, up 2% from currency primarily emanating from markets in Europe, Australia and Canada.</p>
          <p>The next few slides show in more detail the performance of our crop protection business. So please turn to slide nine. Sales at constant exchange rates rose 12% to $10.2 billion. Volume was 11% higher with a strong growth across all regions.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned previously, we saw an improving trend in price, up 1% for the year and 4% in the second half. Sales in Europe were up 11% at constant exchange rates with growth in both emerging and developed markets. Particularly notable was the performance in France driven by the rapid adoption of the cereal herbicide AXIAL and the success of CRUISER seed treatment.</p>
          <p>Emerging market growth was fueled by an upturn in productivity, as well as an expansion in our herbicide business. North America had a strong year driven primarily by increased fungicide application rates as well as the success of both our crop enhancement and weed resistance products.</p>
          <p>Latin America continued its strong performance with sales up 17% for the year. Significant growth in both insecticides and seed care reflected the success of new product launches. Brazil is now similar in size to the United States, reaffirming the importance of this strategic and fast growing market.</p>
          <p>Emerging Asia continued to perform extremely well with sales up 12%. EBITDA, $2.5 billion represented a margin of 24.4%, up 60 basis points at constant exchange rates. In line with our guidance in July, we achieved in the second half a substantial improvement in underlying crop protection profitability, demonstrated in the higher EBITDA margin. And this is due in part to the increased weighting of our business in the second half, but particularly, to the margin improvement from price increases and the operational leverage benefits from the new integrated strategy.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to slide 10, which shows you the performance of our new products launched since 2006. Sales rose 50% in 2011 to reach $619 million with a compound annual growth rate of 55% over this period. This strong performance illustrates the substantial future potential of these products. Sales of our nematicide seed treatment, AVICTA, grew over 150% following success on cotton in both Brazil and the United States.</p>
          <p>AXIAL continued to record strong volume growth notably in the cereals markets of France and Iberia. Our broad spectrum insecticide DURIVO was highly successful in both Brazil, where sales increased three-fold and in Asia. Worldwide DURIVO sales increased 85%. REVUS growth was primarily driven by Europe linked to an increase in potato <mark type="ph" /> fly (9:58). SEGURIS also saw significant growth in Europe, driven by the successful launches on both barley and wheat. Registrations have now been received across several countries and crops. Our new seed treatment, VIBRANCE, has recently received approvals in Argentina and France and will be a further addition to our new product portfolio.</p>
          <p>As slide 11 shows volume momentum has been maintained throughout the year. General market sentiment has remained positive across all regions supported by the continued relatively high soft commodity prices. Volume levels in quarter four remained strong, although tempered by the decision to reduce sales during the morte saison in France. And this had the effect of reducing quarter four volumes by around 2 percentage points.</p>
          <p>As well as volume growth, 2011 surpassed our target of price stability, achieving 1% increase for the full year. As you recall, first half price was down 2% and we took specific price actions in the second half, which resulted in a significant improvement across all regions and a positive price performance of 4%. As we previously communicated, we expect the realization of further price increases as we move into the 2012 Northern Hemisphere season and we anticipate that these will be in the range of 2% to 3%.</p>
          <p>Slide 12 shows the highlights of our seeds performance. Sales increased 12% to $3.2 billion. Volume was up 9% and prices up 3%. Volume growth was driven primarily by Corn &amp; Soybean and Diverse Field Crops. Latin America seed sales increased 34% with growth being driven by the success of our sunflowers business in Argentina, as well as the rapid customer adoption of our Corn &amp; Soybean technology.</p>
          <p>North American customer adoption of our corn technology offer was also strong with growth in corn sales of over 30% and an increase in market share of around 1% to 11% and we see this as a notable achievement in a market where we had previously lost share and provides recognition of the strength of our improved portfolio. EBITDA in seeds increased by over 50% to reach $544 million, representing a margin of 17.1%, far exceeding the 15% margin target. Our portfolio evolution into higher value products has been reflected in the gross margin expansion, which increased by around 200 basis points.</p>
          <p>Slide 13 shows the rapid progression of the seeds EBITDA margin since 2007. Over the same period, sales have expanded from $2 billion to $3.2 billion as we have developed our trait and germplasm portfolio across all crops. We expect further margin expansion in seeds contributing to the achievement of our group EBITDA margin target of 22% to 24% in 2015.</p>
          <p>Emerging markets have played an important role in this expansion with growth in 2011 of over 20%, largely driven by Latin America and CIS. Our sustained investment in R&amp;D, 13% of sales last year, has brought us to the point where we are not only a top competitor across crops but also now recognized for the quality of our innovation.</p>
          <p>This record of innovation is also enabling us to generate licensing revenue, which last year included $50 million from Pioneer relating to our first generation Agrisure corn rootworm trait. And given the strength of our proprietary traits, we would expect further licensing opportunities to materialize.</p>
          <p>Slide 14 shows you the progression of group operating income, which increased 17% to reach $2.3 billion. As you can see, the operating profit from volume at $546 million was the largest single contributor to the growth. A positive price impact of $148 million reflects the 1% price gain at the combined business level. Our saving of $132 million, including $112 million from our new program, exceeded the $75 million target that we communicated with the announcement of our new strategy last year. At the same time, we continued to make important growth investments in emerging markets, research and development and in information systems. Cost inflation, relating largely to emerging markets, reached $70 million. And other business expenses increased by $204 million, linked in part to higher variable compensation. And finally, currency reduced operating income by $91 million.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 15. Here you can see the details of the phasing of the expected $650 million of cost savings as well as the updated phasing of the associated costs. We've now integrated 16 of the 19 territories with the remaining three to be completed by mid-2012. In 2012, we expect to deliver $300 billion of cumulative savings and remain on track to deliver our original target. Restructuring cost was slightly lower than expected this year due to phasing but remained unchanged versus the original estimate of $400 million.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the impact of currencies and oil prices. On slide 16, we can see the major currency and oil price movement since 2008 through to the end of 2011. And starting first with currencies. Our full-year currency impact at EBITDA level was $52 million adverse, which is slightly better than the guidance provided during the half one results.</p>
          <p>And the chart in this slide illustrates the increased volatility in currencies over the last year. The volatility in emerging market currencies in the last quarter of 2011 resulted in higher adverse currency impacts, which were partially mitigated by the stabilization of the Swiss franc following its peg to the euro in September.</p>
          <p>We have a great deal of experience in developing our business in volatile markets and our hedging program allows us to manage our underlying business in any one year independent of currency movements.</p>
          <p>At a high level, you can think about our currency exposure in three elements. We have a long exposure to emerging market currencies, a long exposure to the euro, and a short exposure to the Swiss franc. As a result, in 2012, the strong Swiss franc and generally weaker emerging market currencies will have a negative impact.</p>
          <p>And coming to the price of oil, you can see on the chart that this has also been volatile. The increase in average prices since 2010 will, due to lead times in our supply chain, result in higher raw material costs in 2012.</p>
          <p>In combination, I anticipate our exposure to currencies and raw materials will create a headwind in 2012 of around $300 million to $350 million. However, I expect this headwind to be more than offset by price increases and cost savings.</p>
          <p>Looking now on slide 17 at our earnings per share performance, earnings per share, excluding restructuring, was 18% higher at $19.36. Net income rose 14%, reflecting higher operating income. Our overall tax rate remained stable at 17%, reflecting our continued focus on tax optimization. Whilst we have had for a number of years a low tax rate through specific optimization measures, I do expect the underlying longer-term rate to be around 20%.</p>
          <p>And turning now to look at cash flow on slide 18, free cash flow reached a record $1.5 billion. The improvement was largely driven by the increase in EBITDA. Absolute levels of working capital increased year-on-year, however, as you will see on the next slide, reduced as a percentage of sales. Capital expenditure at $575 million was up marginally on 2010 with the restructuring cost broadly flat year-on-year. Financing and tax expenses at $249 million were down from 2010. And although free cash flow in 2012 may be somewhat below the exceptional 2011 level, we do expect strong cash generation to continue as an ongoing feature of our business.</p>
          <p>Slide 19. As we saw in the previous slide, our strong cash generation has contributed to the maintenance of solid balance sheet ratios. Average trade working capital as a percentage of sales improved 2% to 37%, and the improvement was driven by low inventory levels and rigorous receivables management.</p>
          <p>On the bar chart, you can see the 2011 sales collection ratios in the Europe, Africa and Middle East region, the troubled euro GIPS countries and the CIS. In all cases, our year-end collection ratios are ahead of last year reflecting the rigor that has been established in recent years in our credit management organization. I would like to highlight that in 2011 we did benefit from lower inventory levels and I would expect a small increase in trade working capital ratios in 2012.</p>
          <p>The strength of our balance sheet is reflected in our gearing ratio, which at 15% is significantly below last year. And this ratio provides us with the confidence in our ability to manage the business through volatile market conditions and thus create a potential for us to further increase the cash returned to shareholders, which we have demonstrated today through the proposed dividend increase. And last year, we introduced cash flow return on investment as our new balance sheet measure, aiming to achieve returns in excess of 12%, which we achieved this year with a ratio of 14%, which is an increase on 2010.</p>
          <p>On slide 20, you can see the trend in cash generation over the past seven years and represented in the bars how we have used the cash generated. The total cash returned to shareholders in 2011 totaled $903 million, which was composed of a $198 million share buyback program and a dividend of CHF7 per share. As I previously mentioned, in 2012, we will propose to increase the dividend by 14% to CHF8. And in addition, we are trying to repurchase a further $200 million of shares. And this will equate to an estimated cash return to shareholders of around $1 billion.</p>
          <p>While acquisition levels have been low in 2010 and 2011, we will maintain a strong balance sheet to allow us the flexibility to continue to make growth investments and seek out future acquisition opportunities. As we communicated last year, we remain committed to a progressive dividend as our preferred method of cash return, and we will use the share buyback tactically when the balance sheet permits.</p>
          <p>On slide 21, you can see a reminder of our management structure, both John and Davor, each of have a responsibility for an emerging and the developed region, as well as the combination of global field and high-value customer-focused crops. The significant progress we have made in implementation of our new operating model has facilitated an accelerated move towards reporting our business in accordance with this new management structure.</p>
          <p>From half one 2012, we will provide you with sales and profitability on an integrated basis from each of the four regions, as well as a global view of the Lawn &amp; Garden business. We will no longer provide separate segment profitability, but we will continue to report crop protection and seed sales on a product line basis and, in addition, provide estimated sales on a crop basis. I would point out that sales reported by crop will be on an unaudited basis owning to the multi-crop uses of many of our chemical products. And we will, of course, provide you with full pro forma historical figures in advance of the first half results.</p>
          <p>Turning now to slide 22, you can see an illustration of what this will look like. The chart in the left shows the sales split that you are currently familiar with by major product lines. Note that professional products and flowers will, in future, be reported together under Lawn &amp; Garden.</p>
          <p>The chart on the right shows the integrated crop protection and seed sales by region. As I have just said, we will provide from the half year both sales and profitability figures on this basis. In addition, as Mike will introduce in a later slide, you will see integrated sales by crop.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, slide 23 summarizes our 2012 financial outlook. Although it is early in the season and there is continued uncertainty in the macroeconomic environment, we believe the fundamentals of our business remain strong. We expect to see continued volume momentum, as well as higher prices as we enter the new season.</p>
          <p>We anticipate price increases in the range of 2% to 3% and further cost savings from our new strategy. And I expect the combined effects of price increases and cost savings to more than offset the estimated $300 million to $350 million currency and raw material headwind that I've outlined earlier.</p>
          <p>Consequently, I would expect to see for the group as a whole increased profitability versus 2011 at constant exchange rates, putting us firmly on track to achieve a 22% to 24% EBITDA margin by 2015.</p>
          <p>In addition, I would expect cash flow levels to remain strong and for it to continue to exceed CFROI levels of 12%. We are optimistic about the year ahead but will continue to exert vigilance in monitoring the volatile market environment.</p>
          <p>And with that, I would like to hand you back to Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. As you see now on slide 25, we are already measuring the growth of our business on a crop-by-crop basis. There are many growth drivers within each of these crops and here you see listed just one example for each.</p>
          <p>In corn, the return on our investment traits is now rising with the uptake of our technology in Latin America. As a result of this, together with the benefit of an integrated sales force, we expect to see market share gain for the current Latin American season. The Vegetables business where we have leading positions in both crop protection and seeds will continue to evolve through pipeline projects such as novel seed care application techniques.</p>
          <p>In soybean, we're particularly excited about the launch of integrated rust solutions planned for the end of this year. The combination of rust tolerant rates and new chemistry will accelerate rust control to altogether higher levels.</p>
          <p>In 2011, cereals had two important launches, VIBRANCE seed care and SEGURIS broad-spectrum fungicide. This coming year, we see the expanded rollout of both of these products. Growth in diverse field crops reflects the success of our high value sunflower hybrids. Development of an integrated broomrape control system will be another critical tool for growers in the area of high weed infestation.</p>
          <p>And finally in 2011, we launched Tegra and PLENE, integrated solutions for rice and sugarcane, both of which have been met with enthusiastic response from our growers. Looking forward to 2012, we will be further expanding the reach of both of these programs.</p>
          <p>Slide 26 now shows you the scale of our ambition for these crops. With the acceleration of integrated offers, we expect sales to surpass $22 billion post 2015. Those of who you attended our Capital Markets Day last summer will see that we've now added specialty crop sales into the pipeline and I'll speak more about those opportunities in just a moment.</p>
          <p>Achieving this pace of growth will mean redefining our markets and inventing new segments to create additional value. This is a key remit for our newly created global crop teams and one which is also permeating our R&amp;D organization. Our strategy has the potential to expand the size of the overall market with the integration of adjacent technologies and partnerships adding yet a further dimension.</p>
          <p>The realization of this pipeline will enable us to outperform the competition and to achieve our objective of an annual average 0.5% market share gain. It will also lead to superior value creation for our customers and for our shareholders. In a moment, I will show a couple of examples of how our broad portfolio is being integrated to meet different grower challenges. But first let's look briefly at Lawn &amp; Garden, which was, in fact, our first integrated business and where the creation of partnerships is already playing an important role.</p>
          <p>Slide 27. The total Lawn &amp; Garden market is valued at over $50 billion with $9 billion being the professional market where we focus our activities. In 2011, our sales were $847 million, giving us a 12% share of the market excluding fertilizer where we do not participate. In this business, we brought together chemistry, growing media and genetics to offer a fully integrated service to our customers. Value chain account management and a strong customer facing marketing program, those which promote solutions that are attractive to both retailers and growers are creating pull for our products.</p>
          <p>The ability to provide integrated offers has led to strategic partnerships with companies such as Marriott Hotels, where we provide a program that helps reduce their carbon footprint and meet sustainability targets in golf course care. The partnership with Illumitex, a specialty precision light company, is for the development of superior lighting systems, which will allow us to accelerate and control plant growth rates.</p>
          <p>Please turn now to slide 28 for some insights on how we're meeting grower challenges in some key crops. Resistance management is not new. It's an ongoing problem spanning many crops. Our complete toolbox in soybean, which you can see in the left-hand chart has meant that we're uniquely placed to deal with the onset of resistant weeds in soybeans containing Roundup Ready technology. And this has been caused by the overuse of glyphosate across crop locations and today, there are 11 glyphosate-resistant species in the U.S. and 21 species confirmed globally.</p>
          <p>Our portfolio of pre- and post-emergent herbicides, in some cases marketed as premixes with glyphosate, deals effectively with the problem and as the chart shows has seen rapid growth as a result. We see this growth continuing with the number of reported cases of weed resistance expected to double over the next five years. But with this period, we will also be working on a new trait, which is tolerant to HPPD herbicides.</p>
          <p>The right-hand chart relates to an emerging issue around resistance to insect traits in corn. Firstly, let me say that we've seen no evidence of resistance to our proprietary Agrisure triple stack. But this is not the key point. Our distinction is that we've developed a superior toolbox in corn, incorporating both well established as well as new technology that give growers comprehensive protection against insects as well as nematodes.</p>
          <p>And we'll be supplementing that package with the launch of our second generation corn rootworm trait, Agrisure Duracade, which has an altogether new mode of action. Thus a deep toolkit can be exceeding effective in dealing with long-standing grower problems, such as pest resistance, single-product technologies across multiple crops irrespective of whether those technologies are chemical or genetically modified traits.</p>
          <p>Slide 29 takes us from the U.S. Corn &amp; Soybean regions to the rice paddies of Asia. The products on the chart form a complete program used by rice growers with tailored inputs for each part of the growing cycle. The program includes optimized hybrids, seed care and a full range of crop protection, including our blockbuster products AMISTAR and CRUISER and our new product Virtako, which is part of the DURIVO family.</p>
          <p>We're also incorporating these products into our Tegra-integrated solution for rice, which can increase yields for smallholder farmers by an average of 30%. A complete toolkit here is the enabler to fully optimize solutions for the grower, convenient, reliable and backed by a single sales organization, which can stand behind the assurance of a profitable outcome.</p>
          <p>Slide 30 gives you a brief insight now into the scale and potential of our specialty crop business with sales of just over $2 billion last year, expected to reach $4 billion post-2015. Five crops currently make up 70% of sales with potatoes and cotton being the two largest. Again, blockbuster chemistry plays a key role, including AMISTAR fungicide and our insecticide, ACTARA, which contains the same active ingredient as CRUISER.</p>
          <p>As with our vegetables business, value creation across the chain is a key driver for many of these crops. It means meeting challenges such as uniform quality, high visual appeal and increased shelf life. Integrated offers and new business models will play an increasingly important role in driving growth. In the agreement signed last year with Funda&#xE7;&#xE3;o in Brazil to distribute their cottonseed is just one such example.</p>
          <p>Slide 31. Before I conclude, let me set out the way we plan to communicate progress on our key crops going forward. We plan to hold two crop updates per year covering two crops per event, and these will be hosted by Chief Operating Officer, John Atkin and Davor Pisk for each of their respective crops. The first update will be held on May 11 in the form of a webcast, which will cover corn and cereals. Then in September, we plan to cover rice and vegetables, this time though on the ground in India, which is an important market for both of these crops and you will be receiving invitation with details of the events shortly. Events focusing then on specialty crops and Diverse Field Crops, as well as sugarcane and soybean will be held in 2013.</p>
          <p>Please turn now to the final slide, slide 32. In 2012, we expect continuing growth in demand to support further market expansion, and our aim is to again outpace the competition. We expect to show an increase in profitability at constant exchange rates and continued strong cash flow generation. We will also accelerate the development of our integrated offers and we look forward to bringing some of those offers to light for you at the investor events I've just outlined.</p>
          <p>That concludes our presentation today. And John and I will now be happy to take your questions. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Jeremy Redenius. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. This is Jeremy Redenius from Sanford Bernstein. I have a few questions. First on the price increases that you've implemented, I'm wondering if you're seeing similar pricing movements from your peers. And also we saw an evidence of lower fungicide relief in the U.S. with you and your peers moving similarly versus last year with lower rebates versus last year. I'm wondering if you're seeing kind of evidence that they are moving in a similar way elsewhere.</p>
          <p>Second, are you seeing any threats to your AMISTAR franchise? For example, we've seen United Phosphorus getting registration for azoxystrobin in the UK. I'm wondering if you've seen competition there or elsewhere? And then &#x2013; sorry, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, Jeremy, you had a final question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, I guess, the other one would be price increases on seeds. I know you're facing some cost inflation in seeds as well and are your price increases you are getting in seeds sufficient to you to keep pace with that cost inflation. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, thank you for that. First of all, you might know that we got out there in the first half of last year, 2011, in having led price increases and as John said a moment ago, we finished the year with a good momentum on that coming into now 2012. When we put up our list prices in both Europe as well as LatAm and North America, we got some followership but it was not &#x2013; it was rather modest. So that's both, of course, good news and bad news and would have been &#x2013; I would prefer to see it a bit more robust. As a consequence though, the fungicide discounting that was pretty prevalent in 2010 is not as pronounced, and we're looking forward to a strong season. But that season won't get underway for another few weeks as you know.</p>
          <p>Your second question, so pricing, and you've referred to them as our peers, we think about them as our competitors, of course. And there's still quite a bit of in-season activity that will occur in North America and Europe. But we're encouraged by the momentum coming out of LatAm the end of 2011 and we'll see what this season brings.</p>
          <p>On AMISTAR, look we have always assumed that we were going to have competition for this compound. It's more than $1 billion. We have the highest quality. And by the way, not all quality is created equal on fungicides. It's got a great brand. It's very often commixed with other fungicides that we have. We are the low-cost manufacturer in the world by far. And we have already enabled a number of our competitors to deal with some straight products.</p>
          <p>So I think the strategy that we've outlined for AMISTAR is a strong one. It follows a recipe that we've executed pretty well over the years. And I think we would have assumed that competition will continue to come but we're prepared to fully defend the product. And there's nothing about 2012 or 2013 or 2014 frankly that give us great deal of heartburn around the AMISTAR franchise.</p>
          <p>Finally, the seeds, you're right to point out that the growing season for the hybrids last year was a higher-cost environment than planned. It was tough summer for a lot of seed production in the U.S. forcing us to go down to have more of a wintered market in Argentina than we otherwise would normally plan on but the cost increases will be more than offset by the price increases. So we're going to see some seeds price increases in the low double digits in the U.S. in 2012 but, of course, that is &#x2013; totting all that up is yet to be done. So John anything else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that's right. I think the straightforward answer, we're going to cover the costs on the price increases. And we'll also get some additional mix benefit as the portfolio moves on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeremy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Neil Tyler. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning. It's JPMorgan. A couple of questions, as well, please. Firstly, on the new strategy and the initial implication of that, I wondered if you could just discuss whether that is impacting the seasonality or timing of sales in any of your more significant crop protection products.</p>
          <p>Second question, with regards &#x2013; back to seeds and with regards to the Viptera issue and the registration of that in China, if you could give us an update on whether you think that's still expected in April of this year. Is that still your expectation? And also whether you've seen any knock-on effect on your sales in the early part of the season in the U.S. from last year's issues?</p>
          <p>And then finally with reference to slide 14, your operating profit bridge, I wondered if you could discuss a little bit more within the other category, the source in cost inflation, you mentioned variable compensation was within that. Does that also include the increase in depreciation year-on-year?</p>
          <p>And also, whereabouts do you include the hedging gain, $170 odd million of hedging gain, is that netted off against FX? And with regards to the variable compensation, if you could perhaps discuss a little bit upon what basis that is awarded, so that we can sort of have a go at modeling that for next year. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, by the way, the variable compensation piece, I'll just take that and otherwise ask John to handle the third question. And I'll start off then with both the ICS questions. In the variable comp piece, I think we have a very extensive description of how all the variable comp works was in the company in the company's compensation report and that will be issued, Jennifer, I think in March 14. So we won't otherwise, get into the mechanics of that. But the strength of 2011 drove some of that, so we had a good year. And the mechanics are all low &#x2013; we get generally very high marks on our transparency about how that works.</p>
          <p>First question on ICS. ICS has gone really well and we're pleased with it. It was in the works for a couple of years as a strategic gaming point, Neil. And then the implementation, as you heard, has gone better than planned. Customers have embraced it. And customers, I mean, are retailers and distributors as well as growers. But it had otherwise nothing to do with the CP programs that you've referred to because the programs of 2011 were, of course, all initiated in 2010 before we announced the strategy to our employees.</p>
          <p>On seeds, Viptera. Viptera is doing great. We've sold out of it. And it's the best product that we have in the portfolio. Of course, we wish we had more. And, no, the answer is it had the China &#x2013; the absence of Chinese approval had absolutely no knock-on effect to that because Viptera had largely been sold out beforehand. The answer on the approval is, yes, we still expect approval for Viptera from China in the April timeframe.</p>
          <p>John, the operating bridge?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The number of other &#x2013; the specific answer to your question, Neil, is that it does not include depreciation that's largely &#x2013; increased depreciation is largely manufacturing going to volume. It also does not include the hedging, which is offset against the currency. And the reason why we flagged it up this year in values is largely because of the increase of the variable compensation in 2010. If you remember, 2010 was a low growth year in terms of profitability. So it's figuring up on the walk in terms of a significant move.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just I wonder if we could just quickly follow up on the other, obviously, major moving part is the growth investments. In the past, at this stage, you've been able to give us some indication of the extent to which you expect that to materialize in the following year, and I wonder if you're able to do that now for the 2012 versus 2011 in terms of the fixed costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The growth investments are going to continue to be a feature of our function cost expenses going to continue into 2012. In relation to our new strategy, we see a lot of opportunity, which just needs to be funded. So 2011, we funded somewhere around $130 million to $135 million of growth investments. In 2012, it will be higher and we'll continue to fund growth investments with a variety of projects.</p>
          <p>And having said that though, what we have done in 2011 and despite the growth investments, despite cost inflation figures that you see, we've managed to improve the profitability in relation to expenses by 80 basis points in terms of percentage opposite sales, we're improving the leverage and we'll see continued improvements in the leverage, I think, in 2012 despite further growth investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Thomas Gilbert. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. UBS in Zurich. Three questions please. On slide 25, in the new reporting structure, you kindly provided the growth rates by crop in the integrated crop products. Can I just ask sugarcane obviously has the strongest growth and they are all pretty similar except for vegetables, which is well documented, why that wasn't as high as maybe expected. But the sugarcane is very strong. Where are we on the launch cycle for PLENE, is that accelerating the growth rate from here? Also, is the sweet spot in terms of the launch volume still to come or is that a growth rate you're expecting to continue to see for one, two seasons. That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is, you mentioned a strong performance from licensing and I interpret that as royalty payments in seeds business to licensed growers. Can you confirm that that is a recurring royalty income that we can model a growth rate around that is somehow related to this growth rate in seeds, or were there some one-off lump sum royalty payments in that licensing income in 2011?</p>
          <p>And the third question is staying with seeds in Latin America, can you give a bit of color and as precise as you possibly can on the Latin American traded offer in corn? What your overall branded feature is and how many acres you expect to plant in 2012 with biotechnology? That would be much appreciated. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, Thomas. Maybe I can start with the growth rates in sugarcane, which you spoke of. As you might know, PLENE is virtually a brand new technology, and we're learning as we go. We've got at the initial launch year some $300 million to $500 million of offer of customers lined up for a technology. We're massively expanding the production capacity that we have at <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:27) in Brazil. And everything is going really well.</p>
          <p>But part of the encouraging thing about this integrated approach is we're also seeing that we're getting some terrific pull-through with our crop protection chemistry in sugarcane just by virtue of having more proximity to these growers and more sub-proximity to the kinds of things that they're worried about. So PLENE in the sugarcane will be &#x2013; I think, for the coming years, is going to be a very attractive growth market for us.</p>
          <p>And in vegetables, the same thing, vegetable seed as such had a bit of a more difficult year in North America as well as Europe on account of the recession or the slow growth in the economy. But by and large, and we've got leading offer in the world, and we've got a big broad spectrum of high-production chemicals. So that vegetable business is going to continue to outpace, I would say, the non-traited part of the field crops over the coming years. John, a bit more detail then on the licensing and maybe the seeds, LatAm specifics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Thomas, not an easy answer. The answer is there's a bit of both, it will be a component of the royalty income, you're correct to say that that's what we are describing as licensing income. Some of it will be related to sales and some of it will be lumpy, I'm afraid. But I think the model, I think, continued to increase in some respect, which is going to be related to our continued levels of innovation.</p>
          <p>In 2011, we had about $175 million total royalty income. I'd suspect, it's going to be around the similar level for 2012 and will start to increase more as we get more opportunity from new licensing agreements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's on the royalty. On Latin America, yeah, things are progressing at rapid rates in terms of GM adoption there. We have launched in Brazil, 2012, a triple stack. And Argentina, we'll be launching the triple stack in 2013. Our corn share in Brazil has increased, we believe, last season from around 9% to about 11% and have continued very rapid adoption. Overall, corn in Latin America increased somewhere around 35%, soybeans were up around 50%. So it's an evolving picture and we're right up there with the registrations right at the front of the growth curve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I just &#x2013; if you just allow one follow-up the sort of the slump in the vegetables market in the U.S., has that led to fierce price competition or are people behaving in the wake of this cyclical downturn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It does not have the same dynamic. You can't lower the prices to move seeds in this very niche-oriented business, just the sheer volumes of vegetables because they tend to be a more expensive part of the food basket is just down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Relative to where it was. Thank you, Thomas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tony Jones. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Tony Jones from Redburn. I've got three questions. And are the cost headwinds you're facing for this year, the $350 million, could you split that out please between FX and input costs. And of the input costs again, could you give us an idea how much of it is much of it is glyphosate or other bought-in actives versus chemicals?</p>
          <p>And then for Viptera, you mentioned that it was sold out and through the prior year, is this going to be a production constraint again in 2012 or is there a potential for volume expansion?</p>
          <p>And then finally, in terms of the 3% price increase in seeds, could you help us a bit to understand where it's coming from? Is this higher price per trait or just mix or is it not US GM, is it outside of that, for example, improving mix maybe in Eastern Europe as you've mentioned in commentary. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Tony. John, maybe you can take the breakdown of the cost, the $300 million to $350 million, before you do, just about Viptera being sold out. In &#x2013; this past &#x2013; this crop year that we're in right now, which commenced in 2011 through spring of 2012, Viptera is going to represent about 25% to 35% &#x2013; 25% to 30% of the offer. It will absolutely go up from here. And so 2011/2012 crop year, we were production constrained. And as every year goes on, we will be less and less production constrained. We're also seeing Viptera being appreciated in LatAm, both Brazil and Argentina, and that's going to continue to help us expand the volume as well as the profitability of seeds. John, on the decomposition of the cost increase, the headwinds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The $300 million to $350 million includes ForEx and the raw materials. Within that, you can say somewhere between $50 million and $100 million would be the raw material component. That is all chemistry. It's all largely related to the price of oil going back to recent increases, so $50 million to $100 million on raw materials.</p>
          <p>As regards the sales price increases in seeds of the 3%, see first of all this does not include mix. This is pure price increase on the specific products. So any improvement in the portfolio that we're getting, which is coming through to margin is not in that figure. What more to say, it's spread across all the crops, except flowers, and, yeah, we had something like going into the fourth quarter so far as corn prices are concerned going up to the high single digits in quarter four for corn in the United States but 3% is spread across all products, all crops except flowers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much. Can I just ask a very quick follow-up? If I heard correctly, you mentioned that you were going to go for a double-digit target for 2012 in seeds price. Is that just in the U.S. for your GM traded seeds, or is that &#x2013; what did I miss here? Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we'd be expecting price increases in Latin America as well as in the United States.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger from Helvea. Actually most questions have already been answered. There's just one remaining, and that's a financial one for John, I suppose. Regarding the tax rate, I heard you there mentioning some very brief explanations. I was wondering whether you could elaborate on those a little bit more. If I remember correctly, you had been guiding for 20%, and we came out at around 16.5%, so if you could go into more detail, that would be very helpful. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We're pleased that we've managed to get the tax rate at around 17%, which is the same level as 2010. And the point I was making in the presentation was that we do have to be cautious about this because if you're looking at longer-term planning assumptions, we certainly would be looking at closer to 20% and I've said that before. The reason why we've been able to do so well in the tax rate, we have been very focused on it. And we've taken specific measures, which are not always necessarily sustainable beyond the year in which you implement them and hence why I was guiding to a higher figure for the purposes of forward planning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Andrew Stott. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning. Bank of America-Merrill Lynch. A question for Mike, you look at Q4 and how different that was to the first nine months, the thing that stands out the most is just how weak Europe was and how strong naphtha was particularly in Crop Protection, obviously, but that weakness is also in seeds in Europe. Now you mentioned some specifics, in particular, French credit terms. You also, I think, alluded to inventory levels being tight in naphtha, so I can understand some of the issues. But do you think there is a wider issue here about confidence in the farm economy in Europe as opposed to the U.S.? So I just wonder what you're picking up really from your sales force here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Europe, you're here in Europe as well, Andrew, I know that the people are feeling right now that the Eurozone billet is &#x2013; they're cautious about and cautious about it and of course we have the ongoing banking crisis. We're not picking up any indication that the farmers aren't going to make the full complement of investments, one. Vegetable seeds, yeah, I mean the overall volumes are down and one of the things driving that as near as we can tell is, and we don't think we've lost any pace or any share, retailers are just really watching their margins and they're a bit more cautious on account of the economy but those two things broadly.</p>
          <p>When you look at the fourth quarter as such, don't forget how you &#x2013; first of all, we've had a really strong first nine months where veg was 9% &#x2013; or 12% rather in Europe and so some of that was just the slowing of where it goes from here. We're not hearing anything dire but as we go into 2010 in vegetables, it looks a bit softer than it's historically been. Not the cause for grave concern but on the other hand, you've got sunflower sales in Eastern Europe, wheat's going nicely, or we expect it will go nicely. Corn is in, some of the other field crops are covering it very nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just follow up? You mentioned double-digit price increases in the U.S. in seeds. Was that a reference purely to corn or are you talking about soybean as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's pretty much corn. There's &#x2013; we did have some, and the whole industry, had some production challenges in the Midwest. And we're passing some of those along, we expect that those price increases will largely offset the cost increases. But some year it's better than others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Patrick Rafaisz. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Bank Vontobel in Zurich. A couple of questions first. You've obviously overachieved in your seeds EBITDA margin target for 2011 and we've already discussed pricing. Where's your sort of a roadmap going forward for the seeds margin from these levels? I understand or I recall from earlier discussions that the potential is somewhere slightly north of 20%. Do you have any idea when that will be reached and we're heading in 2012?</p>
          <p>And then the second question, you mentioned the balance sheet gearing has been declining for several years, we're now at 15%. Do you have sort of a floor for the gearing ratio where we just indefinitely increase dividends in order to keep the balance sheet gearing at this level or what's the plan here? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Patrick. First to the seeds margin, as John said, we're going to new segment reporting so we won't be targeting seeds margins as such. However, we've been very consistent in saying that fundamentally, there is no reason why the seeds business can't absolutely rival the Crop Protection business. In fact, in some of our seeds properties we have seeds margins, EBITDA margins, that have been higher than Crop Protection.</p>
          <p>So when we announced last year that we were targeting a 22% to 24% EBITDA margin for the combined businesses, it is absolutely understood that seeds will be an enduring part of delivering that ambition. So it's onward and upward for the seeds EBITDA evolution in that quarter. The other thing we've said when we announced this strategy was that &#x2013; the important thing was that by integrating these businesses, we would be able to accelerate the growth rate of the firm to above average growth rates. Any given year, of course, Mother Nature, the weather, demand can play a bit of havoc with that but the enduring feature of what we're setting out to do is to have a sustainably high profitable business and consistently outpace the competition. So that's what we're all about.</p>
          <p>And you asked a question about gearing. I'll let John comment on that in just a moment. But you say is there a theoretical floor, I suppose a theoretical floor is zero. That's not what we're targeting.</p>
          <p>But having said that, what we have right now is principally a progressive dividend policy, and we've got a tactical share buyback policy. And we've been operating to that now for a couple of years. And we've got a strong balance sheet in an otherwise slightly topsy-turvy world out there. We're very keen to do acquisitions to the extent that they present themselves to us. And as you know, this industry just hasn't had a lot of them come to market but we've got the firepower to take a look at anything that's out there so long as it is consistent with the strategy that we're embarking upon.</p>
          <p>John, anything else on gearing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just to reinforce what you said, Mike, I think that that's clear. I mean, we're very pleased that we got a record cash flow this year, $1.5 billion, which, of course, came through in the gearing number. Our strategy in terms of the balance sheet has not changed. We do intend to keep some flexibility but significantly increase the dividend and increase it substantially and increase it progressively. So we increased it 35% last year. We've been proposing to increase it this year by another 15%. And the progressive dividend will continue.</p>
          <p>We've reduced the levels of buybacks from a few years ago. But nevertheless, we're prepared to use those tactically when the balance sheet permits. But importantly, we do want to keep flexibility for acquisitions and, of course, making sure we don't suffer as a consequence of any outflow from the banking situation. But this position, of course, gives us more flexibility, and we'll be considering all options as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from the line of Fabian Smeets. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much. Fabian Smeets, ING. Two questions from my side. The growth in your non-selective herbicide franchise has been exceptionally strong in 2011. And I was wondering what have been the main drivers for this success.</p>
          <p>And additionally, on AMISTAR, I think you're reporting that sales in the U.S. were up by 50%. I suppose you're talking about full year there. Also up strongly in Asia but up 12% year-on-year for the franchise as a whole. What has been the main reason for sales in Europe and Latin America holding back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Fabian. I think in terms of non-selective herbicide, it is a very strong performance. But it illustrates the strong market conditions largely in the Americas, we've had expansion in herbicide tolerant crops in Latin America and hence been able to sell more non-selective herbicides. In addition, in North America, a very strong market condition, as you see in the numbers as well. And that's also reflected in the non-selective herbicide figure. So those are the main reasons.</p>
          <p>As far as AMISTAR is concerned, yes, we are growing something like 50% in North America. And this is in the crop enhancement sector. And this is a fast-growing new sector in North America. And farmers are getting a very strong effect in terms of yield performance on corn and soybeans there and that's driving growth. As well as in Asia, you may recall that a couple of years ago, we had expanded the capacity of our AMISTAR plant and this enabled us to tackle markets, which did not really put a great deal of marketing effort into in Asia and that is now coming through in the figures. So that's the background on AMISTAR.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also just to supplement that, I mean, we do have the growth of glyphosate-tolerant crops in Latin America. But in North America, we also have the growth as I've said during my presentation, growth in resistance to weeds, glyphosate resistance to weeds; as a consequence, people are having to go to glyphosate that includes some mixtures without the chemistries and Syngenta has the best on offer for that. And of course, don't forget we are coming out of a period of quite a bit of price decline in glyphosate and what we had in 2011 was a bit affirming there in that area. So taken together, a strong year as you pointed out. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Andrew Benson. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Citigroup. The Agrisure Viptera that the &#x2013; you talked about quite substantial bushels per acre lead over the competition, you talked about being capacity constrained last year. Can you just give us an idea of the scale of growth in that product and how significant it could be in the next &#x2013; both this year and over the next, I think, a couple of years?</p>
          <p>Can I just get back on the tax rate, you said for planning purposes 20%, I mean, should we put 20% in for 2012 or will it be some sort of move back towards 20% over the medium term. You're also giving yourself flexibility with regard to the scale of share buybacks and dividends, and looks like your balance sheet will strengthen further in 2012. And obviously, acquisitions are very sensitive issues you don't want to say too much. But would it be right in saying that the acquisition opportunities are perhaps warmer rather than colder at the moment? And as things go well, there's a reasonable probability that we could expect to see some significant moves during the course of 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start with then the acquisitions. I understand that, by and large, the quantity of M&amp;A that's going on not only in this space but broadly speaking is just &#x2013; it's down near historical levels and so you say the activity could get warmer. I think that's right only by virtue of the fact that it's almost non-existent right now. As John pointed out, we've got a lot of ambition. We've got a lot of flexibility in our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>What has historically presented itself to our industry over the last years have been rather modest seeds properties. When you buy a seeds property, of course, it takes a bit of time as you know to integrate the technology. If it's traited, it takes a bit of time to beneficiate the germplasm. So these things don't lend themselves to anything instantaneous. But to the extent that something quite a bit larger comes to market, as John said, we've got lot of scope to do that as well.</p>
          <p>Your question about AMISTAR &#x2013; I mean, Agrisure Viptera. It is the leading insect trait on offer right now. And we're really pleased with it. It's coming at a time when there is more interest in Latin America from the Argentinean and from the Brazilians to control coleopterans and lepidopterans, and it's the best out there. So that combined with a single face to the market in LatAm puts us in a good position to help these markets grow their high quality corn business. And so what we have here is not only Syngenta with a strong competitive offer versus other strong competitors but we're also migrating what we've referred to as the mid-tech corn market, the low tech and the mid-tech corn market is able to come more to high tech by virtue of its ability to control pests that they couldn't control before. So right now, we're headed in the U.S., as I said, 25% to 30% and there's no reason why we can't imagine targeting beyond 50% of our portfolio for Agrisure in the U.S.</p>
          <p>And in Latin America, John said we grabbed a couple of points in market share and we continue to target really high levels, Andrew, I think that combined with our crop protection chemical and seed treatment offer puts us in a position to do that but the one thing that gets a bit difficult is to target the underlying growth of that new corn segment as well as just the evolution of our market share.</p>
          <p>So again, I would say there's no reason in the world why we can't imagine having a number of years going forward with margin and volume expansion in our corn seed business in the Americas and that's what we're setting out to do. John, the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, does that mean &#x2013; I think you went 10% last year to 11% 2011. And then does that mean sort of 13% this year and 15% the year after?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've spoken about this before. I'm always loathe to get myself tethered to an exact &#x2013; the yoke of judging our performance on the basis of corn market share evolution alone. Syngenta has just so much more on offer to do that. But, yes, look we have a 22% or 23% market share in crop protection chemicals in Latin America, in Brazil, particularly.</p>
          <p>I see no reason in the world why we wouldn't imagine targeting just as we had targeted a high EBITDA evolution, why wouldn't I set out our stall shop to say that our market share in Latin America is going to rival our crop protection share. That's going to take time. And we've now got the proof point of a strong offer, hybrids, germplasm and traits, and more traits on the way with our second generation rootworm.</p>
          <p>So I wouldn't want to give you a number because the number might end up being too low for what our ambition is. But I'm not going to say precisely when the year is beyond to say that it's going to be sooner rather than later and more rather than less. John, on the tax rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the tax rate, I mean, clearly we're pleased in the last couple of years, we've been able to put in place a number of optimization measures and some of those in 2011. The nature of them, they tend to be a bit lumpy. So you can't necessarily draw a straight trend line. If you did an analytics of our profits and where it falls, you'd have a tax rate somewhere in the low 20s. I think every year, we're always going to be able to do something. So for 2012, I'd be putting in a figure of 20%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jaideep Pandya. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Berenberg Bank. Good morning, everybody, and congrats on good results. Just a couple of questions. First, on pricing, I just want to understand you are targeting roughly 2% to 3%, is that on crop protection or on Syngenta overall?</p>
          <p>And then just following that on, I mean, if you are assuming about $50 million to $100 million of raw material inflation, it seems that you will have quite a nice positive squeeze if you do achieve the 2% to 3% pricing and it sort of is offsetting the FX headwind. But given the fact that maybe some of your key competitors don't have that FX headwind, and don't probably target 2% to 3%, how confident are you that you will be able to achieve if they probably don't have to go for 2%, 3% to offset the raw material cost increase. That's my first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is more on the FX, I mean, you gave us very kindly your net long or short positions. If you could just give us a bit more color on the sensitivity on may be key currency pegs to model the FX moments. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you for that. Before I turn it over to John, just briefly on the 2% to 3%. This is crop protection and the reason we're clear about that is because at the half year last year, we said we would get out there with some crop protection. We would lead price increases and implement those in our markets around the world. And we were keen to update you on the progress of that. And so that's 2% to 3% in CP. Of course, we have price increases as well in seeds.</p>
          <p>Before asking John to cover on the raw material and the headwinds, just a reminder that, yes, some of our competitors may not have some of the same issues opposite the Swiss franc, nor do they have the tax rates of Switzerland, either. So I think the latter is a bit more durable and enduring I'd like to think than the former. But John, on the raw materials and the FX...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I don't think you can relate competitive moves on pricing to ForEx nor do we. We're looking at the market opportunity when we're looking at pricing. My comparison with other elements in the income statement whether it be cost savings or in terms of the currency effect was just for the purposes of illustration of magnitude. So we don't see necessarily a linkage there. What we're seeing very clearly is that given our plans in terms of &#x2013; and our targets in terms of price increases, our targets in terms of cost savings, then we do anticipate notwithstanding headwinds such as currency and raw materials, we do expect to increase the EBITDA margin for the group in 2012 at constant exchange rates as well as to grow earnings.</p>
          <p>The question about sensitivities, essentially those three components I gave you, I can maybe put a little bit of color on them for you. And about 15% of our cost base in total, about $1.4 billion is denominated in Swiss francs and so that gives you a Swiss franc number and about 50% of our sales are in emerging markets but we are able to hedge quite a portion of that. There is a portion we don't hedge.</p>
          <p>The long position in the euro compared to those two components is actually the smallest component of it. But I think the important point is here, as we stand here today, the levels of hedging we have in place that are roundabout 75% of the currency exposure and given the reasonable estimates of volatility, we operate within $75 million and have been able to anticipate what the currency effects are. So that gives you a bit of color, I hope, in understanding a bit more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Richard Logan. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning. It's Richard Logan from Goldman Sachs. Just on market share growth. You're targeting 0.5% market share gains. Is it possible you can give us an update as to how that's progressed in 2011, and if possible, breaking that down on a regional basis?</p>
          <p>Then on North American crop protection, I realize that the fourth quarter is, obviously, a small quarter. But the 42% growth that you saw there, do you think that that includes any pre-buying or any sort of one-off type effects that have come through there?</p>
          <p>And then, finally, just on the crop protection pricing, the 2% to 3%, are you able to give any sense as to which regions or product areas that you're most confident in with regards to achieving that price increase? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. I think, first on the market share. What we were keen to do when we said that we would have 0.5% market share over the years, this was to underpin our ambition to use our strategy and our deep toolbox to help grow what is today a circa $70 billion industry into a $200-billion industry and that we will help to expand the market. And in doing so, we would outpace the competition in it, so a very big ambition. You remember our introduction of PLENE, and here we're taking in the sugarcane industry and we're inventing a whole new way of cropping this important business for the first time, same thing with the mechanization of rice. So we're going to end up helping to not only grow the businesses for which we've had strong leadership positions like fungicides in Brazil, herbicides in corn, for example, but we're going to do so also creating huge market positions on an entry basis for some altogether new crops. How are we doing against that?</p>
          <p>By the way, the data is better in some places than others. For example, in Europe and in the United States and in Brazil, the data is very good. In places like Asia Pacific, it's a bit more difficult to come by. Government statistics aren't as available. Industry associations are not as reliable. So we're going to do our level best to give you an update on how we're progressing against our crop protection chemicals. And the data on seeds, by the way, is two or three strides below crop protection in terms of its overall quality. So, so far so good, and we don't know the data yet in 2011, but we think we will have gained some share. We will describe that to you a bit more at the half year as we always do.</p>
          <p>John on the fourth quarter of last year, the question of pre-buying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we don't think there's pre-buying in the figures, Richard. But it's a season where we're just basically filling the channel and it has to be seen in that context. So looking at the very large 40% increase, one wouldn't necessarily see a trend line there. But what you can see is it does illustrate very strong market conditions in North America as the farmer sentiment is very strong. They're coming off a very high level of income in 2011, we saw also in quarter three, we saw a strong tank filling and this is selective herbicides, non-selective herbicides and seed care products doing well. It's reflecting strong conditions but I think it's exaggerated in terms of the absolute headline number and we just have to be careful this is all about filling the channel in anticipation rather than product on the ground. But nevertheless, it's encouraging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we do not end 2011 with any expectation that we have of above average inventory in the channel. I just want to be really clear about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In North America not at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. And then there was a question about CP pricing, any areas that we feel better or worse about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think it's an evolving story, I think we're pleased that in the fourth quarter of 2011, we managed to achieve 5% price increase in Latin America. We did achieve our target in North America contributing to that figure we've just been discussing. Of course, there it's all about &#x2013; it's about going into the channel and there's a lot of time to pass before we're exactly clear where the pricing has fallen but nevertheless the quarter four numbers were encouraging. And it's really about the Northern Hemisphere. And as we go into the next few months we're anticipating where we'd like to see the traction. So that's where our focus is going to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, clear. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I understand we have time for one last question. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Virginie Boucher-Ferte. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good morning. It's Virginie Boucher-Ferte from Deutsche Bank. I've got a few questions, please. First of all, could you please give the pricing performance in Q4, excluding glyphosate, if relevant. That's the first question.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you say that in the U.S. you finished the year without any excess inventory. Could you please comment on Europe, especially with regard to the fungicide inventory of last year? Has it all been cleared as of the year-end or is there a bit more to come?</p>
          <p>My third question is linked to the previous one. Could you please give us a volume outlook for Q1, given all the moving parts of higher planting in Europe, very good fundamentals overall? But also I understand, on the negative we've got some dry weather in LatAm and also the lower GDP.</p>
          <p>And last two financial questions, if you could give a CapEx guidance for 2012? And also, the pension contribution was $100 million lower in 2011 versus 2010, if you could comment on that and give a guidance for this year? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Virginie. The first answer is 3% excluding glyphosate on pricing. On Europe inventory, there is nothing &#x2013; we don't have any basis to know or believe that the inventory finished the year higher than it did the prior year. So no to extra inventory in 2011. And, of course, what gets used is still very much in front of us. The answer, I suppose &#x2013; the brief answer on Q1 is Q1 and Q2, for us, is always &#x2013; in a way, it's a seamless season. And we don't, as such, have any specific expectation about Q1 versus last year. We're just going to have to see when people get out there on their &#x2013; get out there on the farms and when the volume starts to move. But right now, it's cold. But Europe looks like it's shaping up to the extent that you can even assess such a thing here at the early part of February as normal.</p>
          <p>In North America, on the other hand, Q1, it's quite a bit warmer there right now. And I couldn't even guess when the season will get underway. An earlier season is probably not as beneficial for us, but we'll just have to see come what may. John, on the CapEx and pension.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Virginie, on the CapEx, we anticipate for tangibles and intangibles a total of about somewhere between $650 million and $700 million expenditure in 2012, which is a bit higher than 2011. And on the pensions, the reason that we had a difference between 2010, 2011, we did make an extra contribution to our defined benefit pension contributions in 2010, which wasn't made up to the same extent in 2011. As far as guidance, in terms of cash contribution is concerned for 2012, I would estimate around the similar level to the 2011 level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Virginie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And ladies and gentlemen, that concludes then our presentation this morning. If you've got additional questions, of course, please feel free to call Jennifer Gough or Claire Hinshelwood in Investor Relations. And I hope you will mark your calendars for the extension of our Capital Markets Days so we can update you on our crop strategies on May 11. So with that, thank you again, and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. This concludes today's conference. And you may now disconnect your line. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>