<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1325307" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2952</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Michael Mack, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John Ramsay, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">John Atkin, Chief Operating Officer, Crop Protection</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Davor Pisk, Chief Operating Officer, Seeds</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Paul Walsh</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jean de Watteville</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Andrew Stott</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Andrew Benson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Neil Tyler</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Tony Jones</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Rim Bennani</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Alex Stewart</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Florian Gaiser</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Patrick Rafaisz</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to this presentation of Syngenta's First Half Results. The presentation will be give by Mike Mack, CEO, John Ramsay, CFO, John Atkin, COO of Crop Protection and Davor Pisk, COO of Seeds.</p>
          <p>Before we start, bear with me while I read out our usual cautionary statement. This presentation contains forward looking statements which can be identified by terminology such as 'expect', 'would', 'will', 'potential', 'on track', and similar expressions.  Such statements may be subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause the actual results to differ materially from these statements. We refer you to Syngenta's publicly available filings with the U.S. SEC for information about these and other risks and uncertainties.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me hand you over to Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jennifer, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen. When we last spoke in April, the Northern Hemisphere season was in full swing after a slow start particularly here in Europe. We told you at that time that we expected volumes to pick up in the second quarter, as indeed they did, with double-digit growth in both crop protection and seeds.</p>
          <p>However, channel inventories of Crop Protection products were high, notably in NAFTA, as a consequence of an overhang from the 2009 season, which, as you know, was characterized by low pest pressure.</p>
          <p>Disappointingly, this led to price reductions, which are reflected in the results announced today. We are, however, very encouraged by the strong progression of emerging markets throughout the first half. Sales in Latin America were up by more than 30%. And in Eastern Europe, we saw a resumption of investment in agriculture.</p>
          <p>Emerging Asia continued its track record of growth. These performances, of course, reflect the dynamism and potential of these markets, but they are also the results of the considerable investments we have made there and which we continue to make.</p>
          <p>At the same time, spending on research and development increased, which reflects our ongoing commitment to innovation. And you'll be seeing just a few examples of the returns we are getting on the investments in today's presentation. But before moving on to that, let me first hand you over to John Ramsay for a detailed review of the numbers. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Mike. Staring then with the summary of the results, sales in the first half were $6.7 billion, up 1% in reported terms, reflecting a positive contribution from currency. At constant exchange rates, sales were 3% lower, with volume up 2% and price down 5%.</p>
          <p>Gross margin was unchanged, as the raw material benefiting Crop Protection and an improvement in the Seeds gross margin offset the impact of lower Crop Protection prices. At constant exchange rates, EBITDA was down 9% at $1.9 billion. An advancement in the Seeds EBITDA margin was more than offset by a lower Crop Protection margin due to price and higher operating expenses, driven primarily by increased R&amp;D and continued emerging market growth investment.</p>
          <p>Currency movements, including hedging, made a positive contribution of around $50 million to EBITDA. Earnings per share were also 9% lower at $13.95. Free cash flow was $74 million, unchanged from the prior year. We continue to expect strong free cash flow generation in 2010 which, as you know, largely occurs in the second half of the year due to the working capital cycle in our business.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the sales progression chart, where you can see that the weaker dollar increased sales by $260 million or almost 4%. Volumes were higher in Crop Protection and Seeds, but were more than offset by a price decline of $359 million, the majority of which relates to Crop Protection in the North American market.</p>
          <p>I will return to price later, but firstly on volumes. As we indicated earlier in the year, we saw strong recovery in the volume in the second quarter and you can see this on the next slide. Crop Protection volume increased 10% in the second quarter with growth across all regions. Consumption return to more normal levels following a season of reduced pest pressure in 2009. This meant that the high channel inventories built up during 2009 and particularly affecting North America diminished in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we saw an increase in volumes across all product lines, whilst the NAFTA fungicide demand was particularly strong, with volume up more than 20%. Latin America completed an excellent season with strong volume growth and record sales, slightly higher than the previous record set in the first half of 2008. And when compared to last year, total half year volumes increased by 3%.</p>
          <p>Looking now the overall performance in crop protection, sales of $5 billion were down 4% in constant currency. Volume was 3% higher, whilst prices were 7% lower or down 5%, excluding the impact of glyphosate.</p>
          <p>After a slow start to the season, the strong second quarter volume recovery, which lowered channel inventories, did lead to a competitive price environment, most notably in NAFTA. EBITDA constant exchange rates was lower at $1.6 billion and at a margin of 31.5%. A $148 million benefit from raw material costs was more than offset by price and our continuing investment in R&amp;D and emerging markets. For the full year, I expect the crop protection EBITDA margin to be closer to 1% lower than 2009.</p>
          <p>I would now like to spend some time putting the first half price decline into context. As the graph on this slide shows, cumulative crop protection price increases in the two years from 2007 through 2009, was $640 million, including 7% in the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Whilst we led the market in implementing these significant price increases, competitive pricing in the first half of 2010 required us to respond with reduced prices in our determination to defend market share. Although price was $340 million lower in the first half and was largely confined to NAFTA, we have still managed to capture significant pricing gains over this entire period.</p>
          <p>Further, in many of the markets in which we operate, we continue to maintain a premium price over our competitors. And these price premiums are only part of the story of why our crop protection business have &#x2013; has, over the years, retained resilient profitability.</p>
          <p>It is only more recently that we have seen volatility in price, largely due to the exceptional dynamics that have taken place in the market since the end of 2007. Prior to that time, you can see that our annual price variance was flat to marginally lower in any given year. For the last 10 years, however, our gross margin has remained resilient due to our ability to offer new and innovative technologies to the grower and typically at higher margins than the group average.</p>
          <p>During that same period, our EBITDA margin has increased significantly, increasing by nearly 500 basis points to 26.9% in 2009. Through these last few volatile years, the business has benefited from a sustained increase in usage of our technology and we expect future growth to continue to be volume-led. Pricing will reflect the competitive market, but our assumption based on past history is that we will see greater stability beyond 2010.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our Seeds performance, sales were up 2% with volume 3% higher and price down 1%. Adjusting for the change in U.S. sales terms, which brought sales forward from the first quarter of 2010 to the fourth quarter of 2009, sales were up 9%, reflecting growth in all regions.</p>
          <p>EBITDA increased to $352 million, with the margin improving to 20%. The EBITDA improvement was driven by a higher gross margin due to the increasing penetration of our triple stack offer in the United States. And for the full year, I expect further progression towards our margin target of 15% in 2011.</p>
          <p>The next slide explains the major movements in operating income. Currency provided a favorable impact of around $50 million, which I will say more about in a moment. Lower raw material costs resulted in a $148 million benefit in the first half. And for the full year, I expect the total benefit to be somewhat higher.</p>
          <p>In addition, we invested around $100 million more in research and development and emerging markets to drive future growth. Business performance decreased $282 million, primarily due to lower prices exceeding the volume increase.</p>
          <p>I will return to expenses in a moment, but let me now comment on currencies and their estimated impact on the outlook for the second half. The diagram in this slide shows some of our key net foreign currency exposures. Beside each currency, you can see the percentage strengthening of that currency against the dollar in the first half compared to the prior year. For example, we have a net short exposure to Swiss franc as our costs are greater than our sales in Switzerland and the franc strengthened by 4% versus the dollar in the first half compared to the same period last year.</p>
          <p>With regard to the impact on our developed market cost base, which as you know, is significant in Swiss francs, sterling and euro, this is, in 2010, largely covered through hedging, as the darker shading on the bars demonstrates. As a reminder, Latin America represents the most significant portion of our business in the second half and we largely operate with dollarized sales in that region. Therefore, I continue to estimate the 2010 net operating income benefit from currencies at around $50 million, with minimal net currency impact in the second half.</p>
          <p>Looking now at net income. Net income of $1.3 billion was 9% lower. The decrease was primarily driven by lower operating income, net financial expense of $55 million increased only slightly compared to the prior year. And for the full year, I now expect financial expenses to be around $150 million and for a slightly higher tax rate in the second half. Over the medium-term, I continue to expect that our tax rate will be in the low to mid-20s.</p>
          <p>Turning now to free cash flow. Free cash flow of $74 million was unchanged compared to the prior year, despite a lower EBITDA. As usual in the first half, we had a net outflow on working capital, reflecting the seasonality of our business. CapEx of $266 million reflected the final stages of our Crop Protection capacity expansion.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, we continue to expect strong free cash flow this year primarily on lower CapEx and a reduction in working capital, as continued volume growth in the second half reduces inventories.</p>
          <p>The benefit from inventory reduction will be partially offset by an increase in receivables as we have increased credit to support sales growth, notably in emerging markets, as the next slide demonstrates.</p>
          <p>This chart shows DSOs relative to sales in the emerging markets of Eastern Europe and Latin America. As we have said in the past, we believe our risk management programs, including customer credit profiling and novel business models, provide us with a competitive advantage in these markets.</p>
          <p>In 2010, these programs have enabled us to increase credit to support the recovery in these markets without significantly increasing risk, whilst also preserving the quality of our balance sheet as the continuing improvement in the DSOs demonstrates.</p>
          <p>As we have shown in the past, we are able to maintain our high business quality through disciplined management of our cost base. At the same time, we have created the necessary headroom to invest in the key growth areas of R&amp;D, Seeds and emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Between 2005 and 2009, we've reduced our cost to sales ratio from 38% to 32%, a 6-point improvement over that period. Because of the first half price decline, our cost to sales ratio will rise in 2010, but will benefit in 2011 as further operational savings take effect. Examples of our operational efficiency measures are included on this slide. A key pillar of our Crop Protection strategy remains low cost production and procurement. However, we are also streamlining common activities across our Crop Protection and Seeds businesses, including shared systems and back office functions.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, our joint commercial operation will streamline resources whilst helping to accelerate market development. Finally our investment in R&amp;D, which will be in the order of $1 billion this year remains unique in the breadth of technology it encompasses and the opportunity it provides in a fully integrated global approach.</p>
          <p>Let me now summarize our outlook for the second half. We expect the volume recovery that commenced in the second quarter to continue through the remainder of the year. Latin America will be getting underway in September and whilst we expect a competitive environment, the fundamentals are favorable and we have an excellent market position, as John and Davor will share with you in their presentations.</p>
          <p>We remain focused on controlling costs whilst investing in growth and we'll see further margin advancement in Seeds. Taken together, we should achieve operating income around last year's level. As indicated earlier in the year, the evolution of earnings per share, however, will reflect increases in net financial expense and a higher tax rate.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me hand you over to John Atkin, who will cover our Crop Protection business in more detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Good morning. Let me begin with my customary review of events worldwide, starting with Western Europe, where a late season was compounded by a build-up of channel inventory in France and by changes in French customer behavior as a result of new government credit regulations. East Europe, on the other hand, picks up well. After the long winter, we saw a resumption of investment in several markets, notably the Ukraine.</p>
          <p>In NAFTA, corn and soybean were planted early, and growing conditions have generally been favorable. But channel inventories were high and led to a very competitive environment with price pressure, particularly for glyphosate and fungicides.</p>
          <p>It was a different picture in Latin America, where the first season is now complete and where the market has been recovering strongly since the fourth quarter of last year. As we stand here today, the outlook for the coming season that begins in September is positive, with soybean prices at reasonable levels.</p>
          <p>Finally, Asia-Pacific, where the drive for yield increase continues with ongoing investment and government support for agriculture throughout that region.</p>
          <p>Turning now to sales by product line, Selective Herbicides sales were 4% lower with some price pressure on older chemistries in North America. We saw strong volume growth in Latin America, while in France and Germany, sales were affected by the phasing of oilseed rape herbicides, which this year, will shift to their normal time of the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Non-selective Herbicides were affected by well-documented movements in the glyphosate market, where U.S. prices came down sharply in the middle of the last year. Volumes were lower because of high channel inventory in the United States.</p>
          <p>Fungicide sales were 6% higher, reflecting strong growth in Amistar, driven by Latin America. Our new fungicide, Revus, showed growth of more than 20%, with launches in nine new countries. Insecticide sales were unchanged, with growth in Durivo and Actara offsetting declines in older products.</p>
          <p>Seed Care sales were down, mainly due to high inventories of treated seed in the U.S. Cruiser continued its advance in both Latin America and APAC. Finally, growth of 4% in Professional Products reflected a recovery of consumer-led areas, particularly in Europe.</p>
          <p>Now on the next chart, you see our sales split into two parts, emerging and developed markets. Let me start by saying that we have successfully driven market share gain globally and that remains our clear goal. We have tailored strategies for all markets. For emerging markets, this has meant identifying opportunities and resorting to fully maximize growth. We have been doing this very successfully for many years, and the business now accounts for around half our global sales.</p>
          <p>These are the markets where the population is growing and people are increasingly able to afford a better diet, and these trends are set to continue. In developed markets, we have gained share through portfolio innovation and our leading customer service and support. Continuing to do this is just as important to Syngenta as achieving growth in emerging markets. Operational efficiency has always been a high priority and remains so.</p>
          <p>Let me start with an example of portfolio breadth in customer support. This slide covers the mixture products that have enabled us to build a leading herbicide position in corn and soybeans. The success of Lumax and Lexar in corn or, more recently, Prefix in soybeans, testify to the critical importance of pre- or early post-emergence weed control. These products are market-leading mixtures and make up the majority of the $200 million business in the blue bars.</p>
          <p>The reasons for success are twofold: the importance, of course, of excellent early weed control to maximize yield and, of increasing significance, the need to control weeds resistant to glyphosate. With this in mind, and in order to ensure that growers can continue to benefit from the convenience of glyphosate whether or not they have resistance, we have added to the mixture portfolio.</p>
          <p>We launched the glyphosate pre-mixed products, Halex GT, in corn three years ago and last year,  Flexstar GT in soybeans. These convenient, ready-to-use products are proving highly effective and are gaining popularity with growers, as you can see from the green bars. And these brands have significant further growth potential.</p>
          <p>And now an example of portfolio innovation in developed markets. In spring of this year, we announced the first registration of Isopyrazam, a new-generation, broad-spectrum fungicide.</p>
          <p>First sales on barley have been made in the U.K. and this will be followed by a launch in New Zealand on wheat in the second half of the year. The photograph on the left illustrates how effective this product is compared with an existing standard treatment.</p>
          <p>Isopyrazam has a different mode of action to other widely used fungicides, and we have high ambitions for its potential on wheat, other arable crops, and fruit and vegetables. A broad range of registrations, also covering mixture products, is planned over the next two to four years.</p>
          <p>And now to Amistar, for which sales are currently split roughly 50-50 between emerging and developed markets. We commissioned our new manufacturing plant in the U.K. in the spring of this year and there is immediate demand for the increased output. And because of our low cost position, the Amistar range will continue to delivery gross margins above our portfolio average.</p>
          <p>In the past, we have shown you many photographs of what Amistar can do for cereals, corn and soybeans, the major field crops. This time, I have selected pictures of peanuts, mangos, tomatoes and onions and they illustrate the remarkable range of uses this product has. This is why we continue to be excited about Amistar's growth potential. It is a cornerstone product worldwide and we've just received a ten-year registration for the European Union. This year, we are also continuing to develop the market for crop enhancement, particularly on corn in the Americas.</p>
          <p>In the first half of the year, sales were driven by emerging markets in Latin America and Asia. It is important to say that in Asia, we are only now starting to exploit Amistar's growth potential, which is enabled by the accelerating need to raise agricultural productivity and improved crop quality.</p>
          <p>So, turning now to emerging markets and Brazil, where sales in the first half the year surpassed their record 2008 level. Priori Xtra continues to be the leading product for soybean rust control and benefited from a season of high disease pressure. This year we launched Ampligo, the first product in the Durivo family on vegetables. Launches in soybeans and corn are planned for 2011.</p>
          <p>We are making excellent progress with Plene, our new planting system for sugarcane and we've received registration for the seed treatment products needy for Plene this year. And we've secured the first orders from sugar mills in advance of the launch in 2011.</p>
          <p>The expansion of our Brazilian business has been underpinned by our excellence in credit management, with around half our sales in the form of cash or barter or more than 25% direct to grower. This allows us to sell complete programs, including with our Seeds products and reinforces loyalty to our brands.</p>
          <p>Now although Brazil accounts for over half our Latin American sales, there is significant business in other countries. Here, I am focusing on Latin America South, which is a big success story, with compound growth of more than 22% in a challenging and volatile environment.</p>
          <p>We have a comprehensive portfolio across all crops, an innovative marketing strategy and customer support model and an outstanding local team. As a result, we are the market leader with a share of 20% and are the number one player in all key crops.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Eastern Europe, after a challenging financial environment in 2009 which restricted credit, most markets have returned to growth this year. There has been significant increase in Ukraine, where the crisis had its greatest impact, and steady growth in Russia.</p>
          <p>Both these businesses will benefit in 2011 from the distribution by Syngenta of the Dow AgroSciences portfolio, a deal announced locally last month. We've increased our share in Poland and in South East Europe, have grown strongly with the establishment of local teams in the important markets, including through the acquisition of a local distributor in Bulgaria.</p>
          <p>This chart on Asia clearly shows the potential of emerging versus developed countries. In emerging Asia, government policies are rewarding higher yield and we are expanding our field force to focus on demand creation and grower education. We are helped by motivated channel partners, with whom we work closely to ensure that they understand and promote our range.</p>
          <p>There are certainly still opportunities in developed Asia, though, and we have been gaining share there with selective portfolio investment and an emphasis on maximizing the effectiveness of our sales and marketing teams.</p>
          <p>The markets of emerging Asia used to be predominantly herbicides and older insecticides. The need to improve productivity particularly in rice has provided the opportunity to launch new insecticides such as the Durivo and Cruiser seed treatment and to develop new markets such as broad spectrum disease control in rice with Armure and now, there is an opportunity for Amistar.</p>
          <p>The evidence of progress is shown on the slide with average growth in these product lines of around 20%. Just as important as the technology is the support for our customers. As an example, Syngenta demonstration events called rice productivity drive have attracted thousands of leading growers and stakeholders in four countries in 2010. Similar events are planned in five more countries in the second half of this year. Agronomic advice and safe use training at field level are also critical components of our strategy.</p>
          <p>Now coming back to our global business. New products was again a pillar of our strategy, with sales growth of 14% in the first half. The nematicide treatment, Avicta, was launched on core in the U.S. and has seen sales double in the first half. Our cereal herbicide, Axial, is showing strong sales growth in East Europe and also further growth in its largest market, Canada.</p>
          <p>I've already talked about Durivo in Asia and we are also exploiting a new opportunity on vegetables in the United States. Revus, until now, focused on vegetable, wines and fruits in West Europe, is expanding globally.</p>
          <p>Our pipeline retains peak sales potential of over $2 billion, despite moving Isopyrazam into the new product category. In the second half of this year, we will make an initial launch in granular form of Invinsa, the first product to treat heat stress in crop. We are making excellent progress with sedaxane, our new seed treatment for cereals and we were delighted to be able to advance our fungicide Hambra into the medium-term launch category. We have other exciting projects for launch over the next four years, which together with the longer-term pipeline, covers all our main product lines.</p>
          <p>Our strategy has been consistently successful and it continues to drive our market share, our market-leading crop protection business. For portfolio expansion, our pipeline and the growth in our new products clearly demonstrate the importance with which we attach to new products. And Amistar has an important chapter in our history of life cycle management. Crop enhancement is an exciting new concept, which is being developed for several products in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Global agriculture is made of thousands of local markets, all with crop, climate and cultural differences. Our tailored business models succeed because we adapt our strategy to the different needs of our customers in all these markets. The scale and intensity with which we do this differentiates Syngenta from its competitors.</p>
          <p>Cost efficiency has always been a key pillar of our strategy and that is why we feel so confident of our ability to compete and to grow in a challenging short-term environment. It means increasing supply chain agility and aligning our resources and our cost base both to market conditions and to our business models.</p>
          <p>And now, let me hand you over to Davor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John, and good morning. As John Ramsay has already noted, our Seeds business showed adjusted growth of 9% in the first half. Corn and soybean sales grew across all regions with double-digit growth in corn led by NAFTA and Latin America.</p>
          <p>In Soybean, which accounted for most of the Q4 sales adjustment, we gained market share in the U.S. and are poised for a good season in Latin America. Diverse Field Crops showed strong internal growth across all regions and were further augmented by the consolidation of Monsanto's sunflower business.</p>
          <p>The rate of growth in Vegetables accelerated, with a continuing focus on high value crops. Although Flowers had a difficult first quarter, the second quarter showed a significant improvement with a strong upturn in demand in West Europe.</p>
          <p>As in Crop Protection, we have a history of growth in emerging markets, which now account for 37% of sales compared with 22% five years ago. We're building on multi-crop opportunities in each region, with a focus on rolling our proprietary traits in Latin America and Asia Pacific, on expanding our field crop positions by maximizing our germplasm strength and on the enormous Vegetables opportunity.</p>
          <p>In the developed markets, this year has seen the expansion of our triple stack offer in the U.S., where it now represents around 60% of our portfolio. This gives us a strong base for the launch of our first proprietary multi-stack corn at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>More generally, we'll be exploiting our broad germplasm base as well as our traits portfolio to achieve market share gains across all the crops. In the near term, we see significant potential from the launch of Agrisure Viptera in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Agrisure Viptera is a trait for broad Lepidoptera control, which delivers an average yield increase of 17 bushes per acre or more than 10%, while maximizing grain quality. As well as improving yield, it delivers cost savings for the grower, which saves time spent scouting for the pest and avoids the cost of in-crop treatments.</p>
          <p>Agrisure Viptera is based on our new mode of action to address insect resistance and is therefore qualified for a reduction in Southern Refuge from 50% to 20%. We will market the trait primarily in combination with our Agrisure triple stack and expect it to be around 20% of our portfolio next year.</p>
          <p>The potential market is the 50% of U.S. corn acres with broad Lepidoptera pressure. And corn in Brazil, where we will also launch Viptera this year as a standalone trait and with a high Lepidoptera pressure across the large part of the corn growing area represents a substantial market opportunity.</p>
          <p>Another major opportunity in the U.S. is water optimization and this map shows you the size of that opportunity. The areas colored in shades of brown and yellow face a medium to high probability of drought stress. In these areas, average yields are substantially below those achieved in the central Corn Belt. Approximately 50% of these acres are irrigated, representing additional cost for growers and often a strain on scarce resource.</p>
          <p>We will be targeting the main corn growing areas within the blue ellipse, which represent, we estimate a market potential of $0.5 billion, of which we aim over time to capture around 30%. We will be targeting both irrigated and non-irrigated acres in areas subject to mid to high drought pressure.</p>
          <p>The launch of our water optimization trait, Agrisure Artesian, in the autumn of this year means that Syngenta will be the first to market with an abiotic stress solution to help growers deal with drought conditions. This is an native trait solution not requiring regulatory approval, which we have developed over a number of years through our extensive breeding program. Our trials illustrated on this photo, which compares Agrisure Artesian with equivalent but non-water-optimized genetics show 15% yield preservation.</p>
          <p>Our offer will mitigate the risk which growers run due to rainfall uncertainty and also allow water savings in areas using irrigation. Pricing will reflect our market segmentation and the value the technology offers to growers in terms of both incremental yields and irrigation costs.</p>
          <p>As we ramp up our offer in the coming seasons, we'll also be working towards combinations with GM technology to achieve further benefits. Longer term, we believe that our technology will have significant potential outside the U.S. in the many countries where drought is an increasing problem.</p>
          <p>In addition to these current launches, we have a number of input trait introductions over the next four years. Starting next year, we will launch refuge stack options, comprising dual modes of action for herbicide tolerance and our Agrisure insect traits stacked with Herculex. From 2012, we plan to offer Agrisure E-Z Refuge, complete refuge in the back solutions for both corn borer and corn rootworm, with 5% refuge in each case. In 2014 we expect to launch our proprietary second generation corn rootworm trait, which is showing outstanding trial results.</p>
          <p>With regard to output traits, Enogen, an alpha amylase enzyme expressed in corn to improve the efficiency of ethanol production, has completed three full scale plant trials with excellent results. The product is ready for launch and has been improved in virtually all the major corn importing countries from the U.S., although we still await full USDA approvals.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to our strategies for the emerging markets, starting with the expansion of our field crop businesses. As for crop protection, Brazil is our largest market in Latin America, but Argentina is becoming increasingly important. We have a longstanding presence in corn and have been selling our BT-11 insect-resistant trait for some years.</p>
          <p>Last year, we received approval to stake BT-11 with our herbicide tolerant trait GA21 and we'll be launching the stack this season. At the same time, following the acquisition of SPS, we're strengthening our presence in the mid-tech segment, where growers are focused on cost efficiency rather than on yield optimization. SPS also gives us an increasing footprint in soybean, which we'll be exploiting to launch a unique integrated offer combining premium genetics with our leading seed care products as well as traits.</p>
          <p>In Sunflower, we're the market leader, having acquired the Monsanto Sunflower business last year, which enhances our existing strong germplasm base while expanding our distribution.</p>
          <p>Our corn sales have also been growing rapidly in the Asia Pacific region, and are expected to reach $100 million this year, excluding our participation in Sanbei in China. this performance reflects in particular the strength of tropical germplasm, which has given us leading market positions in both Vietnam and Thailand. In the Philippines, we are strengthening our position with the launch of GA21 herbicide tolerance, which creates stacking possibilities with our existing BT offer.</p>
          <p>We're also conducting trials with a view to introducing traits in India. To meet growing demand in the region, we are planning to increase production capacity in China, the Philippines and Indonesia. Our sales of Corn and Sunflower in Central and Eastern Europe rebounded in the first half, as growers resumed investment in high-technology seeds. We gained share across the region and most notably in Hungary, where we showed enhanced product performance in Corn as a result of combining elite genetics from the U.S. with our European hybrids.</p>
          <p>We are leveraging rotation opportunities between Corn and Sunflower, where the recent acquisition has further strengthened our position and are starting to combine our offer with crop protection products.</p>
          <p>Sugar beet is also an important crop for us in Eastern Europe and our presence there has been further strengthened by the acquisition of Maribo, announced in June. With sugar beet representing a quarter of global sugar production, we have been focused on reinforcing our presence in the most efficient producing countries. Maribo is a well-established brand which already incorporates some of Syngenta's sugar beet genetics and the acquisition is a consolidation of our existing strong market position.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to Vegetables, which have strong growth potential globally and hence, plays a key role in both our developed and emerging market strategies. We estimate that over the next 15 years, the global Vegetables market will almost triple.</p>
          <p>Growth will be steady across all regions, reflecting hybrid conversion, advanced breeding and the introduction of new traits, with Asia in particular increasing in importance. Driving our market out performance to date, as well as the ongoing potential of this business, is our investment in technology, the extent of which you can see on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Syngenta has an industry leading platform for complex native trait breeding in vegetables. It is a platform that has increased enormously in size over the last four years, as you can see on the chart. The focus has been on our eight high value corps, with the recent addition of lettuce following the acquisitions we made last year.</p>
          <p>We are maximizing the impact of this platform by exploiting some of our field crop technologies and are making significant progress in developing a range of native output traits which will enhance the potential for value capture.</p>
          <p>Vegetables are already a highly profitable business. And as our leading technology enables us further to expand sales and market share, they will play an important role in the future success of our Seeds business.</p>
          <p>Let me conclude by reminding you of the main pillars of our strategy in Seeds. Our global platform is build on breeding expertise, germplasm strength and our growing portfolio of proprietary traits, which we're leveraging across regions with a particular emphasis on emerging markets. We're expanding our footprint through targeted acquisitions which enhance our germplasm base and the breadth of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>As our business grows, we are leveraging the investments we have made in terms of both technology and infrastructure. This together with the transformation of our Corn portfolio, puts us on track to reach our target of a 15% EBITDA margin in Seeds next year.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me hand you back to Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Davor. Given the focus that John and Davor have put on the emerging markets, let me just give you now some quantification of their potential.</p>
          <p>The graph on this slide shows that on average, the difference in yield between developed and emerging markets is over 40%. The main driver for narrowing this gap will be better access to technology, both Crop Protections and Seeds, which will go hand-in-hand with improved farming practice. In developing markets, technology will play a key role in multiple areas, including resistance management and of course, new crop enhancement benefits, which you heard about from John Atkin.</p>
          <p>Given the positive outlook for Latin America and Asia Pacific in the second half, we expect emerging markets to represent approximately 50% of our sales for the full year. We will be accelerating growth in these markets and building on our leadership positions through ongoing investment.</p>
          <p>In the developed markets, we will continue to drive profitable share gain and this means continuing to offer premium products and exploiting the breadth of our range, while maintaining our focus on operational efficiency to ensure that our cost base remains competitive.</p>
          <p>This will give us the headroom to also invest in future innovation and to sustain our record of delivering on our pipeline. The strength of our portfolio will be further underpinned by active management of product life cycles and the continuous adaptation of our range to meet grower needs. We will also increasingly build on our ability to deliver integrated solutions to growers worldwide.</p>
          <p>That concludes our presentation this morning and we will now be happy to take you questions. Operator? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question goes to Thomas Gilbert from UBS. Good morning, Thomas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mike, morning, John and Davor. Thank you for taking my questions. Three of them, one on Seeds, two on Crop Protection. Starting with Seeds, you are launching Agrisure Viptera in 2010 and the portfolio gets stronger and stronger. And in the past, you had to wait for Monsanto and Pioneer to put up list prices for corn and soy. Is &#x2013; are you in a position that you believe you portfolio is strong enough now to get into a price leader position, and could you clarify when you are putting up this price for your &#x2013; especially your corn traits at this year? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is on glyphosate, obviously, Monsanto has abandoned selling a premium versions of the product and your strategy is very much a premium approach with Touchdown and Helix and the Agri H program, I am just wondering whether the Monsanto U-turn in strategy leads to a U-turn or basically a change or a tweak in strategy, how you package glyphosates?</p>
          <p>And the third question is related &#x2013; relating to your outlook for Latin America. You basically say based on strong soy prices, you're hopeful that or you're encouraged that the season will be okay. On the other hand we have very strong disease pressure there and the comparables in some of the crops and some of the usages will be very tough. I'm just wondering how you balance those two items and come to a net-net positive conclusion for the outlook? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Davor, the first question on Monsanto corn seed pricing and NAFTA and then bridge that over John to glyphosate in LatAm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning, Thomas, thanks for the question. We'll be publishing our prices towards end of August, early September, so our customers will get sight of that. You're absolutely right. With the launch of Viptera, we are now in a position to offer a differentiated, highly differentiated technology to the market and to our growers.</p>
          <p>And we're very excited about the launch. We're going to have something like 20% of our portfolio next year incorporating Viptera as a trait. And this will allow us plenty of scope to establish a strong value proposition for that unique technology. And we're going to focus on our products, on the benefits that our portfolio will offer to growers. We're not in a price leadership position in the marketplace, so obviously we'll have to see how the pricing environment shapes up in total. But we're very confident that our portfolio will offer a great value to the grower and we continue to expect excellent adoption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, glyphosate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Glyphosate, yes. Thanks, Thomas. A couple of answers. First of all, on the co-formulations, Helix GT being the leading one. There, we have a different price positioning. I mean, it has &#x2013; it is affected to some degree by glyphosate, but broadly, it is different and the same goes for our co-formulations in soybeans.</p>
          <p>In the straight market that &#x2013; there is a collapsing of the brand ladder, that's clear. And we anticipated that. Our Traction brand, which is a low-priced brand, has been the leading product now for some months. And we will see some impact of that into the second half, but it doesn't mean a strategy change for us. I think we saw this coming.</p>
          <p>LatAm outlook, yeah, the comparables. Well, we do expect &#x2013; the estimates are there will be some acreage increase in soybeans, which I think is perhaps the most important factor for the overall market. For us, we've got new products. We've got our Durivo product. We've got Avicta. We also have Sugarcane opportunities with existing products, which is, we think, an expanding market. And let's not forget Latin America South, which we highlighted in the presentation and there, we do expect to have further growth. So that's why we think there is further potential in Latin America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second call to Paul Walsh at Morgan Stanley. Good morning, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. You mentioned the changing credit terms in France and how that's had some influence, I think in the first and second quarters. Can you just elaborate on that and can you just tell us whether or not we are expecting to see similar changes in credit terms in other European countries?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, looking at the Latin American season, you talked about high inventories putting pressure on pricing in North America. What's the inventory situation like in Latin America and do you see scope for price deflation to moderate in the second half of the year as you move into the Latin America season? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John Ramsay, credit terms and our sense for inventories?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the issue you're referring to, Paul, is specific a French issue and is changing credit terms which have been prescribed by the government. So what is happening is progressively over last year, this year, and next year, there is going to be a shortening of mandatory credit terms. And what this means, of course, is, it does mean that we're going to have to be slightly different in terms of how we manage the supply into the channel and how the channel manages the supply into the grower. But this is unique to France and is something we're dealing with and has no effect on any other countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on Latin America and inventory, it's a very, very different situation down in Latin America. I speak obviously with absolute confidence for us. We invoice to consumption, which means that we don't carry channel stocks, anything like that we &#x2013; that have been carried in the Northern Hemisphere. So it's a very different set up there.</p>
          <p>I think it's also important to point out that the &#x2013; we never had the same sort of price increases in Latin America to the ones we had in North America. So the whole dynamic around that is very different and the grower position in Latin America is quite positive. Soybean prices are pretty good in the whole. So if you look at that objectively, it all looks very different. I mean, of course, as we've always said, it depends on competitive pressures, but there are distinct differences between Latin America and North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Paul. A third call to Jean de Watteville of Nomura Securities. Good morning, Jean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Good morning. Yes, I have a couple of questions. One is for Agrisure Artesian, the first native drought tolerance. My understanding is that native traits, usually the negative of it is that they &#x2013; when there is no droughts, you have lower yields than the leading germplasm. I was wondering if you could share with us what your trials are saying there, when there is no drought, how does the Agrisure Artesian yield compares to the leading germplasm? And secondly, still on that same crop, I would like to know when you will develop the triple stack and triple stack Viptera?</p>
          <p>Then the second question is about Seeds pricing. We understand, obviously, that Monsanto is started to lose a little bit of share. Hugh Grant's talked in a recent conference call about introducing flexible pricing in the U.S., which obviously is raising the risk that the U.S. corn and soybean markets will start to have a very competitive pricing environment. I was wondering, first of all, have you seen any evidence of such price weakness in the seed starting? And what are the views there? Are your 15% target are taking provision that there might be a price decline in the U.S. market?</p>
          <p>And then the third question, you've talked about the capacity expansion for Amistar. I was wondering if you could provide an update about chamatozam, where are you in capacity increase and what's the production outlook for that active ingredient? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, well, thank you for that, Jean. Davor, yield drag, is there any on Artesian and then what is the availability of stacks for Viptera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks very much, Jean. Well, the really exciting thing about Agrisure Artesian is that this is not just a product that's going to help farmers when there is drought. We see very good performance of this product even in non-drought situations. Because essentially what these native traits do, they allow the plant to utilize its water resources much more efficiently. So no evidence at all of yield drag; in fact, so far, our yields suggest something to the contrary. So we're very excited about that.</p>
          <p>On Viptera triples, we will be launching Viptera this year primarily in combination with other traits, so that will be a triple-stack Viptera. So that will give very broad control of the insect complex throughout the U.S. corn market.</p>
          <p>In terms of the pricing question, we certainly haven't seen any particular evidence of price adjustments for next season yet. It's still early in the season. We understand what's being said by some of our competitors, but we believe that we're well-positioned with Viptera to differentiate ourselves and we'll have flexible pricing that is adjusted depending on the competitive environment. There will not be any impact from pricing on our 15% target, on everything that we see today in our expectations. So we're feeling pretty good about still delivering those 15% EBITDA margins next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And &#x2013; John Atkin, the Amistar plant started up a couple of weeks ago. We're taking already first orders and shipments from there. Thimotoxin, how is that going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we're just commissioning the new facility in Switzerland that we built. Volume of Thimotoxin was up on the half, year this despite the carryover stock that we signaled in Seed Care in the United States. There are three &#x2013; if I can just give you three examples of why we are confident about this technology, first of all, Durivo, which is expanding. We talked about that. Cruiser in rice, we are developing new markets here and that is a huge potential and, of course, Plene, our sugarcane seed, if you like, virtual seed that we've created, requires Thimotoxin. All these things are very much on track.</p>
          <p>We always planned that it would be a slower ramp up of demand with Thimotoxin compared with Azoxystrobin. So you will see those volumes continuing to build and the capacity being progressively used throughout the next couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean. The next call to Neil Tyler from JPMorgan. Good morning, Neil.  Okay. We may come back to Neil. Andrew Stott from Merrill Lynch is on the line. Andrew, can you hear us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had a couple of questions, Mike. Firstly on inventories, obviously you expressing some confidence that you think the U.S. inventories are cleared. I just wondered if I could take you to the balance sheet. If you look at your inventory to sales ratio, year-on-year, it's actually gone up 60 basis points. So if you just take a snapshot of inventories from your group level and I know there's going to be currency and Seeds influences there, it would suggest that inventories haven't gone down. So could you square the circle there, please?</p>
          <p>Secondly, a question for John Atkin. Fungicides, obviously, held up better than most categories. I am just wondering how much weather risk there is into the second half. Obviously you've had quite a lot of dry spells, particularly in Eastern Europe, where you've seen that very strong growth. Any risk that you get product put back or that we have an inventory overhang from Eastern Europe or some of Western Europe, as well, going into next season? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, the first question on sort of the difference between channel stock inventories and the visibility of that opposite our finished goods inventory buildup on the balance sheet, John Ramsay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you're absolutely right in your analysis, Andrew, in terms of inventory to sales. And we said at the beginning of the year and because of the shortfall in consumption opposite expectations in 2009, that we expected inventories to come down. Indeed, we are not happy with the levels we were holding at the end of 2009. And, indeed, that remains our intent.</p>
          <p>The volume mix in terms of the products in the first half hasn't had a significant impact on that, but we continue to target for the overall working capital for the year end 2010 about 2% reduction in working capital to sales and more than that coming from inventory, because of the slight increase in receivables due to the volume and growth in Latin America. But we're still targeting to reduce inventories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Amistar inventories in the channel, John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, risk &#x2013; I mean, risk we always have with fungicides as we do with insecticides, in particular. But what we're doing, Andrew, is, if we find one market is weaker than another, then we keep product as long as we can in an active state and then we'll ship it. And we've done that. This is how we are starting to build the Asian market and there is plenty of demand out there for our product. So we don't expect that this will result in unusual inventory build of our products.</p>
          <p>I think it's worth pointing out that in the United States, it really isn't about weather at all. We are building and this is only the third year of this market. We are building a new market for corn and it's based on plant performance, on crop enhancement. And one of the reasons we've seen a price adjustment here is the industry is trying to find the right price point to encourage farmers to make use of what are really excellent products with great benefits. But it is a new market and it's a late-season treatment, a discretionary treatment and so we're finding, I think, the right price points here. But it's not all about weather and I think we have flexibility to get the product to where the greatest demand is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andrew. The next call to Andrew Benson at Citigroup. Good morning, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is a bit challenging to come up with anything precise, but can you just try and define how the weather affected it and had you had 2009's weather, what you think the volume difference might be, just to get an idea of what normal is? But it seems like weather effects have been significant and adverse?</p>
          <p>And secondly on pricing, how &#x2013; what are you doing to try and contain further price pressure and is that inevitable? How do you &#x2013; how are you planning, I don't know your value pricing or the rest of it, but it's a competitive market. Are you planning to contain that?</p>
          <p>And then, obviously, this year, you've had a few significant one-offs, you've had the lower wrong tier of constant currencies. Are there any factors that we can look forward to in 2011 or basically these, in quotes, sort of windfall issues behind us and it will really be underlying volumes that will drive the mid-term improvement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for that, Andrew. I mean, the weather, goodness, weather is in every crop in every market around the world. Some cases, farmers just don't have the &#x2013; if it's too much rain, they literally don't have the means to get into the field to spray. In some cases, of course, the weather gives rise to pest pressures either being more or less than a given year. But, John, to the extent that weather is ever normal, how do we see 2010 versus 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can &#x2013; all the years are different, I can characterize it simply. It's been good in Latin America. It's been good in North America. It's been unhelpful in Europe. We had a dry, cold start and then it's turned dry again. So it's been unhelpful there. And it's been broadly unhelpful in Asia-Pacific. So we've done well despite that, because we've had some very dry conditions in places like Thailand and Southeast Asia has not benefited very well. We live with these things all the time. If I had to summarize the whole year, I'd say swings and roundabouts. You haven't heard us mention the weather very much, so that's perhaps a good indication.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And calling price pressure to the extent that we can never guess competitive behavior, John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and of course we never can. But look, I think what we feel very, very positive about, as we always have, Andrew, is the return on investment that our products bring. And our goal is to deliver these products at fair prices and convince the farmers and our distributors that this is worth investing in. And we've had a lot of success at it.</p>
          <p>What are the things we are doing? I mean, let's not overlook something John Ramsay raised, which is we launched new products. I mean we established new points by launching new formulations, new mixtures, new active ingredients. That's really, really important part of countering any price pressure that we have. We expand markets. We go into markets, brand new markets. We build markets ahead of perhaps what some of our competitors are doing. We talked about Latin America South, an example.</p>
          <p>So these are the things we are doing, but I firmly believe that the products that we offer in the context of today's commodity prices and farmer profitability, which is pretty good, by and large, and better than it was a few months ago. I think the environment looks more positive than it did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's incremental, because obviously that argument applied during the time in the first half this year when prices fell 5%. So you are saying that &#x2013; how does that argument apply? If it applied then and prices fell 5%, and it applies now, why shouldn't prices fall another 5%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think there are two differences. We had that inventory overhang in the first half. We talked about that at the full year. We talked about it at the first quarter. I mean, that was clearly a factor. And I did mention the fact that the industry in some of these new uses in corn fungicides in the U.S. has been trying to find the right price point. These were clearly factors which are &#x2013; we don't have final stock numbers, but we know enough to be confident that they are lower than they were. And the other factor I mentioned, which is the economics crop prices, farm economics look a little better than they did. These are differences.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, John Ramsay, I mean the one-offs, '09 and '10 and to what extent can it help get underneath the underlying demand, volume demand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think there's still six months of 2010 to go and any one-offs in 2011 will bear comparison with 2010. But so far as the raw materials is concerned, we have been faced with relatively static oil prices in recent times and, therefore, not anticipating any similar movement there.</p>
          <p>Two things that are likely to characterize 2011, it will be volume growth and it will be volume growth driven mainly by the emerging markets, as has been specified. And secondly, our continuing focus on operational efficiency. So I think 2011 will be largely a question of those two issues. So far as pricing is concerned, I don't really have much more to add than John. I mean, there is good grounds for believing that the prices have stabilized, but &#x2013; and we will see, but that's the assumption we're working on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you for that, Andrew. Neil Tyler is back. Neil, can you hear us? JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, can you hear me this time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I can. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you, sorry. I am not sure what happened before. Yes, just really wanted to circle back to the margin development, looking at it from a year-on-year perspective. Is it fair to say that the drop in operating margin, which obviously was much more significant than the drop in the gross margin, is primarily attributable to the FX development, other costs and on a constant currency basis developed sort of more in line with the revenues, and that's really the question? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Neil. The short answer is no, it's not to do with the currency. Currency in terms of the margins has been quite minimal in the half, it's had a little effect, but it's quite minimal. In terms of absolute dollar numbers, actually, in the bottom line, currency contributed about $50 million. The story on margins is, broadly, we did not anticipate the price decline that's occurred, and that took 350 basis points, basically, from the gross margin.</p>
          <p>The gross margin, talking Crop Protection here, the gross margin actually is flat year-on-year and that's because of our savings in operational efficiency in the supply chain and &#x2013; but the raw material savings have offset that. So we've got a stable gross margin. But what we have done and intended to do was to continue to invest in research and development and the expenditure on the function costs in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>So when you look at the numbers, that's broadly what's driving the operating margin decline. Now, you have to be careful because at the half year, you can get distortions in the relative weighting of the sales and the development of the function expenses. So I am anticipating that by the end of the year, the crop protection EBITDA margin will be back to just close to 1% decline. And that will essentially be because we have not anticipated the price decline, which you can see in the half year numbers.</p>
          <p>And just to remind you, we have actually achieved something like, I believe I'm right in saying something like a 500-point improvement in the EBITDA margin in Crop Protection since 2001 and, as I mentioned on the answer to the previous call, operational efficiency is &#x2013; has been important in that development and that will continue to be a feature as we go into 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. But on &#x2013; if we just talk about that development since 2001, would you be able to split out what you think the currency benefits has been, the relative dollar weakness over that extended period has been to the EBITDA margin or is that too difficult an exercise to emphasize a try on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not too difficult to do. I don't have the numbers in front of me and &#x2013; but I do expect if I were to do the numbers, there would be a contribution from currency and that might be as much as 150 basis points, maybe about 100. But yes, certainly, notwithstanding recent times, then there has been a broad devaluation of the dollar, broadly speaking in that period, but the majority of it is coming from the maintenance of the gross margin through new product development offsetting very marginal price decline and then the operational efficiency coming through, leveraging the bottom line, has been the major drivers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Neil. And the next call comes in from Tony Jones at Redburn. Good morning, Tony.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. And I've got a few questions. Firstly, could you indicate if any distributor rebates have been offered to clear inventory through Q2 and if so, have they have been paid in Q2 or will we get some cost hits later in the year, maybe Q4? And then on trait licensing, could you give an update on opportunities to license out some of your traits, like GA21 for example, or some of the Vip traits, and when we should start to see revenues coming through? And then finally, could you confirm that the refuge reduction you talked about over next couple of years, will be 5%, so reduce down from 20 to 5 sort of based on dual traits in corn, please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John Atkin, accruals for the rebate program, I guess is predominantly a CP question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CP and NAFTA question, I think. Yes, I don't think you will see anything unusual in the second half in relation to this. Most of the rebating and the incentives have been provided through the channel two to growers to encourage use, as I mentioned before. And that is already reflected. So that's where it is big. There have been some &#x2013; there has been some rebates as well at the channel level, but nothing that I would describe as out of the ordinary and nothing which would give a disproportionate effect in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Davor? The Vip trait licensing revenues as well as refuge reduction, how are we seeing that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We have actually concluded quite a number of trait licensing deals. They are not having a significant impact yet, but over the coming years, they will start to ramp up. So, for example, Viptera has been licensed to Pioneer. We've got the VipCot deals with Dow. We recently announced the bare one and we've also got licensing arrangements around dicamba to Monsanto.</p>
          <p>So a number of deals already concluded. We expect that this will ramp up to in access of $75 million per annum of income, but we are not expecting to see peak revenues from the current licensing deals for maybe another eight to ten years from now. So this will be a gradual ramp up, but it will begin to have the material impact upon the quality of our business.</p>
          <p>In terms of refuge reduction, we expect to see this from 2012, so we will be &#x2013; we're still in the approvals process for that. But our expectation is that in the planting season of 2012, we will have 5% refuge products available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so just so I'm clear, you expect to get it the back end of next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So in the next 12 months, let's say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, we are expecting approvals towards the back end of next year for the 2012 planting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tony. And the next call to Rim Bennani, the Exane BNP Paribas. Good morning, Rim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mike. Two questions. Just a clarification on Crop Protection inventories, I think you've said that they were lower now in the U.S., Europe, I suppose. But I was wondering they were still above normal or we've come back to kind of normal levels or even below today?</p>
          <p>And the second question is a follow-up question on the CapEx plan or the expansion plan. You've signed deals with DuPont, I remember in July 2008, Makhteshim, December 2009 on Amistar Cruiser. And I was wondering if then &#x2013; how the deals were structure then, if they were kind of take or pay close, I mean pre-determined volumes whatever the market was like or if they could adjust the orders and potentially rediscuss prices as the market turns weaker? And I was just wondering as well and this is the last question on the CapEx spend as well, how much these contracts represented us the capacity expansion you are putting in place? Mike, is it 10%, 20, more of capacity put in place that you've locked through these contracts? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rim. John, how is, I guess, what's the new normal, to the extent that we can tell in Crop Protection inventories? And then you heard the question around the fungicide sales to third parties?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, thanks for the question. The inventories, first of all, we can't be sure exactly where they are, because the season is still in motion, but we do know enough to say that they are down. And I expect that they'll be either normal or less than normal. There has been a bit of change in behavior in some places which would tend to push them lower than the average we've seen over the last few years. So that's where we are. We can confirm much more precisely at the third quarter.</p>
          <p>The AZ deals, we are not disclosing details of the contracts that we've signed. But I can tell you that in terms of our &#x2013; the overall capacity expansion, they are a small part. We &#x2013; the capacity expansion was predominantly to meet the needs of our &#x2013; of our branded products. But they are a small part. So they are in the sort of 10 to 15% range of peak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And you've seen already maybe a reaction to the weaker, say 2009-10 season from the guys you've signed contracts with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, in fact. The first &#x2013; let's be clear about the patent. I mean, these contracts only come into effect when the azoxystrobin patent has expired. That has happened in Latin America, so the demand there is quite strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rim. The next question to Alex Stewart of Goldman Sachs. Good morning, Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks very much for taking my questions. Just two quick points. Firstly on the G&amp;A charge, which was just $5 million in 2009 and went up quite significantly to $443 million. And I'm wondering if you could perhaps shed some light on the drivers of that? Secondly just to confirm, when you were talking about the price declines in respect to margins, that, that was 350 basis points on the gross margin? I heard that correctly? Just those two questions, please. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Firstly, Alex, on the G&amp;A, the total for the group, the G&amp;A is showing in the half year about up 100 million. Of it, 60%, 65 million of that is actually currency. So you've got about 40 million real increase in G&amp;A. The biggest component of that is actually our systems implementation in terms of largely driven by Seeds, but also in terms of back office systems or combining Crop Protection and Seeds. We've got some duplication in systems as we do the transition, which of course, is all to drive operational efficiency benefits starting in 2011.</p>
          <p>There is also a component of emerging market growth supporting Brazil particularly, a little bit of ForEx in terms of the real currency there. But basically more investment in terms of support for Brazil, which has significant sales growth, up about 30%, that is bits and pieces of acquisitions and other. But essentially that &#x2013; it's that systems component plus there Brazil support. The second question, just for clarification, when I mentioned 350 basis points, yes, I was referring to the gross margin. But of course, it will trickle down to the net margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alex. Next caller, Florian Gaiser at Kepler. Good morning, Florian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thank you for taking my question. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can hear you fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, the first question would be on how the price decreases that you see now in Q2 and please correct me if I miscalculated that number. I come up with 8% including glyphosate, how that washes out as we go into the 2011 season? Probably see a base effect in Q1 2011 and then basically, it's being washed out in Q2. And then also what is the visibility on that now end of Q2 versus end of Q1, because already in Q1, you said that inventories had &#x2013; the situation had improved, specifically in North America. What has changed since then, so what's &#x2013; and how far is the visibility better now and what's happening starting January 2011?</p>
          <p>The second question would be about the impact of releasing creditor constraints in Eastern Europe, whether you could quantify that a little for us? What was the impact on &#x2013; specifically on Q2? And lastly, you had a shift in selective herbicide sales from Q2 into Q3, I guess in France and Germany, if you could also quantify that for us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I might need to come back to just to clarify your question on the price decrease, what you were actually asking there, Florian. But let me just deal with the other three, the first one was relation to what's changed between Quarter Two and Quarter One. Yes, we did identify a high level of inventory overhang in North America, but let's be clear, it's a competitive environment that reduces prices. High levels of inventory per se don't do that. All they do is provide an environment in which it becomes more likely. So I mean, what we did not anticipate was that there would be a very competitive environment in terms of very specifically on the fungicide, but also extending to other products. And that really is what changed.</p>
          <p>The credit constraint point is, in terms of Eastern Europe, we've relieved credit there and I think successfully. Overall in Eastern Europe, we are up over 5% in terms of net growth but within that, in the markets of Ukraine, in Romania, in Bulgaria is that there is some very specific increases. You are well above that, above 20% in many of those markets. So we are pleased with the impact there and do believe that given the judgments that we've made that we're not taking on undue risk in doing that.</p>
          <p>In terms of the final question was this question of the phasing, this relates to France and Germany and this is a product for oilseed rape, which in total had a phasing effect between Quarter Two and Quarter Three of about $50 million, so we'll see that &#x2013; those sales be made in Quarter Three in this year when they were made in Quarter Two last year. And two-thirds of that is France and a third is Germany. You'll need to clarify the first question, because I didn't get your calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Firstly, I calculated and please correct me on that number, that the price decrease in Crop Protection in the second quarter alone excluding glyphosate was about 8% and I wondered in how far that would affect 2011? I would expect that this price decrease stays with us, a high number in Q1 and only washes out in Q2. Does that make sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, clearly, yeah, I think your calculation is not too far away excluding glyphosate minus 8% is probably approximately correct in the quarter, in Quarter Two. Yes, of course when we get into next year, then we are making comparisons with prices that have come down to these levels and if nothing else changes of course, then we'll be selling in Quarter One and Quarter Two next year at those prices. And given the fact that the prices are more significantly coming down in Quarter Two, yes, you are right. Then the impact should be more equalized, all other things being equal in Quarter Two 2011, you're correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Florian. And we have time for one more call, which goes to Patrick Rafaisz at Vontobel. Good morning, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have one more question. And on the Crop Protection margin, you said the margin would be at the end of the year maybe 1% below what we had last year and obviously we had higher expenses for emerging markets and R&amp;D. But would you &#x2013; what's your guess for 2011? Will the margin revert, will the expenses come down again or will the expenses remain where they are and you would hope to get any much expansion from a higher gross margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, yes, thanks, Patrick. The answer to the question comes to the dynamics in 2011, my answer to the previous question, where fundamentally about volume growth largely in emerging markets and operational efficiency. But we will be continuing to invest in R&amp;D and we will be having to invest more to support that top line growth in emerging markets with more expense investment. But what we are doing and will continue to do is to with our operational efficiency measures, try and provide headroom for that investment. I don't want to be tied down to specific figures for 2011 at this stage, but those are the dynamics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Patrick, and thank you, ladies and gentlemen, for joining the call this morning and we look forward to speaking with you in another 90 days' time or so. And as usual if you've any further questions, please feel free to call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>