<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1283612" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2952</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Michael Mack, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Ramsay, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John Atkin, Chief Operating Officer, Crop Protection</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Davor Pisk, Chief Operating Officer, Seeds</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Andrew Stott</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Rhian Tucker</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Bernd Pomrehn</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Andrew Benson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Rim Bennani</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Patrick Rafaisz</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Neil Tyler</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Bruno Eschli</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Virginie Boucher-Ferte</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">J&#xFC;rgen Reck</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to this presentation of Syngenta's 2009 Results. I'm joined here today by John Ramsay, our Chief Financial Officer; our Chief Operating Officers of Crop Protection and Seeds, John Atkin and Davor Pisk. Also here with us in the room is Robert Berendes, Head of Business Development and Sandro Aruffo, who is the Head of Research and Development for Syngenta.</p>
          <p>We will all be happy to take your questions at the conclusion of the presentation and for those of you following us by webcast or by telephone, of course you can submit yours as well.</p>
          <p>When we met this time last year it was in a climate of considerable financial and economic uncertainty. Now for our business that was manifest by lower crop prices and credit constraints in major emerging markets. And the year brought further challenges in the form of planting delays and reduced pest pressure.</p>
          <p>However, the results that we have announced today show that we've delivered on our undertaking to outperform even in the most difficult market conditions. Sales in 2009 were slightly higher at constant exchange rates, thanks to the determination of the implementation of price increases.</p>
          <p>Our pricing strategy reflects the value of our products to growers in raising yields even at lower crop prices. Sales also benefited from the rollout of new technology in both Crop Protection and Seeds.</p>
          <p>Earnings were close to their record level of 2008 despite significant currency headwinds and raw material costs. Throughout the year, we successfully managed risks, particularly in emerging markets. This limited our sales somewhat but meant that our excellent record on receivables management has been maintained, putting us in a strong position to benefit from the improvement in these markets, which began towards the end of the year.</p>
          <p>We continued our investment in new Crop Protection capacity in order to meet demand for our major products and we made further acquisitions in Seeds in line with our strategy of reinforcing our presence in key crops.</p>
          <p>After taking account of these investments, we still generated free cash flow of almost $600 million, which underpins our confidence in proposing a maintained dividend and a share repurchase in 2010.</p>
          <p>Let me hand you over now to John Ramsay for more detail on our financial performance, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mike. Good morning. I'm pleased to present a strong set of financial results in what was a challenging year. Sales in 2009 were 1% higher at constant exchange rates, with a 4% increase in price and a volume decline of 3% due to the late planting and low pest pressure in the main northern hemisphere season.</p>
          <p>In fourth quarter, however, we saw volume growth, reflecting a strong performance in Latin America. EBITDA increased by 9% at constant exchange rates. Price increases across the business more than offset the impact of higher raw material costs. We also reined back operating costs in response to the difficult environment.</p>
          <p>Currencies had a substantial negative impact on the financial results and reduced reported EBITDA by almost $350 million. But consequently, earnings per share were 3% lower, and I'll return later to the impact of currencies. The ability of our business to generate cash even in a challenging year was demonstrated with free cash flow of $580 million, resulting in a net gearing of 25%. And return on invested capital after tax exceeded our 20% target for the fifth successive year.</p>
          <p>When looking at the evolution of reported sales, you can see the negative impact of currencies, which reduce sales by nearly $800 million or by 7%. The volume decline in Crop Protection was partially offset by growth in Seeds.</p>
          <p>You can also see from the slide substantial contribution from pricing, which overall was up by 4%. Both businesses contributed to the $440 million price increase, which more than offset the net volume decline to leave sales up 1% in constant currency.</p>
          <p>The next two slides show the performance of each business in more detail, starting with Crop Protection. Sales at constant exchange rates were 2% lower at $8.5 billion. Volumes were 4% lower as a result of the reduced northern hemisphere season and risk management in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Prices for the full year were up by 2% and by 4% excluding glyphosate. We've achieved our targets in terms of raising prices and will now focus on keeping prices at the new higher level. With regard to glyphosate, the reduction in price took place in the middle of last year and this means that we will continue to feel a negative impact in the first half of 2010 when compared to the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>EBITDA of $2.2 billion represented a margin of 26.4%, almost unchanged compared with the record levels of 2008. At constant exchange rates, the margin was 120 basis points higher than 2008, reflecting the positive impact of expense savings and higher prices, which together more than offset a $150 million increase in raw material costs. During the year, we were as you would expect in the difficult market conditions, particularly attentive to operating cost control.</p>
          <p>Growth in Seeds was a combination of volume and price. A strong underlying performance across all regions and product lines was enhanced by acquisitions, which added 2% to sales growth.</p>
          <p>Fourth-quarter sales were augmented by change in sales terms in our U.S. Corn and Soybean business. And in order to standardize our processes in alignment with industry practice, we moved to recognizing sales on delivery and this added about 5% to Seeds sales.</p>
          <p>EBITDA increased significantly and the margin rose from 5.5% in 2008 to 9.5%. At constant 2008 exchange rates the margin would have been 11.2%. The main driver was the transformation of our U.S. Corn portfolio, which Davor will tell you more about later in the presentation.</p>
          <p>As this transformation develops, we are improving the quality of our gross margin and are able to achieve greater leverage in our marketing spend. And overall, Seeds is on track with the strategic direction we've set for the business.</p>
          <p>The next slide shows you the significant currency and raw material headwinds affecting operating income. A significant proportion of the currency impact came from emerging markets. In these markets, we were able to achieve a significant offset by stepping up our initiative on pricing.</p>
          <p>In East Europe and the emerging Asia, about 60% of the currency impact on sales was offset by price increases. These are included in the column business performance. We also focused on cost efficiencies allowing us to achieve an operating margin of 17.4%, only slightly below last year's record level.</p>
          <p>Looking now at the lines between operating income and earnings per share, net financial expense of $122 million was lower than in 2008, going essentially to the level of currency related balance sheet devaluations that occurred in quarter four of 2008 and did not recur in 2009. For 2010, I anticipate that net financial expense will be around the 2008 level.</p>
          <p>Due to market conditions in 2009, a lower proportion of our income was found in higher rate tax countries. This together with the continuation of tax optimization measure resulted in a lower tax rate.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we expect the tax rate to revert &#x2013; to be in line with our medium-term expectation of low-to-mid 20s. Earnings per share were 3% lower due to the impact of currencies on operating income.</p>
          <p>Let me now update you on the recent currency movements on our expectations of their impact in 2010. We've used a similar chart before to show you the recent volatility of currencies against the dollar. First, the currency impact was concentrated in the first half following the devaluation towards the end of 2008, with a devaluation of most currencies and particularly those in emerging markets. Most emerging market currencies have recovered significantly, but as you can see, the dip towards the end of the year and remains well below the end 2007 levels.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we will benefit from the improvement of the euro and Eastern European currencies against the dollar. However, the positive impact will be partly offset by the strength of the Swiss franc. The Swiss franc represents around 15% of our operating costs and because of the small size of the Swiss market we've very little in the way of offsetting revenues. We estimate the net benefit in 2010 from currencies therefore at around $50 million, assuming rates around current levels.</p>
          <p>We also expect to benefit from lower raw material cost in 2010. Raw materials account for the majority of our variable costs and as a proportion of total cost of goods sold, they increased in 2009. The seasonality of our business means that production for the northern hemisphere season had to take place for previous year and thus in the first half of 2009, we were selling product manufactured in 2008 when oil prices were high.</p>
          <p>In addition, our raw materials are largely purchased under longer term contracts, which can take some months to adjust the changes in the oil price. Already in the second half of 2009, we experienced a positive swing in raw material costs. And for the full year 2010, we expect a benefit of around $150 million.</p>
          <p>Turning now to cash flow. Free cash flow of $580 million was achieved after above average capital expenditure and the negative contribution from working capital. Capital expenditure reflected spending on our capacity expansion program for Azoxystrobin and Thiamethoxam and the program is now nearing completion, and CapEx should be lower in 2010.</p>
          <p>The movement in working capital reflects the build-up of inventories as a result of lower than expected consumption in the second and third quarters. We're now beginning to reverse this, and as a result are targeting a 2% reduction in working capital as a percentage of sales for the 2010 year. And the impact of inventories was partly offset by control of receivables, which is illustrated on the next slide.</p>
          <p>The chart shows you day sales outstanding in each of the main emerging market regions, and we stated at the outset of the financial crisis that we would actively managed risk in these areas, and we were able to do so effectively because of the strong risk management that we already had in place. Indeed, we have managed these markets through the financial crisis with negligible bad debts.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, we've been operating a barter model for many years providing an unrivaled advantage in managing credit risk among our customers. In 2009, we were able to transfer some of this experience to Eastern Europe, and we will continue to build industry leading models in this region.</p>
          <p>You can see that DSO's in Latin America was slightly up compared with the end of 2008, when the financial crisis was at its height. This was entirely intentional and reflects both the recovery and demand and the improved financial environment for growers. By managing risk tightly over the last 18 months, we've put ourselves in a strong position to take full advantage of more favorable emerging market conditions.</p>
          <p>Now this slide shows you the ways in which we have used our cash flow over the last five years. You can see that we've stepped up the rate of investment in both fixed assets and acquisitions. And we've also substantially raised the dividend.</p>
          <p>Despite this, a sustained cash generation has meant that the net gearing is now back at the bottom end of our target range. In 2010, therefore, we plan a cash return to shareholders of around $750 million. And this will be made up of a combination of a maintained Swiss franc dividend which will be higher in U.S. dollars and a share repurchase.</p>
          <p>A strong financial position means that we can make this undertaking while maintaining the flexibility for acquisitions and to exploit further growth opportunities as they occur. Although for 2010 these are not shown on the slide.</p>
          <p>To conclude, let me summarize the outlook for 2010. Improved business conditions notably in the emerging markets lead us to expect volume growth starting in the second quarter. Let me remind you that the first quarter of 2009 was very strong and presents a tough base of comparison. We can expect the quarter one sales in 2010 will be lower than in 2009.</p>
          <p>In Crop Protection, our priority will be to maintain, grow share in a competitive environment. We'll make every effort to hang on to the price increases we have achieved, but as I said before our success ultimately depends upon the behavior of our competitors.</p>
          <p>In Seeds, we expect to see further increase in profitability as we move towards a target of 15% EBITDA margin in 2011. We expect to realize currency and raw material benefits together totaling around $200 million and these should offset a return to higher growth investments and also a higher tax rate. Overall, this should enable us to achieve good growth in EBITDA, and even allowing for the higher tax rate growth in earnings per share. We expect to continue a record of substantial free cash flow and maintain a return on invested capital above 20%, both of which are key elements of our financial performance.</p>
          <p>With that let me hand you over to John Atkin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thank you, John. You've already heard about some of the broad factors influencing our business in 2009. So, let's look in a bit more detail of the regions, starting with Europe.</p>
          <p>In the season that began late, we saw low disease pressure leading to reduced fungicide applications. For the farmer though things didn't turn out too badly, as late rains boosted cereal yields. In Eastern Europe, though the farm economy generally was affected by credit constraints, and as you've heard risk management was our priority and this had a significant effect on sales.</p>
          <p>Turning to NAFTA, in the U.S. too the season was late and both disease and insect pressure was low. In the middle of the year, a sharp drop in glyphosate prices created some instability although it was helpful to grow our profitability. Glyphosate is of course widely used in the U.S. on corn and soybeans and this is leading to an increased build-up of glyphosate resistant weeds.</p>
          <p>Latin America in the first half of the year was severally affected by drought in the south and by a lack of credit availability. There was a marked recovery in the fourth quarter with the start of the new season and this demonstrates the dynamism of agriculture in this region. Growers in Asia-Pacific seem to have been virtually untouched by the financial crisis of 2009. They continue to step-up investment in order to increase yields and this was reflected in our double-digit sales growth.</p>
          <p>Turning now to sales by product line. In selective herbicides, we saw good growth in NAFTA on both cereals and soybeans. Sales of corn herbicides were lower because of the late season in the United States and our risk management priority in emerging markets. Overall, a significant increase in selective herbicide pricing offset low volumes. Sales volume for non-selective herbicides was up, but this was not sufficient to offset the impact of lower TOUCHDOWN prices from mid-year.</p>
          <p>In fungicides, we achieved growth on vegetables and rice notably in Latin America and Asia. Sales of cereals were affected by the low pest pressure in the northern hemisphere and again higher prices offset the decline in volume.</p>
          <p>Insecticide sales were slightly lower because of the reduced incidence of pest generally and because of risk management in Latin America in the first half of the year. In Seed Care, we again saw a broad based growth led by our flagship product CRUISER. Professional Products were affected by the economic downturn, particularly our Gulf Coast business and sales of professional horticulturalists who supply garden centers.</p>
          <p>Now let me say a little bit more about the contribution of our new products, which represent most of our product lines. Their performance shows how we are capable of generating growth globally. DURIVO is one of the many growth drivers we have in emerging Asia, but the other three have been primarily focused on the developed markets. AXIAL, for example, was first launched in Canada in 2006 and yet in 2009 sales there grew by more than 50% as an increasing number of growers realized its advantages versus competitor products.</p>
          <p>REVUS is proving its worth on fruit, vegetables and wines in a large number of European markets. AVICTA is established on cotton in the U.S. and this year will be expanded to corn, with a subsequent launch on soybeans in Latin America planned.</p>
          <p>Now, looking at some regional highlights of the past six months. There are two important points to be made about Latin America, firstly Q4 was strong, following a challenging first half of 2009 and outlook is positive. Grower sentiment has improved because the Brazilian government is increasing agricultural support and soybean exports are strong. This has led to higher acreage planted.</p>
          <p>Secondly, the major soybean rust market where Syngenta has a leading position with 35% share is increasing as illustrated by the bars on the left. Plentiful rain has favored disease pressure and we expect this to be a record year for the soybean fungicide market.</p>
          <p>Asia Pacific is an increasingly important part of our business. Strong sales growth throughout the year reflected the breadth of our portfolio and customer support on a wide range of crops. Fruit, vegetables and rice are the most important segments and rice is expanding fast, particularly with the rollout of the DURIVO insecticide range under the Virtako brand. We're also developing comprehensive rice solutions, combining crop protection technology and proprietary seed from our rice breeding program.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we'll have the initial launch of Invinsa in granular form in Malaysia and Pakistan to combat heat stress in rice. This is the first breakthrough in commercial use of this exciting new technology. Invinsa is just one example of the ways in which we are addressing agronomic challenges for growers, while at the same time driving yield. Our broad approach underpins a significant gain in market share as you can see on the next slide.</p>
          <p>We estimate that we've gained market share in three out of four regions, including Latin America and Asia, where the expansion of agriculture productivity is most critical. We've achieved these gains despite the active management of risk in 2009 as you just heard.</p>
          <p>The quality of our portfolio and the value of our products to growers enabled us to demonstrate price leadership, in particular over the last 18 months, and we continue to focus on this as an integral part of our strategy.</p>
          <p>Our focus on the differing needs of growers in each region in terms of both products and services already distinguishes us from the competition. Our aim is to continue growing market share, and the next few slides explain how further differentiation of our offer can help us to achieve this.</p>
          <p>Now, plant performance is essential to this objective. We explained last year, how we are already playing a leading role in pest control and providing full crop programs and solutions, taking the grower from the moment he plants the seed right through the harvest.</p>
          <p>We are now starting to take yields to a new level through crop enhancement, which means yield benefits going beyond pest control. This is a multi-crop global opportunity and the potential lies in existing as well as new products. It enables us to address the broader challenges facing growers to maximize productivity whilst making best use of available resources.</p>
          <p>Now let me show you a few examples. Starting with Avicta seed care. Nematodes affect 80% of U.S. corn acres, but many growers were unaware of their existence, that is until our marketing team came up with Ned, the plastic nematode shown here on tool. He is about 20 meters long which is about 20,000 times as big as a microscopic nematode, which damages plant roots you can imagine why the farmers were so impressed.</p>
          <p>Last year in over 1,000 field trials, we showed that Avicta brings an average yield advantage of six to eight bushels an acre, and with the help of Ned, we raised awareness of the yield impact nematodes can have. As I said earlier Avicta is being launched in the U.S. this year.</p>
          <p>My second example is set to revolutionize sugar planting in Brazil. Last year, we carried out successful demonstrations of our new planting technology, which includes our seed care. We have patented this unique proposition for sugarcane growers and are already seeing significant interest from major sugar mills. The new method of planting 4 centimeter segments instead of large sugarcane cuttings will lead to a 25% saving in production cost.</p>
          <p>We are developing innovative credit solutions to facilitate expansion of this technology, when we launch it next year. We see peak sales potential in excess of $300 million and a strong longer term linkage to our development programs in germplasm and traits.</p>
          <p>As I said we are finding crop enhancement effects in existing as well as new products. We haven't talked much about MODDUS in the past. It's a plant growth regulator used mainly in cereals. It produces shorter, strongest stems and increased root mass. Not only does this prevent lodging, it also results in improved water and nutrient uptake and better tolerance of drought and heat. The benefit of all this of course, consistently high yields as crops perform more reliably under environmental stress. We are developing a deeper understanding of the benefits of this extremely useful product and we'll expand the application of MODDUS to new markets.</p>
          <p>Durivo, one of our new products as you saw earlier on, sales quadrupled in 2009. Virtako on rice is a new mode of action which targets insect control and vigor. You can see on the photo how much greener and stronger the crop looks. A very successful launch in China last year illustrates why we are particularly excited about this technology.</p>
          <p>On vegetables, Durivo is one-shot application that controls insects through a simple soil application while invigorating young transplanted plants. Ampligo is another application this time foliar for a wide range of crops.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn to corn fungicides, another example of crop enhancement. And to look at the opportunity in two markets, starting with Brazil where we have led in the creation of a brand new market. Corn fungicides were launched in Brazil just three years ago. Last season, penetration reached 47% and we expect further growth.</p>
          <p>Our product is an AMISTAR mix called PRIORI XTRA also the market leader in soybeans. And we now have close to half the total corn market. Growers using our product achieve a three to one return on investment, benefiting from disease control and the additional plant vigor effect. We are targeting peak sales in this market of at least $100 million. Implementation is in the hands of our joint Crop Protection and Seeds commercial operation in Brazil. Field force knowledge of both categories will help to accelerate market development.</p>
          <p>Turning to the U.S., market penetration in 2009 was lower than in 2008 mainly because of lower corn prices and the reluctance of growers to invest more on late planted crops with uncertain yield potential. Ironically, the benefits of using Syngenta fungicides in 2009 were just as positive as in 2008. For 2010, therefore, we are launching new programs to encourage farmers to invest and benefit from this excellent technology also based on AMISTAR.</p>
          <p>We've introduced a more convenient higher strength product, Quilt Xcel on an early application option for Quadris, which allows the grower to spray by tractor at the same time when he applies his last herbicide spray. We're also communicating new data showing significant yield quality and harvesting benefits. You can see some of these illustrated on the photographs.</p>
          <p>CRUISER is a seeds treatment product you may know well. And it is already used on 43 crops in 76 countries. Wheat is a new opportunity and in particular wheat planted in cold conditions such as those you find in the northern hemisphere. If you look at the photo comparisons in the top, you can see that CRUISERMAXX stimulates the roots and improves overall plant vigor.</p>
          <p>Again the uptake of water and nutrients is improved, resulting in better establishment and higher yields. We see sales potential approaching $100 million focused on the main wheat markets of the U.S., Canada and Eastern Europe. CRUISER is highly compatible with our proprietary wheat seeds business that we are developing in several markets including the U.S., where we already have a leading position.</p>
          <p>CRUISER has now been on the market from some ten years, but we have many products older than that which continue to perform well, reflecting on active lifecycle management. On this slide you see five such products, all of patent for a number of years as you see in the first column. And yet FLEX, BRAVO and SCORE have shown substantial growth over the last five years, while TOPIK and KARATE, both in highly competitive segments, have shown only a slight decline.</p>
          <p>Most of these products showed good growth in 2009 and two of them, FLEX and SCORE achieved their peak sales to-date last year. Together these products have sales of $1 billion, which helps you see why ours is such a cash generative business.</p>
          <p>Factors behind this success are shown on the slide and they are different for each product and that's just the point. We provide new value to our customers and this prolongs the lifecycles of our products for years, and sometimes decades, beyond patent expiry. Which brings me on to Azoxystrobin, the active ingredient for AMISTAR.</p>
          <p>Over the last four years, we have seen compound annual sales growth of 14% across a diverse crop base. And this broad growth is set to continue. In Corn, we have the crop enhancement opportunity that I just talked to you about. In Soybean, we expect further acreage expansion in Latin America an ongoing high disease pressure.</p>
          <p>We're expanding the use of AMISTAR on cereals in East Europe, and in vegetables and fruits we are developing new mixtures and exploring new markets, notably in Asia. All these drivers mean that we need additional capacity and our new UK plant is due to come on-stream in the second quarter of this year. The capacity expansion will increase our advantage as a low cost producer, and this was already reflected in the supply agreement with Makhteshim which we signed in November of last year.</p>
          <p>It's the similar story for Thiamethoxam, the active ingredient for ACTARA and CRUISER. After compound annual sales growth of 23% since 2005, we expect volumes to double from the current level. Mixtures are key to the story and already account for a significant portion of ACTARA sales of which DURIVO is a major part.</p>
          <p>Mixtures are now becoming increasingly important in seed treatment, notably as part of AVICTA Complete for corn in the U.S. and later for soybeans. We expect that mixtures will account for more than 50% of CRUISER sales by 2014, and growth in all regions spurred by the crop enhancement benefits are planned.</p>
          <p>We are an R&amp;D led company and innovation is critical for our future growth. Our pipeline continues to be in excellent shape with a total peak sales potential of over $2 billion. Invinsa and the cereal fungicide Isopyrazam both have &#x2013; just have first introductions in 2010. Three other late stage pipeline products have all advanced and our early development fungicides are showing good progress.</p>
          <p>Let me conclude with an overview of our strategy. Portfolio expansion encompasses a number of aspects as I've touched upon today. New products and the pipeline are of course fundamental to the renewal of our range. But life cycle management can be equally important both in developing and delivering new solutions to the grower and in maximizing returns for Syngenta.</p>
          <p>Crop enhancement is a whole new opportunity to create customer value whether from existing or new products, and I provided several examples of how this is becoming a reality.</p>
          <p>Our unique presence in multiple crops and countries enables us to offer innovative solutions tailored to the needs of the local customers. Technical advice and support is a critical part of this, particularly in emerging markets where we are accompanying growers on the journey towards higher productivity.</p>
          <p>We have consistently shown our ability to manage the operating costs and we will continue to drive efficiency as an enabler for further investments in growth. Our investment in new capacity is part of this and will further enhance our status as a low cost producer.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, we intend to reinforce the leading market shares we have shown you today, and to outperform a market underpinned by the long-term need for increased food production.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me hand you over to Davor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, John. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. In 2009, Seed sales increased across all product lines continuing to demonstrate the strength of our offer across crops. Our Corn and Soybean business expanded across all regions with sales up 21%. Growth in diverse field crops was broad based, up 11%. As we extended our leadership position in sunflower with the acquisition in the second half of Monsanto's hybrid sunflower business and recorded further expansion in glyphosate tolerant sugar beet in the U.S.</p>
          <p>In vegetables, we again outperformed in a growth market with highly attractive profitability. Flowers reflected the consolidation of Goldsmith and Yoder, which compensated for lower underlying sales due to the economic downturn.</p>
          <p>I will now take you through the performance of our businesses in more detail, beginning with corn globally. We have a broad geographic presence in corn with over 50% of our sales occurring outside the U.S.</p>
          <p>As you can see from the graph, we significantly advanced the gross margin in 2009. This increase reflected the continuing rollout of our improved traits and germplasm in the U.S., which command a price premium over the rest of the portfolio.</p>
          <p>In Europe, growth and share gains in the west were partially offset by the impact of our rigorous risk management policies in Eastern Europe. In Latin America, we received approval for our double stack corn traits in both Brazil and Argentina. Brazil also became the first country to approve for cultivation our new broad lepidopteran trait Viptera. These approvals will allow us to play a leading role in the expansion of GM traits in Latin America.</p>
          <p>Our highlights of the year and a key enabler of our future growth was the performance of our leading germplasm across Asia-Pacific. The success of our tropical germplasm in particular, contributed the sales growth of 40% and a gain in market share. We've established a strong market position in South East Asia and plan to support further growth with investments in new production facilities.</p>
          <p>The opening of our research facility in China and the establishment there of new partnerships paves the way for further innovation notably in agronomic traits. Let me now tell you more about our progress in the U.S. market, where the market penetration of triple stack seed continues to increase.</p>
          <p>In 2009, the proportion of our proprietary Agrisure triple stack within our portfolio grew significantly, representing 25% of units sold or more than double 2008 levels. We were however still under-traited compared with the market. In 2010, we expect to see further advances with our triple stack offer approaching market levels and representing more than 50% of the portfolio.</p>
          <p>We're now combining our triple stack with Viptera and are on track to launch our first multi-stack offer this year. Further improvements in our U.S. portfolio will be achieved through expanding the combination of proprietary traits with our top-performing germplasm which is becoming increasingly competitive as the next slide shows.</p>
          <p>The increase in our proprietary trait portfolio is being accompanied by substantial improvement in our germplasm. Here you see the performance of our broad portfolio across different corn growing regions in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Our leading hybrids, when measured against the comparable offer from our leading competitors, showed a yield advantage in the north and south, and continue to improve in the central regions that make-up the main U.S. Corn Belt.</p>
          <p>In these regions, we're narrowing the gap with the competition to the extent that the yield differential is no longer significant enough to influence purchasing decisions.</p>
          <p>If you look at our top five performing hybrids, you see a yield advantage in six out of seven sales regions and this advantage was as high as eight bushels an acre in the north. In 2010, these hybrids will account for around 30% of our offer, representing a significant gain in competitiveness. Overall, this performance delivers an increasing number of wins and provides us with the confidence of the transformation of our portfolio is on track.</p>
          <p>In 2010, based upon the current order book, we see strong demand for our products and our lead AGRISURE GT, triple stack seed is sold out. Further momentum is coming from the pipeline, which we have broadened to reflect our expanding GM offer in Latin America. We now estimate peak sales of over $2 billion from the products shown on this slide.</p>
          <p>Let me update you on Viptera, for which we plan to launch limited quantities in both the U.S. and Brazil in 2010. Viptera, with its new mode of action will provide a higher level of insect control across a broad spectrum of chewing pests, including pests that until now have been poorly controlled.</p>
          <p>Our 2009 trials continue to show excellent results with the yield advantage up to 16 bushels an acre. Viptera brings a refuge reduction opportunity in the South and we'll be progressively rolling out a full array of refuge reduction options, taking accounts of the different needs of growers throughout corn growing areas.</p>
          <p>AVICTA completes, will form part of our Seeds Care offer as John has explained, with Seeds Care viewed by the grower as an integral part of its seed purchasing decision. Our output trait corn amylase, Enogen remains in the final stages of the regulatory process, results from the three plant trials to-date indicate that Enogen can play a vital role in increasing productivity in the ethanol industry. And we remain on track to introduce a native traits drought tolerance solution in 2011, just one example of our ability to deliver new solutions within a competitive timeframe.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to the Soybean, three countries, the U.S., Brazil and Argentina account for around 80% of global production and all increased acreage in 2009. In NAFTA, we have a leading germplasm, which we priced to value and we've maintained these higher prices in highly competitive market.</p>
          <p>Sales in Latin America again grew rapidly. In Brazil, the success of our early maturing V-Max germplasm has enabled us to achieve a share of 10% in just three years. The integration of our crop protection in Seeds businesses in Brazil is accelerating our progress, allowing us to look at combined solutions, for example, in the control of soybean rust.</p>
          <p>In Argentina, we entered the soybean market last year, following the acquisition of the SPS and have now established the platform for further growth.</p>
          <p>Our diverse field crops business expanded across all regions in 2009. The business includes several crops, including a leading position in cereals. But today, I would like to focus on the two largest, sugar beet and sunflower. In sugar beet, we have over the years focused on maintaining and building strong positions in key markets. In the U.S., we have recently growing the business significantly with the introduction of glyphosate-tolerant beet and now have a market share of 35%.</p>
          <p>In sunflower, we've invested heavily in emerging markets, where we've recognized a growth potential more than a decade ago. In these markets, we have launched a variety of native traits offers including herbicide tolerance and virus and disease control adapted to the needs of each territory.</p>
          <p>As you can see from the chart Eastern Europe is an important region for this business. Let me say a bit more about our crop strategy there. Of course, cereals are widely grown across Eastern Europe, intensive cultivation of sugar beet, sunflower and corn, however, take place largely in Western Russia as you can see from the maps in the middle of this chart. Growers frequently rotate these crops.</p>
          <p>We're the market leader in sunflower with a 27% market share and also have a strong sugar beet position. We are leveraging grower's positive experience of our brands to expand our share of a growing corn market. For each crop, we are focusing on the high value opportunity. This means improved hybrids and corn and the move away from farm-saved seed in sunflower.</p>
          <p>We are increasingly addressing the large professional growers with a combined Crop Protection seed and seed care offer something we're uniquely placed to do and which will give us a greater share of spend per hectare.</p>
          <p>Let me now move on to another leading part of our Seeds business, which also have substantial further growth potential. Vegetables is a $3.7 billion market, which is set to double over the next 15 years. Our business is broad based and in 2009, sales grew by 8% after excluding the impact of the divestment of some shell pea activities. These divestments were part of our strategy to focus on high value crops where we target number one or two positions.</p>
          <p>Growth in these segments is driven by consumer demand for high quality fresh produce. And in 2009 we expanded our portfolio through the acquisition of two lettuce companies. We continue to expand share globally and to increase margins from already high level. The fastest growth rates are being achieved in the emerging markets. And you can see this in more detail on this next slide.</p>
          <p>Over the last five years our emerging market business has grown at a compound annual rate of 20%. Underlying this performance is the strength of our germplasm and our ability to harness complex traits to improve both quality and productivity.</p>
          <p>In these markets, our focus is mainly on grower and downstream benefits. Both of which are relatively underdeveloped. We're also working on transposing some of the flavor attributes found in hybrids in these countries to other regions.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to look at couple of examples of what we are doing in emerging markets starting with Latin America. In Brazil, we now have 100% share of the rapidly expanding process sweet corn market.</p>
          <p>We have achieved this in the space of five years by focusing on the traits that matter to consumer's tenderness and taste as well as on efficiency for processors. We have pioneered a shift away from green corn into sweet corn and have developed high quality tropical varieties, which are opening up new export markets for our customers. We have now embarked upon an adapted breeding program to expand our presence into the very fragmented fresh market.</p>
          <p>Turning to Asia, In India, we're the market leader in vegetables, with a 28% share of the high value commercial seed market. We have a broad offer across a large number of high value crops. We've differentiated our technology by adapting it to the local market. We have developed native traits for disease resistance. As you can see on the photo, which shows the tomato hybrid which is resistant to yellow leaf curl.</p>
          <p>In virus resistance we have outpaced the competition in being able to adapt our germplasm quickly to resist new strains of virus. These traits increase the reliability and the abundance of the crop for the growers. Other areas of focus include firmness, shelf life, and affordability in tomatoes. While in hot pepper, as you might expect, the emphasis is on color and pungency. All these enable us to command a significant price premium.</p>
          <p>Before concluding let me say a few words relating to flowers which is a key enabler of our Lawn and Garden business. Lawn and Garden is a $15 billion market and we have leading positions in products for professional users, such as ornamental growers and golf course managers.</p>
          <p>Our portfolio is unique in offering a broad range of solutions comprising genetics, chemical controls and growing media. Our best-in-class innovation comes from our ability to leverage our Crop Protection portfolio and from using our understanding of plant genetics to develop our leading flowers business.</p>
          <p>Environment in 2009 was difficult due to economic recession in the main markets. We focus on the successful integration of recent acquisitions, which have expanded the range of proprietary genetics, for example in chrysanthemum and asters shown in the photos on the slide.</p>
          <p>In summary, we have a truly global platform in Seeds. Through our expertise in breeding we have built germplasm strength across crops, which were complementing the development of GM and native traits.</p>
          <p>We are leveraging our technology across regions, and are seeing particularly rapid growth in the emerging markets, where seeds play a vital role in the improvement of agricultural productivity.</p>
          <p>We continue our strategy of making targeted acquisitions, which further expand our geographic footprint and enhance our genetic pool. Increasing returns for the business are evidenced in the step-up in our Corn gross margin and are underpinned by strong growth in high margin businesses such as vegetables.</p>
          <p>The increased R&amp;D investments of recent years are clearly paying off. And R&amp;D expense will now stabilize at around 15% of sales. We are firmly on track to achieve our target of a 15% EBITDA margin in 2011. And are confident that we'll take this business well beyond that in the years that follow.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me hand you back to Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Davor. I think that John Atkin and Davor in the presentations have conveyed a sense for the depth and the breadth of our business.</p>
          <p>In Crop Protection, the combination of innovation and life cycle management gives us a vast array of options for meeting grower's needs.</p>
          <p>In Seeds our presence across crops and the crops geographies offers a multitude of opportunities to further capture value. And the structural shift towards the modernization of agriculture particularly in emerging markets continues. Our leadership in these markets which now represents close to 40% of our sales has been reinforced and we look forward to renewed growth in 2010. We are only beginning to exploit the full potential for crop enhancement in our portfolio and this will allow us to deliver additional value over the long-term.</p>
          <p>Our combined Crop Protection and seeds pipelines have peak sales potential of over $4 billion and we look forward now to seeing launches from both in 2010.</p>
          <p>Our expertise in both chemicals and genetics places us in a unique position to develop increasingly integrated offers that will encompass multiple aspects of the investment made by growers in their crops.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we expect to grow earnings and to continue our record of strong cash flow, which gives us considerable financial flexibility. We're attentive to maintaining an optimized balance sheet and that is what underlies the cash return we announced today. We're also retaining the ability to finance future growth in a market that continues to offer an abundance of opportunities.</p>
          <p>That concludes your presentation today. And we will now be happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I said earlier we have the phone lines hooked on as well as the webcast. And of course we've people here in the room. I'll first take questions here in the room and if you address the question I'll share those with my colleagues. Please introduce yourself by name and your firm. Thank you. Please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger, Helvea, I have three questions, please, all of them on the outlook that you've provided this morning. First question is you've stated that you'd expect the volume growth as of the second quarter this year. Looking at some of your competitors' statements, it would appear that we've seen a strong start to the year season in both North America and Europe. And hence I'm a little bit surprised why not volume growth in the first quarter already. If you could elaborate on that a little bit, please?</p>
          <p>Then the second question -- competitive pressure in Crop Protection is also an issue that you've mentioned in your outlook. Could you give us a feel for the changes that you have seen over the past few months and quarters? And whether you think that momentum has stepped up in terms of pressure here on pricing, looking forward particularly at, given your broad positive outlook, if you really think that price pressure will continue as it has?</p>
          <p>Third question is on your EPS outlook. If I remember correctly, in the past, you used to provide quantitative EPS growth targets. Why do you refrain to do so this time around? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. I'll first take the EPS question and then John, maybe you can address the consumption of crop protection products in the northern hemisphere as well as some of the dynamic around the pricing pressures that we see exiting 2009 and now coming into 2010.</p>
          <p>On the specificity around the EPS targets, what we have done this &#x2013; in this outlook statement is to give a lot of help in terms of the things that we know about including for example that the currency isn't going to be nearly the sort of headwinds that we faced in 2009. In effect they're going to benefit us in 2010. We won't face the headwinds on raw material costs, which we did a year ago this time, and in the fact that's going to benefit us as well. And we shared with you that we expect volume growth in Crop Protection, some of that on the back of more normal weather patterns, some of it on the back of credit being eased somewhat, particularly in places like Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>John, I think shared with you during his presentation, we continue to believe that the growth of our new products in Crop Protection, certainly the profitability improvement driven on the back of the portfolio transformation in Seeds, all of this together combines to put us in a position where we feel like the revenues of the company are going to continue to expand now.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we aim to make investments in our business. And the investments in the business include R&amp;D and continuing to take advantage of the resurgence of activity in emerging markets. So all of those together put us in a position where we feel like the earnings for the firm are going to improve. And of course there are some things we can't know with any specificity. The weather in 2009 was &#x2013; as John indicated, was good for farmers, but it was perhaps not as strong for pest pressure itself, so we look forward to 2010 with the lot of confidence, and we'll be sure to update along the way. John, on the Crop Protection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. Well in competitive pressure, I think, first of all, let me say that we're very confident about our ability to differentiate ourselves from the competition, we've coming off five straight years in market share gain. And if I can just pick up on two or three areas, we will be back in some of the credit &#x2013; the markets with the credit that we sort of restricted our activities on, like in East Europe in 2010.</p>
          <p>This is a factor. We have expansion of our crop enhancement business in several markets, I've talked about that. And we have a number of new products launches. We've got 70 for example in Asia Pacific scheduled for 2010. So we're very confident about what we can do. I think in general competitive pressures of course around glyphosate where there's plenty of product and prices went down, we saw that. In general, the market is well supplied, so it's a competitive market as it always was. I think we're just signaling that that competition is very much there.</p>
          <p>Volume growth in Q1, yeah, I mean we had a very strong Q1 last year. It was up significantly and I think &#x2013; coming off it was 8% up actually, and we had 22% in '08. So in a market which was anticipating a very good year in 2009 that didn't quite materialize, I think we've explained that to you. So, by comparison, of course, Q1 is likely to be a little weaker in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But overall volumes in the northern hemisphere, Crop Protection volumes we expect to be up over 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thomas Gilbert, UBS. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my three questions. Good morning. One financial and two Seeds question. So I'll start with a financial question for John. Can you give us the IFRS pension deficit for 2009 and the amount of cash top-ups that you plan for 2010, if possible?</p>
          <p>And then the two Seeds question. On your slide 38, I'm probably missing something very simple. You show your global corn seed sales, seems to be around about $700 million flat over '07, '09, yet 2009 Corn and soy sales are up 21%. Again, what was so good in soy? Was it the sales impact of $100 million of sales brought forward, was that largely soy related or can you just explain there the difference there between Corn and soy?</p>
          <p>And then on to the triple stack. You've given us the penetration rate you expect on your acres for 2010. Can you give us an outlook what kind of U.S. corn acres you expect for 2010 overall, and what kind of share you expect in the market?</p>
          <p>And then finally given that the two elephants are wrestling a bit on price on triple stack. If you look at the price per bag of triple stack corn, what kind of inflation or deflation would you expect 2010 over 2009 for your triple stack corn? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, the first question on IFRS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The deficit is around 92% given year-end assumptions, which as you know are affected by interest rates as well as asset returns. Asset performance has been very good, but 92%. We're not &#x2013; doesn't require any specific one-off cash top-ups, but we are increasing the monthly contributions into the funds, probably around maybe $30 million over the course of the year in a cash contribution, but there's no specific need for any one-offs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Davor, the sales evolution year-on-year in global corn and soy and then what's happening in North American corn seed market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll -- excuse me -- I will start with the corn acres in the U.S. I think you've seen the officials from other people, 87 million that's &#x2013; acres, there or thereabouts. That's what we are planning on. I think there is probably a little bit of upside potential to that. I think we've seen winter wheat acres lower than we would normally expect. So maybe that we see some of that shifting into corn. So it may be a little higher than the 87 that we have currently got in, that the USDA are officially projecting.</p>
          <p>In terms of the share expectations in 2010, that will in part depend upon the final acres that we see. But we feel very good about our Corn position in 2010. We are very confident in terms of the order book and all of that suggests that we will see volume growth in our Corn business in U.S. in 2010. Exactly how that translates into share, it's too early to tell. Again it will partly be influenced by the final acres, but we feel pretty good about that.</p>
          <p>And in terms of pricing, we see the impact of the portfolio transition that we've talked about already today and we've talked about previously. So we would expect average prices and some of that will come through &#x2013; a lot of that will come through in mix rather than in price. We expect that to be in double digits, low double digits, so between 10 and 15% average increase in our price across the portfolio, again a lot of that coming through in mix rather than in price necessarily.</p>
          <p>In terms of your question around the year-on-year evolution, I think, there were a couple of things impacting. This one is increasing prices of soybeans, which are a reflection of the movement in commodity prices back in '08, if you recall. So that meant that soybean prices were higher in '09. So that was a significant uplift there. We also saw reduced corn sales in Eastern Europe, for example, due to the credit management policies that we continue to implement very vigorously.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a call on the line. Andrew Stott from Merrill Lynch. Good morning, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning, Mike. I had a couple of questions. One was a follow-on from Davor's comment just then. The 10 to 15% increase in price, was that specific to the Corn portfolio or to the wider Seeds portfolio?</p>
          <p>And the second question was for John, actually. I'm just trying to tally the guidance on currencies, which is the 50 million, with the hit you had in 2009, which was the 330. In other words, just from my calculations and I've obviously done something wrong, I thought you get a bigger benefit than 50 million, so I just wonder if you can walk through the key moving parts again, John. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Davor, clarification then on the price, the price movement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that price was specific to U.S. Corn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And of course it's an indication of our confidence in the improvement in gross margin and EBITDA for the Seeds business as a whole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Andrew, on the currency, obvious to have your calculation there, but I think also have to bear in mind that the $330 million was offset by emerging market price increases. So then we have a net currency in 2009 of negative 150, 140 million. In 2010, I think it showed in the chart in the presentation, that currencies have not recovered, particularly emerging market currencies, to the level of beginning 2008 levels. And secondly we also have impact of the Swiss franc which has been particularly strong and remains so relatively. So I think those are the main drivers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thanks. Can I just steal one more question, sorry? The raw material benefits of 150, to what extent is that sort of nailed down, because you mentioned the word contract, so just how that could move through the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's largely nailed down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. That's great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rhian Tucker from Credit Suisse. Good morning, Rhian. Welcome back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Thank you. Three questions for me as well. The first one is on your buyback. As far as I understand from the statement you're aiming for about $200 million worth of buyback. Is it possible that number could go up over the year with cash flows particularly strong, or is that now fixed and set in stone for 2010?</p>
          <p>Second question, just looking at crop pricing, I mean John said that the pricing will be pretty weak for the first half of the year. Does not mean you predict Crop Protection pricing to be down for the full year in absolute terms?</p>
          <p>And then the last question is on Viptera, you're obviously planning a 2010 launch both in the U.S. and Brazil. Does that mean you've got U.S. approvals already in place for that or are you expecting those in the next couple of months? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Of course. Davor, can you update us specifically on where Viptera is both in the U.S. and in the LATAM?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm happy to do that. Viptera in the U.S., in the final stages, we have the public comment period that is expected to close in the second week of March. And then it's simply a question of how quickly we can get things through the final stages of the regulatory process there. Still hopeful of being able to get a registration in time for sales, for plantings this year. That's obviously uncertain ,but we are extremely confident of registering sales in Q4 this year for 2011 season. In Brazil we have got the full registration in place and we expect to see first sales in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And John, the possibility that prices for Crop Protection can actually be down in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean it's too early to be clear about -- give any numbers about where pricings going to be. But I will say this, that we are determined to continue to do what we've been doing on pricing, which is to lead the market where we can. Having said that, clearly there will be some glyphosate impact year-on-year comparisons in the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And finally, Rhian, to your question about the share buyback, I mean we very purposefully use the word around in that. In no small part because as you said the strength of the cash flows are all still in front of us, but we expect it to be a very strong cash generative business this year. We've always talked about the share buyback as a means of keeping our target gearing in the corridor of 25 to 35%, and that remains largely unchanged. So around is, is around, but it could be more, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take one here from the room. Please, in the front row. We will come back to Alex Stuart, then next with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Bernd Pomrehn, NZB Neue Z&#xFC;rcher Bank. Could you speak a little bit about your acquisition strategy in Seeds, please? What are the crops? Where you still would like to improve your germplasm portfolio? Which are the regions where you still feel underrepresented? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Davor, the acquisition strategy broadly and then areas we've some particular interest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're certainly looking at opportunities in a number of areas. And in vegetables, it's not always easy to unlock the candidates that we have a particular eye on, so in some sense we have to be reactive in terms of what is available. But if you look at what we've done in the past, vegetables clearly, we see opportunities to acquire germplasm that complements our own and that we can leverage then into other markets.</p>
          <p>We are also very interested in emerging market acquisitions, while that would help us to broaden our footprint, but also in the field crops as well. If there are opportunities in some of our major arable crops, you have seen our acquisition in sunflower recently. That's very much in line with our strategy of growing our field crops business as well. So, we will be very attentive to opportunities. We have been proactive as much as we can be, but it takes a willing partner in acquisitions. But certainly it's something we expect to be able to &#x2013; I have some good news about it during the course of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But by and large the strategy remains unchanged and we have the means and the interest to grow that business. Let's turn to Alex Stuart at Citi and then Rim, I see you came on and then dropped off, we will come back to you afterward. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry, it's actually, me, Andrew Benson [Citi], Alex is a colleague.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. Hi, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of questions. Can you just insofar as you can talk through the AMISTAR strategy, obviously you gave some examples of why previous patent expired, didn't led to a collapse in sales, but there is a lot of interest in competing in AMISTAR and that's not just <mark type="inaudible" />. Can you talk about the &#x2013; I didn't really understand the sugarcane, how that &#x2013; how are you going to benefit from that perhaps, so if you could just explain that? The only output trait, the Enogen, the Amylase, can you give us an indication of the sales you expect from that this year? And then lastly, you talked about credit constraints affecting your turnover. Can you give it a dimension to the amount of sales you think you lost out on and by implication that you may recover this year as a consequence of more normal credit environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll just real quickly address the business of Amylase. Amylase has been already approved by the FDA as well as the EPA. It is now in the final stages with AFS, and we don't know when that's going to come. We still hope it's going to be here in 2010, but from a planning point of view there are no significant sales planned for the Group in 2010 with Enogen, though it offers great deal of potential. John, if could you talk through please, the AMISTAR strategy and then whether or not you think &#x2013; take a fly a bit and whether or not we can quantify the amount of sales lost from the credit constraints this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, first of all, AMISTAR strategy. Just briefly, I mean this is a flagship product for us. It underpins our whole crop enhancement strategy. So that's one of the big pillars of growth. It delivers fantastic returns to farmers even if they use it when there is no disease and that's what I was trying to illustrate to you on our corn applications. So that's one of the pillars. And we can see crop enhancement not just in corn, we can see it in soybeans, we can see it in a variety of crops. So that's a big deal for us. Asia, this has been not been a product which has been widely developed and exploited in Asia and we are seeing terrific opportunities for it there. And then perhaps thirdly, which gets into the whole post patent piece, mixtures. About 80% of the product will be sold in mixtures over the next few years. We are building up to this level. So each of these mixtures has a unique profile and it's in many ways just like having a brand new active ingredient because it conveys differentiated benefit. So, we feel very, very good about that. And we're also the lowest cost producer and we are able to supply it to as we showed with the Makhteshim deal we did potentially to Europe. So, we feel that's in great shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sugarcane?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sugarcane, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sugarcane. I mean another terrific story just very briefly. What's the deal? The deal is that instead of the grower having to plant huge long stocks of sugarcane, as we've shown on the slide. He can plant these very small convenient one bud pieces. Now this is a huge benefit in terms of his cost saving, safety actually because they use to do this with large teams of people in rather unsafe conditions, and it can be done mechanically. It can be done &#x2013; we've developed with the co-operator specific planting equipment and cutting equipment. We got patents on this and these little planting segments are quoted with our seed treatment products. So again that's another piece that we're really excited about and we think it's going to be a big deal</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, John, we don't have a specific account for lost sales but may be you can give us sense for the risk management programs and the impact in the accounts in 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Andrew I think it's difficult to put an exact figure on it because it gets wound-up in weather issues and so on. But to put it this way, the credit constraints that we did have at the beginning of 2009 have largely been relieved in Latin America, particularly in Brazil and Argentina. And we're seeing the benefits of that is the sales in the fourth quarter demonstrating we'll also benefit in quarter one. In Eastern Europe I'd say still some constraint, but significantly relieved from where we were in 2009 and specifically also in Eastern Europe. We are expanding our sales modules and barter scheme and variations thereon, to enable sales to be made which would not otherwise have been able to made with security. So broad answer to your question is, the credit constraints are largely being relieved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And does that take care of it, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I just &#x2013; I can see that they were largely relieved. I was just looking for the dimension of the large relief, that was all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's difficult to get a precise figure on it, Andrew. I think we would have to wait and see how we sell, but significant credit constraint is not going to be an issue affecting our 2010 performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Rim Bennani with BNP Paribas, and then we'll come to a question here in the room. Rim, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Thank you for taking my question. I have three questions. The first one is, just to return on the more challenge &#x2013; more competitive crop protection market. Is it &#x2013; is there any change in term of competitive behavior from the Western European crop protection players so far, or not &#x2013; not anything significant that you're saying, just the impact of glyphosate and the challenging Q1? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question, I do get that the transformation of the Seed portfolio is beyond U.S. Corn. But I just wanted to have your opinion on Monsanto's change of behavior since this summer, and more specifically them now wanting to go for the fringes or the lower profitability areas which were easier areas, I guess, for the challengers to keep market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well thank you for that. Certainly in Crop Protection it's a very different environment than it was during the take-up in 2008 but, John, fundamentally any change in the competitive space.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're used to &#x2013; I mean 2008 was in many ways an exception when there was product shortages. I mean, I think we just simply have to say product is in plentiful supply and clearly in that scenario, I think we'd be foolish not to anticipate it being a competitive market, and I wouldn't like to go further than that. Again, we feel well positioned. We got differentiated products, but it will be competitive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the question on Seed portfolio transformation and Monsanto, Davor, briefly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't really want to get into the discussion of competitor strategies. And we're very clear about our strategy which is to continue to bring new technology, much of it is innovative with Viptera, for example, which will address currently unmet needs. We have a fantastic Seed Care line-up as well which helps us differentiate ourselves from the competition and we've got really excellent germplasm coming through now as well. So we believe that our strategy is the right one for us. Certainly, we're getting good feedback from our customers and we feel very confident about that for 2010 and beyond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got a question here and then we'll come to Neil Tyler of JPMorgan on the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Patrick Rafaisz, Vontobel. Couple of follow-up questions. Maybe first on the Seeds business and pricing you've indicated where pricing will go for corn, now how does it look for the remainder of the portfolio? Maybe related to that. You've shown the evolution of the gross margin for corn globally. Now given the 50% share of the triples of the portfolio this year, where will you see that gross margin? And then follow-up for the share buybacks, when will you actually expect that to start and will you open separate trading line for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. John Ramsay, first if you could address the mechanics around the share buyback and the timing, and then, Davor, perhaps will pick up on the evolution of the gross margin Corn business overall. John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We'll open a second trading line for the repurchase and we haven't decided precisely when we'll start it, but we'll look at the market and make that decision as we progress through the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Davor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think two questions, I think one on pricing outside of Corn. We see opportunities for price increases in line with what we've achieved historically. So in the low-single digits, I would suggest would be a reasonable assumption for the rest of our portfolio. In terms of Corn, obviously the transformation that we see in the U.S. will continue to give us an uplift. So we expect a further improvement in that gross profit, which we showed you in relation to '09. So further advance there which will underpin the EBITDA margin improvements that we're targeting for 2011. So certainly strong momentum from price increases not just in U.S. but also as is being pointed out coming from other crops and other regions of corn as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Neil Tyler joins us from J.P. Morgan. Good morning, Neil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Good morning, Mike. A couple of questions please. Firstly, with regard to the step up in Seeds sales that you've seen even excluding the revenue recognition effort, do you see that as particularly as far as in North America and Brazil which have seen the biggest increase, do you see that is translating into a benefit for the Crop Protection business in terms of the full suite offering that you've been targeting for some time? That's the first question. Second question, just a little bit of quantification on the step up in R&amp;D that you anticipate next year? And thirdly going back to an earlier question, but I wonder if, John, you could specify whether you've seen anything in Crop Protection pricing perhaps in Latin America over the last month or two that, raises your concerns over competitive behavior, that you discussed in the Q3 sales call? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well first of all on the R&amp;D, we target R&amp;D at around 10 to 11%. Can't know whether its 10 or 11, because we don't know what our revenues will be, but we do have a very ambitious program there. It's a bit higher in Seeds, than it is in Crop Protection, but these programs of course last a great long time. And as you saw the pipeline this morning, we're with the progress, and investing in R&amp;D represents the priority number one.</p>
          <p>We'll come back to the CP Seeds questions in a moment, but, John, any change in the &#x2013; just over the last month or two in the competitive behavior in Latin America that gives you concern about it in the northern hemisphere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not specifically. I think it's important to say that the consumption of products in Latin America is going very well and we're having a very good year. I've pointed that out, very strong demand for fungicides. Of course this helps, but there's nothing, I particularly want to draw anybody's attention to except to say of course that it just is a competitive market, and we just need to be aware of that. We differentiate ourselves as much as we can, but it's competitive; that's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And LATAM Seeds evolution, Davor, had the question, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think there's enormous opportunities for Crop Protection to benefit from the increasing growth in Seeds, but also vice versa as well. So this really is an opportunity for more integrated offers to help pull through chemicals as well as Seeds. And certainly we in Seeds are looking to benefit from the higher Crop Protection market share that we have with customers. So that allows us to leverage those relationships with particularly the large farmers in Brazil. On the other hand, Crop Protection can benefit from the early purchasing decisions that farmers engage with on Seeds. So this really is a win-win for both businesses, and we're certainly determined to exploit that to the full in the coming seasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take another question from the room. And then come to Virginie Boucher-Ferte of Deutsche Bank on the phone. Yes, over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Bruno Eschli from Bank Am Bellevue. Actually I have two questions. One would be on inventories. I would have expected inventories to be slightly lower what the 4 billion you published. Could you maybe give us some additional indication as to still length of the product mix to certain products?</p>
          <p>And also with just respect channel inventories, what do you see there and how do you think the inventories of your competitors look? And the second question would be to CapEx. I think CapEx came lower in than originally expected. I think you'd guided for 900 million, 700 million for next year. Is there any change to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. John, maybe you can address first the inventories as it relates to all the working cap deployed with the company and CapEx. And maybe John Atkin, you can &#x2013; to the extent that we have a lot of clarity and visibility, talk a little bit about the channel inventories, John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The inventories are basically a bit higher than you expect, but it's largely because of the lower levels of consumption in quarters two and quarters three. So our normal levels of operating inventories are lower than this. And the planning is now underway and we're targeting overall for our working capital to bring it down by about two percentage points of sales during the course of 2010.</p>
          <p>On the CapEx, yeah, the CapEx did come in lower, which is good news. I think the outlook for CapEx -- there's a bit of delay in there and there's also a bit of saving, combination of both. The outlook for CapEx for 2010 is about $650 million including about 100 million for intangibles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, what do we know about competitive activity in the channel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, I think first of all in Q4 half of our sales came from Latin America. And in Latin America, particularly in Brazil, we invoice to consumption. So we don't register a sale until the product has left the distributors to the farm. So as far as our products are concerned, there is not a channel inventory issue in Brazil at all.</p>
          <p>As far as, generally speaking, in most emerging markets channel inventory isn't an issue. They take it when they need it. So we can discount them. I would say in the United States after a weak season for disease control as we told you they're a little higher. We feel we're in reasonable shape, but overall they're little higher. And &#x2013; but in the rest of the world there's normalish, I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Virginie Boucher-Ferte at Deutsche Bank. Bonjour; good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning and thanks. So I've got three questions. The first one is NAFTA has been I think the weakest region in Crop Protection this year. I understand the adverse weather and the lack of disease pressure. But I also wanted to know to which extent this weakness was also caused by the increase in GM penetration, and which company is aggressively ramping up their multi stack corn seed products? Should we expect further impact in 2010 onwards? That was the first question.</p>
          <p>My second question was on R&amp;D, to make sure I understood. In 2009, you achieved 8.7 R&amp;D to sales and the 10 to 11% you were guiding to, is it for 2010 or when &#x2013; what's the timeframe from getting to this level?</p>
          <p>And finally, present pricing. I just wanted to have an update on how your negotiations with the distributors in Europe and perhaps in North America have been going so far? And also with the environmental context becoming very regulated in Crop Protection, should we expect that to have an impact on pricing in the medium term? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. Okay. Three parts, first on the R&amp;D, Virginie. We target 10 to 11% over the long &#x2013; over the long-term, could be up in some years and down in others. Of course many parts of our R&amp;D spend are joined between Crop Protection and Seeds and seed treatment. But broadly speaking, we're investing in biology and we're investing in chemistry and how those things are deployed around the world.</p>
          <p>John, are we going to &#x2013; so the other two parts, the environmental and regulatory environment ,how is that? And secondly, are we still feeling the effects of GM penetration on our Crop Protection business in NAFTA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really interesting question. Of course, over the 10 years &#x2013; almost 10 years of the company's life we've talked about this a lot. And what's particularly interesting is that, GM penetration is turning into an opportunity for our chemical business rather than a disadvantage. And the reason is perhaps, two things I can point to. First of all, glyphosate resistant weeds, I mean this is really an important factor, particularly in the southern half of the United States. We've got six alternative products, six ways that the farmer can deal with this problem and so we see that as an advantage. And secondly, seed treatment, high value seed means it should be protected and this is an advantage for us.</p>
          <p>So the short answer is, no, we don't see that impact from GM technology.</p>
          <p>Environmental impact on price, no; I would say that's not a factor. In fact the environment and we are doing everything we can of course as always to adapt our products to increasing environmental regulation, but it's not a price concern issue. And pricing to the distribution, its going fine, we're in the normal phase here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question here in the room. There was one at this table in the back corner. Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>J&#xFC;rgen Reck from Sal. Oppenheim. One question regarding the Seeds business. Can you benefit currently from the extremely high &#x2013; record high sugar prices in your sugar beet business? I know in the European Union the acreage for sugar beet production is somewhat limited, but maybe there are some opportunities outside the EU, what is your view on this business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Davor...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, absolutely, first of all it's interesting to see in Europe that Europe is now talking about exporting some of its surplus sugar beet, so certainly that would be helpful to acreage maybe not in the current season but in subsequent seasons we may see an underpinning to that. And of course we've got a very important business in North America as well and we would expect these favorable prices to factor into to higher acreage into the future. So it's certainly a positive influence on that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p> I'm being summoned that this concludes our conference and so ladies and gentlemen thank you very much for your questions and thank you for coming to here to Zurich to join us for our 2009 results. If you have any follow-up questions, of course you can contact our Investor Relations department in Basel.</p>
          <p>So, thank you. Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>