<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1120284" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-01-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>451</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Richard C. Dietz, Senior Vice President &#x2013; Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Richard G. Lindner, Senior Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Rich Dietz, Senior Vice President &#x2013; Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="4">Simon Flannery</participant>
      <participant id="5">Richard Lindner</participant>
      <participant id="6">David Barden</participant>
      <participant id="7">John Hodulik</participant>
      <participant id="8">David Janazzo</participant>
      <participant id="9">Richard Linder</participant>
      <participant id="10">Christopher Larsen</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jason Armstrong</participant>
      <participant id="12">Richard Dietz</participant>
      <participant id="13">Michael McCormack</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">Richard C. Dietz, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the AT&amp;T Fourth Quarter Earnings Release 2007 Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question and answer session. Please note that this conference is being recorded. I will now turn the call over to Mr. Rich Dietz, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations. Mr. Dietz, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you Christine and good morning to everyone. Welcome to our fourth quarter 2007 conference call. It's great to have you with us this morning. Joining me on the call this morning is Rick Lindner, AT&amp;T's Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>As you've seen, this was another strong quarter for AT&amp;T and the purpose of this call is to provide additional background on the results that we published earlier this morning. Our release, investor briefing, the supplementary information, and presentation slides are all available on the Investor Relations page of the AT&amp;T website at att.com/investor.relations.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, I need to cover our safe harbor statement. Information set forth in this presentation contains financial estimates and other forward-looking statements that are subject to risks and uncertainties and actual results may differ materially. A discussion of factors that may affect future results is contained in AT&amp;T's filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>AT&amp;T disclaims any obligation to update or revise statements contained in these presentations based on new information or otherwise. This presentation may contain certain non-GAAP financial measures, reconciliations between the non-GAAP financial measures and the GAAP financial measures are available on our website, att.com/investor.relations.</p>
          <p>Okay with that covered, let me quickly cover our fourth quarter EPS comparisons which are on slide four of the presentation materials. This quarter marks AT&amp;T's 11th consecutive quarter and our third straight year of double-digit growth in adjusted EPS. Reported EPS this quarter was 51 cents. We had 19 cents of merger integration costs and non-cash amortization of intangibles. The result is 71 cents, a 16.4% increase from year-ago results. With that background, I'll now turn the call over to AT&amp;T's Senior Executive Vice President and CFO, Rick Lindner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rich and good morning to everybody on the call. I'd like to begin with a few brief highlights which are covered on slide 6. Our results this quarter are a continuation of the good trends we've had in our business for some time. They're in line with what we outlined for you at our New York Analyst Day. And they reinforce the confidence we have in our 2008 outlook.</p>
          <p>First, we had an outstanding wireless quarter. Gross adds were a record 6 million. We had 2.7 million net adds, the best ever by any U.S. provider. ARPU is up and churn is down. Data revenue growth continues to be robust and total wireless revenues grew better than 16%. All in all, just a terrific wireless quarter.</p>
          <p>We also took a significant step up in enterprise service revenue growth. Our sales funnel is strong and we have solid enterprise momentum heading into 2008. Our regional revenue trends are stable, and with these dynamics, we're on track to deliver mid-single digit growth in consolidated revenues in 2008.</p>
          <p>We continue to deliver on merger synergies. Our margins are solid. Free cash flow is very strong, and we're returning substantial value to shareowners, more than 19 billion in dividends in share re-purchases in 2007. With a double-digit dividend increase heading into 2008 and the expectation for continued substantial share buybacks. With that as a backdrop, I'd like to cover now the quarter in a little bit more detail.</p>
          <p>Slide 7 shows our earnings per share growth and margin expansion. As Rich mentioned, before merger-related affects our fourth quarter EPS was 71 cents. Our 11th straight quarter of double-digit growth and adjusted EPS.</p>
          <p>Our fourth quarter adjusted operating income margin was 24%, up nearly 600 basis points year-over-year. And for the full year, our adjusted operating margin was 23.8%, well above our original outlook of 21 to 23%, and at the top end of our more recent guidance of 23 to 24%.</p>
          <p>Given our expectations for revenue growth and cost initiatives, we expect our full-year adjusted operating income margin will expand further in 2008 to the 25 to 26% range, and we expect to deliver continued double-digit growth and adjusted earnings per share. In part, our expectations for margin expansion are based on continued merger synergies and new expense savings opportunities which continue to be substantial.</p>
          <p>Slide 8 has a synergy update, similar to what we've provided to you throughout 2007. We continue to run ahead of schedule on AT&amp;T Corp. and BellSouth merger synergies. In 2006, we achieved 1.1 billion of savings from our AT&amp;T integration. That's a combination of both expense and capital. In 2007, we moved that run rate up to 4 billion, with 75% expense and the remainder in capital savings. This reflects good progress on network and traffic consolidations, labor savings and re-branding. Our BellSouth and Cingular brand migration work is largely complete at this point. That includes vehicles, retail locations and advertising.</p>
          <p>Most important, we have a great deal of headroom in terms of cost reduction. There's more upside ahead on synergies as shown on this chart. And as we outlined for you at our Analyst Conference, we're also underway with operational initiatives that we expect to generate significant additional expense savings above these synergies. When you put the two of them together, our total operating expense savings run rate will increase by approximately 2 billion in 2008. We have good plans on the cost side. They are built into our operating targets; and in addition, given our size, our expectation is to achieve continuous productivity improvements going forward. We also have substantial opportunity for top line growth; and as I said, we're on a good trajectory to deliver mid-single-digit revenue growth in 2008.</p>
          <p>Slide 9 provides a look at our trends. This chart shows total revenue versus pro-forma results for 2006. The slight decline in the rate of revenue growth this quarter versus last quarter reflects the impact of enterprise CPE, or equipment sales, which had an affect on our revenue comparison for this quarter.</p>
          <p>Starting in 2007, we de-emphasized stand-alone equipment sales in enterprise, shifting our strategy to focus on CPE as part of total solutions that pull through service revenues. As a result of this change, fourth quarter 2006 had 180 million more in CPE revenues than our current run rate. Going forward, we expect year-over-year comparisons for equipment sales to be much more stable.</p>
          <p>Adjusting for enterprise CPE, our fourth quarter year-over-year revenue growth was 3.5%, and the drivers are continued solid mid-teens wireless growth, further improvements in enterprise, and stable regional revenues.</p>
          <p>In addition going forward, we expect wholesale trends to stabilize as we move through 2008, and there are a number of factors driving this. Traffic migrations from industry consolidation are nearing completion. The year-over-year impact of merger conditions will be behind us by mid-year, and we expect new revenues from our IBM alliance will begin to provide a lift to wholesale results.</p>
          <p>Also, national mass markets will become a smaller part of our overall revenue picture. This is the legacy AT&amp;T standalone long distance business. It is already less than 3% of total revenues. So the drag we've experienced from that area of our business will be reduced as we move forward. Given these factors, we remain confident in our mid-single-digit revenue outlook.</p>
          <p>Our number one driver of revenue growth continues to be wireless, which we show on slide 10. As I said, we had a great wireless quarter. Total wireless revenues were up 16.3%, and wireless service revenues were up 15.7%. The first driver is terrific subscriber growth. In the fourth quarter, excluding the Dobson acquisition, we set industry records for both gross adds and net adds, and for the full year 2007, we added more than 7 million subscribers &#x2013; and that's before acquisitions.</p>
          <p>The second driver is ARPU growth, total ARPU was up nearly 2% in the fourth quarter. It was our sixth consecutive quarter of year-over-year ARPU growth. And postpaid ARPU was even stronger, up more than 5%. Our network coverage is excellent and is getting better every day. Our sales presence is strong. We're setting the pace with cutting-edge handsets, and these are all contributing to strong wireless momentum.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 slows the details on wireless subscriber growth. Fourth quarter versus a year ago, gross adds were up by more than half a million, nearly 10%. Net adds were up 13.5% to 2.7 million. And virtually all of the year-over-year increase in net adds came from postpaid where net adds were up 37%. And postpaid churn dropped by 30 basis points. At the end of the year, we had 70.1 million wireless subscribers, and we provided a table to show the math, adding in the subscribers from our Dobson acquisition. That acquisition closed in November and did not have a meaningful effect on our net add total for the quarter.</p>
          <p>The other big driver behind our wireless performance is explosive growth in data. The highlights are on slide 12. Year-over-year, wireless data revenue growth was up 57.5%, taking us to more than $2 billion for the quarter. This growth reflects strong increases in both consumer and business data usage. Internet access revenues were up more than 40%; messaging up more than 50%; e-mail growth exceeded 60%; and revenues from data access and media bundles were both up more than 70%.</p>
          <p>Data now represents close to 20% of our total wireless service revenues and $12 of our postpaid ARPU. And yet, there remains huge upside to data growth. Only 37% of our postpaid subscribers are on a monthly wireless data plan. Adoption of smart phones and integrated devices is on the rise, but the fact is, we're still very early in the adoption curve. At this point, about 12% of AT&amp;T's subscribers have these devices, and ARPUs for those customers are more than double the average.</p>
          <p>Data growth is also driven by an increasing number of subscribers using AT&amp;T's 3G network, which now includes more than 260 U.S. metropolitan areas. At the end of the year, we had more than 9 million customers using 3G devices; almost all of them added during the past year.</p>
          <p>We continue to be a leader in bringing to market a rich selection of both devices and services, and a few of our latest and most exciting are pictured on slide 13. We've expanded our lead in PDAs with devices such as the Pantech Duo, a 3G global smart device available exclusively in the U.S. from AT&amp;T; the BlackJack II, which brings the personal computer experience to a compact wireless device; and additionally, AT&amp;T is the world's largest provider of BlackBerry service. We've made a point of leading in feature-rich handsets with AT&amp;T exclusives such as the Apple iPhone, which continues to generate very strong sales. 40% of customers who buy the iPhone are new to AT&amp;T. And iPhone subscribers have very attractive ARPU characteristics, significantly higher than our postpaid average. And the iPhone experience continues to get richer.</p>
          <p>As you may have seen, Apple has announced a number of enhancements to the iPhone, including the ability to create up to nine customizable home screens, location-enabled maps, multiple address messaging, and iTunes movie rentals. And one of the web-based applications users can place on their iPhone home screen now is YELLOWPAGES.COM, our own electronic search service.</p>
          <p>Also in the fourth quarter we launched the Samsung SLM. That's Samsung's newest lightweight mobile phone with music and multimedia capabilities. The SLM features Napster Mobile, a new service that lets customers purchase and download from a catalog of 5 million songs. AT&amp;T is the only national provider to enable customers to purchase full track songs over the air from both Napster and eMusic, the world's largest retailer of independent music.</p>
          <p>We're also working with Wachovia and SunTrust, and together we've launched a mobile banking service that will enable consumers to view account balances and history, transfer funds and pay bills from their AT&amp;T mobile handsets. Our scale, combined with our GSM platform, makes us an attractive partner both for device makers and service partners of all sorts. That's evident in the lineup we offer as we make the wireless experience richer to drive subscriber loyalty usage and revenues.</p>
          <p>In terms of financial performance, one of the big opportunities we have in wireless is further margin expansion. The highlights are on slide 14. As you know, wireless margins in the fourth quarter typically show a sequential decline due to higher gross adds. With our record gross adds this fourth quarter, that is again the case. But that being said, our wireless margin trends are quite positive and continue the strong trends we've established over the past three years versus the year earlier fourth quarter. Our adjusted wireless operating margin was 25.7%, up 680 basis points, and our adjusted service EBITDA margin was 38.2%, up 380 basis points.</p>
          <p>There are a lot of drivers which we've covered with you in the past. We continue to improve our network cost structure. The IT systems migration and shutdowns that we outlined as part of our merger integration are now complete, and the shutdown of our TDMA network will take place at the end of February. We've moved 390,000 subscribers off that network in the fourth quarter, and about 390,000 remain, roughly two-thirds of them being wholesale customers.</p>
          <p>We have significant potential for wireless margin expansion going forward. In 2008, we expect a full-year adjusted EBITDA margin in the low 40% range, trending toward the mid-40s by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to another key area where we saw a substantial improvement. And that's in enterprise. The details are on slide 15. The chart here is the one we've provided for the past several quarters. It shows year-over-year growth rates for enterprise revenues, excluding CPE sales and M&amp;A impacts. We've had a very strong two-year climb. Last quarter, we moved into positive territory at 0.3% and this quarter we stepped that up to 1.8%, and the momentum is good. Demand continues to be solid. Data transport volumes are strong. IP services, which include virtual private networks, managed Internet service and hosting grew 21% year over year. And we're winning contracts. When you look at sales results for the second half of 2007 versus the first half of 2007, our net new orders for products such as VPN, DS1 and DS3 grew by double-digit rates. And for 2008, our new sales projections continue to look good.</p>
          <p>When you take into consideration that new sales can take three to six months to close and that we've seen no evidence of enterprise customers paring back on capital and project-related spending versus 2007, we feel confident in our ability to continue growing enterprise revenues throughout 2008. As we outlined in our analyst event last month, the dynamics behind our global business are positive, and that includes both enterprise as well as wholesale.</p>
          <p>Slide 16 outlines the key trends. First, we have a premier global network serving nearly 120,000 customers in 164 countries. We have 38 data hosting centers around the world and we're making smart, aggressive moves to advance that network overseas and here in the U.S., where we're underway with the nation's most extensive OC-768 deployment.</p>
          <p>Second, we're seeing good fundamental demand in volume trends, driven by wireless and application services. With strong demand and applications management we're seeing the shift to IP deliver faster revenue recovery times than we had anticipated.</p>
          <p>And third, when you look ahead at our wholesale and enterprise business, there are additional incremental drivers that we expect to help growth rates going forward. In October, we formed an alliance with IBM that calls for AT&amp;T to become their primary global network management services provider. As a result, we expect to receive up to 5 billion of additional revenues over the five-year term of the agreement, largely in the wholesale customer category at the outset, and in enterprise as we build the business. These revenues are expected to begin ramping in mid 2008.</p>
          <p>This week, we announced a three-year marketing agreement with SAP America. We will serve as SAP's primary independent hosting services provider for business customers headquartered in North America. As we add to our business through alliances such as these, we're also seeing reduced impacts to wholesale from the traffic migration that has occurred due to industry consolidation. That process is nearing an end. And the year-over-year impact of merger conditions on wholesale results will be behind us by mid-year. When you take these factors together, it leads to our outlook not only for enterprise growth in 2008, but for our return to wholesale growth as well.</p>
          <p>We also had solid results in regional business. Slide 17 provides a quick update. Our regional business revenues grew by 2.8% in the fourth quarter. Revenues from small and midsized firms continue to be solid. They were up 5% consistent with recent results. Regional business data revenues grew 4.2%, led by mid-single digit growth in data transport and double-digit growth in IP data revenues, including areas such as VPN, broadband and managed internet services. Regional business voice revenues also continue to grow in the low single digits, both local and long distance. And at this point, nearly 50% of our small business customers at risk to cable competition have bundled services and has signed new term contracts with us and our activity in this area is reflected in the growth rates. Our product sets with strength in data services and key growth areas, such as VoIP, IP data and application services, gives us an excellent opportunity in regional business. We expect that it will be an ongoing area of strength for us with mid single digit growth.</p>
          <p>Slide 18 shows regional consumer trends where we continue to deliver stable revenues consistent with results over the past several quarters. Broadband penetration of consumer primary lines now approaches 39%. In our West region, California and Nevada, broadband penetration is above 45%. Consumer video penetration moved up to 7.6%. That's satellite and U-verse TV. With games and broadband, and video more than offsetting declines in traditional voice lines, over the past year we had a net gain in regional consumer connections of 568,000. And our consumer ARPU, based on primary lines, was up 4.9%.</p>
          <p>I mentioned that our December 11 analyst event in New York that we had seen some evidence of economic softness on consumer, primarily in access lines and broadband net adds. We have this level of economic softness baked into our business plans and as a result, there is no change to our outlook at this time, which is for continued growth in regional consumer driven by broadband and ramping video revenue.</p>
          <p>Slide 19 shows our broadband results, where we continue to deliver solid double-digit growth in both revenues and subscribers. We had a net gain in the fourth quarter of just under 400,000 and over the past year we've had a net gain of two million broadband connections. That includes a significant ramp over the past quarter in broadband sales without a traditional wired voice line, either standalone or more often in our wireless broadband bundle which we launched in August of 2007.</p>
          <p>And we continue to deliver solid double-digit growth in broadband revenues up nearly 14% in the fourth quarter. We believe there continues to be substantial opportunity ahead in broadband as we add more features and options in the first quarter, including free Wi-Fi access to subscribers who take speeds at 1.5 megabits or above. As you know, we have the largest Wi-Fi coverage of any U.S. provider. Plus in the first quarter we're adding a new 10 megabit broadband service on our U-verse platform.</p>
          <p>The other driver in our consumer business is video, and we continue to see a solid ramp in U-verse as we show on slide 20. Since our last quarterly update, we've added new markets; we're now in 41. We've expanded coverage in existing markets and our install rates have climbed. In mid-December, our last good pre-holiday week, we had approximately 12,000 installs, above the 10,000 per week target we've set for the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Our technicians are gaining experience and expertise. We're seeing further reductions in installation times. Churn continues to improve and customer response is very positive. We have expanded our deployment plan to include the Southeast region with the target of reaching up to 30 million homes by 2010. We've just launched our U-verse Voice over IP service in Detroit and will continue to roll that out to additional markets in 2008.</p>
          <p>We expect a continued strong ramp, and as we said at our analyst conference, we expect our install base to exceed one million by the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>I'd like to close with a few comments on cash flow on slide 21. For the full year cash from operations totaled 34.1 billion, free cash flow totaled 16.4 billion, and we returned substantial cash to shareowners, 19.1 billion when you combine more than 10 billion in share repurchases with our dividends paid. As a result, our free cash flow yield has grown and exceeds that of our peers. And as we laid out for you before, we have a strong balance sheet. We intend to keep our credit metrics stable with a debt-to-EBITDA multiple in the 1.3 to 1.5 range. And our strong and growing free cash flow gives us the flexibility to both invest in the future of our business and return substantial value to shareowners.</p>
          <p>As you know, we've grown our dividend every year in our history, including a 12.7% increase announced in December. And we expect to continue share repurchases. We announced a new repurchase authorization for 400 million shares, which is about 6.6% of our year-end shares outstanding, and we expect to exhaust that by the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>So with that, let me close with a quick recap. I think we had a very solid fourth quarter. We're seeing accelerating momentum across some key growth areas in our business in wireless, in enterprise, and in video. What we're seeing in the economy is consistent with our 2008 operational plan. And we're confident in our ability to execute on that plan as we've discussed in our December analyst meeting. We expect to ramp revenue growth in 2008 to the mid-single digit range. We expect to expand our consolidated adjusted margins into the 25 to 26% range, and we will continue to be a strong free cash flow company, which allows us to invest in the business and return cash to shareowners. We have a deep management team, one that's financially disciplined, and with a strong record of delivering on targets. That's AT&amp;T today. With that, Rich, I think we're ready to open up the lines for some questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you Rick. Christine, if you would, we're ready to begin the question and answer session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The first question comes from Simon Flannery from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Good morning. I wanted to ask about U-verse, if I could. Can you give us some sense of the dilution in the quarter? Any early learnings about things like churn and also the updated timing on getting a second HD stream? And then on the iPhone, if you could give us some iPhone numbers where we stand at the end of the year and any commentary on the business pricing that was rolled out this week. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Simon. Good morning. Let me try to address your questions there. First of all, we feel very good about U-verse results in the fourth quarter. They were right where we had targeted them for the quarter. Churn rates, you know, any new product, churn rates are a little bit misleading because you don't have much of a base there, but our churn rates in U-verse are very good. They're comparable right now to what we're seeing in access line and broadband kinds of churn, and I actually believe they will decline from there. I would expect they would decline, you know, to sub 2% levels as we start to build the base further, but churn and customer response to the product continues to be good. Dilution for the year was, in U-verse, was right at 11 cents. That's right where we had projected it for the year and going forward, there's no change to our outlook or guidance in that standpoint. I think as we go into 2008, we ramp and launch additional markets, increase our gross ad activity. I would expect incremental dilution next year in the 12 to 14 cent range, but the product is moving along very well. We do have, as you noted, we've got some product enhancements slated for 2008, that I think will be key, including whole-home DVR capabilities, second HD stream, and we would expect to begin rolling those out in the market around mid-year. And then a third enhancement that will be frankly important to us going forward because it will enable even additional HD streams, will be &#x2013; where they're required &#x2013; will be pair-bonding, which we expect, late in 2008. So solid results continue I think on U-verse.</p>
          <p>With respect to the iPhone, results continue to be very good. We had very solid sales results in both October and November, and in December, as you would expect from kind of the normal monthly run rate, we had almost double the sales in December. I think clearly as we go forward, Apple will continue to enhance the product. We see some software enhancements being announced and planned for 2008, so I think it will continue to be a very strong product for us. ARPUs on the iPhone are very good, as you would expect. The people that acquire that phone, first of all, tend to have strong voice ARPUs but then in addition are putting data packages on top of it and so, similar to what we see in our entire smart-phone and integrated device lineup, we're seeing ARPUs that are nearly double what average ARPUs are in the rest of the base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just help us reconcile the 4 million number that Apple gave to what you might be seeing in terms of both how much of that is overseas and how much of that is being bought for unlocking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's difficult to reconcile those numbers, Simon, and it will become increasingly more difficult going forward as Apple expands into more overseas markets. But essentially we have finished the year, we were just at or just slightly under 2 million iPhone customers in the base, and if you start to try to reconcile those numbers, the big reconciling items will be first of all, there are devices that we have purchased that are in inventory. There are devices that have been sold and shipped; some of them on line, but were not activated at that point, so that creates a reconciling item. And then third, there's certainly some devices that are being purchased through channels in the U.S. or purchased through online channels that are actually going to international markets. So that creates another reconciling item there.</p>
          <p>But when you look at a device that's been in the market for six months basically, half a year, and it's 2 million devices out of a &#x2013; and you have to back it up to largely our post-paid base, that's pretty significant growth in a short period of time, and we continue to see it as a very strong product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from David Barden from Banc of America Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Thanks. Maybe two related questions, I guess, just talking about the economy obviously. I think the stock is down about 13% from Randall's comments at the beginning of the month talking about the softness that could creep into the consumer business. Although it wasn't apparent to me that we actually saw it, come in full force in the fourth quarter. I guess that the concern here though is that the expectations that have been laid out for 2008 encompass some positive economic scenario which if the data starts to deteriorate, AT&amp;T just won't be able to live up to and that seems to be the bet that the market is making. So Rick I was wondering if you could kind of just discuss the tolerances around the economic scenarios that you've baked into the '08 expectations. How much more unemployment? What kind of GDP growth expectations are the minimum necessary to expect that enterprise can continue to grow, that consumer revenues can continue to grow, et cetera?</p>
          <p>And then I guess the second part of that would be that whole discussion has extended to the wireless arena where data revenue growth has been the biggest driver of it. There's an argument that maybe that's a discretionary component of the business and therefore it couldn't possibly be as strong in a softer economic climate. Counterbalancing that is the fact that you only have 12% of your devices are smart phones and there's a large component of well-to-do people who could be using it but aren't. So I guess if you could kind of talk about those issues as we look into '08, that would be very helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Be happy to do that, David. Well, as you all know, there's been an awful lot of noise in the market, in the media, about the economy. And what I would first say is if you go back to the comments that we've made, first of all, going back to our analysts conference in December, I made comments in my presentation in December that we were seeing a little bit of softness in some of our consumer metrics. And in response to some questions at the conference, we talked about some increases in non-pay disconnects and things that frankly you would expect, I think, somewhat given trends in the overall economy.</p>
          <p>In January, our Chairman, Randall Stephenson, made very, very similar comments. What caused those comments suddenly in January to be a more of a media event than the similar comments we made in December, I can't say, but putting that aside, let's talk about and look at the results we had for fourth quarter. Where we saw some softness, as we mentioned, is in access lines where the rate of switched line loss increased somewhat in the fourth quarter, and we saw some slowing in broadband net adds. In both of those cases, both of those products are impacted by some of the things we see in the housing markets, some slowdown in home sales, slowdown in new construction. They're impacted by, as well, some small uptick in non-pay disconnects, and to put it in context, it's for both products in the neighborhood of about 10 basis points of additional churn &#x2013; non-pay related &#x2013; that we saw in the fourth quarter of this year versus fourth quarter of the prior year. Those were the trends that we were seeing in December, we baked those into our operational plans, and they're reflected in the guidance that we've given.</p>
          <p>As you look across the rest of the business, we're clearly not seeing any impacts in our wireless business at this point. Wireless continues to be very strong, both in customer growth and in ARPU growth, and to some degree it reflects, I think, changes in terms of the way people are communicating today versus maybe 10 or 15 years ago or if you go back to any last consumer economic softness we've had, and that is simply that wireless in terms of access and connectivity is very important to people today. We're not seeing any impacts as we said at the analyst conference and I think as you see in our results in sales to business customers and particularly in sales to enterprise business. And if you think about the products we're selling there and the focus in that business and the movement of customers in traffic to IP, that's something even in a difficult economy when companies are looking to reduce costs, that's actually a service that facilitates and helps them provide more bandwidth and more productivity within their business at lesser cost. And so it's not surprising actually as you look at the results and look at the fourth quarter results, the strength we've had in IP-based revenues there.</p>
          <p>So when you put all of that together, David, I think we still, we feel good about our guidance and our plan for 2008. The economy is always a risk, but I think when you look across our business we're relatively, I think, defensive in nature in these kinds of downturns, and wireless particularly for the reasons that you mentioned and some of the things I mentioned in the presentation, the fact that the ARPU growth is being driven by data and that data growth is being driven by new devices, new smart phones, new integrated devices, and it's being driven by the move to 3G, and together those things are opening up a whole new host of applications that I think will bring value and be very interesting to our customers. I think that makes us feel very good about the outlook for wireless as we go into 2008. So, you know, the economy is something and the impact on our business is something we monitor, we'll watch every quarter as we look at our results across each of the business units, but at this point what I've described to you is what we have seen and it's just some limited impact in our access line and broadband results. And I would tell you even in broadband, while we certainly would say that fourth quarter broadband net adds were a little lower than we had seen in prior quarters, when you annualize the broadband net adds we had in fourth quarter, they're still growing at better than a double-digit pace, so we're still seeing pretty nice growth there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Rick, just to follow up real quick, just, you know, the difference between December and January was, I think, that the market became much more convinced that there was less of a debate about the economy actually softening. So can you just kind of reiterate that with respect to all the incremental data that's come out to this point, your conviction level is still there that you've kind of baked in the appropriate baseline economic environment within a range of reasonable assumptions into the numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think if I understand your question, David, you're asking, with any incremental data we've seen in January, are we seeing trends that support our outlook, and the answer to that is yes. You know, keeping in mind that we're only talking about a few weeks of activity, but generally, what we have seen so far this year relative to fourth quarter is we've actually seen, I think, in these first few weeks, we've seen broadband improve somewhat over the run rates we had in fourth quarter and we've seen access lines certainly be in terms of our run rate be at or maybe a little better than we saw in fourth quarter, but certainly no worse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Hodulik from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions; first in terms of consolidated revenue growth. It looks like CPE had a larger-than-expected headwind or impact on the numbers this quarter. Is that 3.5% growth rate without CPE sort of a good starting point as we look out into '08? I realize the guidance is 4% to 6%, and you went over what are the sort of drivers to get us to accelerate. But, are there any other issues that could sort of surprise us from a negative standpoint beside the economy? We've seen the growth in wireless. I think it seems like you have good visibility on enterprise. I'm just wondering if there is anything else that we're not &#x2013; you know, just sort of some idea of how you expect the growth to trend over the next few quarters. And then, on wireless, looks like the margins were a little lighter than we thought. Could you talk a little bit about the strategy in the fourth quarter and how that plays out in the first quarter in terms of promotions and subsidies and maybe the rate of upgrades you saw in the quarter and do we still expect a nice bump in the first quarter with the turn-down of the TDMA network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, John. Starting &#x2013; going back to your first question on revenue growth, first of all, you're right, CPE was &#x2013; our excluding CPE revenue growth was 3.5%. It's had an impact on us in just about every quarter in 2007, but fourth quarter was bigger in terms of impact; and the reason for that is really kind of simple. As we went through 2006 and we started looking at products and services and what products we were selling, throughout 2006 particularly &#x2013; let me just talk about the enterprise business and enterprise sales &#x2013; we were selling equipment that we kind of divided into two buckets. There are some equipment sales that we make that facilitate and pull through network services, and they're sold as part of a package service and that's something that we feel good about and we like the economics on and it's business that makes sense to us. In 2006, we also saw that we had some CPE sales, and it was as much as 20, 30% of our CPE sales that when we looked at them, they were standalone sales, didn't pull through network services, and they really didn't have any margin to them. And we decided at the end of 2006, that's not where we wanted our resources and our focus and our sales force to be focused on.</p>
          <p>So, we did a couple of things. We made some changes to pricing in terms of how we were going to sell CPE, and probably more importantly, we made changes to our commission plans. The fourth quarter &#x2013; and both of those changes, by the way, had the desired impact, and so what we've seen in 2007 generally are lower levels of CPE sales, but the CPE we're selling is part of packaged deals and it's carrying with it reasonable margins. And so, we've gotten the desired result from it. But then you compound all of that with the fact that fourth quarter is typically a higher quarter for equipment sales, and that's why you saw the impact in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>When you look at &#x2013; when I step back from it and say, "Okay, how do we get comfortable with the run rates we're on and the move to mid-single digit revenue growth?" First of all, the impact from CPE, I think, as we go into 2008 versus 2007, will be much more on our current run rate. We won't have the delta that we had between 2007 and 2006. Secondly, one of the factors that's I think significant to us is we do see that wholesale, which has, throughout 2007, had a year-over-year decline in the 7 to 8%  range, we feel, will stabilize in 2008 and begin to grow for the factors I mentioned in the presentation, that we're nearing the end of consolidation of traffic which has impacted wholesale; that by mid-year 2008, we'll be at the one-year point for some of the price reductions that we put in place as part of our merger conditions. And so that will cease to be a drag. And then finally, the IBM agreement, as it begins to phase in in 2008, will provide a lift to wholesale revenues.</p>
          <p>And then the third factor from a revenue growth standpoint is just the math and the mechanics of the national mass market business which, at the end of the year, was really down to around 2.5 or 6% of our total revenues. The drag from that national mass market decline will be less going forward in 2008 than 2007.</p>
          <p>So, as I look at other issues in revenues, obviously the other thing that mid-single digit revenue growth hinges on is just maintaining the trends we've seen in the business, and we're actually seeing some acceleration of trends in wireless, which is good to see; we're seeing some acceleration of trends in enterprise; and we're seeing, despite the economic impacts, continued stable trends in regional. So, as we move forward, I think because of those factors, it all gives us comfort in continuing to ramp up revenues.</p>
          <p>Finally, when you look at wireless margins &#x2013; as I said, it's not unusual to have wireless margins pull back a little bit in the fourth quarter. When we look at fourth-quarter  results, it's almost entirely due to increases in acquisition costs, selling costs, equipment costs as well as upgrade costs. Fourth quarter is also a high upgrade quarter. So we had about 8.5% of the base upgrade in the fourth quarter, which drives it as well. I think going forward in wireless, it was a typical fourth quarter, I think, in terms of pretty aggressive promotions around devices and handsets, but as we see the results from particularly the higher-end devices we're selling, the results in terms of ARPU is very strong. So it gives me a lot of comfort in terms of what we're doing with those devices.</p>
          <p>I think a key will be how the market continues in the first quarter, typically January. The first part of January, you continue with some pricing and some promotions you had over the holidays and then the question will be, how does the market develop after that? But we will get lift from the TDMA shutdown. I wouldn't look for that necessarily in the first quarter. I think we'll see that begin to ramp more in the balance of the year, and we'll shut that network down in the first quarter, but then we still have to remove equipment from cell sites, and we have to get relief from the rents we're paying on the equipment on those sites. We'll have to adjust our transport, our infrastructure, between the switches and sell cites to reflect removal of that equipment. And so, there's a lot of work to be done to get the remaining TDMA costs out of the network. So you'll see that, but you'll see it as we go forward in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Very helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from David Janazzo from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Rick, you've spelled out the cost-cutting synergy opportunities, other operational initiatives and obviously U-verse is going to be a little more dilutive. I noticed that head count is increasing. And how does that square with some of the cost-cutting and another initiatives?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we have had some increase in head count, David. I would put them in &#x2013; it's in a number of buckets. One is, certainly we are &#x2013; at the same time we're taking force out of the business related to the merger synergies and the other cost initiatives, we are adding force in some areas. For example, we're adding force primarily in terms of technicians and installers for U-verse. And so, we're starting to ramp that up and there's a lead time to that. We've got to hire people, get them trained, and get them on board as we start to launch new markets. So that's been one factor.</p>
          <p>We have also, as part of our merger conditions, we had made some commitments to bring some jobs back that had been outsourced, to bring some jobs back into the country, and so we're following through on those obligations. So, there you may see some head count increases. We're trying to do it such a way that we can minimize any cost increase from it, so we are eliminating outside contractor costs as we're doing that.</p>
          <p>And then finally, we've got some increases that are related to transactions that we've done. So, part of the increase is to bring in about 2,500, for example, from the Dobson acquisition in November. As we &#x2013; we're also bringing people on as part of our IBM agreement, as we take over the network management, much of which, or some of which, had been done in-house at IBM, we're bringing some employees in there to handle that business.</p>
          <p>And finally, we've got some contracts that require us to provide some staffing. For example, we have a government contract in support of the passport offices for example, and they've had high volumes and so we staffed up there but there's corresponding revenues to go with that. I think those are the major things that have impacted force, but our force initiatives related to both the synergies and the other cost initiatives continue to be on track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Chris Larsen from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, a couple of questions. First Rick, on the CPE sales, do you have a sense for where those customers are shifting their purchases? Are they buying them directly from the OEMs or are they going to some of your competitors who are still heavily discounting those products? Secondly, the Apple ARPU, do you reported net of any payments that would go to Apple in your wireless revenues? And then third, and probably the more important of the questions; I'm assuming in your stock buyback, you're in a window where you can't buy it back. When does that window open up? And if you look at your after-tax cost of borrowing, it's now meaningfully below your yield, and how do you think about leverage, short term, in terms of buying back stock relative to your cost of debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Chris. I will try to knock those off one at a time. In CPE, you know, part of the reason for us de-emphasizing sales of standalone CPE as I said is, there's very little margin. We found very little margin in that business &#x2013; because there are a number of alternatives for companies to purchase essentially whether it be a server, a router, or whatever it is, the same piece of equipment. And what you find yourself is, is you're competing with other dealers of that particular equipment, you're competing in many cases, with the manufacturer itself. And so, I can't give you any data in terms of where those purchases have gone, but there's a pretty broad range of alternatives available, and that's why it's just not for us a very attractive business.</p>
          <p>In terms of ARPU on the iPhone, the iPhone ARPU is reported gross, and any sharing or payments are reflected in expense for the iPhone, and that's not different from other relationships we have &#x2013; that we've had for years. For example, our agents typically, as they sell new customers for us, they receive a commission on sale, but they also receive some residuals, some share of revenue, and those are always reported in expense.</p>
          <p>And finally, on stock buyback, we have not been in the market in January because of the earnings release; and so, we will resume our share re-purchase program starting tomorrow. And certainly, we will &#x2013; we will take advantage of both where borrowing rates are as well as where the share price is. And we have a plan as you know, to re-purchase 400 million shares to be spread over this year and next year. But part of that plan includes increasing leverage; not necessarily reducing our credit metrics, but increasing leverage as our cash flow continues to improve. As we did in 2007, we'll be increasing some leverage in 2008, and we'll be using that for share re-purchase. So our expectation, as I said is to be back in the market tomorrow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jason Armstrong from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. A couple of questions. First on wireline; in the prior cycle, you guys were really the first to flag the weakness on the consumer wireline side of the business. In a large part, I think it's due to geographic diversity in the business. Related to that, the step-up in access line loss here, I know you sort of characterized between non-pay housing starts, but can you talk about it geographically? Is a lot of this tied to Midwest sort of Ameritech markets or is it more evenly distributed? And then second question just sort of a follow-up on, you know, numerous economic question. It seems like the economic base case here is still similar to the 'Analyst Day', which you termed at the time, sort of soft landing. If you hypothetically assume we moved to the hard landing scenario, which I'm sure you've run some scenarios on, now how would that change your approach to the business, and maybe specifically on the cost side, what are the levers, the CapEx reductions, the reductions in buybacks? Maybe you could step us through how you would think about the levers at that point if we reached it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Jason. First on the impacts we're seeing in wireline, you know, I've looked at the data, I've looked at it by state, by region and to be honest with you, I'm not seeing any clear patterns by region in terms of changes in the trends. There is certainly some weakness geographically in the Midwest states, upper MidWest, but you know, if you take some cities there Detroit, for example, they've had issues there for some time related to the auto industry. So I can't say that it's &#x2013; I can't say what we're seeing is an increase in a particular area at this point. So I don't see any particular patterns there. I think it's &#x2013; it's more spread across the geography.</p>
          <p>And again, you know, when you're talking about a 10 basis point impact on non-pay churn, that's not a huge impact. So it's &#x2013; you know, you're cutting it pretty fine to try to see it by state or region. You know, right now from an economic standpoint we've got experts that are much more qualified to talk about this, certainly in the country than I would be, but we've got experts kind of on both sides in terms of predicting what the economy will do in 2008. What I would tend to focus on or what I tend to focus on more is what impacts we're seeing in our business and as I said, there's &#x2013; there are some impacts we've seen as we talked about in consumer and in access lines and broadband, but they're not very severe at this point and I think for us that continues to point to more of the defensive nature of our business and in consumer, whether you're looking at wireless or wireline, consumers still are going to want to stay connected, they're going to want to stay connected through voice service and they're certainly going to want to stay connected for data and broadband service. And then on top of that, you know because we're a new entrant, we have lots of opportunities there on the video side.</p>
          <p>As you start to work into business customers, I think the kinds of products we're offering and the solutions we can deliver in IP are really answering problems or issues or challenges that businesses are facing in terms of how to provide greater levels of bandwidth, greater numbers of applications and connectivity throughout their business and to try to do it in a cost-efficient way. That just naturally drives customers to IP, which is a sweet spot for us.</p>
          <p>So I think for me, what that says is I think our business continues across the spectrum to be pretty defensive in times like this. In terms of cost levers, you know, one of the things that we've gotten, I think, very good at is knowing how and when to tighten our belts on the cost side. And something that I think is still surprising to people overall is the level of costs in our business that tend to be variable. We are viewed often times as a large network-based, very fixed cost business, but when you look at the cost in our business, the largest element of cost in our business is &#x2013; is force, but when you take that down to the next level, and this surprises people sometimes, it's not force supporting our network, but it is force that's involved in sales and in customer service and in our call centers. And those areas tend to really to regulate themselves versus the volumes we're seeing in the business. So as volumes decline, calls into the centers decline, we have &#x2013; there's &#x2013; there's always regular attrition in those jobs and so we're &#x2013; we're able to adjust our force in those areas pretty easily. And even on the network side, think about the amount of force there that's &#x2013; that's tied to activity, either installation or repair activity, and so again, as volumes decline, that's pretty self-regulating.</p>
          <p>The second largest area of expense in our business is access, which, again also tends to fluctuate with volumes and so when you put it altogether about 60 to 70% of our expenses are relatively variable with revenues and volumes. So I think that's the other thing that gives us comfort as we go into a period of time where there's some questions about the strength of the economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christine, this will have to be our last question, the next &#x2013; this next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question comes from Mike McCormack from Bear Stearns. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, Mike. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Just a question on, again, I hate to beat the horse on wireline cost saves, but it looks like the sequential drop in cost of service or cost of sales was fairly dramatic. Just trying to get a sense for &#x2013; if there is any sort of one-time impact for the quarter?</p>
          <p>And then looking forward, if we have that kind of expense saving run rate maybe just your thoughts on, you know, if we have wholesale revenue getting more stable with continuation of these cost saves it seems like margin expansion could ramp towards the back half of the year, but may be within the wholesale revenue piece of that, can you give us any sense for what percentage might be wireline carrier revenue? And then secondly, a little more clarity on the merger anniversaries. There are going to be some special access pricing change and I will hit you with one more before I go which is on post-paid wireless ads. It was a good quarter overall for the ads, but within postpaid, still trailing your other competitor out there with a quarter that Sprint put up that was you know, dismal by most measures. Just your sense on how we can take more share of those postpaid subs going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Mike. First of all, on wireless cost of service, there's no...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wireline, Rick, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry, wireline rather wireline cost of service, there's no big drivers there. In fact, when I look and maybe we need to get into some of the numbers with you individually in more detail. When I look at the wireline business third quarter to fourth quarter, the margins were relatively flat, if you look at EBITDA margins, relatively flat between third quarter, fourth quarter. And you know, what we're seeing there is continued improvements in terms of merger synergies and the other cost initiatives offset by &#x2013; in the fourth quarter, I think, primarily two factors.  One is certainly the continued ramp in U-verse provided a more expanse and little more delusion in the fourth quarter versus third or second quarter of last year and then secondly, the fourth quarter typically is a little bit lower in terms of revenue simply because of &#x2013; in a wireline business just lower business days due to the holidays. So fourth quarter would typically be a lower margin quarter for us. We held it about flat this year and that was primarily due to improvements in the cost and merger synergies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah I guess the surprise there was typically you had a margin pressure because presumably you had a relatively fixed cost base with those fewer business days and you certainly saw it with AT&amp;T Corp and I guess I was surprised by the strong cost reduction this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we had a nice ramp in some of the merger synergy areas and we had some, I think, a very good cost focus in our wireline business, particularly in the regional wireline business. So I think helped us in the fourth quarter. In terms of wireless, the postpaid ads, as you said, showed a nice increase year-over-year, and we feel very good about our postpaid sales activity and the volumes we're seeing, store traffic we're seeing. I think the challenge for us and what we have to do as we go forward in 2008 is to continue to migrate churn levels down and certainly as we get beyond the TDMA shutdown, I think that will help churn levels reduce and we need to take, you know, another over time, another 20 basis points or so out of our post-paid churn and that will make I think a huge difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you see that opportunity on the Dobson churn as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think overall, I think Dobson will help us. I think we'll be able to improve overall Dobson results because we can offer customers in the Dobson areas, I think, a much more robust product portfolio. And secondly, we'll see some churn improvement because we'll be taking some or we'll see some margin improvement because we'll be taking some roaming costs out. And just having those areas and being able to better tie them into our networks, we'll spend a little money on improving network quality in some of those areas and that will drive better churn for us as well. You know, a good example is Dobson has an area north here of San Antonio and it's an area where a lot of people in the San Antonio metropolitan area travel to, and so I think the ability to tie that into our network will provide a better customer experience, better churn rates there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have anything on that wholesale revenue for us Rick, and what percentage might be coming from that wireline carrier revenue base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that percentage for you Mike, but generally, the wireline carrier base revenues have been declining because that's where, you know, in effect you see the impact of consolidation in some areas. We're continuing to see very good growth in wireless, and we're seeing some growth in international and I think where we have opportunities going forward, it's going to be in some of the things we mentioned, in particular the IBM agreement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, that will conclude our question and answer session. Rick has some closing comments before we adjourn for the morning. Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Rich, and thanks to all of you for being on the call with us today. I would just reiterate, I think we had a very good fourth quarter, certainly terrific wireless growth. We're very excited about what we saw in the fourth quarter from a wireless standpoint. Excellent momentum continues in enterprise, which I think is a good sign for us, as well as stable revenue trends and regional operations.</p>
          <p>We continued to focus and push cost synergies and they continue to run ahead of schedule and all of that contributes to continued double-digit growth and adjusted EPS and strong free cash flow. Along with that free cash flow, we're happy to report more than 19 billion return to share owners in 2007 through dividends and stock buybacks.</p>
          <p>I think you can tell as overall we're very proud of the 2007 results, but I think what's more important frankly, today is, I believe the opportunities that still lie ahead for us. We have good momentum in some key areas of the business that will allow us to ramp top-line growth. We continue to have substantial opportunities to remove costs. We're on track with the initiatives that we outlined for you in December and all of that gives us confidence in reaffirming our outlook and our ability to drive strong results in 2008.</p>
          <p>As I said at the analyst conference last month, I think AT&amp;T today has a very strong financial profile. We're a financially disciplined company. We're capable of sustained double-digit growth and adjusted earnings per share. We are a strong free cash flow company and a company that's committed to returning value to share owners with a strong dividend yield. And I think that profile, along with some of the defensive characteristics of the business that we talked about today, makes us especially attractive in the current economic and market environment. I want to thank you all again for taking part in the call today and as always for your interest in AT&amp;T.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you Rick, and thank all of you. Christine, that will conclude our call for today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you ladies and gentlemen for participating in the AT&amp;T fourth quarter earnings release 2007 conference call. This concludes your conference for today. You may all disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>