<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1489255" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2013 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>37018</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Global Investor Relations">Kedar Shirali</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="CEO, Non-Independent Executive Director &amp; MD">Natarajan Chandrasekaran</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO &amp; Non-Independent Executive Director">Seturaman Mahalingam</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Non-Independent Non-Executive Director">Phiroz Adi Vandrevala</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Global Human Resources">Ajoyendra Mukherjee</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Cowen &amp; Co.">Moshe Katri</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (India) Pvt Ltd.">Anantha Narayan</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan India Pvt Ltd.">Viju K. George</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities India Pvt Ltd.">Diviya Nagarajan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Ambit Capital Pvt Ltd.">Ankur Rudra</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Janney Montgomery Scott LLC">Jeff S. Rossetti</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (United States)">Keith F. Bachman</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital Securities (India) Pvt Ltd.">Nitin Mohta</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Financial Advisory &amp; Securities (India) Pvt Ltd.">Pinku Pappan</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Edelweiss Securities Ltd.">Sandip K. Agarwal</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good day, and welcome to the TCS Earnings Conference Call. As a reminder, all participant lines will be in a listen-only mode. There will be an opportunity for you to ask questions at the end of today's presentation. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Please note that this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the conference over to Mr. Kedar Shirali of TCS. Thank you, and over to you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marina. Good evening, and welcome, everyone. Thank you for joining us today to discuss TCS' financial results for the first quarter of fiscal year 2013 that ended June 30, 2012. This call is being webcast through our website and an archive including the transcript will be available on the site for the duration of this quarter. The financial statements, results, presentation and press release are also available on our website.</p>
          <p>Our leadership team is present on this call to discuss our results. We have with us today Mr. N. Chandrasekaran, Chief Executive Officer and Managing Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. S. Mahalingam, Chief Financial Officer and Executive Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Phiroz Adi Vandrevala, Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And Mr. Ajoy Mukherjee, Head of Global Human Resources.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Chandra and Maha will give us a brief overview of the company's performance followed by a Q&amp;A session. As you are aware, we do not provide specific revenue or earnings guidance. Anything said on this call, which reflects our outlook for the future or which can be construed as a forward-looking statement must be reviewed in conjunction with the risks that the company faces. We have outlined these risks in the second slide of the analyst presentation available on our website.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like turn the call over to Chandra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kedar. Thank you, all, for joining the call. I think we have started the year very well. The Q1 performance from a revenue point of view is 12.1% in rupee terms, and it translates to 4% in constant currency and 3% to U.S. dollar terms on a sequential basis.</p>
          <p>The most notable thing in this growth has been the volume. The volume growth has been 5.3% overall. And if you take into account the international business alone, the volumes have been 5.9%. It has also been a very encouraging quarter because the growth has come from all the key markets and all the industries.</p>
          <p>In terms of the key markets, the U.S. market grew 2.8% in constant-currency terms, Continental Europe grew 4.3% in constant-currency terms, and UK registered 14.8% in <mark type="ph" /> rupee (02:53) terms. And the life and pensions platform is delivering growth. From an industry point of view, all the industry segments in which we operate delivered a sequential growth on constant-currency terms.</p>
          <p>The most important verticals which delivered significant growth are: retail, 8.3%; telecom, 7.6%; BFSI, 5.6%. And in terms of services, again, we saw a very good growth across the service portfolio. Assurance, infrastructure, BPO and enterprise solutions all grew. And in terms of the new services, we have seen significant demands in mobility, big data, cloud, social media, and all such areas are translating into engagements. The investments that we have been making are all coming off. On mobility alone, we have more than 100 customers where we are actively engaged in doing projects.</p>
          <p>And from a customer perspective, the customer metrics has been very, very good. Once again, if you really look at the migration of customers across the whole, it has been very satisfying. The $20 million customers increased from 99 to 105; and the $5 million customers increased from 245 to 259, 14 more customers in this segment. It pretty much plays to our strategy of being very customer centric and drives our full services capability and continues to invest in new areas, so that we can be relevant to our customers in achieving the objectives.</p>
          <p>The deal pipeline remains very healthy. We have closed a number of deals this quarter, about eight deals that we have closed during the quarter, and they're again from across multiple segments. In the Financial Services Banking and Financial Services space, we have closed three deals: two deals in retail, one in pharma, media and telecom each. The deals again have come from different markets: four from the U.S.; two from Europe, Europe including UK; one each from UK and one from Continental Europe; one in Asia Pacific; one in Middle East. All are very nice deals.</p>
          <p>And the pipeline is healthy and in terms of employee addition, we had a significant gross addition of 13,831 associates. The utilization went up to 81.3%. We continued to focus on employee productivity.</p>
          <p>Then in terms of our platforms, we have been the earliest company to identify platforms as the key area of future business models. And we have the experience of doing it in the life and pensions platform, where we made a bet on that platform in 2005. And it took us a good five years to prove the platform, but I'm happy to say that we are confident of the whole platform strategy. And this year, the platform alone will clock $500 million in revenues.</p>
          <p>Our newly invested platforms whether it is SMB iON or HRO or F&amp;A or Analytics are all seeing customer tractions. This quarter, we have had a significant win for the F&amp;A platform, significant win for the HRO platform, and multiple wins for the Analytics platform. But having said that, our experience shows that we need to continue to invest in these platforms and they take time in order to gain critical mass. Because the platform business is all &#x2013; not only about our capability to build the platform, but the right timing for the customer migration into those platforms because it's a change for the customer as well.</p>
          <p>But it's important for you to know that we are continuing to not only invest in this platform but really invest in a number of other platforms in different industries. For example, loyalty is a big area where we have created a platform in retail, and we look at many other industries as well. Then from a margin perspective, it has been a very satisfying quarter again because we have the currency gain, a significant gain, which helped us to mitigate the headwinds.</p>
          <p>We did have significant headwinds because the wage increase of 8% on an average in Indian market and 2% to 4% in the international market, significant head count addition last quarter, all coming in this quarter, again a significant addition in this quarter plus also our highest ever H1 filings. These are filings this quarter, part of that cost. So, all of those things have been headwinds and largely, we've been able to mitigate it and deliver a margin of 27.5% operating level. And the net profit margin is very good and very, very healthy.</p>
          <p>Overall, I would say that the performance is a result of our &#x2013; not only differentiated strategy but staying close in an organization, which is very agile and empowered, and our ability to stay close and relevant to customers and continuing investments in new services as well as business models as we move forward.</p>
          <p>The other point that I make is in terms of the customer behavior, I think I would like to repeat what I have been saying for the last three meetings at least, once in January, then in March, then in the last quarter. Primarily, the macro continues to be what it is and there are some development of the other &#x2013; in different parts of the world and especially in Europe every day. But customers have learned to operate in this environment, and they have developed their plans to execute for their own business growth, business results, et cetera. And the IT budgets have been developed based on that, and we think they are staying close, and we are continuing to see opportunities, continuing to see deal closures and continuing to see both transformation projects and discretionary projects overall. And that would be the way I would conclude the current status.</p>
          <p>Thank you, and over to you, Maha.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chandra. You have seen all the figures that we have given. Let me give you some more breakup as regards to revenue, the breakup of our sequential INR growth of 12.1% is below: volume growth plus 5.34%, constant-currency realization minus 106 basis points, currency impact plus 8.13%, offshore shift minus 27 basis points. This is the breakup of the INR growth of 12.1%.</p>
          <p>The aggregate margin, we have an EBIT margin of 27.5%, reflecting a modest decline of 20 basis points Q-on-Q. The breakup of this is as follows: currency impact plus 276 basis points, wage increase minus 200 basis points, productivity shift minus 117 basis points, SG&amp;A efficiencies plus 18 basis points, offshore shift plus 3 basis points and cumulatively accounting for a drop of 20 basis points. As you know, as far as foreign exchange is concerned taking note of the highly volatile currency market, we have switched to plain option and therefore, we have avoided the hit. Our other income increased as a percentage of revenue to 1.17% from 0.82% in the prior quarter. The effective tax rate has been put more higher and the net margin was 22.1%, down 15 basis points.</p>
          <p>Our accounts receivables stood at 18 DSO in dollar terms, a slight improvement over the prior quarter. Investment fund as of 30th of June was INR130.2 billion. And therefore, this quarter has been a very satisfactory quarter, and we have ensured that we continue to invest in capacity building and also in terms of improving and enhancing the capabilities that make us more relevant to customers. We have also been disciplined in our execution. We have shown good discipline, be it in selling, in pricing, in investing and in cost management.</p>
          <p>External things like currency work for you sometimes and against you at other times. Our attempt has been to build a resilient business model that deliver superior results irrespective of those externalities. We are progressing well on that part.</p>
          <p>With this, you can open to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, sir. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Moshe Katri from Cowen &amp; Co. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and congratulations on a good set of numbers, especially in this environment. I just want to start by focusing on probably one of the most important metrics that everybody is talking about this morning, which is pricing. Can you confirm to us that at this point you're not seeing anyone in the market that is disrupting that has been &#x2013; that has some sort of a disruptive behavior in pricing that could impact the group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think from our point of view, we participate in a number of deals in a number of markets. By and large, I would say that we are able to hold our pricing, and there is always a situation where somebody is trying to disturb the price. And you know, that is a choice that we have to make and not to bid on those engagements. But overall, we don't see a risk to our pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's fair. And then given the fact that fundamentals of TCS seem to be pretty decent here, are you seeing a pickup in win rates? Are you doing anything different that kind of helps you to get to that level compared to some of your peers that are really struggling here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as I said, the things that we focus on is continuing to keep the organization very agile on the same course in terms of acquiring key clients and pursuing our full services strategy, concentrate on the value proposition, and have to be more relevant every day because there is a multi-stage growth here. It's not that every customer in the same industry does the same thing. Each customer situation is different, and it requires you to be relevant to that customer in that industry. No longer you can say that this particular industry is spending money on this type of stuff kind of situation. So apart from that, it's very hard for me to say, but we are investing significantly in all these technologies and in platforms that's paid off as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you feel that your win rates have improved compared to where they were 12 months ago or at this point, they're kind of the same?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me put it this way, I think I don't know about 12 months, but our win rates continues to improve and also our qualification also getting tighter and tighter. And also, we are beginning to crank up in markets like Latin America, and our platforms like life and pensions platform are beginning to grow. So there are a number of initiatives that we have taken, a number of investments we have taken and we continue to focus, and then make sure that every investment that we are making is yielding results and see it in the context of customers and context of today's environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, final question on visibility, has there been any change in terms of inter-quarter visibility, and then maybe you can talk about this in the context of kind of the broad &#x2013; your broad statement that I think you still expect TCS to grow faster than NASSCOM's target rates for the sector? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we have maintained that at the beginning of the year at the currency levels that were prevailing. We made a statement that we will grow higher than the NASSCOM estimate and we still maintain that. The only thing that we cannot predict is where the cross currencies will be, now what they'll be three months from now, four months from now. So but basically, on the business level, we see things are okay, and we continue to see opportunities. We continue to see that the clients are making decisions, and we have visibility and I think we are just focusing on making sure that we do things right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, congratulations. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Anantha Narayan from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and congratulations on the great execution. Chandra, this is a follow-up to the previous question on pricing. You did mention that from time to time that you see some sort of disruptive behavior, and that's up to you to choose to ignore it. Just in terms of the last six months or so, has such behavior been fairly stable, or do you see them increasing incidents of such disruption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think by and large, it has been stable, I would say, and there is always odd deals you see that someone is very desperate to get, and you got to take the call &#x2013; take your call in terms of not only pricing and other terms. You have to be careful about what you want to commit, and there are deals that you have to get out of. But otherwise, we are seeing the <mark type="ph" /> suggestion (20:12) to be stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a final question on the rest of this fiscal year. Do you expect the usual seasonality in terms of a strong first half, or do you think this year could be more even?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, we don't see any specific data points to be &#x2013; data points to be, what you call, peculiar. We are just saying the same thing that we said in January and the same thing we said in April. Except that in early March, we said that we saw some delay in the discretionary projects and then said that they have started picking up, and that's continuing. So, I can't really see a pattern saying a particular quarter would be superior to the third, our fourth quarter will be superior to the second quarter. I mean it's very hard to say. I don't see such patterns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and congratulations once again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Viju George from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, congratulations. Thank you for taking &#x2013; yeah, sorry. Congratulations to management. I just had a couple of questions, one on the emerging markets particularly India. I was just looking at the performance in this quarter, it's a bit down again. Do you have a problem generally with regard to emerging markets, where things get up and down because the level of discretionary spending is so high and projects &#x2013; project <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:47)? So what do you do to manage that portfolio given that it's about 17% of revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are two types of <mark type="ph" /> uncertainty (22:00). I think the regions like Latin America are a little bit more less prone to discretionary spend at this point in time perhaps. We have a good annual run rate now. Last year, revenues were good but this year, our current run rate is quite healthy in Latin America. But whereas particularly India is concerned, we have volatility because Asia Pacific I wouldn't still put it, because we account Australia as part of Asia Pacific which is a very mature market.</p>
          <p>But if you look at the Indian market per se, we see both volatility and delays. It's very hard to say that the deal will get closed within a particular point in time. It has not anything to do with the spending or budget, but just the process that's followed and the timing with which the deals will be closed. It is a bit <mark type="ph" /> edgy, (23:04) unpredictable, and we have seen it in multiple quarters, again, this &#x2013; it happened this quarter. Actually, perhaps internally, it was a disappointing quarter from what we thought we will do from an India market point of view, otherwise, we should have had better numbers. So given that, I think the only way to manage that is to have a portfolio, which kind of over a period of time gets matured from a discretionary versus annuity. But if it doesn't, then we really have to cap how much is the exposure we have into the discretionary and so on and so forth. So those are things that we grapple with and I've said it multiple times. I hope we can get out of this kind of volatility sooner than later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thanks. That's helpful. One follow-up question is on budget. If there are certain clients who are spending significantly below their budgets currently, is it rational to expect the budgets flush towards the second half of the year? The reason I ask is that if the spending ends up considerably below budget for the year then next year, it's possible that the budget gets reset down to lower levels in line with spending in <mark type="ph" /> TCS. (24:15) So to preempt that situation, would you see such clients spending in the flush towards the end of the year or in the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are two questions here. One is, is there any increase in the budget? Probably not, we are not seeing that. But is there a situation that a customer has got a budget but has the customer spent less in the &#x2013; less so far, and will they spend more? That can happen and &#x2013; but I don't have any data points on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thank you, and all the best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Diviya Nagarajan from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, congrats again on the good set of results, especially the overall <mark type="inaudible" /> (25:10)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, this is your operator. Ma'am, we are not able to hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Given the recent events, <mark type="inaudible" /> (25:22)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, ma'am, we are not able to hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Where do you think that's going <mark type="inaudible" /> (25:29)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, Ms. Nagarajan...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> (25:34) still confident of getting to the 14% to 15% mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir, can we move on to the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ankur Rudra from Ambit Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Congratulations, great performance especially in the current environment. The first question was on, I'm sorry if I'm repeating anything because I think the line was a bit bad initially. Are you seeing any greater competition from multinational firms recently in the last two to three quarters, this should rise by how quickly? Some of the other larger firms, outsourcing business is growing recently. I was wondering if that's leading to any pricing implications. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think the competition profile remains the same. There is no significant change. It's &#x2013; there are a few multinationals and few India multinationals I would say &#x2013; are always in the <mark type="ph" /> frame (26:31) in certain types of deals. And there are certain other types of deals where the product deals or platform deals <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:37), but nothing has changed. No, I wouldn't subscribe to that view. I know where we are going. I won't subscribe to that view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough, just digging on the pricing discussion a bit further, I know at the moment, you are seeing that pricing has remained strong, but just wondering if the macroeconomic environment remains as it is right now. Do you expect further demands for selective price discounting and possibly gain sharing around your BPO testing kind of businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think I would like to answer it a little bit broadly. The deals are also getting complex. Everything is not rate contracts. Some of the contracts are moving to managed services, and the platform deals are coming as outcome based pricing, not small deals. Even if you take a contract like <mark type="indiscernible" /> (27:29) $2 billion deal, it is not a straightforward deal where you could do a standard rate contract. So I wouldn't just directly take any question saying that you know pricing is going to be under pressure and so on and so forth. There can be always selective pressures but overall, as I have said, I don't see that there's a concern to maintain at the current levels. And there will always be a plus or minus, although in one quarter there may be 1% down; next quarter, it may be 1% up. That situation will happen. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:07)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just asking it a bit differently, should it begin &#x2013; we know you're saying that you're not seeing it right now. What would be the best strategy of dealing with it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that I'm going to discuss it in the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you, sir. Best of luck for the remaining year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Diviya Nagarajan from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Can you hear me now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. My question &#x2013; congrats firstly on a great set of numbers. My question is on what do you expect for the rest of the year. I think earlier we were talking about the 11% to 14% NASSCOM guidance being conservative because it was given in December and since then, things have improved. Do you still stick to that view because some of your peers seem to be having a tough time getting to that kind of range? And are you still confident of beating that kind of a number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Diviya, I think probably you missed it. That question was asked, but I'll answer it anyway. I think what we have said is that our commentary has kind of been consistent for the last six months and we have not seen a major shift in the way we see the environment &#x2013; at least the business environment for us. I'm not talking about the macro. So we are the view that we will stick to the statement of delivering at the higher end of the &#x2013; above the NASSCOM estimates at the currency level that existed prior to the beginning of the year. The only thing that we cannot predict is the currency movement, cost currency impact, et cetera. It's just becoming a little bit crazy. So we'll leave it at that. But otherwise, I think we are same course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, got that. And my other question to you is, we typically see a strong sequential growth quarter in September, I think with the exception of the last year which typically had a pickup in revenue growth and volume growth in the second quarter of the fiscal. Are we going to see similar seasonality this year, or are you looking at kind of a different pattern this quarter &#x2013; this year because of the demand environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are continuing to see opportunities, but I think any estimates I would generally be conservative given the overall situation. But otherwise, I think nothing wrong to report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got that. Thanks, and all the best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Joseph Foresi from Janney Montgomery Scott. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is Jeff Rossetti in for Joe. Congratulations on the results. I just wanted to see if you could talk about Europe and Financial Services, both of those areas picked up this quarter. Could you give some more detail on what was the reasoning for that, and just an overview of what you're seeing in those areas currently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have been &#x2013; saying from a Europe perspective that we had good deal closures and at the beginning of the year, we had said that Europe should perform better this year. It's something that we had said, and those deals are coming through and the deals that we won are being realized. So, that is what is delivering growth in Europe. The same thing is happening in Telecom as well. I think we have done well in Telecom. As we have said earlier, we are seeing traction, and we are closing deals and that's kind of getting realized as we move forward.</p>
          <p>From a BFSI perspective, the BFS per se and insurance per se and the BSFI put together, all have grown sequentially this quarter. That's quite encouraging. And actually, as I said, there are projects from an efficiency point of view, there are projects on the risk side, there are multi-channel projects, there are many things that are going on. The banks are under pressure. Their margins are under squeezed. So, efficiency is a very important &#x2013; has become a very important element for the financial institutions. Having said that, I mean that's a sector that we always need to watch out for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then on the eight deals you closed this quarter, can &#x2013; you said that there was improvement on the transformation in discretionary side. Is there any way to break out what you're seeing on those deals close as a discretionary versus annuity comparison?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I would not be able to give you a number, but what I would say, what I was trying to convey at least to clarify, I was saying that overall, the customers this year if they had decided that I'll do so much around the business and so much on, say, in the business. And whether a customer is spending less than usual on, say, in the business this year or spending the same amount can vary from customer to customer. But by and large, probably they are spending less. But the important point is and whatever is the amount that they are &#x2013; that they said they are spending on whatever is the projects, we see those projects getting <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:37) and those projects getting started and we are not seeing any delays in that. That is the point I was trying to communicate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And last question, is there any change from your gross hiring guidance of 50,000 for the year? And thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We had initially given a gross hiring of 50,000 and we are staying the course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir, do you have further questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Keith Bachman from Bank of Montreal. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I had two questions, if I could. I wanted to go back &#x2013; I wasn't sure I understood your answer on pipeline cadence as to, say, in the last 60 to 90 days, have you seen any changes in the close rates and in particular related to the financial services vertical and then I have a follow-up question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We find the pipeline to be healthy, and we find the closure rates to be normal on a particular type of deal normally what it takes is what it takes. We have not seen any changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. And then my follow-up question is as you look out over the next three quarters, if you could just address philosophically, it's a tough macro, how you're thinking about the trade-offs that you have to make between revenue growth aspirations and then margins. How do you think about that trade-off and if you had to, say, sacrifice one, where would you be willing to give so to speak on either the revenue or the margin trade-off? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We always said that any growth has to come with respectable margins. That has been our philosophy. We are in a business where the technology is rapidly changing. The change in technology today is much, much faster than ever before and the technologies are also having very profound impact on customers and their business models, which essentially means that we need to be continuously investing. So, we have to operate at a healthy margin, and that is a premise and any growth, we always plan with a healthy margin.</p>
          <p>So whether a particular deal whether we take out one percentage point down or two percentage point down or we will skip it even for half a percentage point, it's all very difficult to answer. It very much depends on the deal, the nature of the deal, the scope it has, the strategic nature of the engagements, so many things. But by and large, I think we have been pretty disciplined so far, and we intend to be very disciplined. We are not looking at buying revenues and throwing away margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So in other words, if I could just paraphrase, if one of your competitors start to push a little bit on pricing, you guys would see those deals is what I hear you saying, is that a fair statement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will see, it's fair statement, but we will see. Because as I said, there is a strategy that we have today and depending upon how we perform, how the market changes, how the other players behave, et cetera, we need to continuously evaluate. And I don't think it would be fair for you to expect me to discuss this in this call because we don't know what we will do. That's something that we will have a look underground but in general, we will be very disciplined.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Atul Soni from Macquarie Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. This is Nitin Mohta from Macquarie. I just wanted the management's comments on insourcing buzz that has been in the media for a while. I understand this started from the comments way back in January. So from January till now, have you seen any ramp downs for any of your clients because of insourcing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, because of insourcing, it ramped down. No, nothing has really happened there as a result of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's it for my side, and all the very best for the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Pinku Pappan from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my questions. Anything particular in enabling abilities that vertically you're seeing decline for last three quarters, could you tell us what's happening there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it has not declined. It has still grown from constant-currency point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See the only thing that I would say is that there are couple of engagements in India we had on that sector, which means one-off engagements that got completed. So we didn't have &#x2013; we didn't &#x2013; I mean there's no loss of revenue but it's a discretionary project to some of the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:06) engagements and those got basically in the area of APDRP which is the smart area, smarter area, we had a couple of major engagements and they have come off and &#x2013; so there is no follow-on engagements to replace that. And to so any growth that's coming is being &#x2013; even though it is growth still it has to make up for this larger, say, contracts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Are you seeing any signs of trouble in the insurance vertical because I think one of your peers have actually talked about clients facing a lot of pressures there, anything in common there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, our insurance business has grown very well this quarter, last quarter and as per the pipeline we have, it will do well for the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a follow-up, you said you are seeing opportunities in discretionary spending. Could you tell us which markets or which verticals you're seeing in <mark type="inaudible" /> (40:03)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have given some representative engagements to give you some color in the press release, the type of engagements that we have won and many discretionary wants also we have put out there, especially in the new areas. So the adoption of all the new technologies from analytics point of view, from an enterprise mobility point of view are all big opportunities. Multi-channel digital is a big opportunity. And those are the kind of areas &#x2013; and obviously banking, new system replacement is an opportunity. We won a big core banking deal and a couple of more core banking deals in China. So we've got multiple wins that we have announced. So, it really is from industry to industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And lastly on regulatories and compliance spending, are you seeing any changes in the market in terms of clients starting to spend more or you think it's still going to retrospect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that's going to be an area where the spend is going to be there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but you think, I mean, I think last quarter you talked about some of the spend getting pushed, has that started or is it still going on track?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think as I just articulated earlier, all the areas in which the customers have struggled for this, they are ramping up and they are <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:26) are getting met. We're not seeing <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:28).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, due to time constraints, we will take one last question from Omkar Hadkar from Edelweiss Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Sandip from Edelweiss, just a couple of questions. One, sir, if you see the service line, we have seen out of the incremental $80 million revenue in this quarter, around $50 million is in BPO. So can you throw some light on that what is driving growth so far there, first? And secondly, on the book keeping side, we have one question on the utilization front, do you see utilization to further improve from here keeping in mind the kind of gross hiring targets you have given? So these are two questions, which I would like you to answer please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; I have to do the breakup and then answer to you probably we can reach out later <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:23) together, we can give more info on that. But there is nothing specifically except for some one-off revenue. I also call one-off revenue, the first time increase is coming from the life and pensions platform. This time there is a ramp up on BPO side, and then there are three or four other engagements that started. One big telco engagement has started, and one media engagement has started. So those things would have brought and I need to disaggregate and I got to see that.</p>
          <p>What was the second part of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Utilization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, from utilization point of view, I think our constant endeavor has been to improve utilization. We are &#x2013; as compared to Q4, we have improved to 81.3% excluding trainees are concerned. And going forward, yes we would try to improve it further and as we have said, that we would like to operate at 82%, 83% somewhere in that range. So going forward, we would like to see it improve further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But will it be possible in this &#x2013; I mean the way gross hiring has &#x2013; for the <mark type="ph" /> cash there (43:28) so 3,000 people you're expecting to hire. So will it be possible <mark type="ph" /> new item (43:31) to go to 83% level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm talking about utilization excluding trainings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, okay, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, so that is the one that you need to keep in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, okay. Thank you. That's all from my side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, that was the last question. I now hand the conference back to the management for closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in summary, I would say that it has been a very good quarter. And we are particularly very happy with the volume growth, the secular nature of the growth and particularly telecom as we expected it has started to grow. Europe is showing good progress, and BFSI overall has been performing which is very important since it's a significant portion of our revenues.</p>
          <p>So, all of these are very positive.</p>
          <p>The second aspect is the new technologies, the mobilities, the big data and the social media and all those things picking up momentum. So we will be accelerating our investments in these technologies and the new ones going forward.</p>
          <p>As we said, we are not seeing any change in the decision making, and we're going to stay course and we see demand and we have visibility. And we are going to stick to our position that we said earlier this year in terms of delivering about the NASSCOM guidelines.</p>
          <p>And with those words, I would like to conclude the call. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, members of the management team. On behalf of TCS, that concludes this conference call. Thank you for joining us, and you may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>