<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1345032" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-10-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>37018</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Kedar Shirali, Director of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">N. Chandrasekaran, Chief Executive Officer and Managing Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">S. Mahalingam, Chief Financial Officer and Executive Director</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Phiroz A. Vandrevala, Executive Director and Head of Global Corporate Affairs</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Ajoy Mukherjee, Vice President and Head of Global Human Resources</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Joseph Foresi</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Moshe Katri</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Ashwin Mehta</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Edward Caso</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Mitali Ghosh</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Vihang Naik</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Nitin Padmanabhan</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Sandeep Shah</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Anurag Purohit</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Rahul Jain</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Srivathsan Ramachandran</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Ashish Chopra</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Deepan Kapadia</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="corprep">&lt;Q &gt;</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good day and welcome to the TCS Earnings Conference Call. Please note that for the duration of this presentation all participants' lines will be in the listen-only mode. Please note that this conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity for you to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Kedar Shirali, Director, Investor Relations at TCS. Thank you, and over to you, Mr. Shirali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Melissa. Good evening and welcome everyone. Thank you for joining us today to discuss TCS' Financial Results for the Second Quarter of Fiscal Year 2011 that ended September 30, 2010. This call is being webcast through our website and an archive, including the transcript, will be available on the site for the duration of this quarter. The financial statements, results, presentation and press releases are also available on our website.</p>
          <p>Our leadership team is present on this call to discuss our results. We have with us today Mr. N. Chandrasekaran, Chief Executive Officer and Managing Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning, good afternoon, and good evening, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. S. Mahalingam, Chief Financial Officer and Executive Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Phiroz A. Vandrevala, Head of Global Corporate Affairs and Executive Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And Mr. Ajoy Mukherjee, Head of Global Human Resources.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>As usual, Chandra and Maha will give us a brief overview of the company's performance and that will be followed by the Q&amp;A session. As you are aware, we do not provide specific revenue and earnings guidance. Everything said on this call which reflects our outlook for the future, or which can be construed as a forward-looking statement must be reviewed in conjunction with the risks that the company faces. We have outlined these risks in the second slide of the results presentation e-mailed to you and it's also made available on our website.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to turn the call over to Chandra to begin the proceedings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kedar. Hello, friends. It's a pleasure to connect with all of you to share the highlights of our Q2 results. In summary, it has been a very satisfying quarter and the quarter where we achieved several milestones. And, this is the first quarter where we cross $2 billion in revenue and more important &#x2013; importantly our incremental revenues for the quarter is $210 million. And, in an environment which has been uncertain, not only we have been able to see the demand recovery, but also able to capture that demand and execute flawlessly.</p>
          <p>And the volumes have been about 11.2% again; a very, very credible number and, in terms of the U.S. market, our revenues exceeded $1 billion this quarter and all our verticals, our industry segments have grown double-digit during the quarter. All the key markets, namely the Americas, Europe, India and Asia-Pacific, have registered double-digit growth.</p>
          <p>So, it has been a very well spread out performance. And then, in terms of operating margin, we've done very well to improve the margins by 86 basis points and deliver growth at the operating margin level, as well as at the net margin level, higher than the revenue level.</p>
          <p>On a year on year basis, the growth has been 25% on the revenue line and about 32% on the net profit line. To talk about the deals, I think, the pipeline has been very good and, as I said, it has been well rounded and we closed the eight large deals, two in banking, two in retail, one each in insurance, life sciences, government, and media sectors. In terms of the markets, half of those deals came from the U.S. and the remaining deals came each from different markets.</p>
          <p>In terms of services, again it has been an excellent quarter because most of our services have grown double-digit or near double-digit. The Infrastructure Services have seen an excellent demand and a great growth. And, the Enterprise Solutions, which signals the recovery of the discretionary spend, has grown excellently well, more than the company growth rate.</p>
          <p>In terms of employees, again our HR team has done a fantastic job of recruiting the highest ever gross addition, 19,293 employees and, even on a net basis, it is the highest ever addition, all done organically.</p>
          <p>Our pipeline looks very robust and, barring the macro uncertainty that prevails, which we have to be watchful about, we're very positive and bullish about the demand environment and are preparing ourselves for the future. Those will be my initial comments.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn it over to Maha and then later on we can take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chandra. Here are the headline numbers once again. We posted revenue of 92.864 billion rupees, which is a growth of 13% q-on-q and 24.9% year-on-year. In constant currency the sequential growth was 11%. In dollar terms, the reported revenue is 2.004 billion, which is sequential growth of 11.7% and y-on-y growth of 30.3%.</p>
          <p>The breakup of quarterly revenue growth in INR terms is as follows. Volume growth plus 11.2%. Exchange plus 205 basis points. Pricing minus 26 basis points. Total 13%.</p>
          <p>From a margin perspective, we had a significant headwind in September quarter from the promotions given in July. On the other hand, we benefited from a quarter-on-quarter currency movement, higher utilization and greater operational leverage arising out of our continued cost management in the face of good top line growth, and therefore we are able &#x2013; we were able to expand the operating margin by 86 basis points quarter-on-quarter to 28%.</p>
          <p>The impact of different levers on the operating margin is as follows. Currency, 103 points. Impact of promotions and the variable payout &#x2013; additional variable payout, negative 166 basis points. Rate productivity improvement, 95 basis points. SG&amp;A efficiencies, 54 basis points positive. So totally, 86 basis points. Other income was lower this quarter due to net foreign exchange loss of 537 million rupees, and the reduced cash balance after last year's special and other dividend payouts. Our effective tax rate was 18.95%, giving us a net income of 21,065 million. That's a net margin of 22.68%, a 23 basis point expansion q-on-q. Lastly, our DSO for the quarter was 78 days. Invested funds stood at 71.7 billion rupees.</p>
          <p>To conclude, we have had an excellent quarter, posting double-digit sequential growth even in a difficult global economic environment. Importantly, we showed that with customer focus, disciplined selling, full services capability and good execution, it's possible to achieve such high growth without compromising on profitability, or for that matter, cash flows. And this is what industry leadership is all about.</p>
          <p>With that, we can open the line for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-question session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from the line of Joseph Foresi from Janney Montgomery Scott. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gentlemen. Congratulations on some nice results here. My first question is just on demand. Maybe you could just describe to us what's going on in a little bit more detail. Is this a catch up? I mean obviously, the hiring numbers would lead us to believe that you're expecting demand to be strong for a couple quarters going forward. What are you seeing in the environment right now and just what's driving the growth and the strength of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that it is pent-up demand. The way I would like to describe is that number one, we have made investments in different markets and different industries, all of them are picking up momentum, and that is driving growth at one level.</p>
          <p>But at our large customer segment, there are two things that we are seeing. One, every business is extremely focused on becoming efficient, which means consolidation of multiple ERPs. If they're having multiple core banking systems going to a single instance. Or if they have done a lot of acquisitions in the past, wanting to bring it all together. Or in the infrastructure space, if they had too many data centers, if they had too many servers, virtualization, consolidation, a kind of transformation initiative. So a number of things that actually is related to bringing efficiencies. Everyone is focused on that.</p>
          <p>The second trend is every business is definitely wanting to grow. And every business we talk to in our customer segment has got a growth agenda. It is called by different names. Some are focused on getting customer insights. Some are focused on introducing new products faster. Some are achieving growth in geographic expansion. So there is an initiative, there is a focus, and all of this is resulting in picking up of new projects and new initiatives. And so we're seeing opportunities on both sides.</p>
          <p>We have had a preliminary set of discussions with some of our customers. And while the full budget cycle is not complete and we will have more data towards the end of the quarter, on a very small sample of dialogue that I have had, I think we're going to see increase in spending, next fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just secondly, building on that, I guess &#x2013; with kind of attrition rates tweaking up and the rupee appreciating here, the positive side is obviously demand is very strong. What would be your primary concern heading into next year? Is it the later supplies? Is it the movement in the currency? What are you monitoring to just make sure that things stay as good as they are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are four things. One is that the &#x2013; definitely, attrition is something that we'd like to be brought down. And we are at about 14%. While from a statistics point of view, we probably have the lowest attrition in the industry, but it's still a pretty large number. And when you translate it to absolute numbers, it's pretty large. So we are really kicking off a number of initiatives on employee engagement and we are focused on bringing it down. That's one area we really are concerned.</p>
          <p>The second area is definitely currency. And that is a &#x2013; definitely a headwind. And we were comfortable at 46 to a dollar, and it's come down already, so that's an area we will continue to watch.</p>
          <p>The third thing is, we have been able to capture the demand very nicely, and our teams have done a superb job of execution. The recruitment, fulfillment, kicking up of the projects and executing those projects, all of this has worked together very nicely. As we scale, we need to continue to bring that engine to be agile. We're already demonstrating our ability. But to sustain that agility, what are the tools that we can deploy, how we can really bring the organization to work together, to capture the demand. That's something that we have to definitely watch out.</p>
          <p>And fourth is the regulatory measures that is being talked about in different parts of the world, the U.S. in particular, and probably in some other markets. What kind of changes will come. And again, we need to be watching that space and do things to adapt ourselves and make changes to our business model as we go along.</p>
          <p>So these are probably the three or four things that we need to watch out for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One last quick question. Europe did very well. Have you seen a full recovery there? Or is that still a late cycle? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that there's anything called a full recovery. As I said, the sentence that 'we are being watchful of the macroeconomic environment' is going to be repeated probably for the foreseeable future. So, they said it in the past and they are going to keep seeing it for the next several quarters because it's not going to be a quick recovery.</p>
          <p>But, having said that, I think the demand set is very, very good and the pipeline is very strong and we are very positive. And, Europe in particular, if I have to comment, I think it has been slow, it lags behind the U.S., I think it will continue to lag behind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Moshe Katri from Cowen &amp; Co. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks. Congratulations on a very strong quarter. Chandra, can you talk a bit about some of the underlying drivers for the demand per some of the larger verticals at TCS? And then also maybe you can talk a bit about the pricing dynamics and whether we're going to start seeing any improvements in pricing down the road? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, you know, as I said, we've seen the recovery coming over the last few quarters steadily and we saw the recovery in the financial services and that leading the growth. And, last quarter, where we delivered very good numbers, we said that the growth is more well-rounded but, I think this quarter is probably the real perfect quarter in terms of well-rounded growth because every singly industry segment has grown double-digit. And, the &#x2013; initially the broad things is what I explained, we are seeing both the efficiency-related and discussion-related.</p>
          <p>If you talk about the financial services industry, it will be like getting a single customer view, getting the customer insights, whereas if I talk about a manufacturing industry, it will be more about getting a single-instance ERP or doing a transformation by bringing ERP systems and the shop floor systems together. And, if I look at retail, there are a lot of optimization initiatives; inventory optimization, pricing optimization, markdown pricing, sourcing optimization, there are a number of things the retailers are doing. And then, lot of interest in getting consumer insights and then see how to use the latest technologies like social networking. Those things have not kicked-up- kicked-in yet, but those are things that the retailers are talking about.</p>
          <p>Also, there is a broad interest in getting optimization on infrastructure, whether it is consolidating data centers, whether it is optimizing servers, virtualization. So, that is across industries primarily in retail, manufacturing, hi-tech industries. If you take pharma and banking, there is a lot of compliance. There is ICD-10 compliance in pharma, there is Basel-related compliance, a number of compliance-related initiatives in banking and pharmaceutical companies. So, I think the broad theme is efficiency and initiatives for growth, but when you go down to the industry and the individual segments, how it pans out is different. And, I gave you some examples, hopefully that clarifies.</p>
          <p>In terms of pricing environment, I have mentioned in the last call that we will probably see a pricing uptick end of this fiscal. The reason for that is, we were seeing the demand environment improving and growth coming back, and, certainly the volume growth for this quarter has been more than what we would have anticipated about four-five months ago. And so, the recovery has been pretty strong and so, when that happens, I think you should definitely see an uptick in pricing. All of it may not reflect in the immediate quarter even if it &#x2013; the pricing uptick comes in end of the fiscal, it's not going to reflect in Q1 pricing, but it will take a &#x2013; it will have a lag effect but I'm pretty positive that this is going to be around that time that we are going to see some pricing uptick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a final question for Maha. You are exiting this quarter with another record margin level, can you talk a bit about some of the levers that are still in the model and obviously the biggest risk here continues to be currency, that you can kind of go over some of the traditional kind of lever points that you mentioned in the past, and can you give us kind of good feel on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a revenue perspective, the levers that we have obviously volume, which has been delivered, the pricing, as Chandra said, it's not factored into our calculation anywhere, and then, of course, the productivity improvement or something that we are &#x2013; we have pushed quite a lot in this quarter, it has manifested itself through the utilization and that's &#x2013; we will continue to monitor that fairly carefully.</p>
          <p>Exchange is another factor which has worked in our favor in this quarter. Again, a number of <mark type="inaudible" />, as we go to the next quarter, currently rupee is at an appreciated state, so there will be some issues with regard to that. So, if I take the revenue kind of driver that I talked about, there will be, obviously the business momentum is reasonable, I'm not saying that this can be repeated and so on, but there is a reasonable momentum, so that will hopefully be able to give us some sort of advantage.</p>
          <p>The &#x2013; on the cost side, as we have always exercised, we don't want to cut down costs which will hurt us and therefore we are not doing anything with regard to that, but certainly the cost structure that we have could support this kind of revenue, as well as hopefully somewhat higher and therefore cost management, to deliver higher revenues, would always be our priority as we go along. These are essentially the cost drivers and the currency headwind is something that we need to worry about at this point in time, but other than that, I think we are reasonably all right from a cost management perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Maha.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Ashwin Mehta from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi sir, congratulations on a good set of numbers. Two questions. One is, in terms of our cash flow from operations, they, for the first half of this year, seem to be lower than the first half of last year in absolute terms despite our EBIT margins are actually showing a 35% jump? So, if you can just highlight what the reasons for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's essentially &#x2013; the pattern is not a very disturbing one because- mainly because the &#x2013; as far as accounts payable is concerned, it has remained at the same level. We are dealing with the higher accounts receivable at this point in time. And, therefore, you'll see that aberration but the manner in which we monitor that &#x2013; monitor this area is to ensure that our collection comes as close to the billing as possible in a quarter. And, therefore, the accounts receivable is kept at a manageable level. And we have &#x2013; we've been able to do that even with the growth prospect. So, there's no answer that I can give you because when you compare the first half of last year and the first half of this year, there are some differences and, as I said, it's not something that is not &#x2013; it's not a disturbing phenomena.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And secondly, in terms of rental cost of revenue, that seems to have fallen off pretty sharply from almost 146 crores to near 79 crores. What's been the reason for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there is some rationalization that has taken place in this quarter but I &#x2013; I mean &#x2013; and but that is not going to persist going forward. So it will go back to somewhat higher levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a factor of multiple things also that- which projects more to a rented facility, which goes into owned facility, et cetera, there are a number of factors there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just noticed that for the last three quarters it's been in the 140 crore range and it's fallen off to nearly 80 crores in this quarter</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's &#x2013; as I said it would increase beyond what is currently shown in this quarter, and that is not at that state that we want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot sir and congrats again for a good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Edward Caso from Wells Fargo. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my call. Could you help us understand your exposure to the United Kingdom market, particularly the British government?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, we do &#x2013; the total U.K. revenue as a percent of the overall revenue is about 15.5%. 15.3% is overall revenue. And the &#x2013; we have about 3 or 4 contracts in the government sector. One of them is a large contract; all the others are not so large. All those projects are going on intact and there is no risk in any of those projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk a little bit about how you would respond if a legislation appeared in the United States to move towards sort of a 50/50 model or half of your U.S.-based workforce would have to be Americans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, this whole 50/50 bill, we need to see what is the final form it takes. Okay. There is no point in conjecturing what is going to be the final form of the bill. All I can tell you is that we are aware of the bill and we're following it very closely and what form and shape it's going to take is something that we need to watch and based on which we can share at that point in time. It's very difficult to conjecture at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question. Have you seen vendor consolidation over the last 2 or 3 years and are you benefiting from that or are you seeing your clients starting to expand their roster of vendors again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are continuing to see vendor consolidation and we are a significant beneficiary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Mitali Ghosh from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and congratulations on a brilliant quarter. Just wanting to understand the demand trends a little bit more, you've already discussed it on the call, but 2 things, one is in terms of the pace of addition to the pipeline, would you say that that has accelerated throughout the quarter. And secondly, are there any trends to look at in terms of, are there &#x2013; is the demand more for integrated deals and between existing and new customers any kind of trends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mitali, thank you. And in terms of the demand pipeline, I wouldn't say it's accelerating throughout the quarter, but all I would say is that has come to pre-crisis speed. It's very normal and deals are coming, customers are wanting to toast the deals and then move forward, ramp-up et cetera, all those things are happening as we used to do before. That's all I would make about &#x2013; that's the comment I would make. Then with regard to &#x2013; what was second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Integrated deals and any trends between the, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the deals are coming from existing customers, as well as new customers, and it's fairly distributed. And in terms of &#x2013; on smaller companies, we are seeing integrated deals. And in larger companies, we are seeing service based needs, specific service based.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then secondly in terms of the sort of longer-term growth going forward, there's always been an issue with the industry that is this kind of a linear growth sort of sustainable, so maybe if you could just call out some of the investments that you're perhaps making and how the business model might change over the next few years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, I want to make 2 points, Mitali, without sounding too optimistic or guiding you to be extremely bullish. But 2 points, I think on the current base that we have to do volume growth of 11.2% is itself is extremely difficult, credible, you can say whatever word you want to say, because it's a large base and &#x2013; but we've been able to move that. So to that extent, I think as long as you're focused and you're able to work the engine in a very coercive manner and a collaborative manner, I think we see opportunities for growth.</p>
          <p>In terms of the future, I think the <mark type="inaudible" /> initiates have to kick in. We are investing heavily in intellectual property. You are fully aware now kind of investments we have made in the banking sector. We have the most &#x2013; deepest accelerated products portfolio of offerings and intellectual property in the banking space. We have made similar investments in the insurance space and including the Cloud model for the life and pensions, we are making selective investments in the retail, selective investments in the government space, and in the healthcare space. Across the board, we are making investments in building intellectual property.</p>
          <p>We are building BPO platforms and all of them are operational. And we have pilot customers and customers are happy, the model is working, we just need to scale, and it takes time, because it builds a business model change for our customer. It is not something that the customer is doing with somebody and then taking it off or he is doing it himself and you are taking it over. It is a business model change. Whenever there is a business model change for a customer then it takes time.</p>
          <p>The third one is the Cloud offering in the small and medium segment, which again we have launched in &#x2013; we are about to launch in a big way in India. So we are making all those investments, we are making investments in mobility significantly, in predictive analytics, in supply chain, and then just started creating tools in the social networking and social media space. So these are all the areas we are making investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And just finally a quick question to Maha on couple of housekeeping things. One is in terms of the hedge position if you could update us, where that stands and any guidance for tax rate this year and next year and the CapEx spend you are looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the hedge position is concerned, we have very little at this moment in time, it is more of the order of about $500 million or so and this is really on the receivable side. We haven't taken any fresh hedges from the revenue. And so we will see how the situation works, what's our &#x2013; while we have sounded very cautious as far as the exchange rates are concerned, they are all driven by what has happened in the last couple of weeks, but after we see the inflows, extensive inflows of the recent past over, we might even go back to slightly depreciated rupee and therefore we don't really have any hedges that we have taken as far as the revenues are concerned.</p>
          <p>As far as the tax rate is concerned, I made a small error in my earlier one that I said it was 18.95% from the chart, it is 17.3% is the tax rate &#x2013; effective tax rate that we have. And this year, as I have said earlier that it is going to be somewhere between 18, 19%; we think it will play out in that fashion.</p>
          <p>We have had a tax rate of 17.1% last quarter &#x2013; 17.30. So it's somewhere in that range. And next year we will see how that turns out because many of the STP is off. And we'll have to see what kind of issues that arise out of any of the budget provisions. What was the third -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>CapEx, CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CapEx. CapEx, we are on course. We have talked about 2,200 crores. As far as this year is concerned, we are on course with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Vihang Naik from MF Global. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I just had a question. Over two years, we have seen our employee base which is greater than 3 years in experience go from 52% to 61%. I mean what's our view on this and does this remain a significant lever for margins going ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, we would ideally like to increase the bottom of the pyramid. So it is &#x2013; I don't know whether it's a significant lever, it is a lever.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it will be a gradual one. We won't overnight do something, which is detrimental to delivery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I think that overall 61% if you look at from a 3 plus year experience point of view that is also from the point of view of retention of the employees that we do and the significant number of trainees that we add and that we had added couple of years ago which is becoming &#x2013; who are becoming 3 plus years at this point in time. So it's all the factors that is playing into good effect plus the retention schemes that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And over the same period, I mean we've rationalized the SG&amp;A very well. I mean excluding depreciation, it's at around 16.7% of revenues. How do we see this going ahead? I mean will we be able to manage with a constant absolute level SG&amp;A at these levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have talked about all our cost management programs, the direction in which &#x2013; see, the thing is what we can do is to essentially make sure that the percentages are controlled. And in certain areas like travel, software provisional use as well as communication, there will be a certain addition that takes place in the costs. And the other areas we're trying to make sure that it doesn't really go up because the cost structure is already fairly well defined. And we should be able to maintain this at this level.</p>
          <p>So certainly, you have seen that in the recent past, we have kept the absolute amount on the same level. But as I said, there are some costs which will go up, but equally, we will be applying cost management techniques in the other costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Congrats on an excellent quarter once again. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Nitin Padmanabhan from Indiabulls Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, thank you. Congratulations on a great quarter. I think it's difficult to hazard a guess in terms of how much incremental revenues you can add in a quarter. My question is with regard to &#x2013; you mentioned that vendor consolidation have been a reasonable &#x2013; a very significant beneficiary. My sense, with so much growth coming in and we're basically surprising every quarter, how significant has vendor consolidation been in the overall scheme of things. If you could just give some sort of color on that probably?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't give you a percentage, Nitin, but definitely, I can't say that the vendor consolidation has driven the growth. I mean that's not really the point I am making. Whenever in our accounts we have seen vendor consolidation, we have been on the winning side. That's the only point I was making because our presence in our accounts are pretty deep and that helps this and our delivery has been excellent. I think the fundamental thing is that our execution and delivery has been rock solid and that's what is the foundation on which we build everything else. And we'll continue to focus.</p>
          <p>That's why whether it is a pyramid, whether it is utilization, there are questions about utilization. Are you pushing up the utilization to improve the margins? Answer is no. When we say 83.8% is the utilization, it is not that we are keeping the utilization very high to improve the margins. It's primarily to capture the demand and also to execute the projects well. When there is such a surge in demand, and you're hiring lot of trainees, you got to make sure that you put enough experienced people so that the project teams are formed and we execute very well.</p>
          <p>So it's more driven by that particular behavior. And obviously, it does help on the margin side, et cetera. So I don't see the utilization getting overheated or anything like that. So I think the short answer to your question is that it is not vendor consolidation that has driven all the growth. No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And in terms of incremental deals that are out there, is it that we have &#x2013; in terms of the pipeline, let's say, what you would have seen a quarter back before this quarter and what you are seeing today is significantly much more better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to say significant or anything, but it is better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And just one last question, with regard to attrition, would you be of the view that at some point, you would probably have to give a second round of hikes? Would that be a possibility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, see our model has &#x2013; I think &#x2013; wait a minute. See, at this stage we are not considering that as far as this year is concerned. And our model is that we pay based on the company's performance through a variable scheme and that is what we use. And as you know, this quarter we have announced 150% that is 50% additional as far as this particular quarter is concerned. And in the last quarter, we had given 100%. And in Q4, we had actually given 125%. And last year in three quarters, we had given additional variables, 50%, 50%, and 25%. So that's the model that we are using at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our payment will be based on the company performance. And while we are committed it's 100% and we will continue to increase it based on how well we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Sandeep Shah from ICICI Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Just a question on the pricing with the discretionary demand, which is coming back and the growth seen across vertical, maybe the existing planned pricing as you have commented may kick in from the later half of the FY '11, but the new clients are already coming at a higher than the company average?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the answer &#x2013; I tend to say, yes, the amount of revenue from new clients is far significantly lower for us to make any &#x2013; for it to make any impact, in any meaningful impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. But the acceptance in terms of the high rates in the new clients is now not a struggle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. And just on the discretionary spend, would you like to define how it has been different in U.S. versus Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, I think the most of the &#x2013; I mean, most significant of our growth is in the, possibly the revenue is coming from U.S. compared to Europe. And the UK is about 15.3% and Continental Europe is about 9.1% of overall revenue. And I would say that Europe lag behind the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. And Mr. Maha in terms of pricing this quarter, the offshore shift is not so high and we have a discretionary spend on the services, which are also growing and we have a cross currency, but the pricing we have said has been almost like 0.26% down. So what is the reason for the same?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No as I said the pricing is going to be constant you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I add one line on this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually Sandeep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that the one of the factors, which I have been extremely happy with is the fact that we have been able to maintain our offshore leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In a high growth environment. When you see this kind of a growth at that time to maintain the offshore leverage at high levels itself is credible because there is a lot of pressure to stop projects and we have stopped a lot of projects and we have created onsite transitions et cetera, to that extent we have had to move what can solve the existing contracts offshore to maintain the overall offshore leverage. So improvement on this kind of volume growth is probably a little bit unrealistic I feel. And pricing has largely been flat. I don't think there has been any proper advancing as far as the way I would view it is &#x2013; view is that pricing is pretty much flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Anurag Purohit from Alchemy. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, gentleman, and congratulations on a very good quarter. Most of my questions have been answered, but if you could throw some light on how the demand for TCS e-Serve is shaping up especially because last two quarters has been very good for the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, TCS e-Serve continues to do well, and they've got good number of clients and the ramp up is happening. So we are quite bullish about our financial services BPO offering for e-Serve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, in terms of beyond Citigroup, has there been any significant client addition in terms of size?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, there has been a good number of clients outside the Citigroup. In fact the growth is coming from a number of clients outside the Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And one final thing on a data point perspective, this is second quarter that bad debt provisioning has declined. Do you think that further G&amp;A leverage from this aspect is still available?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. This is &#x2013; these are all specific events that take place during a quarter and so on. So certainly it is not appropriate to take this as a sustainable one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you and all the best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The next question is from the line of Rahul Jain from Dolat Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Congrats for the good set of number. I just need to understand with the kind of strong business traction we are witnessing in the last few quarter, how do we see the current momentum different from what we used to see couple of years back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can't give any color on that. I will think about it. Can't give any specific color on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And okay. Just another one. As we've been noticing that we've been scaling quite well on the Gartner's International Retail Core Banking space, there's been a very strong improved positioning over the years, and can you throw some more light as we are seeing a good deal in the European market in that space?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah I think the banking product to the banks has done exceedingly well both in terms of the earnings rankings and also real deal wins and delivery. We are seeing tremendous traction not only for the core banking but also for product like the market infrastructure, custody product, securities, payment solution, insurance product. I think we are seeing very good traction and I think we are very positive about the business opportunity for the banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's it from my side. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Srivathsan from Spark Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Chandra I just wanted to understand if this contract restrictions wherein incumbent MNC players have been there is playing a big role the kind of deals you've been having in the last two quarters as we've just looked at TPI data suggest that lot of the incumbents are losing out especially on deals that they've had historically and Indian vendors seem to be winning, is that a trend you are seeing big in the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I can't specifically comment on that because somebody like TPI will have more data. So I will also depend on the third-party analyst reports because we are there in the deals we are there, but there are many companies with many customers, so we don't have a holistic perspective. So we also depend on the third-party data for that. So I would go by the third-party research reports. We look at multiple reports, but they are the better person to comment on the vendors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, but in terms of TCS dealings is that a fair share of restructured deals that you are winning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sure. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Ashish Chopra from Motilal Oswal Securities Limited. Please go ahead. Mr. Ashish Chopra, your line has been unmuted; please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good evening sir. Sir just had one question in terms of the margins. As you said that the currency would be a major headwind, assuming that the currency stays in the band of 44 to 44.5 in the coming quarters, how is our broad outlook on the margins as compared to the margins made in this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I won't be able to give you the specific answer to that, but certainly margin will reduce. Beyond that the extent of reduction and so on we had earlier said that for every percentage point it will be around &#x2013; somewhere around 40 basis point impact. Some of those calculations are still valid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sir. That's it from my side. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Sandeep Aggarwal from Antique Stock Broking . Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, sir, good evening. Congrats on a very good quarter, excellent quarter. Sir, I have just one question on the India revenues and also I'm seeing that India and Europe is outperforming all other geographies particularly India is doing significantly well and particularly the Cloud thing coming into that, I think what is your view on that I want to just have some more clarity on that side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, the India business has done well this quarter. But in the past several times, I have talked about Indian business where our challenge is primarily the volatility in the India business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wherein we have seen growth in one quarter, then drop in the next quarter et cetera. In the last few quarters I think to some extent, we have seen a steady growth and I would like to wait for few more quarters before I can say that we have the business model by which it's going to be consistently growing. And in terms of Cloud, I think it's in early days. We have launched our offerings, but very early days, and the growth &#x2013; the revenue numbers you're seeing is not from Cloud offerings and that's something that we'll have to wait for some more time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the line of Deepan Kapadia from Proactive Universal Group. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations on the quarter. Geography wise we are expanding in China. What role does China play in the long run and how much difference would it make to our margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, we are very small in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both in revenue and in the head count. Too, too small, for it to today make any difference. I think if it has &#x2013; it's going to be quite a long time before we can talk about material impact on a quarterly revenue basis or a margin basis. So at this point in time, all I would say is that we are keen that we grow there faster. Much, much faster than what we are doing now, and we have a long way to go. So I don't think that we should worry about it now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One more point is, do we feel that utilization and margin's at peak or do we see some more <mark type="inaudible" /> coming in from the next quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the utilization as I said, as long as there is a very strong demand, the pressure on utilization will always be there. We have gone up to 83.8% of utilization in spite of addition of 19,293 people gross. So that basically is because, as I said, when there is a strong demand environment our utilization will always &#x2013; will go up. And I think there is not an effort to push it to 85 or 86 or anything like that; I think we are recruiting and we're trying to be efficient, but we're not trying to push it. On the margin front, I think Maha has given all the comments and we are not able to comment at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen due to time constraints we will take one last question from the line of Pranav Tendulkar from BRICS Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Sir, I wanted to ask about the SG&amp;A details, SG&amp;A costs. The bad debt provisions have been decreasing from Q1 FY '11 and Q2 FY '11 from Q4 FY '10, any reasons for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is &#x2013; this follows a very clear policy in terms of collecting and so on, so there is no pattern or there is nothing unusual about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so will this be reversing in the coming quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, we essentially, you know, it's a question of whether we have over provided earlier in order to take it out now, no, that is not. So I don't think &#x2013; of course we have been &#x2013; if you've seen the pattern, we have been providing and so on and we make always attempts to collect year after we make the provision, because it follows a certain principle. That's about all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sir. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I would now like to hand the floor back to Mr. Kedar Shirali and the management for closing comments. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and in summary, I would like to thank all of you for the confidence in TCS and also for listening to us today in this call. And the results have been very, very good from our point of view, and we see the demand environment picking up quite strong and we are getting all our engines aligned to capture the demand and to respond to the market situation. Those are the final comments I'd like to say and thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen of the management. Thank you, Mr. Shirali. Ladies and gentlemen, on behalf of TCS, that concludes this conference call. Thank you for joining us on the Chorus Call Conferencing service and you may now disconnect you lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>