<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1527330" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2013 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-01-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>37018</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Global Investor Relations">Kedar Shirali</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="CEO, Non-Independent Executive Director &amp; MD">Natarajan Chandrasekaran</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO &amp; Non-Independent Executive Director">Seturaman Mahalingam</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Non-Independent Non-Executive Director">Phiroz Adi Vandrevala</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Global Human Resources">Ajoyendra Mukherjee</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Janney Montgomery Scott LLC">Joseph D. Foresi</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Cowen &amp; Co. LLC">Moshe Katri</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="IIFL Research">Sandeep Muthangi</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Ambit Capital Pvt Ltd.">Ankur Rudra</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="DSP Merrill Lynch Securities Trading Ltd.">Mitali Ghosh</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities India Pvt Ltd.">Diviya Nagarajan</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Equirus Capital Pvt Ltd.">Ravi Menon</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Avendus Securities Pvt Ltd.">Priya Sunder</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="CIMB Securities (India) Pvt Ltd.">Sandeep Shah</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan India Pvt Ltd.">Viju K. George</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Espirito Santo Securities India Pvt Ltd.">Nitin Padmanabhan</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Co. Ltd.">Vinay Rohit</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Edelweiss Securities Ltd.">Sandip K. Agarwal</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Susquehanna Financial Group LLP">Jamie E. Friedman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good day and welcome to the TCS Earnings Conference Call. As a reminder, all participant lines will be in the listen-only mode. There will be an opportunity for you to ask questions at the end of today's presentation. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Please note that this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the conference over to Mr. Kedar Shirali of TCS. Thank you and over to you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marina. Good evening, and welcome, everyone. Thank you for joining us today to discuss TCS' financial results for the third quarter of fiscal year 2013 that ended December 31, 2012. This call is being webcast through our website and an archive including the transcript will be available on the site for the duration of this quarter. The financial statements, results presentation and press releases are also available on our website and have been e-mailed out to those on our mailing list.</p>
          <p>Our leadership team is present on this call to discuss our results. We have with us today, Mr. N. Chandrasekaran, Chief Executive Officer and Managing Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. S. Mahalingam, Chief Financial Officer and Executive Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Phiroz A. Vandrevala, Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And Mr. Ajoy Mukherjee, Head of Global Human Resources.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Chandra and Maha will give a brief overview of the company's performance and that will be followed by a Q&amp;A session. As you are aware, we don't provide specific revenue or earnings guidance. Anything said on this call, which reflects our outlook for the future or which can be construed as a forward-looking statement must be reviewed in conjunction with the risks that the company faces. We have outlined these risks in the second slide of the analyst presentation available on our website.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to turn the call over to Chandra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kedar. And thank you all for joining the call. I'd like to start by saying that we have delivered a very good quarter, another strong performance across all parameters.</p>
          <p>I just want to give a little bit background. As we entered the quarter, typically Q3 is a soft quarter, a weak quarter. And we typically look at two things. One is the lesser number of working days, another one is the furloughs, which has come to be a norm from the manufacturing and the high-tech industry vertical companies.</p>
          <p>And so, our focus was to deliver revenue growth and also focus on operating margin and productivity improvements, primarily because of the anticipated low volume in such a quarter. And during the quarter, we also cautioned that we have had furloughs with more companies, beyond the high-tech industries and manufacturing, especially in the financial services. So, volumes are a little soft.</p>
          <p>In that context, we have delivered an excellent quarter, 2.9% in revenue terms &#x2013; in rupee terms revenue, 3.3% dollar terms. We have seen an operating margin improvement of 51 basis points, which kind of positions nicely for our target for the annual operating margin. And from the net profit perspective, again we have shown a 1.1% increase despite the swing of almost INR160 crores in the forex, negative.</p>
          <p>Then, from the nature of growth, it's been very holistic. We have seen good growth across markets. The U.S., UK, Latin America, India, Asia Pacific, all of these markets have grown. Financial Services has done particularly well. In spite of the furloughs, it has demonstrated very good volume growth. In fact, higher than the company average. And also, Financial Services revenue growth has been very good. And also, we have seen growth in manufacturing sector, retail and consumer product sector, energy and utilities, et cetera.</p>
          <p>Services perspective, we have seen very good traction for GCP and Enterprise Solutions, apart from infrastructure services, and products and our own asset-based solutions.</p>
          <p>So, overall, it has been a very well balanced performance from a growth perspective, from a margin perspective, and also from a distribution perspective, it has been pretty <mark type="ph" /> secular (4:58).</p>
          <p>And the customer metrics is particularly good. We have added clients across all the revenue bands. The $100 million has gone up by two, $50 million has gone up by two, $20 million has gone up by six and a lot of additions in the $1 million, $5 million, $10 million customer segments as well.</p>
          <p>And the deal wins have been very good. Our order book has been solid this quarter; though we don't publish that number, it has been pretty solid, and we have signed at least seven large deals. And also in terms of the pipeline, it is pretty robust. We have not received any cautionary statement from any of our clients or we have not picked up anything from the market in any of the industries or markets in which we operate.</p>
          <p>Employee adds have been solid, over 17,200 at a gross level and 9,500 at the net level. And overall company is at 263,000 plus associates. And we have already come close to 50,000 associates, which was the annual target. And we should be adding at least another 10,000 in the next quarter.</p>
          <p>From our point of view, while our push for non-linear revenues continue and we are seeing traction, we are winning our share of wins in the non-linear space, to establish our reach of our products and platforms, the traditional model continues to be solid and we are continuing to invest in growing the business. The pipeline is healthy and we remain positive about Q4 as well as about FY 2014.</p>
          <p>Those are the comments that I would like to make. And with those comments, I'd like to pass on to Maha for his points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, Chandra. I will re-emphasize some of the figures. Our third quarter revenue of INR 160.7 billion represents a growth of 2.9% quarter-on-quarter and 21.7% year-on-year. Revenue in dollar terms is $2.948 billion, which is a sequential growth of 3.3% and year-on-year growth of 14%. In constant currency, the revenue is $2.9286 billion, a sequential growth of 2.65%.</p>
          <p>Let me now give you the breakup of our sequential INR growth of 2.9%. Volume growth was plus 1.25%. Constant currency realization was plus 1.3%. Currency impact was plus 24 basis points. Onsite effort shift was 9 basis points plus. Our focus on cost management this quarter kept most expenses around the same level of absolute terms or lower as in the last quarter. As a consequence, our EBIT margin expanded 51 basis points to 27.3%.</p>
          <p>I'll give you the breakup of that margin expansion. Currency impact was plus 3 basis points. Productivity improvement was plus 82 basis points. SG&amp;A expenses was minus 50 basis points. Offshore shift of revenue was plus 16 basis points and that has resulted in 51 basis points plus.</p>
          <p>Other income as a percentage of revenue was 1.33% compared to 1.99% in the previous quarter, the difference being on account of forex losses from marking to market the option premium. The effective tax rate was 21.8% compared to 21% in the previous quarter. Lower other income and higher provision for taxes negated the operating margin expansion and led to a net income margin of 22.1%, down 38 basis points quarter-on-quarter. Our accounts receivable stood at 79 DSO in dollar terms, down 2 days from the previous quarter. Invested funds as of December 31 was INR 131.7 billion.</p>
          <p>To conclude, by focusing on cost management and disciplined execution, we not only overcame the margin headwinds of a seasonally weak quarter but even expanded the operating margin beyond 27% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>With that we can open the lines for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, sir. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Joseph Foresi from Janney Montgomery Scott. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. My first question here is, you talked about the pipeline as robust and no major issues. Can you give us some idea of then what you're thinking about 2013? I know you don't give any guidance on that, but does this seem like you could be faster or slower than 2012 just from a positioning heading into the year? And then how can you &#x2013; can you help us reconcile that with December quarter results? Is that just simply seasonality?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have said in the last call and we can either maintain that, what we see the momentum, as we leave December 2012 is better than the December 2011. So, we expect 2013, for us 2013-2014 to be a better year than 2012-2013. It's just that we will &#x2013; we are starting on a much better momentum and sentiment from the market point of view, from the customers' point of view.</p>
          <p>More importantly, there is clarity around what customers want to do. It is not about &#x2013; it's not only about what the budget is. It's about where do they want to spend the money that they want to spend, and do they have clarity around the initiatives or the making decisions, or do think ramp up. So, in all those parameters, I think we are in a much, much better position this year than last year because there's lot more clarity in the minds of customers in what they want to do, whether it is driving efficiency or adopting digital technologies or front-office transformation, what have you?</p>
          <p>So, I think, let me put it differently, the quarter has been from a growth point of view, from the volumes point of view, from the way the different industries and segments, they're behaved and there has been no major surprises apart from the one which we highlighted, which has been extra furlough that we had to face and which we communicated to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just &#x2013; maybe if you could talk a little bit about the market conditions from a competitive standpoint heading into 2013. Have you seen any shifts in competition, anything on the pricing side and what are you focused on? What is going to be the major key for 2013 from a competitive standpoint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think from our point of view, we have said that it is &#x2013; it's a different environment we are operating in. Customer-centricity is key and as much as it will look like a clich&#xE9;, I think we continue to ask ourselves how we can be more relevant every single day, and with every single market, industry and customers we work with, our focus, our team's focus have been to stay relevant and partner and co-creating, because partly the whole discretionary spend is in the area of digital.</p>
          <p>Apart from risks and compliance and regulations, et cetera, there is a significant spend towards digital, whether you call it analytics, Big Data or front-office transformation, customer experience. It's called by different names, but the point is that there is a discretionary spend that's happening and that we need to invest and we need to partner and we need to exhibit that leadership and that's an area where we are focusing.</p>
          <p>And from the efficiency side, we are focusing on service management. Customers are demanding service management, not simple transformation of infrastructure or transformation of application management. Service management is becoming very critical where we are able to take Indian perspective from the customers' view in their existing footprints, so that's an area where we are focused on, apart from all the other usual opportunities <mark type="ph" /> that are in (14:20) assurance, infrastructure or everywhere else. And these are showing up in our pipelines and we're investing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Last quick question from me, how do you think about your margin profile going forward? I mean, what is the thought between the balance of revenue growth and margins and, given the fact that commoditization is happening probably at a relatively decent clip, what is a good margin profile? Obviously, I'm not looking for guidance there but just &#x2013; can you explain the balance there and what you're thinking on the margins over the long-term? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We, of course, have always been saying that &#x2013; traditionally, we want to be somewhere around the 27%. That is based on certain cost structure that we had <mark type="ph" /> evolved (15:04). But one critical thing, one important thing that I want to mention is that while we talk about margins, it's not at the cost of either expanding geographically, because we are expanding geographically, we are investing or in terms of doing a lot of internal work to develop capabilities in the newer areas that &#x2013; in the areas of the one that Chandra articulated just now.</p>
          <p>So we believe that what this would require is continuous improvement in productivity. That is definitely an important one. And that improvement in productivity has to pay for the newer forays that we are making, whether it is in terms of service lines. We have talked about different service lines and so on. Or in terms of the non-linear initiatives that we will be &#x2013; we have &#x2013; we are on the way to growth and so on, and also in geographical expansion.</p>
          <p>So, we believe we can maintain this balance. We're a very large organization now with very mature kinds of businesses in many of the mature geographies and mature industries and so on. And, I think this is one &#x2013; this is certainly the way that we are looking at without constraining the growth parameters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Moshe Katri from Cowen &amp; Company. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks and good evening. Continental Europe had a sequential decline during the quarter. Maybe you can talk a bit about that and maybe talk about the outlook for Continental Europe? And then, Financial Services continues to outperform, maybe we can talk a bit about some of the drivers and is that kind of a sustainable, kind of, I would say, trend down the road? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in this quarter, if you really look at our growth, we had two soft points: one is Continental Europe, the other one is telecom. And so, both are linked as well to a large extent because we've had some projects finishing and some phases finishing last quarter, and we have an uptick in couple of telco clients. And, while they have not really fallen in terms of scope of work or in terms of volumes, and the extra pop that we got last quarter is not repeating. And enough growth was not there with the size and scale that we have in rest of the markets in Europe. And, that's why you have seen a softer performance in telco and Continental Europe this quarter. Nothing fundamentally wrong. Our deal pipeline is good and we are still maintaining. As I said, Europe will have a better year next year. In fact, I won't be surprised if Europe grows faster than many other markets in which we operate. So, I'm positive about Europe.</p>
          <p>From a BFSI perspective, I think there is enough to be done. I think the customers on BFSI are going through a lot of changes, yes. But having said that, technology is going to play a very important role in the financial services sector. So that's what we are seeing. It's not about whether the financial services sector is restructuring itself or rebaselining their cost structure. Yes, different financial institutions, banks in particular are going through different type of situations, but, in all those situations, at least in our client-base, technology has a very important role. And, we are seeing that in our discussions. We are seeing that in our pipeline.</p>
          <p>As I said, in spite of unexpected furloughs in Financial Services, we delivered good growth in Financial Services this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just final question, 31 new client additions during the quarter. Is there a way to break it down by regions and maybe by some of the large verticals for the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I don't have it offhand, but we don't give this information. I don't want to start a new metric. But having said that, I'll tell you, if you see the large deal, it has come largely from &#x2013; we reported seven, two from banking, one each from telecom, transportation, logistics, government, retail, and healthcare. And, from a market...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And by region, is there anything substantial? Sorry. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Region. By region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, by region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>By region, I think U.S. still dominated. Four deals came from the U.S. and one each from Asia Pacific, Latin America and Europe. And if you look at our pipeline, as I said, the order book has been good this quarter, and pipeline wise, fairly well distributed across industries and markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Sandeep Muthangi from IIFL. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking my questions. Good quarter, thank you. Chandra, I have a question on the BFSI. You highlighted that BFSI had challenges in the quarter, despite that the growth was quite good. Can you give us more insight into what happened? What kind of projects were there during the quarter or any specific things that were looking really good?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think &#x2013; as I said, there has not been a pullback in BFSI in particular, except budgetary issues for the year, and furloughs were declared on a couple of clients. And that did affect the volume growth. And again, those furloughs even ended around the 20th of December. So they have started &#x2013; so they had to go through a budgetary cycle and they declared and apart from that, there has been no surprise in BFSI. It's been good for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No special project, one-off projects or anything that has come. It again falls into the same categories that I've been articulating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. And also, in terms of the positioning for the next year, you've been highlighting that 2013, you expect that to be a better year than 2012. Anything else that you can highlight in terms of industries, which industries do you expect to do better and which might do worse off as compared to 2012? Or is it primarily driven by Europe being much better than 2012, I mean, on what your expectations are based on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think, we expect BFSI to do well. We expect retail and consumer goods to do well. We &#x2013; see telecom is our &#x2013; telecom communication, basically, has been soft and we still feel that it's pretty volatile, and we are still &#x2013; while we are growing in some quarters, still we don't feel that we have stability in terms of where we can see a consistent growth. So, telecom is the concern from a industry point of view. From market point of view, I think we are expecting to grow in all markets. I think U.S. is going to be good. Latin America is good. And our Latin America market is pretty stable and it's not only delivering growth, it's also delivering good margins. And we hope that the scale that we attained in India is large enough that we can reduce the volatility. One of the things that we used to suffer from is the volatility in India business.</p>
          <p>We've been pretty &#x2013; we have been working pretty hard on it in terms of having the right mix, picking the right deals and so on. So, I think the volatility in India &#x2013; see, it's not only about growth. It's about ensuring that you are not having the yo-yo. And that has been the case in some markets and we have worked hard on avoiding that. And I think that should pay off. So, it's going to be a balanced, well-distributed growth across markets and industries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Viju George from JPMorgan. Please go ahead. I'm sorry, the line seems to be disconnected. We'll move on to the next question.</p>
          <p>The next question is from Ankur Rudra from Ambit Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. Congratulations on a nice quarter. I was just wondering, given the strong performance in consulting enterprise solutions from you and one of your peers recently, after strong license growth numbers from SAP and Oracle, does this indicate maybe a better environment for discretionary spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ankur, I have been saying for the last few months that the discretionary spend is picking up. And clarity with clients in terms of what they want is very visible and we are not seeing delays. So, I think, it's a question of which clients want to spend where. It will not be uniform. Efficiency is the name of the game for everyone, digital is the name of the game for most people, but from an enterprise solutions point of view, it will be selective in some customers where they are going to spend, but they're making decisions and things are moving. So overall &#x2013; see this is another reason why 2013 will be a better year than 2012. In 2012, the discretionary spend for a vast majority of the year was just not there, or people were watching and I think &#x2013; I don't know how much money will be allocated. I can't be really certain about it, but it will be spent. No delays in decision making, no wait and watch game.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean in terms of the nature of work you're getting, should I understand it's equally spread between the traditional ERP implementations and new technology areas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot on digital definitely and when you say ERP implementation, it may not be a simple <mark type="ph" /> EC6 (25:38) kind of or a simple Oracle implementations. There are lot of implementations related to whether it is a supply chain, whether it is a CRM on a Salesforce.com. So there are varied kinds of deals that are happening in different products. It's not restricted to one or two products, multiple products. And big-data analytics is picking up momentum. And definitely, there are opportunities in the mobile space, which are short cycle projects, but good volumes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Maybe just on the cost now, we saw a rise in sales cost this quarter which was slightly unexpected. Are you hiring sales team aggressively in light of improving demand conditions? And if you could just add some color where are you doing that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You see, we have a certain margin goals which we are meeting, and we are continuing to &#x2013; see we're not investing for the sake of investment, but we are definitely continuing &#x2013; this is a continuous journey, we will always try and invest. We're investing in platforms significantly. We're investing in sales definitely and sometimes related to a new offering, sometimes related to a new industry. But nothing I can mention that's going to stand out or anything like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just finally on the fourth quarter, I know you won't give a guidance, but any particular volume headwind we should be aware of, like lower working days?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. As far as &#x2013; there are no headwinds at this moment in time as far as Q4 is concerned. We've been maintaining that as far as next year is concerned, it's going to be a good year, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think Q4 in terms of working days I think onsite is more or less flat. Offshore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Onsite is down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Onsite is one day down I think and offshore is almost flat or one day higher or something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Thank you, best of luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should not be an aberration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Mitali Ghosh from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks and congratulations on a very tight execution during the quarter. Mr. Chandra, I just wanted to reconcile the commentary on the better business momentum, which you know is also reflected in your upping the hiring target. And how we should interpret &#x2013; so it's reconciling the business momentum with the deal wins that you typically announce and I understand you don't necessarily announce all the large deal wins. So, how should we interpret the fact that the deal wins that you do announce are somewhat &#x2013; had been somewhat lower in 2012 as compared to 2011 with the better business momentum? So, is it reflected perhaps more in increasing discretionary spend and therefore perhaps smaller project sizes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are multiple things, Mitali. One is that just the deal wins alone doesn't translate. As you rightly said, we kind of announce at least a certain number of deals. We don't announce all the deals then because you got to put &#x2013; then you can keep on announcing more things. But we don't announce renewals, for example. So we're pretty selective in what we announce.</p>
          <p>But having said that, there are number of parameters that you need to look at. First of all, the customer migration. So it's &#x2013; sometimes a deal win gets an entry into the customer. After that, you are coming to migrate that account very beautifully. And that shows the momentum for us and how much of volume that we are going in that account, it will not reflect in any deal win. You do see it in the customer migrations. And also the size of the deal, sometimes you do large deals and if we say everything is above $50 million, above $100 million. Sometimes it's $100 million, sometimes it's $500 million, sometimes even more than that. So, it's pretty difficult to just come to a conclusion based on the number of deal wins.</p>
          <p>Deal wins is something that we share with you to tell you that decisions are getting made and what are the profile of deals that are happening, which market it is happening, which industries in which it is happening and that is the intent of sharing it with you.</p>
          <p>I think the reason I say there is a good momentum is definitely customer migration is happening. Our order book is pretty good and even this quarter, the total accumulated order book that we have is excellent. And that has come from both the existing customers and new customers. And pipeline of deals that we are chasing and the size of those deals are pretty solid. And customers have clarity about where they want to spend their money on and they are executing as per plan. And discretionary spending situation is much, much better as we entered January 2013 as opposed to January 2012. I think these are the qualitative comments I can give you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I think that's very helpful. So, basically on the fourth quarter then, like you mentioned, it's perhaps so far started off well. And broadly, therefore, one should expect like a steady quarter from a revenue kind of perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just one question on fourth quarter margins. Again, just one question that despite very huge hiring in the December quarter, utilization has been kind of flat. So, is there a likelihood that utilization could drop in the next quarter because of perhaps hiring towards the end of the quarter and therefore, are there any margin headwinds that we should watch out for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think, from an execution point of view, there are so many things that have been &#x2013; that have come together very well in Q3 in spite of such a low volume growth, compared to Q1, Q2, Q3. Q1 and &#x2013; Q4, Q1 and Q2, this Q3 was lower volume growth. In spite of that, our utilization excluding trainees went up by 10 basis points. So, it's been very well executed from a HR point of view. Even if you look at the cash flows, I think it's been a fantastic execution. I think it's &#x2013; as a positive revenue, it's all time high.</p>
          <p>So I think execution point of view, whether it is productivity, whether it is financial management in terms of cash flows and other operating parameters, or utilization in terms of HR, I think we have a very, very solid engine that's kind of focusing on all these parameters. So I don't think that there should be &#x2013; see Maha has said it multiple times, what our exit rate of margin for the year that we were looking at, around 27%. And I think we stick to that. And since we knew that Q3 is a tough quarter from a &#x2013; or a weak quarter on volume perspective, we did make our efforts on operating margin productivity and that has paid off.</p>
          <p>So, I think we are on a much better wicket with the kind of operating margin that we have produced in Q3 to deliver the margins for the year in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Diviya Nagarajan from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my question. Just trying to reconcile the improvement that we're seeing in discretionary spending, especially on the consulting and enterprise solutions side, but what we are seeing with some of your global peers who seem to be seeing a deceleration in this space. Do you think this is a market share shift going on that we've been waiting for for several years or what do you think is happening here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not extrapolating, interpolating any of those. I think there is a very good traction around a number of areas in consulting, a lot on digital space, whether it is in analytics, whether it is in supply chain, whether it is in mobility. And also, in terms of transformation of enterprise solutions, consulting around domain services like &#x2013; if you take a retail or in CPG, inventory optimization, those kind of deals are coming, and regulatory compliance and risk-related deals are coming. So, there are &#x2013; there is a well-rounded growth in consulting services, both domain intensive and also deals like the front office transformation, so there are lots of opportunities.</p>
          <p>And also you should see it as a thing that is happening as a result of the sustained investments that we have done, it's not a overnight thing. We have always said that when &#x2013; three, four years ago, I remember calls in which, when will you have GCP pick up, et cetera. And the nature of the business is that it's not something that you can do overnight. It's not a question of hiring 500 people. It's a question of hiring people, it's a question of building talent, it's a question of integration, et cetera. So, I think, we are steadily making progress, but we still have a long way to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And could you also give us some color on the kind of discretionary spending that you expect to see across your major verticals? What would essentially be the key areas that are driving that discretionary spend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought I just listed it, Diviya.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. If you could just give us some color across your key verticals, which is banking and financial services and manufacturing. Any specific triggers that you're seeing other than the general trends of cost optimization, efficiency that we've seen in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, see, cost optimization, efficiency, service management is a theme across the board, risk regulatory compliance definitely in financial services and digital is across the board, both in consumer business and industrial businesses there are lots of opportunities. When I say, digital, it's all the new technologies, whether it is cloud, whether it is multichannel, including social media and front-office transformation, Big Data analytics, all those technologies, and the interplay of these technologies, all of these are opportunities that we are seeing, both in consumer business and industry business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. And Maha, just wanted to check what are the levers that you can &#x2013; that you think that you can pull to keep your margin to 27% for the rest of 2013? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We are essentially doing all that we have been saying. You see the first one I would like you to note is, as far as this quarter is concerned is that there has been productivity improvement. Ultimately for realizing higher revenue, the number of people that we have deployed has been somewhat less. So, that is the &#x2013; really, the ultimate definition of productivity improvement that has come in. And therefore, going forward, I think that that will get to exercise a lot more. You will continue to see this kind of productivity improvement.</p>
          <p>The second one is that the cost management, I've always said that we have created capacity. And therefore, we should be able to run with the same absolute numbers for higher growth. And that is another one that we would do. And we are not factoring in at this moment in time any change in the onsite/offshore mix because we are running at a fairly efficient mix there. We are not factoring into account any pricing improvement in terms of renegotiation and so on. And if those things happen, then obviously, there will be an additional lever. So there are enough kind of capabilities with the company to be able to maintain the margins, if not improve it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and have a great year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Ravi Menon from Equirus Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir, congrats on a great quarter. Just wanted to do a housekeeping item, the number of trainees that are being made offers to over the year at about &#x2013; I think about 24,000 or so have joined, right? Do you how many more are expected to join over the next quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The total number of trainees that we had offered was 43,000. Out of that Q2, Q1, a few joined and Q2, Q3 are the majority of the trainees have joined. Q4, we are expecting somewhere around 10,000 to come in. 9,800-10,000, somewhere in that range. As far as next year is concerned, the 24,000 number that you have is the number of offers that we have given to the trainees to join us next financial year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is 24,000. And we said that we'll be giving about 25,000 offers, and I'll be closing that by January. So, we should be completing our campus hires.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So then, it looks like you're relying a lot more on lateral hires next year though. I mean, is there a particular reason for that or is that because of a <mark type="ph" /> deal change (39:50)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's not the way to look at it. There are two or three factors playing out. I think first is that our base is pretty large now. And we still have opportunities growing the relationship. I think the percentage doesn't tell the story. Today, we are a 263,000-employee company and we will be 273,000 and 300,000 pretty soon. And so, we got to look at higher levels of utilization. That's one thing.</p>
          <p>Second thing is the kind of engagements we are doing, both on fixed price, engagements on the consulting, as the engagements require higher level of productivity. That's one of the driver.</p>
          <p>So we are doing it in a little bit calibrated way. That's the whole point. And our attrition has come down from peak levels of 13% to 9.8% in IT; and 11.2%, we had, in the last 24 quarters, the best retention metrics this quarter.</p>
          <p>So, I think there are several plays that are going on, so we need to do it in a very calibrated way. And also, there are markets, some markets in which we will take a differential view in terms of how we want to recruit, depending upon the pipeline that we generate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That's appreciated. And congratulations on a great quarter once again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Priya Sunder from Avendus Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, thanks, congrats on a great quarter. I wanted to ask about the subcontracting cost. This has consistently been going up over the last many quarters. Wanted to understand what are the specific areas where you're actually hiring more of these consultants. And going forward, what would be the outlook or what will be the trend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the subcontracting cost is going up, that is, there are a few reasons for that. One is primarily from the point of view of protectionism and things like that, so visa availability and &#x2013; so that is the one where &#x2013; in order to fulfill, it's one reason.</p>
          <p>And the second one is in terms of the kind of projects that you have, you will go for subcontracting where &#x2013; this is for a temporary nature where you &#x2013; these things won't last for too long. So those are the ones where you will have subcontractors. So, these are &#x2013; and for niche skills as well. So, it is just from that point of view that subcontractors &#x2013; the number and the cost as a result of that will be higher, or has been higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, what are your tax rate assumptions going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The tax rates will remain more or less at the same levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we are seeing at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, yes. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Sandeep Shah from CIMB. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir, congrats on good set of numbers. Sir, just one thing, the employee cost within the cost of revenue line has more or less remained flattish despite adding 10,000 net employees in each of the quarter &#x2013; of this quarter as well as last quarter. I do agree that the employee cost within the SG&amp;A line has gone up, so some of the trainee cost or the bench cost might have been reflected in the SG&amp;A line. However, the proportion of the lateral employee addition continues to remain at 50% to 55%. So what explains this, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the main thing is that you've explained that we put the trainee and the bench cost, everything in SG&amp;A. We don't put it in COR. And what it really reflects is the productivity improvement, efficiency in terms of utilization of people. And therefore, that is the reason why you have seen the kind of percentages that you've mentioned in COR. We are &#x2013; there is an increase in the SG&amp;A employee cost, and that really means that we are positioned to &#x2013; we have enough capacity to meet with additional requirements as we go along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Yes, Maha, what I meant to say is the lateral as a percentage to the gross addition has not been really low. It has been &#x2013; remained at 50%, 55%. That's why I was asking this because I &#x2013; according to me, I think lateral employee cost might have been sitting within the cost of revenue line rather than the SG&amp;A line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lateral is not 50%-55%. If you look at the India hire this quarter, this &#x2013; almost 66% are trainees. The remaining 34% are laterals. Even in the previous quarter, number of trainees were higher, percentage-wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And second, just in terms of the BFSI, Chandra, can you explain us the demand environment in the traditional outsourcing business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think BFSI sector, definitely the institutions are looking to restructure the &#x2013; or re-base, plan the cost structure. So definitely, efficiency is a theme across the board apart from all the other initiatives. So, there is a demand from an efficiency perspective and we are seeing it in the banks. And we're also seeing it in the insurance companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just last thing, in terms of the discretionary projects, you are saying that things are a little bit improving. So, is it fair to say that clients are now little less hesitant in terms of the future macro issues and they are more, you can say, open in terms of releasing the spend, starting the projects and ending the projects versus what it used to be two to three months back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that things have changed two to three months back and I would say that things have changed compared to last year. And basically, the point is, customers understand the macro is what it is and it's going to be a steady, slow recovery that's happening in different parts of the world.</p>
          <p>So, from their point of view, in order to achieve whatever objectives they have, technology is very key and they recognize that. And so, what they want to spend on technology, there is a very clear clarity. And it's just getting executed very well across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. And, Chandra, just one of your competitors said that the pipeline from the Continental Europe is really robust even on a traditional outsourcing. So, do we also believe that besides the organic growth, inorganic growth could be the right solution for driving growth within the Continental Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you always have to do a combination, but Continental Europe has been good for us also. And the base is small. See, Europe is &#x2013; well, you can say Continental Europe is just not one market. Each market behaves differently. France is different from Germany. Germany is different from Benelux and Nordic. So, each of these markets are different. And so, we need to &#x2013; we needed to take calls from each of these markets separately because we can't see Continental Europe as just one market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Thanks and all the best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Viju George from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Congratulations to management on a good performance. I just wanted to understand the furloughs aspect a bit. It seems that on a &#x2013; you're seeing furloughs now extend to other sectors as well beyond traditionally telecom and high-tech, et cetera. Why is this happening and is there any correlation between the sector sort of clients who employ furloughs and their spending for the coming year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Viju, we have not said anything new other than what we have said when we met for mid-quarter briefing. Basically this year, apart from the high-tech industries and the manufacturing, we also saw furloughs in the Financial Services with specific clients. And this, we communicated and that is &#x2013; it's one-off in December that has no bearing on the spend for next year as we can see because these clients have started operating, and the projects have started from December 20 even in most cases. So, there is no correlation with the spend for next year. And I can't tell you what will be the situation next December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you, and all the best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Nitin Padmanabhan from Espirito Santo. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...my questions. I just wanted to understand, in terms of &#x2013; one is in terms of pricing. During this quarter, was it entirely portfolio-led? And what part of the portfolio? That's one.</p>
          <p>And two, I think, Maha, you mentioned that you expect realizations to improve going forward. Just wanted to understand would that be &#x2013; does that mean that you see higher discretionary spends more through consulting, SI and at the asset level solution and, thereby, you see higher pricing? How do we read that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me answer the second question. As I did &#x2013; what I said was that the productivity improvement should be &#x2013; should continue because that has been the kind of thrust that we have.</p>
          <p>One of the questions that keep getting asked of us is that next year you are recruiting only lower number of people. And therefore, are you going to &#x2013; I mean, are you planning for lower capacity &#x2013; I mean, lower increase and so on? So, we are not saying that. All that we are saying at this moment in time is that there is enough productivity levers within the organization to be able to crank up, especially given that our size is very large.</p>
          <p>Chandra just mentioned that he is also questioning as to why the utilization rates cannot go up. We are essentially dealing with large organizations. And we &#x2013; it's also essential for us to keep looking at productivity improvements and so on. And that's where I was coming from, that there is still some more room that we will attempt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So, but would that mean &#x2013; this quarter, I think, has seen fixed-price projects go up by 50 basis points. So, does that mean that it's going to be driven by higher fixed price or it's some other measures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It will not be, purely, fixed price...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we also will operate based on what the customers want. This is not something that we decide <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:44), so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, sure. Thank you. And this quarter was totally portfolio-led in terms of the realization increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Could say that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, sure. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Vinay Rohit from ICICI Prudential Life Insurance. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir, I remember during our interaction, it was mentioned that furloughs in some of the BFSI clients was expected. So, was there a negative <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:16) in terms of higher &#x2013; or more furloughs in BFSI or this was as expected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know when was the interaction, but &#x2013; yeah. It was not something &#x2013; what we had said in October was that we don't expect the furloughs to be any different as far as this year is concerned. And thereafter, it &#x2013; and we said that later on we found that there is going to be a slight decrease. That's about all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think the basic point is that though the furloughs are expected this year, there are more clients and also in Financial Services. That's the main point. So, the volumes <mark type="ph" /> were tough (50:59) this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. That's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Dhaval Mehta from Edelweiss. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. This is Sandip from Edelweiss. Only important question which &#x2013; which is based on the utilization side. If you see, we are now at 81.7% and I remember, the comfort level &#x2013; comfort zone of 80% to 83%. But with the kind of trainees which have joined this year and the number of offers made next year, so do you think that we will be at around 83% or you think that it will be more towards 80% in the first half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, it's very difficult to answer today. But we are comfortable to operate at 83%. In fact, as I said, we will want to explore that further. And if utilization has to be at 81% or 80-point-something, that's okay, we can handle that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. That's all from my side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from James Friedman from Susquehanna. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Let me echo the congratulations about the execution. I wanted to ask briefly if you could have some comments &#x2013; share some comments about the competitive environment. How you might characterize it currently relative to the past couple of quarter or years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean it's &#x2013; there's nothing specific that I can say. I think you always find different companies operating with different strategies. And you will always expect in every offering that you have, in every market that you operate, you face two or three competitors. The competitors may vary, but at the end of the day, it is for us to offer our value proposition and win. So it's &#x2013; I don't think that I would like to offer anything specific because it will all be very subjective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I understand that. But perhaps if you could comment as to how rational you see the competitive environment without naming anyone specifically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean you always have rational players and irrational players. So, you see both, and how, in what situation somebody becomes irrational is, you know, very much depends on the situation someone is in. So, I think we believe that we're going to operate in a way that we can maintain the growth, at the same time maintain healthy margins. And it's very important for us to be able to invest and build the business for the future and we've been pretty successful in doing that.</p>
          <p>So, I think &#x2013; but and there's no particular concern that I have, let me put it that way. We do find time to time somebody is being irrational, but that's fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for your observations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, due to time constraints, that was the last question. I now hand the conference over to the management for closing comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I want to once again thank you all for making the time and listening to us in this conference call. As I said, we've been quite happy with the performance. We pretty much executed very well and we knew that it's going to be a soft quarter on volume, but we're quite happy with what we ended in terms of volumes productivity, in terms of operating margin and also in terms of the client wins as well as the client metrics, pipeline, order book. So I think we are exiting Q3 and entering Q4 on 2013, 2014 with a positive frame of mind. Thank you. I'm looking forward to speaking with you three months from now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, members of the management team. Ladies and gentlemen, on behalf of TCS, that concludes this conference call. Thank you for joining us and you may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>