<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1148145" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1400</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Tim Thompson, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ed Clark, President and Chief Executive Officer, TD Bank Financial Group</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Colleen Johnston, Group Head Finance and Chief Financial Officer, Corporate Office, TD Bank Financial Group</participant>
      <participant id="3">Tim Thompson</participant>
      <participant id="4">Ed Clark</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">&lt;A &gt;</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="7">Rob Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="8">Bob Dorrance</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jim Bantis</participant>
      <participant id="10">Bharat Masrani</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mark Chauvin</participant>
      <participant id="12">Brad Smith</participant>
      <participant id="13">Colleen Johnston</participant>
      <participant id="14">Mario Mendonca</participant>
      <participant id="15">Andre-Philippe Hardy</participant>
      <participant id="16">Tim Hockey</participant>
      <participant id="17">Sumit Malhotra</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="corprep">&lt;Q &gt;</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. My name is Tim Thompson and I'm Senior Vice President of Investor Relations <mark type="audio gap" /> presentation with strategic remarks from Ed Clark, the Bank's President and CEO, after which Colleen Johnston, the Bank's <mark type="audio gap" /> entertain questions from those present, as well as pre-qualified analysts and investors on the phones. Also present today to answer your questions are Bob Dorrance, Chairman and CEO of TD Securities; Bernie Dorval and Tim Hockey, Co-Chairs of TD Canada Trust; Bill Hatanaka, Chairman and CEO; Bharat Masrani, President and CEO of TD Commerce Bank <mark type="audio gap" /> Financial Group.</p>
          <p>As in the past, we're trying to keep the call to about an hour with Ed and Colleen's remarks taking up about half that time. As well we're asking investors and analysts participating <mark type="audio gap" /> an opportunity to contribute. We certainly encourage you <mark type="audio gap" />. We know that this presentation contains <mark type="audio gap" />. These statements are presented for the purpose of assisting our shareholders and analysts and understanding our, pardon me, <mark type="audio gap" /> in our financial position as at the end <mark type="audio gap" />.</p>
          <p>Certain material factors or assumptions were applied in making these statements. For additional information, we refer you to our Q2 2008 MD&amp;A. This document includes a description of factors that could cause actual results to differ and can be found on our website at td.com.</p>
          <p>Over to Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Tim, and <mark type="audio gap" />. Colleen is going to be up shortly to provide details on how we did in the second quarter of 2008. I'd like to start off by sharing my thoughts on TD's performance and reiterate our outlook for the remainder of this year and into 2009.</p>
          <p>I would characterize this quarter as slightly disappointing, but quite acceptable in the context of what's happening in the markets. As I previously indicated, we see 2008 as a pause year in terms of earnings per share growth. A year where we're likely to have to work hard to reach what were great 2007 earnings per share. Now we could get help from a spring back in earnings from Wholesale and Wealth Management later this year if markets improve.</p>
          <p>In contrast, we believe we'll follow up in 2009 <mark type="audio gap" /> minimum we'll get back to our medium-term <mark type="audio gap" /> 10% per year. <mark type="audio gap" /> significant fact at work in this quarter <mark type="audio gap" /> Three things are happening. <mark type="audio gap" /> is facing the market have resulted in unprecedented spreads between cash assets and derivative markets, and this has been most apparent in our credit trading business.</p>
          <p>Market stress has also reduced activity in our franchise businesses and finally this stress has slowed the realization of security gains in our merchant banking portfolio. Fortunately, our retail businesses in both Canada and the United States, which produce in excess of 90% of our earnings this quarter did quite well. All our retail businesses earned $894 million, <mark type="audio gap" /> mark of 2008, we're at just over <mark type="audio gap" /> billion dollars in retail earnings. We're on track to reach our goal for this year of earning close to <mark type="audio gap" /> businesses with the help of <mark type="audio gap" /> strength of our franchise growing earnings 8%, a very solid performance. And we stayed focused on building for the future <mark type="audio gap" /> more customer-facing employees and at the same time delivering record levels of customer service satisfaction.</p>
          <p>I'm especially pleased with the impressive growth we've seen in business banking, a direct result of the investments we made in this business over the past few years. And as we head into a downturn, we're going to stand by our Commercial Banking customers and focus on growing our franchise. We're seeing some expense growth this quarter as we continue to invest in our businesses and widened the gap over our competitors, but our expense growth will stay inside our growth in revenue. You can expect to see continued reinvestment going forward.</p>
          <p>The one exception to solid retail earnings growth was in our Canadian Wealth Management business, which similar to Wholesale has been impacted <mark type="audio gap" /> markets and to a lesser extent strategically <mark type="audio gap" /> will pay off in the future. <mark type="audio gap" /> we remain positive about the underlying trends we're seeing in Wealth and we're continuing to make investments in this business, investing in our network of client-facing <mark type="audio gap" /> and products to ensure we continue to have growth in the future.</p>
          <p>As we announced earlier, TD Banknorth contributed $130 million to our second quarter. Another good performance in light of the continued deterioration in the overall U.S. banking environment. We're feeling very positive <mark type="audio gap" /> Personal and Commercial segment <mark type="audio gap" /> fact that we <mark type="inaudible" /> expectation from sellers to at least 750 million for 2008 and have reiterated our expectation <mark type="audio gap" /> $2 billion in earnings in 2009.</p>
          <p>The close of the Commerce deal is a major milestone for TD. And as I said on our April 21st Investor Call, we're incredibly excited about the progress we're making on integration and we look forward to sharing our plans with you in more detail at our Investor Day on June the 19th in New Jersey.</p>
          <p>As for TD AMERITRADE, they generated solid volumes for building on their long <mark type="audio gap" /> gathering strategy. I like to take <mark type="audio gap" /> Moglia, given the recent news that has moved to <mark type="audio gap" /> Board at TD AMERITRADE. Few <mark type="audio gap" />. He took a company that had a market capitalization of $700 million in 2001 and grew it to over $10 billion today. Earnings per share have grown from $0.32 in 2003 to a forecasted $1.32 in 2008, a phenomenal five-year compound annual growth rate of 35%.</p>
          <p>Joe led TD AMERITRADE to be one of the largest brokerage firms in the United States and the leader in trades per day. He guided the firm through the transformational TD Waterhouse USA acquisition and has led the charge in his <mark type="audio gap" /> gatherer. We are absolutely delighted Joe is staying on. He's going to be an incredibly strong <mark type="audio gap" /> be there to offer wisdom and strategic guidance <mark type="audio gap" />.</p>
          <p>So what is the outlook? Let me start with an overview how I see the financial market is evolving given what's happened. I need a drink of water before I get into this. As banks have become more transparent in their holdings, taken write-downs and raise new equity, the issue in the capital market surrounding banks has moved from a concern over banks solvency to a supply demand imbalance in bank funding.</p>
          <p>The dramatic reduction securitizations combined with the re-intermediation of many assets is causing banks around the world to borrow externally at unprecedented levels. Not surprisingly the cost of such borrowing has risen significantly. The shift in the nature of bank funding will not happen instantly. So we should expect strains in the capital markets for some time and continued upward pressure on lending spreads as banks try to pass on the higher funding costs that they are currently absorbing. The same time the worry is shifting to the impact on banks of a slowing world economy and the extent to which bank funding issues will exacerbate the downturn because of a reluctance of banks to lend.</p>
          <p>Concern in the United States has spread from housing losses to credit cards and auto receivables. We are likely dealing with an old-fashioned credit downturn with some risk that the U.S. will suffer a double-dip downturn as a fiscal stimulus effect wears off while the economy absorbs upward pressure on prices. While the industry may have already felt much of the impact in their mark-to-market books, it is probably too optimistic to assume that there will be no more write-downs although it is hoped any remaining write-downs will be smaller in size. It is difficult for investors and analysts to predict wholesale earnings in normal times, but is especially difficult in this environment. The real issue in the industry going forward is the level of sustainable earnings in the wholesale businesses. This may be harder to discern for some time.</p>
          <p>Clearly some business models have been broken. Regulatory pressures will reduce leverage and heightened concern over liquidity will make many financing structures uneconomic. Short-term earnings will likely be even more opaque because some of the write-downs, which the industry has taken, will bleed back into income.</p>
          <p>For the TD Bank, the impact both small, positive and negative will be more muted. Obviously the market's negative impacts have been less severe. The relative size of our Wholesale business is smaller. We've already made the shift to a franchise focus and our reliance on non-deposit funding is dramatically smaller.</p>
          <p>Going forward as a medium term run-rate, after all the noise has quieted down, we see TD Securities as a 15 to 20% ROIC business with sound growth potential. Interestingly since the issues in the market began last August, TD Securities has earned a 17% rate of return on invested capital while absorbing the full impact of the turmoil. This in my view is a truly remarkable performance. We feel very good about continuing to run a wholesale business model that has taken out the tail risk and is focused on supporting our franchise clients. We have the capital and funding to support our client base and we will continue to do so using in fact this opportunity to extend our franchise businesses.</p>
          <p>As for our other businesses, we believe that the effect of the economic slowdown in the United States on Canada will reduce TD Canada's growth rate as we've seen this quarter, but our franchise strength and our strategy to continue to invest in the future will make us a positive outlier. In the United States as you are aware, we planned for a significant step up in loan losses, but we're very comfortable with our earnings projection even in a worsening economic environment. We're still not seeing any deterioration in our credit numbers. I can't see it in the data we have for Canada and I can't see it in the data we have for the United States.</p>
          <p>Let me add a personal note. You would have seen our press release earlier today that I announced that I'm beginning the program to exercise options later this year. I have frankly struggled to find the most shareholder friendly way to do this. Up to now the easiest way was not to exercise options at all, but I am at the point where I have a series of options which are set to expire. So I do need to act.</p>
          <p>It seems the best way to move forward is to give the market lots of notice, remove any market timing element and ensure that I have a continuous strong incentive to grow our share price over the long-term. For this reason I have announced that I will begin exercising 10,000 options per week starting September 30th of this year, as a way of exercising the 650,000 options coming due during 2010.</p>
          <p>I've prescribed that until at least the end of 2009, 40% of the pre-tax gains will be given to charity and 15% will be used to acquire TD stock. I can't resist putting in an advertising plug for Private Giving Foundation. This is a donor-advising endowment created by TD Waterhouse. This entity gives individuals a simple way to separate the timing decision of when they want to exercise options and the giving decision. It is going to work great for me and I would recommend it to anybody who wants to set up a long-term giving program.</p>
          <p>And on that note, I will turn things over to Colleen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ed. Let me take you through the second quarter. Please turn to slide four. Let's start with the quarterly highlights. Total bank adjusted net income was 973 million, down 2% from last year. This translated to adjusted diluted earnings per share of $1.32, down 3% from Q2 of 2007. Total retail earnings were 894 million, up 12% from last year, representing 91% of total earnings. Our Canadian Retail businesses were up 3% versus last year to 697 million for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Net income from our U.S. Retail businesses, TD Banknorth and TD AMERITRADE was 197 million, up 58% from last year. Please note that while we closed the purchase of Commerce Bank on March the 31st, those earnings will not be included in U.S. P&amp;C results until our third quarter.</p>
          <p>Our Wholesale net income of 93 million was down 57% versus a very strong Q2 of 2007. The Corporate segment posted a loss of 14 million on an adjusted basis compared with a loss of 21 million last year. Our Q2 Tier 1 capital ratio was 9.1%.</p>
          <p>On page five, we see reported net income was 852 million or $1.12 per share and adjusted net income was 973 million or $1.32 per share. The difference between reported and adjusted results is due to items of note. Let me touch on two new items of note this quarter.</p>
          <p>First, the restructuring and integration charges related to the Commerce transaction. These charges taken with respect to the Commerce acquisition totaled 30 million or $0.04 per share. Total charges will be 420 million pre-tax, largely incurred by the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>Second, the timing impact relating to the Commerce transaction. You've seen this before. The Commerce deal closed, March 31, 2008 and we issued 83 million shares to close the deal. Because of the one-month reporting lag, we have not included any Commerce earnings this quarter. The timing impact cost us $0.04 a share.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at our businesses starting with Canadian Retail on page seven. We include a basic P&amp;L for our Canadian Retail business, which combines both Canadian P&amp;C and Canadian Wealth results. Combined net income growth was 3% year-over-year. This result reflected solid Canadian P&amp;C results and weaker wealth management results, which I'll get into shortly.</p>
          <p>Turning to page eight, we show results for the Canadian Personal and Commercial Bank, TD Canada Trust. Net income of 582 million was up 8% from Q2 of '07, but down 3% from last quarter.</p>
          <p>On page nine, we show revenues for TDCT of 2.1 billion, up 7% from last year. The increase was due to good volume growth across most banking products and higher fee income. Good volume growth drove the 104 million or 8% year-over-year growth in net interest income. Real estate secured lending volume was up 11%, while Visa cardholder was up 16%. Personal deposits were up 6%. On the business side, business -- small business deposits were up 7%, commercial deposits were up 11% and total business loans were up 14%.</p>
          <p>Other income was up 44 million or 6% year-over-year, driven primarily by growth in personal deposits, credit cards and insurance. For the balance of 2008, we expect to see revenue growth rates around the current level, although volumes are susceptible to an economic downturn. Over time revenue growth will continue to benefit from increasing our leading position in branch hours, new branch openings as well as improved productivity.</p>
          <p>On page 10, we show our net interest margin for the quarter at 2.96%, down nine basis points from last year and two basis points from last quarter. The decrease from Q1 was largely attributable to continued price competition, which offset the impact of improved prime/BA spread. Compared with Q2 of last year, margins compressed due to continued higher funding costs and ongoing deposit competition.</p>
          <p>Going forward, margins will continue to be vulnerable to deposit competition and also a move to shorter-term lower-margin products. We continue to expect a modest decline for the balance of the year.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 11. Provision for credit losses increased 48 million from last year to 191 million and was also up 19 million from last quarter. Personal banking provisions increased 36 million year-over-year primarily due to higher personal lending and credit card volumes. We're seeing signs that some of the earlier actions taken to address credit issues have stabilized losses.</p>
          <p>Continued upward pressure is expected, but in line with underlying volume growth, while any worsening in economic conditions may also contribute to an increase. Business banking provision for credit losses increased 12 million from Q2 of '07. Our business banking provisions remain at historically low levels and are likely to increase in future quarters depending on market conditions. We expect to see an increase in the currently low business banking formations during the second half of 2008.</p>
          <p>Please turn to page 12. Expenses of just under 1.1 billion were up 6% over last year, but flat quarter-over-quarter. At 51.3%, our efficiency ratio improved by 70 basis points compared to last year. The year-over-year increase in expenses was due largely to investments in future growth, new branches and higher staffing costs for longer hours.</p>
          <p>We said last quarter that the 300 basis point gap between revenue and expense growth would be difficult to maintain in this environment. That was true for this quarter and is expected to be true for the balance of the year. Expenses will continue to be closely managed to ensure spending supports long-term earnings growth. The year-over-year expense impact of longer hours investment will decrease in the last quarter of the year.</p>
          <p>On page 13, we've listed our most recent retail market share data. In the past quarter, we gain share in all four categories and you can see we continue to maintain a leadership position holding the number one or number two ranking across most product categories. On a year-over-year basis, personal market share declined. We saw quarter-over-quarter volume and market share growth in personal deposits, as customers were moving to more liquid, shorter-term products in an uncertain market.</p>
          <p>In business banking, we saw an impressive gain in share. Because of our large and stable retail deposit base, we do not face the same funding challenges as our peers. However, we have increased customer rates to defend market share where it makes sense. We will continue to generate profitable deposit growth by delivering our convenience and service model.</p>
          <p>Let's turn to Canadian Wealth Management on page 14, which excludes TD AMERITRADE. The business generated net income of 115 million, down 14% from last year.</p>
          <p>Page 15, total revenue of 558 million was down 6% from last year. Transaction revenue was down primarily due to lower commissions in discount brokerage as a result of pricing changes introduced last year. Volumes in this business were up significantly. Fee related revenue was down year-over-year as declining markets offset gains in assets under management.</p>
          <p>Revenue from the advice channels was down primarily due to lower new issue activity in full-service brokerage, while revenues were up slightly in the Private Client Group and Financial Planning due to higher asset growth. Discount brokerage revenue was down year-over-year. The impact of new clients, higher margin loans and higher trading volumes was more than offset by lower commissions per trade.</p>
          <p>Earnings were down 5% so far this year compared to the first half of 2007, which compares with the 17% earnings growth we saw in the first half of last year, reflecting the challenging market conditions so far in 2008.</p>
          <p>All in, we're pleased with the underlying factors which support these results. We've experienced a large increase in new clients and new assets. The longer-term outlook for Canadian Wealth Management earnings remains positive, though challenges presented by market volatility may continue to impact results in the short-term.</p>
          <p>On page 16, we've included a few performance measures related to our Canadian Wealth Management business. You can see -- as you can see, we've seen growth in both assets and advisors. Our assets under management of 174 billion was up mainly on the addition of new client assets and an increase in mutual fund assets managed for TD AMERITRADE clients.</p>
          <p>Assets under administration totaled 187 million at the end of the quarter. Excluding the impact of market declines, we're pleased with our asset gathering results. With respect to mutual funds AUM, market volatility has continued to drive an industry wide shift from long-term funds to money market funds as retail investors seek lower-risk alternatives.</p>
          <p>Long-term mutual fund AUM is down 900 million in 2008, due to lower growth and a shift in mix, while money market funds have grown 2.3 billion. In total, mutual fund AUMs are up 5% year-over-year to 57 billion.</p>
          <p>For the fourth consecutive year, we are committing to adding 130 net new client-facing advisors with 43 added year-to-date. We continue to see growth in client-facing advisors as our value proposition resonates with both industry veterans and those professionals new to Wealth Management.</p>
          <p>On page 18, we show our U.S. Retail business, which consists of TD Banknorth and TD AMERITRADE, combined net income was up 58% from last year.</p>
          <p>On page 19, we show the contribution made by the U.S. P&amp;C segment to TD Bank Financial Group in both Canadian dollars and U.S. dollars. We discussed estimates of these earnings during our April 21st Commerce acquisition update.</p>
          <p>TD's second quarter U.S. Personal and Commercial Banking segment net income was Canadian 130 million, up 3 million from last quarter's result and up 68 million from Q2 of 2007. Versus the prior year excluding the impact of higher ownership and the impact of the Canadian dollar, the improved bottom line was largely driven by higher operating earnings. I'm not going to go into details on slides 20 through 22, as we addressed them on the acquisition call. As Ed mentioned, we'll be holding an Investor Day on June the 19th in New Jersey highlighting TD Commerce Bank.</p>
          <p>Please turn to page 23. Turning to U.S. Wealth Management, TD AMERITRADE reported second quarter earnings of U.S. 187 million, up 33% versus last year or an EPS of U.S. $0.31 per diluted share. Net revenue of U.S. 623 million and average trades of 312,000, very strong results. Year-over-year revenue increased by 19% to U.S. 623 million. Commission revenues increased 25% due primarily to higher trading volumes and asset-based revenue rose 15% as client assets increased through organic growth. Asset-based revenues now represent 60% of total revenue.</p>
          <p>Average trades per day were up 23% year-over-year, 312,000 versus 254,000. April trades have decreased 3% from March to 297,000 trades per day. Total client assets rose 9% from April 2007 to U.S. 320 billion where spread-based assets increasing 3% to 31 billion.</p>
          <p>TD's investment in AMERITRADE generated net income of Canadian 67 million, a 6% increase from 63 million in the second quarter of last year. The increase was attributable to higher TD AMERITRADE earnings, partially offset by higher TD funding cost allocation to the segment and the stronger Canadian dollar. Quarter-over-quarter earnings decreased 21 million due to weaker TD AMERITRADE earnings.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn our focus to our Wholesale business. On slide 25, we see Wholesale generated net income of 93 million, down 57% from a very strong second quarter in 2007.</p>
          <p>Let's look at details on page 26. Wholesale revenue of 428 million was down 214 million or 33% from last year. Trading revenue was down from a very strong second quarter in 2007. Strength in FX trading benefited from market volatility and strong client flows was more than offset by continued weakness in credit trading, as well as lower interest rate trading revenues. Also revenues in our equity businesses were down versus last year. Our non-trading domestic franchise revenue was down slightly from last year, as lower M&amp;A and new equity issuance fees were partially offset by higher net interest income and debt underwriting fees.</p>
          <p>The mark-to-market on our loan underwriting commitments is included in the interest and credit trading line. The impact of the mark in Q2 was in line with Q1. The main driver for trading losses this quarter was lower revenue from our interest rate derivatives business and continuing but lower losses in our credit trading book. The credit trading losses relate primarily to the divergence in normal pricing relationships in the cash and bond and credit default swap markets.</p>
          <p>The mark-to-market reflects underlying liquidity pressures on assets, rather than underlying credit quality. Let me give you an example. Let's assume we held TD sub-debt and bought credit protection through credit default swaps. Economically this results in minimal exposure to TD credit risk. However, because credit spreads have widened more on the debt than on the CDS, and in this example the difference in spread has increased from approximately 20 basis points to 100 basis points. It results in mark-to-market trading losses.</p>
          <p>Our credit and loan trading businesses have suffered from these types of liquidity related stresses. Security gains in Wholesale were 83 million this quarter. Unrealized gains this quarter declined in both our public equity and merchant banking portfolios. Expenses of 291 million were down on lower variable compensation.</p>
          <p>On an adjusted basis, our Corporate segment posted a net loss of 14 million this quarter, compared to a loss of 21 million last year and 44 million last quarter. This result is slightly better than our target of minus 20 to minus 40 million per quarter. The quarter-over-quarter variance was primarily due to an unfavorable tax item last quarter.</p>
          <p>Please turn to page 29 for some additional comments on our quarterly reporting. We've reported balance sheet growth arising from the Commerce acquisition. In total, we've added 57 billion of assets to our balance sheet as a result of the acquisition. The final page of the supplemental has a schedule showing the Commerce impact on our consolidated balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Our Tier 1 ratio post-Commerce came in at 9.1%, above the range we provided on our April 21st call. We expect our Tier 1 ratio at November 1, 2008 to be 8% subsequent to the upcoming change in TD AMERITRADE's Tier 2 capital deductibility. We remain comfortable with this target and have flexibility to strengthen the ratio. We have capacity to raise non-common capital through innovative Tier 1 and preferred shares of almost 1 billion each. And today we reintroduced the 1% discount on our dividend reinvestment plans.</p>
          <p>Let me comment on our enhanced disclosures this quarter. The significant write-downs faced by many banks around the world have led many to question how they could have been prevented. I have no doubt that enhanced transparency on the risks bank take will play a critical role in promoting efficient capital markets going-forward. The best practices recently set out by the Financial Stability Forum represent an important step forward.</p>
          <p>From a TD perspective, to report the risk disclosure recommendations proposed in the FSF report. In all substantive respects, we've now complied with these best practices.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, our earnings per share declined by 3% year-over-year. Our retail businesses had a very solid quarter and our Wholesale earnings reflect market conditions. Our businesses have good momentum and we are focused on continued execution of their strategies as we progress through 2008, and we're continuing to reinvest in our businesses to ensure that we grow in the future.</p>
          <p>And with that I'll turn it back to Tim for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Colleen. As I mentioned at the beginning of the call we are asking those participating in the question-and-answer portion to ask one question at a time. Before ending the call, I'll ask Ed to offer some final remarks. So let's get started with people here in the room first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You've been marking your commitment to the BC transaction to market since it was made. Could you give us some idea what the impact on earnings would be if that deal fell through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I don't believe that we're willing to disclose on particular assets like that. I appreciate your interest, but the answer is no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question for Tim. In the last two weeks, the mortgage pricing business has certainly gotten quite interesting. We've seen a fair amount of price cuts at the five-year and relatively deep cuts shorter than that. I mean, from your perspective, I mean, it doesn't seem as if this really has been driven entirely by lower funding costs. Is there anything else going on that you would see would cause the kinds of the industry moving as aggressively as it had?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say it's a good example of the constant competition in the market, especially in a what has been a bit of a delayed spring around real estate lending. So that's certainly the case, and it's also illustrating some of the different philosophies and maybe methodologies by which transfer pricing is done at the various different competitions. We were scratching our heads a little bit on some of them, but it's mostly just competition right now in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any attempt at shifting to them or anything like that -- is there any attempt at shifting to them on the loan work that's going on because it did -- I mean it was 34 beeps I think at the five-year and then it seemed to be 75-80 beeps everywhere else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think that's exactly right. There was an attempt by the marketplace to shift away from what is a very popular product being the VIRM type product, variable interest mortgage. But it's very difficult to get customers to select away from their own preference on term. So it has varying effects, but that's what I would say, the forces are at play.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that why you think the spread compression remains during the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that why you think the spread compression remains in the back half. I think Colleen said, she thought spreads would remain tough right through the year. Do you see spreads going down as a result of this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We certainly see the margin on average earning assets drifting down over the remainder of the year. It's generally competition, certainly on the deposit side. And this one took us -- we weren't the first mover on this side, but the market moved a little bit faster and of course we want to be competitive on the -- on our credit products, but yeah there will continue to be heated competition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any questions in the room?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me come back to Michael for one second, I sounded uncharacteristically rude. I wasn't meaning to be rude, but you can appreciate that this is a highly complex situation and how we are positioned is a thing that could be to the detriment of the shareholders if it was publicly known. So I think it's not in the interest of the shareholders to disclose that kind of information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, let's go over to the phone lines. First caller please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>First question comes from Robert Sedran of National Bank Financial. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good afternoon. Bob, when I look at trading revenues for the different banks it would seem that there is a combination of retrenchment or risk reduction and then just general market weakness. Can you talk about those two factors at TD? In other words, how much is market disruption related and how much is the change in the business model? And I guess on a related note, how comfortable are you that when the market does normalize, there hasn't been permanent or at least long-term damage to your trading strategies on the interest-rate in credit side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The impact that we've had on our trading business has been largely related to the markets themselves than the impact of the liquidity squeeze. I think it's fair to say that in markets where you are experiencing reduced liquidity, where possible, it's more prudent to carry lower inventories than it is higher inventories. So to the extent that various trading desk do that, that's in their empowerment to do so. But we have not reduced our overall risk limits as we've gone through this cycle. And -- but it's I think different, vastly different institutions with reduced liquidity will respond accordingly to that. The a -- but structurally we haven't done anything, Robert.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of where there to be a V type rebound in the marketplace, generally speaking, depending what market it is, you usually don't have as much inventory at the bottom as you do towards the top. So we may have given up some real money on the way through on average and that is not a statement on where we are currently in the market in terms of inventories, just more philosophically that there is probably some truth to what you are suggesting that when markets improve, they generally improve into having lesser inventory.</p>
          <p>And the other part of that is that I think as Ed alluded to in his comments; there are some parts of the market even in with improvement that structurally probably won't come back for quite a while. So to the extent that people have been invested in those markets, they don't think those are coming back in that revenue as it's probably foregone for a period of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next caller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jim Bantis of Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. A couple of quick questions. Ed, on your comments with respect to credit quality and particularly focusing on the U.S., it sounds like your gut is telling that things are going to worsen, but you are referring to the data that you don't see in the numbers. And I am wondering if you can just elaborate on that. Is it the macroeconomic data that you are looking at the U.S. that seems mixed or is it the underlying credit that you see at Banknorth and Commerce Bank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Ed here. I'll start off but I think I will hand it over to Bharat, who is a better risk officer than I would have ever been and also is running the U.S. side so. But I think you've characterized it exactly right. I mean, when you look at what's going on, you have to have a relatively pessimistic view that we're hardly through this and that the U.S. is still facing a pretty tough economic time, and it's hard to see how particularly Ontario runs at hard economic time. And so, you mentally say I don't see how we see as a bank can skate through unaffected by that. I think the positives are that as I say and then I will let Bharat. We don't actually see it in the data. So you can't actually put your hands on it. And secondly, I think we have run some pretty tough risk policies to this point that seem to be working and we have enormous earnings momentum in our retail, particularly in TD Commerce. So those are offsetting factors and that's why I think I am saying, we're comfortable in saying that we can make the kind of earnings numbers we're talking to in 2009 even if credit conditions are worse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what I would add is a, yes, you see lots of announcements out there and that's the general feeling in the U.S. that things are slowing down. And some institutions are announcing some sizeable credit issues. For us, I mean you've seen our numbers, I think there are certain factors that differentiate us and that's why the data Ed sees is slightly more positive.</p>
          <p>Firstly, we are in the northeast of U.S. that is less impacted than perhaps the rest of the country. Secondly, both the banks, TD Banknorth and Commerce Bank have traditionally been conservative lenders and the risk management in those institutions is similar, i.e. in line with what TD would do. So that has helped us through this period. The third point I would make is that almost exclusively these banks originated its own assets. These are not brokered loans or we've not purchased portfolios. So those are the positives, but as you rightly point out, you cannot out run a U.S. recession. And if that happens, yes, our losses will go up. But I feel confident that we will certainly be a positive outlier.</p>
          <p>With respect to the earnings, the April 21st call, we did reiterate in fact increased our earnings estimate for '08 to 750 million and to at least earn 1.2 billion in 2009. And if you recall in those numbers, I did emphasize that we expect our PCLs per quarter to increase substantially. So for each quarter, my estimate is that we will have PCLs in the $75 million range that is much higher than what we have experienced. And that's in anticipation of some of the issues that you're talking about, and this is per quarter through the rest of '08 and throughout '09. So that's the caution that we see within our U.S. segment, but I feel comfortable with the numbers we've put out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bharat, I appreciate that. When you look at the watch list that you have for the U.S. and perhaps even for Canada, have the number of accounts increased dramatically or has the size of the accounts increased, any color there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I will comment on the U.S. side. And I would say, I mean obviously when you have -- when you are in the lending business and we do have a sizeable book, there are certain sectors that are weaker. We've specifically talked about for sale real estate, so is there a steady flow into what I would call our watch list, yes. But conversely, there is a steady flow out in the normal course; accounts are getting worked out in the normal course. So I would say from an impaired portfolio perspective, I see some stable numbers for now. And there is nothing noteworthy that I can point to that would help you with what you're looking for. And I will let Mark or --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So I think it might be useful if Mark kind of explain the dilemma of these people.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Canadian side or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well on the U.S. side as Bharat said, I mean I think that there is -- we look at the commercial real estate portfolio and we -- although it's not showing any signs of deterioration at the moment, we would expect in a weaker economic condition that there would be things like increased vacancy and rental rates go down that would have an impact on us. But we think that we're pretty well positioned, although we think in a downturn there would be a hit on us to some extent. I think it would be well within the levels that Bharat mentioned in terms of the 75 per quarter. And there's a few reasons we think we're well positioned.  It's the geographic area and a majority of our commercial real estate portfolio is actually reducing term loans as opposed to construction loans. So if you take out the residential for sale, which is an item that we've been dealing with for the last year, we've identified has been a problem and we feel is stabilizing. The other area there's a very low content of the construction side, so we think that, that would be kind of lower risk.</p>
          <p>The other areas that we would be concerned about I guess as the economy weakens would be the home equity line of credit, which is a fairly large portfolio in the U.S. But again, it's a totally -- originate to hold strategies, so there is no broker loans in there, about a third of it is first mortgages. And looking at the credit scores, they remain strong throughout the portfolio and we have a relatively low content that is above a high LTV. So again, we think the delinquency numbers have gone up a little bit, but they're quite low relative to the other numbers you see. And we think we're well positioned there to weather a downturn should -- I think it will occur, but I think we should be a positive outlier in that area.</p>
          <p>If I turn my attention to Canada, you asked about the watch list. And if you define that as loans that are especially mentioned or criticized, classified or impaired, there is kind of three categories in there. In all categories in both the Wholesale and the Commercial portfolio, we continue to run at historically low levels, at very strong levels so asset quality is strong. But as the economy weakens, we would expect those to increase, but clearly within levels that would be manageable and reasonable given the economic cycle in our view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next caller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Brad Smith of Blackmont Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just a quick follow-up Colleen. You mentioned the mark-to-market being, I think I just wanted to confirm embedded or netted into the interest rate and credit line and trading income, and that it was consistent with the prior quarter. I'm sorry if I missed this. Have you disclosed the number somewhere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No Brad, we haven't. But what we certainly didn't want people to assume is that the change quarter-over-quarter, the decline was due to the mark-to-market on loan commitments. In fact that was a very minor impact in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that to imply that it was a minor impact at last quarter as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Relatively, yes</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Consistent with last quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Relatively, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about the cumulative MPM? Can you talk about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We're not going to -- we have decided we're not disclosing that particular item as we communicated to Michael earlier. That's fairly sensitive information given that this is a live deal and it's a single client. We don't feel it will be appropriate to disclose that amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I'm sorry. I wasn't talking about a specific transaction. I was talking about in aggregate. Is that the only mark-to-market adjustment that the bank --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's largely. Yeah. Almost entirely that item, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next caller?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mario Mendonca of Genuity Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Can we take a look at exhibit or not exhibit, rather page 18 of the supplement U.S. Personal and Commercial banking, Banknorth, 102 million in new formations, and then Commerce 97. I don't think the 97 or I don't think that represents new formations in that one month for Commerce. But maybe you could just help me understand, 97 million in formations for Commerce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Mario that is strictly the inclusion, for the first-time inclusion of the Commerce balance sheet. So that's the initial inclusion of 97 million in the net impaireds or gross impaireds for Commerce Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the inclusion and --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. The first-time inclusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And perhaps just to clarify, when the bank is consolidated why would there be gross impaired loans? My sense was that you would have written them down substantially that there really wouldn't be much at all in gross impaired loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That is the -- basically is the fair market value of those impaired loans and that's net of the allowance, we don't carry the allowances going forward. That's what changes in the accounting, but we do carry the net amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The 97 is net of the allowance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. That's a fair value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you tell us what the gross amount is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're actually relatively similar. There wasn't a large allowance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One final thing that's sort of related. CBH, can you give us any updates on what's been happening to deposit growth at CBH?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario, it's the same as what we disclosed at the April 21st call. I think there was a slide there what the year-over-year deposit in loan growth numbers were. I don't have it in front of me here, but there is no change to what we disclosed on April 21st.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next caller please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Andre Hardy of RBC Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably for Tim Hockey. In Q1 we had revenue growth of 7% and expense growth of 6 in the period back and there were comments made that operating leverage is not going to be what it's been this year. Looking at the next year, do you expect the expense growth to lead to higher revenue growth and that's how we go back to the normal operating leverage or do you expect expense growth to slow or both?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say both. What we're seeing this year is --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to be very interested in his answer to this question here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I would say both. Because I think the investments we have made very carefully are geared towards future revenue growth. We have said and we telegraphed previously that we are going to see a little bit of a squeezing in the operating leverage both this quarter and for the full year, because of that fact. But the step up in year-over-year expenses actually starts to diminish quite frankly in Q4. And so as a result of that, we collectively Bernie and I said it's the right thing as both Ed and Colleen said, to continue to invest in what customers care about and will lead to future revenue growth. So I guess, the answer is both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And this is all based on prior models and how quickly your revenue comes after opening branches or extending hours?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I would say the wild card of course is the margin question. And a -- but having said that, the models are pretty good at predicting what happens to volume and other revenue generating initiative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And Tim Thompson, can I just squeeze in another one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Go ahead, Andre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For Bob probably, value at risk went from 24 billion on average in Q1 to 42 billion in Q2 and it looks like even if you exclude Commerce Bancorp securities, trading securities were up. So can you talk about what seems to be a higher risk appetite for the bank or maybe I am reading too much into this and its just volatility is higher and that's driving a higher VAR?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's part -- it's mostly the latter run-rates. It's a combination of higher credit spreads in general. So it's credit spreads widening plus credit spread volatility in our VAR model that has driven VAR higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you are trading --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As volatility and/or spreads would reduce, you would see the VAR reduce as well. So in general or on average, it's not an indication that we've been more aggressive in taking on more positions or in taking on more trading liability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That clarifies. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next caller please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sumit Malhotra of Merrill Lynch. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I'll share this one with Colleen. Colleen, if I take the no earnings growth in 2008 very literally and take a look at the 575 the bank produced in 2007, it looks like you have got to do just under a $1.50 per quarter in the back half of the year. You've been very helpful to us in giving us a helping hand with CBH and Corporate. I think we have pretty good visibility on Canadian Retail and AMERITRADE. So am I right in thinking that Wholesale has to do somewhere around 180 million a quarter to make this work? Because that one doesn't sound too different than what you were doing late last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start out, Sumit, and hand it over to Bob. I would say that number based on our calculations is definitely on the high side. We don't expect to see a run-rate at that level going forward, but I will give over to Bob to talk about the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as Ed alluded to in his comments, it's hard to forecast Wholesale earnings at the best of times. We -- and I do feel that we have good strategies in place and I think we're executing on those strategies and we will continue to do so to drive a medium-term run-rate of 15 to 20% in our Wholesale business. And how that manifests itself quarter-by-quarter is difficult to forecast. And I don't think that we're implying that it's going to be 15 to 20 every quarter. That would be an average through a cycle and some of those quarters will do better and some of the quarters as we just finished will do less than that so -- but given the amount of capital we have in the business and given the opportunities we have in the business, given the growth plans and the people etcetera I think, 15 to 20% is a fair assumption as to take a run-rate at what Wholesale can do in the TD platform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just very quickly on top of that, securities gains. You mentioned a few times that we'd probably see that number start to trend down. It was higher than I would have thought this quarter. And your unrealized balance has held in well. Any update you can give us on what your pipeline looks like for that business in the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start Sumit. If you look at the supplemental and the security schemes that we show in other income of the 110, about 83 of that was in Wholesale and the remaining amount was in fact largely in TD Banknorth for a couple of items that we've mentioned previously. With that I will let Bob respond to the Wholesale answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think given where markets are at on the equity side, we're not extremely optimistic about what we might do in the second half of the year. We have some realizations that we think we already know about and it is a function of closing, but we're taking a fairly cautious view of what gains we might be able to harvest in the second half. So I think improvement in profitability would more come out of the dealer than it would come out of the securities gains.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go back to presentation room. Ian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a clarification before I ask my question. So Bob, the rise in VAR is that what threw up the market risk component in the RWAs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18">
        <plist>
          <p>That's just a linear thing. There's nothing else on that. The question is for Ed. When I think back to the Canada Trust where you allowed your balance sheet to really get stretched to get -- to do that deal that worked out extremely well, the leverage was a big part of the success of that deal and really getting the ROEs back up again. It seems that this time you're allowing that to occur again in an environment that as you say, you intuitively believe you need to be more cautious on where you believe intuitively we believe the U.S. is getting weaker here yet you've allowed the capital to drift back down again based on Basel metrics, but you are allowing that to occur again. Can you talk to sort of the philosophy on allowing that to occur at this stage of the cycle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure whether you're trying to prod me to rant or just giving me a soft lob, but I will take it as one of those two. I feel quite strongly that I think we're actually quite well capitalized so I am not actually worried about our capital position. I think when people look at the capital positions of financial institutions they should ask themselves the question, what businesses are they in? How much tails risks are they actually taking? And what's the certainty of their growth prospects on earnings? And to have two institutions, both of them at 9.1% Tier 1 capital and one has $4 billion of solid retail earnings growing and another one would have less, they're not in my view the same -- not a capital they actually need and particularly when you combine that with the Wholesale strategy that we've been running over the last few years and has actually proven itself out in the current marketplace. We used to say to people, well, you will only know whether we're following the strategy when we shock the system with a bad event. Well, the world shocked the system with a bad event and we ended up earning the 17% ROIC on our TD Securities through that bad event.</p>
          <p>So when I look at our capital and we're saying we're going to be comfortably at 8% at the end of the year, I think we're well capitalized. We are not sitting there with lots of excess capital because I completely agree that we are in the world that we are going to, we wouldn't want to be using up a lot of that capital and it does mean that if we're looking at acquisitions, those acquisitions are going to have to meet the test of being financed with shares, and therefore accretive in their own right. It may well be that we will not do any acquisitions in that case, or if the market because of the current demand-supply and balance between buyers and sellers in this market actually produces better rates of return than historically we've seen in the acquisition market. But I'm not uncomfortable given the risk profile we run, the strength of the retail earnings, the future prospects of those retail earnings we'll be going into this downturn with our balance sheet as it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you think about the Basel II changes, I mean I accept that it's a bizarre regulatory framework, but how else would we look at it because I mean, the risk weighting is a risk weighting. So your point on the lower risk, you did get a tremendous amount of help on your RWAs from Basel II. I mean isn't that effectively coming to your point that the business mix is reflected in the Tier 1 number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, my point on Basel II is that all of the capital regimes that we have around the world ignore earnings. As they say, they say that if you had 100% wholesale dealer or you had a bank that had our wholesale dealer tied to $4 billion earnings stream that shocked in the worse scenario in the world couldn't lose money. But they need exactly the same capital. That doesn't make any sense to me from a capital regime. And so the greatest strength in an institution, you look around the world and say what are the institutions that are running into trouble. All of it's proportioned to the size of your wholesale relative to your retail and those that are anchored by strong retail have managed to weather the storm reasonably well. And so Basel II doesn't take into account income, only takes into account capital and doesn't take into account how you generate that income. And I think how you generate where you're going out the risk curve or you are taking tail risk matters very fundamentally in terms of the safety and soundness of the institution. That doesn't mean that Basel II is a bad thing. I think there's a lot of improvements that came out of Basel II, but I don't think it tells you everything when you look at an institution as to whether or not how -- what's its ability to take shocks in the system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question, Michael. Question for Tim or Bernie. Can you remind me what TD Canada Trust stance is toward the independent mortgage broker channel, given that we note there is quite a divergence between some of the other banks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we actually operate in three channels. Two of them proprietary and one through the independent broker. So we obviously have the branch distribution, we have our own proprietary mortgage sales force and we do distribute through the independent brokerage community as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am just going to turn it back to Ed to close the meeting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good, Tim. Well, I think my messages are fairly clear. We did regard it as a disappointing quarter because we are not used to having a drop in earnings, but I think quite an acceptable quarter given the market conditions in which we're operating. I think obviously our Wholesale earnings are being impacted by market circumstances, and I think we're signaling to the market that we do believe that there is a step down in the running rate of those earnings back to impact the kind of guidance that we used to give that this is a 15 to 20% ROIC business able to in fact, earn those kind of returns in even pretty turbulent environment, and that it has solid growth prospects but built around fundamental franchise businesses.</p>
          <p>I think we are closing in. We want to try to get as close as we can, the $4 billion in retail earnings this year, and in fact have quite -- very strong growth in those earnings going into 2009. And we're not pulling back at all from our fundamental belief that we're about building franchises but equally important in investing in those franchises that continue to be a growth company that does it without going out the risk curve. Thank you very much for taking the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the end of the call. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>