<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1429196" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1400</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President, Investor Relations">Rudy Sankovic</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Group President and Chief Executive Officer, TD Bank Group">Ed Clark</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Head Finance and Chief Financial Officer, TD Bank Group">Colleen Johnston</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Head and Chief Risk Officer, Risk Management, Corporate Office, TD Bank Group">Mark Chauvin</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (Canada)">John Reucassel</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Head, Canadian Banking, Auto Finance and Credit Cards; Group and President &amp; CEO, TD Canada Trust">Tim Hockey</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Desjardins Securities">Michael Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="TD Securities">Jason Bilodeau</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Canada, Inc.">John Aiken</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Steve Theriault</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Head, U.S. Personal and Commercial Banking, TD Bank Group; and President &amp; CEO">Bharat Masrani</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Head, Wholesale Banking, TD Bank Group and Chairman CEO &amp; President, TD Securities">Bob Dorrance</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="CIBC World Markets, Inc.">Robert Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Stonecap Securities, Inc.">Brad Smith</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="National Bank Financial Brokers">Peter Routledge</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Canada)">Gabriel Dechaine</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital Markets Canada Ltd.">Sumit Malhotra</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Canaccord Genuity Corp.">Mario C. Mendonca</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Cormark Securities, Inc.">Darko Mihelic</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, and welcome to TD Bank Group's Second Quarter 2012 Investor Presentation. My name is Rudy Sankovic, and I'm the Head of Investor Relations for the Bank. We'll begin today's presentation with remarks from Ed Clark, the Bank's CEO, after which, Colleen Johnston, the Bank's CFO, will present our second quarter operating results. Mark Chauvin, Chief Risk Officer, will then offer comments on credit quality, after which we will entertain questions from those present and from pre-qualified analysts and investors on the phone.</p>
          <p>Also here today to answer your questions are Bob Dorrance, Group Head, Wholesale Banking; Tim Hockey, Group Head, Canadian Banking, Auto Finance and Credit Cards; Bharat Masrani, Group Head, U.S. P&amp;C Banking; and Mike Pedersen, Group Head, Wealth Management, Insurance and Corporate Shared Services.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 2. At this time, I'd like to caution our listeners that this presentation contains forward-looking statements, and there are risks that actual results could differ materially from what is discussed. Any forward-looking statements contained in this presentation represent the views of management and are presented for the purposes of assisting the Bank's shareholders and analysts in understanding the Bank's financial position, objectives and priorities and anticipated financial performance, and may not be appropriate for any other purposes. Certain material factors or assumptions were applied in making these forward-looking statements. For additional information on these factors and assumptions, please see our Q2 2012 MD&amp;A and 2011 annual report available on td.com.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the presentation over to Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thank you, Rudy. And thank you all for joining us today. Colleen's going to be up shortly to talk about our second quarter results in detail. But I'd like to start by sharing a few thoughts on the quarter and tell you a little more about how I feel about the rest of the year. Now, this was another very strong quarter for TD, with adjusted earnings per share growth of 12% versus the second quarter last year. Our retail business generated record adjusted earnings of $1.6 billion, up 14% from a year earlier.</p>
          <p>Our Canadian Personal &amp; Commercial operation performed very well, delivering 14% adjusted earnings growth, despite the low rate environment and slowing personal loan growth. Our U.S. Personal &amp; Commercial Bank, Wealth and Insurance businesses all delivered record results. Our Wholesale Banking results were in line with our expectations, despite difficult markets late in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Together with our robust performance in the first quarter, the second quarter's strong performance has improved, produced impressive results for the first half of 2012, with adjusted earnings of $3.5 billion and adjusted EPS of $3.68. We expect similar adjusted earnings and EPS numbers in the second half, which implies a lower growth rate for the balance of the year. We continue to work hard to stay in the 7%-10% earnings growth increase that we've indicated before, despite increasing headwinds.</p>
          <p>So let's look at each segment. Our Canadian Personal &amp; Commercial Bank expects to deliver good results in the second half of the year, driven by positive operating leverage, solid volume growth, stable credit performance and good MD&amp;A results. We will expect to continue to see margin compression into 2013 as interest rates remain low.</p>
          <p>In Wealth and Insurance, it's a mixed picture. The Wealth business has performed very well this year, but it has been impacted by uncertain markets and lower trading levels. Still, despite the challenging environment, we expect solid results from Wealth, thanks, in part, to expense management and continued good client asset inflows.</p>
          <p>Insurance is set to deliver strong results for 2012 through solid premium growth and good claims management. Our U.S. retail banks should deliver strong lending volume growth, driven by residential mortgages, indirect auto loans, and commercial lending.</p>
          <p>We also expect to see strong growth in organic deposits as new stores mature. The regulatory environment continues to be a headwind, as we try to mitigate the impact of the Durbin Amendment. And low interest rates will continue to exert some pressure on margins. Overall, though, we expect solid adjusted earnings growth for 2012.</p>
          <p>In Wholesale, market volatility, driven primarily by a resurgence in tensions in Europe will have an impact on the business, primarily through a moderation in trading revenues. Nonetheless, I'm confident that our client-driven franchise model will generate return on equity in the 15% to 20% range for the year.</p>
          <p>Now I've referred several times to the macroeconomic environment and the headwinds it is creating for our businesses. We expect this to be a recurring theme. We've said before that the recovery will take time, and that is still our view. The Eurozone sovereign debt crisis has flared up again, underscoring that the ECB's liquidity injection earlier this year provided only temporary relief and did nothing to address the region's underlying structural problems.</p>
          <p>While the euro concept may be a flawed construct, unwinding it has its own perils. Meanwhile, reducing public sector deficits with no alternative growth measures poses both social and economic risk.</p>
          <p>For now, we don't believe that the upheaval in Europe will derail the U.S. recovery, which recent data seems to confirm is gaining momentum. Households are slowly repairing their balance sheet, and job growth has held up fairly well. The main risk United States' outlook is a fiscal shock next year, as a variety of tax incentives expire, injecting a dose of austerity that the economy may not be robust enough to absorb. The U.S. economy has proven its resilience time and time again. We're encouraged by that. But we still believe that the recovery will be slow and interest rates will remain low for some time to come.</p>
          <p>In Canada, the picture's brighter, but there are challenges here, too. Let me make a comment briefly on the housing market. Looking back, a robust housing sector was a positive factor contributing to Canada's recovery from the economic downturn. A strong banking system, combined with low interest rates, fueled this industry. The risk, of course, is that this positive contributor becomes a negative factor if it leads to a sharp correction in housing prices.</p>
          <p>The government has attempted to mitigate this risk by gradually tightening CMA standards. We support these moves where, recently, OSFI has issued guidelines for the sector and intensified this oversight of lending practices. Now we do not believe that Canada has ever been at risk of a U.S.-style meltdown. The structure of our housing market and the nature of our lending practices are different. But it has clearly been prudent to lean against the collateral effects of low interest rates. While the direct costs of the banks of a sharp correction will be quite absorbable, the effects of a large correction on the economy weren't prudent.</p>
          <p>At the moment, we see signs that the housing market is slowing and the risk of a sharp correction are diminishing. We believe OSFI's interventions will have a further dampening effect. As a result, we do not see a need at this time to tighten further, given that the effects of the announced changes have yet to be fully felt. Rather, we should wait to see how the markets evolve. If further restraint is required we favor focusing on high-ratio loans.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, given low interest rates, we believe we will have to continue to work hard to stay in the 7%-10% earnings per share range over the next two years. It's why we're focused on making productivity management a competitive advantage for TD.</p>
          <p>Expense management will be increasingly an important driver of our ability to deliver positive operating leverage and to find the resources to continue to invest and growth market share. As we discussed at last month's Investors' Day, we're focused on finding permanent reductions to our cost base which will then, in turn, allow us to invest in growth initiatives that will drive our franchise for the future.</p>
          <p>To wrap up, I'm pleased with our results today and proud of the management team's impressive performance. As we work through these challenging times, we're going to keep doing exactly what we've been doing for the last 10 years; stay focused, execute on our business strategy, invest for the long term and exploit the growth strategies we outlined at last month's Investors' Day.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it over to Colleen</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ed, and good afternoon. Please turn to Slide 4. We are very pleased with our Q2 2012 results. Total bank adjusted net income for the quarter was $1.7 billion, up 14% from last year, while adjusted diluted earnings per share was $1.82, up 12% versus Q2 of 2011.</p>
          <p>These strong results were driven by record adjusted earnings in our retail business, $1.6 billion, up 14% from last year. Wealth, Insurance and U.S. P&amp;C all posted record quarters. Results in our Wholesale bank were solid, with net income of $197 million. Net income was up 5% versus last year. The Corporate segment had an adjusted loss of $20 million versus a loss of $29 million in Q2 of 2011.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 5. This slide shows you the reported and adjusted view of earnings this quarter. The difference between the two views was due to six items of note. None of these are new this quarter.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 6. Canadian P&amp;C had another very good quarter. Adjusted net income was $838 million, up 14% versus last year. Excluding MBNA, earnings growth was solid this quarter at 9%. MBNA earnings were elevated this quarter, due to better-than-anticipated credit performance.</p>
          <p>As you know, Q2 contained a full quarter of results from MBNA, which added 10% to adjusted revenues, 7% to adjusted expenses, 22 basis points to NIM and $95 million to PCL. Adjusted revenue growth of 4%, excluding MBNA, was solid this quarter due to good volume and fee growth and an additional calendar day versus the prior year, partially offset by lower margins on average earning assets.</p>
          <p>The retail business continues to generate good but somewhat slower personal lending volume growth, with year-over-year increases of 7% in real estate secured lending, and 13% in auto lending. Business lending volume growth remains strong at 14%. We continue to see strong deposit volume growth, with personal deposit volume increasing 6%, and average business deposit volume increasing 9%. Credit quality remains steady, with Personal banking PCL, excluding MBNA, down 10% compared to last year, due to better credit performance and enhanced collection strategies.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of MBNA, margin was down 12 basis points compared to last year due to the low rate environment, portfolio mix and competitive pricing pressures. Margin was down two basis points sequentially. For Q3, we forecast margin to increase slightly, driven by seasonal business activity and pricing initiatives. However, we expect the low rate environment will continue to contribute to margin declines in Q4 as well as in 2013.</p>
          <p>Adjusted operating leverage was 2%. While expenses were slightly elevated this quarter, due to timing of business initiatives and one extra business day, we continue to expect positive adjusted operating leverage for 2012.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 7. Wealth and Insurance, excluding the impact of TD Ameritrade, delivered strong results, despite continued difficult capital markets. Net income of $318 million was up 23% from last year and 8% sequentially. Both businesses had record earnings this quarter. Wealth earnings were up 3% year over year. Revenues were flat, as strong asset and fee growth in the advice and asset management businesses was offset by lower trading volumes in direct investing. Expenses were down 1% due to proactive management actions.</p>
          <p>Insurance earnings were up 51% year over year as a result of lower claims for weather-related events, the addition of MBNA, good premium growth and claims improvement. MBNA contributed nine points of bottom line growth. Expenses in Wealth and Insurance were up 1% year over year. TD Ameritrade contributed CAD47 million to TD this quarter, down 18% from last year and down 15% sequentially, partially due to lower trading volumes.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 8. U.S. Personal &amp; Commercial Bank delivered record adjusted net income of U.S. $358 million for the quarter, up 9% from last year and up 4% from last quarter. The increase was primarily due to very strong organic growth.</p>
          <p>U.S. PNC's organic volume growth, excluding acquisitions, continued to be very strong. Excluding the Chrysler Financial acquisition, average loans increased by 10%, with residential mortgages up 30% and commercial loans up 7% compared to last year. Average deposits, excluding government deposits and TD Ameritrade IDAs, were up 8%, with personal deposits up 8% and commercial up 4%. TD Ameritrade sweep deposits grew 23% compared to last year but were down 2% sequentially.</p>
          <p>The gross impact of the Durbin Amendment remains in line with our previous guidance. And we continue to implement strategies to offset the impact.</p>
          <p>There were a few unusual items in the quarter, including securities gains of roughly $80 million from our investment portfolio and elevated legal and credit-related expenses. TD Auto Finance has record originations in Q2 but faces headwinds in the second half from the roll-off of higher-margin legacy loans. Total PCL was up 7% from last year. Adjusted expenses increased over last year, primarily due to investments in the core franchise, including new stores, legal and credit-related expenses and the Chrysler Financial acquisition.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 9. Wholesale delivered good results this quarter, with net income of $197 million. Earnings were up 5% versus Q2 of 2011, due to higher revenues across a number of business lines, most notably Investment Banking and the positive impact of a favorable tax item, partially offset by higher non-interest expenses and declining fixed income trading. Annualized ROE for the quarter was strong at 19.5%.</p>
          <p>Trading-related income was solid at $278 million. Negative market trends in the late stages of the quarter resulted in lower fixed income trading revenue. We remain comfortable with our previous guidance of $300 million per quarter over a normalized cycle. PCL was in line with the second quarter last year. Expenses increased 12% year over year, primarily due to higher operating expenses.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 10. On an adjusted basis, the Corporate segmented posted a loss of $20 million in the quarter compared with a loss of $29 million last year. The change was primarily due to lower net Corporate expenses. I'll guide you back to a higher loss for Q2 &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; for Q3 and Q4, in the $40 million to $80 million loss range, which partially reflects our pattern of higher expenses in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 11. With revenue growth expected to remain constrained in a slow growth economy, we remain committed to our focus on expense management while investing for the future.</p>
          <p>Our adjusted efficiency ratio in Q2 was 56.8%, a 150 basis points improvement over Q2 of last year. We delivered positive adjusted operating leverage of 290 basis points this quarter as a result of acquisition, solid core revenue growth and prudent expense management. Excluding acquisitions and FX, we expect a low single-digit rate of growth for adjusted expenses in 2012. Expenses remain a major focus across the Bank, with our planning process for 2013 now well underway.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 12. Looking at capital, our Q2 Tier 1 capital ratio was 12%, and our pro forma Basel III ratio was 7.4%. Our guidance remains unchanged on Basel III.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide 13. We are working to deliver within our 7% to 10% EPS growth paradigm, but likely closer to the bottom end of that range. We expect our businesses to post second half earnings at roughly the same level as in the first half. Corporate segment losses are expected to be higher in the second half of the year versus the first half, due to higher expenses.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Colleen, and good afternoon, everyone. Please turn to Slide 14. As a reminder, the debt securities, classified as loans, in the acquired credit-impaired loan portfolios, have been excluded from the credit slides. Canadian credit quality remains strong across all the portfolios. PCL was down $7 million compared to last quarter, despite one extra month of MBNA results. While it's still early, performance of the MBNA Credit Card portfolio exceeds our expectations.</p>
          <p>The positive trends in the U.S. credit portfolio continued during the quarter. Although PCL increased due to the lumpy nature of the commercial &#x2013; lumpy nature of commercial losses during the quarter, steady improvement in the underlying credit metrics remained evident, as indicated by impaired loans and new formations are down in the quarter; delinquency continues to reduce; criticized and classified loans have fallen; and we are seeing fewer problem loans on the horizon. Based on these trends, we're expecting PCL to reduce during the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>Lastly, I can confirm that there has been no change in the performance of the acquired portfolios and debt securities classified as loans this quarter.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn the presentation back to Rudy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Mark. We'll now open it up for questions. And to give everyone a chance to participate, please keep to one question and then re-queue, and we'll get to you if there is time. We'd like to keep this call to end to the hour and end promptly at 4 o'clock, if we can. For those participating in person, can I ask you to identify your name and firm before asking your question. Before ending the call today, I will ask Ed to offer some final remarks.</p>
          <p>So why don't we get started in the room first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So is there any questions by anyone present? John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>John Reucassel from BMO Capital Markets. A question for Ed or Tim. You talked about the OSFI rules. You want time to see how that works &#x2013; the new OSFI rules &#x2013; on consumer lending. Could you give us a sense of how you know they're going to be working? Like what external is it going to be? Is it easy as slower consumer loan growth, relative to GDP growth? And the OSFI rules, as I understand them, actually haven't been implemented yet; that may happen in the summer or the fall. Do you think that's pulling forward some loans, or is the industry acting proactively to institute some of these?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I start then hand it over to Tim. I guess &#x2013; I think our just experience is that if OSFI shows a concern &#x2013; I think it's the difference in the regulatory environment in Canada and the United States is that the United States runs in more prescriptive system. And so you would wait exactly to get any of the rules. And then you'd say &#x2013; you'd figure out in U.S., well, what can I do and what I can't do, given those rules?</p>
          <p>In Canada, I think we run a better system where OSFI says, I'm worried about this area and I'm looking to you to do a risk-adjusted approach to make sure that you're not doing things you shouldn't be doing. As soon as you say that to a lending system, people tighten in. And so I think our assumption is if that's what will go on here is just at the margin, people will go for tighter implementation than they would have gone otherwise. Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what I'd add is that OSFI came out with the guidelines; asked the industry to respond. We went back and, as response deadline is now past, we expect them to come out with the final interpretation of rules, probably in the summer sometime. And that will include an implementation timeframe. Some of the rules that might be implemented &#x2013; depending on feedback or not &#x2013; will have fairly significant systems' implications so, therefore, there's always a implementation timeline. Who knows, could be six months; could be a year, depending on certain things.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; but to your final question as to when we will know, we're clearly seeing the markets starting to soften now and, as you say, these guidelines haven't been implemented yet. By the time that they do get implemented, I think Ed's comments were pretty clear. We'll have them implemented &#x2013; they will have a slowing effect; there's no question. So in addition to those changes, we're not advocating for any additional changes at this time. I think we've been quite &#x2013; I say we &#x2013; the government in Canada have been quite prudent in sort of timing the moderation in lending guidelines to make sure that we have a slowing effect as opposed to a crash effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But has this pulled forward any borrowing that you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't think so yet. It's not widely known. But I believe when they are published, then there likely will be more articles about how one can get ahead of the &#x2013; of it. And there's usually &#x2013; every time we've done this, we've seen a bit of a pulling forward effect, but nothing so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael Goldberg, Desjardins. It looks like you have a high level of loan rehabilitations in the second quarter, quite a bit higher than previous quarters. Is this indicative of an improving trend in loan quality? Where is it happening? And do you expect it to continue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Michael, when you say loan rehabilitation, are you talking about the reduction &#x2013; the increase in OREO in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the <mark type="ph" /> pure (24:34) sales and repayments going up significantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So what we &#x2013; as I indicated, there's been a couple of factors, is that we've &#x2013; we did see a change in the U.S. on a regularity perspective. They've been looking at  because foreclosures are being so extended and long, you're getting to a point where &#x2013; and this is really an industry issue &#x2013; where banks have substantially got ownership but title hasn't actually transferred. So the regulatory community went through that and tightened up the guidelines. So you saw a bit of a shift this quarter, so that was one factor. And that's a one-time...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've invented a new test here is if we're paying to mow the lawn, we own the house.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that was one factor. The other factor is that we are seeing a higher resolution than coming in, right? So we're cleaning up more of the problem loans than what we've seen coming in. And that's been evident in the last couple quarters, and that's probably one of the biggest things I would love, too, to say things are getting &#x2013; improving and getting better, going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that in particular in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in Canada, I mean the portfolios are quite strong to begin with, right? So it's really &#x2013; I mean I kind of put them in this, the Wholesale has de minimis problem loans to begin with. The Canadian Commercial is running at very low rates. So one loan will make a difference, but it's still at a historically low level. And then in terms of the retail, we really see that portfolio back to the kind of the pre-recession levels and at run rate, which I think is quite good.</p>
          <p>So I don't see anything materially changing there. But what you did see &#x2013; yeah &#x2013; and actually, you would have seen an increase for MBNA because now, as we go further in that, so that kind of &#x2013; notwithstanding that, we still went down a bit. So it's all, to me, indicative of a strong credit quality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Jason Bilodeau with TD Securities. Ed, you talked a little bit about the interest rate environment continue to be a headwind for the business. But once again, we're starting to see a little bit chatter that maybe Canada may be among the first to start moving up rates in the fall, maybe 2013. I'm just wondering if that's materially different than your outlook, or are they just sort of fairly small and gradual increments that wouldn't materially change your view on the low rate environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think, depending on your forecast, I mean there are some forecasts where it would make a material difference to the operations in Canada. I think it depends on how pessimistic view you have of what Europe's going to look like and its rebound effects on Canada. And so I think in this period of uncertainty, I think policymakers are going to be biased to hold rates down rather than move up.</p>
          <p>And so I think we should be running the business on the assumption that rates stay low and, therefore, getting the cost structure down to accommodate that. And if it turns out that rates move up faster than that, that's just a bonus. But we're not going to run the bank on the basis that rising interest rates solve our problems for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. That makes sense. I guess what I'm trying to get at is &#x2013; understand the sensitivity a little bit. If rates go up 25, 50 basis points in the back half of the year in Canada or early 2013, is that still what you would consider to be a pretty difficult low-rate environment? Or does that to start actually alleviate some of the pressure for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't alleviate the need to still lower the cost structure because the rates at which we're rolling off &#x2013; the things are rolling off and the rates that we're putting new tractors on will be lower than what we're rolling out. But it will be substantial. We have enough &#x2013; our core talents are big enough that 25 basis points times a big number is still a material number to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. All right, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>John Aiken with Barclays. Just a couple quick questions on the Chrysler Financial. Colleen, in your prepared remarks, you talked about the roll-off the auto loan and concerns about that. I'm assuming that's just on the spread in the revenues, not necessarily on volumes. Correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's right. So really, two things are happening right now. So the legacy book is declining, and the spreads were quite good on that business. The newly originated business which, again, we saw record originations, but we're seeing thinner spreads on that business and we're working hard &#x2013; I'll turn it over to Tim to comment on this &#x2013; but working hard to really optimize that margin going forward. But that's a dynamic you have in the book right now. Tim, I don't know if you wanted to elaborate on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Tim, just &#x2013; sorry, if I can step in because that with the follow-on question was, it looks like we've seen some very strong growth coming out of the auto lending business. And are we at an inflection point now that you're starting to see the business pick up from the deal that you've brought on? Or is it still just going to be a bit of a slow burn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's no question from a pure volume point of view, we're now &#x2013; call it a running rate every month in the U.S. only of about $800 million. So that's significant uptick, and we're now well over 8,200 dealers.</p>
          <p>Now, a year in, essentially, we're at the point where we're saying, okay, now what's the best way to optimize the risk-adjusted margin? So it's not just going for pure volume of both dealers as well as volume itself, but where is there spread available to be taken? What's transpired in the market over the last year is prime and super prime has gotten very tight. And there's some risk-adjusted margin to be taken in the sort of near-prime &#x2013; not subprime &#x2013; we're not interested in that &#x2013; but in the near-prime space. So as a result, we're trying to say, now, based on the market dynamics, where can we really broaden out the spread?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Any other questions in the room? Michael, we'll ask you to re-queue. Thank you. We'll go to the phones now, please, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Steve Theriault from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. <mark type="ph" /> Sir (30:19), just to follow up on the auto loan roll-off, just quickly. So is it the conclusion then that the roll-off will have a material impact on the margin sort of in the near term, or not necessarily?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm trying to think about the margin &#x2013; the TDAF U.S.-specific margins. In the near term &#x2013; let me get back to you on that. I think I've got a file that I &#x2013; the bottom line...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, are you asking about the U.S. P&amp;C margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:49).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Or are you asking about the TDAF margin overall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the U.S. P&amp;C margin. Like is it big enough to see it come through that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean maybe, Bharat, you'd want to comment generally on where margins are. You see margins bump around a little bit. You saw an increase this quarter. Part of that was the ACI accounting, which we called out in the slides, so you see things bump around a little bit. But I think we have a &#x2013; sort of a reasonable range that we expect going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So, Steve, there is &#x2013; this is Bharat. There is a slight headwind on margins, obviously, with overall rates being depressed. So you will see compression in &#x2013; over time. But many quarters ago, we said the range you should expect from the U.S. is between 350 to 375 basis points. And I think that is still an appropriate assumption, given what we know today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. That's great. I want to ask Bob Dorrance, please, a question on risk-weighted assets. You had a big step up in Q1 on the back of Basel 2.5. And in short order, you pared, it looks like about $3 billion off the risk-weighteds this quarter. So maybe you could just talk about some of the things you're doing specifically to get the relief. Is there runway for more of that?  And maybe you can't answer this, but I'll ask it anyway. Is there the possibility of getting back to the high-$30 billion range of RWAs getting back a lot of what you lost at the beginning of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think &#x2013; the quick answer is that we implemented the model at the beginning of the year. So this is the first time when all of the desks are really working with the model &#x2013; the models. And the ask of them was to review their businesses, look at all the positioning that they were taking to make money and see if they couldn't do it in a more effective way and a more optimal way. And that what's been going on.</p>
          <p>I guess as an example, non-investment-grade credit is significantly impacted by stressed VAR. So the ask there is, let's just, from an inventory perspective, hold less non-investment-grade credit. And, in fact, that's what the market's doing. We're not the only one that's implementing the strategy. So I think what you're seeing is just both the market and ourselves respond to the new rules and how our job is to try to keep the same level of profitability, revenue and used as &#x2013; the optimal amount of capital to do that.</p>
          <p>Is there more room for improvement? I think that there's &#x2013; potentially, there is. Offsetting that, VAR is also impacted by market factors, so those are not controllable. And if market factors deteriorate, that can add to VAR. On the other hand, we're still looking at ways as to how we're using the capital that we have in business to see if we can't reduce it. I don't think we can get back to where we were before, when we started, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Steve. Next question, please, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Robert Sedran from CIBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. I just wanted to return to the issue of the housing market. I guess, Tim, you answered that &#x2013; an earlier question that suggests that, that market's already slowing. And I guess my question is, if the market is already slowing, is it a good idea to have any more changes in terms of the framework that OSFI's putting forth? I mean is there any risk that we overshoot and, rather than tapping on the brakes, we actually slam on the brakes? And you sound comfortable that's not going to happen. I'm just curious as to why.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's certainly a risk that the factors already put in the marketplace will have an overshoot factor, but we don't see it as being large. And, as we say, there's already been &#x2013; if you talk to our Chief Economist, he'd say there's a 10% to 15% correction in the housing market that is appropriate, anyway. Do I &#x2013; am I certain that we're not going to overshoot? Of course not. Which is why we say, let's &#x2013; we've given feedback on the OSFI guidelines. Some of them may be put into place; some of them may be changed. Then let's watch to see what happens.</p>
          <p>At the end of the day, low interest rates do trump lots of other factors. And housing is incredibly affordable, still, so there has to be a little bit of leaning into that for us, for us to slow down the market overall. But there certainly is a risk that it will overshoot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I &#x2013; just a quick follow-up I had. Don't want to ask a second question, but, Colleen, you mentioned the MBNA having an impact on Insurance and Wealth of 9%. Is that for the overall or just to the Insurance part of the segment? If I think of the 16%, is it actually 9%, excluding...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. So this is strictly related to the Insurance bottom line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we grew by 51%. Ex MBNA Canada, we would have grown by 42%. So it was still a fantastic quarter, needless to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Brad Smith from Stonecap Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I had a couple of questions. Just with respect to the U.S. segment disclosure, Colleen, I believe that you mentioned in your preamble something about some legal costs in the quarter. I was wondering if you could elaborate on that and, perhaps, put a number on that. I was also &#x2013; I was curious about that because you, I believe, you took a very large accrual in the fourth quarter. And the implication of what I heard you say was that there were further expenses hitting the P&amp;L relating to legal.</p>
          <p>The second question that I have is just sort of a general question. You mentioned an $80 million gain on the sale of some AFS securities. I &#x2013; as you know, I follow the U.S. regulatory filings fairly closely, and I saw an $80 million gain come through there in the December quarter. And I'm just wondering, is that the same gain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So to start with your first question, we did have some items that we would call unusual in the quarter. But overall, I'd say they netted out to a &#x2013; more or less a neutral effect. So on the revenue side, we did have the securities gains of about $80 million. And we're not disclosing a specific number, Brad, but we did have very much elevated legal and credit-related expenses and higher PCLs. So I think net-net, that was pretty neutral. And then so if you look at the 9% growth in the bottom line on a year-over-year basis, I would really characterize that as core fundamental growth. So, again, it was quite a good quarter.</p>
          <p>It is &#x2013; as we both know, it is tough to go back and look at the call reports and completely align it with the &#x2013; with what we're reporting on the segment side. The GAAP view is different, so the U.S. returns are on a U.S. GAAP basis. We're reporting now under IFRS, so you won't always see a complete connection there. But we did have additional legal expenses this quarter for some items that we settled.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Just with respect to that GAAP versus IFRS issue, I mean what I'm seeing here now is just a general decoupling on your expenses between your call report, which was about $1.3 billion in expenses in the latest quarter, and the roughly $960 million that you're showing as adjusted expenses. Is there some different type of allocation going on? Is that &#x2013; where would that difference be going in the consolidated statements?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, there are differences between the legal entity view versus the management reporting view, which is the one that we're reporting from a segment standpoint. And there really hasn't been any substantial shift in that, but that's why it is hard to compare it &#x2013; to compare the two views.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But accounting differences aside, the legal view ends up going somewhere in the management view, does it not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean that would be the starting point, typically, for the segment results is, you would have the legal entity view and then, again, you may have other items that relate to that entity but may not be incurred directly in the entity. So those are some of the differences that do come about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brad. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Peter Routledge from National Bank Financial. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I was just noticing on Page 29 of your Report to Shareholders, assets to capital multiple kind of ticked up for the first six months of this year pretty significantly to 18.1 from 17.2. So, I guess, what's driving that? Is that just loan growth and deposit growth in Canada and the U.S., A)? And, B), how much of that is a resistor to future balance sheet growth, given that you're getting closer to the OSFI limit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we're quite comfortable with where we are right now on the assets to capital multiple at 18. We've still got lots of room. IFRS is impacting that result to a certain extent. And then we also had a balance sheet re-class this quarter, which added to our assets so that we would have seen a bit of a tick up in that. That was accounting related to certain Wholesale assets. But overall, we're quite comfortable with where we are in that ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That'll &#x2013; I mean under IFRS, that'll be more &#x2013; you can correct me if I'm wrong &#x2013; but it seems like that'll be more of a gating capital issue than, say, the Tier 1 or common equity Tier 1 ratio. Given that, does it change how you look at the marginal profitability of a loan? Does a low spread product like a Canadian mortgage look to be like a weaker ROE product than, say, a commercial loan, given the &#x2013; you're going to be near the limit on that ACM ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The boss wants to take this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think at the margin, we are still bound by risk-weighted assets rather than the leverage test, even under Basel III. So I think, for the moment, there's a point where you could so de-risk the bank that you would actually change your capital allocation models. But for the moment, we're using a risk-weighted capital test.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Peter. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Gabriel Dechaine from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just a question here on the mortgage book &#x2013; just the maturation of it or the roll-over, I guess. As I understand it, in 2008, 2009, spreads were in the 200 basis points range and now, they're in the 80 basis points range. What kind of &#x2013; what percentage of the book is already kind of re-priced at those levels, and maybe those numbers are off? And then also, saw on Page 17 the securitization &#x2013; of the supplement &#x2013; sorry. You had a big uptick in securitized assets, mortgages and the amortization of them as well. The securitized amount was $7.6 billion. They're usually in the $3 billion to $4 billion range or closer to $4 billion. Is that some sort of a sign of a big refinancing spike, or what's going on there? I don't quite understand it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I start with your second question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then, we'll go back to Tim on the overall margins. So yeah, when you look at that particular page, I think it's Lines 2 and 3 looked quite inflated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They both were inflated, and you have to sort of look at the two more on a net basis. But we did do some additional securitization this quarter, which did affect line two. So again, it's hard to sort of interpret the two lines individually, is the way I would phrase it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; what &#x2013; I can see why one would be like the Line 2, the $7.6 billion just choose to securitize a bunch. Why would the amortizations spike up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that becomes your &#x2013; that's your pay-down number. So again, you have to look at the two. And you can top off, obviously. So you have to look at the two more on a net basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's people paying down their mortgages, and you have to re-secure &#x2013; or secure the new mortgages into the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. We can talk up in the pools.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it is refinancing activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It can be. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Back to Tim on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just generally on the real estate secured lending portfolios, your 200 basis point number was quite high. Traditionally, the margin on a mortgage, call it &#x2013; whether it be HELOC, fixed or a fixed mortgage is about, call it, 85, 90 basis points. We're running a little bit higher than that, I would say. But it is drifting down, as you would say, because of &#x2013; primarily a mix shift. We have seen quite a shift from variable interest rate mortgages to fixed, as people are taking advantage of low rates for &#x2013; to lock in for longer term. But the general margin erosion is onesies and twosies at best in that whole portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sumit Malhotra from Macquarie Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon. First, numbers, very quickly, for Tim Hockey. If I look at the balances &#x2013; the <mark type="ph" /> as at (44:09) balances for the Canadian portfolio on Page 27 of your presentation, Credit Cards &#x2013; the Credit Card balance down about CAD400 million quarter over quarter. Can you remind me &#x2013; well, maybe first off, just telling me how of this relates to the targeted MBNA runoff that you had communicated when that purchase was made? And how much of that &#x2013; I think it was the teaser rate portfolio that was going to be planned runoff. Where should we see that number settle out in terms of the planned runoff of that portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me just jump to the answer of your last question, which is, we expect to see about CAD1.6 billion runoff of that teaser rate at the end of this year, pretty much. I would say that one of the factors we're finding out with the MBNA, as you've heard from Colleen, there's no question that the credit performance of that book is better than we expected. And part of that has to do with the underlying economics of the teaser portfolio. So I would say our view is changing as to the quality of that business. So we still expect to see the runoff of some of the business. But that was our &#x2013; we're on plan for about a CAD1.6 billion runoff of that book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so it was &#x2013; if I have the numbers right here, it was roughly CAD7.4 billion when the acquisition closed in December that you added to your Credit Card portfolio. So the CAD1.6 billion is off that base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that was a couple of months of results. I think it's actually &#x2013; we should sort of settle out at around the CAD6.2 billion, I think, is the number I have in my head <mark type="ph" /> indiscernible] (45:46).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That sounds right. And then on capital, probably for Ed Clark. So your Basel III communicated today at 7.4%. I think it's fair to say you're adding roughly 30 basis points a quarter from normal-course operations. I guess the feeling I have is that Basel's talked about a floor of 7%; OSFI has indicated they'd like closer to 8%. And then after, that the banks would like, for lack of a better term, a little bit of walking around money. So it certainly seems like you're going to get to that 8% level, perhaps, 8%-plus by the end of the year &#x2013; and please correct me if I'm wrong.</p>
          <p>My question for you, TD's never been a bank that's been overly interested in buybacks &#x2013; at least in the last number of years. It seems like the acquisition &#x2013; the pace of acquisitions has slowed somewhat in the U.S. Can you remind us on how you're thinking about outlays for capital deployment, and what priorities would be &#x2013; particularly, when you look at the operating environment as it is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I certainly look forward to the day where we have to answer that question and have excess capital and try to figure out what to do with it. I would say, in terms of acquisitions, our current focus has been and continues to be more on the asset side. As you know, we have a significant portfolio in the United States. And as margins thin on the deposit side, that does make sense if you can find the right assets and only if you find the right assets. And we'd probably walk away from 10 deals for every one that you might think of doing. But if we can find assets to put along that, that earn a good rate of return on the incremental capital, then we would redeploy capital to do that. So far, as I say, those have been hard to find that meet our test. But I think that's probably the natural place we'd put capital for the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that number &#x2013; if you're in the range of 8% to 8.5%, is that a &#x2013; in your mind, an excess capital position or, perhaps, not yet with some of the changes that are happening on the regulatory front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've indicated 7.5% to 8% for the year end, and I think we're comfortable that we will certainly make that. I think we're waiting for some guidance. I think most people assume that the guidance from OSFI is going to be 8% of what the national SIFI is. But I think in the second half of this year, there are going to be guidelines coming down from the SSP. And I think we'll get some indication from OSFI as to the pace of which they want us to go to that. So I think by the end of the year, we'll have clarity about what that number is, what pace you have to get it and what kind of cushion you'd want to have in getting there. But we haven't got that guidance yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sumit. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mario Mendonca from Canaccord Genuity. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon; for Tim Hockey. The slowdown in real estate secured lending was apparent at your bank and many others. And my suspicion, of course, in this has been, I think, confirmed by what some of the retail &#x2013; or what some of the brokers are saying &#x2013; mortgage brokers, that is &#x2013; is that the banks really did pull back; not so much in pricing, but in other ways.</p>
          <p>Could you talk about what TD did to slow down the mortgage growth? And then, secondarily, is there anything else planned for the next quarter? Or are you pretty much content with where you are now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of additional actions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, tough to judge. I would say we are &#x2013; the actions that we've taken, for example, is tighten up on our non-income verified lending &#x2013; what's know in the industry as equity lending. That was at a level that we thought was too high. So that did have an effect in the last quarter. There've been other smaller items, but it's no one large lever that's been pulled. I think the effects of the levers to date will continue to be felt over the next little while. And as we've said, obviously, that's even before the OSFI guidelines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you anticipate introducing anything brand new into Q3 that you hadn't already introduced in Q2 to slow down lending growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Okay. And then just a quick follow-up on expenses. Colleen, you referred to the back half of the year expense levels being higher; that's entirely consistent with what we've seen in prior years. But if I could take you back to Q4 2011, when expenses really popped; something like $300 million sequentially. And there were a number of reasons for that; pension expense, for example. Is that the sort of thing you would guide us to again in Q4 2012, another significant move? Or was that specific to Q4 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do tend to have a pattern of large &#x2013; much larger expenses in the fourth quarter of each year. So it was a larger increase last year, but we did have that same phenomenon in 2010. So we're doing a lot of thinking about that as a management team and looking at our forecasts. I think, Mario, I'll be in a better position to give you an update on that outlook by the end of next quarter. But typically, we do see a bit of a slower start, in particular, on some of our initiatives spend, which tends to be a bit lower earlier in the year. And then that does tend to ramp up towards the end of the year. So it's something that's very much on our radar at the moment. But I'll give you more guidance next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is it conceivable we could see that kind of a $300 million move quarter to quarter? Or is that something you really want to wait to guide us on later?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I would say that our preference would be not to have a number as large as that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was going to say it's not out of the question, but anyway &#x2013; we'll see where we end up. I hope Ed is right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got time for &#x2013; thanks, Mario &#x2013; one more question, please, and then we'll end the call with Ed's remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Darko Mihelic from Cormark Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Rudy. I'm going to sneak in two. Tim, real quickly, I've heard some concern that appraisal values in Canada, some people are nervous about them. Can you discuss that, made any changes in TD? And then my second question, also for Tim, is, it looks as though deposits rates in the GIC market are spiking, the short end. Looks like TD might be one of the leaders in there, especially in the broker market. Wondered if you can talk to that as to why you would do that? And secondly, what impact, if any, in that would possibly have on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Darko, it's Mark Chauvin. I'll take the first question on the appraisal values in Canada. In some of the hotter markets &#x2013; I guess Vancouver and Toronto &#x2013; we're seeing a &#x2013; we're not seeing them &#x2013; they're slightly above maybe purchase prices, but not wildly above. And we've always followed a policy of financing against the lower of the purchase price or the appraisal. And the other thing that we follow is that we've always followed a sliding scale, which protects you against inflated values at the higher end, meaning that we will lend 80% up to $900,000. But beyond that, we would only lend 50%. So if you take a $2 million house, you get a loan to value of 56% under the sliding scale. So we're really not seeing a lot of it, but we feel we have &#x2013; our existing policies would protect us against that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Darko, on the term pricing and the broker market, I'll take that one away. I would say our general practice is that we want to make sure we price appropriately in term products to keep franchise customers rather than broker customers because we're quite comfortable with our funding position, generally. So if we're overpaying for deposits right now, then that's something I don't need to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; there's one more question in the room. So, Michael, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So with Ally in the U.S. selling its Canadian operations, and your interest in been adding assets, what's the likelihood or interest that you could have in their Canadian <mark type="ph" /> auto (53:50) receivables? And do you expect there to a lot of competition for those receivables?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as you know, Michael, we don't comment on acquisitions, so I'm not going to change that policy today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I guess that concludes the questions, very abruptly. Anyway, over to Ed for final comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously, we're both happy with the quarter and happy with the first half. And I think our outlook and our strategy remains pretty much the same. We like our business mix. We like our model. But we also recognize the economic and regulatory headwinds, and we get paid to try to make our earnings target. And that's what we intend to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much, Ed, and that concludes the second quarter call. So thank you very much for attending or listening on the phone. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude our conference call for today. Thank you for participating. Please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>