<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1323514" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>685</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Mar&#xED;a Garc&#xED;a-Legaz Ponce, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Santiago Fernandez Valbuena, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">David George</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">David Wright</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Guillermo Ansaldo</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Luis Prota</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">James McKenzie</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Tim Boddy</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Matthew Key</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Robin Bienenstock</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Iv&#xF3;n Leal</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Santiago Fernandez-Valbuena</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Jonathan Dann</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Will Milner</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Stanley Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Jesus Romero</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to Telef&#xF3;nica's January to June 2010 Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator instructions" /> As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would like to turn the call over to Mrs. Mar&#xED;a Garc&#xED;a-Legaz, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Telef&#xF3;nica's conference call to discuss January-June 2010 results. I am Mar&#xED;a Garc&#xED;a-Legaz, Head of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that this document contains financial information that has been prepared under International Financial Reporting Standards. This financial information is unaudited. This presentation may contain announcements that constitute forward-looking statements, which are not guarantees of future performance and involve risks and uncertainties and that certain results may differ materially from those in the forward-looking statements as a result of various factors. We invite you to read a complete disclaimer included in the first page of the presentation, which you will find on our Web site.</p>
          <p>We encourage you to review our publicly available disclosure documents filed with the relevant securities market regulators. If you don't have the relevant press releases and the slides, please contact Telef&#xF3;nica Investor Relations team in Madrid by dialing the following telephone number: 34-91-482-8700.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn the call over to our CFO, Mr. Santiago Fernandez Valbuena, who will be leading this conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mar&#xED;a, and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and thank you for joining Telef&#xF3;nica's 2010 first half results conference call. Today with me are Julio Linares, our Chief Operating Officer; Guillermo Ansaldo, Head of Telef&#xF3;nica de Espa&#xF1;a; Jos&#xE9; Mar&#xED;a &#xC1;lvarez-Pallete, Head of Telef&#xF3;nica Latin America; and Matthew Key, Head of Telef&#xF3;nica Europe. During the Q&amp;A session, you'll have the opportunity to ask questions directly to any of them.</p>
          <p>Telef&#xF3;nica has released today a strong set of results based on execution of the management priorities established for 2010. Our results are consistently improving on a quarterly basis from top to bottom line, leveraging its solid underlying operating and financial performance and positive impacts from Forex. Our wide diversification fully explains our strong results, despite challenging conditions in some markets. Revenue growth in the second quarter picked up noticeably, led by improved trends across all regions in the back of the strong commercial push, focused on expanding the base of high-quality customers and robust growth in wireless data in our markets. We continue to post robust profitability with enhanced margins sequentially, despite reinvesting efficiency gains to fuel future revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Operating cash flow generation went strong, which is coupled with a solid balance sheet that allows us to face current headwinds from a comfort zone. Year-to-date performance is in line with expectations and we do confirm our 2010 guidance for all metrics, with <mark type="inaudible" /> growth expected for the second half of the year. And let me stress that our growing dividend policy is fully reaffirmed.</p>
          <p>Starting with a summary of the P&amp;L on the slide three, we see that in the second quarter of the year, we have posted improved trends sequentially in major metrics, reflecting a ramp up in growth across regions, a measurable a currency boost, mainly from the Brazilian real and the Mexican and Colombian peso offsetting the sharp Venezuela bolivar devaluation. Group sales grew by 5.4% year-on-year to over &#x20AC;29 billion after June, ramping up 3.7 percentage points quarter-on-quarter. In organic terms, revenue rose 2% in the first half, 1.1 percentage points more than other previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Six months operating income before D&amp;A reached &#x20AC;10.9 billion virtually flat year-on-year in reported terms, which currently the 2.3% decline rate in organic terms due to mainly by the fast customer growth and the negative impact from regulatory measures and non-recurrent effects. Operating cash flow in the first half exceeded &#x20AC;6.6 billion impacted by the recent &#x20AC;1.4 billion investment in Spectrum in Germany. Our disciplined management of non-operating results allows top line growth to fully flow into net income as the slide number four shows.</p>
          <p>January through June, net profit topped &#x20AC;3.8 billion, or 9.4% above last year's figure and 10 percentage points above operating income growth. All things considered, first half 2010 reported EBITDA reached &#x20AC;0.83, equivalent to a 18% year-on-year increase.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide number five, based on customer expansion after June has been a key lever for our sound performance reflecting our strategy to build the foundation of the country's economic recovery and set the basis for the new wave of revenue growth. With the commercial momentum continued in the last three months leaving to net adds in the first half of the year doubling the volume recorded a year earlier. Growth in net adds was powered by higher gross adds as well as churn control across businesses.</p>
          <p>I would like to stress the 8.9 million organic mobile net adds recorded in the six months to June, 76% up year-on-year with the particularly noteworthy performance in the contract segment and mobile broadband connections. More than 56% of the net adds were in contract well above last year's figure, while mobile broadband accesses have already surpassed the 17million mark that already account for 8% of our mobile customer base mainly pushed by the growing traction of smartphones. For the prepaid to contract migrations and mobile broadband adoption will foster mobile growth in the coming years.</p>
          <p>Growth in fixed broadband is also to be highlighted with first half organic net adds increasing 30% year-on-year on the back of higher penetration of bundles, which also drove improved trends in the traditional fixed-line services. Our commercial push-on value on growth levers led us to reach 278 million accesses at the end of June 2010, it was 7% more than a year ago in organic basis with 110 basis points improvement sequentially.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to slide number six for the review of the top line. Year-on-year, organic growth ramped up in the second quarter marking the company's third consecutive quarter with a sequential improvement boosted by the sharp increase and growth in accesses. Excluding the drag from MTR cuts, first half organic sales growth jumped to 3.3% year-on-year, 90 basis points up on the first quarter. The sound diversification of the revenue mix is to be highlighted with growth driven by our businesses in Latin America and Europe that already account for over two-thirds of our revenues by services growth businesses mainly broadband connectivity are increasing its weight in our revenue mix.</p>
          <p>In addition, global initiatives launched a year ago to fully capture the benefits of our scale in terms of roaming, global procurement and IT are already bearing fruits with these actions having a direct positive impact in the different businesses in terms of savings for better conditions. Meanwhile, this <mark type="inaudible" /> of procurements in TGS is being reflected at the original level with an additional positive contribution from services to vendors of &#x20AC;90 million, group revenue in the first half of 2010. In reported terms, revenue growth is benefiting from a positive currency effect during the second quarter and the consolidation of HanseNet and Jajah from the first quarter of the year. And as I said before, revenue trends are improving simultaneously in our three regions of operations.</p>
          <p>Despite the commercial growth, in terms of our future growth profile, operating profitability remained healthy as outlined in slide number seven. OIBDA declined 2.3% in organic terms year-on-year affected by non-recurrent items and negative regulatory impacts, which dragged growth by 2.7 percentage points. Also our group operating expenses rose 5.5%, in organic terms after June mainly driven by higher commercial expenses 8.1% year-on-year due to fast customer growth, higher commissions and concept subsidies. Increased network maintenance and expansion mainly in Latin drove higher network costs. On the country, interconnection costs remained virtually stable driven by MTR cuts across Europe. Consolidated OIBDA margins stood at 37.5%, down 1.7 percentage points year-on-year in organic terms, but expanded 80 basis points quarter-on-quarter. Margin erosion eased in the second quarter on the back of the rebound in sales and the benefits of our scale with global initiatives contributing with &#x20AC;85 million after June.</p>
          <p>Continued solid cash flow is shown in slide number eight. Operating cash flow in nominal terms topped &#x20AC;6.6 billion in the first half of 2010, while stripping out investments in the spectrum it would have reached almost &#x20AC;8 billion, posting a 3.4% growth year-on-year purely organic. Operating cash flow increased across Latin and Europe, while Espana delivered sound operating cash flow at &#x20AC;3.5 billion, down year-on-year. Efficiency ratio stood at 75.3% for the six months ending June 2010, leveraged on disciplined cost management and focused CapEx.</p>
          <p>Please turn now to slide number nine for an update on guidance. First half results are fully aligned with year-end targets with revenue increasing on the guidance criteria 3.3% year-on-year and OIBDA still below our annual target, but consistent with anticipated performance along the year. OIBDA growth for the whole year will be within the outlook range with a strong boost in the second half of the year as we will have less challenging year-on-year comparisons in Colombia fixed and commercial activity increase from Q3 '09 onwards. We also maintain our CapEx target for the year with first half figures reflecting CapEx and seasonality.</p>
          <p>Let me now walk you through the operating and financial performance of the three regions just starting with Telef&#xF3;nica Espa&#xF1;a. Let's now review our regional performance just starting with Telef&#xF3;nica Espa&#xF1;a on slide number 10. Our results continue to be constrained by economic weakness in a very competitive market, though the trends show a gradual improvement in both top line and OIBDA.</p>
          <p>In comparable terms, revenues delivered a fourth sequential quarterly improvement since we reached the bottom in the second quarter of '09 on the back of better performance in our businesses driven by the increased commercial push in recent quarters and mild voice traffic recovery and a good growth in wireless data. Disciplined execution on OpEx initiatives allowed to support the commercial boost while containing the OIBDA margin erosion to 1.2 percentage points in the first half of the year on a comparable basis. We continue to post healthy margins at 47.7% after June in comparable terms.</p>
          <p>Regarding CapEx the year over year rise was driven by increased investments in growing businesses like mobile broadband.</p>
          <p>On slide number 11, wireless service revenues in Spain declined by 5.7% year-on-year in the second quarter, an improvement of 1.3 percentage points on the previous quarter, pushed by robust growth in mobile data, strong customer growth and better usage patterns. Telef&#xF3;nica led the market growth in the quarter, particularly in the contract segment, where we have added close to 450,000 customers since the beginning of the year, 3.6 times higher than a year-ago, reflecting our focus on growth opportunities and allowing us to maintain a superior revenue market share.</p>
          <p>The strong growth in contract data was driven by a 37% year-on-year raise in gross adds and stable churn. As a result, our customer base was up 7.4% year-on-year, with the contract base already accounting for over 66% of the total. Voice traffic trends also improved sequentially with this stable pricing environment versus previous quarters and continued to drive from MTR cuts. On the very positive side wireless connectivity revenues continue to grow sharply 64% year-on-year as of June on the back of the good traction of our mobile broadband offer. We have already exceeded 3.8 million mobile broadband customers leveraging our purchase on the smartphones and data plans.</p>
          <p>On the wireline business, revenues in the quarter also delivered a small improvement in trend with a 3.8% year-on-year decline in comparable terms in the second quarter, one percentage points higher than the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>This evolution is mainly driven by the sustained positive contribution from data and IT businesses, the slight recovery in traffic and lower line losses and the return to growth in broadband.</p>
          <p>Commercial efforts focused on the bundling strategy, delivering results with the good gross adds and churn rate coming down across all services. Let me highlight that retail wireline losses, despite having the lowest unbundle local prices in Europe continue to decline both quarter-on-quarter and compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Additionally, due to growth in wholesale accesses total wireline accesses limited their year-on-year decrease to a 0.9% up to June. In fixed broadband with all major changes in our competitive behavior, we maintain our leadership in the market with a customer share above 54%, thanks to the 5.4 growth achieved in broadband customers. We continue to focus on quality and service improvements, which have allowed us almost double net adds year-on-year in the first half.</p>
          <p>The market density continues with the total broadband declining 7.4% year-on-year despite the increased contribution from value-added services, especially in <mark type="inaudible" />  which reached more than 20% of total broadband ARPU. In pay-TV, we continue to gain market share to over 18% at the end of June on the back of the sharp reduction in churn, which led to strong net adds in the first half compared to net losses posted in the previous year.</p>
          <p>In summary, slowly year-to-date, we are seeing better trends in Spain across business, going forward it is too soon to anticipate the potential impact from the governmental statutory measures and the recent increase in value-added tax that could be an additional challenge on consumption starting in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>We now move to slide number 13 to review our Latin American properties. I'd like to stress the solid results delivered in the second quarter highlighted by the improved trends in customer revenue and OIBDA year-on-year growth in organic terms benefiting from better economic environments in the region. Strong commercial momentum was sustained with 3.8 million net adds in the quarter and 7.5 million in the first half, close to three times those of the year-earlier leading to ramp-up in accesses growth to achieve the 176 million mark. Revenues grew a healthy 6.2% in organic terms in the January through June period, ramping up sequentially and improved growth in most markets.</p>
          <p>OIBDA after June rose close to 4% year-on-year in organic terms, a 0.5 percentage points improvement on the previous quarter with OIBDA margin reaching 37.2% in the first half sustaining a healthy level, despite this stronger commercial activity versus last year and the negative performance at Telesp in Colombia. As we already anticipated at the beginning of the year, year-on-year comparison should improve for the next quarter on a much better performance from these two operations in more comparable commercial efforts across the region. On reported terms, operating cash flow increased by over 7% year-on-year to &#x20AC;3.2 billion in the first half, despite the bolivar devaluation.</p>
          <p>Let me now spend a few minutes on the performance of our Latin American wireless businesses. After June, year-on-year customer growth ramped up to 12.6%, topping 142 million customers led by the strong performance of the contract segment, which grew over 23% year-on-year. Our focus to enhance customer value is reflected in the shop reduction in turn to best ever levels, the significant increase in prepaid to contract migrations and the voice and mobile broad band. As of June, we had more than doubled our mobile broadband customer base to around 4% of our mobile customers in the region. The growth potentially shoot and we are well positioned to capture this opportunity in the region due to our best-in-class networks.</p>
          <p>Let me highlight that 50% of the 7.2 million net adds recorded after June were in contract from 25% one year ago bidding competition. 19% of our customer base is already in contract, 160 basis points up year-on-year. The fast customer expansion drove traffic up close to 30% in the first half, which together with a very strong growth in mobile data allowed ARPU to remain pretty flattish versus last year in organic terms, underpinned by the 3% advance in outgoing ARPU. As a result, revenues accelerated across all services posting double-digit growth even on total revenue.</p>
          <p>Data revenue growth is impressive, but close to 50% year-on-year. In the wireline businesses, we're also delivering improved trends. The broadband business posted an outstanding performance in the quarter leveraging the bundle strategy and enhanced quality metrics. The second quarter broadband net adds increased 92% year-on-year and 28% quarter-on-quarter driven by better gross adds in churn reduction to the lowest levels ever posted, particularly remarkable is the evaluation of retail fixed taxes, which returned to positive growth up to six quarters of net losses adding  56,000 accesses in the second quarter of 2010. As I just mentioned, bundles are key with 57% of our broadband connections being part of a duo or trio package totaling 28% of our fixed line accesses of broadband. As a result, new revenues from Internet and pay-TV grew double digit, increasing its contribution to total revenues with an average rate of 22% in the region, up over one percentage point on last year's figure.</p>
          <p>Let me now cover the performance of tariffs on the slide number 16. For the third quarter in a row, the company is gaining commercial traction, capitalizing on the strong growth and quality and improved customer satisfaction and lower churn levels. In the traditional business, net adds turned positive for the first quarter since Q1 '06 adding 64,000 accesses in the quarter leading to access growth since December 2009. Performance in broadband was even more outstanding with net adds reaching a new record since the launch of the service ten years ago, the strong gross adds and reduced churn. Better commercial results are starting to flow into financials still gradually. Year-on-year revenue trend improved, being virtually flat in the quarter on better traditional base line revenues sequentially and growing contribution from broadband and TV revenues.</p>
          <p>Reported OIBDA continued to grow sharply, though in underlying terms, the performance improved significantly quarter-on-quarter with the single-digit year-on-year decline in the second quarter and emerging expansion totaled 36%. Commercial turns show we're working in the right direction and they should become even more evident in the financial performance in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>On slide 17, our businesses in Colombia are also showing signs of improvement. In the wireline business, fixed broadband net adds remain strong in the second quarter, growing significantly from a year-earlier while traditional access performance was very solid virtually flat in the quarter versus 64,000 net losses in the second quarter of '09 and still negative figures in the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>The improved trends in the operating metrics are gradually translating into better financials as the graph shows. The wireless business net adds continue to post growth -- to post good growth, compared with negative figures a year ago, big noteworthy, there is strong focus on the contract segment, driving 50% of the net additions recorded in the quarter. In addition, ARPU in local currency was 5.6% up year-on-year. In terms of our financials, top line expected growth advancing 2.1% in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Let me now quickly review the other hot topics in Latin America. In Mexico, we're focusing our efforts on postpaid, driving contract customers up 48%. Service revenues grew close to 10% year-on-year on the back of strong data revenues with further advances in profitability not only in terms of margin, but operating cash flow. Mexico continues to be a key growth driver for the group and the recent spectrum option has allowed us to strengthen our position in this market.</p>
          <p>In Venezuela, we are still posting some financials despite the toughest trading conditions and the bolivar devaluation. Data services are moving, driving a solid service revenue growth up to June. However, commercial activities reduced as we maintain our selective customer acquisition approach, enhanced availability has become more limited. So the OIBDA margin is hit by the inflation in the devaluation. It is still very sound at the 45% level.</p>
          <p>Finally, Vivo continues to deliver outstanding commercial and international results. Vivo outperformed the market, gaining market share for the fourth quarter in a row with strong focus on contract. Service revenue year-on-year growth ramped up in Q2 to double-digit growth boosted by extremely robust data revenues and the boom in net traffic. Profitability improved to the 30% level despite the strong commercial push.</p>
          <p>To finalize, with Latin American let me illustrate that we're very pleased with the agreement we reached yesterday with Portugal Telecom to get full control of Brasilcel. This agreement allows us to become the leader in the telecommunications market in Brazil, while at the same time, we are removing an uncertainty that has been impacting our stock price. We are in a second to none position in the market to capture the significant growth potential of the telecom industry in this country, and it gives us a quantum leap versus all the other players.</p>
          <p>The entity resulting from a combination of Telesp and Vivo will be totally the largest integrated operation in the growing Brazilian market by operating and financial metrics, but also the most efficient player with the combined OIBDA margin of 35% in 2009 and for the room to improve as a result of the very significant synergies that will arise from the combination of the two companies. And more importantly, this transaction was accretive in terms of both net income and the free cash flow from year one.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide number 20, the price conditions of the final agreement are substantially identical to the economic value of the offer supported by Portugal Telecom shareholders at the EGM, which included a cash payment of &#x20AC;7.15 billion plus other conditions with additional value and we avoid a long litigation process. Taken into account that 40% of the price agreed will be paid to Portugal Telecom in deferred installments and that PT will not receive Vivo's 2009 accrued dividends. The net present value is equivalent to &#x20AC;7.3 billion, which internally leads to a 7.1 billion value, if you were to exclude the value of the co-option on us taking PT that the previous offer had included. And all other obligations included in the previous offer disappear or are subject to a non-compete condition in Brazil. Let me say that on our stake in Portugal Telecom were the happy holders and will benefit from many appreciation of the stock in the near-term.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to slide number 21 to review the financial metrics of the acquisition. The 7.3 billion net present value of the price we're paying for PT stake in Brasilcel compares with a DCF valuation of Vivo in the 3.4 to &#x20AC;4 billion range taking in WACC and G assumptions. We're firmly committed to generate the minimum value between 3.3 and &#x20AC;3.9 billion through operating synergies from the combination of Telesp Vivo, benefits for Vivo from our regional management model, financial and tax synergies. In the sense, it is our intention to merge Brasilcel into a Spanish entity, so the direct interest in Vivo is directly held from the Spain.</p>
          <p>From the closing of the deal, the Brasilcel's structure becomes unnecessary and this could also lead to tax synergies significantly higher than initially anticipated. The round figure of synergies will depend on the different structures and the strategies implemented in the integration, but we are committed to give additional details after the closing of the transaction. We do also reiterate our intention to acquire the remaining voting shares of Vivo at 80% of the price offered to PT, which will allow us to average down the price to 10.2 times from value to 2011 EBITDA multiple excess synergies.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we want to use our internal assumptions in synergies as multiple would be significantly lower. If you consider the book value of our current stake in Vivo as approximately for the historical cost of our investment in Vivo, then that as a result of this transaction we will be the undisputed leader in Brazil, the equation much more balanced and we expect the Brazilian market to be re-rated on the back of the strength of this current economy and all the structural reforms made in the past years.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me just remind you of the key dates of the process in slide number 22. The closing should not take longer than 60 days from the signing of the agreement, and therefore, we expect to get full control of Brasilcel by the end of September with the approval of Anatel within the closing period. This will take the control the maximum period for closing the tender offer for the voting shares will be 150 days, so the whole process should be finished by the end of February 2011. To sum up, a key strategic movement for us that benefits both companies' shareholders and positions Telef&#xF3;nica in an unmatchable place in the Brazilian market.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to Europe in the slide number 23. In Europe, we continued delivering good financial and operating performance in the second quarter of the year, consolidating our solid momentum in the UK and German core markets and also seeing signs of improvement in the Czech and Irish markets. The company continued managing activity its portfolio of assets, asset sale of non-core bench telecom demonstrate.</p>
          <p>Year-on-year performance across key growth drivers were maintained with total access exceeding 54 million, improved quality adds is reflected in the two percentage points increase in the contract mix over total mobile customer base at 48% at the end of June, while mobile broadband accesses increased year-on-year by 54% over 8 billion accesses mainly on smartphones.</p>
          <p>To highlight this strong year-on-year growth in non-peer to peer SMS data revenue 72% in the first half of 2010 in organic terms. As a result, organic revenue growth in the first half of 2010 ramped up to a 6.5% year-on-year excluding the impact from MTR cuts. Profitability was remarkable, despite the increased commercial activity across countries with OIBDA margin of 28% in the first half maintained over 2009 in comparable terms. Operating cash flow grew 10.3% year-on-year as well in comparable terms.</p>
          <p>Telef&#xF3;nica O2 UK continued to deliver a steady growth in the second quarter of 2010, with mobile service revenues ramping up to 10.3% year-on-year, excluding the impact for mobile termination rates. The main driver was the 2% year-on-year expansion of the contract customer base to reach 47% of the total base at the end of June. This combined with the direct 1.1% churn rate reinforces O2's status as the network of choice in the UK market for high-value customers. Underlying ARPU evolution 2.2% year-on-year in local currency and excluding regulatory effects chose our success to drive demand for smartphones, which resulted in robust year-on-year growth in mobile non-peer-to-peers SMS data revenues in local currency, up 43% up to June.</p>
          <p>The recent most to achieve data pricing to be applied from October for new customers signing in is setting the standard for the industry and it is an important loop in order to fully monetize the explosion in data traffic. Second quarter revenue growth was also positively impacted by improved roaming trends. Finally, and despite increased commercial activity, O2 increased its OIBDA margin year-on-year to reach 25.5% in the first half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Please turn now to slide number 25. Telef&#xF3;nica O2 Germany made further progress with its strategy to maintain its third position in the market with HanseNet integration progressing smoothly, the acquisition of additional spectrum in May setting vision for future growth and benefiting from additional scale in the mobile broadband space. The company grew its mobile customer base 9% year-on-year up to June on the back of the solid growth in the contract base and then improved performance in the prepaid segment in the quarter due to seasonal promotions launched through partnered channels.</p>
          <p>Mobile service revenue rose close to a 3% year-on-year in the second quarter driven by the success of O2o tariff and sustained progress in mobile broadband, which involved non-P2P SMS data revenue is up 35% year-on-year in the first half of the year. Please notice that service revenue growth after June was dragged by MTR cuts with a negative 1.4 percentage points hit and also due to the My Handy product, which removes the handset subsidy component from the service revenue. The company also posted a solid increase in fixed service revenues.</p>
          <p>OIBDA rose an increased the scale and higher efficiencies in most cost areas growing 9.5% year-on-year in organic terms, in the first half of the year, which have reported 23.5 margin -- 23.5% margin stable over the previous year in organic terms. The higher margin achieved in the second quarter of 24.4% was driven by the above mentioned seasonal campaigns, though it was lower year-on-year on different shaping of natural roaming cost recognitions along the year.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 26, you'll see that our ratio of the net financial debt to OIBDA stands at 2.2 times or 2.3 times when included debt like cash commitments, basically the same level that we had at the end of the first quarter. And the euro weakness has added &#x20AC;2.2 billion extra debt and throughout the year due to translation into euro supply availability denominated in Latin America and in other foreign currencies.</p>
          <p>We have continued reinforcing our liquidity position, our undrawn committed credit lines have reached &#x20AC;10.1 billion, &#x20AC;1.8 billion higher in the year and we have continued our refinancing in July. After relying in the euro and U.S. phone markets, we have now tapped in the bond market and the 11 subsidiaries continue their financing activities in the local credit markets. We have signed an &#x20AC;8 billion loan including the &#x20AC;3 billion five-year transfer refinancing future loan maturities, where we raised since last quarter close to &#x20AC;800 million in Latin America, of which our Mexican subsidiary issued four-year and 10-year peso denominated bonds for close to &#x20AC;362 million equivalent in July. This shows our ability -- the ability of the group to diversify its funding sources in a tough credit market. Our financial results include a foreign currency loss to commercial debt in U.S. dollars in Venezuela, while our effective interest rate kept the improvements seen in the first quarter standing again just below 5% of our &#x20AC;47.8 billion average of total debt.</p>
          <p>To recap, we are fully exploiting our diversified profile, our scale in our strong execution capabilities to deliver strong earnings with significant sequential improvements in growth rates across the P&amp;L despite economic weakness in Spain. The increase in our second leader will further force the diversification then increase our exposure to the growing Brazilian market. These solid results are highlighted by our superior organic top line growth, our strong margins, and our robust cash flow generation in any context of reinvesting efficiency gains to force the revenue expansion.</p>
          <p>A focused commercial push and not just expanding our customer base, but also enhancing customer value through an improved quality base and through the broadband adoption and CapEx focused on growth levers like mobile broadband spectrum reflect our strategy to deliver the next solid growth in our markets. At the same time, we maintain a robust balance sheet, a key differentiator factor and the current turmoil and we are fully on track to make 2010 our mid-term guidance and we do confirm our dividend targets for the coming years. Shareholder remuneration continues to be our first priority for the use of free cash flow and year-to-date we have returned substantial cash to shareholders with close to &#x20AC;3 billion having been paid in dividends. Thank you very much for your attention and now we're ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from David George from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Firstly just on your M&amp;A strategy, post the Vivo deal and the expected Telesp merger. I mean what are your remaining hours of focus if any, and what are the implications to these deals for shareholder returns or specifically buybacks over the next 12 to 18 months?</p>
          <p>And secondly, if I could just ask on the guidance, obviously, you've reached all your mid-term target today, but obviously, the Vivo deal and the anticipated material synergies from the Telesp merger, does that actually give you scope to raise the mid-term guidance, or this more about reassuring on the achievability of the existing guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks this is Santiago, thanks, David, for the question. On the M&amp;A strategy, we're just following the path that we set out in October last year in our investor conference. We then said that we wanted to finalize our deals in Brazil with the Vivo transaction business that is pretty much completed. We wanted to buy spectrum in both Germany and Mexico and this has been completed and the only pending thing from that list is an increase in our China Unicom investment up to 10%, but we are under no rush to do so, but eventually it might be complete. Other than that, our scale diversification and end-market consolidation capabilities have been pretty much fulfilled. We're quite happy that we could do it ahead of the end of the year.</p>
          <p>On Brazil, we're not going to change guidance until the whole thing changes, now the decision is going to be a multiple months process. The combination of Telesp y Vivo will not be done overnight and we'll regularly update you on when and if things change and what kind of an impact that you should expect. We have certainly said that this combination is going to elicit a very significant synergies and we have already committed today to be much more precise until the closing of the deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question comes from David Wright from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's David here. I have a couple of questions. I guess the first one is very simple follow-on from the previous. When do you think Telesp transaction could potentially take place within the timeline you've given? And on just on the Vivo transaction for the moment, when could you give us some guidance on how you will treat goodwill, for instance? Then my second question is on Spain, you had indicated about yourself, I believe, and also Guillermo to mete out from the middle of May also you had seen a slowdown in consumer behavior following the announcement of the austerity measures. Is that what is driving some of the slower minutes of use growth? I also noted there was some pressure on DSL ARPU. Is there a need perhaps to or has there been a need to reduce pricing a little just to retain some subscribers? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, again on the Telesp y Vivo combination, we should first wait for the closing of the Vivo transaction then for the execution of the mandatory tender offer for the voting shares. This is as I think we said in the presentation unlikely to happen before the end of February and that we will run this as fast as we can and the most of the plants are literally already being built. But Ii is not very easy to see that transaction having been complete, I don't know before the end of the first and maybe the second quarter of next year. But again, there are some gray areas that we have to work on in the coming weeks and we'll regularly update you on that.</p>
          <p>On the goodwill question, by the closing of the transaction, we'll allow exactly in which way we've finally struck to the deal. We now think that having Spanish entity buying or emerging into the Brazil or Dutch entity might have some beneficial effects and if that is indeed the case, we will certainly try and maximize them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, this is Guillermo. Regarding Spain, there are two separate issues. One is the shape of a consumption in -- across the quarter. As you remember, and you mentioned, April was a great month for us basically in consumption and traffic and in sales. And since mid-May we start to seeing some slowdown and some decrease in the recovery of consumer confidence. We are also seeing some slight recovery by the end of the June. July is coming better than May. So there was a slowdown and regarding austerity measures, remember that we're announcing May that we're not implementing until July. So it's much more -- the shape of the consumption is much more expectation rather than real impact. So we have to see going forward what happens on the consumption. I note that much concern on our product sector revenues and this just was multi-year flat type of contract, but consumption may be affected for example in the VAT increased prepaid customers tend to be more expense fixed in other segments.</p>
          <p>Regarding ADSL ARPU, it's a different story. We have still about four degrees in total ARPU in broadband fixed ARPU in Spain. It's a combination of factors. One, last year in the first quarter, for example, we have in the gross adds a &#x20AC;9.9 promotion, while this year in the first quarter we have 99.9, so the first quarter this year looks a little bit less stretch down previous year. But when you look at the second quarter last year, we had 29.9 that's the promotion and this year 99.9. So on the other side and the mathematics works on the other way around. Also this quarter, in April we took the decision to decrease the price of our 10 megabit, is a small portion of our base by this decrease in price. And also there is a series of small adjustments. So I expect the third quarter evolution of ARPU will be better than the second one, but the ARPU of the ADSL the shape in the second quarter is much more due to several factors added on consumption changes. What is true? As you mentioned is that in general the broadband market was slower in the second quarter and the first quarter in general.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all. That was very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Luis Prota from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello. My question -- my first question is from the Portugal Telecom shares. You were mentioning something Santiago in the presentation that I was missing, sorry for that. But if you could give us on update on what's the current status whether you physically own the shares already or what's this equity swap contract at the moment and whether -- I think you were mentioning some positive impact in the short term, from that you could elaborate a bit more on that and whether there is a book gain, a difference against the book value to be recorded in the potential in the third quarter, I guess, it would be useful?</p>
          <p>And then, the second question is on the adjustments you made for hyper inflation in Venezuela. If you could -- I've seen that in the first quarter, there was a negative impact of -- it was eight, &#x20AC;9 million, but then it was very, very positive more than &#x20AC;100 million in the second quarter. If you could just explain to me the math behind that would be useful? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Luis. On our previous shares, we hold physically more than two -- I think north of 2% of the shares and we have equity swaps for just about 8%. So we're long on PT stock and we are under no obligation to deliver it or we have finally not granted any call to anyone, which means that we are free to trade as we see fit. That's the only point I was trying to raise in the call. That we are now as any other shareholder interested in PT shares doing well and we hope that they certainly do well going forward. If and when eventually the full service is done, and that is not something we're contemplating in the short-term, it will be the time to record a book gain, because we bought the share so long ago that we are now sitting on a profit there. on your hyper inflation in Venezuela I think there is a technicality involved and it is because the valuation happened on January 7, technically we have seven days of 2.15 average rate.</p>
          <p>And whatever 30, 27 days or the 17 days of the new regime and that's what makes confusing and actually hyperinflation should be on -- in general a small positive for the numbers. But if the Q1 is the exception because there is a combination of average exchange rates coming from last year in two months and three weeks of the new regime and that's what is confusing. It's difficult to derive at an undisputable number that basically takes you from Q1 to Q2 numbers without any doubt. But we can try and walk you through that details if you so wish.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question comes from James McKenzie from Fidentiis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Couple of questions. First of all, on the options 150 million, over 150 million shares you mentioned in your previous presentation. I was wondering, could you give us anymore detail about those options and do you still hold them? And then secondly, I think, your guidance on the interest rates for the year at the event conference call was 5.5 to 5.75%. In the year-to-date, we're looking at slightly below 5%. Would you be willing to revisit that guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, James. On the 150 millions calls those are elongated, we still hold them and I'm sure that they will pull their words in due course and we have of course intention of keeping them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our interest cost, we guided at the beginning of the year for, I think, it was  5 3/4 quarters. We have since improved that thing it is now more likely than not that we will end up say below 5.5% although the highly volatile marking-to-market of <mark type="inaudible" /> liabilities and some FX, make it difficult to be more precise, because of course nobody knows what the exact shape of the currency markets will be in Q4. We are highly confident that a bid on the 5.5 number is going to be achieved out by year-end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sure. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Tim Boddy at Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks. Question for Matthew in fact around the impact of VAT increases in Europe, more generally, obviously less color on that, but should we expect those to be passed through or would they have a similar impact to the one we've seen in Spain and really, any color on those type of austerity measures across the European businesses will be very helpful. Secondly also, it would be great to get a better understanding of your strategy in Germany now you've been successful in the auction for 800. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tim. Let me kick off on the German question. As you know, we had a very clear strategy going into the auction to acquire the 800 spectrum that we wanted and some 2.6 as well. So we came out with the spectrum that we wanted. We're now launching our first commercial trial in 2010 in Munich and Halle both in Germany. Going forward, as far as network share and strategy is concerned what we've done is put ourselves clearly in a very strong position to have choices. In principle network share is something we would do and that's the case in certainly in all the countries in Europe. What shape that takes, we'll wait and see, but it's clear with the spectrum base that we've got and the network base that we've clearly got choices in terms of what we do and who we potentially partner with.</p>
          <p>On austerity, I think we're relatively lowly exposed to government expenditure, apart from in the Czech Republic and the good news in the Czech Republic is we've clearly now got a government there, whereas previously we've had a mid-term government and so we expect that that spending to return in the Czech Republic and Germany and the UK relatively lowly exposed. I guess my only concern would be consumer confidence and that something that clearly we'll need to see in all other markets, not overly worried in Germany, maybe in the UK. From a VAT perspective, we would likely parse it through, we would have to look at market conditions, but I wouldn't expect us to absorb any VAT potential increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Robin Bienenstock from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just two questions. I'm wondering if you can give us any update on Venezuelan cash expatriation and then really I'm just curious about your debt, I'm wondering if you can update us on what percentage of your debt is variable and in what currency it's split? And if you did increase in China Unicom, how would you think about doing that, is that cash or shares? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robin, I didn't pick up your last sentence from the question, could you please repeat it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sure, the last question was really about your debt. I'm wondering what percentage is variable and in what currencies it's split, and then also were you to go &#x2013; were you to increase in China Unicom, I'm wondering how you would think about doing that, is it shares or cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On Venezuelan cash, we are now sitting in roughly $1.8 million worth of idle cash there. We have lower expectations for that to be repatriated now than we had at the beginning of the year two things have happened there. The market for the parallel dollars have been shut down. And now dollars are much more difficult to get for any purpose and the economic environment in there has actually become more difficult and so the environment is now less conducive to the promises or the commitments that we had heard, being able to be honored.</p>
          <p>On the debt composition, we have now 69% of our debt in euros roughly 16% in Latin American currencies, British sterling is 7%, U.S. dollars straight 4%. The Czech Crown is 4%. So you see not a major change or a slight increase in euro relative to where we were. Were we -- to increase our stake in China, it is more likely than not that it will be done through a cash commitment. But that decision will have to be made when and if that opportunity presents itself, which is still not the case. On variable versus fixed, we have an active management for our maturity profile, and we have if anything tried to be slightly shorter this year on some currencies, 46% is now fixed and the other is either bounded or fully floating, although there are some differences -- there are some differences depending on the currency you look at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question comes from Iv&#xF3;n Leal from BBVA. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello. Good afternoon. A couple of ones. The first one in Spain for Guillermo, you say that you've made some efforts in pricing in the broadband prices in the second quarter, but actually if we look at the net share of -- the share of net adds in broadband in the couple of months, in the last couple of months have increased very much. Why exactly is that? Is it increased competition or maybe just strategy has changed and you're trying to sustain prices I mean if  you could tell a little bit on that in detail if you're going to take any specific step to rearrange that? That's the first one.</p>
          <p>And the second one in Mexico, I think you've been very successful in the spectrum auctions, which just took place. I don't know if that changes your strategy in the market going forward in terms of -- I think that you had a target of sharing mobiles of 25% going forward. So I don't know if that's going to change a bit your CapEx going forward and your strategy going forward in the Mexican market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Iv&#xF3;n, this is Guillermo Ansaldo, I will answer the Spanish questions. First, let me clarify what we did in pricing in the second quarter is we changed the price of one of the services to 10 mega bits, which is a small portion of our base and we reduced it from 44.9 to 41.9, the three unit reduction for our base and only for those people that have 10 Mb connections in our base, the majority, as you know, in Spain it's 6 Mb.</p>
          <p>Now regarding our performance in net gains, two things. First, it's not churn. Churn in fact is improving from the last three quarters. It's more robust and regarding gross adds, you have to see two things in the second quarter  the market was slower, so that the growth of the market was smaller than in the first quarter. And obviously in our case, also we have a smaller share of this gross adds basically we have a similar number of very strong campaign in the first part of the year that was very successful and in the second part of the year. year what we did is that we changed our brands.</p>
          <p>So we focused our communication, our advertising on the changes of our brand and bring in Movistar to our fixed portfolio and also trying to build brand values around Movistar. And also we've seen in competition -- very, very active competition for example <mark type="inaudible" /> and Orange with very aggressive promotions ranging from just 7.95 as a promotion for a few months and also Orange with an 11.95 promotion for six months. So I think the major factor is not churn, it is gross ads, the market was slower and we're much more focused in the second quarter on changing the brand and building our brand values around Movistar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we have to assume that you are going to do something to change that in the coming quarters. I mean you're not comfortable with that 20% of share net adds that you have been delivering?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, obviously we prefer to have more share of net adds than less but are not going to do any a wild move. We'll continue with our strategy of trying to extract more value and for us to reduce churn is a value driver and it's better to get this performance with this churn then with more gross ads and more churn. So we are satisfied with this route. Obviously I prefer more a share of net adds than less no? But there's not going to be any sharp change in the short-term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Taking your question on Mexico, so we've been successful in getting a significant part of the spectrum we're looking for. We are very happy about that because we have been looking for a long, long while to get more spectrum and therefore to enlarge our data capacity in the country. In fact, that was part of our strategy already this year. Remember that we have been trying to focus on the contract part of the customer base and we have been able to get 35% of the net ads of the quarter on contract. That was already our strategy. We needed to pursue that strategy more with spectrum namely on the capital city. We have managed to get that spectrum and the spectrum has been already awarded to us and we think that it's already operational. So our traffic is growing, our total traffic is growing.</p>
          <p>We think that we are on the right track and we will foster our prepaid campaign because we have been a little bit weak on prepaid in the second quarter. But everything is being developed as we were planning on the budget the only thing that we're missing is a spectrum, and now we have it. So nothing other that I can tell you. Data revenues by the way are growing very nicely almost 20% year-on-year and they already represent 22% of total revenue. So we are on the right track and now we think to push a little bit more on prepaid and to get going on this data expansion on the contract customer side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question comes from Jonathan Dann from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions. One is on the stake in Portugal Telecom. Once Portugal Telecom has a stake in Oy, would you be allowed under Brazilian regulation to hold, I guess, stakes in Telecom Italia directly in Vivo, Telesp and also an indirect stake in Portugal Telecom? And then my second question, if you had any thoughts on how the UK spectrum auction might change under the new government?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jonathan, let me start with the Portuguese. And we have owned a PT stake for 14 years. We have been together in Vivo for a long time. We in principle see no reason why that -- this new move, which is just an increase in our stake, not a beginning of a new stake, it should mean any change. But if there is anything, we will of course state it in great detail.</p>
          <p>On our Italian end that it took the regulators in Brazil almost two years to clear that our absence of conflict and we expect no change from that end, so we don't particularly see any reason why that could be changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jonathan, I'll pick up your UK question. The Statutory Instrument of the government announced yesterday, I think, was already focusing on creating a digital Briton. We welcomed it. I think the two key moves for us was clearly allowing 3G on 900 megahertz, which is a big thing for us, particularly virtually all of the smartphones that are coming now have got that inbuilt to the chipset, so that's a big positive and also clearly the license extension on 3G.</p>
          <p>As to the structure of the auction, I think the Statutory Instrument was less clear. It was really thrown over to Ofcom clearly what they've got to consider firstly is -- everything everywhere will have to get the 1,800 spectrum as a result of their merger. And then the second question of outcome clearly needs to approach its caps on the 800 spectrum. So we welcome 900 on 3G and the license extension and wait to see what happens on the auction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Will Milner, Arete Research. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. Couple of questions. Just on the Vivo deal, you said yesterday I think you expected the deal to have a positive impact earnings and cash flow. I just wanted to understand whether you still think the deal would be accretive, if mobile termination rates get cut 20% annually, as I think some recent rumors have suggested they might, Looking at Vivo's results yesterday, I mean I guess interconnect revenue is less interconnect costs are about 20% in revenue and 60% of EBITDA. So I mean it's like doubling up of your mobile exposure, I mean, MTR cuts is a risk, whether the deal is accretive or not.</p>
          <p>And then secondly to Matthew on the mobile data, you mentioned you're ahead of a learning curve in understanding customer behavior and usage patterns. And I just wondered if you can talk a bit more around that that's an interesting topic, particularly given the decision to drop unlimited data bolt-ons from September. Do you think this is n evitable shift that all operators will make. I'm thinking further ahead, how do you envisage the pricing model for voice and data looking in, say, five years time? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take your question of the MTR cut in Brazil. Let me first say that the numbers that you're running are not the ones that we have in terms of net exposure to OIBDA, the net exposure to interconnection, the level of OIBDA is now below 20%, on the level of OIBDA therefore the exposure is much lower than the ones you were contemplating. And now on the question of when and how that the MTR cut is going to happen is a big uncertainty. Recent rumors were pointed to our false decision on that. And now it looks that is again postponed, we think is going to happen. We are now in, but we think it's going to happen progressively rather than a drastic initial cut.</p>
          <p>Anyhow, remember that a significant part, the large majority of our traffic is already on the traffic, and that the reduction of interconnection exposure to OIBDA has been going down progressively in the last year and as I was telling you before is now below the 20% first quarter the level of Vivo. So we will, as you might imagine, keep you posted, but that was already embedded in the business trend that we are running, when making the offer that that was going to come. So it's no surprise and the only question is when and at what pace. So just from on that side, we will monitor that and we will let you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me try and pick up your questions. It was a -- I think there was three or four in there. On the mobile data usage, clearly we've been through a massive learning curve in the UK and particularly in London. We're now using right across the group from a Telef&#xF3;nica perspective. I would say there was two key take-outs for us. The first is that I think the interactions with the network is a lot more, what I would call, snacking it's a very quick interactions in and out the phone pool in the network, whether you're using Facebook or getting an update on the latest Tour de France results or whatever.</p>
          <p>So lots of small interactions backwards and forwards. Clearly what we with our network partners learnt an awful lot from that. The second one on the mobile data is huge localized peaks and that's then all about getting the right share in process, which is why we've done the deal with Vodafone and one of the deals we've done with Vodafone in the UK, particularly if you use the phone at London bridge, you'll recognize that this network problems are because of the availability of sites.</p>
          <p>From a data perspective and the amounts of our tiering, I think it's inevitable any industry needs to match its revenue and its costs, and what was happening, I think, in the heavy data market is the traffic was exploding from a data perspective and therefore the cost to serve it, but revenue was staying flat, because of the effective flat top. So what we've clearly done is, it introduced or will introduce in October, I think, it is sort of tiering structure. Why and where with the first thing to say, we've introduced a 83% of our customers will be impacted by it initially. And we pitched it there on purpose to give you a view to those, 3% of customers actually use about 65% of the data going through our network, so a massive strain on the network there. Those customers will either end up paying more or going to another operator, either one is positive for us.</p>
          <p>And the key for us is that actually where we've pitched it people's data expansion, our usage is clearly expanding all the time. And over time, more and more of customer base will move into that charging area that we've set.</p>
          <p>Your third question was on data and voice and how I see it going forward. Clearly, what is happening in data is expanding, voice is decreasing with voice competition and some Voice over IP minutes going off of our network. The real question for the industry is how quickly did data offset that voice decline, clearly what we're getting is a lot of access data at the moment and you can see in our ARPUs and our ARPUs excluding MTRs in the UK and actually going up now and hitting a positive trend. The more data that customers end up paying for, clearly ends up in a positive trend overall it will more than offset the voice decline. So hopefully, I have picked up all of your questions in that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Very helpful thank you. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from Stanley Martinez from Legal and General Investments. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. First, returning to the <mark type="audio gap" /> case, within the 3.3 to &#x20AC;3.9 billion or is there a minimum level of NOLs that can be applied to the Spanish and Dutch entity? And second, on financing, the Brasilcel transaction. On slide 20, you used a 5% discount rate to present value, the cash outflows. And that's equivalent to Telef&#xF3;nica's effective interest rate. However, Telef&#xF3;nica had 6.6 billion in cash and equivalents. And I surmise that perhaps &#x20AC;4 billion less than what's truly necessary to have cash to run the businesses and the term facility that you agreed to last night probably has less than a 2% all in cost including the commitment fees. So especially given the deferred cash payment schedule is it very conservative to assume a marginal interest expense that's associated with the transaction as &#x20AC;7.5 billion at a 5% rate, or is it more realistic that Telef&#xF3;nica can fund the vast majority of the Brasilcel buy in just by using internally generated free cash flows and not having a marginal interest expense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, the condition was pretty bad so I'm not sure we have picked up every detail and if this is the case please either interact or ask the question fully. If I understand your question correctly you're asking that this is not the appropriate discount rate to be used for discounting and projecting the cash flows to be held from Brasilcel. So this indicated loan package that we finished at last night is a euro loan and therefore on a very competitive terms that Telef&#xF3;nica along with some, but not many borrowers can take.</p>
          <p>So you may want to use that number. For the commercial purposes of the delayed payment reported on Portugal Telecom we have used around 5% and just not to be very confusing, but you may want to use your best guess or your best value for that number. We don't claim that to be the only discount rate possibly applicable there. And other than that as I mentioned in the presentation, we strive for a lower than 5.5% overall increase, we have cash not idle, but actually earning interest in many places. We don't really open the exception of Venezuela, is because it doesn't make sense to do so for tax reasons. So we try and run as tight a ship as possible, lot of the cash that takes in some of our subsidiaries gets channeled upstairs through our cash treasury or -- cash treasury management programs and instrument and again with the exception of Venezuela where we don't have idle cash, we will bring it home. But again with the exception of Venezuela everything we do is for a good reason most likely they are coming on transaction -- I'm sorry on taxes on short-term transactions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for one additional question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The final question comes from Jesus Romero from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have two questions on the Vivo transaction. The first one for Santiago, if you could give us a detail of what level of net debt to EBITDA you expect to see in next 12 months in terms of, what would be the peak. And then I don't know if you can give us any more detail on the what percentage of the synergies your giving us or coming from taxes? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the headline number that we expect and the increase of debt to OIBIDA, especially taken into account that a lot of the OIBITA still remains to be generated in the second half is 0.25. So that's the overall increase in the net-debt-to- OIBIDA ratio at current exchange rates everything is sensible to a program into the leverage ratios.</p>
          <p>How much of that is going to be taxes, and again remains to be same, assuming that closing is a smooth process, which is what we expect. And we will then know in which manner the final taking of Brasilcel shares has been down and whether or not the tax synergy can be taken from the transaction level. Of course we have been very vocal in the process about what the combination of Telesp y Vivo might entail in the form of <mark type="inaudible" /> or a goodwill to be generated in Brazil, but that is not likely to come this year but rather next year. Specifically we'll keep you updated very in full when the transaction closes essentially by the Q2 results and that's done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the opportunity to thank you all for having attended this summer conference call for Telef&#xF3;nica. We certainly hope that the second half of the year will be more benign in both the economic environment and as balmy as the weather seems to be in most parts of the Northern Hemisphere. All the best to all of you, who have still a few days off and to go on holidays and we'll see each other or we'll listen to each other in a few months. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>