<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1157098" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>685</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Mar&#xED;a Garc&#xED;a-Legaz Ponce, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Santiago Fern&#xE1;ndez Valbuena, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Damien Maltarp</participant>
      <participant id="4">Guillermo Ansaldo</participant>
      <participant id="5">Santiago Fern&#xE1;ndez Valbuena</participant>
      <participant id="6">Mar&#xED;a Garc&#xED;a-Legaz Ponce</participant>
      <participant id="7">Terrence Sinclair</participant>
      <participant id="8">Christian Kern</participant>
      <participant id="9">Matthew Key</participant>
      <participant id="10">Javier Mar&#xED;n</participant>
      <participant id="11">James Ratzer</participant>
      <participant id="12">Jos&#xE9; Mar&#xED;a &#xC1;lvarez-Pallete L&#xF3;pez</participant>
      <participant id="13">Luis Prota</participant>
      <participant id="14">Julio Linares L&#xF3;pez</participant>
      <participant id="15">David George</participant>
      <participant id="16">Mathieu Robilliard</participant>
      <participant id="17">Iv&#xF3;n Leal</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to Telef&#xF3;nica's 2008 First Quarter Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to your Chairperson, Mar&#xED;a Garc&#xED;a-Legaz, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. And welcome to Telef&#xF3;nica's conference call to discuss 2008 first quarter results. I am Mar&#xED;a Garc&#xED;a-Legaz, Head of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that that this document contains financial information that are reported under IFRS. The financial information contained in this document has been prepared under International Financial Reporting Standards. This financial information is generated and therefore is subject to potential future modifications.</p>
          <p>This presentation may contain announcements and that constitute forward-looking statements, which are not guarantees of future performance and involve risks and uncertainties and actual results may differ materially from those in the forward-looking statements, as a result of various factors.</p>
          <p>We invite you to read the complete disclaimer included in the first page of the presentation, which you will find in our website. We encourage you to review our publicly available disclosure documents filed with the relevant securities market regulators.</p>
          <p>If you do not have a copy of the relevant press release and the slides, please contact Telef&#xF3;nica's Investor Relations team in Madrid by dialing the following telephone number, 34-91-482-8700.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn the call over to our CFO, Mr. Santiago Fern&#xE1;ndez Valbuena who will be leading this conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and thank you for attending Telef&#xF3;nica's 2008 January-March results conference call. During the Q&amp;A session you will have the opportunity to ask questions directly to the members of our Executive Committee.</p>
          <p>Also I have here today with me Julio Linares, our Chief Operating Officer; Guillermo Ansaldo, the Head of Telef&#xF3;nica Espa&#xF1;a; also Jos&#xE9; Mar&#xED;a &#xC1;lvarez-Pallete, Head of Telef&#xF3;nica Latinoam&#xE9;rica, and Matthew Key, Head of Telef&#xF3;nica Europe who is connected by a conference call.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter of 2008, we have delivered another set of strong results and we are well on track to meet our full year guidance both for the group and the three regional business units. Against the backdrop of a softer European economy, we continue to post strong organic growth rates showing our distinctive profile in the industry.</p>
          <p>Our highly diversified portfolio and the integrated management of operations translates into a robust organic revenue growth rate, which ramps up to the bottom line leading to an over 25% increase in earnings per share year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet remains solid allowing to transfer the high cash generation to our shareholders. Shareholder remuneration continues to be our first priority and our commitment is supported by the accelerated execution of a new share buyback program that we announced two months ago.</p>
          <p>For the 15th quarter in a row and despite negative impacts from changes in consolidation and foreign exchange, we have posted simultaneous year-on-year growth in the key items across the P&amp;L as shown in Slide number 4.</p>
          <p>In the first three months of the year, revenues rose 1.1% to end just below 13.9 billion euros. Organic sales growth stood at 7% year-on-year, well ahead of our peers being the 17th consecutive quarter to bring organic growth of up to 7%.</p>
          <p>Operating income before D&amp;A reached almost 5.4 billion euros in the first quarter showing a 5.3% annual increase which turned into 8.2% growth rate in organic terms. Operating income exceeded the 3 billion euros mark in the three months period, up 14% in nominal terms or 17% organically. Operating cash flow topped 4.1 billion euros, 9% above the 2007 first quarter figures while in organic terms it rose close to 12%.</p>
          <p>As in previous quarters, operating results are fully flowing into the group's net income as you can see in slide number 5. Generally through March, net income reached 1.5 million euros, 22% above last year's figure and more than 8 percentage points above operating income growth.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share in the first quarter of '08 reached 0.328 euros rising 26% year-on-year. If we exclude the impact from the purchase price allocations from EPS, EPS would have reached 0.362 euros.</p>
          <p>On slide number 6, we show the outstanding customer growth recorded across businesses and regions. Our commercial push to fully exploit growth potential mainly in mobile and the fixed broadband and to capture the value from the bundling opportunity have allowed us to reach more than 253 million accesses by the end of March or 13% higher than a year ago.</p>
          <p>Strong customer growth led to more than 4.7 million net adds in Q1, 42% above the last year's figures. Mobile net adds were very strong representing over 80% of total net adds, leading to a total of mobile access base of 172 million.</p>
          <p>In the broadband field, group retail connections grew 27% year-on-year, topping close to 11 million with net adds in the quarter exceeding the 550,000 mark. We ended the quarter with almost 2 million pay TV accesses or 64% more than in March '07, with our new offerings in Latin America showing good results. I would like to stress that 36% of our total assets are voice, broadband, TV bundles, leading us to capture more value from our customers.</p>
          <p>Now moving to slide number seven, we show that the solid operating performance, reflecting the expansion of our customer base and higher usage of our networks does fully flow into the revenue base despite the depreciation of the U.S. dollar versus the euro, the strong revenue growth recorded by Telef&#xF3;nica Latinoam&#xE9;rica places it as the largest contributor to group sales with over 37% of group revenue in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Our operations in the region, which have posted a close to 13% increase in sales in organic terms continue to drive our growth, explaining more than 60% of Telef&#xF3;nica Group organic revenue growth in Q1. In addition, the sound top line expansion recorded both in Spain and rest of Europe allowed to deliver a best-in-class organic growth rate, which reached 7% at the group level.</p>
          <p>From a business perspective, mobile and fixed broadband are the main growth engines with a 27% year-on-year organic increase in mobile broadband revenues and a 13.6% organic growth in fixed broadband and value-added services sales.</p>
          <p>Top line revenue is the company's <mark type="inaudible" /> sustained benchmark profitability levels, as you can see in slide number eight. Consolidated operating income before D&amp;A grew over 8% in organic terms, showing the higher efficiencies achieved; a continuous focus on cost controls and the materialization of tangible synergies through the integrated management model.</p>
          <p>Again, Telef&#xF3;nica Latinoam&#xE9;rica continues to drive growth at the group level with a year-on-year organic increase in OIBDA close to 12%. The group's OIBDA margin reached 38.7% in Q1, 1.5 percentage points higher than the last year's figure due to the enhanced margin at Telef&#xF3;nica Espa&#xF1;a and stable margins posted both in Telef&#xF3;nica Europe and Telef&#xF3;nica Latinoam&#xE9;rica despite strong commercial activity and the ongoing process to transform our businesses.</p>
          <p>Please turn now to slide number nine for a review of our regional business units starting with Telef&#xF3;nica Espa&#xF1;a. In the context of global economic growth, our business performance in the first quarter remains solid with revenue growth reaching 2.6% on a comparable basis. Both wireless and wireline show sound growth rates with the 2% respectively on a comparable basis sustaining this superior performance.</p>
          <p>Higher bolt-on revenues and healthy trends in traditional voice services back an above average revenue performance in wireline while we continue posting data right in the nexus of 16% year-on-year led to a 3.4% customer revenue growth in wireless. Roaming in revenues performance was outstanding despite global prices showing the benefits of the integrated management of wholesale roaming agreements at the group level.</p>
          <p>Underlying OIBDA growth excluding real estate capital gains and a recovery of bad debts reached 2.8% driven by a robust 4% increase in wireline, or lower IT and personal costs and a 1.3% year-on-year increase in wireless.</p>
          <p>OIBDA margin remains flat versus Q1 '07 at Telef&#xF3;nica Espa&#xF1;a on a like-for-like basis at 48.8%. Margin in wireline advanced 0.9 percentage points to a comparable 47.9% while in wireless profitability remained healthy with a 43.4% underlying margin in a very competitive market.</p>
          <p>Slide number 10 provides more color on the trends we are seeing in wireline. The Spanish traditional access market continues to record good growth rates plus close to 2% year-on-year despite the shortfall in the construction sector. Telef&#xF3;nica's cross activity in non-bundling was similar to previous quarters. However, there was a change in non-bundlers' approach driven by the introduction of the new loop type named naked shared loop. Even though this new loop was approved by the regulator at the end of 2006, it has not been until the first quarter '08 that non-bundlers have started using it as a new direct take up or as migrations from shared loops.</p>
          <p>In naked shared loops included as fully unbundled loops account already for 57% of the 135,000 full ULL let out, whereas shared loops fell 21,000 in the quarter mainly driven by migration to naked shared loops.</p>
          <p>Our pro active commercial approach with a Free Connection Fee campaign from late February to early March has allowed us to cut through part of the market growth, limiting the line loss in the quarter to 77,000 compared with the 135,000 lines captured by unbundlers. Year-on-year fixed lines were down 0.6% showing an outstanding performance versus our European peers.</p>
          <p>In broadband the market continues to decelerate, though trends have improved versus previous quarters with lower year-on-year declines in net earnings. In this context our retail broadband net asset reached 222,000 with no material changes versus previous quarters despite the seasonality of the business. We continue to enlarge our commercial portfolio launching new offers to capital market segments. Let me highlight that our broadband market share remained stable at close to 57%.</p>
          <p>In pay TV the growth is ramping up versus previous quarters. Net adds in Q1 were pretty much in line with the last quarter of '07 figures despite business seasonality. While compared with the first quarter of '07 net adds were up 21%. With more than 550,000 customers Imagenio's market share is now over 13%.</p>
          <p>In summary, solid operating metrics despite economic slowdown, consolidating our leadership in the market while capturing more value for more customers as reflected by the 2.4% year-on-year increase in wireline ARPU.</p>
          <p>Please go now to slide 11 for our spotlight on the performance of our wireless operations in Spain. A more mature market where new MVNOs are emerging, our commercial imports are focused on higher-value customers. In the last 12 months we have increased our total customers by 5.5% year-on-year to over 23 million on the back of a very healthy performance in the contract segment, which already represents over 16% of our base.</p>
          <p>In Q1 contract net adds were 305,000 leveraging our benchmark churn rate, which came down year-on-year to 1.1%. Regarding usage both MoUs and ARPUs declined a similar basis as in the fourth quarter of '07. Incoming ARPU was impacted by lower mobile termination rates; while outgoing ARPU was 2.1% down year-on-year in line with the performance posted in the previous quarter. Lower voice usage was partially upset by strong data ARPU growth.</p>
          <p>Outgoing minutes of use showed a weaker performance reflecting over traffic promotions versus the first quarter of '07 and lower usage by our customers. We continue to monitor usage patterns very closely having already launched new initiatives to force re-consumption. Outgoing data ARPU is performing very well up 11% year-on-year. A good performance in connectivity is accompanied by a strong portion content sms driving a 17% increase in total data revenue. 3G penetrations continues to expand to 19% of our total base excluding end-to-end. At the end of March we had 4.2 million 3G devices or 2.8 times more than we had a year ago.</p>
          <p>Let's now continue with a review of our Latin American properties in slide number 12. During the first quarter of '08, we further accelerated our commercial activity leveraging the strong macros in our main region with both Brazil and Peru having already become investment grade in 2008. Our total access base grew 18% year-on-year boosted by the strong increase in wireless, broadband and pay TV which reinforced the positive evolution in fixed line accesses. Telef&#xF3;nica Latinoam&#xE9;rica revenues were up 10% year-on-year in nominal terms or 14% in organic terms, with very strong growth rates both in mobile, Internet and TV revenues. By countries: Brazil, Mexico and Venezuela contributed with more than two percentage points each to revenue growth, highlighting the increasing rate over wireless businesses in the region.</p>
          <p>OIBDA increased 10% from last year, from last year figure in euro terms or 12% in organic terms on the back of very good performance in Venezuela and Mexico. As a result, and despite the strong commercial push, we pushed in a healthy margin at 36.4% versus the first quarter of '07. Margin expansion in mobile businesses offset the impact of the different revenue mix in wireline. We also recorded a strong operating cash flow generation with positive contributions from all our operations including Mexico. We are fully on track to achieve our 2008 guidance with Telef&#xF3;nica Latinoam&#xE9;rica with year-on-year growth rate accelerating in the coming quarters both in revenues and OIBDA.</p>
          <p>For an overview of Latin America wireless businesses, please turn to slide 13. Results in Q1 reached 3.1 million, up 37% year-on-year on the back of robust gross adds in most markets and churn containment in the region. Our total customer base achieved the 102 million mark, rising 23% year-on-year with double-digit growth rates in every single market and a strong performance in Brazil, Mexico and Peru. We continue to further expand the GSM base which already accounts for close to 70% of the total versus 43% a year ago driving down subscriber application costs. I'd like to stress the ARPU performance in constant terms, as it remained flat year-on-year despite a sharp growth in customers in lower mobile termination rates. This performance was driven by the healthy 4.5% year-on-year increase in constant currency in all outgoing ARPU. Then to mention that we don't notice any material impact in ARPUs from the Easter effect across the region.</p>
          <p>New commercial offerings are stimulating voice usage while data services are increasing their contribution to revenue, posting a 40% year-on-year growth, where they just represent 13% of service revenues, showing a significant growth potential. We are seeing a good evolution in 3G data propositions based on CDMA, EVDO, in Brazil and Venezuela, having already launched 3G services in Argentina, Chile and Uruguay, with other countries to come in the coming months.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the wireline businesses in slide number 14, we continue to advance in the transformation of the business, which strong net adds both in broadband and pay TV in the first quarter. We are fostering broadband and pay TV growth promoting bundles, which not only allow to increase ARPU but are a good retention tool. Bundles already represent 55% of our fixed accesses, or 12 percentage points more than in March '07. At the same time we continue to strengthen our competitive precision, enhancing our commercial portfolio with higher speeds as we have recently done Brazil and Chile and expanding network coverage in Colombia, the deployment of the network in new areas like Bogot&#xE1;, is already producing good results with a significant ramp in broadband gross adds in March versus February.</p>
          <p>In pay TV we are also getting momentum with total net adds in Q1 doubling the figure of Q1 '07 after having incorporated TVA in Brazil, and in countries where our pay TV offer is starting to take off, diverging global content. As a result, we are seeing a significant change in the revenue mix of our Wireline operations with an increased contributions of Internet and TV revenues to total revenues. That brings between the 2 percentage points increase in Argentina to 7 percentage points in Colombia. As such, the operators are having net exposure to regulated revenues. I'd like to stress that the increasing adoption of double- and triple-play offers is driving total wireline revenue brackets up 1.9% year-on-year in constants terms.</p>
          <p>To sum up, in Latin America we are capturing the strong growth potential of the region. The solid top line performance across our markets shows the strong growth rates recorded in broadband, TV and wireless revenues. Broadband and TV services grew above 20% in all markets with Colombia posting a 120% increase year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Mobile service revenue recorded double-digit growth rates among most markets driven by a good performance in outgoing service revenues, showing the combination of customer in up year expansion which outpaced mobile termination rate cuts in some countries.</p>
          <p>Let me highlight the robust year-on-year increases posted in Venezuela, Peru, Chile and Colombia. While the growth was also strong across the region, on the back of significant advances our wireless businesses, which offset the pressure of wireline operations order.</p>
          <p>If we're finishing with our Latin operations, let me quickly review our two major mobile operations. In Brazil, Vivo maintains its momentum, combining a strong customer growth with higher outgoing ARPUs and solid margins despite running through different imports. The 18% year-on-year growth in customers was driven by the boost in gross ads and churn control.</p>
          <p>In Mexico we continue to reinforce our competitive position with a 42% increase in our customer base year-on-year to 13.3 million customers, reaching a 19% market share. The better quality of the customers we are getting is reflected with the further reduction of our churn rate and 13% increase in also in ARPU and local currency. As a result, outgoing service revenue grew 64% year-on-year while the economies of scale led to a 19% margin in the first quarter of '08, 4 percentage points more than a year ago. And we have started the year with a strong improvement in operating cash flow which reached 57 million in the first quarter of '08.</p>
          <p>Moving now to slide 16, Telef&#xF3;nica Europe delivered a strong start of the year. The exit of Airwave from the Group last April and the weakening of sterling versus the euro impacted revenue in OIBDA growth in the first quarter on a reported basis. But like-for-like, both revenue and OIBDA growth was towards a top end of guidance. Part of this success has been down to anticipating customer needs and delivering the attractive propositions in both fixed and mobile.</p>
          <p>Across the group we saw good net additions on contract and an 80% increase compared with last year, reflecting the focus on quality growth. O2 UK continues to outperform the market with revenue growth of 12.6% in local currency while the margin was 24.1%, in line with last year, with a focus on acquisition and retention at the start of the year.</p>
          <p>In pre-paid, the focus is on revenue rather than customer numbers and pre-paid ARPU growth of 7.5% year-over-year in the quarter, the most rate of success we have had in this segment. In Germany there are encouraging signs with positive revenue growth for the first time in four quarters and an improved trend in mobile service revenue growth along with strong net adds, especially in contracts.</p>
          <p>The Czech Republic, line loss was reduced year-over-year and revenue growth of 1.6% was impacted by timings of revenues of <mark type="inaudible" /> City contracts which will come later in the year. Slovakia diluted margin by three points in the quarter, although excluding Dente the underlying dilution was two points, in line with 2007.</p>
          <p>Ireland contract net adds were one-third higher than last year, while revenue and OIBDA declined to the lower pre-paid date. The new pre-paid offers launched at the start of the year have helped the business regain momentum in that market.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 17, we show that O2 UK recorded another strong quarter of contract net adds on the back of iPhone and traditional handsets connections and a refresh of the tariff portfolio. Mobile service revenue was driven by continued customer and strong ARPU growth, in particular the record net adds on contracts in Q4 of last year. Investment in the customer composition continues to deliver benefits with contract earnings in the quarter down to 1.5%. Tariffs such as simplicity offer value and flexibility and are an attractive option in our current economic climate.</p>
          <p>In broadband we launched our mobile composition in April while our DSL service is delivering high quality and satisfaction, adding 61,000 customers in the quarter with limited marketing and population coverage of only 57%. The service has now gone nationwide as of May 1st, along with the DSL service for business.</p>
          <p>In Germany, we are pleased that some of the actions we put in place last year are starting to show some encouraging signs. The first quarter saw strong net adds with both 02 and <mark type="inaudible" /> delivering a good performance. Distribution channels were also expanded with a tea and drugstore chain and Fonic adding almost 1,000 new outlets and a new contract with Debitel. We now have strong compositions in those segments with mobile and fixed flat rates for voice calls, and internet access via DSL at the top end, and our Fonic brand at the lower end, with a range of genuine and bundled tiers, plus loop prepaid tiers in between. We also have our successful partnership with Tchibo and HanseNet.</p>
          <p>The trends in mobile service revenue improved from the fourth quarter with total revenue growing 1.5%. Renewed contracts with major ISPs in the markets such as freenet and genetic internet will help to drive growth in our ULL business which added 174,000 DSL lines in the quarter. With a growth of just under 1% reflected the reinvestment of the savings from the restructuring of last year and growth, along with the break even in the ULL business, which will deliver a positive contribution to OIBDA for the first time this year. We will continue to invest in profitable growth and grow our share in a competitive market.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our financial profile on slide number 19, we show that net financial debt has moved from 2.3 times OIBDA to 2.1 times, during the quarter. This has been the result of close to 900 million euros of reduction coupled with all the ongoing increases. When honoring our commitments to the financial debt, the ratio is down 13.25, just at the midpoint of the range set in the last investor's conference. Our progress in this field deserves a positive reserve, a positive outlook by the Fitch Ratings agency last February.</p>
          <p>Given the current situation of the credit market, it is worthwhile to note that Telef&#xF3;nica does not face any funding needs as maturities in 2008 are lower than the cash available to the company, and our average debt life exceeds six years. On top of that, we have over 9 billion euros of undrawn credit lines, more than 50% of which are long-term.</p>
          <p>Interest rate movements in the quarter pushed up our costs. The present value of our commitments rose due to decreasing long-term rates used for discounting them adding 24 basis points to our unrealized effective interest rate. At the same time, we took advantage of this movement by hedging 2.8 billion euros debt through swaps and county spreads. We keep intact at 6% target for the debt average debt cost in 2008.</p>
          <p>Finally our liability mix benefited from the Pound appreciation in the quarter, more than offsetting in the Czech Koruna strength leading to nearly 400 million euros reduction in the size of our debt when measured in euros.</p>
          <p>Now turning to slide 20, we show that our strong results in the solid free cash flow generation allow us to deliver on our first priority for additional free cash flow, Telef&#xF3;nica shareholders remuneration. In addition to the increased dividend per share for 2008 and given the visibility of our cash flow generation ability and the fact that our debt ratios are on track, we have decided to bring the end of the current share buyback program announced at the end of February forward to the end of 2008. As a result the 100 million shares program will be completed within this year.</p>
          <p>We are progressing fast in the execution of the program. As of today, we have already completed 35.7% of the new share buyback program. Overall, combining dividends and buybacks, our 2008 cash yield is around 6.5% which we think represents a very attractive granulation package.</p>
          <p>To sum up, in the first quarter of the year we have posted a strong set of results and we are well on track to deliver 2008 guidance across regional business and at the group level leveraging benefits of the highly diversified growth platform. Our superior organic growth profile continues to differentiate ourselves from our peers with high single-digit growth rates both in revenues and OIBDA on a double-digit year-on-year increase in operating income reflecting our continuous focus to enhance efficiency.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, solid growth prospects both in mobile and broadband should lead to a ramp up in OIBDA rates in constant euros in the coming quarter on the back of the sound economics in the region.</p>
          <p>In Europe, where we are facing a economic slowdown in the first quarter of the year we have seen limited evidence of significant impacts on our businesses but we will continue to monitor them very closely. We maintain a robust financial position with leveraged ratios in line with our targets while the strong free cash flow generation is allowing us to accelerate the execution of our share buyback program, highlighting our commitment to increase shareholders' returns as the first priority for the use of cash. Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen and now we are ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Damien Maltarp. Please go ahead, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. The company is Cazenove. Two questions, I guess just looking at the Spanish, also the trends in Spain. Minutes of use in mobile down 6% and even adjusting for the change of accounting, it looks like your domestic fixed traffic revenue trends are deteriorating a bit. Can you just expand a bit on whether you think you are seeing any impact from an economic slowdown, specifically in Spain? Or whether you have changed your internal outlook as to what impact a slowing economy might have on your internal forecasts? And the second question on Latam. Is there any way you can just give us a guide for how much of your mobile revenues in Latam you generated from income as opposed to outgoing? Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Guillermo Ansaldo answering to your question about the minutes of use evolution in Spain. You've seen an evolution here in Winter there's a huge loss as a decrease of 5.6 in the first quarter to the similar quarter in last year. The trends are similar to the ones that we explained last year and basically with these three type of things.</p>
          <p>First the nature of the promotions that we launched in the equipment campaign are different. This year, the last Christmas campaign was much more focused on retention actions so the minutes that we are giving away are for clients that have been staying for a long time. At Telef&#xF3;nica basically is one week of free of net traffic for each year often that is with MobileStar. So basically it's for times that have been long for us and you have to stay to capture the benefits of the promotions. While in the Christmas campaign of 2006 basically we were sending minutes away for all the customer base. And second there's another issue that put some noise in the comparisons is that as long as we are growing in machine to machine type of lines and data only seems obviously the number of lines without traffic is growing. So we think that these two effects, the different nature of promotion and the growing number of machine-to-machine and data-only explains like two-thirds of the variation. The other third can be explained for other explanations. They would be seasonality or decrease in the consumption of the client base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Taking your second question about incoming percentage of total revenues, the figure is 25.6% in terms of the incoming revenues, out of which 16.5% is the cost and as a result is a net effect of roughly 9.2% of service revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, did you say 9.2%? I didn't quite hear the number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The answer is 25.6% in terms of the income out of those, 16.5% is the cost of debt. So net is 9.1, 9.2%</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Terence Sinclair. Please go ahead, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, it's Terry Sinclair from Citi. Couple of questions. First of all, on Spain, given that there is some kind of slowdown that you're seeing in your nevertheless good growth rate, one, do you agree that there is a slowdown in the growth rate? Would you expect to outperform the economy as the economy slows, and under-perform it as the economy recovers? Secondly, if we look at the cash conversion of your earnings, is it correct to say there was a significant working capital outflow? And could you tell us in which geography that has been incurred? And could you just explain something about the interest timing, since cash interest out significantly exceeded interest in income statement? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terence, this is Guillermo Ansaldo. Regarding the question on Spain, obviously the guidance that we provided this year is lower in terms of growth when you compare that to the actual growth we have last year, so we are acknowledging that the growth will be lower. The first quarter we have a decent and a solid growth, which is in line with the guidance, so we do believe we can outperform the economy and we are doing our best to do so. So we have to have very close monitoring of the situation, and we believe that we can, of course we can meet the guidance and will again provide the very solid performance vis-&#xE0;-vis what's going on in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Terence, this is Santiago. Let me take your second double question on the cash immigration and the interest. The main reason for the difference between accrued and cash interest in Q1 comes from the fact that we have annual coupons, 400 million of which came due and were paid out in Q1. Of course that is only paid once per year, and so that effect will wash out in the remainder of 2008. And then you may have missed that point last year because we also issued the significant amount of bonds, which are becoming due for payment. With interest are become due for payment in early 2008. So that's the bulk of the explanation of the difference between interest and cash interest cost.</p>
          <p>On the other part of your cash conversion question has a lot to do, not with geographies, but with the way CapEx accrued versus CapEx paid is behaving. Roughly half of the working capital consumption in Q1 comes from a net of this payment relative to accrued of almost 600 million euros, part of which is reflecting the exact inverse profile in Q3 and partially Q4 of 2007. This is also an effect that you may have seen in 2007 and we expect that the bulk, the majority of that number, will again be washed out as the year progresses as a difference between accrued and cash CapEx converges throughout the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Santiago, may I just press you on that? The CapEx term I understand because you write checks in January for commitments made at the end of the year. But there was a working capital outflow as well, wasn't there? Where &#x2013; which comes forward in the difference between EBITDA and the cash level on operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well certainly. There's a reasonably long list of minor issues, which when taken together are contributing significantly to that working capital consumption. We have had something like the IOP, which is a long-term cash incentive paid to a large number of employees which became due and was paid out in Q1. There were one-off payments down in Brazil, down in Germany, which are due when they are due. And they are paid out, but they are not recurring and therefore will not happen again next year. There is a reasonably long list of them. And I'll be more than glad to go in detail with you over those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Christian Kern. Please go ahead, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. It's Christian Kern from Lehman Brothers. And two or three questions, please. The first one would be on the domestic mobile competition front. Orange Spain has just announced a flat rate today, which includes mobile roaming. We've seen Vodafone moving in their domestic UK market moving towards flat rate mobile and Internet. So just was wondering what your views are, how the Spanish competition is going to shape up? Second question would be with regards to sales in Germany, what makes you so confident in the turnaround and where do you stand on the network rollout? And finally, Santiago, if I may ask you on your views as you are accelerating the share buyback program the question is obviously when are you going to think about shareholders returns for '09? Is there anything we should put on the agenda for the second half? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding your question in Spain regarding the mobile flat rates, of course you know in the mobile market there are some characteristics that have to be taken in account first. In the case of Spain, in the case of Orange for example and Vodafone we're speaking about semi-flat rates, meaning it's a package of minutes regardless of where we go commercially that is a package of minutes for a fixed price. It's different from the flat rates we have in there for example in the Deutsche in the fixed traffic business.</p>
          <p>Some of these tariffs, like the one in Vodafone is targeted to higher ARPU type of client, so it has a very specific and very limited impact. In the case of Orange, it's a reposition of previous tariffs and also compares with the tariff that we have which is more expensive in terms of value so our reaction will be targeted. We do have plans, we are going to launch more plans, but always targeted to certain type of clients, of certain type of traffics. We do not want to enter into any kind of price wars. We have a strategy of providing more value and a targeted response. So we do have some plans, as you know, like the 30 plan, 60 over 90 where basically you pay a fixed amount and you get a very good price, and we will continue working on that arena, but always with targeted responses and always without entering in price wars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the share buyback in the other shareholder conversation, well typically this is around the end of the year that we start thinking about what the next year's policy should be, if there are anything that we can change. So take that as just an indication of what has happened in the past. We don't commit to revise on that every year. We think we have a reasonably attractive package in place. We just bought the share buyback program towards the end of this year, and we don't have any specific plans going on but it is likely that before the end of the year we will do another round of thinking about this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should I pick up the German question, Santiago? Christian, I guess I would l point to two or three things. The first thing is, if you look at our performance in the market over the last three quarters, actually we've done net ads of half a million for each of the last three quarters. So you can see clearly what we're doing in the marketplace is working, and I think that's from a tariffs perspective. Fonic is clearly going very well' over 300,000 customers on Fonic now. But also distribution perspective in terms of signing new partners and we just signed a deal with Debitel as far as expanding our distribution there. You used the word turnaround, I would green shoot Germany and I think I'm very pleased that in the first quarter we've gone revenue positive to the first quarter and in the last four, but it is green shoots at this moment. As far as the network is concerned, clearly we are rolling out now after the Waway deal that we signed, particularly in 3G and HSDPA so you'll see from the German perspective an acceleration of our roll out in Germany over the next three quarters at the back end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very kind Santiago, can I ask you one more on the domestic environment? Just on the heading back lower bad debt provision. This sounds counterintuitive in an economy which is slowing down, just was wondering what your view on this is, the 25 million euros you added back on your OIBDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in the case of spend, we have an extra and not ordinary effect that we sell. We sold the portfolio of non-performing builds so that's why we have an external OIBDA impact and that's why the provision is negative. And that's a non-regular, non-normal impact so that's why in the information we share in the transparencies we were trying to show the numbers of the growth without this impact, also without the real estate and also without other effects, but this is something that is a one shot event. It's the same a typical sale of a bad loan portfolio, if you want to put it that way. And that's why we have a reversion in the buckle coalition because the price was better than the provision we have already in the balance sheet now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Javier Mar&#xED;n. Please go ahead announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I am Javier Mar&#xED;n from Cheuvreux Bank. Question on non-organic expansion, I was wondering whether you can share any of your views of doing business spending your money on two of the markets namely broadband in Germany and maybe the Pay TV in Spain and names that comes to my mind <mark type="inaudible" /> for instance in Germany. And also regarding Brazil the first steps on the creation of a national champion, has that increased your visibility on any potential corporate structure of your different businesses there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Javier, let me take the Germany question first. In Germany we continue to monitor the situations, we have not seen anything that makes us change our mind and it's already in May. So I think it's not likely that we will change our mind any time soon. Our chairman has specifically excluded some of our other possibilities just a few weeks ago but we continue to monitor very closely Brazil, Mexico and Germany as our focused ones but, as you already know, we have had limited progress in all three of those fronts. And we continue, well I can tell you, that we continue to be very close to anything that is happening in those markets but we have nothing to report on that part. And on our Pay TV we will not consider that an excursion into other territories. You know we are very interested in developing our triple play platforms and so certainly if anything that can accelerate or improve our position in that particular segment of the market will likely come under review, but there is nothing to report either on this front as of today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Will Miller please go ahead announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks this is Will Miller from IRSA Research. Couple of questions, firstly on Spain and mobile broadband, I just wonder what is your strategy with respect to mobile broadband and specifically how it's priced in Spain. Overall prices seem fairly high, particularly in relation to other European markets where we've seen them fall pretty sharply. I just wonder if you will be the first to lower prices to drive take up or whether you are going to take a back seat and wait for others to lower those prices first. Second question on Latin America, obviously Colombia has taken a fairly huge termination rate hit this year and obviously that's coming from American mobile numbers as well. I wonder if you could just talk about which of the other businesses are exposed to termination rate cuts over the next couple of years that we should be aware of. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As in mobile broadband, first point, we've got it under review, we do see the service as a complimentary service to the fixed broadband. And we have analyzed this very carefully and we are tracking the results and we are very satisfied to see that literally two-thirds of the editions are complimentary and another six, so half of the remaining third is new market, meaning clients that are not &#x2013; that were not considering fixed broadband and they're adding up to the mobile broadband. Regarding pricing we have two type of tariffs. We have daily tariffs that are for the people that use mobile broadband on an occasional basis and we also have the traditional flat tariff, monthly tariff for people that have more intense usage. As long as users increase we will see as we've seen in fixed broadband, better pricing and better offers. But with that leading to more usage and more value added.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to your question about the termination rate of the exposure that we may have for global year after the Columbian example that you mentioned. First on the Columbian example let me tell you that the second is basically neutral for us in terms of the structure of our revenues and cost in our mobile operation in Columbia. But globally speaking, our exposure to the incoming exposure that we have in terms of termination rate is less and less every year. I've been already saying this, in this call, that the net exposure this year is about 9% and is becoming less and less relevant as the outcome in part of our revenues increasing significantly year-on-year. So whatever the trend is in the region, which is again showing I would say, year after year, more with each exposure to the termination rate effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I just, I mean specifically, which markets do you know about where you have termination rate cuts coming through and do you see a risk for example with Vivo that rates might be cut earlier than 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the time being we don't have, or we are not aware of having an immediate process in mind, but you might imagine, we will monitor that, but what I can tell you is that the trend of increasing dependence keeps going on year in year 2008 so the net effect at the end of the year is going to be even lower than the one that we have right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Laurent Sierra. Please go ahead announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Laurent Sierra from Redburn in London. A couple of questions. The first one on associates. It seems that the lower profit was due to Portugal Telecom. Can you give us any update on zone or so as you own 5% of the company? My other question was on other companies and elimination. This is an accounting question because it seems that you have eliminated up to 200 million euros compared to last year's reporting and the results of the contribution from Atento, which was around 300 million euros. So can you give me a bit more visibility on that? And I would like to know also that you have apparently changed your reporting on the number of fixed lines in Spain and also in Latin America. What was the change in the reporting? It seems that in Latin America you have added the mobile, the fixed wireless, but that's not occurring in Spain. Can you give me more clarity on that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the question about the contribution of our associates. You are right in pointing out that the main difference between this year and last year is the lower contribution, but still positive for Portugal Telecom. You know that Portugal Telecom went last year through a very dynamic change in their perimeter. And so the total contribution that Portugal Telecom had to us has come down quite significantly from 33 million euros, to slightly above 7 million euros. And that explains the vast majority of the total. The rest is the only inclusion in the list of associates that is with us this year. This is mostly in telco, our investment vehicle in Italy with our Italian partners, which showed a very small negative contribution as a consequence of the interest costs borne by the vehicle. But other than that, there is not much more to report. If you look at the caption, changes in other counties and elimination, you will see that Endemol, which was last year with us, is no longer part of the company. And that explains probably, although I don't have all the numbers in my head, the vast majority of the changes, and they not being present in '07 and not being present in '08. By the way you mentioned the percentage on OPT, is close to 10%, almost 10%, or 5%, which I think is the number that you mentioned. We continue to hold the same percentage that we did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of your question about the changing criteria in the fixed line accounting or in terms of the reporting, in Latin America we are including the fixed wireless units right now, this at year in terms of fixed line accesses, rather than in the previous year that were included in the wireless activity. That's for Latin America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding Spain, the only change that we made in the way we presented the numbers in accesses is that we have include Irrebanda. Irrebanda is a small company. That &#x2013; where we have 51% control and basically we have restated all the number from December 2006 so the number is in the tables in our report are already all the numbers we have given. To give you a flavor of the numbers, which are very small, in the fixed lines is only 23,000 and in broadband roughly 60,000. So the only change is very small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of James Ratzer. Please go ahead announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's James Ratzer from New Street Research. I have two questions please. The first one was just regarding your Mexican business. It seems like you have adopted a slowdown in competitive activity in the first quarter. Your average price per minute seemed to rise for the first quarter in three years. And as a result, your revenue market share in Mexico seems to have stabilized. I was wondering if you could explain your strategy here in a bit more detail. Is this a distinct decision you've taken? Do you expect to get more aggressive on pricing in the upcoming quarters? And the second question is regarding O2 UK and the rate of growth in this business continues to be pretty phenomenal. Your service revenue growth accelerated to the highest level in five quarters. Is there anything on the horizon that means you can't continue that rate of growth over the full year? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thanks for your question taking the Mexican market. First we have basically this first quarter we have slightly changed one of the promotions that we were making in terms of not adding so many free minutes. But, you could expect that we will keep pursuing the same strategy of maintaining or even lowering the ARPM in terms of &#x2013; because for us the elasticity has proved to be very positive. And we think that that's the right way to approach that market, which is by the way, growing very significantly. Our ARPU has been increasing in the first quarter of this year in spite of the seasonal effect of Easter. We have been able to increase ARPU and we have been also having, I would say a significant and sound share of net assets. So, for us the Mexico market has proven to be very sound this first quarter. Take also into consideration that we have a different criteria in comparison and when you compare to different ARPUs between hours and Bell's ARPU, they claim based calculation is different. We clean up the claim base after 90 days of non activity, which is different. So I think that's &#x2013; the levels of ARPU are probably not comparable, even though we have been able to increase our ARPU in the first quarter. And on top of that our minutes of usage is growing, which is also important for our strategy. So we tend to think that the proposal, the value proposition that we have made to customers in Mexico has proven to be successful and we'll keep going in to the same direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have any growth content can we accelerate, as we go through the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we keep going in the same direction, we are right now and 19% market share in terms of total customer base, but again, taking into consideration that the customer base are probably not comparable. Ours has a different, employ a much more strict criteria than our competitors. So we guess we'll keep going to the same direction</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James, it's Matthew here. I'll pick up the o2 UK question. Yes, 13% growth in quarter 1 we were very pleased with. We expected to outperform the market and I think we will continue to outperform the market for the balance of the year. I think the outstanding question for us is will we continue to outperform the market to the extent we did in the first quarter? And I think that does have to be questionable because you must see how competitors react, I think to the results we're producing in the UK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of John Carradice. Please go ahead announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, very much. It's MS Global. I have two questions please. Firstly, is it possible to get some guidance on tax, both in terms of P&amp;L tax rate and cash tax if it's possible for the full year and maybe for an extra year that would be great? And secondly in Germany, yesterday the regulator announced a naked DSL rate of 20 euros. And is this close to irrelevant for your business in your local bundling business in Germany or does it actually undermine it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Santiago, let me take the tax question first. We don't provide specific guidance but I can give you an idea of where things might be headed. Two things have happened this year and it is that in some of the European markets where we're most exposed, tax rates have come down. The Spanish tax rate has come down from 32.5 to 30%. That is going to have a positive P&amp;L effect across the flows of this year would be on tax terms lower than those of last year. We have in a very varied array of businesses in Latin America where the tax rate and the tax systems are wildly divergent, so it's hard to generalize. I would think that this year's P&amp;L tax rate should come lower by one or two percentage points versus last years as other countries like Germany have also been included in the lower tax rates. And in the cash terms, it's highly volatile on a quarterly basis, but we should end up 2008 with a slightly higher cash tax consumption of last year. The Q1 number, which is about 50% of cash tax over P&amp;L tax, is unlikely to continue and I would expect the number to be closer to last year's average, or last year's Q1 &#x2013; which is closer to two-thirds or so. So in order to model that, although I insist it is highly volatile, anywhere from 50 to 66% seems a sensible approach.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John. I'll pick up the German question. I think that first thing to say is it was broadly where we thought it would be. And interestingly we've got a balance in our business, because obviously we've got a retail DSL business as well as our local loop un-bundling business. So clearly it may bring some more pressure on the local loop un-bundling part of our business, but probably brings us some potential upside and on the retail side. And the other thing I would say is on the wholesale side, clearly we've got our partners and it's not just a matter of price, it's also a matter of quality as well. So, I would take out that it was probably in line to where we expected it to come out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, gentlemen. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Luis Prota. Please go ahead, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Luis Prota from Morgan Stanley. I have two questions. The first one is whether you can clarify if you have included any kind of one-off charge this quarter to reflect the retroactive cut in bitstream tariffs recently by the regulator? And the second question is, following your exit from Sofit Cavulay and the speculation on new shareholders that are coming to Prisa, do you see any real score change to your strategy and contents or any other implication business-wise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Luis, this is Guillermo. Regarding the question in Spain, yes, we do have one, one-time effect, negative effect that is recorded in our numbers. Basically have an impact of 18 million euros in the OIBDA. This is a retroactive effect of the OIBDA new regulation. We don't agree, will not agree with this regulation. We are applying against this regulation, but we are accounted in this and it's drawing a negative effect. Preferably, the business absorbs some positive effects, so this impact, so the growth that we're having in beginning Spain is well in line with guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Luis, this is Julio Linares. You know we have commercial agreements with Sofit Cavulay (60.44) regarding bundles in both sites for both companies. And in addition to that, we're having content and those rematch (60.32) are working. We are very pleased with the way that they're evolving and, of course we are going to continue this kind of cooperation with Sofit Cavulay (60.44).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Guy Peddy. Please go ahead, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. It's Guy Peddy from Macquarie. Two quick questions, firstly aiming at Matthew. In the UK, Matthew, retail data was recently shocking but your performance has totally been absolutely exceptional in Q1, but do you think that you have flexibility in your business, in your model, to be pro-active and actually cut your voice pricing, given the fact that a UK consumer continues to pay what is a relatively high actual revenue yield relative to, for example, other markets and especially your own German property? And on a secondary question, Santiago, you highlighted the effective interest rate was around just over 6.2% in Q1, but you've got a target of just 6% for the full year. Can you just talk us through how you expect the interest rates to decline and what would be the drivers of those in the coming quarters? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'll pick up the UK question first Santiago. Yeah, I think the reason for our key success in the UK, Guy, is basically we're doing the right thing for customers and what customers want. And I would use an example of Simplicity in the UK, which when we looked at the market last summer we felt there was room for a SIM only proposition without a handset, that gave good value in terms of the rates, in terms of pence per minute and was a 30-day rolling contract, which effectively meant people didn't have to commit to 18-months or two years when they were a little bit nervous about the economic outlook. So, and on that one product, I we've now got over half a million customers. So, I would say that what we've done in the UK is absolutely done the right thing for the customer and produced products that the customers love. So, very happy with that performance and don't see any reason why we can't continue to win in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, in terms of the evolution of interest &#x2013; the fate of interest cost, the main reason why we expect them to converge lower than what they are is that in Q1 we have registered a strong increase in costs coming from the mark-into-market of the value of our personal liabilities. We subsided &#x2013; I'm speaking off the top of my head, something like 200 million. It is in our view unlikely that this mark-into-market will be necessary again as the interest rates that we are now going through are more stable relative to Q1 and they were relative to Q4. It is that and together with the interest rates that we have a very fixed in the environment of interest rates that makes us believe that we are going to end the year, as we said, around the 6% level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of David George. Please go ahead announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. It's David George from Credit Suisse. A couple of questions, firstly on the fiber trials in Spain, could you update us on your progress there? And specifically I think we've had a number of comments now from the CMT on how they see the regulation of fiber developing. I wonder if you could give us your thoughts on how you feel about that and when we might see the start of a more full scale fiber build in Spain? Is that possibly next year? And secondly, just going back to the domestic trends question on Spanish Mobile, just on the ARPU outlook for the rest of the year, obviously some of these roaming cuts will begin to drop out in 82 but you also have some termination records to come. So I wondered how do you see that ARPU trend evolving? Is it possible to see a better ARPU trend in the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, this is Guillermo. Regarding the fiber, we do have authorization to do a new pilot in fiber to the home up to 5,000 clients and we agree that we are not going to win the clients from the competition, so it's basically for our clients or new clients. This pilot will help us to keep on improving all the processes and the value proposition for clients and help on the technical and commercial side.</p>
          <p>Regarding full scale launching, we are not, we have not been authorized yet to launch our retail fiber to the home services. We expect and we hope to launch the services in the last part of this year but it will depend on regulation. We are analyzing the first date resolution from our regulator and we have to see if we are able to launch it this year or we have to delay it to next year. But our intention is to launch it as soon as possible.</p>
          <p>Regarding the trends in ARPU there are several, as you know, several things impacting. On the positive side, data ARPU is behaving very healthy and very strong and the trends in connectivity we see that that will continue and we continue in a positive way, data connectivity. Regarding SMS, that will also continue along the same trends that we have seen the last six months. Regarding premium SMS, we do have prior campaign this quarter but we will not repeat it in the following quarter but we will come with similar campaignings maybe later in the third and fourth quarter so that will have a discontinue on a quarter on quarter basis. On regarding incoming ARPU, as you know that's affected, as you mentioned by the MTR cuts appearing April and October so that's something that we can focus on and, as you know, the decrease of the cost is lower than the competitor cost because we are comparing to the same number and to this asymmetries and so the decrease is negative for us but it's more negative for the competition.</p>
          <p>Regarding the rest of voice, that will depend of course on the MOU evolution and the trend that we are seeing in the last six months, we hope we continue in the rest of the year and we are also planning for several target ventures in order to boost MOU consumption. We understand that that's very challenging in this year but we will continue working on those lines. So all in all, it's very hard to predict the number for the rest of the year, we have to take a closer look but there are some positive trends and some challenges ahead of us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mathieu Robilliard. Please go ahead announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Mathieu Robilliard, Exane BNP Paribas. I have two questions regarding Latin America. First, at Telesp, I see margins are a bit under pressure, it ends up you are facing a lot of competition from cable operators in Brazil and that forces you to integrate different platforms to do triple play now. How &#x2013; when do you think you can contain that margin pressure because for the moment, as far as I understand, IPTV is forbidden and in terms of the personal, you've already done quite a lot, so is there a moment where you think you can stabilize your margins there?</p>
          <p>And then a second question also on margins in Argentina, an official inflation is apparently running above 20% and a lot of your tariffs are actually regulated and you can't increase, your prices. So how are you going to escape also margin compression in Argentina, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question. Considering Telesp, of course if you run the comparison, the first quarter of 2007 versus this first quarter, you need to, I would say, decorate the effect that we had in the first quarter of 2007 like the real estate sale of Combaia. Out of that, if you have that and if you take into consideration the fact that also in this quarter we have been including a contingency which is a fine that has relating to a boost to us as imposed to our that we keep fighting that we have been accounting. And on top of that you consider the restructuring provisions that we have been also including in the last quarter. You will find that the margin that we are having in Telesp in this first quarter of 2008 compared with the last quarter of 2007 is basically the same, in the neighborhood of 39%. So we are starting to stabilize margins, it's taking us a while. Take into consideration also that the products of Telesp in terms of revenues is completely changing. We are now having more bundles. We are now having more TV and more broadband and the back of those businesses out of the total revenue of Telesp is increasing and those businesses have lower margins than the previous one.</p>
          <p>And you are right. We keep doing a significant effort in terms of labor cost, but because in a &#x2013; I would say a non-ending loop for efficiency. And I think that we still have to look when we're taking into consideration that intensive restructuring of the payroll, 1,000 people have been leaving Telesp in April and those are not included in March. So we keep going to the efficiency practice. So net of all the comments I just made, roughly EBITDA margin is more or less the similar or the same in the last quarter of 2007 and in this quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>In Argentina, the situation is different because of the impact of inflation. You're right, and we are facing significant pressure from the inflation point of view and we have not been able to impact that properly in the revenue line, in spite of the fact that we are growing 10% in revenues in Argentina. So we keep looking for efficiency and we keep asking and talking with the government on that. Also take into consideration that we are increasing also the transformation taken in this bundling, and  when we bundle, we are effectively having slight price increases. So we'll keep you posted. Basically, Telesp, we think we are on the right track and up until now we'll even see to waiting to seek other ways to prevent inflation unfortunately that we are having right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll have time for the last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question comes from the line of Iv&#xF3;n Leal. Please go ahead, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good afternoon, gentlemen BBVA. Just couple of questions, the first one on coming back to the domestic business, and most specifically the Broadband business. We've seen a sound member of subscriber growth in the first quarter of the year, though the revenues growth just grew by 11%, which shows slight weakness on the ARPU. I'll be concerned that, in fact, your most aggressive promotions in terms of Broadband offers have come up I think in March and April. So should we be concerned about the ARPU decreases in the Broadband business in Spain? And if that's the case, do you think you will be able to compensate that through a stronger increase in subscribers?</p>
          <p>And the second question is regarding Latin America. Given that senior presentation now Venezuela is one of the countries which most supports growth in the regions, how comfortable do you feel about the possibilities about repatriating the dividends from the country? I think that in the interest quoted you were pending the authorizations on repatriating dividend I think from year 2005, 2006. Do you have the okay on that? And how comfortable do you feel on how that is going to double up in the future? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Julio Linares. To answer your revenue question about domestic growth, when you see the numbers of Broadband income you have to take into account you have obviously the retail side and the wholesale sides, so that's effective for both effects: the retail and the wholesale. I mean the wholesale, as you know, there has been reductions in the fees we charge to third players in the indirect access so that affects also our numbers. Regarding the retail, take into account that you have also connectivity and value added services. And as you know, we &#x2013; our connectivity ARPU is being reduced by between 5%, 6% on a yearly basis. And we are growing in value of the services, Imagenio is part of that. And so the net impact so you have to know obviously affects wholesale, value of services and also domestic retail connectivity.</p>
          <p>Regarding connectivity, as you mentioned, we launched new products on the lower side and on the upper side of our portfolio. On the lower side from 18.9 and at 1 megabits with limitation of down load capacity of 2 gigabits and at 29.9 both are bundled with voice and 1 megabit. And so and on the upper side we have been selling for the last quarter 10 megabits. So the game here is to sell as much as possible of lower and higher on higher part of the portfolio so as to defend the connectivity. So basically that's the game we're trying to play. We're going to keep on adding services on the upper part of the portfolio. And we have to monitor that in order to sustain our revenue. That's the trick to sustain connectivity so that the decrease is no more than 5, 6% or 7% and to keep on selling value-added services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regards to your question about Venezuela and the dividend approval. The one that we're spending was finally approved I think a few weeks ago and we submitted the approvals. So for the time being, we are not seeing any major difficulties on having those approvals being done. So we'll keep you posted on that but for the time being, things are running normal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, ladies and gentlemen, with this we bring this conference call to an end. We appreciate your presence and your interest. Let me remind you that our investor relations team is available to answer any further questions that you might have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation today. This concludes today's call. You may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>