<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1488434" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2932</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Communications &amp; Media Relations">Tor Odland</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Jon Fredrik Baksaas</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Richard Olav Aa</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Carnegie Investment Bank AB (Norway)">Espen Torgersen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="DnB NOR Bank ASA (Broker)">Christer Roth</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Andrew J. Lee</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Andy W. Parnis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Jakob Bluestone</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Barry R. Zeitoune</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Maurice G. Patrick</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Terence Tsui</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Handelsbanken Capital Markets">Jan Dworsky</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to the presentation of Telenor's result for the second quarter of 2012. We welcome you, whether you're here in the room, listening on the phone, watching the webcast or using mobile video. My name is Tor Odland. As usual, there will be a Q&amp;A session directly after the presentation. I will come back with how we conduct that. We aim to end the action here on stage around 7:00, including the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>To present the figures today, we have our CEO, Jon Fredrik Baksaas; and our CFO, Richard Aa. First, I'll leave the floor to Mr. Baksaas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Tor, thank you, and good morning to everyone. I hope you got here dry this morning. It's been a wet summer in many ways. This second quarter 2012, we are having another good quarter in Telenor. Operationally, we are quite pleased to present the quarter with continued growth and solid margins also this time. The growth is somewhat slower than previous quarters, but still it's strong in the sector. And cash flows in this quarter amounts to NOK5.1 billion, which is roughly to 20% of the capital margin.</p>
          <p>The performance in Norway is quite strong this quarter, and given the period that we've been through some quarters back, we're quite pleased that we can show signs of improvement and growth again after a period where we were a bit late in the competitive response to the market place.</p>
          <p>The situation in India remains undecided from a regulatory perspective. The final auction and conditions are not yet confirmed. And in order to reduce this risk going forward and also to reduce the cost level, we have decided to restructure the Indian operation to focus on the nine best performing circles, and we will get back to this more in detail throughout this presentation.</p>
          <p>To follow up on the ambitions of the Group to meet with expectations on the attractive shareholder remuneration, also this year we are launching a 3% share buyback program, and Richard will do the details on this when it's his turn.</p>
          <p>If we then take a deeper dive into the Norwegian performance this quarter, we're very glad that the migration to bundle mobile tariffs has been working the way we intended. It seems to work nice for us. The EBITDA margin has recovered and we saw these trends in the first quarter and they are more or less confirmed in this quarter. 52% of our postpaid consumer base is now on the bundled tariff structure. And this means that the majority of our active data users are now enjoying data traffic from these bundled traffics.</p>
          <p>And this, we find, will reduce the risk of the cannibalization from IP-based services, from voice and SMS moving in that direction in the periods to come. However, that work is not over yet. Total revenues in Norway increased by 2%, driven by 8% in mobile revenues, and adjusted for one-time effects in second quarter last year, mobile revenues increased by 5%. Standing here last year, you may recall that that was after the network failure.</p>
          <p>So far this year, we have seen a more rational competitive market environment in the mobile sector. However, the pricing structure that we now have adopted better reflects the underlying usage pattern from customers, and that needs to be strengthened also in the future because of the heavy investments that we are undertaking at the same time as we are seeing the very strong shift from voice and SMS to data services.</p>
          <p>The fixed revenues continues to decline more or less at a regular speed. However, not as fast this quarter you might argue compared to previous quarters. But for the first time, we are recording the number of lines connected in the fixed line for telephony services below 1 million lines connected. And those of you have that have followed statistics, this was close to 2.5 million at its peak. So it's really a big transition that has been going on and still is ongoing. And of course this will also have implications on the future cost structures in the Group as we will move along and don't see this kind of development stop here.</p>
          <p>We are continuing to make significant investments into the high-speed, both fixed and mobile networks, in order to deliver the superior coverage and capacity service that we do in Norway. So far this year we have spent NOK2 billion to modernize our networks, to bring capacities deeper into the networks, and to strengthen the high-speed data and also prepare for 4G to be launched later this year. And throughout this year, all in all we expect that the CapEx figure will end roughly at NOK4 billion for the full year.</p>
          <p>Then if I move on to Europe, Kjell-Morten Johnsen was recently appointed the Regional Director of a new set of companies, a new combination in the Telenor Group. We have decided to combine Sweden and Denmark with that of Central and Eastern Europe, seeing these operations more of a similar structure. And we anticipate and have the ambition to grow the ability to drive the industrialized agenda in these countries going forward from here.</p>
          <p>From a performance perspective, it's a bit varied picture. Sweden and Serbia show strong development this quarter; subscriber growth, 47,000 in Sweden and 22,000 in Serbia. Handset and tablet sales dilute the margins to a certain extent, as this handsets distribution has become part of the go-to market strategy. And there is a good OpEx development both in Sweden and Serbia as well. Migration from prepaid to postpaid continues in Serbia and results in an ARPU growth. Handset subsidies is now also becoming a part of the strategy.</p>
          <p>The reported EBITDA in Sweden includes a provision of regulatory costs from previous periods of NOK48 million, and adjusted for this small time one-off, the margin is slightly up year-on-year in Sweden from 24% to 25%.</p>
          <p>I say the varied picture if we then address the Danish market. It continues to be very tough. It is an intense competition there, price pressure, and in combination with loss of wholesale revenues. This resulted in a weak revenue development and also reduced profitability.</p>
          <p>In Hungary and Montenegro, there are new sales taxes reflecting the overall economic situation of these two countries, and telecoms as an industry has been targeted to cover some of these revenue shortages that the governments are looking for.</p>
          <p>And the new telecom tax in Hungary comes in addition to the one that we already have, but which is assumed to end by the end of 2012. So we are in a half-year period where we have a double taxation set-up in Hungary.</p>
          <p>If I then make some comments to VimpelCom. Through two transactions this spring, Telenor has reestablished the ownership position in VimpelCom that we had before. The dilution that took place after the Wind transaction was completed. The Russian Antimonopoly Service, FAS, argues that our deal with the Weather is in violation with the Russian Strategic Investment Law, and there is a court hearing scheduled over the issue at the 17th of October.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, there is an injunction in place which blocks upstream of dividends from VimpelCom in Russia to VimpelCom Limited, and this has made VimpelCom Limited to postpone final dividend payouts for 2011.</p>
          <p>Of course, Telenor has been in Russia for many years and we know our whereabouts when it comes to the Russian law, and of course we respect any national law in any country. However in this one, we solidly believe that the claim is without merit and that we have &#x2013; at the end that we are in full compliance with the FAS approval that was granted in 2010. The FAS even said last month that it was pushing for an out-of-court settlement between shareholders of VimpelCom. And as always, we are ready to engage in such discussions if the opportunity rises.</p>
          <p>However, as we have indicated and emphasized on many occasions, the operational performance of VimpelCom is to our great concern. And we believe that the operational improvements in the Group could create visible value creation. We are continuing to follow-up on these issues and push for an improved operational performance in the Group. And as we saw in first quarter 2011 &#x2013; 2012, we saw some improved performance in Russia showing that VimpelCom might be back on track when it comes to go-to-market activities. And this coupled with the recent announcement of LTE licenses in Russia as well seems to position the company quite well.</p>
          <p>We have a long-term perspective in VimpelCom, we've always been, and we want to impact the operational development of the Group.</p>
          <p>Asia still, for Telenor, represents the source of growth. It's in the Asian economies that we see ongoing growth and ongoing usage patterns changing in the different market places. We're 9% organic this quarter in all our four established markets. We have a high activity level in all operations, with networks swaps and network improvements in the region, in particular in these days when we embark on the swaps in Pakistan and DTAC and DiGi. DiGi soon being finished, DTAC more or less halfway.</p>
          <p>In the two of our biggest Asian markets, DiGi and DTAC, very strong growth I would say on seeing the market moving to data activities, and also new devices will be very important going forward. And we see also here handset manufacturers opting for new smartphones below $100, and for those of you that has followed the industry over quite a period of time, the real explosion in Asia for mobile activities happened when we saw handsets on the 2G generation coming down below $50, and even reaching $20- to $30-brackets for handset prices. So we believe that this we will see a similar kind of development also in the smartphone area, and believe that the mobile operations in Asia is fantastically well-positioned to entertain that kind of development trend.</p>
          <p>However, in Grameenphone this quarter, we have a too-soft revenue growth compared to market in general. So there are things that we need to come to grip with in Grameenphone in the periods to come, and we do see signs of that already. The subscriber growth was now 16% higher than last year. And the competitive situation in Bangladesh, where the penetration is the lowest compared to the other operations, has intensified. We have several initiatives then to turn this trend and anticipate that second half will be showing improvements from where we are today.</p>
          <p>In Pakistan, we have another solid quarter, strong top line growth, 18% in local currency, driven by higher usage as well as an increased subscriber base. And also in this quarter, we see that financial services really shows &#x2013; takes a big portion of that growth element, 4% this quarter. We have here started the swap with ZTE, and we hope that we will be able to carry through as much as possible throughout this year, as this will be a good contributor to improved energy efficiency in the network, where energy distribution is quite a challenge for all operators.</p>
          <p>Generally speaking, they agreed was having half-time deliveries for the time being and that means that we have to run base stations on these and to a large extent. And the new network generation will offload that quite considerably.</p>
          <p>Coming then to India and Uninor, let's refer a little bit to the operational performance of Uninor in the second quarter. Once again, I have to say that we're impressed of the Uninor management and their ability to keep on the work under these challenging conditions in the regulatory field. We see 2.2 million new subscribers this quarter and we continue to take market share, and according to the regulator, we took 18% of net-adds in India in May &#x2013; in the month of May, and this has taken us to strike below 5% market share pan-India.</p>
          <p>In addition to this, we are reducing the operational cost base and as a consequence, the operational losses is gradually being reduced as well, as you can see from this slide. However, due to the high uncertainty on the regulatory side, we have decided to expense all our investments in Uninor this quarter. That means that we do not take anything of what we usually account for as CapEx. We take everything of that into the P&amp;L. So we are showing, compared to previous periods, somewhat weaker EBITDA development in Uninor in this quarter. But this comes from this change of accounting principles.</p>
          <p>With the continued subscriber uptick and cost efficiency measures that we have done, we have now decided to focus on the best-performing circles. And some of these will also reach EBITDA breakeven towards the end of the year beginning of first &#x2013; of the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>On the restructuring of this, we have made some decisions of quite importance. With the regulatory uncertainty in India, and as you know, both timing and the framework of 2G is still unclear, we have decided to restructure the operations and focus on the best-performing circles. We will then gradually scale down operations in four circles, that will be Kerala, Karnataka, Tamil Nadu and Orissa. And these four circles, they represent 14% of Uninor's revenues in Q2 and also 14% of the subscriber base in June. However, they do account for a much higher relative proportion of the EBITDA losses in the same period.</p>
          <p>We then plan to reallocate the resources within our Indian footprint from these circles to other areas. By doing this, we believe that we can make Uninor self-financing. That means cash flow breakeven within the end of 2013. And in our previous business plan, this target was in the first half of 2015, so really we are taking cash flow breakeven one-and-a-half year on a constant &#x2013; more concentrated &#x2013; in a more concentrated geography. As before, we are firmly committed to the peak funding limit of INR155 billion, and of course we urgently wait for clarity on the auction framework and the timeline on that one.</p>
          <p>To conclude my presentations on this second quarter 2012 reporting, I'd like to mention three things. We want to move what we see in the Nordic countries when it comes to how to handle the transition from voice to data. Under these challenges, we need to adopt new pricing principles and apply pricing structures that better reflects the change in user behavior from voice to data and IP services. And the examples of these are plentiful by the people in this room, because we are all part of this change.</p>
          <p>We want to make sure that we utilize <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:50) networks in a way that gives us a competitive edge and makes it possible to monetize on these investments in the longer run. Coupled with this, there will be initiatives also from the Telenor Group to take positions and explore opportunities on the service side of the new ecosystem, that of the digital services.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we will execute on operational excellence. We need to see more and continued progress, towards those targets we have set for 2013, and focus on execution and closely follow up on our targets for 2013. Here we will see a combination of local efficiency initiatives in combination with group-wide initiatives based upon the scale of the group and the competencies that we have in the different OpCos. Here we are also thinking about new operating models, the same through everything that we're going to do, we need to think about how we go to market and how we treat the customer side.</p>
          <p>And finally, and very important as well, make the operation in India self-financing within the new time limit that we've set for ourself, and execute on the restructuring plan that we have announced today. And having spoken to Sigve Brekke already, he is there speaking at the same as we are speaking here.</p>
          <p>And with these comments, a strong quarter, a lot of good prospects and possibilities going forward, I'll hand over to Richard who will guide us through the financials. Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fredrik. I will do four things. I will take you in more detail into the financial performance. I'll update you on the funding of the Group, including the financial restructuring also of Uninor. I'll go through the share buyback program, and finally the guiding for the Group. So let's start with the financial performance and the revenues.</p>
          <p>We have an organic revenue growth of 5.4% this quarter, reported is 4.1%, difference being a weakening of the currencies in Central and Eastern Europe. Both the Serbian dinars and the Hungarian forints are at a significantly lower level than last year. Anyhow, we added NOK1 billion of revenues year-on-year this quarter driven by Asia, as Fredrik said.</p>
          <p>If you look at the various operating units, there are large differences. Denmark being definitely the weakest one in the Group, with a decline of NOK387 million, and that requires some more detailed explanation. About NOK89 million of that is a drop in the mobile service revenues, which is most important long-term. NOK129 million is related to the loss of the Onfone wholesale contract, and the rest is a mix of interconnect currency and continuous decline in the fixed business.</p>
          <p>Hungary, a decline of NOK196 million, 75% of that is due to the weakening of the foreign, and 25% of that is due to interconnect. Underlying revenues are stable. Then the Asian units contributes to close to NOK1.1 billion in growth this quarter, and that really is all from the DiGi, DTAC and Pakistan. Grameenphone in local currency is more or less &#x2013; no, in Norwegian kroner is more or less flat.</p>
          <p>Then India, flat ARPU but still subscriber growth, but a weakening rupee gives us NOK336 million extra revenue. In other, it's Norway contributing most of the NOK163 million in increased revenues.</p>
          <p>Then how does this translate into margins. The EBITDA is up by NOK584 million and stands about NOK8 billion this quarter. The margin is 31.7% this quarter compared to 30.6% last year, an underlying margin improvement of 1.1 percentage points. That is mainly driven by reduced operating losses in Uninor. If we exclude Uninor, the operating margin of the Group is 35.7%, which is more or less in line with second quarter last year, a small improvement.</p>
          <p>However, we know that we absorb an increased 5% revenue share in our second biggest mobile operation, DTAC. That is about 0.7% on the margin. So adjusting for that, there is an underlying margin improvement on 0.8 to 0.9 percentage points in the quarter. But again big differences between the various business units.</p>
          <p>We're very happy to see that Norway contributes an additional NOK200 million in EBITDA. But we have to remember that we had NOK100 million extra expense for second quarter last year due to the network outage. But strong mobile figures in Norway this quarter.</p>
          <p>Denmark, the currency development and interconnect doesn't translate into reduced EBITDA. So what you see here, or NOK222 million, is the sum of the mobile, fixed and the wholesale revenues going down in Denmark.</p>
          <p>Strong performance in DiGi in Pakistan, improved margins, good growth close to &#x2013; or more than NOK300 million in EBITDA growth from those two operations. And then India, reduced cash burn given the new accounting definition of NOK340 million, and here we have also expensed approximately NOK100 million that normally would have been treated as CapEx. Other units, more or less stable.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the CapEx this quarter, it's higher than second quarter last year with some NOK226 million, about NOK458 million of that is related to higher CapEx in DiGi and DTAC. DTAC due to the 3G rollout on 850 MHz and the network swap; DiGi due to the network swap.</p>
          <p>We are NOK200 million lower in Uninor, both due to a reduced investment level, but also due to the new accounting of CapEx. And Norway is still at a high level, NOK2 billion CapEx in the first half-year, and we expect that to be the same in the second half year. And as you see from the pie chart, Norway now constitutes about one-third of the CapEx in the Group.</p>
          <p>So this results then in annual operating cash flow, as Fredrik said, approaching NOK20 billion on a 12-month rolling basis. It's now NOK19.7 billion, including the cash burn in India. Year-on-year, the cash flow is up NOK370 million due to the explanations I've been through, but the main contributor is of course the reduced cash burn in Uninor.</p>
          <p>Then going through the P&amp;L. We have already explained the development in revenues and EBITDA. Other items in line with last year, we have a significant manning reduction in the Swedish operation this quarter. We have accrued for about 140 people leaving the company.</p>
          <p>On the depreciation, we have significantly lower depreciation due that we had the higher acceleration of depreciations last year due to the network swaps. So EBIT comes in approximately NOK1 billion higher than last year due to lower depreciations on higher EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Then we have a couple of line items that require some explanation. We have the associated companies, which largely is VimpelCom. Last year, we had several one-offs that in sum was quite positive accounting-wise. We had accounting gain of NOK1.6 billion related to the dilution of our shares in VimpelCom following the Wind transaction, and we have the C More impairment. So net of that, there is a decline in associated companies from NOK1.4 billion to NOK700 million approximately.</p>
          <p>That NOK700 million drop is all related to VimpelCom and there are two big effects. VimpelCom had a currency gain in second quarter last year that is not impacting this year. That is about NOK380 million impact. And the other one is that we owned close to 40% economic of VimpelCom in the second quarter last year, and before we bought the common shares this quarter, our ownership was down to approximately 32% economic. And that dilution effect, VimpelCom still makes good profit. It's about NOK280 million.</p>
          <p>So underlying there is not that much change but there are these special explanations that bridge the NOK2.6 billion to the NOK700 million.</p>
          <p>Net financials also have a big swing of about NOK1.3 billion from last year to this year, and there are really three explanations behind that. First, the net interest expense of the Group is NOK280 million higher this quarter, that is all related to increased proportional rupee debt in the Group, which is very expensive, and I'll come back to how we deal with that.</p>
          <p>Then currency gains was NOK354 million positive last year and the other currency loss of NOK180 million this quarter, that is on hedging instruments that we cannot book as hedging due to IS and it is really driven by an increased dollar in the quarter. So that explains about NOK540 million of the delta between second quarter last year and this year.</p>
          <p>And then finally, on financial instruments, we had a gain last year and a loss this year and the loss this year is related to the TRS in VimpelCom. We had a big gain in the first quarter, then the shared price of VimpelCom dropped until we terminated the TRS, and that's resulted in a loss in the second quarter of about NOK285 million and all these VimpelCom shares are then accounted for as associated with the share of profits going forward.</p>
          <p>On the tax line, NOK1.5 billion in tax expense, about 10% of that, or NOK150 million, is a one-off, so underlying tax expense this quarter is about NOK1.350 million. Minority stands higher due to strong results in DTAC and DiGi, where we don't have 100% ownership, so net income to Telenor this quarter is around NOK2.1 billion and EPS NOK1.31.</p>
          <p>Then moving on to the balance sheet. Net debt stands at NOK28.6 billion at the end of this quarter. That is up NOK9.3 billion from first quarter. This is as expected. There are two main drivers behind this. It's the dividend payout to Telenor shareholders and minorities in our Asian subsidiaries of NOK8.5 billion. And it's the purchase of common shares in VIP of NOK4.2 billion, total NOK12.7 billion on those two items driving up the net debt to EBITDA. The ratio net debt to EBITDA stands at 0.93%, and as you recall that is well below our self-imposed cap of 2.0%, and still among the lowest leveraged telecom group in &#x2013; groups in Europe.</p>
          <p>Then on the Indian side, it's not only operational restructuring, it's also a financial restructuring which has an impact on the financing of the total Telenor Group. Since the license cancellation in India, 2nd of February, the launch of Uninor have been in default. And we have &#x2013; and Uninor has been in discussions with the lenders since this happened and this has resulted in that the lenders have decided to accelerate the loans, and asked Telenor to largely pay-up on the guaranteed debt.</p>
          <p>This is not unexpected to us. We have informed all along since the license cancellation. And the impact to Telenor is that it has zero impact on our exposure. This is already consolidated as a part of the debt, and the risk we've had all along since we started the guarantee for the debt. I would rather put it very positively that this will enable us to reduce our interest costs significantly going forward. The repay loans are very expensive, with rates from 12%, 13%, and they're able to refinance that at much lower cost at group levels. It also enables us to draw the debt in the currencies that makes more sense to us, which basically will be euros and dollars. We don't need that much rupee exposure given Uninor's size of the total Group.</p>
          <p>We're also now working on various funding options for Uninor until completion of that company. We have decided to bid in auction, if we get that far, through NewCo, and also then working on how to finance NewCo.</p>
          <p>Of course, payout of dividends by buying of VimpelCom shares, share buyback program, and also restructuring of the debt in Uninor, where Telenor's steps in as a creditor, requires a lot of liquidity. So we have worked a lot of that in the second quarter. We have issued two bonds, each of &#x20AC;500 million. First one with maturity of five-and-a-half years and a coupon of 1.75%. Second one of a maturity of nine-and-a-half year and a coupon of 2.75%. And I'm proud to say that these coupons are the lowest ever issued by a European corporate, which shows the strength of the Group.</p>
          <p>Also on backup financing, we have replaced one of our revolving credit facilities that was maturing next year with a new credit facilities with Nordic banks, maturing in 2017. So the backup facility now stands at NOK2.8 billion with maturities in 2016 and 2017, and these are all undrawn. So we have good liquidity and good lines, and with a restructuring of the rupee debt, also the interest cost should come significantly down.</p>
          <p>Then the buyback program. Fredrik said, third years in a row, 3% buyback. So we will bought back close to 9% of the shares in the Group. That equals about 47 million shares, 3%. 22 million of that will be aimed at buying &#x2013; will be bought back in the market, and then we have an agreement with the main shareholder, Norwegian State, that they will sell down proportionally, and that will equals about 25 million shares. And then this is all done, these shares will then be put forward to the general meeting next spring for cancellation and then target to be cancelled third quarter next year.</p>
          <p>So as you see from the bar chart, total approved payout to shareholders this year of Telenor is NOK12.6 billion, up from NOK10.7 billion last year and NOK8.8 billion a year before. So the shareholder remuneration is growing steadily and is at a healthy level.</p>
          <p>Then approaching the end here, the guiding. We are still guiding ex-India given the regulatory uncertainty, and if we get an auction on how we will get through an auction, there's so much uncertainty about the figures. So we think it's prudent to guide without India. We are basically maintaining our guiding that we released in the first quarter, organic revenue growth still about 4%, that requires a recovery in GP and also continued strong mobile performance in Norway.</p>
          <p>EBITDA margin, 35% to 36%. That is an underlying improvement from last year when we look at increased handset sales diluting margins and the revenue share in DTAC, the margin on the service revenues is going up.</p>
          <p>CapEx to sales, a slight adjustment. Previous guiding was 10% to 12%, nothing mysterious about that other than the we are six months through the year and that we have high activity level on 3G in Thailand, swaps in Thailand, swaps in DiGi and now starting swaps in Pakistan.</p>
          <p>Finally, 19th of September is a great day for Telenor. That's the Capital Markets Day. We will have five business units presenting this year, the obvious one, Uninor and Norway. In addition, Sweden will present their strategies, how they tackle the data revolution. Pakistan, midst of the growth curve combined with financial services, and DTAC now approaching becoming the biggest mobile operation in Telenor.</p>
          <p>In addition, you will learn more about our key initiatives on digital services and Group industrial development. I wish you all a hearty welcome to the Capital Markets Day on the 19th of September. Then Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. We are ready to take you questions. So I invite Mr. Baksaas back to the podium. To allow questions from as many as possible, we ask you to limit yourselves to one question per person and one follow-up question if a clarification is needed. Please wait for the microphone to be handed to you before you ask. We want everyone also on the webcast to be able to hear your questions. So let's start it here in the room and then we'll take questions from the phone or from the Internet afterwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a hand over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Espen Torgersen, Carnegie. Just a quick question on India. Should we understand that the following way that you have taken the formal decision to bid for somewhere in the region of nine licenses in spectrum on the basis of how the regulatory situation is looking today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way the decisions on the regulatory area in India is taking is difficult to predict and you cannot read into this that as a consequence we will automatically go for licensing in these circles. On the other hand, we have now concentrated resources in the best performance circles, number them by nine and take the restructuring now. And of course the answer to your question will solely depend on what kind of regulatory framework that ultimately will be on the table, for all nine of them.</p>
          <p>And in that equation, we will evaluate existing spectrum positions by existing place and reference price will be very central, and it's all going to be wrapped up within the INR155 billion peak funding setup that we've set for ourselves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Christer Roth from DnB. Just a quick question on the financial restructuring in India. How does that affect your bargaining power towards Unitech and how far away are you in your view in terms of a settlement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I couldn't fully hear you, Christer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. I'll try again. In terms of the financial restructuring in India, how does that affect your bargaining power against Unitech and how far away are you from a settlement with Unitech in terms of ownership?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we never comment on any discussions we may or may not have on the M&amp;A side, so I can only decline to comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions from the audience here in Fornebu? No further questions? It means we can switch to callers, please? First question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew Lee. Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. A question on India, please, and just around your peak funding target of INR155 billion. Does this exclude deferred payments of spectrum? And if it does exclude deferred payments, how can you give us comfort about the maximum you might pay to stay in the market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think deferred payment is one of the main features we need to see in this auction coming up, as we need to control the risk of our Indian investment, and that is, of course, an important part of the peak funding discussion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There were four real elements feeding into the overall framework for the next phase in India. That was the rollout, it was the number of frequencies available. It was the payment profile and it was the reserve price. And all these four elements, both by one by one and accumulatively, spells out the platform and we don't know as to whether &#x2013; how the two last ones will be decided, and that's what we and others are waiting for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Just to clarify, if you are given deferred payment, if you are allowed to make deferred payments, if we bundled all the deferred other payments over the next 10 years into one payment at the start, could that push you above the INR155 billion? I.e. could this take us above that peak funding target if we accelerated it all into one overall payment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take that one. No, you cannot look at this way. Obviously, we have a target now, we're reaching cash flow breakeven of Uninor next year and then Uninor will start to generate cash. The INR155 billion is how much operational cash flow we are willing to expose in India. So obviously we would assume that the positive cash flow of the 2013 would be able to pay down any deferred payment without increasing the INR155 billion that's on the table.</p>
          <p>Having said that, we also strongly state that we need a good return on new money that we put into India, so the deferred payment is not in any way compromising on the returns we are seeking on any new money we will put into Uninor &#x2013; or sorry, into a NewCo or Uninor until completion and through an auction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next caller, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy Parnis, UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, guys. I've got one question as well actually on India. I just wanted to &#x2013; what is your current assumption or understanding around getting the original $350 million you invested, or Uninor invested, in 2G spectrum back in 2008? Should we think of that as bring an incremental set of cash to be spent in India on top of INR155 billion peak funding requirement? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The original &#x2013;  the INR155 billion, that is, we have been very precise, that has always been stated as operational losses plus CapEx, because that is what we report every day. What is obviously &#x2013; where you have to make a bridge is obviously that what is being approved of funds into Uninor is both our equity investments that take care of some of that original investment in license, and also interest cost going forward, the equity investment and the guaranteed debt. And those numbers will not be the same, but the INR155 billion has been defined as EBITDA losses plus CapEx since we invested in the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to clarify, the $350 million that you originally invested in spectrum, would that be used in India, if you got that back, to fund your Indian operation or would that go elsewhere in the Group as it would fall above the INR155 billion peak funding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way that is &#x2013; the claim there is obviously that it's Uninor that has that claim on the Indian government. And there is also a debate in India whether or not that claim is valid. We see some statement that from Indian authorities. We think Uninor has a valid claim on that, but obviously that is a part of Uninor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jakob Bluestone from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Could you possibly talk us through a little bit what were the criteria for selecting the regions that you chose to exit. Jon alluded earlier to that it was a relatively low share of revenues and a higher share of the losses. Was that basically how you made the decision where to stay and where to exit? Or was there anything else you could maybe share with us in terms of the thought process? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well the decision profile on who's in and who's out is an evaluation of what we have achieved so far, the competitive situation in those areas and our own judgment on how can we recover or how can we not recover. And all in all, and with the need of also reducing the risk factor to a certain extent, we have taken this decision today. And of course this is also a difficult decision to our colleagues in Uninor because we are, on the one hand, putting more efforts into some circles and leaving other circles. And there are consequences on individual level.</p>
          <p>However, given the uncertainty in the regulatory framework and the constant postponement on decisions coming through, we think this is a prudent way of how to think on how to move forward. And then make ourselves as independent on other decisions as soon as possible, mainly to take it to breakeven as soon as possible, knowing that in that period, there will be, hopefully, there will be a decision and an auction, and then we have to evaluate the detailed parameters at that point of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just ask a follow-up, could you just talk about what happened to those four exits that you reach, and do you pull the plug or is the plan to sell the subscriber bases in the network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The assets in these circles that we will gradually scale down will, on the network side, gradually be deployed in other circles. So we will take base stations down and move them into the cluster philosophy that we have in other circles that we want to continue. So in that sense, we have 6,000 rough base stations that can be reused in other parts of India.</p>
          <p>And on the sale of the customer base, since this is a prepaid market and you have a high churn figure, the value and the possibility of such a sale is very limited. We're more talking about a port &#x2013; an agreement of portability rather than sale of a customer base. I think we have to be as realistic as that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Barry Zeitoune, Berenberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Just two questions on India, please. First is whether you can be a bit more specific on what the actual EBITDA loss in the four regions you're leaving was in Q2, or at least give us some idea of the proportion of your total India EBITDA loss that it represents.</p>
          <p>And then second question is really looking at the current consensus on spectrum pricing seems to be a 20% discount due to TRAI recommendation, and the consensus on the payment profile seems to be the EGoM recommendation, which was a 35% upfront payment and then a deferral over a 10-year period. Now when I apply that to the TRAI recommendation, what you basically get is about $500 million of total spectrum cost upfront, that's for 35%, of which about $200 million is in Mumbai.</p>
          <p>Now on my math, that would take you over your peak funding based on 5 MHz in each cycle. So I'm really interested in how you believe you can stay in Mumbai, and why you kept Mumbai within the nine circles remaining in. And whether you're confident staying in Mumbai will be possible while keeping within the INR155 billion peak funding target. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you have dived into one of the &#x2013; this is not pre-spreadsheet number, 25. I think we're already at a detailed level that we can't take at this stage. And I also have to say that despite rumors and speculations that both the reserve price and the deferred payment issue has been on the agenda of media in India over the last couple of weeks. I don't think we should preempt that that will end up as being the final decision. So I think we have to wait until the decision really has been seen. And knowing that this is not only an EGoM issue after all, this is also now to be confirmed by government after it becomes &#x2013; after that, and it's only after that that it will become a decision. So I'm not prepared to walk into those -that detail of level on Mumbai that you asked.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe if I ask it in a different way then, was Mumbai a region you were definitely dead-set on that you wanted to stay in, or was it borderline when you attempted to include that with &#x2013; on top of the four that you're currently leaving?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have an interconnect arrangement, a roaming arrangement, with another player in the Mumbai area that makes things a bit differently for that specific region, knowing also that we've had reasonable good traction on how to go-to market. And maybe that can be utilized for some good purpose in the next round.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just on the EBITDA question, can you give us an idea of the proportion of the EBITDA loss that was &#x2013; that came from the four circles you're planning to scale down your operations in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you're able to analyze that yourself. However, it's definitely more than double the percentage of revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one or two more questions from the phone, Barry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maurice Patrick, Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, guys. A quick question around inflation, whether it's import price or impact of commodities. Are you seeing any major changes at all that are impacting your numbers, whether it's demand or cost? Would love to get a sense of that, thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Asia in particular?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't have an inflationary element to sort of point to when it comes to how network capacities are being used by customers for the time being. Since the oil price basically is where it is, we haven't had the energy side, except for our own cost side of being an energy consumer ourselves. But it seems quite okay.</p>
          <p>And if you take a look at Thailand and Malaysia in particular, the intensity on how people use digital services is growing strongly. And knowing that 3G has only just started in Thailand, we already at this point can say we have above 1 million users on our 3G offering. So we have great expectations really on how this can move forward if, as you indicate, the economies can stay the course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could also add that in Thailand and Malaysia, we have seen strengthening of both baht and ringgit, which of course also put down inflationary pressure on imports. So this quarter we have not seen any signs of import inflation in those countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we will take two more callers and then we will round up here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terence Tsui, Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good morning, everyone. My question is on Bangladesh, maybe you can just give us a bit more color on your turnaround strategy there and be a bit more specific where you saw the increase in competition? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, what we saw in the second quarter was that some of our competitors were able to take a big share on net adds. That's been done as we see it due to pushing pricing, due to pushing higher commission levels in the trade. We as a market leader cannot sit still and look at that so we are taking actions now, especially in the trade and the distribution, to counteract that development as the clear market leader in Bangladesh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think we should be in a way open and register that Grameenphone has usually been very, very clever on how to judge the speed in the market when it comes to new segments coming in. And need to get back in that position. Penetration still stands low in Bangladesh and we will probably see the growth into new user segments in Bangladesh as we've seen in other countries. And Grameenphone should be as best-positioned to handle that as anyone else. And it's that attitude that needs to get back on the table.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jan Dworsky, Handelsbanken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, thank you. One last question here on India perhaps. On a similar math to Barry's earlier, it looks like if we go through region by region, the suggested cost with a 20% cost cut on TRAI prices that it's very far from possible without deferred funding and hardly possible with deferred funding. Would it be correct to say that deferred funding is a prerequisite to stay around in India? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we're in a way back to a previous question that we had on this session. And you're absolutely right in the fact that deferred payments will make a continuation more possible than if it's not there, and that's been our clear message all the way through as well. So deferred payment and a level of reserve price. Those are the two decisions that we're waiting for, whereas there is another element in this discussion as well. This probably delays decisions in India, and that is how to reform or how to get the whole of the market, all players, onto one platform on how to pay for spectrum, namely that the reforming. And I guess that that question is of a very high importance to incumbents as it doesn't treat a newcomer like Uninor in the same way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you everyone for your questions. That concludes the session here today. Thank you everyone for joining us online or here in the room. We are open to conduct interviews here on stage. I maintain a list for the media, so come to me first. And give us a few minutes before we start, so we can freshen up here. Thank you, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>