<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1290744" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2932</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Scott Engebrigtsen, Communication Manager</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jon Fredrik Baksaas, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Richard Olav Aa, Appointed Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Martin Hoff</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Arild Nys&#xE6;ther</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Frank Maa&#xF8;</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Marianne Moe</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Ole J&#xF8;rgen R&#xF8;d</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Tim Boddy</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Peter Kurt Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">James Britton</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Ulrich Rathe</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Soomit Datta</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Andrew Lee</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">David Wright</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Presentation of the Quarterly Figures for the Fourth Quarter of 2009. My name is Scott Engebrigtsen, and I have the pleasure of guiding you through this morning's presentation.</p>
          <p>First, I would like to inform you about the emergency exits to the people who are present here at Fornebu. They are located on the right hand side of the bottom of the stairs through a door in the glass wall behind you and in addition to the same door you used when you came in this morning.</p>
          <p>We hope that everyone has the material that we've made available. That is our press release, a copy of the presentation, which will be used here in a minute, and of course, our quarterly report. And you will find all this information also on our website at telenor.com.</p>
          <p>You can watch this presentation live or in recording on either the Internet or on a mobile phone and you may also send in your written questions during this transmission, and you'll find information on these alternatives also from our website.</p>
          <p>As usual, after the presentation there will be a Q&amp;A session and we'll start with the audience present here at Fornebu, then turn over to the ones participating on the phone before we offer the opportunity to do individual interviews.</p>
          <p>And today our CEO, Jon Fredrik Baksaas, will present the figures. So I'll leave the floor to you, Mr. Baksaas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Scott, and good morning to you all. I have to say that while standing here in February 2010 looking back at 2009 and the prospects that were prevailing only one year back in history we feel that 2009 after all has come out with quite a solid &#x2013; has come out as a quite solid year for Telenor.</p>
          <p>We have delivered on our guidance for 2009. We have adjusted our priorities significantly. And we've come out with an all time high cash flow, operating cash flow, of NOK20 billion. And in addition to that, on the operating side, we have achieved a successful launch of our Indian operation and we have also taken quite some significant steps out of the conflict area with our Russian friends and we've got the VimpelCom Limited transaction into the streets yesterday.</p>
          <p>And this leads up to the conclusion that we based upon the operating performance in 2009. In our Board meeting yesterday we have proposed to issue a dividend for NOK2.50 per share payable in after the general election this year.</p>
          <p>If we then move on to the operating side of the Telenor Group, I will start in the Nordics. We have delivered on the cash flow target that we set for ourselves back in the Capital Markets Day in 2007. That was NOK10 billion, and as you can see from the figures, we are very, very close to that. We're at 9.983 or something, which means that given the priorities that we've set for ourselves throughout this period, has come through.</p>
          <p>This has, of course, been helped by the fact that there is a very strong demand for mobile broadband in the Nordic area and Norway, in particular. So this has been helped by the fact that the Nordic countries, and Norway again in particular, has been fairly unaffected by the recession effects that we could think of beginning of this year.</p>
          <p>In fact, in Norway as such we can look at 7% mobile revenue growth in Norway alone, which is a very strong figure. Half &#x2013; and half of that comes from the handset sales, primarily from the iPhones and the other half comes from increased usage, also primarily from the new handset generation that the iPhone leads.</p>
          <p>We have also come through with new vendor agreements which will have a longer term effect in the Telenor Group and we will see effects of that both on service levels, capacities and also CapEx figures into the future. And the future in this respect is two to three years. In the Nordic area we have also had quite good performance in the broadcast area.</p>
          <p>For this quarter there is a 5% revenue growth driven by Canal Digital and also satellite broadcasting. And we have, as you know, successfully launched Thor 6 as the latest satellite that was brought into orbit successfully in December this year. So, all in all, I have to congratulate the management team in the three Scandinavian countries and broadcast basically for this performance because if we again refer back to the prospects for 2009 the way we saw them one year back, I think this is very well done. And I also think we are very well prepared for positioning Telenor further in the Scandinavian markets with this base.</p>
          <p>If we then move on to the Central and Eastern Europe region for Telenor, this region also produces a significant very good margins, but this is done in a very challenging and much more challenging economic climate than that in the Nordic areas. We can see though that in Kyivstar we have a slight pickup in average revenue per user in local currency. But, the currency effects when you convert all this to Norwegian kroner is, of course, very significant. The organic growth figure between the fourth quarter 2008 compared to this fourth quarter in 2009 is on a reported basis very significant. But, on an organic figure is 11% and that stems from a significant drop in usage basically, when the Ukrainian market saw the recessionary effects coming at the beginning of this year.</p>
          <p>Kyivstar as an operating company has done very well under these circumstances and are delivering an operating year with solid margins and the position for the company moving forward also opting for the 3G when that eventually will happen is, of course, something we're looking forward to.</p>
          <p>The other countries in this region have been hampered by more or less the same effects. Both Hungary and Serbia, the governments in those two countries has introduced new taxation, both on VAT and special taxation on telecom services. And, of course, this picks into people's pockets and in Pannon we register a 7% lower ARPU as a consequence of this. Despite this, we are able to run Pannon in the mid 30s when it comes to the margin and we consider that we shall be able to maintain this level going forward.</p>
          <p>If we then move to Asia, we see another trend, all the Asian markets seems to show signs of growth again. There are subscriber growth in all countries, Bangladesh Grameenphone leads in this respect with 1.3 million new subscribers. And this is, of course, driven by SIM tax subsidies. In Grameenphone we have taken the stand that when there is market growth, both in revenues and customers we need to take our share of that to maintain market leader position. And despite ourselves seeing Grameenphone showing lower margin compared 2008 and 2009 there is a phenomenal operating year for Grameenphone throughout 2009, with also an impressive improvement in cash flow, which I will come back to.</p>
          <p>But we also see positive signs in Thailand, which is very good to see, and if we refer to the Thai premier's, the presentation of the Thai economy after Davos. I think we also can confirm that we're seeing some of those signs that he described, being that tourism is coming back to the country and it looks better than what it did one year ago. This combined with the strong capital discipline that we have exercised in all these operations has given us a very good operating year and again a good position, we believe, the way the competitive landscape in these countries are for the time being.</p>
          <p>Then for India, the launch that we made in India was done in an impressive speed. We were able to activate more than 13,000 towers in record time and, as you know, we have launched now in eight circles. This covers around 600 million plus people. And in this geography at the end of the year we recorded 1 million subscribers at the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>We had some scaling challenges on the IT side to begin with the first two weeks. But, after that we've seen a quite steady growth of number of customers coming in. And we are also satisfied with the subscriber uptake in January and these figures will, by the way, be released in quite a short while.</p>
          <p>It's too early though to say something about the trends on the usage side and the ARPU development will, of course, be key to how we move forward. But so far, we're reasonably happy with how we've started and how the subscriber, the reception among potential customers, has resulted in subscriber buildup.</p>
          <p>The second launch phase is likely to be somewhat delayed due to the new security approval that the government of India has introduced. This relates to approval for all purchasing orders for technical equipment that the telecom players will install in their networks in India, and this constitutes a delay in the rollout picture. The second launch phase might therefore be sliding into the second quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>If we then take a look on how revenues have built for Telenor in this immediate period. Reported revenues are down 11% but this is mainly due to the weak Norwegian kroner that we had in fourth quarter 2008. As you probably remember, at that point of time we had sort of the weakest point of the Norwegian kroner as such compared to both periods before and periods after.</p>
          <p>Organically, there is an organic growth figure here of minus 1%, which aligns fairly okay with our guidance, which was at the level with 2008. The EBITDA dilution that you can see in the fourth quarter here is primarily due to the launch in India.</p>
          <p>If we exclude this, we maintained an EBITDA margin at more or less the same level as previous quarters in this year. If we then look at the CapEx development, also, this one is in line with our outlook for the year. We have exercised a very strict capital discipline program this year based upon what we see as being the new volume development in each and every market.</p>
          <p>We have a satellite coming in in the fourth quarter here of NOK950 million for Thor 6 and the CapEx spending in India in fourth quarter is, of course, also part of this. If we exclude the satellite and the India operation as such we are at 14% CapEx to sales in the overall portfolio of mobile companies and fixed Norway. And, given the situation that we are in, I think this is sort of the level which reflects the change in economic surroundings basically that we've seen in all markets cumulatively.</p>
          <p>There are some CapEx, of course, that comes in at probably the end of the year in all operations. But, this last quarter effect in the year hasn't been as significant this year as it was for previous years, again, coming from the capital discipline approach. All-in-all, therefore, if we look to the operating cash flow in 2009 there are, the way we look at it, a very strong development curve. In the Nordics we have steadily grown towards the nine &#x2013; 10 billion. So, looking back to 2007 when we set this target I think we felt that the target was a stiff one to reach. But, two years down the line we have managed to do that and we are as well positioned in the markets as we were at that point of time.</p>
          <p>In Central and Eastern Europe both volumes and currency effects brings the cash flow down. Margin wise we are &#x2013; we have the highest cash flow margins in this region within the group. But in nominal kroner the figure is being reduced. That is not the case in Asia, on the contrary, the cash flow from the four more mature operations are building up very strongly and in fact Grameenphone, as I said, has improved their cash flow in 2009 compared to 2008 with as much as NOK2 billion. And maybe this is something also which is reflected in the stock price development for Grameenphone after it was stock listed late last year. But, also it's worth mentioning here that in Pakistan, our people in Pakistan, have managed to bring forward a close to cash flow breakeven operation for 2009, which is actually close to one year earlier than we had in our business case.</p>
          <p>The good thing in the telecommunication market in Pakistan for the time being is that it is in the growth phase where the market really expands their use of telecommunications and the market is with Telenor as a good contributor to that healthy growth.</p>
          <p>If we then move over to financials, the net interest bearing debt has been reduced significantly throughout this year. And also the net debt to EBITDA has been significantly reduced. And it is, of course, this situation that enables the Board to propose for the dividend transaction that we have informed. There is an accumulated currency effect in 2009 in this picture of around NOK5 billion, because of the weak kroner that we had at the beginning of the year compared to the stronger kroner that we have at the end of the year, and this effect came primarily in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>After that it is the operating performance that basically has driven the net debt down and, of course, strongly helped by the fact that we have got full dividend payments from Kyivstar for all the years that was outstanding and also for 2008. And this is also a significant figure, of course.</p>
          <p>With this situation altogether we feel comfortable that the balance sheet has the strength and that the prognosis for how we intend to run Telenor forward can give room for moving back to paying dividends, returning to paying dividends in the way we have proposed and that comes here. There is a proposal here to pay a dividend for NOK2.50 per share. This will mean a total payout of NOK4.1 billion. The rationale for this is then the strong operating performance in 2009 and the prospects that we are now seeing for 2010. And this has, of course, also been facilitated by the fact that we have resolved the dividend issue for Kyivstar and altogether there is a 5 billion inflow of dividends from VimpelCom and Kyivstar in 2009.</p>
          <p>From 2010 it is therefore the intention of the Group of returning to the normalized dividend policy where 40 to 60% of normalized net income is to be distributed as dividends. And it's also our aim to have a nominal increase in dividends going forward. So, we're very happy that we can return to this dividend policy compared to the statement that we had to take last year due to the impairing at the same time as the recession effects came in as they did.</p>
          <p>We have also given some mention to 2010. There is, as far as we can see it, signs of market recovery in Asia. We're not the only one noticing that but we're at least also seeing some pickups in all our Asian countries. We still see a challenging economic climate in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>However, I do think we've seen an interesting slight pickup in ARPU figures for Ukraine. We are so far at the plan for our Indian Uninor operation and the completion, of course, to establish VimpelCom Limited is one of the main priorities for us. The approval by the Russian authorities last week, the prospectus being issued yesterday, are the natural steps and milestones in this process moving on towards the final closing. Again, expected to happen sometime second quarter.</p>
          <p>I will then close with the outlook for 2010. Last year in 2009 we saw a reasonably stable revenue development with an EBITDA margin of 32.5% on reported basis. And reported basis in this structure means that this guiding covers all entities in the Telenor Group, except Kyivstar. We also had on this structure a 16.5% CapEx to sales figures in 2009. We do believe that there is a potential for a slight revenue growth to happen in 2010. We are indicating this as being a low single digit growth factor.</p>
          <p>We are seeing an EBITDA margin which will be lower than 2009, in the range of 27 to 28%. And the reason for this is, of course, that 2010 will be the most significant year in India for us when it comes to building up the full operation. But CapEx to sales in India including will, the way we see it now, stand at 14 to 16% and if we sort of take India isolated from this, but they being included in the figures that I just mentioned, we're seeing an EBITDA loss in the range of 4.5 to NOK5 billion and we're seeing a CapEx figure of around 2.5 to NOK3.5 billion. And the reason for these figures then to be wider in the guiding setup than we've been used to is, of course, that there are some monitoring possibilities and trimming possibilities going forward in 2010 that we want to watch out for. These figures do not include potential licenses, for example, in the 3G field that might emerge through 2010 because these license processes are quite difficult to forecast precisely.</p>
          <p>In India, we are also standing very firmly on what we said before that we are on the north side of the peak funding of INR155 billion that we have stated for the business plan as such.</p>
          <p>And we also believe that the vendor agreements that we have in the Nordic countries will assist in reducing CapEx figures going forward. There will not be that significant effect of that in 2010 and there also might be some quarterly events here that might bring the CapEx figure slightly higher. But, on an annual and on a yearly basis, these are our guidance and outlook for 2010.</p>
          <p>And with those words, I'm through with my presentation today. I'm now happy to introduce to you the new CFO to Telenor Group, Mr. Richard Aa. Please, Richard. Richard comes to Telenor and will take up his position from 1st of March. He comes from the financial control area, not surprisingly, from other companies in Norway, prominently from Elkem for many years when Elkem was stock listed, and has also participated in the industrial and energy group after that period. He is 43 years of age. I have to come to learn him as a sharp guy, so let's hope that it stays the same picture when we get to know him closer. Please, Richard, you're welcome to Telenor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fredrik. It's really a pleasure to be here today. And I certainly look forward to start working with the Group. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We are now ready to take your questions and I would like to invite Marianne Moe to the podium. Marianne is head of our investor relations department in Telenor Group. And as usual, we'll start with the audience present. Please be so kind as to wait for microphone and also state your name and company.</p>
          <p>Okay. I think we'll start with Martin Hoff here, Arctic, then Arild Nys&#xE6;ther.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Since no one used these emergency exits I think I can congratulate you with the very good results and I have two questions. The first one is your very strong operating cash flow in Q4 alone reducing net debt by well over NOK3 billion, and I remember your former CFO, Westlie stated that you have a target, net debt to EBITDA target reported of keeping below 1.6 and it's now 0.8. Perhaps you could say why aren't you paying a significantly higher dividend than 2.5 because it actually sounds very low looking at the figures, even if we know that India is going to be a cash flow drain for 2010?</p>
          <p>And my second question is the Ukraine market is developing weaker than the Russian market. Is there any risk of a renegotiation of your ownership stakes in new VimpelCom Limited as a result? Or is the ownership stakes that you've announced set in stone? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Firstly, I'm glad that you didn't use the exit, the emergency exit. And if I recall, you didn't use them last year either. But, joke aside. The 1.6 target that we set for ourselves was set in a period where we were sort of stretching the rating parameters basically for the group. And to really institutionalize the capital discipline approach that we now see the results from, that was necessary.</p>
          <p>In 2009 &#x2013; sorry, in 2010, which will be the heaviest year for the buildup in India, we anticipate that we need some leeway up against the 1.6. And also for the potential of seeing a weakening Norwegian kroner again, we feel that it's necessary to see a certain leeway up to the 1.6. To come back to the regular dividend policy of Telenor to 40% to 60% we feel that NOK2.5 per share is a very good beginning under these circumstances.</p>
          <p>As to your second question, everything in the VimpelCom transaction deal is based on a fairly long number of condition precedents, at least it has many factors. And everything has moved according to the milestone setup for that transaction. And apart from that, now seeing the transaction on the streets, we are very comfortable that we are seeing this good progress and that the same progress should follow through the remaining part of the closing period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Arild Nys&#xE6;ther [Fondsfinans ASA]. Just hand over the microphone to him, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I also have a question on Kyivstar though more operational. We've seen there's a healthy pickup in ARPU in Q4. But we know that there is a strong competition, price competition in Kyivstar and that the other competitors are offering quite significant lower prices than Kyivstar have been doing and that there is some pressure for Kyivstar also to lower their prices now in a weaker economic time than previously where they were able to command stronger price premium. Can you give some comments about your expectations for the Ukraine market in light of those perhaps opposing factors, if there is a slight fundamental pickup but then Kyivstar needs to be more competitive?</p>
          <p>And the second question is; is there anything you can tell us about the legal process in Russia, which is still the last outstanding condition that has to be met, there's not that much time left now, so perhaps you can tell us something about your expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You're right that in the fact that Kyivstar has a market position building strongly on brand values in Ukraine and the strength of the network quality combined with a very wide distribution, and this strength has enabled Kyivstar to carry out a pricing philosophy and a pricing structure, which has delivered phenomenal results over the years. And I must also say that the robustness of Kyivstar is up against the new economic climate that we've seen in Ukraine for 2009 has been very good. But, we're watching out for those characteristics that you're describing, of course, and Kyivstar will, in that sense, position itself to avoid to the utmost extent possible any sort of strong negative impact from those characteristics that you're saying.</p>
          <p>On the other side we've just seen an election in Ukraine, the Ukraine has been through a period with uncertainties when it comes to the results of the political situation and with this now at least cleared on the top there is reason to believe that we also can see some action that might revive the industrial activities in the Ukraine and that there might be some effects of this coming later towards the end of this year.</p>
          <p>As to your last question, the legal process around the Farimex case, this is one of those condition precedents, which is carved in stone around the VimpelCom Limited combination and as such the Farimex case needs to be resolved within the timing parameters of the closing process. And there is no change in that setting. How the parties in Russia basically will resolve is not up to Telenor to participate in. The conclusion is that the Farimex case needs to be resolved without any financial consequences for Telenor or its shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a question here from Frank Maa&#xF8; [DnB NOR Markets].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Two questions if I may. The first one is more related to again the first question which was asked earlier. It's relating to the net debt to EBITDA ratio and which you set back at 1.6 at the Capital Markets Day, and now you mentioned that you needed some leeway but if you add that up, if you make &#x2013; run the numbers, I see that it's at least NOK50 billion for leeway up to the 1.6 based on your current guidance, at least that just from running the numbers in my head right now. So, I mean that's quite some leeway and if you see that some of those points, the data points, going in the right direction when it comes to the need for leeway through this year, would you be willing to consider buybacks again in order to ensure the right capital structure? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is another one to the exchange ratio in Kyivstar, we saw that the exchange ratio in Kyivstar in the prospectus yesterday was based on among other things a fairness opinion from UBS. And those numbers for Kyivstar which they included in their estimates were clearly missed today at least on the EBITDA level. So, my question then is, and that &#x2013; those numbers were updated as of October 3, so my question is do you feel that based on this there is a need for an updated fairness opinion, when it comes to that exchange ratio? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm happy that you at least recognize that there is a dividend transaction under these circumstances being proposed. We also have to recognize that you are looking at the figure could be bigger. But, on the other hand, this is the leeway way of thinking of it, the way you did, is then sort of balanced out in the NOK2.50 per share, NOK4.1 billion as dividend for this year. That doesn't lead us into a buyback kind of thinking. So we have no comments to that at this point in time.</p>
          <p>As for Kyivstar, the prospectus will be updated, based upon audited figures sometime mid-March. And, I think, it's far too early to speculate on any consequences of that as of today. And there are many parameters that plow into the overall balanced viewpoint between the two companies in that equation, you could say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would also, regarding the first question about buybacks, I would also like to add that, for the time being, we don't have any buyback permission from the Annual General Meeting. That's given on a one-year basis and it was not renewed in May 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Are there any more questions? Yes, please, we have a question over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ole J&#xF8;rgen R&#xF8;d of First Securities. You continue to deliver quite modest profitability from your Swedish and Danish operations, in part explained by charges this quarter. But, still, at what time &#x2013; point in time should we expect that you reach closer to your potential in Sweden and Denmark? And can you give us some pointers regarding what that potential might be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sweden has been through a turnaround in 2009. No doubt about that. Both market-wise and operating-wise, we needed to really turn around in Sweden. And those measurements were carried out between third and fourth quarter, this autumn, or in the autumn 2009. And it is our anticipation that we, through these measurements, can see a margin development for the Swedish operation next year, without me quantifying it here and now.</p>
          <p>You can see some effects of it already on the margin. But I do think that with the downsizing that we did in Sweden throughout the second half that we shall see those results, both on the operating expense side as well as on the activities that we're carrying out on the market side.</p>
          <p>Remember here, also, that are three product lines in Sweden, where both broadband and fixed-voice telephony has been under pressure, revenue wise. And this has not fully &#x2013; had been previously been compensated by the growth of the mobile revenues, but, as you see in this fourth quarter, that compensation is there.</p>
          <p>If we then look to Denmark, the competitive structure in both Sweden and Denmark is different from that in Norway. And, in a fairly small country from a geography point of view, that competition is quite intensive. So &#x2013; but I think that, given the priorities that we've set for ourselves in Denmark, we have maintained market &#x2013; revenue market share. And we've positioned Telenor in Denmark reasonably well. And I also hope that we can secure markets &#x2013; margins from that base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any other questions from the analysts present?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Telenor has become more or less a mobile company. Mobile telephony is all about &#x2013; it's all about this thing which is a bad telephone. But you have home ground and that's Norway, Denmark and Sweden. And you have to prepare for the future. And then you have to use those as a playground and the test bed. Then it's strange to me that you reduce the spending in research and development. When you look at the politics of your major owner that wants all companies in Norway to increase spending in research and development for preparing for the next 10 to 20 years, and we're going to have now 4G telephony in a couple of years.</p>
          <p>And you have to prepare for that. That makes quite an interesting investment. It needs to be much, much more of the fiber. And then I'm going to ask you, what is your, then, strategy for both next-generation mobile telephony, which is going to be going all around the world in 10 years' time? And then the fiber strategy for fiber to the home and fiber to the building, which is going to be more and more what is needed in the next 10 years for commercial use?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that is, of course, an important and a very big question. The development of the telecommunication industry from being very infrastructure oriented to become a service-oriented industry and not so money intensive as it was previously, results in the fact that the innovation and development work is done differently in this decade than it was done some years and decades ago. Previously, there were national standards and national monopolies that did this work. And this led to both the mobile development in the 80s and it led to the GSM protocol in Europe in the 90s. And the Scandinavian telcos, Telenor included, was part of that work.</p>
          <p>In 2010, the development work and innovation work is done in collaborations at industry levels between operators and vendors in quite a different manner and on a much different scale. So, for us to work in the same way as we did a couple of decades ago, in this period, is out of the question. We need to monitor our resources on the research and development, closer to what you ended your question with, namely that of the commercial development. And that is exactly what we're doing.</p>
          <p>There is a change of competence needed here in the ecosystem from within Telenor towards the ecosystem of telecom and IT. And that is the change that we are executing &#x2013; that we are in the midst of executing. And we've taken an aggressive, and among the first operators, in the world to standardize on the next generation of mobile systems in Scandinavia, through the new vendor agreements that we made for the three Nordic &#x2013; Scandinavian countries.</p>
          <p>And, again, we believe that the fourth generation of mobile technology will show that the Scandinavian countries will be the new showcase for how mobile communications will develop, where data communications is as significant a driver for how these networks will develop, as voice was it back in the 90s when the GSM protocol came.</p>
          <p>We've taken some important decisions in that direction. And you could also argue that the next generation of mobile networks in Norway starting to be launched towards the end of 2010, will be of the same importance as digitalization of the fixed network was in 26 November, 2000 &#x2013; 1997, when we were the second country in Europe completing that exercise. So, I think there is a comparison here of complete and new makeovers of the base technology. Then comes, also, service development innovation that is needed to participate in to get these new high-capacity networks to work.</p>
          <p>Your last question on fiber. Fiber is considered as the bulletproof technology for the future for every purpose. And the issue of fiber to the home on a country base has been an underlying question for many years. Commercially, there is no way that there can be fiber to the home to all households in Norway, because the commercial factor needed to do that is not present for the way we know the cost structures as of today. But in central and heavily populated areas, fibers are gradually coming in, both through Telenor initiatives and through other initiatives.</p>
          <p>And gradually, this will happen. First and foremost, of course, and it has already happened to companies, secondly, to household units and then freestanding households as such. And that competition is, in central areas, ongoing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we need to turn over now to the participants on the phone and give them a chance as well. And I know that we have a lot of questions from those participants as well, which is delightful. But I will have to urge you to please limit the number of questions as much as possible, due to the fact that we're having several questions. Okay, please can we have the first question from the ones participating on the phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Tim Boddy, Goldman Sachs. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks for the question. I wanted to ask just a bit more about India. With the upcoming 3G auctions, you've mentioned that you may need some CapEx for that. If you could just help us understand how you think about that?</p>
          <p>Also, if the government regulations around consolidation change, is Telenor more likely to be a buyer or a seller in India in a potential consolidation scenario?</p>
          <p>And then lastly on CapEx, it'd be helpful &#x2013; you had this, I think, very unusual contract that you've agreed, in Norway in particular, which looks like, over the medium term, it could dramatically lower CapEx to sales for your Norwegian mobile business. I wonder if you could just talk, in an LTE environment, where you think CapEx to sales in Norway would head? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>3G in India has, again, been postponed. There was a date in February when it was anticipated to take place. Now I think that the timeline is more in the third quarter. We have no changed viewpoints on 3G. We will not participate in a nationwide 3G auction in India. We might consider other arrangements. But this, again, is decided by what kind of structure we will eventually see on the 3G issue, as such, in India. And it also plays into how the remaining frequencies available in the 2G field will be delivered to us, as a newcomer, and the rest of the market.</p>
          <p>Are we buyer or seller? I cannot comment on that question as of today. Future will show what kind of end game type of results there might be. Our ambition in India is to build an industrial position in the first round, reaching for an 8% market share in the longer term and the financial parameters around the business case as you know them. What consolidation might &#x2013; what type of consolidation that might come here, that's for the future to show.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But what we said on Capital Markets Day in September is still valid. That means that we will not make any major cash acquisitions next two to three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that was a sort of happy underlining. And then, as to the CapEx to sales in Norway, yes, in the short to medium-term picture, we will have to carry out the renewal kind of CapEx activities in the Norwegian mobile network, which this change to the 4G technology will mean. But in the longer-term perspective, this modernization should, potentially, also lead to a lower CapEx to sales figures in the longer picture. By how much? It's far too early to have a viewpoint on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Peter Kurt Nielsen, Cheuvreux. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, Fredrik and Marianne. Two questions please. Firstly, domestic mobile. Your broadband, mobile broadband subscriber base now totals sort of around 10% of your total subscriber base. Could you talk a bit about what trends you're seeing in mobile broadband ARPU in Norway at the moment, pricing, usage-wise and how much of your revenue now, if possible, is from data and mobile broadband? And what sort of shift you're seeing there in terms of trends, revenue growth, et cetera?</p>
          <p>And second, if I may escalate into CapEx. In 2009, your paid CapEx has obviously been somewhat below your booked CapEx. I suspect this relates to India. Do you expect paid CapEx to catch up with booked CapEx, so-to-speak order CapEx in 2010? Or will you be able to continue to push some of those payments forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Peter Kurt. I would actually start with your last question, paid CapEx versus booked CapEx. It is correct, as you said, this is part of the explanation for paid CapEx being lower than booked CapEx is India. The CapEx booked is paid at some later time and there is a timing effect in that. In addition, the fourth quarter, we have the effect from the satellite, which is booked, 1 billion in fourth quarter, but has been paid in previous quarters. As long as we are in a rollout period in India, it's &#x2013; there will probably be some gap between the CapEx booked and CapEx paid.</p>
          <p>And then regarding your question about mobile broadband in Norway and ARPU trends. I think it's &#x2013; we have to admit it gets more and more difficult, actually, to give you one ARPU number because there are very &#x2013; there are different price plans and different &#x2013; and hence different ways of calculating ARPU in mobile broadband, because we have some price plans which are add-on to the existing SIM and then gives an add-on to the reported ARPU. Whereas other mobile broadband subscriptions are separate SIMs and dilute the ARPU. So, I think this will &#x2013; to avoid details here and now, I think it's better to take that with the IR team afterwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, James Britton, Nomura. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I've got two detailed financial questions focused on 2010. Firstly, on the guidance on margin, if we strip out guidance for India, it seems that the guidance for the rest of the Group implies a 1% decline in the EBITDA margin for 2010. Can you say what region you expect to see margin pressure and what is causing this?</p>
          <p>And secondly, can you just talk about your expectations for Nordic cash flow in 2010? Do expect to increase this further or will the mobile network overhaul make this difficult?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Firstly, I think there might be a change in principle that gives you the impression that the margin is slightly lower. Remember here that our guidance for previous years included Kyivstar. And Kyivstar has, on average, a higher margin than the rest of the companies in the Group. So, if you strip out that effect, and India, then the margin combination of all our OpCos is more or less in line with previous years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would also like to add that in 2009, in the third quarter, we had a positive effect from change in pension scheme in EDB Business Partner of NOK570 million, which added 0.5 percentage point to the full year margin in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then to your second part, to the Nordic cash flow. We have moved from a situation in 2007 up to a new level, I'd say, with reaching this NOK10 billion cash flow target for the three Nordic countries &#x2013; three Scandinavian countries. And we intend to steer at that level going forward. There might be some changes quarter from quarter here because of the transition and move into the new networks. But the overall longer term picture is that we're reaching for this level going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Ulrich Rathe, Societe Generale. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Two short questions, and a clarification. The first one is on working capital. The fourth quarter working capital outflow was sort of NOK1 billion higher, as far as I can tell, from previous years, just from a seasonality perspective. Is this to do with the CapEx booked versus paid, or is there something else going on in working capital? That would be my first question.</p>
          <p>The second question regards domestic fixed. Given the pressures that you experienced in Q4, and you're pointing in particular to these international carrier services business exposed to FX, can you give us a sense of how that business will develop into 2010, in particular, on the margin side?</p>
          <p>And my third is just a clarification. You said when you talked about the improvement you expect in Sweden, you talked about next year. I suppose you meant 2010 there. Am I right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to the third element, the answer is yes.</p>
          <p>Working capital growth in fourth quarter might have a relationship to the settlement terms around revenue share paid in DTAC in Thailand. If that explains the difference in this year, I'm not &#x2013; I cannot take here and now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Every fourth quarter, there is a cash effect from payment of revenue share in DTAC in Thailand. It is accrued for in the previous quarters, and then, paid in the fourth quarter. And it amounted to NOK2.4 billion cash outflow this fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then for fixed Norway, if you look closely at the figures that we presented today, you see that fixed and mobile, revenue wise is at par with each other. For the first time, we have seen in this quarter that monthly revenues in mobile are greater than monthly revenues in fixed. And the continuous trend &#x2013; but, bear in mind, there is still NOK13 billion plus of revenue in both product lines. So, despite us seeing a gradual reduction in fixed-line revenues, it's, by all means, still important, and will be important, in the overall business combination of Telenor going forward.</p>
          <p>We have the intention of being able to, within sort of both short and medium term, to stay at the margin levels for the fixed line going forward, also from this point of time compared to what we have achieved over the last years. And there is a phenomenal work of change that has been carried out in the fixed-line operation since, let's say, 2002, 2003. There is a reduction here of around NOK6 billion over a period. And we're still running the operation with the margin that we do. And we're targeting that margin level, also, going forward.</p>
          <p>This quarter in particular, there is a 2% effect on the EBITDA margin on the activities of Telenor Global Services, which sort of tilts the figures a bit coming from the currency effect. But on the national fixed-line operation, we intend to move forward as we've done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Soomit Datta, New Street Research. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. A couple of questions on your Asian businesses please. First of all, in Pakistan there was obviously a very good margin in Q4, 29%, can you talk about how sustainable that is please? And maybe, are you able to quantify the decommissioning of the leased lines and the energy costs, to give a sense of how much that has impacted profitability in Pakistan? That's the first question, thank you.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, in Bangladesh, obviously, there's been a subsidy of the SIM tax back in the marketplace. I was a little surprised there wasn't a bigger pickup in revenues in Q4. Could you, perhaps, talk about the competitive environment there? Was pricing impacting revenues perhaps in that market? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Pakistan 29% margin. Yes, that's an impressive margin, I'd say, through fourth quarter, the effect coming from &#x2013; partly from higher business volumes, of course, but also from the cost structure side on the backbone. We've seen Pakistan building impressively, despite the unrest on other fronts in that society. Communication is important.</p>
          <p>I think Pakistan &#x2013; the Pakistani market proves that. That people need it under all circumstances. Pakistan is &#x2013; the Pakistani operation of Telenor is, of course, vulnerable, to a certain extent, to energy prices. We saw that in 2008. I don't &#x2013; I can't give you a factor on that. But energy is important. And we, as an operator, need energy in distributed parts of the world. And this is also where renewables can play a more important role going forward.</p>
          <p>As for the revenue side in Bangladesh, remember here that there is an underlying service traffic and subscription revenue increase of 7%. But it is basically the interconnect rate that has been pushed down by the regulator that gives a reduction the way you see the figures. So, the underlying, in local currency, communication revenues generated by Grameenphone customers, basically, runs positive with the factor of 7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the competition is intense in Bangladesh, as it has been for some time. It varies from quarter-to-quarter. Competition has not affected other prices than the starter-kit price, which where is &#x2013; that's where the battle is in terms of subsidies on the SIM tax. So, during fourth quarter, the starter-kit price has been down BDT250 most of the quarter, compared to the normal price of 900.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I want to underline, also, that if we reflect back to the situation in 2008 for Grameenphone, we've been through a quite a makeover when it comes to both attitudes how we run the company, and also running through the stock listing of the company. It's become much more visible, of course. It is the market leader. It's the strongest privately held company in the economic landscape in Bangladesh. And, of course, we are proud that we've been through this with this company for that many years and want to use its good base to move forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And may I also add, we can add here that we yesterday, launched a tower-sharing agreement with Banglalink. Learning from the tower-sharing principles that we're using ourselves so extensively in India, that we have some initial steps also on tower sharing that might contribute to both the energy situation, as such, as well as the CapEx situation, of course, for others giving revenues to the market leader having the most towers in the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Andrew Lee, Citigroup. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Just a quick question. I may be asking for too much here, but on the guidance you've given, on slide 13, you've talked about directional improvement in the Asian markets. You've also taken us through how you think positively on Swedish and Danish margins, going forward into 2010. Do you bake those trends into your revenue and margin guidance, or do you take a less optimistic approach for economic or structural recovery?</p>
          <p>And then just secondly on your CapEx guidance, most of the reduction versus where consensus was appears to be from India. But are there any other regions in particular where you're noticing reduced equipment costs, or anything else? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I had a bit of a challenge here to sort of understand the flavor of your first part here. But if I got you right, I think we gave our viewpoints on how we see the recovery being led by the Asian region. And also saying the Nordics being pretty good positioned in that situation, whereas Central and Eastern Europe, probably, will be that region that might be the latecomer to that recovery.</p>
          <p>As to your &#x2013; to the last part, the new pricing structures that we achieved with vendors in India, has already proven &#x2013; given us proven effects into the new vendor agreements that we made for the Nordic countries. And when there are renewals and changes of technologies, or next level of investments to be done, every company in the Telenor Group will benefit from that kind of development. And that will come gradually, as it has done over the previous years. When we entered Pakistan in 2004, we saw the same effect. We were able to add new volumes, technology matured, efficiency increased. And it's the same happening where we stand now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm afraid time allows us to have only one more question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, David Wright, Deutsche Bank. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. A couple of quick questions. Firstly, on the Kyivstar VimpelCom &#x2013; well, the VimpelCom exchange offer that was put into public domain yesterday. There were some estimates for synergies, I think, that were posted independently and a very broad NPV would give around $1 billion for the whole Kyivstar-VimpelCom merged entity. It looked a little cautious given some estimates we've seen from other European operators on merger synergies. I wondered if you could comment on that.</p>
          <p>And then separately, in India, I think your initial customer run rate was really quite strong. I wondered if you could comment on to what extent that has been sustained, whether you've seen a further ramp-up, etcetera? And, perhaps, within the guidance, any kind of indications you could give on subscriber targets would be good? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As to your first question, I think I'll restrict myself to give the comment that these kind of questions need to be addressed to VimpelCom Limited as it emerges as a new group. This is the starting point for the prospectus. We are working very well together in order to get VimpelCom Limited to the starting blocks. And I think we have to take that from there.</p>
          <p>As for the customer, I'm happy that you're noticing that we're satisfied with the customer ramp up in India. As I said, we had some difficulties on the &#x2013; to scale the IT system in the first two weeks. But when that was resolved, we've really seen some nice daily figures coming in. Which means that Indian consumers, basically, have seen that, yes, there is a newcomer here, which I'm interested to test. And I think we have to be realistic. That is exactly that that is happening.</p>
          <p>People are testing the Telenor service offering. And what really counts here is that we can get our distribution model to work in such a way that customers of Telenor &#x2013; of Uninor in India, basically, comes to Uninor, get their SIM card, but that they also return to our sale point &#x2013; points of sales and do their next top-ups with Uninor in the Indian marketplace. And we saw this effect building gradually up in Pakistan when we started there in 2004. And it took one to one-and-a-half year before this really showed an impressive impact, where we started to build that operation significantly, compared to the competitors.</p>
          <p>So, we have a cautious and sort of patient stone-by-stone approach here. We've done the network rollout in record time. We've established a distribution system for &#x2013; to handle a huge number of points of sale in, also, record time.</p>
          <p>Now, we need to get culture and attitudes into this distribution model, so that it works also for the future top-ups that our customers will execute. Because I'm convinced that, from a number of customer point of view, there will be huge figures to be seen in India. But &#x2013; and also, given that the economic climate in India has the growth factor that we now see, both for 2009 as well as for 2010, gives us a very interesting and a promising year, the way I see it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you think you are competing directly...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think that concludes this session. Any unanswered questions could be directed to our Investor Relations Department. I think that's it from us. Thank you all for joining us this morning. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>