<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1386353" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-05-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2932</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Communication Manager-Corporate Issues">Scott Engebrigtsen</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Jon Fredrik Baksaas</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Richard Olav Aa</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Fondsfinans ASA">Arild Nysaether</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Carnegie Investment Bank AB (Norway Branch)">Espen Torgersen</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Andy W. Parnis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux International Ltd.">Peter K. Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Ulrich W. Rathe</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (UK Branch)">Barry R. Zeitoune</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">David A. Wright</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Nick Delfas</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">James S. Britton</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Maurice G. Patrick</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="RBS Capital Markets">Kevin M. Yates CFA</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Justine Dimovic</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Nordea Capital Markets (Sweden)">Stefan Gauffin</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="&#xD6;hman Fondkommission AB">Thomas Heath</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen: and welcome to the presentation of Telenor's Results for the First Quarter of 2011, whether you are present here at our headquarters, listening in on the phone or watching this via webcast or on the mobile video.</p>
          <p>I am Scott Engebrigtsen and I have the pleasure of taking you through the presentation this morning and we hope that everyone has the material that we have made available for you. That is our press release, the quarterly report and a copy of the presentation to be used here any minute and you can also find the material on our website at telenor.com.</p>
          <p>You can watch this presentation live or in recording on either the Internet or on a mobile phone and during the live transmission, you can also send in your written questions via the Internet and you can find the instructions on these alternatives from our website.</p>
          <p>As usual, we will have a Q&amp;A session directly after the presentation here, and we will start-off with the audience present here at Fornebu, then we will continue with the ones participating on the phone. And finally, you will have the opportunity to do individual interviews. And to present the figures today, we have our CEO, Jon Fredrik Baksaas and our CFO, Richard Aa.</p>
          <p>And first, I'll leave the floor to Mr. Baksaas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Scott, and good morning to all of you. Snow has left this country. Spring is coming. Here are the figures for the first quarter of the Telenor Group. We have started this year by confirming the very good momentum that we had in the second half of last year. There is a organic growth factor of 7% for the Group in this quarter and this stands inline with what we had both for third and fourth quarter last year.</p>
          <p>This growth is primarily driven by the Asian operations, but I will come back to this later. The consolidated operations in the Telenor Group added as much as 9 million subscribers this quarter and this is almost, sort of, a figure of standards way back. This has been driven of course by 5 million new subscribers in India alone, but also in Bangladesh, Thailand and Pakistan, we have been able to connect many new subscribers this quarter.</p>
          <p>Combined with this, we have generated a cash flow of solid NOK5 billion and this happens in parallel with Greenfield investments in India as well as the ongoing network modernizations and network swaps that are ongoing in particular in Scandinavian countries, but also in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>And to do this in combination, we consider this as a strong feature that we can generate the healthy cash flows despite the initiatives both in India as well as on the network side. This requires a bit more than average the previous quarters. Based on the results that we bring forward for this quarter, we maintain our financial guidance for 2011. And both me and Richard will come to that a bit later.</p>
          <p>If we then move onto the different regions of the Telenor Group. I will start in Scandinavia, there is unstable mobile voice usage in the countries throughout this quarter. This question has been raised in the industry after KPN released their figures and at the same time as the voice revenue, the voice usage is standing pretty stable. The data growth continues. We have the same momentum on growth for data in this quarter as we've had before on &#x2013; in the mobile networks. There is, however, a very clear price pressure in particular in Norway and Denmark.</p>
          <p>In Norway, the competition is driven by asymmetrical mobile termination rates and as such, the third operator, third and fourth operator in this country has an advantage in their figures for the time being from this asymmetry, which is suggested by the regulator to be &#x2013; to reach symmetry mid-2012. The final decision from the ministry on this is expected in second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Both in Norway and Denmark, we have introduced new service offering as a consequence of this competitive situation and there are new price plans, which we expect will strengthen our market position in these markets, so that the Telenor operations can regain the momentum that we have had over the last years in these two areas.</p>
          <p>Simultaneously, we are removing the handset subsidies in Denmark. And we do that because of the short period of contract that is allowed in Denmark, six months, which we now see has sort of lost its impact over the years the way it has been practiced.</p>
          <p>To mitigate the price pressure and deliver on operational excellence targets, we need then to further work on the cost structures and take these into more efficiency levels in all the Nordic countries going forward. This is an industry with great transitions and changes, and also when mobile data moves in and becomes a much more important service, the same is about to happen, changes and revisions both because of market condition and technology development.</p>
          <p>And there are many important areas in this manner that can be worked at the network modernization programs that we are in the midst of. For example, we'll significantly reduce our further network operating costs. And these are on track and will be finalized during the end of this year.</p>
          <p>There are also other initiatives required both related to IT and the work processes in general. And we've done this for sort of many years, almost decades, in the telecom industry before and this work has to continue.</p>
          <p>Then if we move to Central and Eastern Europe, the picture is a bit more varied. We have started the year by confirming a very strong &#x2013; we started the year in Serbia by confirming a very strong quarter from the Serbian operation.</p>
          <p>There is an 18% organic growth in Serbia this quarter. It's probably one the strongest figures we've had. And this is coming from a strong ARPU growth of 9%, which is linked with the fact that the tax that was introduced last year was taken away again beginning of this year. And this has had a positive effect on consumption. And this combined with 6% subscriber growth has driven the organic growth up to 18% altogether.</p>
          <p>In addition to this, our operational excellence initiatives are also driving cost and operating expenses down. And this has resulted in a 4% margin increase to &#x2013; at the EBITDA figure. So there are reasons to congratulate the Telenor management in Serbia on this achievement.</p>
          <p>In Hungary though, the underlying trend is not the same as it's in Serbia, but it's at best stable from what it's been for previous quarters. We do expect though somewhat improved consumer spending in 2011. But despite this challenging top line growth situation in Hungary, we are delivering on the margin, although there is a six percentage point drag coming from the country-specific tax on telcos. And this tax mechanism has and also will be challenged by and within the EU system.</p>
          <p>We have now introduced the mobile Internet service Klikk also in Hungary and we did so in Serbia in the fourth quarter. And it's been a great success to see how smartphones and the Klikk mechanism based on the Opera Mini can facilitate the extended usage of mobile Internet access. We consider ourselves to be ahead on the network modernization programs both in Hungary and Serbia and these will go on in 2011.</p>
          <p>If we then move to VimpelCom, the reported result for 2004 the fourth quarter &#x2013; sorry, the fourth quarter in 2010 shows that there is a still a need for operational focus and a look at the operational performance in particular in Russia. Including the final dividend that was recently declared, the Telenor Group will altogether receive NOK2.3 billion or US$400,000 in dividends from VimpelCom Limited for the operating year 2010.</p>
          <p>And this payout is in line with the dividend policy, which declared 50% plus of the payout of free cash flow from Russia and Ukraine. The acquisition of Wind Telecom was completed the 15th of April and after approval of the special shareholders meeting addressing the issue, which took place 17th of March. And as you know, Telenor voted against the transaction. So did also the set of minority investors. However, the preference shares of Altimo took this deal through the general assembly.</p>
          <p>Going forward, Telenor Group will, of course, support and push forward for improved performance in the VimpelCom Group. In parallel with this, we will continue the arbitration process that we have initiated, where it is our aim to protect the shareholder rights that we have under the shareholder agreement and as such, maintain the position as we had before the deal was announced.</p>
          <p>If we then move to another part of the world, and let me start in India. Most of the questions related to this quarter reporting will probably be circling around the regulatory situation in India, but there is also an operating situation development that we should focus at.</p>
          <p>Uninor in India continued the good trend from second half of 2010. We have consistently taken significant shareholder subscriber growth in the Indian market in this period. And in Q1 alone, we reached the subscriber growth figure of 5.2 million, reaching 7.4 million customers according to the Telenor way of counting customers. You know there is difference there on what is going &#x2013; what is being report to the TRAI, to the Telecom regulator in India. And on that counting, we had 22.8 towards the end of this quarter.</p>
          <p>Uninor is constantly working on improving operational efficiency and execution throughout the value chain. And the most important part of this is the sales and acquisition costs, and we can not say that we have reached an ultimate and sustainable, over time, cost level on all these processes. So our aim to establish what we've called an ultra low cost operator, this work will continue.</p>
          <p>The investigations of the 2G license award process that took place early 2008 prior to the Telenor entry to Uninor are still ongoing, and speculations runs high on several aspects of that process and the consequences of it. We are in the midst of this and we are describing and advocating the Telenor position and make our viewpoints visible in the Indian environment.</p>
          <p>And of course, we are welcoming an early clearance of this regulatory field, which is so vitally important both for us, for the rest of the operators in India, as well as for investors in the Telenor Group.</p>
          <p>Lastly, let me say some words on the strong performance by the established Asian operations. Those have very strong growth momentum in all the four countries. The operations have, combined, an organic growth factor of 13%, which is in line basically with the two previous quarters in the Telenor Group. And it's very interesting to see that this growth momentum maintains itself also into 2011.</p>
          <p>Both DiGi and DTAC reported their Q1 results last week and Grameenphone earlier this week. So these facts are in the market already. But it has to be said that there is a very strong performance by all the four operations, and have given visible results both from cost and efficiency initiatives as well as good effects on how we go to markets for the time being.</p>
          <p>In Bangladesh, the SIM tax subsidies are reflecting their margins, but though has of course then led to a 2 million subscriber growth figure for the quarter alone, which is one of the stronger customer growth figures that we've had from Bangladesh most recently. And Grameenphone maintains its market position, as a consequence.</p>
          <p>Also the operations in Pakistan is continuing its excellent progress from earlier quarters, have expanding the margin and has generated cash flows in this period. And we expect further improvements to come also from Telenor Pakistan going forward. And of course, this is also necessary in order to also defend the investments that has been done in the country. Altogether, we have now 106 million customers in our five Asian operations.</p>
          <p>Let me then conclude by looking a bit ahead. To sum this up, it's been a good start of the year for the Telenor Group, especially with regard to the top-line growth. There are, as before, a lot of things that we should focus at from an operating perspective, both short-term and long-term. And to mention a few of them, to mention the transition from voice to data, where the capacities and capabilities of the mobile networks are building data access capacities quite extensively in all the markets.</p>
          <p>More specifically, to become an ultra low cost operator in India. That's what it take in order to work toward our ambitions of a breakeven figure towards the end of 2012. The operating focus in VimpelCom is very much needed both because we've seen VimpelCom slide their market position in Russia, but also because of the fact that the new group is now much more leveraged than what it has been before.</p>
          <p>And then sort of as a general comment, to maintain and speed up the cost efficiency impact over the &#x2013; across border, overall our operations is what we are focused at. Altogether, we're maintaining our guidance for 2011 and we believe that we've had a good start when we look at the growth figure that we reported for this quarter in particular.</p>
          <p>And with those words, I'll leave the floor to Richard, who will take us through the financials in a deeper fashion, as well as give some comments to the guidance. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fredrik. I will just take you somewhat into more detail into the numbers, but let me just put the quarter into perspective as seen from a financial point of view. It's a solid result this quarter. It has no special effects or at the large side. And based on that, we will maintain our guiding for 2011. So that's the context you should listen to this presentation in.</p>
          <p>Apart from what's already been covered on the growth side, we see that EBITDA margin is at 31%, which is in line with our guiding. And we have a stable operating cash flow, despite that we still continue to have a significant negative cash flow in India and that we are basically now modernizing all the networks in the Telenor Group. So based on that, we are also able to reduce the net debt about NOK4 billion and I will come back to all that, reconcile.</p>
          <p>Let me just then start with the revenues. And we see that we have improved our revenues with about NOK1.8 billion first quarter this year, compared to first quarter last year.</p>
          <p>We have one business unit that has a slight decline in revenue and that is in Norway. And I think I would like to take a little bit more into detail on those numbers. There are really two drivers behind it on the mobile side. It's that interconnect rates have gone down due to regulation and also roaming prices have gone down. That is the main drivers explaining the drop in the mobile revenue. It's important to note, like also Fredrik said, that underlying mobile revenues on the traffic side, they are stable. We have been able to compensate price reductions with other measures, not at least, the growth in the data and mobile side.</p>
          <p>On the fixed side, the decline in the subscriber base continues with the migration from fixed line to mobile. But also in this quarter, we have a price effect on the fixed side, especially towards the business segment, where we have reduced prices to meet increased competition, not at least from IT.</p>
          <p>Then Sweden has a strong performance. Sweden is the country in Western Europe now that has the highest growth. Also we have currency effects there, strong start of the year in Sweden.</p>
          <p>Then in Thailand, we have the strongest revenue growth in the group this quarter and DTAC has added more than 2 million customers year-on-year and also been able to have a rather stable ARPU development at the same time and also the positive currency effect behind those numbers. We also see that DiGi is contributing very good this quarter, as it also did in 2010, adding more than 1 million customers from last year to this year and also, fairly stable ARPUs.</p>
          <p>Then, Uninor now starts to show a significance on the total revenue numbers in Telenor. We have increased the number of subscribers by 15 million year-on-year, although it was only 2 million in first quarter last year, and it now contributes to &#x2013; with an improved revenue of almost NOK0.5 million.</p>
          <p>Then in Bangladesh, we have added in this period 8 million customers, although now we are reaching out to more rural areas with lower ARPU customers that also have a high subsidy. So, the overall revenue impact is not that good. But we're adding subscribers for future value creation.</p>
          <p>And on the rest of the Group, we have a strong performance in many companies, but not stacking up to that big numbers, but Serbia should be especially mentioned. So that explains the NOK1.8 billion revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Then on the EBITDA, we have improved the EBITDA by approximately NOK200 million year-on-year. There, we have three units or three explanations going in the negative direction, that's Norway dropping with about NOK200 million.</p>
          <p>On the mobile side, if you look at, like I said, the overall underlying traffic revenues on subscribers are fairly stable. So the big effect on this drop is really coming on the fixed side. That will continue to have subscribers going from fixed to mobile and also some price pressure and some adjustments on prices behind that.</p>
          <p>In Hungary, there are really two big effects behind these numbers. It's the Telco tax that contributes a little bit more than 50% of the drop of 121, and then it's also the drop in the Hungarian currency.</p>
          <p>Then we saw this down in EDB from accounting perspective by the merger with <mark type="ph" /> Erder group (24:59) last year. Then we don't consolidate EDB anymore. So that has negative EBITDA effect of 130. And then we see that especially then Thailand and Malaysia is contributing to an overall EBITDA growth, coming from the strong revenue growth and also that we're able to keep costs under control in this growth environment, which is very good.</p>
          <p>Pakistan, like Fredrik mentioned, has a very strong quarter, able to increase the ARPU and keep the costs quite well in check; so, almost NOK100 million coming in from Pakistan. So that's the main explanations on the EBITDA.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the CapEx, we have also a very low CapEx in this quarter 10%, NOK2.4 billion, which is inline with first quarter last year. But as a percent of revenue, it's 10% compared to 11% last year, because we have a higher revenue base. And this is quite low, given the fact we are sloughing out basically all the networks.</p>
          <p>We are guiding at 12% to 13%, so we are expecting this to increase the rest of the year, but we have started the year maybe somewhat lower than we also expected ourselves. And we really see now that the prices of equipment are coming further and further down and it will be very interesting to see how CapEx efficient Telenor can get in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>Then I said the CapEx was basically stable at NOK2.4 billion. We see that Norway, which is now in the middle of the network swap, they have increased the CapEx by NOK272 million. They are now 53% through as we speak of the network swap in Norway. And the project is going on schedule and is expected to be finalized by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Then on India, we see a lower CapEx of close to NOK400 million. We're basically only doing now infield CapEx in India in the areas where we already are operating to cater for the growth in the voice. We are not expanding into new circles and we are also keeping the CapEx to the areas we are already established in the circles where we are.</p>
          <p>And then we have a slight increase on other CapEx and that also comes from the network modernization. That takes us to the cash flow, which stands at close to NOK5 billion, which is slightly higher than the same period last year. And the explanations for the change in CapEx can really be seen here on the right side, and that's really just a sum of the previous explanations on the EBITDA and the CapEx side. I don't think I need to take you into details there, because it's really the same trend, that the FX in Norway is taking a toll on the CapEx, while that is being recovered by strong performance in the Asian units.</p>
          <p>And we really see now that the four established Asian operations, they are contributing a lot more to the cash flow in Telenor than the Nordics in this quarter. Low CapEx and high revenue growth and good EBITDA performance.</p>
          <p>Then reconciling also the net income, which stands at NOK2.8 billion this quarter compared to last year, we already explained the revenues and the EBITDA. Like I said initially, there are very few special items this quarter and we see that on other items nets out to NOK244 million. Then on associated companies, we have a profit of NOK1.1 billion and that compares to NOK93 minus million last year and the reason being that we did not take in anything from VimpelCom first quarter last year, but this quarter, we get the normal effect by taking in fourth quarter results of VimpelCom.</p>
          <p>Then on the net financials, we had hedging losses in our investments into India in the first quarter last year. We don't have any special effects of that this quarter. Although, we have some more technical financial costs due to IFRS, but I would say overall, the net financials are on the normal level.</p>
          <p>We have higher taxes due to higher profit, but also the underlying &#x2013; all the tax rate this quarter is very closed to the underlying tax rate, it's maybe little bit higher, so that we then end up with a net income of NOK2.8 billion in the quarter and an earnings per share of NOK1.71.</p>
          <p>Then on the debt side, we started the year with a net debt of NOK19.3 billion and we end the first quarter by a net debt of 15.1, a reduction of a little bit more than NOK4 billion. That comes from the EBITDA of 7.4, like I said, normal interest, NOK300 million, normal taxes, slightly higher than accrued taxes, 1.5, also paid CapEx a little higher than accrued CapEx, 2.9, paid out dividends to minorities in Malaysia.</p>
          <p>We received, like Fredrik said, about NOK500 million in dividends from VimpelCom this quarter. And then we have the special effect at the revenue share, which is a significant cost base in Thailand. It's accrued during the first three quarters and paid in the fourth quarter. So that contributes positively to the cash flow and then reduces debt by about NOK700 million. And then we have some currency effect and some improvement in working capital that takes the net change to NOK4.2 billion.</p>
          <p>And like you see, we have now net-debt-to-EBITDA of ratio 0.5, which is very low. We will have about NOK9 billion going out of Telenor in the second quarter, both as dividend payments as an all-time high dividend and also the payment for amortization of the shares that will be done with the Norwegian government.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to say that we have an intention like we said in the fourth quarter, we have an intention this year to also give a total competitive shareholder remuneration and that's why we have asked the AGM of Telenor to approve our share buyback authorization to the board for up to 5% for the shares. So that will be decided later in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>I'll go not go in detail through this slide, but it's just a visualization of what really going on in Telenor these days. This is probably one of the main strategic programs. It is one of the main strategic programs in Telenor that we are really swapping out the network in all our operations.</p>
          <p>Pakistan is not there, but that's &#x2013; it's likely to be on there. And we see the effects from the new network. It requires &#x2013; and the new base station. It requires less space, less energy and it costs a lot less than before, and its also modern and ready for future better quality and service offering. And what -- like I said, what this will do to our CapEx level going forward, I think we'll go more into detail on the Capital Markets Day later this year.</p>
          <p>Then also, the important item for top management and the entire Telenor organization is really to make sure that we meet our operational excellence targets that we set out last year on the Capital Markets Days.</p>
          <p>We should reach a 35% OpEx to sale in 2013. We started measuring this in 2009, where we are at 39%, the rolling 12 months now, we're at 37%. So we are on a way. But this is a challenge to reach to 35 &#x2013; below 35%, and we really are working hard now on both like I said, the modernization on the networks, but also looking at onsourcing and outsourcing.</p>
          <p>And then on the retail side, we have quite significant portion of our cost and customer service and distribution, which we need to just push further ahead on, on optimizing. And like Fredrik said, also a continuous push and pull on improvement of the business processes.</p>
          <p>On the CapEx to sales, we are already down to the 10%, and like I said on the pricing side and what's really happening in that market, I think that one is already well within reach.</p>
          <p>Then just ending on the guiding, let me start with India. We have the first quarter EBITDA loss of India about NOK1 billion and we are guiding around NOK4 billion for the year. The underlying loss in first quarter is somewhat higher than the NOK1 billion. That's because we had on record for energy expenses last year that we could release now when we had reconciled it. So that number is underlying somewhat higher, which points in the direction that there should be some improvement in the EBITDA per quarter going forward, underlying.</p>
          <p>But like Fredrik said, it costs a lot of money in India to acquire customers and really to get the customer acquisition cost and other cost in our Uninor operation. To become a ultra low cost operator is the main priority on operational side in India now.</p>
          <p>The CapEx stands at about NOK300 million in the first quarter, like I said in field CapEx to cater for the growth where we already are and that's basically the NOK1 billion to NOK1.5 billion we are guiding at as well, is really what is planned used for.</p>
          <p>Then going up to the total numbers and like I started the presentation, also Fredrik alluded to, we are pointing to a very solid and strong year for Telenor this &#x2013; in 2011 as well with revenue growth above 5%, first quarter was at 6.7%, and an EBITDA margin of about 31% and CapEx to sales in the range of 12 to 13%.</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. We are now ready to take your questions. So I invite Fredrik back up to the podium. We will start with the audience present and please wait for a microphone and also, please introduce yourself.</p>
          <p>I have one question. I would kindly ask both the ones here probably and also the ones especially participating on the phone to limit your number of questions to one and if necessary, one follow-up question.</p>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And we'll start then with audience present here. If there are any questions? We have one here, please. Start here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (37:18). You tell us that you have to do a comprehensive cost reduction in the Nordic region. What does that mean when it comes to the number of employees in Norway, for example?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Arne (37:33), I've known you for ten years, then you know &#x2013; more than that and that means you know the industry development over those 10 years as well. Technology is moving, participation is strengthening. Technology is driving the industry from a personnel-intensive activity back 10 years plus to more and more this top and the new technologies taking care of capacities in the network differently from what was the case before. So the number of full-time employees in this value chain has been regularly reduced from year-to-year, and that development will probably also continue. To raise numbers on that, is not for my doing today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a question here from Arild Nys&#xE6;ther, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Arild Nys&#xE6;ther from Fondsfinans. Could you comment a little bit more on the operational trends in India? I see the ARPU seems to be a little down from Q4. I haven't seen it in local currency, it's like a different currency, but it seems at least a little down. But at the same time, minutes of use is sharply up, about 20%. So that should imply that price per minute is down something like 20% or 25% since Q4. So can you comment on what's happening on your pricing strategy and the market in India?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can begin here a bit and Richard might flow in. I think it's under the circumstances, it's been done on remarkable job on how to make the no service offering visible and reach a level where it stands out in a pretty healthy, competitive field, the way we have presented ourselves in the Indian market. And the response in this case where we see 5 million new subscribers coming in is a result of this.</p>
          <p>The other side of this coin is that yes, minutes has been used in order to achieve that kind of growth together with the push factor that we have in the distribution. And as both Richard and I has -- have mentioned the cost or the price tag of the sales and acquisition side on customer series needs to go through a revision in such a way that we reach a higher degree of efficiency in that.</p>
          <p>But in this phase, where we are building presence and customer base, we have seen this necessary to build this position where we are. And in Indian Rupee, the average revenue per user is fairly stable from fourth quarter to first quarter, despite the fact that we've had this significant growth factor in number of customers coming in. And you may fill in some here, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, more from the market side in India, we see that these so-called STVs, the Special Tariff Vouchers, are really heavily used on the street level now in India, where the actual price level in the market which is there are really the one paisa per second that the DOCOMO introduced and 60 per minute. It's not that that's really that attacked by the operators, but you give away a lot of free minutes in this Special Tariff Voucher to attach customers. And if we and in the Indian market, it's a lot about price when you want to acquire customers and we just have to be competitive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Follow-up, is this something you can hope to be able to do to raise the effective price again at some point, is this more campaign or do you think that the new price point is set sort of effectively per minute?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Generally speaking, the price level in India after the introduction of what TATA Telecom introduced at the time and after we launched is that a more stable pricing environment than what was the case before reaching that state. And in the meantime, we have had the 3G auction process. So we don't see sort of a ongoing downward price pressure, but do we see the opposite? I think that's too early to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a question up here, please. Espen Torgersen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Espen Torgersen, Carnegie. Just a follow up on India, if what you are seeing now continues in line the way with I read you, you are going to very aggressive in the following quarters in India. Will this have any implications on your CapEx, given the minutes of use growth correlated with the subscriber growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For India specifically, the answer is no, because the key question here is whether we will get access to 6.2 megahertz growing from 4.4, which was the initial delivery from the authorities under the license. We are of the opinion that Uninor qualifies for 6.2 according to the original setup for the licenses. So that was awarded in 2008 and we advocate that.</p>
          <p>But as you know, there is a process going on, on how to set the framework for the telecom industry in India going forward and that was expected back in 2008 to happen in March 2011. So we are a bit overdue in that respect and this clarity is highly needed, as I said both from our point of view, the rest of the industry as well as from the investor side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any further questions from the audience at Fornebu? No, it doesn't look like that. We will have time for one question, written question from ones following us outside, if I may? It's from <mark type="ph" /> Jakob Julmeden (44:11). If Telenor makes a significant acquisition, would that change your ambition to resume buybacks later in the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's an excellent question for you, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our ambition is to give a competitive shareholder remuneration and we see that the telco industry, which we has done the benchmark for being competitive, is a higher and higher yield industry in the stock market.</p>
          <p>Telenor has the higher growth profile than most of our European peers. So we're not aiming at being among the best in shareholder remuneration, but I think clear ambition to be competitive and any acquisition has to be seen in that context. We have to be competitive on the shareholder remuneration side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will then turn our attention to the ones following us via the telephone. And I call on the call conference host to open up for the first question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Andy Parnis, UBS. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anyone on the phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy Parnis. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. It's Andy Parnis from UBS. Just one question on Norwegian fixed, it was obviously quite a bit weaker in Q1 than it was in Q4. And you said it was primarily due to price cuts in business. Should we expect those to continue to come through the numbers now for the rest of 2011 or have you put in place steps to try and correct the weakness in fixed voice in Norway?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we &#x2013; like we said, we are maintaining overall guiding from &#x2013; for the Telenor Group at 31%. We have done what we believe is very necessary price adjustments in the fixed business. But we will continuously monitor how we position ourselves both in the fixed and mobile business, as they are quite dynamic environment these days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Generally speaking, we can say that we're probably now at 70-30 when it comes to voice minutes over the mobile networks compared to the fixed network. And I think it's only five years ago, we were the other way around. So it's been quite a strong transition from fixed to mobile and the way we use our mobile phone and the convenience of it obviously proves that, that is the most handy voice instrument for a lot of customers.</p>
          <p>That leaves the fixed line to roll in this more and more as an access type of network delivering broadband capacities and be stronger on that part than and on the back of &#x2013; than on the voice retail. And the consequences of that has also to be taken into the price structure, since that's the way that we can maintain the revenue streams from the usage pattern that is there in the same way as we've done before, when the other services are over the top, so to speak. So for us, it's a &#x2013; to use the pricing mechanism in a smart way to slow down the reduction from the fixed line utilization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Peter Nielson, Cheuvreux. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. Just a question related to <mark type="ph" /> VimpelCom  (48:12) and your comments on your changes of maintaining your position there. Are we to take that as at this stage, your intention is still to exercise your preemptive rights, in case they are granted to you by the arbitration court and do you have comments on your position? How you will view that in <mark type="ph" /> telecom (48:34) should the shareholder agreement cease to or expire as, sort of, as your models indicated recently? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Here you are raising, in a way, a hypothetical questions of the quality, what will we do if...? And firstly, I say that we are now concentrating on feeling, in our viewpoints, on how the new VimpelCom Limited asset, the combination is going to be operated. And they are focused on operating factors as well as getting the culture to be set between the two arms that comes together is priority number one. Priority number two from a Telenor perspective is to prepare a solid case under the arbitration and that when the result is ready, we will address the question that you raise in that sense, Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please. Do we have another question from ones on the phone, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Ulrich Rathe, Jefferies. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Given you have organic revenue growth around 7% and you're guiding for above 5, that sort of hurdle is obviously lower than what you do at the moment. Is this more a safety margin or is there reason to expect a slowdown in revenue growth in the rest of the year in terms of the operational trends or market trends that you expect? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's also an expression of the fact that that we had pretty strong growth factors the second half of 2010. And when we reach the second half of 2011, the growth factor is obviously to be measured from a higher level. So I think it's more an expression of that than to say that yes, this is moving into a flattening phase. So, the way we have begun the year, solidly builds the case that we believed in the Asian economies to grow and the market position of the companies are fairly stable, even some small pluses on the market share here and there. So from that perspective, we are able to take our fair share with this small plus behind in Asia and that's exactly what we want to do also in the year &#x2013; the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd just like also to point out that we are not pointing to a specific number. We're saying above 5%, not around 5%. And I don't think you will see us guiding at an exact revenue growth figure, it will be ranges or above.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Barry Zeitoune, Berenberg. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, it's Barry Zeitoune from Berenberg here. I am going to labor the point on VimpelCom, if that's okay. One could you argue even with the shareholder agreement with Altimo, the market did not give you any credit for influence over the asset. With the shareholder agreement not in place, why should the market assign any value for influence? And if you don't have influence over VimpelCom, even if you are able to exercise your preemptive rights, would you be open to the possibility of divesting your stake? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the last dimension of your comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. The last dimension was simply that in the scenario where even should you exercise your preemptive rights, where you lack influence or lack the kind of influence that you would consider significant stake in an asset, would you be open to the possibility of divesting your VimpelCom stake?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. This is also in a way pointing to a scenario, so what of the nature of what if and what then? As I said, I think we will concentrate on the two priorities that we have set, one from an operating perspective of the new group and one from the Telenor perspective, which has to do with the arbitration process. Whether there is a development on the shareholding agreement in between, that remains to be seen. If it comes, we will address it when comes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, I mean your partners already stated that they intend to terminate the shareholder agreement. So you can expect it to come reasonably or at some point over the course of the next year. So in light of that, I am just wondering what your response would be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we have to see whether there are realties behind that intention. So I can't dive into that question more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, David Wright, Deutsche Bank. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's David here, a couple of questions, please. Are you still seeing some quite wide divergence on the performance in different circles in India? Are there any circles that are in particular, outperforming, for instance, that blended ARPU you're showing or any circles that continue to underperform? And just beyond that, some very interesting comments from you on CapEx and in particular, equipment pricing. Does it continue to surprise you, the rate of decline of equipment pricing or is it in line with your expectations now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, having Ericsson in the room here, as I can see, probably some others as well, I doubt whether I should sort of go to the very, very bottom of that question. But yes, the competitive situation between the vendors in that area has given the operators leverage to the extent that the network swaps the way we have executed them has given us new price levels. And I would say also that part of the technology move into new phases, where it becomes lighter and more efficient from both an energy point of view as well as from a handling point of view.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; and that, I guess, is an expression on how the technology develops both within Ericsson and the like of other operators. Has it surprised us? Well, our entry into India gave us a new leverage that has been utilized across the Group and has &#x2013; and we have gained new price levels from vendors in all other operations coming from actually our stepping in India because that gave us new leverage as such. Being in India also has taught the Telenor Group and the, of course, India Group that asset-sharing principles can bring forward new cost efficiencies, that basically has to do with future improvements, which were not considered part of the &#x2013; an operating formula some years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Interesting. And maybe a quick comment on the circular &#x2013; the circle performance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe you can do that, yeah. Yes, there are variations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the variations are not so big on the APRU side. Where we really see the big variation is the ability to maintain a good subscriber growth without a too high churn and a too high subscriber acquisition cost. That's really our main focus now between and to really benchmark and transfer knowledge, people and best practices, is really how to prevent the high churn and get the subscriber acquisition cost down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very interesting. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Nick Delfas, Morgan Stanley. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much. It's also about India. I just wanted to challenge you on the INR155 billion, I mean, it seems clear that towards the end of this year you are going to need to decide whether to increase that cash funding figure, given the fact that you are paying away maybe 50% of revenues currently to power companies and maybe another 30% to other operators because of a low level of on-net calling.</p>
          <p>So really, I just want to get your perspective on your attitude to changing that figure, whether it's cast in stone or whether you'd be open to increasing the investment and also whether you would be willing to give some more figures on the activity rates of your customers? How many of those are actually live on any one 24-hour period? What percentage of calls are actually on-net versus off-net and therefore, what your gross margin looks like? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think you are approaching a bit of &#x2013; a set of details here that might not be fully met by how Richard is going to answer this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I think we'll start on the big picture, the INR155 billion. Like you said that's not written in sand, it's written in stone. That's the guiding we have said. What we have guided as the cash flow this year is more or less in line with the INR155 billion figure, but we also see that we need to take down the costs further, especially the SAC, but also the general level of the costs in India in order to reach the 155 billion and that's what we are really working on now and what is behind the statement on Fredrik's slide, which is the ultra low cost project. So that is &#x2013; a key goal is to create the momentum going into 2012 that points to an EBITDA breakeven toward the end of the year of 2012 that's in line with our guidance so we also can maintain the INR155 billion. When it comes-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very clear. I just wanted to double check then so, if for any reason, the INR155 billion couldn't be reached, you would have to look at a divestment or some other solution to the problem, I suppose, because otherwise, one needs a lot more detail in order to be able to assess the chances of actually reaching a cash flow breakeven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to your question on activity levels and so on, I think it's not right for him to go in detail on that, but I would just like to say that on net is, of course, a vital feature in our service offering in India, due to the high termination rates in India.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, James Britton, Nomura. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. The first question on the margin. The group margin is down 1.5% year-on-year and obviously, it's guiding to pull a slight improvement for the full year and so can you just comment on where you expect the margin improvements will flows through in the rest of the year or would you be willing to accept a slightly lower margin this year in order to drive the strong or better top line growth? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>Second question, can you perhaps talk a bit about your appetite for M&amp;A at the moment. Has management got enough from this play with the challenges you sort of highlighted of the Indian rollout and the VimpelCom situation, the efficiency initiatives and then monetizing data? Or do you have that capacity now to manage another big acquisition?</p>
          <p>And then finally quickly on Denmark, will the move to remove handset subsidies make you less competitive in this market or do you expect the other operators to follow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That was a whole set of questions, I would say. As to the margin part of your question, I think we have a good sense on how the different operations are moving ahead in this year. Of course, to improve margins, if you take a look at Grameenphone, for example, you have sort of one of the outposts having a low margin this quarter, because there is a significant customer acquisition activity going on with more than 2 million new subscribers.</p>
          <p>And if you compare that margin with what was there one year ago, where we only have, if I recall rightly between 600,000 and 700,000 new subscribers, there you have areas that place directly into the margin figures. And there are other examples as well across our operations. So to be specific on that, is not what we're going to be today. But knowing the size and the variations amongst the operations, questions on how the competitive situation will, of course, play into this throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Appetite for M&amp;A, well, what one could wish and one could execute, there are probably possibilities coming out, Will we look at them? We will look at them if they are sort of in the vicinity of where we are from before and whether we can get financials to tie together. But we don't have sort of an acquisition type of look in our eyes when we are looking into the telecom markets as such.</p>
          <p>The last one, in Denmark, will it make us less competitive? Well, we surely don't hope so. On the contrary, we hope that it will make us more competitive. And we feel that the benefits of a six-month locking period has reached a level where one can say goodbye to that kind of business model. And of course, it will have a consequence going forward. Distribution will still mean &#x2013; will be very important to the competitive situation going forward. And I think we can handle that in Denmark with the strength that we have in the Danish operation, knowing that Denmark is a very competitive market in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Maurice Patrick, Barclays Capital. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Maurice from Barclays. In the Nordic areas, you seem to be going from a phase of high-end data growth towards increased low-end competition, especially in Norway and Denmark and <mark type="ph" /> urgent (1:04:50) similarly, different drivers for these. You have repriced your plans in both markets. Do you see this trend accelerating throughout the year? And do you think is a temporary move in the market dynamics or more of a fundamental shift in terms of the overall behavior of market to market? Thanks you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah that also interesting aspects of looking at it, yes, of course the high-end growth that we have experienced in the Scandinavian markets, driven by the introduction of the iPhone a couple of years back, is shifting to and spreading into other customer segments. And we hope with the price submissions that we have done in Norway in particular that we can offer to high-end customers sustainable price rates that are competitive in the marketplace, as well as inviting other customer segments to grow their usage along with the advantages of what the mobile communications system can offer to them</p>
          <p>So, yes, if we an establish a pricing structure where people and other segments are moving into the data field, becoming users more regularly in the same way as the high-end has become. Then we have sort of achieved to do the same on the data side as we did on voice telephony some years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Kevin Yates, RBS. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Kevin Yates from RBS. Just had a question on the wholesale businesses in Norway and there appears to be gross margin pressure, whether that's through better prices to MVNOs or whether that's based through a mix effect on the wholesale revenues in the fixed line business. Wonder if you could talk us through the dynamics at play there and how structural this is versus temporary? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think one of the effects you see on the wholesale is really the roaming. So I don't think that is that much change on the pricing to them and else in this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of the fixed line business and perhaps the mix going away from domestic to international traffic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You have some effect on that or Telenor Global Services on the international traffic side has a good growth and that obviously have a somewhat lower margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that aiming &#x2013; you think that's going to be structural or just a temporary effect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Like I said and also Fredrick said that the whole positioning on the fixed operation is continuous work and it's also something we just have to do in a dynamic way going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Justine Dimovic. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Justine Dimovic, Exane BNP Paribas. One quick follow-up. Last year, you had a one slide in your Q1 results presentation that stated your financial priorities. You touched upon attractive shareholder remuneration, which was the number two. The other priorities were, maintain as solid balance sheet with an EBIT to EBITDA below 1.6 times and a disciplined and selective approach to M&amp;A. Could you update us on this two other financial priorities and what you &#x2013; I mean, what you, we shall understand by your disciplined and selective M&amp;A, <mark type="ph" /> that's few stance (1:08:51). Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the priorities should also be stacked up. That's really to maintain a solid balance sheet is the first priority. And I think we are really fulfilling that, maybe somewhat over-fulfilling it by being down at 0.5. But like I said, we will also aim this year at paying our competitive shareholder remuneration. So you should really look out for what we may do on the share buyback side. Dividend is up for approval on the AGM later this quarter. So I think those &#x2013; so the balance sheet is maybe somewhat on the strong side.</p>
          <p>Then on the remuneration, like I said regarding for a competitive shareholder remuneration also this year. And then on the selective and disciplined M&amp;A, I think what we have said is that we really would look at M&amp;As in a careful way. That's not our priority these days, like we answered earlier today, that we have many other things on our plate. But we have to look at opportunities that arises around the assets that we have, and see what can be taken out of industrial synergies and bring the Telenor Group forward if thing comes up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Stefan Gauffin, Nordea. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Just a couple of questions. First of all, there is a small dispute in India with your partner Unitech regarding the financing situation. Can you give us some update on that? And secondly, can you just comment something; first of all, you have made some price adjustments in Denmark. I know it's quite recently, but could you give any initial reactions on this change? Secondly, the removal of handset subsidies. What kind of effect does that have on the EBITDA margin in Denmark? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Now on the Unitech side, Uninor has a need for long-term funding and with the regulatory controversies that are in India, raising long-term debt in India is impossible these days. It's also a fact that raising debt without recourse back to Telenor is also challenging, despite any operating environment. And given that situation, we have a shareholder agreement that really points out that the financing of the company should be balanced between the shareholders. And we are now down to the level where equity is needed as no other instrument alone will take Uninor where it needs to be on the long-term funding.</p>
          <p>And then there is, what should I say, this agreement between the shareholders that Telenor really wants to follow the shareholder agreement and put in more equity, while Unitech tries by various methods to stop that right we have under the shareholder agreement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for one more question, so last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Thomas Heath, &#xD6;hman. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thomas Heath here. Two questions if I may, firstly just to follow up on what you said about India and debt guarantees from Telenor. If you could just give us an update on what the current status is there in terms of how much is guaranteed and I think specifically in the scenario where you might have to pay fines? And the, secondly a question again on India about CapEx. To what extent is this a selective rollout and CapEx spending circle-by-circle linked to sort of ongoing regulatory disputes, if you could elaborate on that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, now I think on the debt side it's, you can just look in our notes. We disclosed what is guaranteed by Telenor each quarter. So we don't have to go into detail on that now. When it comes to the CapEx, we will really like to also have spectrum in some of the circles we have not got spectrum in, like in Delhi. But until we wait for that spectrum and also spectrum at 6.2 megahertz, we're operating now at 4.4, we are rolling out very selectively.</p>
          <p>But I would also say that as a general note, that when you don't have spectrum and you don't get money, it's kind of interesting to see the creativity in an organization, how much more capacity they can tweak out of the network. So that gives some ground for optimism in terms of reaching a very low cost position in India.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think that concludes the Q&amp;A session. And I'd like to thank you all for participating, this morning. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>