<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1344573" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1279</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Elana Holzman, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Shlomo Yanai, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Eyal Desheh, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Randall Stanicky</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Gerard Van Odijk</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Richard Silver</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">William Marth</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Ken Cacciatore</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Chris Schott</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">David Amsellem</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Marc Goodman</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Gregg Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">David Buck</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Timothy Chiang</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Elliott Wilbur</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">John Boris</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Corey Davis</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Michael Tong</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Frank Pinkerton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Diego. Good morning, and good afternoon everyone. Welcome to Teva's third quarter 2010 earnings conference call.</p>
          <p>We hope you had a chance to review our press release which we issued earlier this morning. A copy of this press release is available on our website at www.tevapharm.com.  Additionally we are conducting a live webcast of this call that is also available on our website.</p>
          <p>Today we are joined by Shlomo Yanai, President and CEO; Eyal Desheh, Chief Financial Officer; Bill Marth, President and CEO of Teva Americas; and Gerard Van Odijk, President and CEO of Teva Europe. Shlomo and Eyal will begin by providing an overview of our results.</p>
          <p>Please note that Shlomo will be referring in his prepared comments to non-GAAP gross margin, operating profit, net income and EPS. Eyal will provide additional detail on the items excluded from our non-GAAP results. We will then open the call for a question-and-answer session.</p>
          <p>Before we proceed to the call I would like to remind everyone that the Safe Harbor language contained in today's press release also pertains to this conference call and webcast.</p>
          <p>Shlomo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Elana. Welcome everyone and thank you for joining us today as we review Teva's results for the third quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>This was an outstanding quarter for Teva, a quarter of record-breaking sales across all our geographies and major businesses leading to record-breaking financial results across the board. Net sales for the quarter reached $4.3 billion, representing 20% growth over Q3 '09. Quarterly operating profit reached $1.4 billion, a 44% increase over the third quarter of 2009. Net income in the quarter reached $1.2 billion, a 47% increase over Q3 '09 and all of this brought us to non-GAAP EPS of $1.30.</p>
          <p>We also had record cash generation during the quarter with $1.2 billion of operating cash flow an increase of 16% over Q3 '09, and $866 million in free cash flow, an increase of 23% over Q3 '09.</p>
          <p>The most important strategic achievement of the quarter was the closing of our acquisition of ratiopharm on August 10, and as you know, last week we signed an agreement to acquire Theramex. I will elaborate on both of these a bit later.</p>
          <p>It was an exceptional quarter for Teva in North America where sales reached $2.7 billion, up 22% over the third quarter of 2009. U.S. generic sales reached approximately $1.6 billion, up 34% over Q3 '09 on the strength of our launch of venlafaxine ER, our generic version of Effexor XR, as well as strong sales of budesonide and mixed amphetamine salts, our generic version of Plumicort Respules and Adderal XR. It's been an especially great year so far for Teva in the U.S. where we have introduced 17 new generic products since January.</p>
          <p>While we're on the topic of U.S. generics, I would like to provide a quick update on the status of our pending generic Lovenox application. We recently met with representatives from the FDA to discuss the status of our ANDA. During the meeting we confirmed that our version of generic Lovenox meets the FDA's criteria to demonstrate chemical sameness and accordingly that data related to immunogenicity are currently under review at the Office of Biological Products.</p>
          <p>This was also an outstanding quarter for Teva in Canada where our ability to capture market share in a competitive landscape and our closing of the ratiopharm acquisition has made us the number one player in the Canadian generic market based on the dollar share of the market.</p>
          <p>Let's go now to Europe where following the closing of acquisition of our acquisition of ratiopharm, sales crossed the $1 billion mark, up 21% over Q3 '09 or 33% in local currency terms. Sales were up in all major European markets on the strength both of the ratiopharm business and excellent growth of Teva's revenues in key markets like Italy, Spain, Poland, Portugal and Hungary.</p>
          <p>In several other markets, including Germany and France, we experienced pricing pressure during the quarter. In Germany, our largest market, certain reforms impacted our prices. Nevertheless, we are pleased to see continued growth of our Teva portfolio in Germany on top of the growth we experienced from the addition of ratiopharm's business. The combination of the two businesses resulted in net growth in market share over Q3 '09.</p>
          <p>Immediately upon our closing of ratiopharm on August 10, our integration teams were hard at work and I'm pleased to report that the integration is right on track. The more deeply we get to know ratiopharm the more excited we are about what our combined company can accomplish. In addition to our leadership in Europe and all its key markets, we are very well positioned to compete in every important business segment from retail generics to OTC to hospital to specialty and innovative niche areas and biosimilars. We are confident that we will be able to achieve our objective of $400 million in synergies. In fact, we are already realizing synergies.</p>
          <p>Some of you joined me last month on a visit to ratiopharm's headquarters and I think that the experience of meeting the outstanding ratiopharm team, seeing the efficiency of the operations and understanding the strength of ratiopharm's market position and brand in Europe make it clear why we are so enthusiastic about the possibilities that lie ahead for us, for our company.</p>
          <p>Coming back now to our results, Q3 was another excellent quarter for our international business, where sales reached $525 million, up 13% in local currencies over Q3 '09 driven by especially strong sales in Latin America, Israel and Russia. In Latin America every one of our local business units, including Argentina, Mexico and Chile, grew faster than the market contributing to a 20% increase in sales in local currencies.</p>
          <p>Once again, it was a record-breaking quarter for Teva's innovative business, global in-market sales of Copaxone, the world's leading therapy for the treatment of multiple sclerosis, grew to over $800 million. We enjoyed good unit growth in Europe and in the U.S., Copaxone sales grew by 9%. According to IMS data, Copaxone continued to grow its leading market position in the U.S. with a record share of TRx of 40.3% and a 39.1% market share of NRx. Clearly Copaxone's efficacy, its superior safety and tolerability profile and the fact that it is the only MS therapy on the market with compelling long-term data continued to make it the first choice of physicians.</p>
          <p>The MS community values Copaxone and the many product innovations and services we regularly provide as the category leader. Teva is committed to continuously improving the patient treatment experience and continuously strengthen its Copaxone leadership position through ongoing clinical research.</p>
          <p>As you know, as you all are aware, our SONG trial examined a lower volume 0.5-milliliter injection of Copaxone for which Teva submitted an sNDA. We've had recent communication with the FDA on this lower volume product and conclude that clinical data to establish similar efficacy of this new concentration and the currently marketed product will be required for approval. To support the approval of our sNDA we have supplemented clinical trial data from our FORTE study which was designed to assess the efficacy, safety and tolerability of glatiramer acetate in the same concentration and I'm pleased to update you that recently we received a notice of allowance on our patent related to our 0.5-ml product.</p>
          <p>Let's go now to Azilect, sales of which grew 28% over Q3 '09 to reach a record $81 million. Sales were especially strong in the U.S. where Azilect is the number one wellness Parkinson's disease therapy on the market.</p>
          <p>Q3 was a great quarter for Teva's women's health franchise which grew 13% over Q3 '09 driven primarily by exceptional growth of our Seasonique and ParaGard brands. We also had strong sales of Plan B One-Step, up 55% over the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Last week we were excited to announce another important addition to our global women's health business. Our acquisition of Theramex with its diversified product portfolio, seasoned sales force and promising pipeline will accelerate the exception of our global &#x2013; expansion story of our global women's health franchise and provide a strong platform for cross-selling of our existing products in key growth markets in Europe and in the rest of the world.</p>
          <p>Theramex's main markets are France and Italy, two core markets in Teva's European strategy and as part of the agreement, we will be taking over Theramex sales in a number of countries including Spain and Brazil which are also key markets in our long-term growth strategy. By combining Theramex's products and pipeline with existing products and our strong R&amp;D capabilities, we will be creating a powerful new global women's health division and we are very excited about the prospects for this business.</p>
          <p>Our global respiratory sales reached $207 million a decline of 15% compared to the third quarter of 2009. It is important to recall that in Q3 '09 we benefited from earlier and greater sales due to the severity of H1N1 and seasonal flu viruses. ProAir continues to maintain its market leadership position with 49% market share and Qvar ended the quarter with a 20% share of new prescriptions in inhaled steroid corticosteroid market, a new high, solidifying our number two position in that category.</p>
          <p>We are excited about the future of our respiratory franchise and we are looking forward to sharing with you more details about our respiratory portfolio and R&amp;D at our investor meeting this Thursday.</p>
          <p>Before I pass the call over to Eyal I would like to provide you with an updated outlook for 2010 sales to reflect the inclusion of ratiopharm. We now project 2010 revenues to be approximately $16.4 billion. We continue to expect that our 2010 EPS will be in the range of $4.50 to $4.60 which includes approximately 3 cents dilution from the ratiopharm acquisition. The acquisition will become accretive on a non-GAAP basis in the first quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>We are now developing our war plan for 2011 and beyond and we are extremely enthusiastic about the many opportunities that lie ahead for Teva as we look forward to another year of continuous profitable growth.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention and now let's turn the call over to Eyal for a more detailed financial update. Eyal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Shlomo and good day to everyone. I hope you have had an opportunity to review the press release we issued earlier today.</p>
          <p>As you can see, we reported another excellent quarter with all-time highs in sales as well as gross profit, operating profit, net income and earnings per share on GAAP and non-GAAP basis, completing a very strong first nine months and heading to an excellent 2010. We also reported record cash flow from operations of $1.2 billion and free cash flow of $866 million, both representing impressive record results.</p>
          <p>Before we delve into the numbers, I would like to touch on two technical topics. First, I would like to remind everyone that we are representing GAAP and non-GAAP results. In our non-GAAP presentation, we have excluded the following items this quarter: amortization of purchased intangible assets amounting to $144 million, amortization of ratiopharm intangibles will commence in Q1 2011; we adjusted for an inventory step-up of $54 million relating to the ratiopharm acquisition; non-cash impairment of long-lived assets and intangible assets of $27 million; restructuring and acquisition costs of $27 million related mainly to the ratiopharm acquisition. These expenses were offset primarily by financial income of $45 million related to hedging activities in connection with the acquisition of ratiopharm, and in addition related tax benefits of all of those items of $74 million in total.</p>
          <p>You should note that the items excluded in arriving at our non-GAAP results for the third quarter of 2009 are not identical to those in the current quarter. Please review our press release and related tables for reconciliation to our GAAP numbers and more complete information. As indicated in the past, we present non-GAAP figures to show you how we, the management team and our board, look at our financial results.</p>
          <p>Second, foreign currency continued to play a significant role in our results with different impacts on P&amp;L and the balance sheet as I will detail below.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, foreign currency differences had a negative impact of approximately $122 million on sales as compared to Q3 2009. The impact on sales resulted primarily from the strength of the U.S. dollar relative to most European currencies which was partially offset by a decline in the value of the U.S. dollar relative to other currencies. Nonetheless, the impact on operating profit continues to be negligible with a negative contribution of $6 million. Teva's diverse geographical presence continues to provide us with a good natural hedge that mitigates much of the P&amp;L risk involved in currency fluctuation and minimizes the impact on our bottom line.</p>
          <p>Before I review the P&amp;L in more detail, one more comment on the impact foreign exchange had on our balance sheet, namely on our equity which was a positive one. The weakness of the U.S. dollar on September 30, primarily relative to the European currencies, increased our equity by approximately $1.5 billion compared to June 30. Further, the impact of translation differences on long-term assets such as good will and other intangible assets as well as cash balances held in euros. We expect that translation differences will continue to cause fluctuation in our equity as we have significant assets, mainly good will and intangible assets, in non-U.S. currencies.</p>
          <p>Looking at the consolidated results for Q3, sales totaled $4.3 billion, an increase of 20% compared to Q3 last year. In local currencies we delivered even a higher growth of 23%. About 55% of our growth was organic while the rest resulted from the first time consolidation of ratiopharm.</p>
          <p>North America, which grew 22%, delivered record generic product sales and strong profitability. Europe grew by 21% in U.S. dollars and by 33% in local currency terms due substantially to the first time consolidation of ratiopharm results. Sales in the international markets grew by 7% in U.S. dollars and by 13% in local currency terms.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP operating income reached $1.4 billion, up 44% compared to Q3 2009, benefiting from strong gross margins, tight expense control and the take-back of the Copaxone royalties on North America sales from Sanofi-Aventis. Non-GAAP net income reached $1.2 billion, up 47% compared to Q3 2009. Non-GAAP fully diluted earnings per share were $1.30 per share, up 46% compared to Q3 2009.</p>
          <p>A few housekeeping points related to earnings per share calculations. The weighted average share count for the fully diluted non-GAAP EPS was 921 million shares and the add-back for the non-GAAP EPS calculation was $11 million.</p>
          <p>Now let's discuss profit margins and operating expenses. Non-GAAP gross profit margins, which exclude amortization of purchased intangible assets, were 62.5% in the reported quarter compared to 58.2% in the quarter last year due primarily to favorable product mix. Gross margin continues to benefit from contribution from new and recently launched generic products in the U.S., solid gross margins of the U.S. generic base business and the contribution from sales of our innovative and branded franchises. Gross margins also benefited from our continued effort to improve efficiencies. Please note that this quarter's high gross margin is an exception to our long-term gross margin range of 57% to 60%.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP operating margin reached 33.9%, up 5.8% from 28.1 in Q3 2009. Mainly contributing to the exceptional operating margin were high gross margin and a termination of payments we made to Sanofi-Aventis over the past two years of 25% of Copaxone in-market sales in the U.S. and Canada.</p>
          <p>Net R&amp;D expenses were up 23% compared to Q3 2009 reaching a record of $239 million or 5.6% of sales. Gross R&amp;D before reimbursement from third parties for certain R&amp;D expenses and R&amp;D investments in our partnerships with Kowa and Lonza was $248 million or close to 6% of our sales. The growth in net R&amp;D expenses over the comparable quarter last year is attributed to both our branded and generic R&amp;D activities. The increase in the branded R&amp;D expenditure reflects progress mainly in laquinimod related activities as well as biosimilars and respiratory projects. We now expect that for the full year, net R&amp;D expenses will be approximately 6% of our net sales.</p>
          <p>Selling and marketing expenses, excluding amortization of purchased intangible assets, totaled $742 million this quarter or 17.5% of sales compared with 18.6% of sales in Q3 2009. As already mentioned, the decline in selling and marketing expenses as a percentage of sales resulted primarily from the termination of payments to Sanofi-Aventis which were recorded as sales and marketing expenses, was partially offset by higher royalty payments in connection with new and recently launched generic products in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Global G&amp;A expenses this quarter were $236 million or 5.5% of sales compared with 6% of sales in Q3 last year. The synergies from the Barr acquisition and tight expense control continued to contribute to the decline in G&amp;A expenses as a percentage of sales. We recorded $48 million of net financial expenses on a non-GAAP basis in Q3 compared with 52 million of non-GAAP financial expenses in the comparable quarter of 2009. The lower financial expenses resulted from lower interest rates on our outstanding debt offset by higher levels of debt in the reported quarter following the acquisition of ratiopharm. You should note that we excluded from our non-GAAP financial expenses in the quarter a gain of 45 million-dollar realized in connection with hedging the ratiopharm acquisition.</p>
          <p>Tax expense provided for the third quarter was $207 million on pre-tax non-GAAP income of 1.4 billion. Our current estimate of the non-GAAP annual rate for tax for 2010 in whole is 15% compared to 16% for all of 2009. The estimated tax rate for 2010 on a GAAP basis is 12%.</p>
          <p>Now let's have a look at our cash flow. Cash generated from operations this quarter totaled $1.2 billion, up 16% compared to Q3 2009. Our free cash flow excluding gross capital expenditure of $175 million and cash dividend of $167 million, partially offset by profits from the sale of certain assets of $14 million amounted to a total of $866 million or 23% above Q3 2009. The improved cash flow was driven by strong sales and collection in the quarter.</p>
          <p>On September 30, cash and marketable securities totaled $1.2 billion, down approximately 4 billion from June 30, as we used more of the cash on hand to pay for ratiopharm. Our total outstanding loans, bonds and convertible debentures stood at $7.1 billion, only slightly up from $7 billion as of the end of June.</p>
          <p>Our debt remains essentially unchanged as we incurred additional debt in connection with the acquisition of ratiopharm while we paid off the debt incurred in connection with the acquisition of Barr completely as well as other bank debt. The debt incurred in connection with our acquisition of Barr is now fully paid.</p>
          <p>Our financial leverage as of September 30, 2010, was just under 25%, down from 27% at June 30. DSO, Days Sales Outstanding, amounted to an exceptional 42 days this quarter as the result of very strong out of quarter collection compared to 50 days in the previous quarter. We calculated the DSO after netting out from the receivables our sales reserve and allowances and we always do this.</p>
          <p>Inventory days stood at 178 days compared with 172 days in the previous quarter or 195 days in Q3 2009. Net capital expenditures reached 161 million this quarter compared to 90 million in Q2 2010. To remind you, in Q2 2010 net CapEx included proceeds of $46 million from services and assets versus 15 &#x2013; 14 million which are included in the current quarter.</p>
          <p>And now for dividends; yesterday Teva's board approved a quarterly net dividend amounting to approximately $173 million. On a per share basis, our dividend, which is declared in Israeli shekels, is 0.7 shekels per share. Basing on yesterday's rate of exchange of the shekel to the U.S. dollar this translated to approximately 19.3 cents per share.</p>
          <p>Thank you for all your time and attention today and now we'll be glad to take your questions. Operator, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />. Our first question comes from Randall Stanicky with Goldman Sachs. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Hi, guys thanks for the question. Just a quick one for Eyal and then a follow-up. Eyal, I know we can all do the math but can you just &#x2013; for the 4Q implied EPS, that's $1.21 to $1.31 and that reflects the three cents of dilution from ratiopharm, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That is true for the first five months. Of course it's improving every month and as Shlomo mentioned, Q1 2011 will already be accretive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. Then, Gerard, can you just help us a little bit more with Europe, maybe spell out a little more clearly what was the constant currency growth? I know you talked about a 5% constant currency back half outlook and how are we tracking there? And then maybe what's the countries where you're seeing the most weakness versus where some of the offsets are coming from in terms of potential growth? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gerard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Randall. I think what we've seen in the overall growth in Europe we've seen no surprises, as I said before, we've seen some movement in some markets that were, as Shlomo mentioned it, I think we saw in Germany and other markets a bit of price pressure kicking in August.</p>
          <p>But all in all, I think if you go Southern Europe it has shown what we expected it to be, a market that showed positive dynamics. It has been turbulent but we believe that for us it's been quite relatively well done. I think if I look at the ratiopharm itself it's only two months after we just closed the deal and it's a bit early days to expect any positive sales synergies but it's clear that, as Shlomo said, everything we see, we like.</p>
          <p>In Germany reforms announced early this year started as expected in August, as said, and despite that, our Teva German business, core business, developed well and in addition I would say that the combined market share of the two companies, we gained a little bit versus last year. Italy, Spain, but also Eastern European markets like Hungary and Poland are growing quite well, I think we did very well in there. And I think if you add all of these things together, for us this was a solid quarter. It was not like Q2 but it was a very solid quarter and we're very happy to see the first very positive signs of having the ratiopharm business in there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you still tracking consistently with that for a mid-single-digit constant currency growth rate going forward that you highlighted last quarter, is that fair to say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we haven't seen big movements versus that. If you look at the market in total, without Germany, it's in the low single digits. If you take the market with Germany included it's in the low single digits. If you take excluding Germany it's in the higher single digits and that's still tracking very well.</p>
          <p>If you look at our current performance year-to-date it's been quite well, it's in the double-digit numbers, in the middle double-digit numbers and you can perhaps do the math yourselves as well if you do the strategic plan outlook for us at 2015 we need to deliver around about, after ratiopharm about 10% CAGR over the years and we're well on track of delivering that.</p>
          <p>So we're outperforming the market, the market is more or less in line of what we do, every quarter is different. In one quarter you have tenders kicking in and another quarter you've got a price measurement kicking in, in other quarters we, like you merge with another company. So there are a lot of moving parts in this quarter-on-quarter comparison but the underlying current, the underlying trend is exactly in line as I declared before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's helpful, thanks a lot, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Rich Silver with Barclays Capital. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. First question is on the low volume Copaxone, can you just tell us what the timetable is for approval, whether this data submission, which you said the data has been submitted, changes the PDUFA date?</p>
          <p>And then you had a notice of allowance on this patent assuming that it issues and it's listed in the Orange Book, what might that mean or not mean in terms of P-4 filings, 30-month stays, etcetera?</p>
          <p>Follow-up question is on the gross margin, Eyal, when would you expect the gross margin to be back in that 57% to 60% range? Could it be as early as the fourth quarter or is it more likely sometime in the first part of next year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Bill, will you take the Copaxone question and then Eyal will follow on the gross margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Rich, thanks for the question, there's a lot to talk about on the Copaxone 0.5 sNDA. I think a lot came out of our interaction. Several points are mutually agreed upon. That being the unknown method of action and the lack of PK measurement and what we've concluded basically is there's no known shortcuts for glatiramer acetate. So I think that's very, very important. And I think when you think about this broadly, a clinical requirement for even a change of concentration has broad implications for any type of follow-on product or generic product. So I think that's an important point to make.</p>
          <p>And then, you know, the fact that we're supplementing the file with clinical data from FORTE with over 1100 patients, if accepted, significantly improves the treatment experience of over 100,000 MS patients in the form of an enhanced product with the requisite three-year exclusivity would be likely. So I think that those are all very positive things as we think about this sNDA.</p>
          <p>Your question on the notice, it generally takes a couple of months for the patent to be issued and I would remind that, you know, in a case on the 0.5 we could eventually use all the patents in litigation as well as the 0.5-ml patent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the PDUFA date and the timeframe for approval, Bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's really no change at this point, Rich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the additional data doesn't mean that the action that we would expect on January 1st would be any different than we would have expected without that supplemental data?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, good question. What we did is we've supplemented with this data, now the agency will look at this data, the completeness of this data, decide what they want with this data and they may reset that PDUFA clock, but they may not. So we'll have to wait and see. That's a dynamic we can't really do anything about, but hopefully, this is a much better situation for us, we're very pleased with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And the gross margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rich, regarding gross margin, gross margin in Q4 is expected to be back below 60%, if you took Shlomo's forecast for the year and extracted what we've done in the first three quarters, you have a number for Q4, so sales are higher, but there is more ratiopharm in it which comes with a lower average gross margin than what we have delivered and the components inside between target for generic launches and other products is a little different than in Q3, so by and large we've got to be below 60 which is where our natural area is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Ken Cacciatore with Cowen &amp; Company, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys. Bill, I don't want to dwell too much on your comments on Copaxone, but I guess maybe circling back a little bit, can you just describe the low-dose formulation and maybe a little bit more on your interactions with the Agency? What level of nuance did you get into? I mean, was there discussions about the potential for doing biological assays, biochemical assays on your low-dose? Was there discussions about doing specifically inability to do the PK studies? I think you hit on it, but maybe a little bit more about that interaction so we have a better sense in thinking about a generic to Copaxone?</p>
          <p>And then also &#x2013; well, why don't I let you answer that and then I'll have a follow-up, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ken, good morning. Hey, I think, you know, I pretty well said it but I would just reiterate there are many points of discussion, we can't talk about all the discussion with the Agency but the conclusion, again, remains that we're similarly situated with unknown method of action. Again, there's a lack of PK measurement and so we can't conclude that there &#x2013; well, we can conclude that there are no known shortcuts for glatiramer and I think really with no known markers, there's no other way to go other than a clinical requirement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>OK, maybe on the litigation front, can you just give us an update of what's happening there following the summary motion in your favor? Can you talk about steps forward that you can take or are planning on taking? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ken, I think it would probably be kind of be helpful to walk through the process because I think there are some misunderstandings out there because we have an excellent understanding of the litigation process and thus far we are really pleased at where this litigation process is going.</p>
          <p>Mylan and Momenta have been essentially consolidated for all purposes and trial. So I think probably the best way to do it would be to take you through the anticipated flow. So on Mylan's claims construction hearing will be January 12th after which, some period of time, Judge Jones would issue the claims construction. We will then proceed to a summary judgment.</p>
          <p>Now, the summary judgment is an undefined period but, you know, it could be a substantial period of time in due course to go through summary judgment motions. After the summary judgments are ruled on, it's about a 30-day process. Judge Jones will bring us in for pretrial conferences. After that pretrial conference, she'll set a trial date. After the trial, you know, we'll begin the trial, we expect it to be about a two-week trial and Judge Jones will render a decision at the appropriate time. That's pretty much the course. But we feel really good about where we're at right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Chris Schott with JPMorgan, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, just another follow-up on the low-dose Copaxone data, I think you mentioned 1100 patients, could you remind us how long of duration of therapy we saw with that data set?</p>
          <p>The second question on Copaxone, could you just talk about your expectations for the growth of this product with the introduction of Gilenya? As you discuss that, just do you anticipate Copaxone will remain at a price discount to Gilenya over time? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Yes, thank you. Chris, with respect to the data, the FORTE data is a one-year study, and again, it's about 1100 patients dosed on various of the 20-milligram to 40-milligram. And the second question was...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Growth dynamics for the Copaxone with the new competition in the market and just kind of thoughts around the price discount we see for Copaxone versus Gilenya at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>0We still anticipate revenue growth for Copaxone in 2011. As far as, you know, the pricing flexibility on Copaxone, because Gilenya has come out with a relatively high price, we really can't comment at this point in time. We're much lower priced, we don't like to be too low. I've always said that being what I consider to be the standard of care in the MS market should not put us in third or fourth place on pricing so we'll have to just wait and see how that works.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from David Amsellem from Piper Jaffray, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just coming back to the Copaxone litigation, just so I'm clear, is it your expectation that the trial date will be sometime in 2012? And then is it your view that, given the protracted process, is it your view that the FDA wouldn't necessarily have any sense of urgency in terms of reviewing the filings from Momenta and Mylan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David. I think to say that the trial in 2012, that is not unreasonable at all. That would be fine.</p>
          <p>With respect to how fast, you know, the FDA moves on approving their product or processing their file, that's very difficult, really, to say. That's something that happens within the FDA. But, you know, we know from our experience with enoxaparin that it took a very, very long time and the FDA did not get tremendously motivated until litigation was done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful and then just one more question. Can you just comment on your appetite for a further presence in Brazil? It's a hot market these days, it's attracted a lot of interest in the space, can you talk about your thoughts on this market, how you're looking to further build your business there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this is Shlomo speaking. As you know, we're active in generic and in branded as well and as I said when we presented our long-term strategic plan, we mentioned and I pointed out some key countries or key countries for our expending or expansion for generics and Brazil was on that list as well. So Brazil definitely represents an opportunity, but there are others in some other countries or key generic markets that we are also excited of the opportunities that lay ahead for us and, as you know, in M&amp;A activities, it's a very opportunistic arena so I cannot refer anything more specific on any given market or target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Marc Goodman with UBS. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, can you talk about this rest of world line a little bit? Russia, Eastern Europe, Japan, and the inputs that go into this line item and give us a sense of, you know, just what's the normalized growth rates there? We didn't have any acquisitions that impacted the numbers so I would think this is all Teva. So give us a sense what's going there, please.</p>
          <p>And then there was a comment that there was pricing pressure specifically in France and Germany, I understand the German tender. Can you just talk about France and what kind of pricing pressure you saw there and what we should expect there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me first take the question on the &#x2013; let's call it the international arena or the rest of the world if you skip North America and Europe. I think that we are doing very well in that part of our business and I just said, roughly speaking, this area is growing by 13% quarter-over-quarter, but I think if you deep dive into the countries then you may see or I may comment that Russia is doing very well for us. On generics and OTC, we have a double-digit growth there. And we are expecting continuous growth for next years in this very important market.</p>
          <p>As for Japan, this is an accounting issue, this is a JV and therefore, we are not recognizing sales, but we are doing there very well. Actually, we are in a run rate of more than $200 million per year of sales. And if you add it to our international activities then, actually, we are, roughly speaking, on the 16, one-six, percent growth, which is in line with our long-term strategy expectation, and, of course, this attractive part of our business, definitely, though, as way to provide us growth is in line with what we plan for the coming year.</p>
          <p>And your second question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pricing in France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you like to add to that, Gerard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A pleasure, thank you, thank you, very much, Marc. I'll start with Germany and then I'll hop over to France, yeah? First of all if we talk about Germany we need to distinguish between what's happening in the innovative part of the market in Germany versus the off-patent market. The German government has increased mandatory rebates for innovative products from 6 to 16% and they also have installed a price freeze at the level of Q3 prices last year, August last year for all &#x2013; and for the off-patent market, we've seen an adjustment of maximum reimbursement prices in the marketplace which is sort of a recalculation they used to do every couple of years and they've done this year twice. So that's all. So, but despite all of that, the German gross generic market has grown 4% this year in any case.</p>
          <p>In terms of net sales and I think that's what you sometimes pick up when you listen to other people talking about the German market, it's very difficult to calculate the impact of all of that for each individual player in the market because rebates and portfolio diversity is very difficult to &#x2013; to look at it. In our case, as I said, we've done reasonably well. We gained a bit of share in that.</p>
          <p>In general, the tender segment, that is the low price segment, has continued to grow, but it's not growing faster as we had forecasted before. And it has been a bit more stable, it's been more or less stable during 2010. We also expected to expand during the next few years but that's what we've modeled for with anyway in all of our expectations also when we acquired ratio.</p>
          <p>In other segments like OTC, hospital or even the semi-branded products where ratiopharm and we are strong, we see an even much more stable market in Germany. So yes, you see price dynamics in Germany, they're moving in the same direction as we've seen it, but it's only in half, let's say, of the market really significant to see.</p>
          <p>If you take France, in August last year, the government decided to take out a serious price cut out of two different types of products. The proton pump inhibitors, the acid reducers and the statins, the cholesterol-lowering groups. That had an impact of around about 100 million on the total market. And that's now just ticking through as we go through the year.</p>
          <p>What you also see is that there was an announcement in the summer by the French government to take some quite forceful measures into the budget of the healthcare system. But after a detailed study you will find out that only about 100 million of that is currently some sort of earmark as being a price decrease on the gross prices of generic pharmaceuticals in the French healthcare system. How that is exactly going to be implemented is currently unclear but it's clear that it is happening -- that there is serious talk about that and we're waiting for that to play out further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I want -- if I may comment because I understand that Europe is getting a lot of attraction, the price pressure and I'm going to comment in a very overall kind of a comment. I think that when you are a market leader in generics, price pressure is something that is part of your business environment. I used to say that in United States this is a constant price pressure every year and it becomes part of the business environment that you guys are not even questioning it anymore. Price erosion in generics is part of the business environment and it goes also with something that's called more market share. As a market leader I believe that we know how to manage this kind of phenomenon and to increase our market share to exceed the impact of the price pressure and that's, of course, not relating to any specific quarter or market or countries but I believe that that's one of the things that we are doing for many years and with a nice track record.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Gregg Gilbert with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, one for Bill and then one for Shlomo and/or Eyal. First, good morning Bill. On gemcitabine in the U.S., are you confident that your tentative will go final on November 15th, and are you confident that FDA will be supportive of the CBE-30 approach to transfer the product and minimize the delay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, there's still a process that we've got to go through. You can never be sure that the FDA is going to convert you in a rapid manner. We hope to get it converted. We have time, we know that the forfeiture rules leave us until January so we'll do our best to make sure that we get it approved and hopefully out the door by then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I have a question for Shlomo and Eyal. I know that the company believes that acquisitions are still the best way to maximize shareholder value but I have to ask, has the thinking of you and the board shifted at all to a more balanced approach of acquisitions plus a more aggressive dividend and/or share repurchase strategy? It seems to me that the absolute level of cash flow you're generating these days calls for at least a slightly different look at your cash deployment strategy unless, of course, you think you should continue to do larger and larger acquisitions over time. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the question, it's a very broad subject and I'll try to be short, because it deserves more than just a quick Q&amp;A session time. But roughly speaking we're trying to follow our long-term strategy which we, of course, are reviewing every year and from time to time if we think there's a reason for that. And we still believe that the growth is the major value driver for our shareholders and when you come to the acquisition part, which, let me remind you that as we said it's about a third of our growth will come from acquisition and two-thirds from organic growth and we are active in looking for acquisitions in generics which is more about increasing our market share in attractive markets but also in the branded we would like to strengthen our branded part of the business and we have right now four interesting and attractive franchises, let me just highlight the last week announcement which is a typically branded kind of acquisition.</p>
          <p>And as for size, I don't think the size is the issue or, as you know, in our size and with the strong cash generation of Teva, when we need, we will have the needed resources. It's more about the strategic fit to our strategy and to our famous three criteria, which one, I already mentioned, strategic fit, but it should also, of course, be associated with good economics and accretive within a year after the acquisition. And that's how we actually are managing this part of our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe one more comment on that. I think you're all seeing what we're doing with cash. We generate it fast, we use it to pay back our debt, then we take debt in order to finance acquisitions. The ROI of our acquisitions, we have an excellent track record and the return on acquisition or return on our investment. And now we go around generating more cash and paying back those debts. So, so far, I think it works very well in generating value and I think that you asked about dividends, we're currently at the 1.5% dividend yield. We see ourselves as a growth company. And we need to have the right balance between all the factors and how to create shareholder value and I think so far we're more or less in that balance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from David Buck with Buckingham Research Group, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, first a confirmation from Eyal, I think you said that 55% of the growth was organic. Using those numbers it looks like ratiopharm was about $315 million in contribution for the quarter, could you just confirm that and whether there was some seasonality associated with it being the third quarter or weaker quarter?</p>
          <p>And then for Bill, just can you give us an update on or some type of quantification or qualitative what the impact of venlafaxine might have been for the quarter and a reminder of how competitive you expect that market to be after six months? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do confirm the number 55% of the growth was organic and ratiopharm contributed 45%. Remember, it was only a couple of months or a little short of a couple months. In the third quarter, which seasonally is a low quarter. So when we compare this to what we had in our plan, it was right on the money and we're happy with the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh-huh, Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David. On the venlafaxine, I guess that the public record would suggest that there's likely to be not as many players in the first part of 2011, but, you know, it's hard for us to really have visibility to the players that haven't settled so that leaves it a bit unclear for us. Other than that we had an excellent quarter with venlafaxine, it's just the conversion rate was tremendous but pretty much as you would expect it to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one follow-up also for Bill. Any sense of timing of just when you might see an enoxaparin response?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think we have any update from our prior, you know, prior comments but as we said, we did meet with management and we do know that we've established sameness and that we are with OPB so that's very important and we're very pleased.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Tim Chiang with CRT Capital. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Gerard, I had a question in terms of Europe. You've talked about market share gains, steady market share gains and with ratiopharm, how will that accelerate your position in Germany? I mean, if you look out a year, I mean, is the goal to become the number one pharmaceutical company there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but I'll let Gerard answer the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Shlomo for teeing this one up. First of all, yes, definitely, we have the ambition to go after the leadership position in Germany. As you know, we were very enthusiastic of the acquisition of ratiopharm because it would give us a critical mass and pricing power in quite a few markets in Europe that would lift us up and that would allow us to find for synergistic strength in our top-line generation.</p>
          <p>First of all, in Germany, I believe the total constellation of our portfolio both of products and customers will allow us to really take advantage of the size. Everything we see within ratiopharm is making us enthusiastic there. I am spending, myself, quite a lot of time in Ulm and I can tell you it's a real enthusiastic and opportunity-rich field for us over there. Bringing together the Teva global strength and the strong reputation and brand equity value in Germany that ratio brings is clearly something that is going to deliver us much more than just maintaining the dynamics as they are. There is a lot of potential for positive synergies there but it's also true outside of Germany.</p>
          <p>Take for instance markets like Italy and Spain, where we will clearly separate ourselves from the pack with this merger of these two companies. We'll be number one in Spain. We are number one in Italy. We're not only number one on the national level but also in the different sub-regions that are important in these markets, as you know, it's sort of a devolved decision-making system and that should allow us also to take advantage of the strength and the knowledge of the different customers, there's very little customer overlap so we can, say, take advantage of each position and enrich our position.</p>
          <p>If you take France we can claim to have the broadest portfolio that we can offer to the marketplace for all of France which is bigger and broader than number one in France who are my American colleagues so that should give us also some leverage there which would translate into very positive dynamics so it gives you just a few elements there.</p>
          <p>On top of all of this you know that there is some sort of consolidation at European scale going on with our major buyers. Our major let's say customers, the wholesalers with their retail chains. They prefer to work with a company that has a broad and a strong presence in each of the key markets of Europe. We have the exact right profile for that now so that's also something that I have a lot of confidence in that it will bring extra value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick follow-up to that, I mean, what role does vertical integration sort of play in this whole European market? You know, you guys have always been sort of viewed as the leader in being vertically integrated and I guess that should provide you some benefits longer term in terms of operating margins. Could you comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely and you have touched a very important and a good point. Part of our tools, so to speak, how to do the job in the European arena is based on our advantage back integrated. Many of the acquired companies have third parties suppliers and we are going to bring back home part of this product so it's definitely one of the best ways how to generate more value in improving our margins by taking the advantage of this back integration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it too soon to quantify what sort of benefits you can get on the operating margin side at this point or do you think you'll be able to provide a little bit more color there next year on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think I can share with you our numbers on that, it's a process as you well know, transferring product from suppliers, it takes time. But it's not a long time. And this is part of our integration, long-term planning in Europe why we're integrating the companies, we did it with PLIVA, now we're doing it with ratiopharm, and that gives, again, part of the ways how we are going to maintain our differentiation, or how to differentiate ourselves in the market versus on the part of our competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Elliott Wilbur with Needham and Company, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just if at all possible, if we could drill down a little bit more on Copaxone ex-US trends, I was trying to get a sense of the negative impact of austerity measures versus timing of purchases and some of the other factors that were cited for the year-over-year decline?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, maybe just for Bill, can you just give us an update on the Irvine injectable facility, kind of where you are in terms of reintroduction of products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, as for Copaxone on the non-U.S, if you take out the FX impact and the fact that in part of the non-U.S. companies we are selling our Copaxone by governmental tenders which are sometimes not necessarily occurring in the same a quarter, i.e., there was a shift between the quarters, then, actually, Copaxone grew in that quarter. These two elements, as I mentioned the FX and the tender shift is why you see actually a negative growth year-over-year and to a very small degree is also some price that are in some countries in those countries it was mentioned, a price reduction in Europe but the major part of that decline is FX and the tender part.</p>
          <p>Bill, you want to take the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, Elliott. With respect to Irvine there's probably not a lot new that I can add. We anticipate startup between now and the end of the year. At some point during that startup process the FDA will come in and do one more inspection and we've discussed that with them. We have released a number of products, as we've talked about before, that &#x2013; in cooperation with the Agency, most of which are medically necessary, important products for the market so we're proceeding along with our plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from John Boris with Citi Investment Research. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the questions and congratulations on the results. Question for Bill on Copaxone. Can you just comment or give a little better clarity on the type of intellectual property that's going to be issued? Is there a device involved? Is there any competitive advantage that you'll have with using a device along with the 0.5-cc? And have you started to build launch quantities on the 0.5-cc formulation in whatever device that you might be using?</p>
          <p>Second question has to do with the dialogue you're having with the FDA on Lovenox, where are you in that process with Lovenox? Has it completed and you're just waiting for a final response from the FDA, any kind of update there would be helpful, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, John, thanks for the questions. I guess on the patent we can just say that it's around a formulation of delivering the 0.5-ml and that's really all we can say about that. Again, that will be added to the other patent estate that we have and can be used in any further litigation when we get to the 0.5. The other question about 0.5...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Launch quantities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Launch quantities we wouldn't comment on, but one would assume that Teva's always prepared. Any more on the...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess on &#x2013; so always prepared meaning you're only about 60 days away from FDA action on January 1st so...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I would remind you, it was brought up earlier that we have supplemented with clinical data that I wouldn't be shocked if it took them more time to respond to this clinical data. But, again, you have to hedge your bets and although we're not saying that we've built launch quantities we always tend to try to be prepared.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the enoxaparin, boy, there isn't a whole lot more color to add to enoxaparin other than, what I think is important is that we achieved chemical sameness and we're in review with OPB, and meeting with management helped us feel much better about the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it in your guidance for this year, Lovenox?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't really say about the guidance, whether it's in or not, the fact of the matter is we are still hopeful that we could see it yet this year. In fact, I'd be deeply disappointed if we didn't get the approval yet this year but I, you know, again, can't be certain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your candor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Corey Davis with Jefferies &amp; Company, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, first question, I think today and tomorrow there's an FDA Advisory Panel about biosimilars and looking down the agenda is a who's who of biotech pharma and generic companies and Teva has some representation there, so any thoughts about whether or not there's anything meaningful that's going to come out of this meeting or any updates you have in general about how you're feeling the regulatory path is proceeding with the FDA in getting biosimilars approved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, will you answer the question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, good morning, Corey. Yes, the next couple days I think will be very revealing, but I don't think we can make any real predictions just yet. We do have Dr. Rivka Riven-Kreitman down there who will be presenting, and we know she'll do an excellent job of portraying our positions. It will be very interesting for us to hear the others' positions as well. I think this really is about a forum for the agency to be able to get all the opinions and begin to &#x2013; I'm sure they've thought deeply about their own position but they may want to think how they might alter their position or think differently, but I think it's a very, very good forum. So we're pretty excited with all the stuff that we see out of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question just on Copaxone growth and looking at this quarter, without asking for specific guidance, but do you think the growth around 4% worldwide this quarter is predictive of where it's going to be over the next quarter, next couple quarters or is this more of a downside anomaly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Shlomo very well articulated earlier that you have bumps from quarter to quarter. What we can say is that if you look at the first nine months of the year, total boxes of Copaxone are up almost 10%. But it moves from quarter to quarter outside of the United States based on all the governmental process bids, tenders, etcetera. So, you know, you just have to look -- right now the global growth trend is good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thanks, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Michael Tong with Wells Fargo, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. For Eyal, as you start to think about inclusion of ratiopharm how should we start to think about the longer term tax rate on an adjusted EPS basis maybe into 2011?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, the recently announced acquisition of Theramex, is there any ability for that operation to enhance your manufacturing efficiencies as it relates to the U.S. women's health business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding tax rate the acquisition of ratiopharm will not have a meaningful effect on our effective tax rate which is as we've guided anywhere between 14-16%. I believe that this is what we're going to see it for next year. So we're pretty much in a stable environment despite the fact that ratiopharm will profit next year coming from synergies, bears a slightly higher tax rate than the average in Germany it's about 28%. We'll absorb that.</p>
          <p>On Theramex I can take the question. Basically we're not talking about a U.S. production facility, we're not going to move the products that we make for the U.S. market to be produced over there, right now it's designed to support its own product portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Frank Pinkerton with SunTrust Robinson Humphrey, please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. I might have missed it, but can you please just discuss your sales for your two follow-on biologic products in the quarter and the trends there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could give you the overall number, also you'll be able to see the other details you'll see on our 6-K. Our total biologic was just above $30 million this quarter, compared to 25 last quarter so we're growing. Ratiopharm is adding, or will add next quarter another dimension on biosimilars but other than that we don't provide any more details on what are we selling and by product by product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Just as a follow-up, can you talk about in 2011 I think the proprietary pipeline has some data points coming out in the first half, can you give us anything on timing or conferences and presentations? I think laquinamod's got a couple of studies, StemEx has a study and you've also got something on the perennial rhinitis for your HFA product? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Part of the answer to your question is going to be given on Thursday when we will present the respiratory franchise. We will provide the data on our pipeline and status of some of the products that we are developing. Other part of your question you'll have to be patient until we will provide more guidance regarding 2011 and laquinimod, as you know, is scheduled for the beginning of 2011 when we are going to end the third phase clinical trial and that will definitely be a major milestone for laquinimod.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, there are no further time for questions. I will now turn the conference back over to Mr. Shlomo Yanai for closing remarks, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and thank you all for joining us today. As you've heard, this was another great quarter for Teva. And we're excited about how the rest of 2010 is shaping up. Thank you all for joining us today and we hope you can join us again this Thursday for our respiratory opportunity meeting. Thank you, and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference. All parties may disconnect now, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>