<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1211649" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1549</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Andrew Butcher, Executive Director, Communications and Media Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Donald G McGauchie, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2">Matt O'Sullivan</participant>
      <participant id="3">Sol Trujillo</participant>
      <participant id="4">Tony Boyd</participant>
      <participant id="5">Ross Greenwood</participant>
      <participant id="6">Tracey Lee</participant>
      <participant id="7">Donald McGauchie</participant>
      <participant id="8">Desley Coleman</participant>
      <participant id="9">Dominic White</participant>
      <participant id="10">David Blair</participant>
      <participant id="11">Andrew Butcher</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Ben Spincer, Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep">John Stanhope, Chief Financial Officer and Group Managing Director, Finance and Administration</participant>
      <participant id="14">John Stanhope</participant>
      <participant id="15">Mark McDonnell</participant>
      <participant id="16">Laurent Horrut</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="18">Christian Guerra</participant>
      <participant id="19">Sameer Chopra</participant>
      <participant id="20">Mark Blackwell</participant>
      <participant id="21">Sachin Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="22">Alice Bennett</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay good morning to everyone who's joined us here at 400 George Street and to everyone on the line? We had a slight change of plan and schedule this morning. My name's Andrew Butcher. I'm with Telstra Media Relations.</p>
          <p>This morning we'll speak initially about the CEO's planned departure and then we'll move on to our normal earnings presentation. For those on the phone that will be likely around 9:45 that we'll start with the earnings. With me today is Telstra Chairman Donald McGauchie and Telstra CEO Sol Trujillo.</p>
          <p>Donald will make a brief statement this morning and then he's happy to take -- both Donald and Sol are happy to take questions from the media, and as I said we'll then move into the normal analyst presentation.</p>
          <p>So with that I'll hand over to Donald.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Andrew and good morning to everybody. As you'd be aware by now that we announced this morning that Chief Executive Officer Sol Trujillo is going to leave the company on the 30th of June and return home to his home in the United States. Sol and I and the Board discussed his intentions yesterday and over the last little while and let me say that through our Nominations Committee we are very well prepared with our succession planning as we've been looking at this over a very long period of time. And given that we are now well advanced in our transformation plan and that plan is very much on track we agreed very much between us that this is a suitable time to formally commence a wide-ranging search for Sol's successor. And as a Board we expect to be in a position to make an appointment by the 30th of June.</p>
          <p>On behalf of the Telstra board and let me say the Board reiterated this to me again this morning I want to very publicly congratulate Sol on his outstanding leadership and extraordinary achievements that have taken place in this company under his leadership over the last four years.</p>
          <p>What I'd like to do is just make a few comments about Sol's contribution to Telstra because it's been so extensive that I think it's worth at least putting a few of these more outstanding features on the record. Let me start by going back to where we were in 2004 when we started looking for a Chief Executive to run the company going into the 21st century.</p>
          <p>And what we were looking for at that time was a leader with strategic vision. A vision for what Telstra could be as we went into this quite remarkable century that we are going into in terms of telecommunications and the media. Someone who had a deep knowledge and experience of the telecommunications industry because obviously this company still has a very substantial base in traditional telephony as well as the opportunities that we see going forward in the new media. We wanted somebody with international experience in competitive markets. So that was clearly lacking in the company at that time.</p>
          <p>We wanted somebody with experience across the range of platforms and services and in particular someone with a recognition of the opportunities that would be available to this company through the integration that a company of this nature could actually bring. Both on individual who was capable of driving cultural change and indeed someone with a track record of successful implementation of change programs both cultural change and physical change in a business.</p>
          <p>At the time I was frankly overwhelmed by what I saw when I met Sol for the first time in Palo Alto a bit over four years ago and the vision that he showed. The strategic thinking that he showed about this industry and this company was something that impressed me and has impressed me and continues to impress me in Sol. And indeed he has delivered above and beyond anything that I think we could have reasonably expected out of somebody over this last four years.</p>
          <p>That vision and strategic direction and commitment to execution that Sol brought with him and the other people that he brought in and the people that he's developed within the company has positioned Telstra as a media and communications company and I say this very carefully but I think its most important with a very wide range of options for what we can do going forward and to build ongoing growth into a company that is going through quite dramatic change and will continue to go through quite dramatic change I think as far as the eye can see.</p>
          <p>Under Sol's leadership Telstra has significantly outperformed the market and its global peers. We've produced world leading results for the telecommunications sector. I don't think there's doubt that the Next G Network is the world's best national mobile broadband network and amongst a number of outstanding achievements I think that stands as Sol's greatest achievement. And I think more time will prove even more just how important that decision was both a strategic decision and the speed of implementation of getting that Next G Network in place because it has fundamentally changed the face of telecommunications.</p>
          <p>And just an aside I met a former executive of Telstra a couple of days ago just who's now working outside of Australia who I ran into in the hotel whose comment after we exchanged pleasantries was what an outstanding achievement Next G has been what a game changing effort that has been in terms of telecommunications in this country and I think it is without doubt the case.</p>
          <p>And as somebody who lives in the country at least some of the time when I'm able to get home I can tell you from a rural perspective it has been the most outstanding achievement in communications in this country. So integrated Next G Network the Next IP Networks the critical role that Sol played in the successful completion of Telstra's privatization and I don't think again there is any doubt again that was the most difficult privatization ever carried out in this country and maybe any.</p>
          <p>His drive and his motivation and his commitment to innovation across the country. I don't think we ever have a conversation where we don't talk about how innovation is important to the company, how it's important to our customers, how it's important to the country. And Sol's ability I've heard it described as being able to see around corners in terms of what's coming has been a major driver in putting innovation into this company in the way that it has.</p>
          <p>We have now migrated seven million customers to our new IT platforms a massive effort and that's proceeding apace. The rollout of ADSL2+ to exchanges covering over 80% of the population and I think we all need to bear in mind just the scale of this country geographically that it is the size of Western Europe or continental USA with a population of 20 million compared to 300 million in those countries and yet we've managed to achieve these remarkable coverage's. Next G covers 99% of that population.</p>
          <p>Sol's introduction of markets based management and customer segmentation has revolutionized the marketing in this company. The launch and rollout of our T[life] stores first two here in Sydney and then Melbourne and then across more of the company and that's still continuing apace have changed the retailing face of the business. And I think whilst its been small but growing the successful expansion into mainland China with the acquisitions that we've made there have set aside another platform for growth going into the future.</p>
          <p>In 2005 when Sol first arrived he presented to the Board and then the market a plan for the company and the performance and financial metrics that he wanted to be judged against. He laid those down firmly at that time and that was a courageous thing to do because it's in black and white and people are able to go back and look at it. But I think the important thing is that he has delivered against all those metrics that were put there.</p>
          <p>So in concluding let me say that this company is very well positioned for the future. It's well positioned for the future because of the work that Sol and the team have done and I have no doubt that we will go from strength to strength and we will certainly see that we do.</p>
          <p>So Sol I want to wish you the very best for the future and thank you for the work that you've done but let me also say to everybody in this room and everybody else around I look forward to seeing Sol continue to drive this business up until midnight on the 30th of June and I have no doubt he will. It may even be sometimes towards one or two o'clock in the morning if any experience of most of us is there that he will still be driving the business at that point.</p>
          <p>And I have no doubt that the leadership that he's shown to Telstra over the last four years will long be considered a pivotal and critical period in Telstra's history as we see the success of the company going forward. So much of that will be attributable back to the last four years.</p>
          <p>So Andrew happy to take some questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Donald. Can we take questions from the media if you just give your name and the organization you're from both Sol and Donald will take your questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Matt O'Sullivan from the Sydney Morning Herald. Just interested to know what do you think your legacy will be here in Australia. How will you be judged by the Australian public in five, 10 years time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt It's hard for me to say. I think Donald probably described it better than I could because I've been in the middle of everything trying to move the agenda trying to change the culture trying to have the networks and systems and everything built that changed the face of a whole competitive landscape. So for me to describe it I don't think I can. I'll just say listen to what Donald had to say because he had a chance not to be distant from it but also to be enough removed to observe what happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so where do you go from here. What's next for you? Are you going to have a job to go to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My job right now is very focused on as Donald said until midnight June 30. I'm very focused on that but also I have some personal considerations as well in the sense that I spent a couple of years in Europe and then moved here and spent almost four years here at this stage and I have family I have parents I have elderly parents, I have children I have all kinds of reconnecting that I need to do and to be quite frank I've got to lose about eight kilos too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So does that you're not going to another job?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this stage no. My focus has been Telstra it still is Telstra and were going to get as much done as we can until the day that I leave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sol, Tony Boyd from Business Spectator. I wonder you know the company better than anybody the talents within the organization is obviously great because you've achieved all your targets. Do you think its time that an Aussie now ran Telstra or could we expect to get someone from inside?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Tony ultimately the decision of my successor is a board decision and the job that Donald and I talked about actually when we first met was and I've said this publicly before the job I took my job is the day I began planning succession because I think every CEO needs to do that. And that was part of the conversation that ultimately getting as many great people developed inside the company and obviously from a diligence standpoint boards tend to look both externally and internally but I'll leave that to Donald to talk about as Chair of the Board. But I think we have terrific talent but I think its going to be a board call in terms of who's my successor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ross Greenwood from Channel Nine. Sol it could be argued that you have managed to antagonize two governments both from opposite ends of the political spectrum. From the shareholders point of view and from the company's point of view is that success or failure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Ross, I think that the way that we always measure success is whether were winning in the marketplace and that is marketplace the financial marketplace and the customer marketplace. If you look at the customer metrics were growing were outgrowing not only our competitors here but were outgrowing all of our peers around the world so that's one set of metrics. The other set of metrics is the share price and the total shareholder return. And you can take the ASX back three years ago, four years ago, whatever period of time you want to look at. And you'll see that basically we've outperformed on that front as well, when you look at the total shareholder return. Unfortunately were going through a tough period right now economically, where all share prices are depressed. But as you've seen in the last year, there's not many companies that have done better than Telstra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes hi this is a question from Tracey Lee from Australian Financial Review for you Don. I just wanted to know you've been in this situation before with the succession when Sol took the job and we know that Ziggy was leaving before you announced a replacement. Is there concern that you're basically announcing someone leaving before having the chance to say who the successor might be, and I suppose the criticism there would be if you have someone in a lame duck position just to comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can tell you now this guy will never be a lame duck. He will continue to drive this business as I said right up to the very minute that he hands over and I'm very confident we will have a replacement in place by the 30th of June so I think were well placed to do that. Were well prepared to do that and we will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Desley Coleman from ABCs Lateline Business program. You have come under a fair bit of criticism and you have being an American that's been a focal of a lot of press attention. Can you just give us an indication of how you've enjoyed the role at Telstra and the experience in Australia and especially the media attention?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well let me take it in piece parts. I really enjoyed my experience here transforming Telstra working with the people inside Telstra working with the Board working with basically everybody that's been part of this transformation. And I would say that again if you were in Barcelona last week at the World Congress on mobiles if you are at other kind of global industry events everyone is looking at what's happening here in Australia. And I think all Australians should be proud of what's going on here in Australia. In terms of the enjoyment factor of being here in Australia I think almost everybody that's here in the room that works with me would say that Sol hasn't spent a lot of time out enjoying Australia. I've had a chance to visit a lot of places because I've traveled the country, but not really for pleasure purposes. I think the people here in Australia when I came and still today have been some of the most welcoming people that you'd find anywhere. But it's been tough with a lot of the constant focus on the personality side and the personal issues. But that comes with the job. It's probably a little bit more here in Australia than other places but that's understood and I think you learn how to manage around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sol, good morning. My name is Peter Payne from Telside. This maybe a little bit of an unfair question but could I ask you to step up from Telstra CEO to maybe global IT executive perspective. You've come to a country four years ago where roughly three quarters of every dollar spent on telecommunications passes through Telstra and during the time the role of Telstra Wholesale has been deemphasized to where it was before. Do you think compared to your home country which has got such a vibrant competitive market. Do you think it's healthy for Australia to have Telstra in such a dominant position in the telecommunications market in Australia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well this is a pretty complex question. I think you heard me say for almost four years now that I'm a believer in a robust competitive environment and I think we need that here in Australia but you don't do it by creating artificial competitive platforms. What you see in the U.S what you see in Western Europe and other parts of the world is others invest to compete not stay back and wait for a single company to invest and then share their investment. I think the policy issues of encouraging investment in infrastructure is the way that the best kind of future for Australia will be not for governments to subsidize individual companies either indirectly through a company like Telstra but to say to companies we want you to invest we want you to compete but you have to compete based on being better not by being subsidized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sol Dedridge from Channel News. One item that you're going to leave on the agenda is the broadband issue and Telstra's exclusion. Where do you see Telstra being going forward and what is the role play for Telstra in the rollout of national broadband that you've been excluded from? What do you see as Telstra's future in this space?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Telstra is already the leader in broadband in Australia. As Donald pointed out we already have broadband essentially through our DSL what we call ADSL2+ platforms reaching over 80% of the households or capable of reaching over 80% of the households across Australia today. We already have the world's best wireless broadband platform that's capable of reaching 99% of the population and last week we announced were equipping it to be able to handle peak throughput speeds of 21 megabits today and moving to 42 megabits by the end of this year. So if you wanted to look at a company that's already in the broadband business already in a market leadership position and already with plans and strategies to take it to the next level that's Telstra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you can add to that list the HSC Cable Network which is already delivering 30 megabits plus to nearly 2 million homes with capacity to take that further as well. So capacity across a range of platforms in high-speed data is really very, very strong and well grow. We'll get better</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Joe Cratchley from AAP. For you Don, can you give us anymore indication of where the successor will come from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We will now engage that activity full strength and well ensure that we get the best possible candidate to run this Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it will be internal and external search?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be a very comprehensive search, internal external international. This is a very, very complex company. I don't think there are many more complex companies than this one with the range of things we currently do, the areas were expanding into, the base of the company as it stands. This is a very, very complex and difficult company to run and we need somebody who is able to manage the legacy systems and see where the company's future is. And its an enormous challenge and well be looking for another outstanding leader to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Donald I'm just wondering whether or not this signals a shift in strategy for Telstra. Is this an attempt to reenter into negotiations with the government over a national broadband network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look I think you guys have got to get over this obsession with that particular issue frankly. We dealt with that we've moved on. Were more than happy to talk to the government on those issues but I think its an interesting story that just in the last little while we've laid out a piece of optical fiber across the Northern Territory in conjunction with the Northern Territory government and the aboriginal communities and Rio Tinto. We've got a fiber network that runs Victoria that we've built in conjunction with the Victorian state government. Were doing things like this all the time and it would be nice if this country got off the political kick and got on to the innovation investment concept and understood that there is a lot of ways to skin a cat and we've learned a lot of ways to skin this cat and well continue to learn more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi it's Dominic White from the Australian Financial Review. It's a question for Donald. Would you agree it's far from ideal to be losing your Chief Executive at such a critical moment in the company's history?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is never a perfect time to make change but the trick I think in these things is to pick the best time. And Sol came here he delivered us a plan five-year plan that he has brought to the board brought to the market delivered on up to this stage. What we have to do now is look to the next three to five years and clearly Sol is not going to stay through that length of time and I really think the next Chief Executive is the one who has to deliver us the next three to five-year plan. And so the time to move on is always a hard one to make that decision but we talked about it with Sol and the view that we've all formed is that now is the appropriate time to do that and move to that next phase of the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What are the main sort of three characteristics you want to see in a successor that you're looking for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there's about six or seven characteristics and I wouldn't like to pick them out. But look whoever does this job has got to be an outstanding leader. They've got to have the capacity to conceptualize the future. They've got to be able to strategize that and then they've got to be able to execute it. And then we can go into all of the issues of managing the legacy understanding the legacy parts of the system understanding the future where that future is likely to take us. So it is as I said a very complex company. We are the largest media company or at least advertising business in the country. Were developing media assets around the world? The changes in technology that are taking place the ability to understand what those technologies are which ones are likely to perform because over the years I've been on this Board I've seen new technologies emerge that people said were going to change the world and most of them disappeared by the wayside. Only a very few of them actually delivered and I think that's been part of the achievement of Next G that in fact I think both here and in other parts of the world people wondered what this crazy thing we were doing was. Now of course it's recognized universally as being the outstanding achievement. So we really do want someone who can see around corners and then deliver.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>David Blair from the Daily....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll have just one more question and then we'll move in to the analyst presentation and we'll of course be back later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>David Blair from the Daily Telegraph. Sol not to take the focus away from your departure but I was wondering if you had any comment to make about the prototype phone Microsoft phone that was reportedly stolen last week in Barcelona.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well to be quite frank I saw it for about five seconds. I never had possession of it so its interesting to me that there was a story about Sol losing a phone or having his pockets picked which never happened. But in terms of the phone itself we have been working with Microsoft on creating the next generation capability that again integrates much of what you've heard us talk about over the last couple years with a lot of their operating software capabilities to simplify the experience for a customer, and leveraging some of what we do with unified communications and some of the things that you'll see us introduce later this year. So it is a terrific next step and but what I would say is everything you have seen here at Telstra next steps are great but even a step back and that's already underway as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you to our friends for getting us to the big issues. With that well convene a little later for more media questions. Perhaps if journalists could head out to the boardroom and well get all the analysts seated and then well come back later. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. My name is Ben Spincer from Investor Relations. I'm from Investor Relations. I would like to welcome you here today to the other event, the announcement of our half&#x2010;year results. We obviously have the briefing here in Sydney; I would also welcome the callers who are online as well. I will now hand over to Sol Trujillo, who will run through the half&#x2010;year results, followed by John Stanhope, and then we will be able to take questions from both here in Sydney and also from the conference call this time around.</p>
          <p>So I will hand over to Sol. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, Ben, and good morning to everybody. I would like to welcome all of those here and everyone else tuning in via our live webcast and teleconference links. Let me just first start by saying, once again, Telstra has delivered a strong performance across the business, despite many of the economic pressures that I think we read about, hear about every day going on globally, and specifically here in Australia. In spite of the headwinds, let me emphasize up front that we remain on track to achieve our 2010 objectives and have not been distracted by extraneous debates and speculation on other issues. The transformation remains our priority and we continue to be focused on that as the main event, as it has been for the last four years.</p>
          <p>Our focus on customers, networks and services gives us a tangible competitive advantage, and I think that one of the most important things that I think about all the time, and I thought about when I first came, is the fact that building differentiation, sustainable differentiation, is key, and I think you will see that now in our numbers. The results are clear. In our mobile services business, growth continues to exceed 12%, with margins now 12 percentage points above the number two player in this market. So we are continuing to grow and growing ARPU and growing margins.</p>
          <p>In broadband, we grew fixed retail broadband revenue by 20%, with SIO growth three times our largest competitor, and in IP and data we grew IP data or access data revenues by 28%. In Sensis we grew sales revenue by 8% compared to what you might see around the world negative growth and even in this market here in Australia, negative growth from some of our competitors, when you look at the media companies and other directory kinds of businesses.</p>
          <p>In broadband, we grew fixed retail broadband revenue by 20 %, with SIO growth three times our largest competitor, and in IP and data we grew IP data or access data revenues by 28 %. In Sensis we grew sales revenue by 8% compared to what you might see around the world negative growth and even in this market here in Australia, negative growth from some of our competitors, when you look at the media companies and other directory kinds of businesses</p>
          <p>At Foxtel, we grew revenues 13%. So Telstra continues to hold or gain revenue market share. In my eyes, this is an impressive performance, consistent with all the objectives that we laid out relative to our transformation. Across our major segments we are seeing a flight to quality from business and enterprise customers, whilst in Consumer strategic investments in T[life] and the end-to-end customer experience is driving market share gains, in spite of, I guess, what I would describe as significant price-driven competition.</p>
          <p>While today is about results and the operating outlook, I'm going to touch very briefly upon NBN. NBN is a long-term issue. It has no impact on our guidance and our strategy is not dependent on it. I know you have heard me say that before, but it seems that it is worth repeating. We have repeatedly said that we see major challenges to any potential alternative bidder or builder in terms of financing, timing, technology, logistics, and even all the way through legislation. And with world-class high-speed broadband networks already in place, that we own and operate, we are able to offer our customers what they want, where they want it, when they want it. And NBN now sits with the Minister and the Cabinet. I think there have always been win-win outcomes for Telstra, Australia and the Government, and we have looked towards a solution since basically I first proposed it in August of 2005, but, as I have also said in the past, and I think those of you who were here in the room a little bit earlier would have heard Donald said it as well, we have moved on.</p>
          <p>So, let me now spend the time on the important stuff. First, let me touch on some of the financial headlines that John is going to go into more detail on later. We have grown sales revenue 3.2% to 12.6 billion. This is an improvement on the 3% growth reported in the second half of fiscal 2008. Strong retail sales were again the driver of growth as we used market-based management and differentiation with our quality products and services to win in the market. Discipline was maintained on expenses and we held OpEx growth to 1.7% on a reported basis.</p>
          <p>On an underlying basis, it grew just under 1%. Reported EBIT declined 1.3% in the first half. However, this figure includes a number of one-off factors that John, again, will take you through, such as accelerated depreciation at CSL, costs of the marketing simplification redundancies and acceleration of some of our store roll-outs and other initiatives in the business. Adjusting for these factors, first-half underlying EBIT and EBITDA growth was 4.8%. In the face of the current macro climate, few major companies from our domestic and international peer group have been able to report such sustained momentum in the half. And critically for shareholders in these difficult times, we have maintained our interim dividend payment at $0.14 per share as our free cash flow continues to grow aggressively, growing above 40%, now leading into 2010. So for those of you who have been listening to me since November 2005, cash flow and the 6, $7 billion target, the EBITDA margins that we talked about and the top line growth, along with a few other variables, still are at the top of mind, and we are well on path to hitting those numbers.</p>
          <p>So let me move to guidance. Against the rapidly deteriorating economic climate, we are pleased to be able to reiterate all of our guidance for 2010, with continued growth in the business, expanding margins, and, as I like to say many times inside the business, and I will say it many times now to those of you who don't work inside the business, free cash flow is the critical metric and, again, we reiterate the targets of 6 to $7 billion for next year. The transformation remains very much on track. While we continue to expect revenue growth in the range of 3 to 4% this year, we now expect EBITDA growth in the range of 5 to 6% and EBIT growth in the range of 3 to 5%.</p>
          <p>So let me highlight that this still represents strong accelerating bottom line growth in H2, but it is a lower guidance, and I want to be clear on why the guidance is lower and, again, John will talk about it as well. The lower guidance is due to a combination of essentially one-off factors, but some pressure on the top line, as we see declining PSTN and mobile call volumes as customers in today's environment are managing usage down in this rapidly deteriorating macro environment. If we look at PSTN &#x2013; and, again, I'm not going to steal John's thunder here -- PSTN is a very profitable part of our business and so it has disproportionate impact when you look at not only the decline or slow-down at the top, but it has accelerating impact on the bottom.</p>
          <p>As we look at the one-off issues, there is going to be additional cost from the catastrophic Victorian fires and Queensland floods; further accelerated depreciation at Hong Kong CSL. We are accelerating our T[life] store roll-outs because what David Moffatt and the team are doing is exciting, the results are terrific, and so we are going to accelerate; we don't believe in slowing down. And finally we have been -- again John will talk about an increase in bad debts, given, again, the current economic conditions.</p>
          <p>Finally, as we noted in November, the cost benefits of the IT transformation will come slightly later as we focus on improving the customer experience during the transition phase. We talked back in November about when you migrate the six to seven million customers that we do, with new billing platforms, new bill call detail, all kinds of change for the customer, we have gone through a bubble period, October, November, December and January of heavy call volumes into our offices. But despite the current economic environment, shareholders can be confident that the overall business continues to perform well. We have reiterated our guidance for 2010 and are happy with the current consensus position on next year's outcomes. Again, John will get into more detail in his presentation. So I'm going to move on to the business performance.</p>
          <p>Our retail revenue grew by 4.1% as we continued to execute our market-based management, driven strategy. Excluding handset sales which were uniquely inflated last year because of the CDMA migration, retail revenues grew 5.1%. There were many highlights. In Consumer we grew revenue at 3% or 4.7% excluding this handset phenomenon from last year. In Business, we grew revenue at 7.2% and achieved revenue growth of 34% in broadband and 15% in mobile services. In the Enterprise &amp; Government segment we had 20% revenue growth in mobile services and our best ever growth in IP and data access revenues. Total growth for Enterprise &amp; Government, half on half, was 3.9%. At Sensis, we maintained positive Yellow print revenue growth, while growing our digital media revenues by 37%, and achieved sales revenue growth of 8.4%, again, as we outgrow the market.</p>
          <p>So when you look at the performance relative to competitors, relative to other peers around the world, you can see that our growth and our performance really is best in class. We achieved total domestic growth of 2.8% with the mobile IP and directories growth partially offset by a 5.1% decline in PSTN. We plan to stem this decline by reinvigorating usage going forward and some other tactics that we have in the market.</p>
          <p>Now there are certain things that we cannot change, the fact that people love calling on their mobiles versus fixed line at least in the near term, but there is more coming. We cannot change the economic climate all by ourselves, and there are going to be some issues there relative to growth, but we think there are other initiatives that you will see literally happening in the market shortly to, hopefully, stem some of these market conditions. But part of what we have been focused on has been reinvigorating the retail experience, and, again, David Moffatt and Andy Ellis, who he recruited in a year or a year and a half ago, have really, with the T[life] stores have I think, hit, using an American term from baseball a home run.</p>
          <p>We've increased customer lifetime value with average revenue per post-paid device commanding a 20% premium over our non T[life] channels. So the returns, the growth, the ARPU, the customer satisfaction, are all there. So while our largest competitor is cutting back its retail network roll-out. We recently opened our 35th T[life] store in Sydney and plan to have 80 nationally by June, as we accelerate our roll-out.</p>
          <p>And in addition to our T[life] expansion, we are in the process of opening 17 more dedicated business centers. Deena Shiff and her team are looking again at this acceleration. Because remember the growth rates that we are talking about that I referred to just a minute ago. Significant growth. We are now over 50% penetration on our Next G/3G capabilities in the market, still growing ARPU. So what Deena and David and the rest of our team are looking to do is very important in the retail context.</p>
          <p>All Telstra Business products and services are going to now be experienced as well in these stores, much as we have seen in the consumer space. Our retail performance again contrasts the 4.1% decline in wholesale revenue, due to the continued impact of ULL and LSS and continued migration to retail broadband. Again, this is part of the plan, part of what we knew back when we talked in November of '05, as the regulator was changing the structure on wholesale, as the regulator was de-averaging, and as the regulator was essentially setting prices below cost.</p>
          <p>So when we look at the performance now, obviously in the case of wholesale we are competing well, but we are going to continue to finish out the migration that we had and we understood would happen with the changes in the regulatory settings. But the key here is that in the aggregate the company is performing well, driving our retail business while our wholesale goes through that readjustment period.</p>
          <p>In terms of our Next G network it continues to set the global standard for both speed and coverage and to drive both top and bottom line growth. Recently we became the first telco anywhere to deliver 21 megabits, peak network download speeds with compatible 3G devices. If any of you happened to be in Barcelona or saw footage of it, it was actually pretty fun, if you were an Australian, to be standing there and having the rest of the world talking about what was happening in Australia and actually going to some of the stands, whether it be Ericsson or even the GSMA, and seeing this demo where through-put speeds were actually running on their platforms at 16 to 19 megabits per second on average. So we are pushing the limits. We are driving it. Because this is about differentiation and it is about customer experience. So part of what we talked about was not only the 21 megabits, but also setting the stake in the ground for what this team will deliver by the end of this year of taking it to 42 megabits as well.</p>
          <p>So, when we look at the Next G impacts, many mobile highlights: service revenue growth of 12.4% and those of you who have covered other markets, where you look at 100% penetrated markets, go to Europe, go to a few other places, you won't find anything close to this kind of growth, and that is in light of the challenging economic conditions that we have. Growth was actually marginally better than we achieved in fiscal 2008.</p>
          <p>Blended mobile ARPUs grew nearly 10% to $53 and, again, this is a countertrend to what everybody else is doing. We passed another key milestone with more than five million 3G subscribers, while maintaining the postpaid 3G/2G ARPU premium in excess of $20, and as John and I continue to visit with our operating unit heads &#x2013; David Thodey and Deena and David Moffatt and Geoff Booth, we kind of smile, because that $20 that people were skeptical of back when we first started about that differential between 3G and 2G is actually getting bigger, not declining.</p>
          <p>So Postpaid subscribers were up by 284,000, and our total mobile subscriber base climbed 371,000 to 9.7 million in the half. Prepaid wireless ARPU increased 21%. The biggest driver of growth was again data, as revenues grew 37% to reach nearly $1 billion. Wireless broadband revenues continued to grow strongly, driven by an increase in SIOs to 828,000 in the half.</p>
          <p>Wireless broadband ARPUs were diluted by the launch of prepaid and some tariff rebalancing, but remain well above average wireless ARPUs, at around $80 per month. We had solid growth in the fixed retail broadband market with revenue up 20% to $783 million. The slowing growth rate this half reflects SIO adds moderating as the market moves into its maturity phase, as penetration is increased from the point in time when I came here at about 15% to a little less than 60% penetration today. So a lot has happened in this period of time, but there are still significant opportunities from Telstra's 81% ADSL2+ coverage and 92% ADSL coverage.</p>
          <p>Part of our strong performance in fixed broadband comes from the 6% ARPU growth achieved as customers continue to migrate to faster speeds and liberty plans and subscribe to new BigPond content and services. For example, we have had strong double-digit revenue growth in each of BigPond Music, Movies, Video, Advertising, Shopping and Games.</p>
          <p>So Mr. Milne has been a busy man continuing to drive this continued differentiation as part of the brand positioning, part of how customers think about Telstra, versus the secondary choices in the market. But we continue to face very strong headwinds as we are required by the regulator to sell ULL and LSS below cost and, indeed, at some of the lowest prices in the world. Wholesale broadband revenues declined as our competitors added another 88,000 ULL SIOs and 65,000 LSS SIOs, although this uptake is also slowing as the market matures and their on-net or migration strategies evolve.</p>
          <p>In IP we had our best half ever, driven by our investment in the Next IP network and applications and services that utilize the network's capabilities. And I guess I would say that David Thodey and Holly Kramer, in partnership with all the network partners, with Mick Rocca's team, have done some really, I think, cool things that are now allowing us to drive IP access revenue growth of 28%, our IP MAN and IP WAN ports reached around 84,000 as customers switched to the cutting edge technology in the IP access capabilities. The IP access ARPU for Enterprise &amp; Government customers is up 40% from FY07 levels.</p>
          <p>So have you note a consistent theme here about not only are we growing in terms of revenues or SIOs, but we're growing in ARPUs and that's critical as I think about a successful strategy? I wanted to detail how we achieve this by revisiting the IP access ARPU escalator that we talked about last August. Strategy simple: target new customers with their standard IP network solution and then we up-sell value-added products, leading to significantly higher ARPU. As you can see from the penetration rates, we have already been successful increasing the penetration of advanced IP services, but our belief is that there are still huge opportunities remaining with clearly built competitive advantage and our continuing to invest to keep on driving the difference between us and those that we compete with.</p>
          <p>So let me turn now to MediaComms where our revolution continues. Telstra Media's vision is to develop unique capabilities to deliver engaging content and services to customers. In Australia, we've built world-class, integrated and intelligent networks. Customers are accessing our superior content and services across mobile and fixed platforms and again, in a similar integrated fashion. MediaComms are growing portfolio sites keeping BigPond visitors engaged for longer.</p>
          <p>In October alone we had more than 100 million site visits. BigPond is number one in games downloads, movie downloads and sports reach and advertising and number two in music downloads. We continue our innovation leadership with the recent launch of BigPond Health and BigPond Travel. As part of this strategy, the Trading Post, including its online and auction sites, we're going to now move over to the Telstra Media portfolio. Again, we can create that continued integrated experience for our customers as they think about doing the themes of shopping, buying, in this online kind of context.</p>
          <p>Our China strategy is about taking our core competencies from Australia and applying them to organically develop our businesses to leverage their traffic to add value and drive growth. We are entering the market on the back of our media businesses in the online and mobile content areas. In addition to the financial returns we generate, we're also going to develop strategic relationships with key players in China to continue to access further opportunities.</p>
          <p>So again, part of the strategy is porting our competencies to other markets and in some cases, as we've seen with a few of these businesses, we can port back to Australia some of the technology platforms and capabilities to be able to deliver at even higher skill points what we do here in Australia, so a lot of synergy, and more of our strategy will continue to evolve over the coming months.</p>
          <p>As announced earlier this month, we acquired a controlling interest in two of China's leading mobile content and online music businesses. China M runs the WAP portal for all of China Mobile's 600 million users and serves mobile content to 350,000 customers daily. Sharp Point operates China Mobile's rapidly growing mobile music platform.</p>
          <p>And we are very pleased with the price we paid, less than seven times 2009 EBITDA, if all of our targets are met. Our existing China businesses continue to perform very strongly. SouFun had another stand-out half year highlighted by its expansion to 100 cities, which was part of the drive that we announced when we first made the acquisition, revenue growth of 54% and EBITDA growth of 74% and the integration of Norstar Media and Autohome/PCPop acquired eight months ago is on track and the business is performing strongly with, again, revenues up 71% and EBITDA up 148%. Assuming we owned all our Chinese assets for the whole of 2008, the combined business would generate in excess of A$250 million with margins in excess of 40%.</p>
          <p>On this basis, these businesses would have a bigger EBITDA, clearly, than Telstra Clear and we believe these businesses could double in size in the next three years. There is an extraordinary opportunity in China as penetration of mobile phones and personal computers rapidly increase. China is forecast to continue to grow substantially faster than the rest of the world, even taking into account the impact of GFC, and we are perfectly positioned with our strategic relationships and suite of new media assets, which includes leading online verticals in the real estate, auto and PC segments and a key position in the mobile value-added services portion of the market.</p>
          <p>Remember that just in the month of December, the Chinese Government approved 3G licenses. As a result of that, the Chinese Government has essentially authorized spend by the three companies of about $59 billion to build out these networks and once they're built out and once they migrate their customers, what they're going to do on 3G platforms will be no different than what we see here or in Japan or in Europe or in the U.S and that means usage.</p>
          <p>In China we're on track to reach $1 billion of revenue and margins of 30 to 40% within five years. To me the growth there is exciting. We are developing a reputation in China that I think is highly unique in our sector and we will continue to exploit it with the work that Bruce Akhurst and Justin Milne are doing literally as we speak.</p>
          <p>At Sensis, Yellow continues to underpin the Sensis result with double digit online revenue growth and positive print revenue growth and significantly, Yellow online EBITDA margins are approaching Yellow's print strong margins. Again, we think about businesses in a very dissected way and so as we look at this kind of performance where White Pages', Online's and Yellow Pages' margins are so rich and we can keep on growing those margins, obviously that's a perfect combination, especially if you're growing at the top line.</p>
          <p>Digital Media businesses revenues also increased 37% to 288 million or 28% of Sensis revenues, which I think again is a tremendous achievement over the last three years. The strength of Sensis' performance is clear when compared with domestic and global peers. This is not an easy business, just look at News Corp, just look at Fairfax, just look at the TV stations and others. It's a tough business.</p>
          <p>And in the online space, the Yellow's online margins are significantly higher than local peers, such as Fairfax Digital and major global online peers such as Google, Yahoo and eBay. And News Corp recently announced a 4% decline in Australian advertising revenue in the past quarter. So again when you look at it in the comparative sense not only against directory publishers around the world but those who we compete with for the dollars here in Australia, we're outperforming.</p>
          <p>In the case of FOXTEL, it also continues to deliver a very strong financial performance. As I said earlier, revenues were up 13% to 906 million and EBITDA was up 19%. We continue to drive our key IT transformation objectives. The migration of Telstra mass market customers from legacy systems continues on track. We are operating at scale and the new systems are working really well.</p>
          <p>By early February we had deployed 1,900 internal and external sites with the new system, trained 17,900 users, we have now migrated more than 7.1 million customers and 13.1 million services. We've issued 27.2 million billing invoices, we received 24.6 million payments, completed 3.5 million orders and we are processing 230 million records everyday. So the system is working well.</p>
          <p>However, as we said in November, we were challenged as we migrated millions of customers to new systems and monthly billing. During the half and as the migration peaked our processes dealing with order provisioning, customer queries and complaints have been severely tested. During this time our customer experience metrics were not where we wanted them to be. And what I mean by that is if you called into mostly David Moffatt's call centers we would see that we had a high level of long-hold times or not meeting the kinds of metrics that we would like in terms of speed of answer but that's been part of what we expected would happen when you migrate your customers on to a new system. New bills, annual, monthly versus quarterly and then a whole new bill &#x2013; detailed bill scheme. So we're now basically past the peak of that. We're on the other side of that and now we are working the other way.</p>
          <p>So I'm very proud with our IT team; Tom Lamming and John McInerney and the whole team have driven there working with David Moffatt and his operating team. This has been primarily centered on consumer, a part of our business at this stage and parts of it now are into business and we will move in to the next stages as we progress during the year. So as I look at our customer experience it's getting better and as I said earlier we're on the other side of the bubble.</p>
          <p>Now as we think about extracting the benefits, the benefits of all that we have been doing or getting now reflected in our continued and sustained growth. We are a big company with a big revenue base that in order to sustain the revenue growth that we're taking about, it does require a lot of better customer experience, better consultation with customers as that they do business with us. So whether it be in our stores, or whether it be in the call centers that's what we are working on is continuing to make it a better experience and that's where the partnership between our IT leadership and our market units is so important.</p>
          <p>Now as we think about environmental, social and governance issues on another topic I just wanted to mention some of our ESG initiatives. These include the laying of fiber optic and Arnhem Land working with the authorities to disperse community safety information and helping improve energy efficiency. Our corporate responsibility report from November 2008 contains a lot of the details of what we would call our ESG initiatives.</p>
          <p>So a lot has been going on, a lots being done, we're very focused on sustaining growth, very focused as you see on our underlying operating expense numbers continuing to drive that and we are very focused on our EBITDA margins as we go forward.</p>
          <p>So before I hand it over to John I want to emphasize again this focus. It's a focus on increasing shareholders returns. And we will always try to act with shareholders' best interests, as our number one priority.</p>
          <p>We're now at a point where everyone can rest assured that we have improved our customer experience, that we are capable of sustaining growth, that we now have clear competitive differentiation in the market, that our value-based competitive strategy does work and our integration strategy of integrating services and products and capabilities does work. And finally, as you will always hear me talk about above all else, we remain determined to achieve our long-term management objective of six to $7 billion of free cash flow in FY '10. And just as a footnote, it's not just about FY '10 it's about beyond FY '10 as well with all that we have underway.</p>
          <p>So with that I'm going to stop and turn it over to John. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sol and good morning everybody here in Sydney and elsewhere in the country and perhaps beyond. As you've already heard, its been a challenging six months for our business but we're reporting a good set of numbers here. And I hope other events that have occurred earlier this morning don't detract from the good performance of the business. The sales revenue grew by 3.2% to $12.6 billion and total revenue, which we is what we guide on and includes FOXTEL distribution increased by 2.7% to $12.7 billion.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses increased by 1.7% to $7.4 billion and for the second consecutive half, operating expense growth is less than sales revenue growth. EBITDA was up 3.1% to 5.3 billion and margins were steady at 42.2% despite some of the one-offs in the half. On an underlying basis, our EBITDA margins increased by 70 basis points half-on-half, and I'll go into EBIT in a bit more detail shortly but reported EBIT fell 1.3% to $3.1 billion whilst underlying EBIT, and I'll explain how we get to that, grew 4.8%. So, despite the economic slowdown we have maintained strong cash flows and interim dividend at $0.14 per share fully franked.</p>
          <p>Let me first look in detail at the EBIT decline in the first half. And by the way, I did foreshadow that we would be flat or negative sometime ago. Although we flagged that issue back in November, it's probably worth repeating some things here, it &#x2013; because it might surprise a few of you.</p>
          <p>What are the factors here and why is adjusted EBIT closer to the 5%? As you can see from this slide, we had a few one-offs that I've highlighted here that we booked in the first-half of '09 that went out there in the first-half of '08 or vice versa. Those will not be there in the second-half of '09. The waterfall shows some of the major drivers of the absolute change to EBIT and the contribution that each makes to the overall EBIT growth rate.</p>
          <p>For example, in other income, proceeds from the sale of eBusiness of $37 million in the first-half of 2008 compared with nil in this half, which took 1.2% of the EBIT growth in the first-half. And what I'm trying to explain here our graph here.</p>
          <p>In terms of labor, we have excluded the $49 million one-off impact of the 800 staff reduction we announced last September as part of our marketing simplification program. So we pulled through forward if you like some initiatives. And this took another 1.6% off the growth rate of EBIT. Finally, the 103 million of accelerated depreciation and amortization at CSL New World booked this half compared to none in the first half of the '08 fiscal took 3.3% of the EBIT growth. So when you take those factors into account, it tales us to an underlying EBIT growth of 4.8% for the first half of fiscal '09.</p>
          <p>But just as a reminder and to stop any unjust criticism from any quarters, our EBIT guidance relates to reported not these adjusted numbers. The only reason I've gone through this analysis, is to prevent the half year outcome being extrapolated to a full year outcome because the first half was driven by some unusual occurrences as I've gone through.</p>
          <p>So let me talk a little bit more about the guidance you've heard from Sol and I've already said it today, these are tough times. With the benefit of six weeks trading activity in this second half we know the conditions are not getting any easier.</p>
          <p>Revenue remains strong, particularly in the key areas of mobile data and broadband. However the deteriorating macroeconomic environment is beginning to bite into fixed and mobile voice usage, as people do manage down their usage more than we had expected. And we now believe that our current year revenue growth will be towards the low-end of our guidance range which is you can see there three to 4%. And that is even after taking in to account, the favorable currency impact of CSL New World revenues, which by the way at the EBIT line is close to a neutral outcome.</p>
          <p>I'd like you to understand that with revenue growth moving toward the low end of guidance, this impacts the EBITDA and EBIT growth disproportionately; for example, a negative $130 million on the revenue growth line or on the revenue line, has a 0.5% impact, but of course impacts EBIT growth by about 2%, so obviously there is a disproportionate impact, especially when you are talking about higher margin voice usage revenues and that have no cost of goods sold associated.</p>
          <p>With respect to the expense and EBIT growth in the second half we acknowledge that changes to have bills, and billing has generated more customer cost and therefore higher costs. So, in the interest of those customers we are handling those volumes and doing so, and in doing so we are incurring some additional costs.</p>
          <p>In addition to this we have incurred some out-of-plan costs, which might run into the tens of million of dollars for the floods in Queensland and the bushfires in Victoria plus the continuation of accelerated depreciation in CSL and the acceleration of the T[life] stores rollout that Sol referenced.</p>
          <p>We have also seen a rise of about $20 million in our bad debt expense in the first half particularly in the consumer and business segments and that's largely driven by the impacts of the slowing economy on business insolvency and a deterioration in the delinquency of consumer aged debt. So taking those factors into account, we still expect robust bottom line growth for the full year, with EBITDA growing at five to 6% and EBIT growing at three to 5%, I know many would like to have numbers like that.</p>
          <p>It is still very strong growth given the current climate and certainly compared to what our global peers are predicting as witnessed by recently -- recent quarterly and half year results announcements.</p>
          <p>We have built sustainable growth and still expect to generate free cash flow of six to seven billion in 2010. Many of these factors are a matter of timing and that's why we are not changing our fiscal year 2010 objectives although again these may come in at the low end of the guidance range, but we deal within the consensus.</p>
          <p>I'll move onto something a little more simple I guess, and that's the continued growth in momentum in our key products. This slide shows both the revenue growth in our key product areas and importantly the change in the contribution to total sales from each product. The size of the bubble indicates the actual dollar amount of revenue. We've had another great half in mobiles, with mobile services revenue growing at 12.4% to over three billion and as I said earlier it's mostly driven by mobile data.</p>
          <p>Mobile continues to increase its contribution through our overall revenue pie and it is now 27% of total sales revenue. Mobiles EBITDA margins continue to improve. They went up 1.5% from this time last year to now 38% EBITDA margins.</p>
          <p>Fixed retail broadband revenue grew by 20%, $783 million with customers up 9% to 2.3 million and ARPU continuing to grow, it was up 6% to $57. IP and data access and Sensis also had a good half. All these areas of the business are growing above the Group average growth rate. Contrast that to PSTN where revenues declined by 5.1%, PSTN now makes up only 25% of our sales revenue which is down 2.2 percentage points from this time last year.</p>
          <p>The revenue decline was very due to the wholesale business <mark type="audio gap" /> half of the year. You can see here our success of growing revenue and market share is in the more likely regulated parts of the business and in the parts of the business, where we've actually made major investments.</p>
          <p>And going to the retail segments now, I thought I'd start with our Enterprise and Government business, as we are seeing many of our global peers reporting a decline in their enterprise segment as a result of slowing economy.</p>
          <p>Well, I'm happy to say that our Enterprise and Government business has had a great half growing sales revenue by 3.9%, another great half in the Enterprise and Government mobile segment with mobile services revenue growing 20% in that segment. Data revenue now accounts for over 46% of mobile services <mark type="audio gap" />, behind accelerating IP and data access revenue growth of 9.3%. We are growing share in this category as we show customers, how we can improve their productivity from employing our integrated product and solutions offerings. Despite the economic slowdown the sales pipeline in T&amp;G looks very healthy.</p>
          <p>When you have a look at business, the business segment just like Enterprise and Government segment, the Telstra business has delivered strong results and has shown a high level of resilience over the past six months recording growth in sales revenue of 7.2%. And as you can see from this slide growth rates across all products have remained relatively constant indicating that Telstra business has been able to increase market share across categories despite the economic headwinds. On top of fixed revenue growth in this segment mobiles continues to power along recording growth of 13.7% in the half, ARPUs including voice ARPUs are growing as is the subscriber base with 72% of small, medium enterprise customers' mobile base now being on 3G, all being 3G customers.</p>
          <p>Impressive growth has been achieved from our business broadband and IP data offering into the SME market. We are seeing a willingness from customers to invest in the productivity of their business and they are choosing Telstra due to the reliability of our networks and the total service offering. And pleasingly, expense growth has slowed to below that of revenue growth for the first time as the segment completes its transformation of the business unit, completes its transition from being a brand new business unit only a few years ago.</p>
          <p>Finally, to our largest segment consumer where sales revenue grew at 3% this half. Importantly our consumer segment grew their bottom line faster than their top line, so good news. Whilst our competitors are going backwards in their commitment to channels, distribution and the overall customer experience now more than ever we have continued to invest in all of these areas. We're still continuing to play hard in this space and it's certainly paying off and will put us in a great position.</p>
          <p>The statistics coming out of our T[life] stores that Sol talked about earlier, really tells a great story and the improved customer experience has translated into value added services penetration. In the half PSTN value added services grew 8% and that includes things like easy call and call number display message bank and so on. Broadband value added services grew 46%, postpaid value added services was up 19% and prepaid mobile value added services revenue was up 23% and that includes things like SMS, non-SMS data and so on.</p>
          <p>Consumer have also demonstrated operational excellence through declining their subscriber acquisition rate contracting costs. In consumer, the blended average cost of acquiring and retaining a customer declined by 18% or $112 per customer.</p>
          <p>I'm going to look now at operating expenses. Now, operating expenses grew just 1.7% to 7.4 billion, that's before D&amp;A, while labor and other expenses both rose, goods and services purchased fell by 1.6%. And I'll go into each of those categories starting with labor.</p>
          <p>Labor expense rose by 2.9% to $2.2 billion while we reduced head count by over 1,300 in the half, taking our head count reduction to 10,143 against our fiscal year 2010 targets which you will recall were between 10,000 and 12,000. The savings at the labor line are not expected until next half. The full redundancy impact of the reduction in FTEs was 131 million all taken -- all taken in this half.</p>
          <p>One of the larger contributors to the increase in the labor line and this does notes an explanation, was due to a fall in the 10-year government bond rate over the period and so what's that got to do with labor, it is used to calculate the present value of our non-current long service labor obligations. And as the discount rate reduces, the present value of our long service labor obligation increases. And so -- and that's represented on the slide there as an extra $67 million in costs. If I was to factor that out, I mean it's a real expense at least in an accounting, the labor costs would &#x2013; were actually flat in the half.</p>
          <p>The increase in the other category includes the impact of FX movements in our offshore labor. We also had an increase as a result of higher payouts to Sensis staff as their results exceeding their sales targets.</p>
          <p>So we move on to the directly variable costs, they did decline 1.6%, which is an impressive productivity gain. Significantly driving the expenses down this half was the total cost of good sold within this category which declined by 14.9% or $161 million to $918 million? It was offset by some higher costs totaling a 110 million in service fees and they are related to the increase in selling Pay TV bundles.</p>
          <p>Network payments, as more traffic land on other networks and predominately due &#x2013; and they were predominately due to some FX movements on our terminal out payments for our landing traffic offshore and to a much lesser extent would have a bit of an increase in usage commissions.</p>
          <p>The decline in the cost of goods sold mainly consists of both postpaid handset subsidies, the cost of handsets and some BigPond-related cost of goods sold. The total cost of our postpaid handset subsidies declined from this time last year almost entirely due to lower subsidized volumes. Just to give you the example, 713,000 handsets were subsidized in the first half last year, whereas only 538,000 handsets were subsidized in this half year. And this is not that we're just &#x2013; we're selling less so much as we are managing subsidies much better and encouraging customers into taking other options.</p>
          <p>In terms of subscriber acquisitions and recontracting costs over the whole company, so not just consumer as I spoke about before, the average blended subscriber acquisition and recontracting cost decreased by $21 to $135 from the $156 in the first half in '08. We continue to improve our operating leverage of the mobile business evidenced by that downward trend in the acquisition and recontracting costs of customers and our blended mobile ARPU was $53 and you can see that in the slide.</p>
          <p>Let me just address the other expense category which is a fairly broad category, we list out some of the elements in it. It rose by 4.1% service contracts and agreements represent almost half of that. Days increased by 6.8% in the half primarily driven by our IT transformation related costs and you might recall I did mention that as we do the migrations we would be spending the money to do the migrations and that's exactly what has happened. Within that category the service contracts expense line grew 8% to 833 million as we completed that migration of consumer, customers on to the new billing systems.</p>
          <p>Higher costs were incurred in the half as a result of also increasing inbound call volumes which I mentioned earlier associated with those customer migrations. The movement in the exchange rates also had an impact on other expenses category as a result of the significant depreciation in the Aussie dollar. So that really is the un-hedged part of some of the activity that we have with offshore companies.</p>
          <p>Bad and doubtful debts also increased by 5.5% to a 124 million and that's due to the deterioration I mentioned before in the overall -- portfolio as a result of the worsening economic environment. You can see I mentioned that it was about $20 million in consumer and business so we've had some upside in other parts of the business but nevertheless I do expect the trend to continue particularly in consumer and business in the second half. But we continue to manage credit carefully and as tightly as possible in these tough times.</p>
          <p>Depreciation and amortization as you saw last half we did book some accelerated depreciation in CSL in Hong Kong, as they build their new network. So the life of the old network has been shortened. It continued into this fiscal year to the tune of a $103 million. The increase from the previous half is predominantly due to FX movements. The accelerated D&amp;A in CSL is expected to continue into the second half at a similar level to the second half of fiscal 2009. So, I guess it's around 70 million or so. Now we are however still on track to meet our fiscal year '09 guidance in depreciation and amortization of around $4.5 billion of total D&amp;A.</p>
          <p>I wanted to show you given revals, and fair value and interest adjustments, I wanted to show you on this slide the movement in our real interest expense versus the movement of finance costs. The net interest expense increased by $55 million is the bottom line here, or 9.5% to 632 million. This was due to higher credit margins and a higher level of net interest bearing debt, consolidated debt actually increased.</p>
          <p>Our average borrowing costs increased 32 basis points since the first half of '08, however we expected a small reduction in average borrowing cost in the second half.</p>
          <p>Of the other adjustments to net finance costs of 229 million, that is the fair value adjustment. It amounted to $248 million more than half of this related to an unrealized gain on effective fair value hedges primarily due to an increase in Telstra's borrowing margins. So our overall net debt balance increased by $1.1 billion in the half to $16.4 billion, but 681 was reval or revaluation, so, in terms of new borrowings so new money, new cash this amounted to $465 million in the half. I'm just trying to explain the fair value accounting here.</p>
          <p>Our debt position, I've mentioned just before but very quickly to reiterate, our balance sheet really has become our strength. We have no long-term debt refinancing needed until March 2010, and we sit comfortably as you can see there within our target financial parameters.</p>
          <p>This is probably &#x2013; just moving on to the next slide, this is probably the first time we've given you two balance sheet slides and I can see the excitement in the audience. But there are some significant movements on the balance sheet. I'm the CFO, give me a break here, that we needed to explain. And the largest movement that you'll see is the swing in the defined benefit asset of 182 million positive at June 2008 to a defined benefit liability of 1.2 billion at the 31st of December '08.</p>
          <p>The largest contributor of this is a fall in the discount rates used in determining the present value of the projected benefit obligation for the scheme and the reduction of the rate was from 5.5 to 3.4 and that's resulted in an increase in the future benefit liabilities also contributing to the movement has been significant decrease in the market values of just the plan, the scheme assets. You all know that the movement here due to the discount rate and fall in asset values, we take to equity, so it doesn't fall into the P&amp;L. So there's not a profit and loss impact. Obviously, I watch our level of retained earnings and our equity.</p>
          <p>In terms of the contribution we made to the super fund, we told you people in the market last year, that we would recommence superannuation contributions, so this is real cash in late November and we expected to pay $110 million for our series of payments through to February and up to the 31st of December, we had contributed 43 million. The market deteriorated further in the December quarter reducing the average, what we call the vested benefits index further and we now expect to contribute approximately 115 million during the quarter through to May. So those contributions have a balance sheet and cash flow impact of crediting our cash balance and the debit goes against our liability.</p>
          <p>So whilst the calculation of the VBI and any associate liability is an issue for actuaries in Telstra Super, you need to know we expect that top-up payments will be necessary in the rest of fiscal '09 and into the 2010 year. But I do want to quickly add that in the '09, '10 year in particular, in setting a six to $7 billion free cash flow target, we have taken into account that we would need to pay or have a cash outflow for the pension fund.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow, whilst I'm talking about the cash, you can see here we generated close to two billion of free cash flow in the half. That is a 44% increase from the last year. Operating cash flows of 4.2 billion, while investing cash flow outflows were 2.3. The significant reduction investing cash outflows from the previous half of $500 million or $0.5 billion comes as the capital intensity of our transformation has passed its spending peak and will continue to go down in the '09, '10 year.</p>
          <p>So to conclude, let me reiterate a few points. We have a strong business with robust growth expected for the full year. We had maintained a strong balance sheet through these difficult times and are paying a healthy, fully franked dividend of $0.14 per share this half. We have maintained our 2010 long-term management objectives importantly our free cash flow target of between six and $7 billion in 2010.</p>
          <p>So thank you for listening to that and I will now ask Sol to come back to the stage and we will take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Going through the detail on all that. Ian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sol. On the one hand I want to congratulate you for where you've taken the company over 3.5 years, but on the other hand you haven't actually got there yet. And I notice this is the first result in a long time with the guidance actually going down, but you won't be here in August to report on that. So I wonder who has the responsibility for it, who wears it, if that new guidance isn't delivered. And more importantly next year's targets, what's the validity of those now with the change in CEO? What's the prospect that in August or February next year we're standing here and a new CEO says, they were Sol's targets, I'm taking the company in this new direction and here are my targets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well let me take it in pieces here. In terms of delivering on the numbers, I own it, John owns it, the whole senior management team owns it between now and the end of June. Period. End of story. As you heard, I think &#x2013; I don't know if you were here earlier. The Board has asked me to stay on and drive the results that we need. So, you are not going to see any lessening of intensity on the delivery here and I think that, you'll have a management team that minus one person, they will be able to answer the question &#x2013; the same question that you'll ask in August.</p>
          <p>In terms of the '010 numbers, these are numbers that not just management have signed up for, it's the Board as well. And everybody is committed to making sure that we drive these numbers. Now the most important thing, when we talk about free cash flow, when we talk about EBITDA margins, when we talk about the top-line growth as kind of the front and center objectives.</p>
          <p>We have all kinds of cost take-out work that John has covered a year-ago in November, last November in terms of cost take-out initiatives that are part of our transformation. The whole series of initiatives around growth driven by our call centers, driven by our retail front store &#x2013; the T[life] stores. And so, I would just say to you Ian that because I leave, doesn't mean that those things won't be done. They're already identified, they're tagged, they've got people, they've got dates, they've got actual numbers in delivery, and John and the whole senior leadership team that's here, very well aware of it and that's part of their set of targets, not only for this year but also for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Sol.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sol. It's Phil Campbell from Citigroup. I was just wanting to get some insight from you, how you might change running the business over the next 12 months or so even though you are leaving but just how, some of the plans you are going to put in place. With this slowing economic environment, I'm just interested to see how you might mitigate some of the accelerated decline in the fixed line business whether or not you may look at possibly doing some brand segmentation, introducing a second or third brand at the lower levels, maybe some other things you might be doing on costs and possibly also CapEx just as we go into a tougher economic environment, that would be useful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, number one I think you will see in particular in consumer because that's the biggest part of our revenue stream. You are going to actually see some acceleration in how we think of our revenue second half versus first half. But you're going to see some initiatives specifically targeted around PSTN. Now when we talk about PSTN, we always need to segment the two big drivers of PSTN, one is the access lines, the physical elements and there we're doing fine. It's the call volumes that have dropped off, and that's you can go to almost any country now and you will see that kind of significant drop off.</p>
          <p>So, we needed a lot of ways that we can stimulate more calling, ways that we can terminate more calls on a network, ways that we can encourage customers to take advantage of the capabilities both on our fixed and our mobile platforms. And I think you'll start seeing some of that show up in some of our advertising. You'll see some of it show up in terms of what we're doing in our call centers and what we are doing at our retail stores as part of the experience that we're going to encourage customers in terms of their use.</p>
          <p>And I would say that there are other things I'm not going to talk about, because of competitive sensitivities, but we have a whole set of strategies around this as well that you'll see unfold as the year progresses. So again whether I'm standing up on the stage or not, there's lot of work going on behind the scenes literally as we speak that our team here is driving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you consider a multi-brand strategy going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My reaction to multi-brands is that, that is not part of a character of Telstra and part of the strategy that we have here. It's always about differentiation and not being what I call a low-end price based competitor. I think we can grow it by adding value by differentiating and by stimulating behavior that we haven't done for a while. And again you are going to see some of this starting to play out literally within the next week or two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on the cost side, I mean, we are obviously locking down hard on areas of our costs. But as you've heard us today, we are not cutting back on investing, where it generates revenue. So I hope we're still investing in the T[life] stores and front-of-house sales and so on. So, yes, we are doing things that other companies are doing to make sure that we're very, very tight on costs but not to the detriment of the revenue line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark McDonnell from BBY. Two questions, firstly, Telstra Clear, performance continues to deteriorate. I realize there are some currency impacts in that, but no sign of any real turnaround. And Sol a couple of years ago, I asked you about this and the gap between rhetoric and reality around the maintenance of underperforming businesses. So I'm wondering if you could update us on your expectations for that business &#x2013; pardon me, and whether or not retaining presence in New Zealand with a business that's perennially under performing is in the best interests of the company and the shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think the answer I'll give you today is similar to the one I gave you a couple of years ago. In terms of the strategic portion of Trans-Tasman capabilities for some of our major costumers is still there. It's not any different today than it was before, it actually becomes more critical in terms of how customers are looking to integrate and simplify their platforms not only in Australia but also in New Zealand or not only in New Zealand but also in Australia. That need is more imperative if you talk to some of our enterprise customers. So that's hasn't changed.</p>
          <p>Number two, in terms of the numbers, obviously, the New Zealand business has not been a growth engine for us but it is not cash flow drag or it is not earnings drag it's basically been a business that has not performed at a high ROI level but it's performed adequately given the context of what we need to do for the strength of our core domestic business here.</p>
          <p>Right now we are getting impacted in New Zealand just like we are in Australia and other places regarding the economy, the downturn, lowered spending, slowdown in spending et cetera, so the focus continues and I can tell you that we do have our reviews, but I think there is a finite amount that you can do when you're a reseller and you don't have the broad-based platform of asset ownership. And we have made some investments there, where we have invested infrastructure, the returns look better. But at the end of the day that has not been kind of the priority of the company and the team. To divest at this stage still doesn't make sense for us to just simply because of the Trans-Tasman requirements that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it fair to assume from that answer that you don't believe the changes in industry structure and regulation in New Zealand significantly improve the prospects for Telstra Clear?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well to be quite frank, we still aren't clear on all of the outcomes of regulatory settings and pricing and terms and conditions and some of the issues there. We keep on waiting and I think it's now been at least a two-year process of getting clarity. And these things have to work themselves through. That's &#x2013; that's &#x2013; some people think it's easy to just make a decision and do paper math, but building out an infrastructure, building out correlating policy, setting the right tariffs and all that is a very complex process. They're not there yet. And so we're not going to over invest in something that we're not clear on in terms of what the real settings are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll just make one other comment about Telstra Clear. I mean our objective is to improve the bottom line. So I mean the EBITDA is quite positive but the EBIT line is marginal, right. And we're doing things to like bringing or integrating some of the functions back here to Australia. So for example, the payroll for the Telstra Clear people pay is &#x2013; the administration is out of Australia, the audit function, some of the finance functions are all brought back to Australia. So we're just trying to get that business as lean and mean in our operation sense -- operation &#x2013; operating sense as possible. That's what we're trying to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my other question relates to capital management. I know that you've held the dividend constant at $0.14. That's against 15.5 EPS. The cash outflow impact of the $0.14 is 1.7 billion and you've got a free cash flow of 1.9. So I'm wondering, given the confident reaffirmation of the six to seven billion forward-looking projection and the additional capacity that exists in the results that you've just announced, what the attitude is to returning more cash to shareholders, who have been held at these levels now for some years and more broadly, what the capital management policies are for Telstra given the likelihood of very strong free cash flow in the year ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I just to address the first point as a matter of a technical point. Yes, $1.7 billion dividend; yes, 1.9 free cash, but I've got $632 million interest bill there right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, the answer is that we're obviously very confident of the transformation plan and getting to those free cash flow levels. And as we've said all along, when we reach that point in time at the end of this fiscal year, again the Board will be able to sit down and look at what's possible in terms of rewarding shareholders for their ownership of the stock. I'm not forecasting or predicting any behavior at this stage, but our job has been to give the Board lots of options and flexibility and capacity. And I think that's what's happening and as we've said all along during this, the Board has been very focused on shareholder returns and there will be a point in time, when the right time the Board looks at this and says we think we can do X, Y or Z. And beyond that I won't say much more. But, I think the calculation of lots of free cash, gives Boards lots of options.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Laurent Horrut, sorry, JPMorgan. So I understand from your comments you're saying you're not engaged with any conversation with the government anymore on NBN. Do you have any visibility at all in terms of what maybe in the making in terms of where the government is going to be thinking NBN model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually I don't. I mean, again I don't spend a lot of time, worrying about it, thinking about it because as you've probably heard me say before Laurent, customers decide who they do business with. Customers make the purchase decisions regardless of what governments or regulators say. Now as David Quilty said in his speech two days ago. We're open to a call. We're open to conversation. And what I mean by that is just, this has being something we think, we could do &#x2013; we could do well. But, again we don't know the process it's been very protected, quite process and we respect the process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Isn't that just a worry, just in &#x2013; in a sense that here's a $5 billion investments with government putting major investment, major money into it and that's going to define the economics of this business for the next 10 years. And Telstra the incumbent operator in Australia has no visibility whatsoever on this process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Laurent there is a &#x2013; I'm sure you lived around the world and looked at other places around the world. There are lots of examples of paper processors that never work out in reality. The degree of difficulty of building, the degree of difficulty of financing, the great degree of difficulty of operating, those are variables that on paper get way under estimated.</p>
          <p>It takes time to build, it takes time to engineer, it takes time to construct, it takes time to turn out, it takes time to win customers and as you progress saw in a speech I gave in January, we estimated impacts and they're dramatically different than any impacts that you've estimated because you've got a what I call a very optimistic view of what people can do, or we do as we look at what reality is and degree of difficulty.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just another question, were you a bit surprised at the level of cycle in the business and the magnitude of the slowdown since the Investor Day? At the Investor Day you sort of gave confident sort of &#x2013; the message was reasonably optimistic although you did flag there were some softness. Were you surprised by the magnitude of that slowdown since that point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again as you said we flagged it pretty clearly back then that as of &#x2013; at that point it was September reporting period and we had not seen a lot of impact. But as we have all seen now looking across all industries whether it be banking, retail, construction whatever here in Australia, everybody has hit the wall in this last period of time, which is why we said, we will always be prudent in terms pf how we give guidance. At that point of time, we weren't changing, didn't have enough data. Now we have, as John pointed out and I pointed out, we have a pretty significant drop in PSTN calling and as you know that's a profitable part of &#x2013; disproportionately profitable part of our business. Can we do things about it? I think we can, and you'll see us executing around that. But it's hit us like it's hit every other company around the world.</p>
          <p>Okay. Ian before we go to you, we have some calls on the phone or on the line here, so I'm going to ask the operator to give me one of those calls.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a question from Christian Guerra, Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning and thanks for your time and congratulations on the results. I have just three questions for you this morning, Sol and John. Firstly I guess onto some of the IT transformation you've made some comments during the presentation about some issues during the period with the call center volumes and higher than usual customer queries et cetera, et cetera. Just wondering is there any change to the targets in terms of customer migration, cost savings, platforms, switch-offs, et cetera?</p>
          <p>My second question is on the guidance of fiscal '10. Again you've said in the presentation today that some things happened in the period that surprised you and clearly the macro is one of those. Just wondering if you could still sit on to how much conservatism or fat you've actually built into those targets.</p>
          <p>And my third question is actually a question for you Sol on your departure. Just wondering I guess how you thought about that, in terms of the timing given that you've basically done the hard work I think over the last three years and really the benefits start coming through in the next couple of years and I guess it's a little bit surprising that you're not going to be there to deliver those fiscal '10 numbers in August, next year. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Christian, regarding the call center volumes and all the associated questions on, does this impact what we communicated back in November of this year and November of last year the answer is no. Are there delays in terms of our systems? The answer is no. So, let me just take a little bit of time and explain again what &#x2013; when we talk about what's happened in the bubble here of call volumes that affected our channels.</p>
          <p>It's not about systems, I talked about 200 plus million records that we're processing everyday and the million &#x2013; tens of millions of bills and other things. Systems are working fine. What happens is that, if you are a customer and you're used to quarterly bills, and you now get a monthly bill, it's different. And so what happens is that stimulates calls and call volumes. I said this I think back in November, that what happens is that in my experience because I have done this twice before is that you go through a cycle of two or three bill periods, where customers are calling and you get accelerated volumes into channels.</p>
          <p>The second thing is, is that we changed our bill formats, so when you are migrating six, seven million customers on to a new platform and there is new bill format. A percentage of those customers then have questions. And what happens then is that they call into our call centers, and they start filling up what you normally staff for in terms of the volumes. We anticipated some of that, not to say that we didn't forecast for some of that increased volume. But what happens is, is that if you have an acceleration of call volume and a customer calls in at a certain point of time, and the average speed of answer is low and you're on hold for a while, you'll generally hang up and you'll call back again. And if you hit at another peak period you'll generally hang up and call back again. So what happens is that you go through this, this period of time where you've got a lot of accelerated call volumes and you don't have essentially enough capacity to handle it till you work it through.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately, I don't know of any other way because I've, like I said, I've done this twice before, you just work through it in two or three bill cycles. Customers get used to it, they get their bills explained, they understand it and then you move on. And that's the way it works.</p>
          <p>So as I said before, we're now on the other side of it. We've climbed the kind of the high end of it and now we're working through the other way. We have other migrations. We have another major release that's coming in this half. And we have some other big releases in the latter part of the year as we articulated back in November. So all of that work continues, all the migration work continues as we talked about back in November. And the retirement of systems, Christian to your part of your question that will continue. We've retired over 400 systems already, 450 or so. We've already retired a whole large number and we're going to continue to retire more. But not all the cost take out is just at the very end. We've got cost take out as we reduce volumes, as we reduce some other work and attention that goes on to these legacy systems.</p>
          <p>So that's all still in train and that's part of what I said, Tom Lamming, John McInerney, they've got tagged, they've got a whole work plan around that and you just have to work through that. So none of that essentially changes.</p>
          <p>In terms of your question about &#x2013; I won't use the word "fat" &#x2013; in your &#x2013; the '10 objectives because we don't build fat into targets. It's a best view that we have. We are &#x2013; we have been pretty optimistic about stimulating growth which back in '05 Christian you may remember most people were skeptical about the growth rates that we said we were going to generate and what the consensus view at that point of time, which was about negative one or negative 2% growth over the period of time; we've generated that.</p>
          <p>As we look at the cost side and the cost take out, we believe that we have plenty of opportunity to take out more costs. We've now achieved the 10,000 &#x2013; we've crossed over the 10,000 threshold in terms of FTE reduction that we talked about, 10 to 12,000. It was a point of discussion at our Investor Day. Some people asked the question, are you backing off of your targets? because we reminded everybody of 10 to 12,000. Well, we've now crossed over 10,000. We've got more to go. There will be more that will happen as part of a plan that's underway.</p>
          <p>So the long answer to your &#x2013; or shortening the answer to your question, Christian, about FY '10 is the management team has very specific targets about how to get to these numbers, not to say that it won't be difficult, not to say that people aren't going to be working hard, to get to there but we think that they're achievable. Can a horrible economy, if we go into a true recession, depression kind of environment, would that change some of the guidance and some of the views? The answer is absolutely. But that's not part of our view at this stage.</p>
          <p>And then in terms of the final part, your departure, wouldn't it be nice to stick around til when all the fruits of all the labor are there? The answer is yes, but that was never part of the plan at least for me personally; my family and I think the Board understood that. We just reached the point yesterday, where as we talked and as we sat down and we visited about, when is the right time. I and the Board both felt, now is the best time to make that transition.</p>
          <p>I want to give the Board enough time to find the right successor, to go through the right process and also that we don't lose any momentum while they're doing that. And as I said, earlier in one of the other answers, the Board is as committed to hitting the numbers as anybody. So, continuity, focus, none of that changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to clarify on the fiscal target there. I think John said in the presentation, on the fiscal '10 targets. John mentioned that, you're now expecting to come in at the lower end of the target. So that's &#x2013; so we should interpret that as being wholly and solely due to the softening macro environment and as opposed to any sort of the reduction in your cost out targets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's exactly right, Christian. I had to take into account the softening. So, that's why I say they're at the low end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll take another question on the calls and then we'll go back to Ian here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question is from Sameer Chopra, Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning gentleman. I had two questions, if I may. The first one, any further room for head count saves, seeing as you've already hit your transformation targets for 2010, and congratulations on that. And the second one is your guidance, are we still aiming for 5 to $800 million of cost out in the OpEx line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the head count, the answer is yes, that's why we set the target of 10 to 12000. We think that there is more that will come naturally and what I mean by naturally is, is that we talked in terms of full time equivalents. And we do a lot of contracting, we do a lot of other work that's been part of our transformation and a lot of that work will go away as we turn up systems and as we shut down systems and that will be part of the story. Part of the story will be productivity, continued productivity increases and again last time you've heard us talk about our field force productivity improvements of being nearly 50% over the last three years. And I think you're going to see some pretty dramatic productivity improvements as we go forward in the front-end of the business as well.</p>
          <p>In terms of the cost out, the 500 to 800, the answer is absolutely because John, a year-ago in November, and then this past November, spent time trying to help everybody understand how we get to these EBITDA margins and the free cash flows are cost structure points that we want to get to. So the answer to that is simply, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, one of the reasons for that question was, with the retail Aussie dollars I was wondering whether that was impacting input costs, particularly cost of good sold?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, not to a large extent, the big thing impacting out cost of goods and this has worked I think to our benefit, this year as you heard John go through the numbers. The volumes on handset sales are down dramatically because we had the big migration from CDMA to Next G, over the last year and half or so. And we've gone past that peak and now we are into another era where we're going to back to these questions about driving voice, driving more ARPU, the growth, we are into another era of the migration now where we're going to see a lot more smart phone sales, we are going to see a lot more usage that gets driven off of that, we have lots of great data. We talk a lot about iPhones, we talk a lot about Blackberry Bolds, though we can also talk about our HTC products and other products that are out there, that are driving a lot of usage, so COGS is affected to some extent but not to a great extent, so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions Sol. First, is there any evidence yet the -- or perhaps indications that the growth in wireless broadband is having an effect on fixed broadband, subscriber numbers or revenues. And secondly, just want to explore the margin in Sensis and what's its impact is on the overall group's long-term margin trend. A couple of years ago, Sensis margins, EBITDA margins about 50%, were above the group level? They've fallen to 45%, fallen 330 basis points in the last year. Still above the group level, but I think one of you said that online margins were trending up which suggest the print margins are trending down and perhaps the two meet somewhere in the middle around 40%. That will be below the group margin next year then.</p>
          <p>First of all, that's bit of a drag isn't it on the long term margin trend if Sensis margins are heading down that's 7 or 8% of revenue. And secondly, isn't kind of symptomatic of what's happening generally that we are moving more into this online world where the cost structure is more complex, there is more content cost and complexity and so on. That doesn't -- what is happening in Sensis perhaps presage what's going to happen in the wider business in terms of the margin trend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No actually, Ian. I think it's important to look back a couple of years ago as you did. But I understand why, the margin has gone down you know. Part of what we went through was a period of time when our print business was in decline. And Bruce and the team and myself, we kind of made a decision that we need to kind of regenerate, and reinvigorate that business. So Bruce undertook what he called Project Morph, which is kind of -- kind of IT transformation of the business that enables a different experience but also enables cost take out. That's ahead of Bruce in terms of his operating plan. And what I mean is timeframe wise. We also invested in some additional distribution of books, and other capabilities out in the market, opening up local offices so that we can compete more effectively given the kinds of margins that we generate, so if anything our margins are going to be going up. If you look at the aggregate numbers of Sensis they really bias downward by a couple of businesses and whether it would be Trading Post, which we've talked about before and the mapping business. And then obviously the new addition on the China businesses which as they grow, they will get to scale. But I think the interesting point to your question about online, is it our online businesses are generating higher margins than what you see in the broader industry. A long answer, short answer is now; I think that margins will continue to be healthy in the business. We're just going through again an investing period and a changing the mix where that's had some dilution for a point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And wireless broadband? Is it having an effect on fixed broadband subscription?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, Ian in terms of wireless broadband. I probably can't stand here and say that there isn't some impact in terms of substitution because there probably is with certain segments. But in terms of having a material change in terms of our view with the business, the answer is no. If you look at fixed, what we've now reached is about a 60% penetration point. But we had a lot of growth over the last three, four years in terms of that fixed portion of the market. The wireless side is now new and it's exciting and we keep on making it more exciting with more speed, more throughput and a better experience.</p>
          <p>So you're going to see growth rates on wireless broadband being much higher than on fixed, as the market continues to evolve. And then its going to become once penetration levels get probably in a year to two years much higher, then you're going to see what I would call, how do you keep on growing at ARPU, on it? much like which you see with us and what we do on our fixed broadband which is continuing to grow ARPU.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. Two questions if I may. The first one is given that you may need to accelerate your broadband rollout and consequently the capital required, how tangible do you believe your 2010 cash flow protections will be in light of what you've communicated to the government as being the required capital to invest?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, one of the points that we have made consistently from three years ago was that our free cash flow, our CapEx estimates or targets were always asterisked, you know subject to whatever happens with broadband, what we now call NBN. So if for example, we &#x2013; the government called up and said, hey, we are interested in hearing your thoughts about how the broadbandize Australia and et cetera, et cetera. And we said, okay, here's our thoughts. We'd probably invest up to $5 billion. You're talking about lets say, a plus or minus $1 billion a year of additional CapEx which would reduce the free cash flow and would increase whatever CapEx forecast that we've given to this point in time. And we've said that now for three years and that hasn't changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, my point is given that you're out and you need to maintain a competitive network moving forward, would that not necessitate, you spending additional CapEx ahead of your 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we already have the best network in Australia. We already have the leading market position in Australia. So, I'm not as worried about that because the degree of difficulty of what is being suggested by others we'll deal with given our wireless platform, given our HFC platform, given the ADSL platform we already have in place plenty of options. And the good news is a big portion of the infrastructure is already there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a last question, are you indicating a significant change in your channel strategy by following a road map or start to draw the analogy commander by rolling out your own stores on an expansive basis and if so, what might be the down sides to your channel partners?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm not going to talk in any detail about what our strategy is because as you have hopefully seen over the last three or four years, we don't talk too much about what we're going to do, we just do it and then let everybody understand what we've done competitively. But we are very sensitive to our relationships with the partners that we have. And I think David Moffatt and his team are working hard at finding the right strategies that work both for Telstra and the partners. And you will see some of that play out during the year. And like I said, you'll see it play out and then we'll explain what we did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Another call, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a question from Mark Blackwell, Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, just further to your early comments of the slowdown occurring really in the later part of the half. I'm wondering if you could confirm that it was sort of that latter part and what that implies for the second half? And secondly just, I note your guidance for revenue growth is retained and just given your comments on the economic outlook, I'm a bit surprised by that. I felt like there might be some softness in the top line as well as in the EBIT. So if could just comment on those two issues, that would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let John took this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What I said was yes in the latter part of the half, but I also said we have now six weeks trading and that hasn't changed from the last part of the first half. So, the first -- the latter part of the first half, the first six weeks of trading this year, suggest to us that there is a softening of the revenue and where I said it is, fixed voice and mobile voice. To your other question and I'll try to explain this also that we expected revenue fundamentally in the top end of the growth range and now we expect them in the lower end of the growth range and when you are talking about $26 billion business, this 1% is 260 million, so that's why we haven't changed the guidance on the top line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I would just add one other thing that this issue of volumes that I described a minute ago, we tied up a lot of our selling capacity by just simply answering calls. Now that we are on the other side of that, we are going to free up more capacity for outbound and inbound on the sale side, so the good news for our competitors was that there were some consumption of our capacity and the bad news is, look out, we are coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I look forward to some sales Telstra then. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question is from Sachin Gupta, Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. I have three questions. Firstly, I think John, I'm not sure if you've talked about this, but can you quantify how much are you factoring in for one off costs for the bushfires and the floods? And my second question is I think John, I think you mentioned that there will some further accelerated depreciation for Hong Kong CSL in the second half, I was wondering if you can quantify that place and if I recall I think you said there would be no more accelerated depreciation after the first half. I'm just wondering why is that continuing? And my third question is if you look at the PSTN retail revenues that's appears to be declining now its down 2%, But it seems to be driven more from lower usage rather than lower access lines. I was wondering is that a risk going forward and what are you factoring in your guidance, please. Thanks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, let me take the last one first because its probably the easier one. Yes, it is usage, that is impacting our view of the guidance and I think we saw that quite a few times. When you're a Telstra customer in economic hard times what can you control? You can control how you use the services as distinct from the cost of access and so on. So that in fact is what's happening. With respect to the costs of floods and fires and so on, what I did say was it's already in the tens of millions. So it's not huge numbers. There will be some capital requirement and there will be some expense requirement. So tens of millions of dollars with respect to that. With CSL New World accelerated depreciation and, yes, the network is taking a little longer to build in Hong Kong than we anticipated and so, therefore the accelerated depreciation has been spread over a longer period of time. You might say, well, that means it should be lower. But we've also have the FX impact on top of that which is unfortunately taken the advantage of it being spread over a bit of the longer period. So it now will go into the second half and with the impact of the FX difference that's being taken in to account. The guidance and what I said about second half it's about $70 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Can I just ask another question on guidance, then, if you to look at past results back in August, we had CapEx increase, no extra EBITDA growth slowing down, margins were still at 42%. Transformation still not complete, NBN is still pending. So I was wondering against this backdrop and given what we are asking in the macro-environment as well. How confident can one be with the 2010 guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I guess, we're pretty confident in the sense that the things that we can control, which are costs. We've got basically everything tagged, everything binding, by date, by a lot of things internally. So that's the big part of what you going to see on EBITDA margins improvement right. We have communicated that, and that's what management can control. We can control -- some of the macro-economic variables and issues there. That's why John said we're looking at the lower end of our revenue guidance, but on the cost out. We know where it is, we know how to find it, we know how to get it. And I think that's where, we stand here today and say yes we're pretty confident about the 6 to $7 billion on free cash and EBITDA margins. And if it turns out that our guidance on EBITDA margins is 46 to 48 and we hit 45.7, right now we have at the margins that we were out today we are the best in the world. And very few companies in the world that are getting better EBITDA margins are going forward. So we think there is a relatively high degree of confidence here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>-- Sachin Gupta: Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay I think. We have one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your last question is from David Kane, Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's actually Alice Bennett here. Just I guess following on from pervious questions on guidance for FY'10, I understand you've got planned cost out as a part of the whole restructuring program but just wondering what capacity you have to cut discretionary costs, such as advertising or may be pulling back on, on handset subsidies, if we do have a more severe revenue downturn if the economy deteriorates faster. Could you talk a little bit about the discretionary costs that you could pull in order to maintain that guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we look at every cost line so -- we look at initiatives in a macro sense, but we look at right down to every line item and as I mentioned earlier, as you would expect us in even in this '08 '09 year, due to the impact of the economic climate, we're bearing down on all those sort of discretionary costs. And we'll continue to do that into the fiscal '09'10 as well. So, yes we will and we're doing it this year right now and we will continue to do so in '09 '10</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We don't have any more questions online. We don't have anymore questions here. So let me just close by number one, reiterating the fact that the guidance that we're giving for '10, we have a lot of confidence relative to the fact that the driver variable there is going to be cost out and that's what management controls. The management team, the whole management team not just Sol, not just Sol and John, but the whole management team is very focused on delivering that and everybody has got their assignments and they're are all communicated and they're all very clear.</p>
          <p>The second thing in terms of the growth, we're showing that this wireless business is a very strong business. We're showing that broadband continues to be part of the strength of this company. We're continuing to grow in terms of our Sensis advertising related portfolio of businesses. And that as we look at our enterprise side of the business we continue to grow there as well because of the differentiation that we built. There's no question, no question whether it be on the consumer side, the enterprise side, small, medium business side, customers really do have a distinct choice and that's what competing and winning is really about. So, now it's about execution and to some of the questions between now and the end of the year, Ian there's no question about focus. There is no question about delivering in terms of what we've said today and what we have said in the past and that will be part of the story, that the management team reports next up or in August of this year.</p>
          <p>So thank you all for coming and we'll be talking to you. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>