<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1284808" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1549</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Ben Spincer, Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David Thodey, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John V. Stanhope, B Com (Economics and Accounting), FCPA, FCA, FAICD, FAIM, Chief Financial Officer and Group Managing Director, Finance and Administration</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Sameer Chopra</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Justin Milne</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Christian Guerra</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Ian Martin</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Sachin Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Fraser McLeish</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Mark Blackwell</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Andrew Levy</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Good morning, everyone. My name is Ben Spincer, Head of Investor Relations at Telstra. I'd like to welcome you to this &#x2013; results for the half year through December 2009. In a moment I'll hand over to our CEO who will run you through the results. I also welcome for those listening on the phone and also the webcast for using the BigPond's TV Platform for the webcast this half year which I hopefully will provide a very good quality experience for those on the webcast.</p>
          <p>After David and John have run you through the results, we will be taking some questions both from here and Sydney and also from the phone lines.</p>
          <p>Without further ado, I will hand over to Telstra's CEO, Mr. David Thodey. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning everybody and good morning especially for those who are coming on our webcast. Glad to have you here and thank you, Ben.</p>
          <p>Well, it has been a challenging six months and on many fronts for the company. However, as I'll give you the six monthly results on the half year, we remain very optimistic about the business. The demand for our products and services do remain very strong. The key challenge we are facing is how we really drive value from that incredible demand.</p>
          <p>So as we finish the half, while we have not achieved revenue targets, I am pleased to report a number of strong results. Free cash flow very strong. We have managed our expenses well, which is very important as we have come out of the transformation. Margins are strong, which has been good, and EBIT has improved.</p>
          <p>Also, while we still got a lot of work to do around customer service, which is so important for us, we are feeling that we are making progress, so it's still early days and we've got a lot of work to do. But this is a multi-year project. This is not going to be something we can fix very quickly.</p>
          <p>I'm also pleased to announce today that we have been able to maintain our dividend of $0.14 per share, fully franked, and also we're also confident of meeting our core objectives, which I talked about as we came into the year, of $6 billion of free cash flow for 2010 fiscal year. So that's what I'll do today, is to talk about our results, then give you a little bit of color about the initiatives we're taking as we go into the second half, and of course, give you an update on NBN. But first, the results.</p>
          <p>So I know the release has already gone out, but let me just run you through this. Sales revenue decline of 2.5% at the top line, operating expenses declined by 4.8%, and EBITDA margins expanded as we moved from the transformation program. We're driving out the value from that initiative that we've done over the last few years. Now, on an adjusted basis &#x2013; now, adjusted basis means if you take out KAZ, also the currency movements, which have impacted us, which I talked about on investor day, and also the fair value adjustments, which I think more accurately gives you some feel for the underlying performance of the business.</p>
          <p>We achieved a decline of 0.7% on the sales revenue. We had good expense management of 2.1, because KAZ had a big clear space. EBITDA grew 0.2% and profit after-tax was 13%. So they were strong results. Now, John is going to take you through more of the color of that in a moment. I'm going to give you sort of the broad-brush feel for the business.</p>
          <p>Now as I said, free cash flow is still going strong, $2.6 billion generated this half, which is an increase of $708 million compared to the first half of last fiscal year. So we're on track for that $6 million target. But I do want to stress, we're generating this free cash not at the expense of the existing business. Our CapEx to sales ratio is still running at 13% for the half. I want to stress this because we must continue to invest in this company, and new products and services as we go forward.</p>
          <p>So we're not generating free cash flow by stopping investment, and that will be a very, very important part of our strategy as well. But let me give you a little bit more insight into these results, because I think the top line -- I think it's very important that we can sort of get down a little and say, hey, what's really going on.</p>
          <p>Now, there's no question, there is lot of changes going on in our market, and if you look at our broadband and our mobile business, we definitely lost share in broadband and in mobile SIOs. So that is a concern, but that's being done trying to manage profitability, and this is sort of a bit strategic balance that we're trying to work through at the company.</p>
          <p>So if you look at the product performances, let's just quickly touch on them. Firstly, PSTN. Negative charge on $22 million year-on-year. Now, this is unquestionably our immediate challenge, because what we're seeing is an acceleration in our PSTN revenue decline, and that's started from six months ago, but also in the last two months. And this is some of the immediate burning platform for us. Fixed retail broadband was up $11 million, mobile was up 145 million. Advertising and directories was down 53, and I'll talk a little bit more about them, because Sensis continues to perform well in a very tough market.</p>
          <p>In summary, our growth in mobiles and fixed broadband is not offsetting that PSTN decline and that's what we keep having to try to balance as we go forward.</p>
          <p>So let's look at what we think are the key drivers of this change. Now, as we talked about, I think, probably last October-November, there is still very strong competition, but mostly it's price-led.</p>
          <p>Now if you look at what the average price movements have been over the last year, we've seen quite a lot of cost reductions across a wide range of products. For example, in wireless broadband, there has been a decline of about 30%. This is on average, or round about. ADSL has been down about 20%, and that's 15% roughly for postpaid. Now these are market moves. And so we have to remain competitive while truly differentiating our product and making sure we are selling value.</p>
          <p>We'll talk a bit about PSTN later on, but there has been a significant decline in voice calling, and we want to get &#x2013; take you through a little color on that. And of course, we are seeing the broadband market maturing in terms of penetration. And we'll show you some statistics around that as well. We are seeing the number of households that have fixed broadband actually starting to peak up a bit and then starting to flatten until the new people coming on.</p>
          <p>But what's important for us is how we respond to these changes, and we've been putting new offers into the market over the last few months. So we've put bundled offers out there, which have done very well. I'll be talking some more about that. New wireless broadband pricing has been very well received, and of course in fixed broadband, we put some new pricing plans out there, as well. And we're very pleased with the early response we've received from the market.</p>
          <p>But what we witnessed, and it just took us too long to get to the market with the new offers. So it was December and January before we got out there, and that has probably stopped a little bit of momentum we were expecting. But we do believe that these offers will improve our competitiveness, and it will allow us to see revenue growth, but that revenue growth may take a while to flow through.</p>
          <p>So let's talk about how these changes have impacted the retail business units because what's happened is the PSTN decline has flowed through to all the retail facing business units. Consumer's down 0.2%, business is down 0.4%, enterprise headline decline is 1.6, but if you take out the international portfolio, then they're actually up 0.3. Wholesale was down 3.3, Sensis is down 7.3, but that's on a reported basis. On adjusted basis, it was just sort of roughly flat and you see quite a strong result.</p>
          <p>Now the retail business units, I am not happy with that, and I have already taken a number of actions. TC and the consumer group as I said put these bundles out there. Since we announced those new products, we've had 80,000 new customers which is very encouraging. I should say 80,000 new bundles, not necessarily new customers. That would be misleading.</p>
          <p>Telstra business is running out with the business center strategy, which is being very successful, and we are very pleased with that. We're also continuing with our aggressive rollout of the new shops, the two large shops. We're now at 133. And we are very pleased with the response we are getting from the market from the two large shops, and they really do generate more sales, and we are very pleased with how they are performing.</p>
          <p>Enterprise and Government have been focused on driving value from the big contracts we have signed over the last two years. CBA, New South Wales department of education, <mark type="inaudible" />. They really now have to focus on driving this. Once you sign these contracts, you've still got to drive the value out, get the revenue flying, but we are making good progress here.</p>
          <p>Sensis is doing well. They are focused on the online and mobile advertising business as a real growth engine for the future. And I am pleased to say that the IT systems and the transformation there has gone well. We're sort of through the tough bit, we think, and I'm very pleased with the progress there. So that Sensis has been going through their own transformation.</p>
          <p>So we really do have a large number of actions going on in the market and we're quite excited about the next few quarters.</p>
          <p>So let's now turn to the PSTN business which is &#x2013; as I said is our immediate challenge and we really do need to address this. The decline has been more severe and pronounced than they had anticipated.</p>
          <p>And as I said six months ago and even two months ago. Traditionally, they performed very well and you can see the historical performance there. But it has accelerated and I think there's been a number of reasons for that. And I'll take you through these now because it's important you understand what's going on in the market, there is about four key reasons.</p>
          <p>Firstly, voice traffic is down across all categories, now that's local, national long distance, international and fixed mobile, all decreased. So that's straight calling volumes. So that's a real change in terms of behavior going on in the market.</p>
          <p>Now the majority of that decline was in the local call category. Local call revenues down almost 13% and our customers are now making five least local calls to what they did just a year ago. That's quite a change on a monthly basis, quite a change.</p>
          <p>Subscribers were also down by 188,000 on retail, 22,000 on wholesale and that's been over the last six months. Now as well as that you've got the wholesale impacts with ULL and LSS subscribers.</p>
          <p>That now going into 72,000 ULL and 92,000 LSS subscribers over the past six months, so that's continues to be pretty steady as we see wholesale customers moving across. So the movement of subscribers and the lower usage has translated to our retail PSTN decline of 5.9% and wholesale is 14.2%, so you can see the dynamics going on in that business, so it's pretty important for us to really address this, and I'm &#x2013; that was part of the reason before just <mark type="inaudible" /> run the, now we called voice broadband and media division and he is very focused on how we can drive that portfolio of products out to maintain momentum as we go forward, so we are pleased with the early planning as we go forward and we think we can really make a difference. So that's the PSTN.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to the broadband market. We believe there is some maturing going on in this market and it is having an impact on our business. There is a chart that shows while broadband market share has declined, we think the entire broadband market growth has slowed as you've got the 65% penetration level for homes in Australia.</p>
          <p>If you look at the numbers were seen reported it seems to confirm that there is a slide, and that has been seen right across the world and in some ways the wireless proposition <mark type="inaudible" /> going to see some substitution in terms of the fixed broadband market, now the percentage of homes also who now have no fixed line at all is getting close to 10% and we talked a bit about that in the Investor Day briefing, and this is sort of in line with overseas experience. We do expect this to increase over time. But the underlying demand for our product does remain strong and so we need to capitalize on that as we move forward. And so we remain very positive about the broadband business, we think that the media working with PSTN <mark type="inaudible" /> does create a very strong value proposition for our customers.</p>
          <p>So the big question is how we're going to return the growth, because negative turn on half top line does not look good and that's not where we want to be. But we have taken a number of actions and we remain positive about the business going forward. But I want to stress it firstly, the real foundation here that we must have is good customer service, going on and acquiring customers not give any good customer service experience is not acceptable. And we're pleased to see the early signs of an improvement in that area, but we've got to keep going, because without that it's really not worth driving too much growth, because then we get a disadvantage experience and we must be able to retain our customers.</p>
          <p>Now secondly, as I mentioned we are driving out a number of new initiatives that really should address some of these key factors. In terms of PSTN, we've got some great new and innovative products coming to market both across the business market and also the consumer market. The T-Hub which is this new home phone will be available in the market shortly and the T-Box as well which is a <mark type="inaudible" /> broadband TV experience and we really want to push that hard because we really need to add values to that experience to differentiate as we move forward.</p>
          <p>And as I mentioned the bundles have been a great response to the market requirements and we think that they will continue to be strong. Mobile is an important part of our growth strategy, and I'll take you through that in more detail in the next chart. And of course IP continues to be at the heart of our growth in the enterprise space and now growing into the business space. IP is a very critical product, there is the hallmark it moves to an IP world. And the next IP platform is a wonderful platform and we have seen good strong growth, we had revenue growth of 21% in that category, and we are very pleased with that. And we think we can do more in that area as we move forward.</p>
          <p>And then of course meter and online assets remain very important for us, and we think there are some good strong growth opportunities there across our channel asset Sensis and Telstra Media. So as we focus on these things, we must also focus on good type cost management, so we can deliver on our commitments to our investors.</p>
          <p>So let's turn to the mobiles business, I'll give you some view where we see that business now. There is two key parts for our strategy, we're seeing tremendous growth in the wireless broadband space, but we need to have new offers coming to market all the time. Let's just talk about those two, because these are the real pains of our growth strategy as we move forward.</p>
          <p>We've recently announced new product called enterprise mobile broadband +, which is a wonderful product, which is specific for the enterprise market, it provides security and many different functions. So now we &#x2013; what we have which is unlike many other operators, it's in fact the quite unique in the world, we have four different products ranging from the high end enterprise right down to prepaid wireless broadband experience.</p>
          <p>And so we're starting to differentiate the wireless broadband experience rather just calling it the wireless internet, we're really building unique products to just different market segments. And we think this is going to be a very powerful differentiator for us as we move forward and our sales teams are able to sell it. So very strong part of our strategy, good strong growth in this portfolio.</p>
          <p>But also we've seen some wonderful new opportunities in the wireless market. Firstly, smartphones, which now represent what's a little bit over million smartphones in the market. I'm pleased to say that the iPhone represents about 25% of those smartphones in the market; we're really building our momentum in that area. But there are large number of new products coming to market this year &#x2013; tablets, which you would have seen, but also machine-to-machine communication. So this whole market opportunity is very exciting.</p>
          <p>We also are excited about the new Android operating system, which will bring new product to market in a very near future. BigPond Wireless home network gateway product is a wonderful product and it's tied at household beyond the DSL footprint and that's been very well received and we are very pleased with that. And of course we have changed the structure of our plans with this is no excess usage. So that's being very well received, and as I mentioned before, we are starting to see some good movement as we move forward.</p>
          <p>So what does all this mean? Well, as we look at the full year, as I said, our biggest challenge is around the PSTN decline. And as we looked at our December and January results, we believe that the top line revenue is going to continue to be under pressure. So as we looked at that, while we're taking a large number of initiatives to really start to turn that around we don't think that will flow through quickly enough in this calendar year. So now we are expecting the low single digit growth in the revenue &#x2013; top line revenue reported sales for this year.</p>
          <p>Now the remainder of our guidance remains unchanged and we have worked through that, we think that is good guidance for now. And we will continue to focus on that top line growth. As I said earlier, we will continue to invest in the business; we must continue to do that as we expect accrued CapEx to sales revenue to be around 14%.</p>
          <p>We're also remained committed to our shareholders and we now are confirming our target of $6 million of free cash flow, which is very important to all round business. So that's the business. John is going to take you through little bit more color in the detail in a moment.</p>
          <p>But before I finish up I'd like to address where we're at in relation to the national broadband network. As I said in December, we've promised to give you an update and a large amount of work continues to be done.</p>
          <p>We remained very constructively engaged with both the government and NBN Co. and we do remain committed to try to find a mutually acceptable outcome. But I've got to stress, these are very complex considerations, very complex and we need to move slowly and very deliberately.</p>
          <p>So throughout these talks we've been &#x2013; as I've always said, looking at the best interest of our investors, our employees and our customers. So while we are making good constructive progress, we really &#x2013; that's about it for today in what we can say. We will continue to keep you updated, and as soon as we know what is &#x2013; anything that is of significance we will definitely announce it to you.</p>
          <p>Right, to conclude, let me try to bring this all together and go back to what I talked about is our core strategy in October. And this strategy remains unchanged and there were three main areas that we've focused on.</p>
          <p>Firstly, how do we manage these market dynamics which I talked about, and there is profitability versus revenue growth and market share. We need to keep these very carefully and balanced.</p>
          <p>Also, how we execute and respond quickly to competition, so we can really be fast to market and respond to any changes, and also the customer experience which is at the heart of what we do in terms of retaining and allowing our customers. So this is all about focusing on the core business, our network capabilities and our customers.</p>
          <p>This focus will lead us to profitable growth and create value for our shareholders. We remain confident that we're moving in the right direction. The direction we're taking we believe will make us more competitive in the market, and at the same time as operating &#x2013; our operation channel to driving productivity and also tight cost management. This remains an exciting industry with enormous opportunity. Now we need to go and address our topline growth and share opportunities. So, we're taking these actions to drive growth and we'll talk a bit more about that, and John will take you through the numbers now and I look forward to <mark type="inaudible" />, so John, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David, and good morning everybody in Sydney and elsewhere and wherever you might be viewing or listening to this presentation. It's not a good idea to correct your boss, but I did think he said low single-digit growth for revenue; it's low single-digit decline is the guidance. So look clearly, our topline is facing some challenges at the moment. But this half we also took another important step towards our key fiscal year 2010 free cash flow target.</p>
          <p>As David articulated, there is confidence, so we have the pathway to return to topline growth. So I just have to work with this, with more discussion on our retail unit's business performance. First, let me take you through the key numbers for the half on a reported basis. Sales revenue declined by a modest 2.5% to $12.3 billion or a decline of $321 million. And as we said in December, this reflects challenging conditions with strong domestic competition. It's driven by a growth of fixed and mobile broadband offers in the market, and of course, the ongoing impact of ULL and shared spectrum offers.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we've been impacted, as David mentioned, with increases in wireless-only homes, which have negatively impacted our PSTN and our fixed broadband businesses. And we do have some tough operating conditions in Hong Kong, and all this has been compounded by the strong Australian dollar impacting our revenues for our offshore entities. And lastly, of course, on a comparative basis, the revenue that was the there last <mark type="inaudible" /> is no longer this year and that has about $160 million impact in our business service category.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we reported OpEx has fallen 4.8% due to very strict, disciplined management of our cost base and the start of the realization of upgrade benefits which we would expect.</p>
          <p>EBITDA fell 0.3% or 78 million to $5.3 billion impacted by the change in the product mix, in particular as PSTN has declined as has been described to you. EBIT rose by 1.7% to $3.1 billion, a solid achievement given the intensely competitive Australian market and the continued revenue decline in the higher margin legacy products.</p>
          <p>Profit after tax and minorities was down 3.3% as reported financing cost increased due to the fair value adjustments and I'll talk a bit about that in a minute. <mark type="inaudible" /> free cash flow continued its very strong growth rising 37% to $2.6 billion. And finally as David said we've maintained our fully <mark type="inaudible" /> interim dividend at $0.14 per share.</p>
          <p>I just want to take you through really on an adjusted growth rates basis and it's important as it gives you a feel for the real performance of the business. So to be a clear, there is adjusted growth rates of only being normalized for the sale of KAZ business, FX fluctuations and lot of the EBIT line, the fair value adjustment included in the finance cost.</p>
          <p>So the magnitude of those adjustments is set at on the right hand side of this slide. After these adjustments are made the sales revenue declined by just $0.7% so fairly flat performance. And OpEx declined by 2.1% in the half, which is still a very good performance. So the adjusted EBITDA was marginally positive year-on-year and EBIT grew by 2%. After removing the fair value adjustment profit after tax and minorities was up 13%. So you can see the impact that the fair value adjustment has.</p>
          <p>A key driver therefore of the bottom line is $156 million reduction in borrowing costs in the half. I'll talk a little more about now. So our adjusted performance was resilient despite extremely tough comparative conditions and as David said the larger than expected, particularly in recent times the PSTN decline. We also had to navigate some continuing consequences over the IT transformation, including some limited outbound capacity in the channels and restrictions on price movements have to settle the market on some products until late in the period, a little later than expected, but they were conscious decisions we had to make. And we've faced very strong headwinds from a challenging product mix as the customer changed to emails and SMS away from the higher margin legacy fixed access and calling products, and that's the securities we are managing their in cost, so bottom line growth remains.</p>
          <p>Now moving onto our key products here you can see the slowdown from the second half of last year, in mobile service revenue growth is still healthy driven by mobile data and the mobile data growth was 21%. You all know we introduced new wireless broadband pricing last month, and we've also implemented new technology into our network to increase network speeds, which will translate into enhanced speeds for customers in selected locations when new compatible devices come to market later this year.</p>
          <p>There is also a significant growth potential for us from the exciting new smartphones that are emerging in the market and David mentioned some of the tablet devices. Fixed rate broadband and IPX's revenues are still growing admittedly at a slower pace than before, and David spoke a lot about IP at Investor Day and this portfolio continues to drive as we manage our customers, the migration of the customers from our legacy products on to the new IP platforms.</p>
          <p>The growth in those three categories was not enough to offset the revenue decline in PSTN, which fell 6.9%. The acceleration in the revenue decline has been driven by decline in customer numbers and calling substitution, as customers continue to switch to more email, SMS, mobile calls. As the indication, local calls declined by 325 million or four calls per line per month. David mentioned five, five was entitled, but most of them saw four calls per month in the local.</p>
          <p>Let me just now talk about the major business units quickly, Consumer, our Consumer segment faced the challenging first half with revenue declining as you saw by 0.2%. Within the Consumer segment PSTN revenues declined by 5%. A strong ULL growth and the accelerated move to wireless-only homes reduced the customer base &#x2013; the Consumer customer base. However, continued strong growth in wireless broadband customers and revenues contributed to a 5.5% increase in mobile services revenue in the Consumer segment. The wireless broadband growth came despite intense price competition as customers sought out the strength of our Next G network, which still remains a very strong competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>Underlining our focus on improving the customer experience, we did open another 49 T[life] retail stores in the half and the sales starter, as David alluded to, for T[life] stores remains compelling and support our investment in those stores nationwide. But also we believe we can increase fixed broadband penetration in certain segments by leveraging our market price management capability, and capture mobile market share through continuing innovation in pricing and as you heard we've just launched some innovative pricing, and the value that we have in our products and services to meet the customer's needs.</p>
          <p>Customer response to our recently launched new bundles has been very positive, but PSTN continues to be the headwind as David described.</p>
          <p>So moving on to our business segment, revenue in this segment declined by 0.4% to $1.9 billion due to the combination of the economic downturn and the impact of competition on prices or yield. The decline in PSTN revenues accelerated to 6.1% in this segment as usage and the customer base continued to decline as per consumer. But on the app side, mobile services grew by 9% with rural customers taking data packs on smartphones.</p>
          <p>Fixed retail broadband revenue grew by 8% in this segment on higher average revenue per user as more customers elected or selected business-grade broadband products. Business-grade broadband grew by 31%, with scope for significantly more broadband penetration in this customer base for us.</p>
          <p>We do anticipate a stronger second half for a Telstra business segment or in that segment and a quick return to a positive growth trajectory as we begin to see the benefits of their investment in higher ARPU products, particularly business broadband and smartphones.</p>
          <p>Enhancing the customer experience again in the service level in the business segment remains a priority. Business centers are contributing to this and delivering three times more overall sales than retail stores and selling five times more total broadband applications.</p>
          <p>So let me move on to our Enterprise and Government segment. The Enterprise and Government sales revenue adjusted for sale of cash declined by 1.6%, with fixed revenue falling 7.6% due again to the sharp decline in PSTN <mark type="inaudible" /> emerging here. Excluding international carriage business, the segment revenue grew 0.3%, so if you extract the offshore activity, it's almost a flat performance in the segment.</p>
          <p>However, the overall strong results in Mobiles and IP entire access portfolios. Mobile service revenue growth was 12% with 45% coming from mobile data. 3G customers increased by 43% in the Enterprise and Government segment and now account for more than half of the mobile customer base in this segment.</p>
          <p>The Next IP network continues to provide our customers with premium IP solutions underpinning a very strong 21% growth in IP access revenues which now are at $346 million in the half. As David mentioned, we headed into some important strategic partnerships with customers during the half. We also continue to rollout major IP services and capability for customers such as the Commonwealth Bank. We are enthusiastic about the sale pipeline in there <mark type="inaudible" /> government and optimistic about a stronger second half from this segment as we ramp up the delivery of products and services, so it went up like last fiscal year.</p>
          <p>Just little bit about Sensis, our Sensis headline sales revenue declined by 7.3% in the half as you saw that when we do adjust for the transfer of the trading post to another part of Telstra, the sale of &#x2013; and the closure of China post print activity. The sale of Universal Publishers and the currency movements from the China properties Sensis China properties, sales revenue declined by only 0.1% and EBITDA grew by 4.8%.</p>
          <p>Yellow Pages print revenues declined with advertisers reducing their ads spend across all media and also of course the Yellow Pages and this is somewhat of a consequence of the global financial crisis in metro &#x2013; and this was really manageable in metro areas in particular.</p>
          <p>However, we continue to see strong growth in online directories and in the China businesses, and as a result online mobile share of our entire revenue grew to over 30% so, directory on mobile and in online White Pages, Yellow Pages. Going forward the stabilized action of the changing yellow print is a priority for Sensis and we expect the advertising market to pick-up as the economy picks up.</p>
          <p>Let me talk about CSL New World because CSL has had an impact on the half year result &#x2013; some significance and even when you discount the currency impact.</p>
          <p>The conditions in Hong Kong are very difficult. The GDP actually declined by 2.4% in the September quarter. So not quite experiencing &#x2013; well experiencing worse impacts than we are in Australia. CSL New World top line performance is being hit by several factors. These include intense price competition in that market both locally and for international roaming and a sharp fall in the demand for the VAS upgrades. And that's slightly to due to the economic conditions probably in Honk Kong we use to try and the ship handsets quite frequently and now they don't. The decline was compounded by the strengthening of the Australian dollar of course.</p>
          <p>However, the impact of those external difficult conditions has been mitigated at the bottom-line by some strong cost management in CSL. And a result, the OpEx declined at a greater rate than the sales revenue decline.</p>
          <p> Even in previous half, due to the absence of a substantial accelerated depreciation cost incurred in last year, as we rolled out the old networking we put in the next gen network in Honk Kong. Depending on the speed of economic recovery in Honk Kong the outlook looks more positive with CSL &#x2013; with CSL's Next G network giving it high competitive advantage to rig nice growth in Honk Kong. However, in this second half, the currency is still is likely to be impact the Australian dollar results.</p>
          <p>Let me talk about costs now, a highlight of our performance, I believe, has been our continuing -- continued focus on tight cost control. As a result, our OpEx declined at a significantly greater rate than sales revenue, and the table behind me shows reported OpEx declined 4.8%. But, again, for a more accurate insight into the real trends and very consistent with one I've just talked about on top-line, let's look at the OpEx adjusted for KAZ and FX. So on an adjusted OpEx basis, OpEx declined at 2.1% in the half, adjusted line across 4% with a reduction driven by significantly lower levels of redundancy payments and overtime payments as well as lower contractors and agency payments.</p>
          <p>In addition, we achieved reductions in salary costs due to lot of staffing levels. Adjusted DVC sales to weakly variable costs increased marginally as cost to goods rose with higher handset subsidies, but this was partly offset by lower network payments.</p>
          <p>And adjusted other expenses for about nearly 5%, this reduction included lower cost of service contracts, as we continue to exit transformation activities. We also continue to reduce general and administrative cost through control of discretionary spending and pay <mark type="inaudible" /> as we control marketing cost ahead of some new product and plans launched at end of the period.</p>
          <p>However, partly offsetting those savings, we had impairment cost rise by 29% and that's primarily been driven by the increase of $63 million in debt and doubtful bids to a level now of 187 million, as consumer debt delinquency and business insolvency increased again due mainly and largely to the economic conditions.</p>
          <p>I just wanted to mention a few key expense lines. Labour productivity has been a constant focus and we continue to achieve significant gains as well for throughout the business with fewer staff and we our team capabilities.</p>
          <p>The total workforce reduced by 477 full time equivalents this half, excluding the acquisition and divestment activity as productivity initiatives continue. In fact just to give you a little flavor, our productivity improved 2.6% in the half and we measure productivity revenue on the topline divided by labour and labour substitution. That's how we measure our productivity performance.</p>
          <p>And I think grow <mark type="inaudible" /> and this brought some revenue reduction by 2.6, that's a good outcome. We have an objective for the year of productivity improvement <mark type="inaudible" /> segueway, of around 4%. Another thing worth mentioning here is the blended average SARC or the subscriber acquisition and recontracting costs. It increased by 13%. It's half on a blended basis so it's mainly across postpaid and prepaid. We're comfortable with this increase as it does reflect the lower to higher value smartphones such as <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>These customers also tend to take higher value plans and we expect to get higher ARPUs and therefore return on the SARC investment <mark type="inaudible" />. There were also double-digit declines in many categories of discretionary cost including travel where we utilize our own technology to achieve very large cost savings while increasing our own productivity. And consultancy expenses dropped 28%. So we kept a very close control on <mark type="inaudible" /> expenses. Let me move on to capital.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure and depreciation and amortization. Accrued CapEx which is about 23% to 1.6 billion as the wind-down of transformation related to spending continues leading to CapEx declines, costs a range of areas. CapEx in IT alone declined by 187 million as new customer care and billing system near the completion.</p>
          <p>Transmission CapEx fell 103 million after the completion of our Sydney to Hawaii cable way and there are Asia or American gateway cable across Asia while fixed assets CapEx dropped by 102 million on reduced demand for PSTN services. Accrued CapEx also includes around $80 million for part of the costs of the upgrade of the HFC network in Melbourne to 100 megabits per second.</p>
          <p>In a business there's usual environment, we still expect CapEx to stabilize around 14% of sales revenue. Depreciation and amortization fell 3.1% to 2.2 billion this half. The reduction was mainly due to the absence of accelerated depreciation at CSL, or in other words its presence in the last year. The increase in amortization was due to software additions and amortization of the Trading Post masthead.</p>
          <p>I wanted just to reference our financial parameters and borrowing costs. Over the past 12 months, we've actually reduced down net debt by nearly 1.3 billion as free cash flow increased in borrowing costs, and gross debt fell. As a result, we've maintained a strong financial position with our financial parameters, again, remaining at the stronger end of our target ranges.</p>
          <p>So debt servicing, our net debt-to-EBITDA is 1.4 times versus our target of 1.7 to 2.1 times. Our net debt gearing ratio is at 54.5% and our target is 55 to 75. And EBITDA interest coverage 10.8 times versus our target of more than seven times. You can see on this page that our borrowing cost reduction, so real interest expense reduction is 156 million. And then you have the fair value adjustments following, <mark type="inaudible" /> that on the page.</p>
          <p>So let me turn to free cash flow. It has continued its steady upward trajectory. It's half way, achieved 2.6 billion in free cash flow, an increase of 708 million or 37%. And as you can see from the chart, the free cash flow, the increase came from a mix of sources.</p>
          <p>Firstly, cash from operations grew 285 million as the business continued to generate solid returns. However, this was offset by an extra 187 million we had to pay an extra <mark type="inaudible" /> contributions.</p>
          <p>Cash CapEx was reduced by 441 million as the planned reductions in CapEx continued from the previous transformation levels. However, we received 97 million less from investing activities partly due to the absence of the FOXTEL distribution in this half just gone.</p>
          <p>And finally, our cash tax payment totaled 266 million, which is fairly significant. It was mainly due to tax rate funds received from the tax service for the prior year mainly due to assessment associated to some R&amp;D claims, <mark type="inaudible" /> fund relating to the fiscal year '09 maturing, and us taking advantage of the investment allowance that the government introduced.</p>
          <p>As those trends continue in the second half, we are confident of achieving our target of $6 billion of free cash flow even after contributing close to 500 million into our pension fund. The recent market really has not significantly altered our expectations for pension contributions.</p>
          <p>The Board, as it usual does, will consider the use of any excess cash prior to our August results. But I would just like to remind you that our franking credit balance is limited or low and this will constrain our ability to increase our fully franked dividends for the time being of course dividends don't have to be fully franked, but I want to make sure that is understood.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion, this has clearly been a challenging half year for a number of reasons, but when we sit back and look at the half the challenge of course is on the top-line and &#x2013; but we have on the upside, retained a tight control of costs and that will continue. And as David mentioned we now expect a low single-digit decline in sales revenue on a reported basis, but no change to our guidance for fiscal year 2010 on all of the other parameters including free cash flow of $6 billion.</p>
          <p>So thank you for listening and, we will &#x2013; Dave and I will take questions, ably assisted by some of the senior team here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John and Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a while the time when the chairs come out, we'll take the first three questions from Sydney here, and then we'll go to phone lines. We should have plenty of time to take as many as questions as people have this morning. First question from Sameer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Sameer Chopra here from Deutsche Bank. I had three questions. First of all when you look at your guidance statement you are saying that you are looking for low single-digit sales revenue decline, and EBTIDA growth in the low single-digits, which would suggest that in the second half of this year, you're looking for quite a lot of cost-out, I was wondering if you can tell us where this cost-out is coming from so which line items do you think can be pulled back?</p>
          <p>The second one is looking at the capital structure itself, you have a net debt to gearing target of 55 to 75%. You're currently sitting under that. Does NBN in any way change the way you look at some of these targets? I am just trying to understand how the Board and management are thinking about the NBN and target gearing.</p>
          <p>And the last question is about that CapEx, your CapEx has surprised on how quickly you've managed to pull the CapEx back. But, David, you said that you're investing for growth. I wanted to understand where in your CapEx can we see you investing for growth, which product segments are you investing in? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Let me get John to answer the one on the EBITDA, because that's also very important to <mark type="inaudible" /> total cost down, and then I'll come back. Dave I want you to <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'll take it the due ratio</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll come back and talk about investment CapEx and what we're going to do <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Sameer, your first question, we expect two things to happen in second half. One is we do expect improvement on the top line but the costs take-out we expect to really continue where we have been taking cost out.</p>
          <p>So there will be a continuation of the full year effect of labor reduction. We are not -- we were taking a lot of people out of this company. We're no longer doing that, so we have a &#x2013; the redundancy line is also, year-on-year basis, favorable of course. And we're right across all the discretionary items. I can tell you travel reduction will reduce. I can tell you that all those administrative line items will reduce. So it's a continuation, and in the discretionary area, probably, an acceleration of some declines in those areas.</p>
          <p>So that's where we're going to take the costs out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any big change in the service contract lines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yes, indeed, because we're not saying labor alone, sorry I mean, labor substitution. So yes, service contracts and agreements and the labor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a lot of work in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>IT professionals. I mean, they're all people that are in the company and as the transformation slows, as it had been in the first half, they decline.</p>
          <p>On your second question about the net debt gearing ratio, yes, we are at the lower end. One of the great uncertainties for this company is are we cooperating or are we competing in the environment, and what will our CapEx needs be going forward. And they will vary significantly as to which of those outcomes occur, so &#x2013; but our free cash flow is pretty strong, and I don't see us going to the market for a great increase in borrowings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the third one was the changing nature on the CapEx spend. But as we move away from big infrastructure &#x2013; network infrastructure, we're going more into building solutions in products I mean, T-Box, T-Hub, but some new offerings coming into the business market. So the nature of the capital expenditure is changing from these big, chunky bits of infrastructure now into really driving additional value added services and initiatives. So we need a little CapEx for that. That's really the key thing as we go forward.</p>
          <p>The only other thing in terms of that cost, I mean we're still driving from the transformation work, because we really see Seibel rolling out in the front of the house, while we've put a few more people in there to improve service. We are seeing productivity gains starting to come through there. The Seibel System one view of the customer starting to see some good things there, and that also start to flow through as well, very important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I should mention the field force productivity was fantastic and continues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple of questions. The first one was in terms of the revenue decline, can you give us some feel for kind of what percentage was structural, what percentage was cyclical? And then what percentage might have been due to the fact you did take longer putting in some of these price changes or some of that response.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously can be qualitative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll give you my best guesstimate on that. I would say it's about 50% industry structural change calling patents, et cetera. I would say sort of &#x2013; there is 25, 25 &#x2013; that's what I'd say. John, are you going to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's about right. I mean calls were down a lot. People just &#x2013; if you call that structural, that's fairly structural. I mean we tend to be somewhat victims of our own success. You have a good wireless network, people are moving from our fixed network to the wireless activity. So there is a price and volume contribution to the decline.</p>
          <p>I mean we're also continue to put a lot of capped PSTN plans as well. And just to give you a number here. We've got now 841,000 on PSTN subscription plans. And that's 159,000 more than this time last year. And there is a little tendency now -- we were &#x2013; a lot of customers were on $99 plan. There is a tendency now, which is not surprising for more to go on to the $49, and that brings your operating down but we keep the customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question was just I'm wondering, if you could just help us understand, how we should think about the economics of the tariff rebalancing. Because I suppose one, the reason for asking the question is obviously the revenue guidance in the single is for flat revenue growth. Now we've got a slight decline in there. So I'm just wondering is that a case of either some of these structural things have accelerated or is that a case of this tariff rebalancing is actually maybe going to take longer in terms of the revenue and possible margin impact of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, there were two major factors in why we have changed the guidance. And we did &#x2013; we want to be &#x2013; tell you exactly what's going on the business.</p>
          <p>Firstly, the PSTN decline in December and January were just &#x2013; we thought the calling might come backup, because it had declined and we just have seen no change in that. So we think we can't really expect that to comeback.</p>
          <p>And as we've got the plans in &#x2013; new plans to the market, it does have some short-term impact as we're re-contracting customers. So we think it's just going to come in later in this calendar year. So that's been the challenge in terms of top-line revenue growth. And then we just got to manage the business to deliver the bottom line performance.</p>
          <p>So that's been the equation we've worked through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Three questions. Firstly, David, in your opening remarks you referred to there being a revenue recovery, but after a lag. I am wondering if you can help us identify the length of that lag? Are we talking positive revenue growth in FY '11, or is it the second half of FY '11. What is your expectation around that recovery?</p>
          <p>Second question relates to SouFun and the talk about an IPO there, but it's really a bit broader than that. What I'm actually interested in is the extent to which your free cash flow target of $6 billion would be assisted by the proceeds from such a divestment or partial divestment of that holding or in other words, how sustainable is $6 billion free cash flow target for this year into next year and the years beyond?</p>
          <p>My third question relates to your brand strategy. You seem to have a fairly stable market share. For example, around 42% in mobiles. When I look at Optus, I noticed that they have differentiated brands, such as Virgin, for instance. When I look at other industries -- for example, Qantas -- I see that companies that are wedded to the national, they are the leader at the premium end of the market can also launch back brands for the price sensitive consumer. I see nothing of that sort coming from Telstra. I am wondering why not? Have you given up on the price sensitive segment in your market, or do you in fact have some strategies around brand and around differentiated product offerings that could lift your market share in the medium term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ian. Let me address the first one. I'll give John since he is on the Board, so finally he can talk to that one. And then let me pick up on the brand strategy, after John's respond to that one.</p>
          <p>Firstly on revenue, as we said we expect a stronger second half, but at the moment, we're not giving a long-term forecast on revenue. We want to continue to balance as we go forward in terms of delivering good revenue and profit improvement, but we're not forecasting anything.</p>
          <p>We do &#x2013; if you wanted to characterize anything, we think share is very important now because the stability of share for us is critical. You don't want to lose your relationship with the customers. So I think that would be probably more the determining factor for us going forward, so we don't lose share.</p>
          <p>I'll come back and talk to brand, because that's quite a long discussion, and we have been in lower price offerings with different brands before. And I'll come back and talk about how we think about the cycle of products. But let's do the SouFun and then I'll talk about brand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My answer on that is pretty quick. The $6 billion cash flow target did not anticipate or include the sale of SouFun. Sustainability of free cash flow -- I'm really not going to give any free cash flow forecast here, but I will just say it will depend on where we end up, we end up with NBN again, and what our CapEx requirements might be. But needless to say, we will remain a very strong free cash flow company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So just very quick on the brand one, the &#x2013; if you go back, what, 2001-2002, we had the Communicate brand in the market. That was sort of, is the 2G network had been in the market for quite a long time, and we felt it was a good time to introduce new brands. We had a different distribution strategy, it was only online, and it worked very well for us for a number of years.</p>
          <p>When we bought our Next G, I mean a truly differentiated product, we definitely feel that it was a premium product, truly differentiated, which it still is today. Two million square kilometers versus, or two times there, compared to about 21 megabits, going to 42 very shortly.</p>
          <p>So the issue was when and how. So I don't think it's a no, but we definitely don't think in the mobiles area, it's the right time to do it, but we continue to look at this. This is a very important part of how you can address different market segments. And as we've talked about before, the consumer market segmentation is critically important as we look at how our brand works in those segments, what is the best offer to put there. But we're very conscious that at the moment, we are a premium provider, and over time, we will continue to look at it. So it's on the radar, but I won't disclose too much more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Just to clarify on the first point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So did I understand correctly that you're not wanting to make any prediction about revenue growth for next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now go to the phones lines for a couple of questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question is from Christian Guerra from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thanks for your time. I have three questions for you this morning.</p>
          <p>Firstly, just on the guidance for sales for next year, I'm just wondering if you can maybe discuss it in a bit more detail, given that on the 28 of October at the Investor Day, you're talking about low single digit growth. You then downgrade it to flattish on the 18th of December, and now you're talking about low single digits in terms of the decline for this year?</p>
          <p>In my history of following the company, you've always been very, very good at forecasting &#x2013; apart from any sort of PSTN, back to 2004, 2005. So I'm just a little bit surprised that the guidance has changed so materially in only about eight weeks.</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the transformation program, again I'm just wondering if you could maybe discuss the fact that you've invested over $10 billion as part of the transformation and yet we're talking about sales growth flat at best. I wondered if you could discuss please -- I wonder what message you've got for investors there, in terms of that investment?</p>
          <p>And my third question is on the census with Yellow Pages' print sales down 9% in the first half, given that you typically have a pretty good handle for the full year numbers, given the pre sales, just wondering what we should be expecting for Yellow Pages print for the full year of fiscal '10? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So let me handle the first one. I'll let John remember to talk for the second one.</p>
          <p>Yeah, look, on guidance, we have <mark type="inaudible" /> very good. And John's always been &#x2013; pretty much across the business we've always taken it pretty seriously. But the business -- the PSTN business -- call them declines. and that's what has got us concerned. It's accelerated faster than we had expected, and it has been an accelerating trend. So we think it's very important. We tell you what's going on, and we are &#x2013; that's where it is at the moment, and what we want to do.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of switching gears, we've got a number of initiatives going into the market now. We think it's very important to hold share, and we'll be focused on those as we go forward.</p>
          <p>You want to <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure. Christian just a little more color on the guidance change. I mean PSTN is being a little more volatile and unpredictable than we've previously experienced. And we did notice in the last two months, as David said, unexpected changes.</p>
          <p>On the question about transformation program, yeah, we have spent over $10 billion on it. And we &#x2013; as I've said on Investment Day &#x2013; we continue to monitor the specific benefits from the IT transformation very closely. The good news is that the &#x2013; and it's about half and half revenue benefits and cost benefits &#x2013; and the good news is that we are achieving both. We're at about 9 million behind or something on the cost benefits. I'm going to say that's in the noise and we'll catch that up.</p>
          <p>On the revenue side, we're actually ahead and you might say well, hang on, your sales revenue is flat. The good news is, from the IT transformation, we are actually getting a benefit. So for example, the strike rates that we're getting because of single view of customers <mark type="inaudible" /> introduction, we're actually achieving higher strike rates and therefore the revenue from it. The bad news is that we've got this PSTN fall off and so on.</p>
          <p>So you could argue &#x2013; and rightfully so &#x2013; if we weren't getting those higher strike rates, we might be going worse than we are. So that's the transformation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Since the start of Yellow Pages, we have come through the new systems. And I think Bruce and the team are feeling costs have about stayed up, but print will be down, unquestionably, <mark type="inaudible" />. But if you compare how people have performed in the media market, it's been a very strong effect. First, I think maybe you have a little bit increase share in terms of spend is what we're thinking.</p>
          <p>So it's just the changing dynamics. We're getting a lot of good growth in online. We're getting those books out, which has been &#x2013; as you move the IT systems, we've got to keep that production going, and Bruce has got one here and he could show you, which is by the way a very important feat in that business. So we think that we're holding our own in that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And sorry, just a follow-up question, just back on the transformation, John. You talked in the past fairly extensively about how the transformation has driven lower unit costs across the board for Telstra. Given your throw in the market, I would have thought that -- you talk about the increase in competition and that sort of thing, but I would have thought, given your scale and given the cost savings from transformation. you could afford to go out there and maybe be a little bit more aggressive with some of your competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You've raised a good point. What the transformation provides us is the opportunity to reduce the cost base. And that allows the scope to be more price competitive. But we still, as David said earlier, look at value that we provide to our customers. But value premiums can't get away. And you learn to be competitive in the market. And yes, we are driving cost out of the business and economies of scale in order to make room to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'd say a part of our new offers into the market, Christian is probably reflecting a little bit of your thinking, which we think we can be more competitive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from the phones, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Ian Martin from RBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David, I'd just like to ask about the transformation and the billions spent on that over the last few years. A lot of it of course intended to improve your cost efficiency, but also it's supposed to provide inputs to the market based management to allow you to deal with segments and understand what's going on in different segments, to have a dialog or some contact with customers to see how those demand preferences are changing. And yet here we've had in this half some major changes in trends, in PSTN and calling rates, wireless broadband and so on. And the systems you've got not only haven't helped to anticipate those, but the reaction has been right at the end of the half year, rather than as these things were occurring.</p>
          <p>So just wondering going forward, as these things are going to continue and there'll be new developments in the market and so on, whether the systems and processes you've got, and have spent all this money on over the last few years, really put you in a position to understand and respond and even anticipate what's going in market demand? Because I've got to say my confidence has been well undermined by this result about your ability to do that.</p>
          <p>And second question, right through these last few years, the one thing that's been consistent is the $6 billion free cash flow. It's been held out there as shareholders' reward for sticking with the company through this transformation process. And yet despite being on track for that this year, nothing additional coming back to shareholders, not even an extra cent, 125 million or so, out of that free cash flow coming back in dividend this year. I know you've got some uncertainties around NBN, but surely shareholders themselves should be making that decision about what capital if any goes into NBN. And I'm just still &#x2013; I got to say disappointed that we haven't seen a extra cent or two in dividend this half year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, look, Ian, firstly on the our new Seibel system and how that we can collect information, get better views of customers. Look, it is settling in well. I mean I think we are starting to get some good views. But it's still early days. And I wish I could predict more &#x2013; better than what we have been, because one of the things on PSTN calling volume, that's not an easy thing to do.</p>
          <p>But in terms of giving flavor of different customers' spending, historical spending requirements or spending patterns and then we have to predict what sort of plans we should do, we are trying to get some really good feedback. So that should start to feed into the retention. I'd love to get one forecast of usage, I haven't found it yet, but it's &#x2013; it will be good.</p>
          <p>But coming back to your point, we did not anticipate the rate of decline in PSTN, that is the fact. So it is what it is. We just try to get on, and now we've got to see what we do gain forward.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of the dividend &#x2013; John, do you want to <mark type="inaudible" /> I mean we understand your sentiment, Ian. It's fully frank. It's that's what the Board decided in light of the future outlook for the company of NBN, where he thought that was better to hold at this time.</p>
          <p>So I think that's really about it. I don't know...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And decided to make sure that it was a fully franked dividend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Had we gone higher, wouldn't have been &#x2013; would not have been fully franked, you can work that out from our franking credit balance. And with respect to the full year, I mean, although things that I mentioned have to be taken into consideration. Of course, we've realized and the Board realizes that we're building up free cash flow and our propensity has always been to return it to shareholders. I did make the point out and did point out today the limitation of our franking credit balance. Now not everybody wants 100% franked dividend, so we'll have to take that into consideration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. We have another question from the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is Sachin Gupta from Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. I've got couple of questions. Just firstly, <mark type="inaudible" /> the lower tax rate is up, you mentioned that you are expecting a bit of the investment allowance . So just wondering if that is something that's likely to continue into the second half? And also just on the network cost, it looks like that's come down due to some adjustment of bad policy estimate, just wondering if you can quantify that or what is that likely? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I may have to check on the second question. But, yes, the investment allowance will continue into the second half. Just to give you some additional flavor on the tax impacts, not $41 million favorable impact on tax came from the investment allowance. R&amp;D claims are 148 and we claimed a deduction of 91 million for trading post amortization.  So that's some more color on the tax. I think you were talking about network payments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay. So part of our goods and services cost management has been from a reduction in network payments and it's come from some good negotiation up in Hong Kong between CSL and the fixed network provider for backhaul post SAW and we have got the benefits of that. And that continues. I mean it's a new deal and it's a new lower charge for backhaul in Hong Kong so we continue to benefit from those lower rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks John. I will come back to Sydney now further on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>John Laurent Horrut with JPMorgan. I just had a question on the NBN and maybe you can share some thoughts with us in terms of how you see the timing panning out. Because &#x2013; and second question today is, is it fair to assume that before you put anything to sail on this boat, you want to have clarity on things like NBNCo future pricing, where their footprint is going to be, etcetera, things that will impact your business. And so in that sense how do you see &#x2013; how quickly do you think you can get your point with NBNCo and the government? Where you do get this clarity and therefore in a position to assess what the impact on the overall business is going to be.</p>
          <p>Second question on the NBN, if there is such thing as a heads of agreement announcement; would there be any numbers in this heads of agreement? Plus, it's a pretty simple question. Second question is on the revenue initiatives. Do you think the revenue slowdown was sort of experiencing through the business is also a function of how aggressively you've pulled back on CapEx and to some extent, do you see as you're trying to reaccelerate the top line growth, do you see capital intensity in the business having to be above say 4 billion of CapEx per annum? Or you can sustain it at current level?</p>
          <p>And lastly on the dividend, that also have sort of crosses with the NBN issue. Would you advise to the Board be &#x2013; to basically not change the distribution until clarity is established on the NBN in a meaningful way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me try to address the NBN one. The first thing is that that we are very much in a very complex transaction. It has got so many aspects to it, as I said. It's all the things you mentioned, plus regulatory outcomes, what it will be like in the future. It's about the nature of the transaction, how it would be. It is just &#x2013; I mean, there must be about 15 major areas that we have to consider. So you've got to get them aligned before you can even start to think of getting to a conclusion.</p>
          <p>Now on the timing, we are really driven by <mark type="inaudible" /> and the government. We all have a desire to get this thing agreed and get on with life because I think we all need that. It is a distraction at the high &#x2013; at my level. But we have to do the work and be absolutely sure that we're doing the right thing. And if it takes another month or six months, I'll invest the time because it's so important for the company and I'm not going to be driven into a short-term decision. And we've got to be very, very clear about all the considerations because you could miss one little thing that will have an enormous impact to the future of the business. So that's where I am. And as soon as that we'll know more, we will let you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on that, if you reconcile that <mark type="inaudible" /> in terms of their timetable, the need for industry consideration, is it fair to say that we are looking at months, in fact, several months before we actually get to a point where you can submit something that shareholders can take a view on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do think it's months before we can get to shareholders, yes. And if we &#x2013; look, we've got to &#x2013; we've just got to get so many factors sort of aligned here. And I look &#x2013; it can't be said more strongly, the amount of detail and the need to be very, very considered about every aspect because you could do a transaction at top level and forget about an element that could just cost the company enormous amounts of money going forward. So we are going to be very considered.</p>
          <p>In terms of hedge agreement, look I don't know and we haven't thought about where to put the number in the hedge agreement. Of course, if we do any agreement with the <mark type="inaudible" /> in terms of the initial announcement I think we've got to be ought to be ready to really present it to shareholders so they can really understand. So I try to underline that no, we haven't really thought that through headway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, the important thing is we shareholders would want to know the shareholder value of index. And we're going to have to have that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So rest assured that that's absolutely parallel in amount. In terms of the two questions <mark type="inaudible" /> has CapEx put that kind of impact on revenue? I don't believe so. I think it's about industry, structural change and our execution capability. That's the two and then what was the second one on maybe top line growth...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> on the dividend...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The last one was dividend. I will ask John to take this. I though there were two questions on revenue, CapEx pullback.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just in that context if you can sustain CapEx below 4 billion or you see CapEx going up, I appreciate you want to give guidance on <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, what we think is in that range. I mean every other cell car in the world is around about 12, 14% range and I think that sort of seeps through that, right but we will let you know as we tie that up. Okay? John, talk to the dividend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean you are really asking, why you recommend to the Board that ABN clarity is necessary before any change to dividends, I think the Board, we don't have to recommend that to the Board, the Board already want to know that, so I mean that's going to happen anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's completely understandable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Fraser McLeish from RBS. Let me just follow up to the bond NBN, David, it's obviously very complex negotiations, but is your feel there is any certain major issues where the sides are just pull apart or is it more about nothing, and some of this detail you've talked about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look it's really, I can't give anything more than what I've said today, I look &#x2013; I would like to but &#x2013; there is many considerations to it first up, very complex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that's going to make it. And John just on the cost side of things, it sounds like productivity you are expecting that's improvement to the second half and you still got some transformation benefits coming through, does that mean in FY'11 you know, we are looking at sort of flat to negative cost line potentially or would they will or what type of system by then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm not going to give a cost guidance either but you heard what I said, hopefully, you did on Investor Day and it continues out to 11, 12 and we are on track for our IT transformation cost <mark type="inaudible" /> and revenues, <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David, good mooring, John. Two questions this morning, firstly you commented David this morning about market shares being very important to you and previously you've talked about chasing profitable growth. So if you can give some more color around managing those two objectives and whether you will be able to maintain the current level of margins going forward given your focus on market share? Secondly, on our customer service, if you could just talk us through what you have done specifically so far in terms of delivering on that objective?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on what kind of timeframe you are looking at on delivering those objectives and what financial benefits will flow, and will those benefits actually be delivered to shareholders in terms of increased profit or reinvested into pricing to actually manage share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I'll let John take the last one. So let me talk about the first two, this &#x2013; the importance of share. Yes, look it's &#x2013; as you look at the business, maintaining that relationship with customers is pretty important. But it is this margin &#x2013; as I talked about the decline in prices in the market. So, how fast you move with that? What premium can you truly justify? How do you differentiate your product both at an individual product level but also total relationship?</p>
          <p>But at the end of the day for a large company like ours, you must hold share, because if you let that share get a way on you, then it has an enormous impact about ongoing ability to have relationship with the customer and so in other products and services. So we continue to look at this mix.</p>
          <p>Now as I said, we'd like to have these offers into the marketable area that before Christmas, a little bit slow. So you can see that we are trying to remain competitive. And we've got to manage that impact on margin, but <mark type="inaudible" /> it's about EBITDA growth, because that drives your free cash.</p>
          <p>And so, everything we will do is going to be about driving EBITDA growth, maybe the slightly decline margin, but then okay, if along we can get the EBITDA growth then we should be okay. So that's been &#x2013; that's the nature that we are working with at the moment and the whole team focused on. And we continue want to surprise the market and move forward with many different things going forward. That's number one.</p>
          <p>Number two in terms of the customers. So let's talk about why I said, I've got some encouraging &#x2013; at least some early signs. We are starting to see some flattening in terms of the TRI compliance, that's the <mark type="inaudible" />, and that's been ramping for a number of months and now we are starting to see some flattening, slight decline, but you wouldn't want to declare victory yet. And we still got to get them back down.</p>
          <p>We obviously do a lot of surveys ourselves and well, we are starting to just see the early signs of improvement. Now, there have been a large number of things done and we still have a long way to go. I do not want to leave the impression that we have finished at all. I see opportunities everyday.</p>
          <p>But from aligning the whole culture around customer service and I want to make sure you know service and sales go together. It's not one or the other, and we're not going to suddenly make it also <mark type="inaudible" />, we should be &#x2013; they go together.</p>
          <p>But we've got the alignment and you can feel that it in the company, that's <mark type="inaudible" /> this is important, that's what they would like to. And we've got targets out there. We run &#x2013; every manager has three initiatives to improve the customer experience right throughout the business, whether you're in credit management, in network engineering, what can you do to improve this.</p>
          <p>So people, who are not in the frontline or who are supporting, that think about things to do. We've got end-to-end process improvement. One would have &#x2013; and I should have mentioned Robert Nason has joined us. He's sitting in the front here. And he's going to be driving these end-to-end processes, he has been thinking about &#x2013; and I think there is enormous cost to take out.</p>
          <p>As you look at broadband activation, Deena and Robert are working together even now, hearing the voice of the customer, bring them in there, got work groups looking at the reengineering of the whole process. So that we don't have two technicians going for a business broadband connection.</p>
          <p>We don't, we have good billing that comes out, there's good expectations. This is enormous program. So it's both &#x2013; cultural, people, reengineering, alignment of targets and holding the whole company accountable. So I think we're aligned. Now we just got to do the execution as we go forward. So the list is very, very long.</p>
          <p>Do you want to handle the last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The question what will we do with the money? Look it's &#x2013; that had partially answered. I mean it really, at the end of day is about cash management and EBITDA growth is a goal. I mean it's a balancing act. We will use some of the cash generated for through better customer service. If you get to customer service, right, your cost should come out, because part of the evidence of bad customer service is you get <mark type="inaudible" />, you get far more calls, so you get this whole mess of unnecessary costs from bad volumes and so there should be with improved customer service, obviously revenue improvement, satisfaction of customers, but also cost reduction. And as I said earlier, we will have to think about how we use some of that cash to be competitive in the market in terms of price and some of it falling through to the managed for shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And have you done any quantification so far &#x2013; you've been talking about this for the last six months in terms what the real costs or benefits are? Are we talking 1% or 5%, what kind of materiality can we expect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. One of the reasons we brought Robert along is to help us identify exactly what we can give, it's easy to say, what I've just said. We really got to get down to specific programs and the benefits, both revenue and cost of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we expect some more clarity at the full year result on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I can say is this is a critically important factor for us. Part of Robert's job and all of us is to continue getting the right structure for this business going forward and we are very determined to do that. And we'll give you a color just as that works through; we've got some initiatives going on now but you just &#x2013; rest assured we're doing it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's Mark Blackwell, Morgan Stanley. Just a couple of questions for you, and firstly looking at the various elements in your guidance, it's clear that to achieve the six billion working capital is really going to be critical element given your tight guidance on EBITDA and on CapEx, is that that we saw in this half actually that particularly payables came down to a cash outflow and payables, are we going to see a rapid turnaround in working capital in the second half and is that going to be a driver of the six billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Really &#x2013; I'm sorry, you have more questions, go on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry. The second question is just was there a discussion at Board level about impairment on the fixed line asset given the NBN discussions, are we at the point where we are saying that that asset, whatever it's worth is now worth less because the government or someone else is not going to pay as much as what we'd pay for that, is there a discussion at that level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you &#x2013; why don't you take that, I'll add some color to the second one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes the $6 billion target does depend on improvement in working capital, and you know that's part of our plan. It also includes &#x2013; is dependent on a FOXTEL distribution and we expect that how much is up to the folks to abort So, yes, is the answer to your question. And achieving cost and achieving our EBITDA and achieving CapEx target, which is as you know our guidance less than 3.8.</p>
          <p>On the impairment, look the Board Audit Committee &#x2013; the Board through Board Audit Committee constantly asking, as they should, the question about fixed line impairment. It's a matter of where this all turns out of course. There is likely to be accelerated deprecation of the copper network as a result of NBN. But remember this thing is going to take eight years to build. And the copper network has a value. So will it be a significant yearly impact on the business? Not really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I was going to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Andrew Levy, Macquarie. Thanks. A question on the mobile space and the tradeoff you're talking about between EBITDA growth and protecting your market share. Just the history of the Aussie market with a heavily subsidized handset market is sort of showing that people to take share or even protect share have usually seen at least in the short term the subscriber acquisitions cost go up. You can see that in your pack as well, I hope this is doing right now. So your target to protect EBITDA, is it possible you'll have to take a hit in the short term on a 12 months basis to get back into some of those markets where you probably let a few subscribers go? So that's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second was just a clarification on the HFC upgrade. I know you said there are some costs in the half we've just had, is that still on track and you're still spending money on that for a roll out this year, I think was the target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Look, you're absolutely right in terms of mobile share. It has been the nature of this trending market, you've got to subsidize those handsets here and that's what we missed a bit with the iPhone quite honestly and I think we've talked about that before. But if you spend more there, you got to save it somewhere else. So if we are &#x2013; we're going to take the cost out somewhere else so that we deliver on our EBITDA growth targets. So that's the nature and, yes, we may need to. We've already upped it a bit as you saw in the results. We did specially on a few products, and we will continue to look that as we go forward. So yeah, but if we do, we got to find it somewhere else.</p>
          <p>The second one was on the HFC. There's nothing on the HFC at the moment. We've done the 100 megs rollout in Victoria and that's all done. We're in market and it's early days. We're finding that the customers are the most &#x2013; have the greatest propensity to take the service of those who had more than one person, although actually three or four people in the home, all using broadband because for a single user just on a PC, it really doesn't change the experience that much. PCs don't get 100 megabits per second here. So it's a multi-home dwelling user environment where it's going to be most appropriate, but still very early days along the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what are your views in going into &#x2013; to Sydney and other markets given obviously going with 100 megabits per second. Is the Melbourne experience compelling enough for you say, we got to be there &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> when they get there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all I am not 100% sure what <mark type="inaudible" /> are doing with $25 million. I mean, that's what I understand, so you'll have to ask them that. But at the moment we're just sitting tight and we just want to prove this out. And make sure we've got it because also you got to have things that people use it for and we're very happy where we're sitting at the moment and we'll just review as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey John and Dave. Just looking at the results from your cell phone Octave and if you look at the acceleration or let's say no real broadband growth in the market from fixed line, we still got a continuation in wireless. I am just trying to get a gauge in terms of obviously with ongoing discussions with the government and NBN Co. whether these dynamics which will obviously changing on a day-to-day basis have changed the tone of your conversations since December because obviously we have seen those changes. And with regard to the announcement overnight from Google as well in terms of obviously trailing things in the States, does that change the dynamic as well. So it's interesting to see &#x2013; hear the commentary in terms of obviously whether the tone is changing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our tone hasn't changed. I think we have always been very clear about what we see as the future opportunities and the commercial returns around investor. The Google announcement in the U.S., I mean it is a trial. It's only in the U.S. We have spoken to Google about their intentions. It's an interesting development. Google has opening to put that cable across the Pacific. Now they are going in &#x2013; locally in the U.S. I think Google is going to continue to be <mark type="inaudible" /> therefore we have many flaccid relationships with Google. That hasn't changed the tone of the discussions? No, no. We are very clear about what we think is the future take-up rights and opportunities. John, do you want to -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think you're absolutely right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks <mark type="inaudible" />. Dave and John, related to the NBN, we have obviously got the consumer and competition safeguards built which might be reintroduced the senate from the &#x2013; I think the 22nd of February, what are you expecting in terms of that. Are you expecting to be a modified build from what we saw in November?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do not know the answer to that. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm sorry. We &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> you are hoping to see in terms of that, especially the first half of the build, which obviously has the ability to start triggering functional separation with the timeframe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. But we continue to work with the government on all these aspects and where &#x2013; we will see where it goes to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have one final question from the phone line, is Christian there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So we have Christian Guerra from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I have got a follow-up question. It just relates to the pricing changes you put through both on fixed line broadband and wireless broadband. I guess the key to bring the people together was that the price changes you put through the fixed line broadband at the end of November were &#x2013; what I would call fairly cosmetic whereas the changes you put through on wireless broadband were probably most significant we've seen from the company' in sometime. So, could you please just talk through your strategy there is question number one.</p>
          <p>And question number two, have you seen any noticeable reduction in chain or customer growth across both of those products since the changes. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, it's only about strategy has not changed. We still want to come out of the premium because we think the proposition of faster speed and better coverage is with premium. However, it's about what premium you can sell and if the market gets its way on you you see I can't justify 30, 40, 50% premium. So we must remain &#x2013; able to truly quantify our pricing position. Well, as well as we move prices because we've got our own growing <mark type="inaudible" /> &#x2013; 1.3 million wireless broadband customers. And so you understand the impacts as you put price in the market, and you've got people who re-contract and so you look at that impact, but Christian you should take off of that announcement.</p>
          <p>We must remain competitive and share is important to us. And then, but we got to balance that. Well, we've got a little bit of margin though as well as I'm going to give you EBITDA growth and therefore there is true growth, that's what will drive us.</p>
          <p>If we're doing it at an EBITDA, perhaps that EBITDA is going to get down that's not a good strategy, so that's the balance where we continue to work with. We've been pleased with the response so far and it's definitely had an impact and I'm just looking <mark type="inaudible" /> running that business and I am sure it's just a little bit too early to really declare great victory, but we're seeing some early signs of that is coming back at both, but we will keep you posted on that.</p>
          <p>But look we must continue to work with our customers, got a good customer service, good offers, people care about those things. And by the way, I should mention customer service does relate to processing strategy too. Customers &#x2013; if you are too expensive and I fear and I've been very low I say, why should I stay . So you've got to really balance this out going forward. And the market has moved significantly and we must remain competitive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have no more questions. And if David wants to make any just closing comments and we will close that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Ben. Look it has been a challenging six months. We did not expect the decline in the usage on PSTN. However, we are going to take action to continue to be competitive and drive this business forward, we must and we will do what's necessary going forward. Thanks mate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>