<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1489337" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2927</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Group Investor Relations">Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Lars Nyberg</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Per-Arne Blomquist</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Swedbank AB (Broker)">Sven Sk&#xF6;ld</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nordea Bank AB (Broker)">Stefan Gauffin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="SEB Enskilda (Sweden)">Andreas Joelsson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Andy W. Parnis</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Trinkaus &amp; Burkhardt KGaA (Broker)">Dominik Klarmann</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Andrew J. Lee</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux International Ltd.">Peter-Kurt Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Jakob Bluestone</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Laurie Fitzjohn-Sykes</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Svenska Handelsbanken AB (Broker)">Thomas Heath</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Ulrich W. Rathe</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Barry R. Zeitoune</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Terence Tsui</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Carnegie Investment Bank AB">Lena &#xD6;sterberg</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">James S. Britton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Welcome everyone and very warm welcome to TeliaSonera's Second Quarter Result Announcement.</p>
          <p>My name is Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m, Head of Investor Relation. I have, as usual, with me today our President and CEO, Mr. Lars Nyberg; and our Financial Officer, Mr. Per-Arne Blomquist.</p>
          <p>We will do a short review of the result and then followed by a Q&amp;A session. And we have ambition to finish this call within one hour. So to keep that deadline, I'll leave the word over to Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone. Welcome.</p>
          <p>I'll go through the numbers. I think we had a mixed quarter. Some things are I think pretty happy with and we have some challenges. We came in on EBITDA level a little bit slower than last year of course. And our growth rate was down to zero and I'll comment on that little bit because it's really a mixed bag. Of course, we had a lot of influence from the MegaFon deal as you understand.</p>
          <p>So as I said, for the first time in several quarters, we have no growth or very little growth. A third of that is actually referred to equipment sales and a third is about billed revenues and a third is a mix of other things. The equipment sales, of course, I'm not concerned about. This is not the profitable business for us and if we can reduce the subsidies in equipment that will be good for our business.</p>
          <p>So I said it's a mixed bag. We have Eurasia, our growth engine, continues to be as a growth engine with 12% growth, high EBITDA margin as you know. I think Broadband Services seems to be stabilizing a bit. The decline that we have seen for several years seems to be stabilizing. I think the challenge is in Mobility Service. I was talking to one of you before we started that the mobility industry has seen growth every quarter for what is it now, 20 years? And I think we are facing a challenge, which I will comment a little bit later on, which is a change of the business model in Mobility, which I think will lead at least for a while to lower growth rates than we are used to. And that's not only for TeliaSonera, I think that's for the industry in total.</p>
          <p>This is a very important picture. It has to do with the changing of the business model. You have heard me talk about 80% of our revenues in Mobility is voice, while the traffic, and I mean 95% of the traffic today is data. So what is very important for us is to see the relationship with the growth of traffic in relationship to the growth of revenues for that traffic. And I've shown this picture a couple of quarters. You can see that on mobile data, the volume is up 88% and the revenue is up 29%, so a third. And that's probably okay. We can certainly live with a third. A year ago, it was half and it's now down to a third. A third is okay from a business perspective.</p>
          <p>And you see the revenue declining in voice. I think we will have to assume that any growth in revenue will have to come from mobile data, will not come from voice as it has done for 20 years. And then on the right hand side, you can see how the equipment has gone down, which I think fundamentally is positive for us.</p>
          <p>Yes. The industry is in a big flux, in a big change, coming from yesterday's voice business to tomorrow's or even maybe today's data business. And we were talking before with some of you and I believe over time the voice business will tend to have a flat fee, just like Verizon introduced five, six, seven weeks ago in the US. And that underlies the important of what I have been preaching for four years, you can't have flat fee for data. We have to have a relationship with price and the amount of traffic generated in our networks on data, while voice generates relatively little traffic and therefore I think we will go towards a flat fee on voice and messaging.</p>
          <p>This is good news I think. We have been struggling in Sweden, particularly with the rollout of fiber. We are convinced that fiber is the best technology to provide telecommunication services to fixed locations like homes and offices. The very encouraging thing is that in the last areas where we have rolled out fiber in Sweden, of the total population, 4 out of 10 chooses to order the service from us, which means that I think we can count on like six or maybe even 6.5 out of 10 after a year or 18 months. And I think that will make fiber a profitable investment for us.</p>
          <p>I believe that this is so important for our Broadband business because broadband historically has been copper and voice. And the only feature for a fixed network is triple play and fiber in my opinion, and, of course, TV, that's a -. Eurasia, I said I was happy with Eurasia. You can see how we have reduced the dependency on one or two countries. Historically, Kazakhstan and Azerbaijan have been the drivers of Eurasia and the other countries have been relatively small. The fact that we have been extremely successful in Nepal over the past four years has reduced our dependency on Kazakhstan, and it's a more balanced picture today than four years ago. We're obviously very happy with the performance of 12% growth in Eurasia in the quarter and healthy margins, about 50%</p>
          <p>We did decide to change the outlook, not with a lot, but we did decide to change the outlook to indicate that I think the growth rate of 1% to 2% is a bit optimistic, and an EBITDA margin of around 35% is still one of the highest in the industry, if you compare with the portfolio that we have. And we have over the past four years improved it from something like 32%. What we said in the beginning of the year it would be the same as last year, which meant 35.4%, so we offer 35.5% maybe, so we took away 0.5%.</p>
          <p>Of course, we have realized here in the quarter &#x2013; this is old news, but I have to show it anyway. We have realized a lot of value in MegaFon, and you can see it on the cash flow statements, of course, from the quarter. More concerning is the dead-lock situation in Turkcell remains. We were very disappointed that we were not able together with CMB to have the Annual General Meeting where we would have supported both the distribution of dividends, as well as more importantly, increasing the number of independent members.</p>
          <p>What that means is that if you would follow the decree because there's more or less a law, if you would follow that, that would prevent Cukurova from having de facto veto right. So, of course, they're not supporting of it. But I think there's still a possibility that during the fall, with the help of CMB, we might be able to resolve this problem. Ultimately, if we don't, it will be resolved in the Privy Council decision that is expected end of this year, beginning of next year where there's a conflict between Altimo and Cukurova. We're not involved in that, but that conflict makes these decisions impossible to take. And we expect that to be resolved in the Privy Council decision end of this year, beginning of next year.</p>
          <p>I'd like to spend a couple of minutes or at least a few seconds on corporate governance. There have been a lot of discussions during the spring you were all aware of. The framework, we are trying to become more transparent and share how we work on this, and we'll do more work, but we have at least started. And the framework in which we work on corporate governance and CSR, of course, is based first and foremost on international standards and guidelines.</p>
          <p>Then we have our own core values and code of ethics and conduct. We have our corporate governance system and we have risk management and internal audit. So we would like to use the internal audit just to audit this as we audit the numbers or other processes. So that's the framework in which we are building this activity.</p>
          <p>Our current focus, first of all, we still need to comply with the legal and the license-based requirements in every country; in this country and in Norway and Uzbekistan, everywhere. So that's sort of the starting point. We have agreed with the Danish Institute for Human Rights to help us to do humans rights impact assessments. So they will go &#x2013; they're professionals in this, they'll go to the different countries and do an assessment on the impact of what we are doing and what we could do so we get &#x2013; or the active third-party kind of description.</p>
          <p>Systematic implementation of the Group Privacy Policy. And I think personally that the best thing we can do and the most effect of what we can do is actively drive an industry dialog. As an independent company, we can do relatively little, but we are together with 10 or nine other telecom operators driving these discussions, and we were one of the founders of this group. And hopefully, hopefully from that group we will have a bigger impact on these issues and on the governments in several markets.</p>
          <p>So I stop there and give it to Per-Arne.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars.</p>
          <p>Lars talked about the second quarter, now we'll talk about the first half year to start with. As you can see, we reached close to SEK52 billion in net sales, which means an increase of 1.5% in local currencies. We're somewhat below last year EBITDA in absolute terms, SEK17.8 billion. Earnings per share is also somewhat lower than last year, but cash flow radically better. And even though we exclude the cash that we got from the MegaFon deal, we are better than last year. We actually achieved SEK5.2 billion compared to SEK4 billion, SEK4.1 billion.</p>
          <p>In this quarter, we have perhaps something more that we need to explain more in detail than we perhaps normally do. So I will take the opportunity to look a bit more into the net sales, the EBITDA margin and the effect of the gross margin on the EBITDA margin, the non-recurring items that we have big swings in in different direction this quarter, and also talk a bit about our free cash flow and working capital, which is very rarely discussed in this industry.</p>
          <p>As you can see on the previous slides, yes, we have a downturn on the net sales growth and it's very much coming from Mobility. Before we get into the details there, you could also look at broadband that has sort of stabilized on a still negative level, but a bit better than before. And even if you take away the low-margin business from international carrier, they are now below 3% in negative growth. And I think what we could see right now is that IT-based services is getting a momentum. We are not there yet when it comes to an inclination point or &#x2013; but they could overtake the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (12:30), but I think that we are moving in the right direction.</p>
          <p>The slowdown in mobility, that actually went down from a growth of 2.6% to a decline of 2.1% between quarter one and quarter two is connected to a number of different issues. First of all, we have from a market perspective, I could divide it into three different markets, we have the Baltic countries where we have a decline of 6% to 8%. We have not seen a regain in the economy in the Baltics that we had hoped for. We still have price competition in some of the markets, pretty severe. We are also losing in the Norway and Finland between 5% to 6%, and Denmark it's even an outflow with minus 14%. But we're gaining in Sweden and Spain.</p>
          <p>This time, we are losing more on the billed revenue side than we have done before and that, of course, put certain pressure on the margin. It's very odd to say that we are selling less in equipment <mark type="ph" /> and thus will help our multiples. (13:40) It's such a low-margin business. But that's actually a fact.</p>
          <p>So when we look at this <mark type="ph" /> 2 or 3 growth (13:46) I described, you can say that on the billed revenue side, yes, Yoigo continues to increase, even though overall the growth was close to 4%. The billed revenue increased with 18%. We also saw increase in Sweden over 3%, meanwhile, the other markets were minus 7%.</p>
          <p>I think Sweden has continued to deliver very, very good results. We are talking about the 22nd consecutive quarter of growth. And even though we had tough price competition in the second quarter, we added on 42,000 customers. And they are still operating at a EBITDA margin of 42%. So I think it's very, very strong underlying business that we see in Sweden.</p>
          <p>Gross margin that we introduced couple of quarters ago has been the major reason for the impact of the EBITDA side. However, the less growth that we have seen in equipment has actually helped the gross margin to improve somewhat, if you look at the consecutive quarters from Q4 and onwards. But still the higher decline that was in billed revenues put pressure on our margins today.</p>
          <p>We have been able to some extent mitigate this decline on the gross margin with the cost base, addressable cost base, our OpEx, where we are &#x2013; if we compare the quarter in Q2 in 2012 with the quarter in Q2 in 2011, we're roughly SEK1 billion below on a rolling 12-months basis. So we have done I think a good job there.</p>
          <p>But as you can see, even though we have a positive gap between the sales and the cost ratio, we cannot offset the decline that we have on our gross margin. So overall, gross margin is &#x2013; EBITDA margin is down, with close to 1% units on a quarterly basis. And we are now operating around 35% on our rolling-four-quarter basis.</p>
          <p>This time, we have a shift when it comes to the associated companies. We have seen weaker results in Turkcell previously. This time we saw an improvement from Turkcell. And if you remember the Q2 in 2011, we had quite a lot of negative one-offs. It was the devaluation in Belarus and also <mark type="ph" /> the write (16:13) on the goodwill. This is now offset, and they are actually improving the results in more than SEK600 million. The SEK600 million is not only on the one-offs. They also have an operating improvement on the results with close to SEK64 million on the EBIT level.</p>
          <p>Business is growing in Turkey, but if you look at the EBITDA margin, has really gone down now. It's below 30%, so roughly 29%, 30% on EBITDA margin, which is different compared to MegaFon, where we are at roughly 41%, 42%.</p>
          <p>However, in this quarter, we had some hits, especially on the FX side in the MegaFon. You should remember that when we did the deal with MegaFon, they had to borrow money in the market, and they were borrowing roughly SEK35 billion. And what happened here was that they had some kind of currency moments, 1% to 2%, and that created a loss of roughly SEK400 million, SEK500 million on the FX side. And that's what's actually hitting the result today.</p>
          <p>The non-recurring items in Q2, as I said, has been pretty large. First of all, the positive side with the divestment that we made in MegaFon, we generated a net capital gain of SEK3 billion. At the same time, we have also made an impairment of SEK3.1 billion in goodwill. We have looked at the long-term perspective in the markets <mark type="ph" /> all around the chain (17:33) and compared to what we actually paid <mark type="indiscernible" /> (17:39) which we did buy early 2000. And ultimately made a decision to write down these assets with roughly SEK3.1 billion.</p>
          <p>EBIT are more or less at the same level as last year. You can see that from a EBITDA, we are somewhat down, but it's compensated by other non-recurring items. We had a lot of redundancy payments in Q2 last year, which is not repeated in this year. So therefore, we are close to the result that we had last year.</p>
          <p>We also have a weaker result when it comes to net interest income &#x2013; is connected to, first of all, the higher gross debt that we have, creating more interest costs. We also had I'll say FX effect. And what's going on right now is a gradual devaluation, especially in Uzbekistan, that is hitting the FX result and will continue to hit the FX result during this year. I think this is a sound thing that they are doing there, but that will have a negative effect on our results.</p>
          <p>Extremely low tax rates. I have tried to convince my colleagues internally that we should keep the 15%, and no one <mark type="ph" /> guy has agreed (18:59) so I don't think that. Over time, we will probably be at around the 22%, 23% as a normalized rate. But given the things we have done during the second quarter, we went down to 15%, and that has, of course, impacted our result in a very positive way.</p>
          <p>So when you look at the earnings per share, you can see that the taxes are actually giving us another SEK0.12 to our EPS, which ends up at SEK0.98. And if we should take away the one-offs when it comes to MegaFon also the goodwill, we should have had an EPS of SEK1.03, which I think is a good development.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest. <mark type="ph" /> We're rough flat (19:42) more than 14% right now, and we will continue to invest during the year.</p>
          <p>I think it's important to take the opportunity to invest when you have the opportunity. However, I think we start to be much more also cautious to do investment where we did not see that we have returns. So we are working very much with our return on investment in order to make sure that we get the right profitability out of the investment that we are doing.</p>
          <p>Cash flow continued to be with a decently strong SEK3.1 billion underlying in this quarter. You could see that the change in working capital is positively affecting us right now. But even if you take that away, we will have an improvement of the cash flow.</p>
          <p>I think when we look at the change in working capital here, this is more or less a postponement of payments, and that will hit back in the next quarter. I'll come back to the working capital issues that we are facing in this industry right now. You can see that on this picture. We have during the last couple of years actually decreased our working capital. To start with, we have been very fortunate that more or less our customers have funded our business. So we started with a positive, in the sense working capital on SEK5 billion four years ago, which gradually has decreased over time.</p>
          <p>This is actually connected to, first of all, we are moving people from prepaid into postpaid. We have more expensive phones today, 50% higher price per, I will say, a phone, given that we are implementing the smartphones. We're helping the customers to fund this over, let's say, a 22, 23 months and we are paying our suppliers in 30 days. That requires more operating capital or working capital and we are working with that very intensely right now internally to make sure that the new offers that we startup also looking at the payment conditions and also how it affects our cash flow. But I think this an issue that we will see in the whole industry and all operators would have the same pattern as we are having here.</p>
          <p>I am very happy to say that we have started to work with our balance sheet because I think it's necessary going forward to control this kind of movement. We will also look for our payment terms of suppliers in order to improve it. We will also look at the invoicing in terms of <mark type="ph" /> how tolerant customers (22:02) to mitigate the negative outcome of operating capital.</p>
          <p>Finally then, net debt to EBITDA continues to be pretty stable compared to the first quarter. The dividend that we paid and the MegaFon dividend that we received both more or less washed between the tenders, so we still are at 2.0. And the level will be depending on our planned IPOs that we are working with how much that will go down during the year.</p>
          <p>So summarizing the second quarter, net sales unchanged. We have seen a slowdown with the mobility, but is partly compensated by Eurasia and broadband. We have an EBITDA margin that is negative depending on the lower gross margin, and we have an underlying increase in our free cash flow.</p>
          <p>Lars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Per-Arne for that more detailed than usual presentation. I think it was worthwhile given the moving parts in the P&amp;L this time.</p>
          <p>And Lars is also welcome back, and we will start with the Q&amp;A session. And we have a few questions here from the floor and then we will open up for the conference call as well. We start with Sven here on the first row. Please introduce yourself with your name and company name as well. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, Sven Sk&#xF6;ld from Swedbank. First a question on Swedish mobile. I'm a bit surprised first on the positive subscriber intake and on the other hand I'm also surprised by a very weak margin in the second quarter. Can you discuss the quarter and also the outlook for Q3?</p>
          <p>And my second question is about M&amp;A. There have been some rumors in Swedish newspapers about TeliaSonera being interested in selling the Spanish business. Can you comment on that and also on potential M&amp;A in the Danish market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Danish market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Danish market, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we saw a decline in the EBITDA margin in Sweden. You shouldn't forget the absolute number. I mean, it's 42%. I wish you had 42% in some other countries. We are the number one player in the Swedish market and I think we have therefore responsibility in how we act in this marketplace. That's why we did not participate in the price war, or whatever you want to call it, that occurred during the quarter.</p>
          <p>I think if we can stay north of 40% in our home market, I think that's an acceptable result and then not losing market share that's the other point. I think I said already five weeks ago when I came in here that if you have like 40% market share, it's not theoretically sound to think you would like to have more as the number one player. So I must tell you, I'm pretty happy with the position and what happened in the Swedish market in the second quarter. I haven't seen the numbers of the competitors, obviously except three maybe, but Tele2 and Telenor, et cetera. So, I have to wait a little bit to actually see those numbers before I'm really certain how good or how we should see the &#x2013; but the performance in the Swedish market, I mean, Per-Arne was saying we have been growing for 22 consecutive quarters, it's pretty good I would argue, so.</p>
          <p>With regard to the rumors about Yoigo, I mean, first of all, we don't comment on those kind of rumors, but I mean there is no secret that I have said one day we will see if we can sell Yoigo. That's not secret. I want them to play the second half, so that's what I have said and now there are rumors and tomorrow there will be other rumors. We learned long term ago not to comment on the rumors. And Denmark, there must be rumors and I don't comment on the rumors. So I don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just put some more flavor on the Swedish market, if I may. Remember that there was a one-off item in Q2 last year, so the margin in Q2 last year was a little bit artificially high. So the drop year-on-year is more 1% than the 3% reported. And I think the feeling is that the competitive environment is a little bit more stable now than it was in the beginning of the Q2. I am sure there are aggressive offers out there in the market, but not by a mile as aggressive as they were in the beginning of March or April. So, a little bit more rationale competitive environment now at the end of the second quarter. We can leave the microphones to Stefan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Stefan Gauffin, Nordea. First of all, I would like to come back to the margin in Swedish mobile and just if you can quantify the extra cost for retention caused by the campaigns by Tele2 and 3, just to &#x2013; sort of the extra cost for that.</p>
          <p>Secondly, I was a bit surprised by the strong subscriber intake in Spain, given that we have seen the regulators numbers for April and May and you also say that you have launched new offers in June. So, could you say something about the development during the quarter on subscriber intake, is the massive subscriber intake in June or &#x2013; and then also I was a little bit surprised by the ARPU development in Spain. I know there was interconnect cuts, but what kind of impact did the offer have on the ARPU development?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those I think was a record in the level of detail question that we had in a long time. Where shall we start? Apparently, my margin explanation was not enough on Swedish mobile. Per-Arne, I'll leave that to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think that, first, we did not really quantify the extra cost we have, if we have had extra cost for the marketing. Then if you look at the retention, I mean, we have had a very low churn rates still in Sweden, more or less at the same rate. There has not really a decrease or increases. It's still at 15%, 16%. So I think you have to remember the 42% is a very, very good margin. I think that's where you should stay.</p>
          <p>If you then take Spain, you have to remember that during the second quarter, we have had a severe financial crisis that more or less exploded at the beginning of June, and of course that affects the market conditions as such. And it will be interesting to see, as Lars said, what has happened with the other operators when they come out. That's why I highlighted that the billed revenue is actually increasing with 18%. We have a good net intake of customers which means that we are doing something right in the market.</p>
          <p>I don't want to go into the details how it looks during the quarter. But we're talking about the quarter. The operating model works pretty well right now with the market conditions we have in Spain, but of course it's very, very tough market given the financial environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and as I have said, we have to wait until we see the competitors' numbers, but I mean Telefonica reported for the first quarter a decline of 18%, and we have an increase in the second quarter. We will see what they say about second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We take one more question from the floor. Andreas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Andreas Joelsson, Enskilda. And a question on Turkcell. Do you think it is a possibility to have another AGM before the Privy Council has said their ruling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think there is a possibility and I hope it would happen. I think it's in everybody's &#x2013; nearly everybody's interest.</p>
          <p>And I realize that Cukurova, it's not in their interest, because the de facto as I said before they have a veto right as long as we don't have more independent directors. But now the Turkish authorities has decided that the biggest 30 companies in Turkey should have an certain number of independent directors.</p>
          <p>We are very supportive of this. This has been discussed for years. It is now a decree, a law, which Turkcell has to comply with. Common sense. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:22) soon. But I think CMB has a responsibility to help to create that AGM. So I am really trying &#x2013; or we are focused on working on it trying to help to get there.</p>
          <p>Now, if we don't get there in the fall, the issue, as I said, will be resolved I think by the Privy Council decision end of this year, beginning of next year. The company is doing somewhat better now, but I still believe that this is a big distraction for management, has been for two years now and has affected the performance of the company. So it should be in most people's interest to resolve this issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>May I also ask on Finland and the performance there and how you should turn the Finnish operation now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think we have to be honest. I think we've been beaten the last four to eight quarters. And I felt that &#x2013; we felt this already a year ago and that's why we made some changes. We did change the organization structure in Finland by appointing a Head of Sonera in Finland, Robert Andersson who joined us in May, I believe. I think that will make a big difference, because Sonera is a big company and they need a face, public face who is responsible for Sonera, who is Mr. Sonera, who is there every day.</p>
          <p>So, I think that plus what I call the some multi-market operation, it's all about the product portfolio also. It's not only about the performance of individual people, it's also about having an attractive product portfolio and particularly in B2C, I think we have been losing more than B2B. So, I think we know the challenge and I have some confidence that we will at least gain something back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll leave the world on the questions to the conference call. Operator, can we have the first question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>First question from the line of Andy Parnis. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, guys. It's Andy Parnis at UBS. I've two questions. The first one is sort of a bigger picture question. So, what kind of growth fell to 0% or flat in the quarter? Do you think it's now possible to get this sort of back positive, back above 1%, 2%, 3% in the sort of medium term, or should we now expect to be flat or even slightly negative going forward?</p>
          <p>And then second question, I guess probably related is on Danish service revenues seems to come in around minus 20% in the quarter. Are you worried that this is also going to turn a bit more negative now, 3 seems to have lowered its pricing on its main brand and reintroduced subsidies into the market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if I look &#x2013; this is Lars, if I look longer term, not like next quarter or this year, the answer on growth in mobility is going to be data. I don't think you're going to see growth on voice. Actually I think we will see further declines on voice. So, changing the business model to a data pricing which is very strongly related to how much you consume, I think, is going to be the answer.</p>
          <p>Now, the fundamental was good, is that the service of surfing on the mobile is something people like. You look at the roaming prices. We reduced the roaming prices, we're one of the first operators in the world a year ago, quite dramatically for Nordic and the Baltic and then we went more or less to the rest of the world in the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>We can see how the traffic is growing very rapidly in mobile data outside of Sweden. When Swedes go to the other countries and they know it's a SEK49 per day and if you feel safe with it and I think is a reasonable price, they start surfing. And so there is an underlying need for our services. So that's a good thing. The question is, can we monetize it? So, that's why I showed you the picture where we have a 90% growth in volume and a 30% growth in revenues, still relatively small number compared to the voice business, but that's going to be the challenge.</p>
          <p>We look three years from now, we're going to have another balance between the source of revenue being voice and being data. Data going to be the big portion of the revenue compared to voice. And if you have a flat fee on voice like the Verizon introduced, like I expect the industry to go towards, the key is going to be data, and an underlying demand for it, I think, is unlimited. The appetite for bandwidth is unlimited. So I don't think the fundamentals are wrong, I think we have a transition period as an industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Denmark, yes, I mean, they have had a very &#x2013; another very tough quarter and I don't know how much actually this will be impacted by the new offerings from 3, but what I know from our side is that we also tried to gain some kind of momentum with our 4G launch that we have made, and I hope that, that will help us somewhat to improve the numbers over time. But Denmark is a tough market and you should remember that we have a pretty large number of MVNOs that are also pushing down the prices, it's not just only 3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think back to this business model a little bit. In a market with three or four players, the number one player has a special responsibility, I think, on how to act. I think we take that responsibility in the Swedish market. I believe Telenor, at least, sometimes take that responsibility in the Norwegian market. And TDC does not take that responsible in Danish market. TDC has more than three, I think, fighting brands that are pushing down the prices in the whole marketplace. They don't disclose for good reasons I suppose the EBITDA margin any longer on mobility.</p>
          <p>Last time they did this a couple of years ago, it was 30 and it's not higher today, I can guarantee you. So if the number one player has 30, then the market is going to be very difficult for three or four players. And the consequence of that is, that if you want to us to invest more money, we're going to be hesitant. So this is an issue I think, it's a balance for the regulators to ensure that we have investments in the marketplace to have a modern infrastructure. At the same time, you need to have a return on investment and the current profitability in Denmark, I'm not interested to invest much more in Denmark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy. Will you take the next question, operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Dominik Klarmann. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, thank you. Dominik Klarmann, HSBC. Question on the fixed line side of the business, I would be interested in your take on the EC proposal on fiber regulation from last week. And connected to that, in Sweden broadband <mark type="ph" /> offshore (37:21) is already growing nicely, thanks to fiber and apparently demand is picking up. So I'm wondering how confident you are that we see a revenue inflect from the minus 3.6% currently? And how far you think that is away?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, on the EU statement the other day, I have spent quite some time together with the colleagues in the industry. We have an association called DSMA and I'm on the board there. And we have spent quite some time in the last two years trying to understand Neelie Kroes and EU. Their ambition, their prime ambition is to ensure that it is invested in the telecom infrastructure in Europe, because they believe and I think they are absolutely right, it is going to be a prerequisite for growth of the economy in Europe is that we have a modern competitive telecom environment. We have argued that if you want that to happen, then you've got to give us some stability on the outlook for the investment. We have got to have some sort of return on that investment and the rules around the business got to be fairly stable.</p>
          <p>I think some of our investors actually had a conversation with Neelie Kroes before the vacation and they argue the same thing. And I think what we saw is a result of that discussion that Brussels has understood that if they are going to have these very huge investments, we're talking maybe &#x20AC;100 billion kind of investment over a number of years, of course, if we're going to see that kind of investment, we got to have some stability in the environment. And I think what they did, they gave us some hope for stability, which I think is very positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My second question was on Swedish fiber more in detail, the inflection point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think fiber has been very attractive for the market. I think our problem a year ago was actually to practically roll out and deliver the fiber to our customers. We struggled quite a bit doing that unfortunately, which meant that a year ago said, we're going to stop marketing this too much, we've got to get our processes in order and make sure that if we say we're going to deliver in three weeks, we can deliver in three weeks.</p>
          <p>Even Per-Arne himself has been involved in that project to ensure that we improve. I think we have improved and it's very interesting, it's very encouraging when you talk to people who finally got their fiber, maybe three months too late, once they got it, they are very happy with it. And so I think this is a great opportunity. Of course, we won't roll fiber to every household in Sweden, but both multi-dwelling units and single-dwelling units are I think both interesting segments. And I'm all in favor of rolling fiber and rolling it faster.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was that okay, Dominik?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks a lot. I mean, would you stick out your nose and now give a medium-term outlook in terms of what that means for Swedish fixed line revenue trend, say, on a three to five-year horizon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's too early to do that because, I'll tell you, honestly, I felt only months ago that we could start thinking about pushing the button to increase the rollout, and I want to see some results. I shared with you that in the last rollout, we have about 40% take-up. I want to see the second wave because 40% is not enough and we will see that during the fall, we rolled in the north part of Stockholm, for instance, a year ago and we are now getting into the second wave. And I think a lot of people who said no thank you, then will say yes please now. If we can get like the 60% penetration, I think we have a business model that's going to work very nicely for us. But I will maybe be able to speculate on those numbers towards the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dom. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Andrew Lee [of Goldman Sachs]. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thanks for taking my call. Just first question on Swedish mobile, sorry to come back to that again. I understand margins are high, but following the end of the 3 and Tele2 promotions in March and April, I would seem to see an increased marketing and retention spend from you and further promotions from 3. So I wonder if you could just comment a bit more specifically on whether you think the marketplace is now more aggressive or unsettled than it was before March.</p>
          <p>And then second question, hypothetically, if you did have any assets sales over the next few months, would your preferred use of cash be further paying down of debt or do you consider distributing by dividends or share buybacks? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can start with the second question first. It's the leverage that we are working on right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think the Swedish market is different now than it was in January. Not much anyway. It was an interesting period of a couple of weeks. And I think it has stabilized. It can change again. I mean, this is business, but that's how we feel about the market right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would answer the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to answer the deleverage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Deleverage. It's very short. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:13)...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Clear. (43:20) Well, good. Next one, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Peter Nielsen [of CAI Cheuvreux]. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Yes, Lars, you've already discussed it tend to be sort of the bigger issues in mobile and broadband, so a couple of a smaller items, if you will. Firstly, is this still your intention in Sweden to start charging for mobile apps around this summer time? And if so, have you had any discussions or indications from the regulator whether they might have any objections to this? And secondly, are there any &#x2013; at the present time any updates on the MegaFon or Kazakhstan IPOs timing, et cetera? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we did was, we introduced separate charge for mobile VoIP in Spain as a past case, that's what we did and then we said somehow we got to manage this transition between voice and data. And I think the most likely outcome I think is that we are probably going to include IP in the bigger packages, maybe in the smallest entrants packages they might not be included, but I really think the solution to this issue is the industry is going to go towards flat fee for voice and messages. And then it doesn't matter anymore, because if you can call as many minutes you like domestically in Sweden, why would you use anything else than that service.</p>
          <p>But this is a discussion that industry is having and we haven't made any final decisions on how we're going to do with and when we're going to do things. But I'll repeat again, the whole industry is challenged with the business model change. For 100 years, this industry has got all its revenue from the voice service. That will change dramatically in the coming five years. The majority of the revenues will come from data, not from voice. And that's very exciting. It's a little bit uncomfortable because it is the numbers we talk about, but I think this is a very natural progression, seen what has happened with technology is all about data. It is going to be all about data, not voice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are you anymore concerned or reassured now than a year ago that the industry will succeed and get paid from its customer last?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think what the issue is, is that as an industry we need to maintain the ARPUs that we have today. Of course, if the industry would lose half of its revenue, then we have a real problem. I don't think that is going to happen. I think we are going to maybe have some bumps on the road, but I think we will basically see the same kind of ARPUs, but it is defined differently, much smaller portion called voice and a bigger portion called data. I think that's exactly what is happening in the United States right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:22), I mean we are working with the preparations for this, but we haven't disclosed any time plans. I think we need to have a sort of solid IPO market to do these kind of all transactions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we are doing the preparations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are doing the preparations, right. So we are -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will be ready at somewhere in the fall. Whether the market is ready, we will see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Jakob Bluestone [of Credit Suisse]. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Thank you. I've got two pretty quick questions. Firstly, just to follow up on Andrew's question on use of cash flow in the event of further asset disposals, could you just remind us what sort of net debt to EBITDA you're targeting? And then, secondly, just kind of referring back to the slides you had on working capital in your presentation, I mean, what is your expectation of how working capital continues to develop from here? Do you think it will continue to become more negative or do you think you can reverse that trend? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, start with the working capital, I don't think that we could reverse that trend in a short-term perspective. I think that will continue as long as we are now phasing out sort of the old pricing model into the new one, and we really have to mitigate this with our other kind of activities and looking order payments, conditions we have to our suppliers <mark type="ph" /> and then also how we found this (47:43). I think this will be an ongoing thing for the next, I don't know, one, two, three years.</p>
          <p>And then coming back to the net debt to EBITDA ratio, we have said that we should be between 1.5% and 2%, that's the target range we have right now and that remains so. And now we are operating at 2%, so of course, I mean that's why we're talking about that we would like to deleverage with the proceeds that we get there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's also clear, I mean, if you do the predictions, if you assume the IPOs happening et cetera, we will get to 1.5 relatively quickly and actually provided we just continue to generate these cash flows, we'll go below 1.5 and then at that point in time, I'm sure the board will pick the appropriate decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's discuss that at that point when we got the money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:31). Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from the line of Laurie Fitzjohn-Sykes [of Citi]. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning. Firstly, on guidance. It implies the margin improvement in the second half. Could you give us some color on which divisions you expect this improvement from? Is lower promotions in Sweden is going to factor? Then secondly, looking at a bigger picture, you're talking about the need to restructure tariff, but can you just give us an update on Sweden, how much of service revenue at the moment is still from variable charging for voice and text and how the progress currently in Sweden restructuring tariffs there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the last question I can't answer out of my head, but on the first one, I think the main driver of the second half is always the third quarter. You know third quarter is always the strongest, the best margin in all four quarters, so I think that's the major contributor to the improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you look at 12-month or four-quarter rolling as Per-Arne show, we are at 34.9% now in the second quarter. So it's purely math that we'll get to the 35% due to a stronger Q3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:41) the 4.9, not the 5.1. I mean, from a <mark type="ph" /> book-to-loan (49:50) perspective, this is a very small amount. So we're trying to indicate that this is the rate that I think we will operate on, so to give you sort of the bigger picture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question I think was the split of revenues in Swedish mobile, if I understood you correctly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've shown you that in the past. We didn't show you this quarter. But voice and messaging is around 50% of mobile revenues in Sweden.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thomas have been waving here from the floor for a time. We take one question here from the floor before going back to the number of questions on the conference call. But Thomas, in the meantime.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thomas Heath here from Handelsbanken. Two question if I may.</p>
          <p>You talked about the shift in price model for mobile data and how this is going to pressure mobile for some time. Where do you sort of foresee that the pressure &#x2013; if voice becomes flat priced, do you lose on the high-end customers trading down? Or is it the low end customers getting voice for free that's the problem?</p>
          <p>I mean if we look now we can see a fast transition of tariffs on the high end to bucket plans. But all the low-end plans are still based on call setup charges and per minute. So if we're going to feel pressure here over a few years, where do you expect to see it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, why is somebody going to choose us? It's not all about price. I think we are too focused sometimes on price, and are we going to lose in the low level or high ARPU?</p>
          <p>I generally believe that our customers choose Telia because we have better network quality or they perceive that we have better network quality, and the most important is the customer service. We are so dependent on these services, these phones, that if there is a problem, you want it to be resolved simple and quickly. And I've been arguing for five years that these two points are the two out of three priorities with TeliaSonera.</p>
          <p>Yes, I do agree, price is not unimportant, and yes, we can analyze whether we're going to lose there or there or there. But fundamentally, we're going to win this battle if we have the best quality in the network, and if we have world-class customer experience when you deal with Telia in Sweden or Sonera in Finland. That is what the priorities are.</p>
          <p>And I think we will win if we are successful, and we are working extremely hard on it. That's why I was happy I got the question on customer service in broadband, which was a real problem year ago, year and a half ago, and has improved quite dramatically. It's not where it needs to be, but it has improved. And I am convinced that has a bigger impact than &#x2013; or whether we are 10% cheaper or more expensive than a competitor at a certain point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second question then on &#x2013; like you mentioned on Swedish broadband. It sounds that you're more optimistic, I mean. And if we could &#x2013; what's the potential that we speed up a rollout significantly?</p>
          <p>Previously, you targeted single dwelling units and almost left the MDUs alone. I mean, for example, a Stockholm <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:55) property where there is already coax, is that sort of something you could go after with fiber, if you sort of rollout more aggressively?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're always ahead of us, guys. We need to think a little bit before we decide.</p>
          <p>And I just said to you that I think we have a higher level of confidence that we can rollout and deliver the way we said. I won't see that happen now in the fall. If it happens, then I will put pressure up a little bit, but I'm not prepared to say, oh, now we go full out, because I don't think we are ready for it.</p>
          <p>But I am convinced that fiber is a very important part of TeliaSonera 5 or 10 years from now. I am absolutely convinced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We go back to the conference call, operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Ulrich Rathe [of Jefferies]. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. And two questions, please.</p>
          <p>The first one is on the downgrade &#x2013; sort of the lower expectations for the full year. If you take a step back and try to sort of tell us where ultimately you had to lower expectations? Is it because of competition because of the macro environment? Or because of TeliaSonera's specific execution? Sort of in those three buckets. I would be interested to see where you see the sort of a main reason.</p>
          <p>And the second question is very specific on Turkcell. Is there any process or a legal possibility to have Turkcell pay a dividend without simultaneously settling the board of directors issue. Is there any way sort of to essentially agree on the side on the dividend and then leave that other issue for some other process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the last question, theoretically, yes. But you have to have an AGM, and you have to have a decision on the AGM on both the independent directors as well as on the dividend. So there's nothing we can do outside of an AGM.</p>
          <p>On the issue of growth, I mean, I think if you look back when we started the year, I think the growth rate or actually the decline in mobility is the main reason why we were pretty hesitant than when we went into the year. Because we actually said 1% to 2%, and several of you guys said that was conservative. And it turned out a little bit too optimistic, actually.</p>
          <p>And the main reason is mobility. And again, what is then in mobility? Well, it's a combination of a number of things.</p>
          <p>Spain is not the engine of growth it has been. It's nothing to do <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:49), it has to do with the macroeconomics in Spain.</p>
          <p>Sweden has been growing, and I've been saying many times and you heard me say I'm surprised we can continue to grow that kind of growth rate in Sweden. Now we come down to 3.5% or 3.6%, which is maybe a more normal growth rate.</p>
          <p>The economies &#x2013; the macro-economies in the Baltics states have not improved for &#x2013; at least not for the telecom operators yet. So that's not helping us. And then we have the Danish situation and the Finnish situation.</p>
          <p>So it's all mobile. It's macroeconomics in several countries. It is some execution of ourselves, and particularly in Finland. And there is a business situation in Denmark that is different from other markets. So there are several explanations to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ulrich. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Barry Zeitoune. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Barry Zeitoune from Berenberg. I've got three questions.</p>
          <p>Just going back to Finland, I'd like to &#x2013; I know that you've hired somebody else now that's going to be running that business and that will make a difference. But if I look over the longer term, we've seen declines of market share in the region of 5, 6 percentage points over the last three years. Do you feel like you need to do something more radical in Finland to really win back market share and win back the brand? And have you decided which brand you're focused on yet, whether it's the Sonera brand or the Tele Finland brand?</p>
          <p>And then my second question is really on how you allocate capital. You talked about paying down net debt. And it's very clear that once the IPO proceeds are in, you're going to be in a more favorable scenario. But as we're seeing growth slow &#x2013; and potentially I know you won't talk about it, but if you were to sell Spain, that would also be kind of one key growth component loss. You've been very good at acquiring growth in the last couple of years specifically with Nepal. So are there opportunities out there that you're looking at? And do you think acquiring good growth would be a strategy that you would like to use some of your capital for?</p>
          <p>And my final question is really just looking at MegaFon and the recent deal with Yota. So I saw that Mr. Usmanov has consolidated his holding of MegaFon with Yota. And I was just interesting &#x2013; interested why that didn't happen at the MegaFon level and why you wouldn't have wanted it to happen at the MegaFon level? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the last question is more for Mr. Usmanov to answer. I mean, we did the deal we did, and we were happy with that deal. Mr. Usmanov has many assets and wider ambitions, I think, than TeliaSonera as a telecom operator. So I have no further comment on what he did or didn't do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>M&amp;A?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, M&amp;A, we have &#x2013; I think we have executed the M&amp;A strategy for the last three, four years that we said we would. We would like to increase our ownership in particularly in Eurasia.</p>
          <p>We had relatively small ownership, like 51%. And in practice actually in Kcell we had much less than that. And we have increased in nearly every country, which clearly helps us with the EPS with Kcell particularly.</p>
          <p>There aren't many opportunities to increase ownership in existing businesses anymore. And yes, of course there are some opportunities in that region that we are looking at. I think we have a track record of being conservative. We don't want to overpay. So sometimes we can't do the deal because we think it's too expensive.</p>
          <p>But yes, if I could buy, at a decent price, growth in Eurasia, I'd be very interested in that, obviously.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My first question was Finland, the radical changes...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think firstly you asked about the brand Sonera and Tele Finland. we'll keep both.</p>
          <p>I actually think it's more blocking and tackling &#x2013; or lack of good blocking and tackling &#x2013; than radical change in Finland.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Barry. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Terence Tsui. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, it's Terence from Morgan Stanley. I just have two quick questions please.</p>
          <p>Firstly, on Spain, do you think we could see the imminent return of handset subsidies into the market now, especially given that the monthly data which was referred to earlier was weak for the major operators, but also just on the smaller ones, as well?</p>
          <p>And secondly, maybe you can just give us a quick update on how's it going with the sales of your LTE smartphones? What's the data usage like there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You start with the smartphones or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think it's a little bit too early. Actually, we don't have enough volumes to see actually a good pattern of the data usage level. We have to get back to that on the next quarter or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to subsidies on hardware, it's obviously not in the operators' interest. And if we could reduce &#x2013; eliminate or reduce subsidies on terminals, we certainly will be supportive of that.</p>
          <p>I must, though, say to you, I am not sure it will happen. I'll be happy if we could reduce the subsidies or at least have them on a manageable level. But totally eliminate subsidies, I think, is difficult. Because fundamentally, our customers goes into a Telia shop or whatever, and says I want to buy phone X. They don't come into the shop and say I want price plan A. They come in and say I want to buy a Galaxy 2, and what sort of price plans are you going to combine that with?</p>
          <p>So if the customers are really buying a phone more than buying a price plan, then subsidies are probably going to be there for the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Terence. We have two more, so we take them before closing this conference call. Next question please, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question from the line of Lena &#xD6;sterberg [of Carnegie]. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, guys. Just wondering a little bit on &#x2013; you've been very good historically at cutting costs to offset the margin decline, but current quarter still has not really materialized. <mark type="ph" /> Instead you've (1:02:47) taken some restructuring charges in early quarters for cost cutting.</p>
          <p>So I was wondering if you are a bit delayed or if it's more difficult to cut costs now, and what we should expect for margins going into next year? Then also, if you maybe could give us some guidance on the restructuring charge for the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the cost cutting. I think that we have so far managed the cost cutting quite well. I mean, we are on a half-year basis down <mark type="ph" /> the 2% (1:03:16) on the cost. But we have also said that we are somewhat delayed in certain areas, and we'll need to speed up the present plans. So that's correct.</p>
          <p>We don't give any guidance on sort of the restructuring charges for this year. So if it occurs, we will tell you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I could add something to it. I mean, we spent, as you said, Lena, we've been pretty good at managing the OpEx. And we spent very much focus on the OpEx.</p>
          <p>I think the focus will now move away a little bit from the OpEx &#x2013; continue to manage that &#x2013; to the cost of goods sold. Because that's where we have the pressure. It's on the gross margin we have the pressure. And we have probably more cost in kroners calculated as cost of goods sold internal cost compared to OpEx, or at least similar amount of numbers. Much more complicated, but it's something we will have to be focusing on going forward, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's what I actually talked about at the Capital Markets Day, where we said that we will focus on this. Because we will increase the cost base from roughly SEK30 billion perhaps up to SEK60 billion, SEK70 billion <mark type="ph" /> I think to work with (1:04:21).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I ask you how much of the COGS is actually addressable for you to work with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Enough. Enough. Yeah, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But as a percentage of the total COGS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I don't want to give you that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a lot of money, Lena.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a lot of money. But I mean, if you really want to do the analysis, you need to sit down and really understand what is addressable, as you say. Because that's the keyword. What of that amount is addressable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it also differs from mobile to broadband.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's two different business areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lena. Let's take the final question, please, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>And your final question from the line of James Britton [of Nomura]. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, guys. First question on Finland, can you give us an idea of the incentive measures you've put in place for the new President of Finland?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, when you talk about the business model transition, I struggle a little bit to understand why this is really taking effect now because your Nordic markets have the most advanced smartphone penetration, and in Europe, not that far behind the States. So why the cannibalization is taking effect now as opposed to what we saw with KPN last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm not saying that cannibalization starts now, I think we have been managing this thing pretty well as an industry. What I'm saying is that over the coming two, three, four years, the whole industry will change, not just Nordic. And actually, as I said, I think, in the US, they are sort of leading the change with Verizon's offer. And that's going to be a very exciting journey, a bit scary as well.</p>
          <p>So, I'm not trying to explain anything that happened in the quarter, I'm just saying I can see a trend whereby voice will be a much smaller part of our revenues and data has to become a much bigger part of our revenues and I think there might be a chance that voice will be charged on a flat fee basis, data can never be charged on a flat fee basis, I've been arguing that for four, five years and I think most operators agree with that now. So it's not trying to explain something that happened in the quarter, it's really trying to explain how does the environment look like for a telecom operator going forward, let's say, two, three, four years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I may add to this, if you look at Sweden today, I mean, they are growing the billed revenues with 3% and the messaging is still increasing 2%, increasing the data with <mark type="ph" /> 16% and voice is down (1:07:08) 4%, but still pretty stable in Sweden.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just to be clear on that point, you talked about a lot of growth for few quarters from now, but that's not linked to the business model transition that you've been talking about today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we're unaffected by, but that's not the major reason, that's not the major reason. On the last question, the first question you had, Robert Andersson is also a member of the group management of this company and as you're all aware since three, four years back the 10 people in the group management had no variable pay. So he has a fixed salary and a pension.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think that was the final question and despite the bad weather, we wish you a nice summer and see you all back in October. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>