<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1245075" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2927</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m, Vice President, Group Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lars Nyberg, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Per-Arne Blomquist, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Lena &#xD6;sterberg</participant>
      <participant id="4">Stefan Pettersson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6">Peter Kurt Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="7">Thierry Cota</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jan Dworsky</participant>
      <participant id="9">Stefan Billing</participant>
      <participant id="10">Lars S&#xF6;derfjell</participant>
      <participant id="11">Michael Andersson</participant>
      <participant id="12">Damien Maltarp</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, everyone and welcome to this busy reporting day. My name is Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m, Head of Investor Relations. We will share with you today our thoughts on the second quarter report. With me, I have our CEO and President, Lars Nyberg, as well as our CFO, Mr. Per-Arne Blomquist. We will start with a brief presentation by Lars, followed by a review of the financials by Per-Arne and we will then open up for a Q&amp;A session, both from the floor and over the telephone conference.</p>
          <p>With that, I leave the floor to Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Welcome all of you and TeliaSonera's performance I think is strong. We had a good quarter in a very tough economic environment. Our sales grew almost 9% in the quarter. EBITDA was up 13% and cash flow by as much as 42%. Having said that, I want to point out that we actually manage this company in local currencies, as the Swedish krona is so volatile and in my opinion distorts the picture. Therefore I will relate to actual developments in local currency in my presentation today.</p>
          <p>Top-line growth was more or less flat in local currency so the improvement of profitability and cash flow is actually driven by actions that we can control ourselves, cost reduction and careful capital spending. For years, we have been talking about cost reductions without showing any evidence of it. Now we have worked hard for two years and finally have the numbers to prove that we are able to turn continuous annual cost increases to real cost reductions.</p>
          <p>The same with cash flow. For the first time in many years, we are scrutinizing CapEx in its details and as a result, we generated a very strong cash flow. For the first half of this year, we have kept tight rein on CapEx and our investments are therefore somewhat back-end loaded, but for the year as a whole, CapEx will be lower than last year and this is needed. The telecom industry is not affected as much as other &#x2013; many other industries by the economic downturn, but we don't fool ourselves. We are and we will be affected by it. As GDP goes down and unemployment rises, our industry will also suffer. But I believe we are well prepared for it.</p>
          <p>If you now look at our 20 markets, they are at different stages. Eurasia is a positive surprise in the quarter with organic growth picking up compared to the first quarter and we maintained a very impressive EBITDA margin of 50% as a result of tight cost controls and a balanced growth approach. We maintained our leading market position and traffic volumes continued to grow but prices are under pressure.</p>
          <p>Sales grew in all countries except Azerbaijan and Georgia, which in addition to the recession have been affected by internal political problems. Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan, Tajikistan, all experienced strong revenue growth and an increasing number of subscribers. And our most recent acquisition, the business in Nepal contributed to the revenue growth.</p>
          <p>TeliaSonera now has more mobile subscribes in our majority-owned operations in Eurasia than we have in the Nordic and the Baltic markets together. The number of subscribers now exceeds 20 million. Mobile penetration rates are substantially lower in these countries than they are in the Nordic and the Baltics. And voice is still the dominant service. Therefore, the growth potential in Eurasia is significant, both by growing the number of customers and expanding our services.</p>
          <p>Mobility Service in the Nordic countries outside of Sweden feel the pressure both on the top line and on the margin. In Sweden, we added yet another great quarter. But in view of the expected rise in unemployment in this country, we believe the pressure is on for the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>The Baltic States are already there. But as a result of our priorities when economies contracts namely we give up volume first, then we give up EBITDA in absolute terms and we fight for the margin. We have lost revenues in the Baltic States, but we managed to protect margins as this illustration shows you.</p>
          <p>The recession has so far had a limited impact on our Broadband Services. This business is changing. The migration from traditional fixed-voice services to mobile or IP-based services continues. Demand for IP-based services is increasing and these services now represent more than a third of the revenues in broadband. The price increase on fixed telephony here in Sweden, which was introduced in the first quarter to offset the declining volumes only had a modest effect on revenues in the quarter. Our IPTV revenues tripled and IP Telephony revenues increased by more than four times, as a result of more subscribers and higher level of usage. This is by no means a dying business.</p>
          <p>On the contrary, I believe that the appetite for increased bandwidth is virtually unlimited. And we will continue to invest in fixed connections, as we believe that the fixed access to point &#x2013; to fixed points, such as homes and offices will be the best solution when it comes to meeting our increasing communication needs for many years to come. Watching TV in high definition, downloading films, taking part in video conferencing will require high transmission speeds and high reliability. In these respects, the fixed network is superior to the mobile network.</p>
          <p>As I said, we have worked hard with our OpEx for the last two years and at the end of last year, we finally got traction in broadband, realizing the urgency of making sure that costs come down to safeguard our long-term profitability in this business. Broadband Services have done a great job in reducing cost and delivering a margin we should all be pleased with. The cost reductions are both related to tighter cost control and personnel reductions. Since the beginning of the year, the number of employees has been reduced by some 1,250 people, primarily within Broadband Service in Sweden, Finland, and head office functions.</p>
          <p>For the Group as a whole, we actually reduced operating expenses by more than 4% in the first half of 2009 and close to 6% in the second quarter. If you take a closer look at the second quarter, we reduced operating expenses for Sweden and Finland by as much as 12% and that is in my opinion quite an achievement. Negotiations with the labor unions have been tough, but constructive. Competence has been as important as length of employment and we have thereby been able to safeguard critical competence in the company and maintained the age structure. We now work under the same principle as the rest of the Swedish industry when it comes to unions. We are on a journey and I believe we are making quite a bit of progress.</p>
          <p>There are some really interesting strategic opportunities and challenges ahead of us, which we will share with you during our Investor Day on September 7 and I hope you all will be there. So let me summarize. We had a very good quarter. Top line is flat in local currencies. Costs are down and our EBITDA margin and our EPS are both up. We are encouraged by these developments and we believe that the top line for the Group will be around or slightly below the level of last year while we expect OpEx in local currencies to be lower than last year and therefore, we raise our outlook for EBITDA margin and expect it to be higher in '09 compared to '08.</p>
          <p>We also continue to be careful in relationship to capital spending and we expect to reduce it to 13 to 14% on Group sales compared to the 15% of last year. All in all, I believe a strong quarter and a good outlook in a very difficult year.</p>
          <p>Now over to Per-Arne to go through the details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Lars. I think it's very nice to be pleased, I should say for at least for an hour or two when we are presenting this result and I think that we all be confident with what we have produced in the last quarter, but not only that, also the first half year. And I will make some small comments upon the first half year and also second &#x2013; the quarter based on the reported figures for a very obvious reason, just for comparability with other companies. We are reporting on the local currency perspective, but just so you can compare it to what other companies has reported this week.</p>
          <p>And first of all, if you look at all the signs in the second quarter, we had a strong development, 9% growth on net sales, we are improving result from maybe say eight up to 13% depending on different result levels. Especially cash flow is strong, and I think I'm very pleased with that right now. In this situation in this market, we need to focus on cash flow. We have done that and we have also succeeded to deliver a strong cash flow as such.</p>
          <p>The tendency, if you look at the first half is also more or less the same, growth of 10%, and we have an EBITDA increase of 14% and down to EPS, an increase of 4%, and here you could also see the free cash flow is up with 117%, extremely strong in this environment. However, what I think perhaps is most important in these two pictures is actually the increase of the EBITDA margin. There, you could sort of more or less neutralize sort of the effect of the currencies. But it is actually based on, first of all, a strong trend &#x2013; a reported trend on net sales. But above all, the change of especially the cost behavior that Lars talked about. And that means that if you look at the quarters right now, the last two quarters, we have changed the pattern. If we should have gone back, let's say another three or four quarters, we should have seen a rather dramatic decrease on the EBITDA level for the Group. We have been flat now at close to 32% during couple of quarters, and we are now exceeding the 32%. And behind that, we have you could say different patterns. First of all, high stable margins in Eurasia, close to 50% over time. They are very good in balancing the growth, good in balancing the cost spending to keep up this margin.</p>
          <p>We could also see a shift when it comes to broadband. They are now up to 29.4 and here we are talking about rolling four quarters, which means that they are close to the level of Q1 2008. Where we see more problems is, of course, in the Mobility Services even though we have some strong areas for the Mobility which I will come back to, they are going down and that's the reason also why we're focused so much right now on the cost side with the Mobility. We have seen the effects what it does to their margins when we talk about the Broadband and we are now also focusing in the same way on the Mobility side.</p>
          <p>Mobile as such has been influenced by the economical environment. We could definitely see impacts when it comes to minutes of use, we could definitely see impact when it comes to ARPU. I think we could claim that we are partly stable on the price levels or what level it is slightly negative than, let's say, overall the prices are kept up, which I think is a strong sign.</p>
          <p>When I look at Mobility, I'll try to divide it more or less into four different areas. First of all, we have Sweden. Strong growth still, 5% this year and they have also been successful in improving the margins, going up to 39% which is an improvement of 2% even if you compare it quarters-on-quarters. We then have another sector, which is then Finland, Norway and Denmark where we are down between four to 10%, talking about underlying business and in local currencies.</p>
          <p>First out here is Norway, where we have seen effects from lower interconnection fees, and also that they have lost a national roaming agreement. However, Finland succeeded in actually increasing the margins. Denmark is flat and Norway is slightly down. So we are still working with the cost side in these areas to make sure that we could offset more of the downturn, especially in Norway and also Denmark.</p>
          <p>The Baltics are having a tough time, down with 20, 25%, reflecting the environment in these countries. I think they have done a good work when it comes to protecting the margins here and Lars showed that previously. Lithuania is even increasing the margins compared to the same quarter last year. And I would say that they're still attempting to protect the margins; meanwhile Latvia is going down.</p>
          <p>Spain continued to grow the business, up with over 100% in growth, 120%. But for us to continue to improve margins within this area, we will focus on cost as well. So &#x2013; and that will be both personnel cost, marketing and IT that will be scrutinized. Broadband has worked with their cost side and we could see that now in the figures, 15% as we said down on cost.</p>
          <p>We have seen real improvements when it comes to margins within the Swedish operations. They are up from 25% up to 32, which is a huge increase. Finland has gone up from 17 up to 30 and that is sort of what is behind this improvement. Finland, as we know, the major emphasis would be in broadband. The Baltics here show a slightly different pattern compared to mobility. Estonia is more or less flat on sales. Meanwhile Lithuania is down with 9%. Both these countries are protecting their margins in a pretty decent way.</p>
          <p>Finally, Eurasia as was said before, we have reached more than 20 million subscribers in these countries. I'm very pleased actually also to see that we continue to grow more than in the first quarter. They had a certain concern at the beginning of this year that they should see a more harsher slowdown on the growth than we have seen so far. And if you look at our underlying figures here, Kazakhstan is growing with 8%, Uzbekistan with 170%, Tajikistan 50% and so on. So we have an underlying growing business here. Azerbaijan and Georgia is down with seven to 10%.</p>
          <p>Here, we could also see that we have been very cautious on the CapEx side. We are down to 27%. And that also includes, actually I've added two countries here, both Nepal and Cambodia is included in the CapEx figures. But that doesn't mean that we have stopped to invest. I think it's very wise to continue to invest. We are so far 11% compared to net sales, which is of course lower than last year. We are down with 34% compared to last year. But we have said that we will be back-end loaded and you will probably see higher investments during the last half-year if the market not drop more dramatic as it has done so far.</p>
          <p>Cash flow, I mentioned that before, still strong. We have worked with the cash flow very thoroughly. We have taken down our accounts receivable roughly 10% with 1.5 billion during the last six months. We have &#x2013; when we look at accounts receivable, we have taken down the outstanding days from 38 to 32 days. And we have a very low &#x2013; loss ratio is well below 1%. So we do not really see any major shifts there. But of course, we still work with the cash and we still work with the operating capital to make sure that we could keep this good flow going forward. But also helps us to keep up a stable balance sheet. As you can see here, net debt ratio continues to be on a very healthy level, now 1.4 as a multiple of the EBITDA. That also gives us sort of &#x2013; continues to give us strong financial key ratios, 70% (sic) [17%], the return on capital. We are at 37% on net debt/equity ratio and well above 50% when it comes to equity assets ratio.</p>
          <p>Our debt maturity schedule continues to be rather smooth. We have now for the coming four years refunding needs of six &#x2013; five to six billion which is, for a company like this, rather small amounts and we will continue to fill up the bank account with more long-term. The bond market has been extremely favorable during the &#x2013; I'd say the last three, four months and we have seen in the Eurobond market all-time high when it comes to issues. There's still access to liquidity; however, I think that you should be a bit cautious going forward because at some point in time, it might be more tricky to get liquidity. And that's what we are planning for now to come under pressure at the wrong time.</p>
          <p>Finally, the outlook, which has been revised and you could see perhaps the reason for this. Net sales, we are today after the first half-year, close to zero on &#x2013; compared to last year underlying. Addressable costs, down 4.3%, that's the reason why we say that we will be below the 33.8 compared to last year. Margins, as we have discussed up to 32.7%. CapEx today 11.1, we will say that we will come out to 13, 14%. Number of employees today close to 31,000, will be around 30,000 at the end of this year. I'll stop there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Per-Arne and thank you very much, Lars for that presentation. We will now open up for a Q&amp;A session, both from the floor and also from the audience over the telephone conference. We will start with a few questions on the floor and please be so kind to introduce yourself when asking the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a question from Lena.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lena &#xD6;sterberg, SEB Enskilda. First of all, a question on Spain. You keep gaining market share, losses contracted somewhat and we now stand without a guidance going forward. So I was just wondering what you would guide because with the intake now it seems that you're getting relatively close to break even if you take out the subscriber intake, what &#x2013; how do you view the business going forward? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>And then also you say that the price hikes on fixed telephony and wholesale had only a limited impact this quarter. I was wondering if you could, sort of, maybe quantify that somewhat in percentages how much we should expect going forward versus how much we saw in this quarter? And then finally, on CapEx to sales, you indicated that you're at 11% now for the first half year and your guidance is 13 to 14% that it will be back-end loaded, but still it seems it's quite low, so I was wondering if you still aim to get to 13, 14%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually if I start with Spain, you are right, I think we're making progress in Spain. It doesn't change my position on Spain. I have no progress to report right now, but I subscribe to what we said. The intake is good, it helps the case. But principally position, it's the thing and I have no news to give you today. On the issue of &#x2013; on the fixed voice, I think, as I tried to say, this is not a dying business and I think fixed voice is one thing. But it's actually fixed telecommunication services. I mean it is voice, it's Broadband, it is IPTV and I happen to believe that in the countries like Sweden and Finland and some of the Baltic States, this is a real opportunity for us. And I think we need to change our mindset talking about fixed voice. We need to talk about fixed telecommunication services, and I'm pretty excited about it. And I hope you'll be able to discuss at more length at the Investor Day because I happen to believe that we have an advantage here. What was the third one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you say 13, 14, we mean it; otherwise, we should say something else. Right? But you are right. It is back-end loaded, and it is not by accident is back-end loaded. We said that when we started this year we will back-end load because we weren't sure how the first half would look like. Now the first half didn't look too bad; actually pretty good I would say. So our people, the people we work with are waiting for us to say, okay, here is the CapEx, go out and invest it. Is there a little more buffer, of course, I have buffer on every number. Otherwise, I wouldn't be running the company, right? So &#x2013; but you should assume that we will have much higher CapEx in the second half compared to the first half. Because we want to invest, we want to increase capacity in our networks; we are investing in 4G, as you know in Oslo and Stockholm, we need to expand in Eurasia. So we have plenty of possibility to spend the money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on your second question regards to the effect on the line rental, the price increase in Sweden, we stick to what we said in the previous quarter that it would be a gradual impact throughout this year and you will not see the full effect until the year-end, and we don't have any percent to give you on the progress on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And next question comes from Stefan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Stefan Pettersson, Nordea. First, I would like to start with Eurasia, which reported very solid numbers today, I believe. Looking at the change in organic growth, you've earlier talked about handset sales having a negative impact on the top-line in these regions. Did you see a change there? Also, Telenor reported a price stability in some of its emerging markets, are you seeing the same trend in Eurasia? And then looking at the fixed-line business in Sweden, we saw a pickup in line losses in the fixed business. Would you say that that pickup was as expected given the price increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, to the last one, I think we have said all along ever since I came here two years ago that we expect the fixed-line telephony to go down every quarter, and I'm trying to answer the first question, I must say, I think we can change the game here a bit. It is not about fixed voice only; fundamentally is how are we going to provide telecommunication services to fixed point like offices and homes, if the appetite for bandwidth is unlimited. If people want a 100-megabit per second or one gigabit per second, how we're going to do that? I can promise you we're not going to do it over the mobile network because we can't afford, nobody can afford to invest hundreds of thousands of base stations. And we happen to have a network that we have to fiberize. Of course, we'll have to replace the copper over time, particularly in the highly densed areas with fiber and we can provide a gigabit per second in bandwidth and then all of a sudden, we can provide services that you could only dream of. This is not a discussion about fixed voice only.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the handset sales, I mean we talked very much about that in Baltics not so much in Eurasia, you don't have the same subsidy structure in these countries as we have in the Baltics. And I want to comment to the price level as such; I mean if you looked at this, I think you could say we've had a serviceability on prices even if you see minutes of use going down, ARPUs going down. But if you should simplify it, you could say that we don't see any radical price...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in some countries, we have some real price pressure in Eurasia. There's no discussion about it. You take Uzbekistan, for instance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we manage it pretty well, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question relating to Eurasia. When you talked about your new countries, you only mentioned Nepal and not Cambodia. And there are some assets for sale in Southeast Asia. Are you looking at Millicom's assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean we look at every asset that is available. We've also looked at Millicom. I have nothing more to comment on that. And of course, that's our job to look at all assets. You have to make a difference between Cambodia and Nepal. In Cambodia, we are really a small player right now and in Nepal, we are "the player". So I think they are on different levels, these two markets and that's why I mentioned Nepal and not Cambodia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we'll take a few questions over the conference call. Operator, can you please have the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Peter Nielsen from Cheuvreux. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Peter Kurt Nielsen from Cheuvreux. A couple of questions, please, relating to your domestic business. Your performance on the cost side has obviously been impressive in the first half of this year and the 6% run rate is strong. Would you say we're seeing, in Sweden and Finland that is, the full effect now in Q2 or is there even more to come in the second half?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on Swedish Mobile, a very strong revenue performance here by any standards, I'd say. Most other operators in Europe are talking about weakness within the corporate segment within mobile. Apart from lower roaming and lower mobile termination rates, have you seen any material weakness in Swedish Mobile so far? I heard your comments about the outlook for second half but have you seen anything so far?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, despite the flat broadband subscriber base in Sweden, I know that your ARPU here is up by double-digits, which seems quite strong in the current environment. Are your customers upgrading to higher speeds in Sweden? And finally if I may be a little boring, Per-Arne's comments about reducing volatility, etcetera, the working capital seems to have turned materially negative in the quarter after a positive Q1 and any elaborations here would be appreciated. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with Mobile Sweden. I think, I thought I said that, I think we added yet a great quarter in Mobile Sweden this &#x2013; the second quarter, we grew more than 5%. We beat competition quite handsomely. However, we also are a bit cautious about what's going to happen in the second half, because if unemployment in Sweden will rise to 11%, as some people predict, it will certainly have an effect on our mobile business. And yes, you are right; we do see particularly the pressure from B2B also in mobile. When it comes to the cost, I don't think we have seen all of the effects because we reduced by 700 people in the first half in Sweden and quite a number of those people left towards the end of the second quarter. So we expect to have some additional benefit in the second half. And that's partly the reason why we now state that we think that the OpEx will be lower in '09 compared to '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to working capital, as I said before, I'm extremely confident when it comes to the free cash flow and we have been working to reduce volatility when it comes to our result. I think we are also sitting pretty well. Now we're working also with that within the operating or working capital. And we had some areas, this time it was Denmark, Spain, and Eurasia that affected this. But I think we will over time perhaps see less volatility in working capital, but I'm very confident for the free cash flow and capital as such.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the ARPU increase in Swedish Broadband?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you're right about that, Peter Kurt. There are two things impacting that. The first one, as you said, that people are upgrading to higher speed, but in that number is also included IPTV revenues. And as we have said there, revenues from IPTV tripled compared to last year, and now all our subscribers are paying customers. And that is what's been shown in the ARPU figure for the broadband side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Super. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of movies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As Lars says, they're renting a lot of movies, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one more question over the conference call. Operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Thierry Cota from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, three short questions maybe. One, the first one on the cost cutting in Sweden, a large part of it, I think is from the personnel cost. Now you have pointed to the risks in unemployment. Now given the large stake of the Swedish Government, I was just wondering what are your experiences vis-&#xE0;-vis influence from the Swedish Government that might not want to see significant head count cuts in this particular time. Do you see sort of an influence coming through the Board there in the part, or would you expect that?</p>
          <p>Second, you are guiding the margins up and the revenues down very slightly. Would you be willing to tell us what you expect for the EBITDA net-net? And my third question is with regards to the total minutes of use you're seeing in your networks, they are declining pretty much everywhere outside of Sweden in the Nordics. I was wondering whether you're &#x2013; that this is at the moment confined to the business segment or whether you're actually seeing minutes of use declines in the consumer segment as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the first question. The Swedish State has absolutely no influence and doesn't try even to exercise any influence on how we run this company; that is decided by the Board to which I report. And the Board is very strongly behind, of course, these cost reductions, because for me, the fact that we've been able to reduce the cost by 4% in the first half is a significant achievement, because as I said, we've been talking about cost savings many, many years, but basically in practice, we've had automatic cost increases every year. And this is the first time, this is a real change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I may add also to the cost side and is basically personnel cost; no, I would say it's a combination of personnel, marketing and also IT cost, that's the big numbers that we're working with all the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a question also about, if we would give some more color on the EBITDA, I think I know the answer, but Lars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We have given everything we want to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there was a final question about minutes of use if we see that more in the corporate segment, I think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps not the minutes of use as such, but I mean it's given that we will see a much more unemployment coming up here and I think we should be a bit cautious with corporate side going forward. I think that I'm not that optimistic about the corporate side the second half year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rich. Then we'll take a question from the floor and we go to Jan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Jan Dworsky from Handelsbanken. Coming back to your impressive work on the cost, maybe not to focus so much on the next quarter, but if you look at it strategically if you look at your efforts there as a journey, or at the beginning of that journey to bring down costs and improve efficiency, so are you halfway or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you remember that two years ago, we talked about we can't afford to have structurally a higher cost than competition and we concluded we had that in Sweden and Finland and we identified the number of people to 2,900. Now we now have worked for nearly two years on this issue and we have a couple of hundred people left of the 2,900. So in that sense, you could say we are at the end of the journey. But we have totally changed the way we operate this company in terms of cost, in terms of relationship with the unions. So, in that sense, I think we are in the beginning of the journey, because we will always have to work with cost. First of all, you have to take the structural cost out if you have higher structural cost than competition. We are taking cost out in the last three quarters in Sweden and Finland because of the recession. How do you defend the EBITDA margins in the Baltic States unless you take cost out, if the revenue goes down to 20%, of course you have to take cost up. So, I basically think there are three drivers for our success, short-term, medium-term and long-term, and that is how competitive are we on the cost side? How good is our customer service? Is it really world-class? And the third one is network quality. Those three things are the drivers for the success of TeliaSonera. So cost will always be part of the equation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Then an additional question on the Baltics, which of course was hit the first in this downturn. If you look at the second quarter, is there &#x2013; are there signs of the sort of stability or stabilizing at the low level, or is it continuing to deteriorate through the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you could say that we are stable on this sort of the downturn. We are roughly at 20, 25% we have been that now for over the last two quarters, but I think it's very much too early to say whether we have seen a more long-term stability there, I think it's too early.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take another question from Stefan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Stefan Billing, HQ Bank. I have a question on the free cash flow and the tax payout. You reported in the P&amp;L for the first half year about three billion in tax, but in the cash flow statement, you have paid out roughly 1.6. So what's your forecast for tax payout ratio for second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we have given that at all, no. We haven't given anything for that, what we have said is that our tax rate will probably be 23%, but then what will be paid under what sort of account, those are two different things. So we don't give any forecast on that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one more question from the floor. Lars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lars S&#xF6;derfjell, &#xC5;landsbanken. I was thinking about the margins in Mobility Services given the interconnect fees changes you see coming through in second half and particularly in Sweden. I know you said it's going to be neutral on the Group level, but do you think specifically on mobility that will be &#x2013; you will be able to maintain the current margin levels in the light of these lower interconnect fees? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start without getting into the small numbers, but I tried to indicate that I think in Sweden, we have done a great job in the last five, six, seven quarters, and we had yet another great quarter. I'm also trying to say, I think the second half will be tougher. I think there will be pressure on the top-line and automatically then there are pressure on the EBITDA line. And we have talked about the necessity for mobility to look at their OpEx. They started that and you see some signs of it in the second quarter, but in my opinion, it's not enough. Do you want to add something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think, that &#x2013; I mean, if you look at Sweden right now, they are at 39% in the second quarter and to be around that level, I think that's an achievement as such, so it might if it is 1% down also, I mean it's still a very, very high margin business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one more question from the floor, then we go to the conference call, but we'll start from the floor and Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Michael Andersson, Evli Bank. When reading your report and also your peers and competitors, the word regulation is used more and more, I would say, that's been going on for several years now, but still is that &#x2013; are you highlighting it more, or am I just reading the report more thoroughly, or is it actually an increased pressure both on local level, on European level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I haven't been here long enough to really have an opinion on it. I don't think it's increased in the two years I've been here. I think it's been an issue; it is an issue, it's something part of being in the industry. It's an uncertainty. It's a potential threat. But it's also something you have to live with because this industry is regulated, and I tend to believe it has to be regulated. And I think we've been managing that pretty well. You look at Norway now where we had a fairly significant change in interconnection fees beginning of the year or end of last year. And of course, we are under pressure, but we tend to be able to compensate it somehow, either with OpEx going down, increase in volumes. So I don't think we are highlighting it more today than two years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'd also think the reason for highlighting right now is that the impact from the regulatory issues are perhaps even worse than from the economical climate, that's the reason why we mentioned it, especially within Mobility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the EU, if I may make a comment there, we actually welcomed the lowering of the prices because I still believe they are too high. I know I'm maybe not speaking for everyone in the industry, but having the relationship with our customers is very important than that, that our customers feel that what we charge is fair and reasonable. And I still don't understand why. When I go to Brussels and if I call from Brussels compared to calling from New York, it's a huge difference in price. And I think at least that we have &#x2013; EU has capped it a little bit now, I think there is more work to be done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a stable trend you would say also looking into maybe next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of regulation...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the regulation and impact on your....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You never know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the problem of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You never know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And above all, I mean Sweden has some depressed prices compared to Europe. So, I think from that perspective, Europe will have a tougher time there. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we take two questions from the conference call. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Damien Maltarp of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. I've got a couple of questions. I'm just looking at your cash flow, I guess very strong in first half for the full year, maybe EBITDA slightly better, CapEx lower, so therefore cash turn is looking quite solid. How does this, I guess change your thinking if it does at all in terms of shareholder returns for the full year?</p>
          <p>And then the second question was just on MegaFon. It looked like you are unable to reach an agreement on a dividend to come out of that company. Can you give us a bit more maybe insight into where the disagreement lay and was it more on the size of the dividend or was it more on the strategy of MegaFon that you are unable to reach an agreement on with the other shareholders? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the MegaFon. We are all in favor of dividend, but we mostly have been very clear we want a dividend policy. We don't want a one-time dividend. And within the Board, they understand they haven't been able to agree on a dividend policy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And when it comes to our cash flow and dividend, we have a dividend policy for the Group where we have stated that we should pay out on 40% of the net result, and that's still valid, and then we'll see what happens at the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And no change in your thinking on potential share buybacks given I guess you now have got authorization for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But given our view on the capital market, I think that we should be happy to have a strong cash position. Now we will see what happens at the end of this year. I think cash is king right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question from the conference call. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. David Wright of Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess a couple of my questions have just been answered, but I might just ask one more on Spain. The recent regulatory proposal to lower the termination rates and close the asymmetry pretty rapidly, I guess works against you. Does that mean you push much harder over the next couple of quarters to gain subscribers; and does it change your thinking about the company in any way? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it doesn't change our way of thinking or my way of thinking. Actually there are a very few regulatory decisions in market that fundamentally makes us change our mind. It just sometimes makes the challenge a bit bigger. And I think we have a track record saying we can manage most of those decisions fairly well; at least over mid-term we can certainly manage them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is there a bigger push for subscribers in the near term to try and build a little more scale, bring more of the traffic on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think you should be that sort of tactical. You have a plan and you deliver on the plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that concludes this presentation. Thank you very much for showing up and we look forward, as Lars said, to see you on our Investor Day on the 7th of September here in Stockholm. With that, I thank you and see you next time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>