<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1469647" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-04-19</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2927</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President &amp; Head-External Communications">Thomas J&#xF6;nsson</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Lars Nyberg</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Per-Arne Blomquist</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nordea Bank AB (Broker)">Stefan Gauffin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Swedbank AB (Broker)">Sven Sk&#xF6;ld</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Maurice G. Patrick</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Andrew J. Lee</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux International Ltd.">Peter K. Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Terence Tsui</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="SEB Enskilda (Sweden)">Andreas Joelsson</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Carnegie Investment Bank AB">Lena &#xD6;sterberg</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Barry R. Zeitoune</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Laurie Fitzjohn-Sykes</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Andy W. Parnis</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Ulrich W. Rathe</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Jakob Bluestone</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">James S. Britton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very welcome to TeliaSonera's First Quarter 2012 Results Presentation. My name is Thomas J&#xF6;nsson. I'm Head of External Communications for TeliaSonera. I'll be the host today. I'd especially like to welcome those, well &#x2013; you in the room as well, but also those joining us via webcast and via teleconference. So, warmly welcome. The program is quite familiar I think to most of you. We will start with the presentation from our President and CEO, Lars Nyberg, followed by our Chief Financial Officer, Per-Arne Blomquist, and after that we will have time for questions. And then, we have time after that for further talks and chats with our IR colleagues and other colleagues that are present here today.</p>
          <p>I would like to make a little special promotion for those of you in the room. Starting last quarter, we actually tried to show a bit of what we do in our own services. And this quarter, we're showing our video conferencing solution. So once we're down with the show, I hope you'll all take the opportunity to see and feel and experience a little bit of the latest in video conferencing, which is a very important area for us. It's our colleagues from our business services part presenting that. So please take a few minutes and see what we do in that area, once we're done with the presentation.</p>
          <p>With that, I will leave the floor to Lars. Lars, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone. Welcome. The growth rate looks impressive or at least satisfying, but I think the quality of the 2.9% growth has some question marks or at least some remarks which is valid and I will make them in a minute. This is actually the first time in over three year that we are declining the EBITDA margin. We have improved that margin for 13 quarters. This is the first quarter where we're declining. It's totally driven by gross margin decline in all three business areas for different reasons. On a high level, I can say it's basically a mix issue.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share is down by SEK0.14; SEK0.12 of those is coming from our associates. Actually, those of you who have followed us for years know that in the mid-1990s &#x2013; sorry, in the mid mid-2000s we had lots of help from associates for many years. But if you look at the contribution from associates, this is MegaFon and Turkcell of course, since 2008 their contribution to our earnings per share have reduced by 35%, which has been compensated by increases in earnings per share from our business that we manage ourselves. So, I sincerely hope that we will be able for instance to resolve the deadlock in Turkcell soon so we can start focusing on the performance of that business.</p>
          <p>Yeah, I talked about the growth rate at 2.9%. It's solid in Eurasia, although Kazakhstan had a lower growth rate than normal because of price competition which also in &#x2013; was affecting the gross margin in Kazakhstan. But the growth rate in Eurasia is solid, 13%. The revenues in broadband looks to be flat, but then we should remember that part of the growth in International Carrier makes it looks flat; otherwise it would be down 2.5%, and International Carrier has a low gross margin &#x2013; or low EBITDA margin. So, it doesn't really help. And in Mobility Service, yes, there was growth in Mobility Service but it was mainly driven by equipment. And you all know that equipment does not generate good gross margins. So yes, I'm pleased with 2.9% but it's not really the 2.9% that we are used to.</p>
          <p>Yeah, here you can see the gross margin decline which I described to you before. We continue to be diligent in managing our cost base. Despite the 2.9% growth rate, we had a decline of OpEx by 2.1%.</p>
          <p>This is, of course, the environment we are active in. We've talked about the need to change our business model many times. And I will share some numbers with you &#x2013; continue to share some numbers with you to indicate I think this &#x2013; my conclusion is that we are managing this process pretty well. We are going from minute-based charging to tier pricing, from voice to data. That's basically the environment we operate in.</p>
          <p>This is for me a very important chart or information. When we talk about growth we typically talk about total growth of the company, but it has different components. So, if growth comes from equipment, it's less valuable to us. What is really important is what happens to build traffic revenues. And within that concept of build traffic revenues, we need to look very carefully on what happened to voice and messages on the one hand and what is happening to data on the other hand, especially the relationship between growth in volume of traffic, data traffic, compared to growth of revenue from data traffic. And I think this picture shows &#x2013; we used the same numbers that we presented in fourth quarter. You might remember we gave you the numbers per month for Sweden and how the growth of volume correlated to the growth of revenues.</p>
          <p>Now, we do it for the whole group. And you can see that the revenue on voice is down 3%, the revenue on messages is down 3% and mobile data is up 28%. That equals out. And the 28% of growth in mobile data generates a growth of traffic in our network of 70%. And I said last time that if we have the growth of traffic to be double than the growth of revenue, then that model we can live with. We can make money in that model. It's when you grow 70% and you only get 5% revenue, then we have a problem. So, we have that situation with these numbers &#x2013; the whole of last year, we have it in the first quarter. It gives me confidence that we are managing this business transition so far.</p>
          <p>We have strong development in broadband. The name of the game in broadband is to replace <mark type="ph" /> P (06:52) as the end customers with triple play customers, particularly fiber customers. We have slowed down the rollout a little bit in Sweden. We've been public about it. I don't &#x2013; we weren't happy with our internal processes and how we delivered or not delivered this service to our customers. Despite that, we have these numbers. I sincerely hope and expect that we will restart the rollout of fiber in Sweden, because that is the long-term solution for broadband, to provide triple play to fixed locations like offices and homes.</p>
          <p>Yes, this was the growth rate from Eurasia, solid as always. Interesting is to see the Kcell, Kazakhstan, growing only 3%. We &#x2013; I think we should write that on the account of price competition from Tele2. We also saw a significant decrease in the gross margin in Kazakhstan. But on the other hand, Azercell is back growing 11%, and of course Nepal is going like a train. So, 13% growth rate in Eurasia. And we have no reason, we think, to change the guidance of 1% to 2% growth and to remain on the same EBITDA margin as we had last year.</p>
          <p>Per-Arne?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lars. I will continue to elaborate a bit on what Lars has already said, the development of our gross margin especially. We have, as you can see, continued to deliver on the &#x2013; what we call, the OpEx side, and we have, I would say, a healthy development when it comes to the topline growth and the OpEx decline. What was new, as Lars mentioned, is that we see sort of the gross margin compression for the first time on &#x2013; at this magnitude. So, despite the fact that we're actually saving on the OpEx side with 2.1%, our EBITDA margin is actually going down with 1.5%. I don't think that we have released these kinds of numbers before, but I think it's good to do that to understand what is actually happening in the business today.</p>
          <p>You can see that all different &#x2013; all of the different business areas have a decline of roughly 3% in gross margin. At the same time, they are also actually saving in mobility and also broadband on the OpEx side. And you can see that Eurasia has a healthy balance on account to the topline growth and also the growth of the addressable cost base.</p>
          <p>Basically, I would say that if you take Mobility Services, the decline of 2.8% is explained by their equipment sales, the 2.5%. So, 2.5% of the 2.8% is actually equipment sales. If we take the Broadband Services, it's very much so that we have an impact from the shift from classic to IP, and that would explain roughly 2.5% or 2.7% of the decline of 3.6%. At the same time, International Carrier is also impacting with 1%. So, that is sort of the major drivers. If you also take Eurasia, you can see that we are going down with roughly 3% and the biggest impact is, as Lars mentioned, the CapEx down where we see a price compression and also effects of interconnect.</p>
          <p>Mobility has continued to deliver, I will say, a very, very good development with fantastic growth in Sweden. They grew more than 5% in this first quarter. They had EBITDA margin of 45.2%, which is an increase compared to previous years, and at the same time adding on 72,000 in net adds even if they have had a price war here in Sweden. Denmark and Norway continued to be under pressure, between 7% and 9% on the topline, declining. We have voice &#x2013; pressure on the voice prices. We have also pressure on the wholesale business in Norway. Baltic has not really rebounded yet. We have a mixed picture in the Baltics where we are growing 2% in the zone, and at the same time we are declining in Lithuania. Spain continued to grow with 111,000 of net adds, which means 25% on topline growth but with a very small margin for the time being. So if you take the equipment within Mobility, I will say that after the SEK150 million that you see in the decline on gross margin, SEK120 million is actually coming from the equipment <mark type="ph" /> end slide (11:42).</p>
          <p>Broadband Services, I will say a mixed picture. We &#x2013; at the first glance, the 0.2% decline is much better than we have seen before. At the same time, it is driven by International Carrier, which is growing maybe close to 14%. For you who actually have followed us a bit, you can see that we are now revealing the numbers for International Carrier for the first time. And you can also see that their EBITDA margin is pretty low, 4.2%. You'll probably ask me if that's good enough. Of course, it's not good enough and that's what &#x2013; why we're working with the profit improvement program within International Carrier.</p>
          <p>We have added on another 30,000 fiber customers in the &#x2013; these business areas and we continued to control, I would say, the cost in a good way. The issue is, as Lars also said, we have to push on the cost side to make sure that the shift from the classic business into the IP business also create margin in the same level as we have in the classic business. Positively, I think, we're actually defending, to some extent also increasing our market risk within broadband. We have today more than 1.2 million TV customers, where over 530 is in Sweden. We have more than 550,000 fiber customers in the whole Nordic area where half of this is in Sweden. So the investment that we have done is, I will say, yielding in the right way. When it comes to the fiber, especially you who live in the Swedish area know that we have been a bit slow on the rollout. We are making quite a lot of efforts right now to make sure that we have the right processes when we continue to roll out the fiber later on this year. We have made somewhat a hold on the new sales. We've tried to make sure that we could deliver on the sales we have done before.</p>
          <p>Lars mentioned Eurasia, so I won't <mark type="indiscernible" /> (13:42) to be more than that. They keep the margin on EBITDA 2011, given that we have a strong base of growing company, not only Kazakhstan is growing but also the other entities. And I think it's fantastic to see Nepal where we today have a growth of, in the first quarter, 64%. If you take the 12-month <mark type="ph" /> role (14:03), then we're talking about more than 80%. They have an EBITDA margin of 58%. And they have actually reached the return on &#x2013; or they have <mark type="indiscernible" /> (14:13) operating capital. We still think it's a good sign on a good investment.</p>
          <p>Lars mentioned the associates; this time we were hit by roughly SEK600 million in the result negatively. So we're down from SEK1.6 billion to SEK1 billion, and that of course affects our EPS, which I will come back to later on. Here's the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (14:39) is explained by the associates. We also have a hit on the net financial result. We have increased our net debt. We have some extra cost also from the Kcell transaction that is hitting here, partly then offset by taxes, but we are down from SEK104 billion down to <mark type="ph" /> SEK90 billion (15:01).</p>
          <p>We continue to invest. In this quarter, we do not have so much of spectrum as we had last year. So, the underlying investment trend is actually higher in Q1 2012 compared to Q1 2011. But we strongly believe that it's needed to invest in the different areas, enough to say that we have a rather similar investment happen in the different business areas. It's been 25% up to the 40%. And we strongly believe that this is the right place to go when it comes to future business.</p>
          <p>We have had a somewhat lower free cash flow, partly explained by higher cash CapEx and also change in operating capital. We have had last year less of accounts payable &#x2013; payments which is higher this year. And that also explains the SEK500 million of downturn in the free cash flow. The Kcell transaction has increased our net debt from SEK65 billion up to SEK74 billion. So, we have today roughly a net-debt-to-EBITDA of 2. Given that we will work with the IPO for Kcell in this year, I expect at some point in time the net-debt-to-EBITDA to also go down below the 2. We have our debt maturity schedule, which I think looks a bit nice. We do not have any that is us under pressure when it comes to repayment. And if you look at 2013, 2014 and 2015, we are talking about roughly SEK22 billion to SEK23 billion repayment need. So that is, for me, a good reason to believe that we will be able to also take down the net-debt-to-EBITDA the coming years.</p>
          <p>So summarizing this quarter, we have an improved organic revenue growth supported by equipment sales in International Carrier. I think we'll defend our core revenues in Mobility, as Lars said. We have a customer &#x2013; a positive customer trend in Broadband. We continue to see double-digit revenue growth in Eurasia. We see difference this time in the quarter with a decline in gross margin. We continue to work with the addressable cost base, and we will for sure continue to work very hard on improving the gross margin as well. And we continue also to review our other assets. As you could see, we have increased our ownership in Ncell. We have exited from Cambodia, and we are also having discussions about the ownership &#x2013; or governance of MegaFon.</p>
          <p>That it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you very much Per-Arne and thank you, Lars, for that. With that, we're ready to move into the Q&amp;A and I ask the operator to please open the line for questions while I move one slide forward to the Q&amp;A slide. And I think with that, we're ready for questions, also from the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...in the room and &#x2013; yes, please. And normal reminder, it would be great if you state who you represent and who you are. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Stefan Gauffin at Nordea; and I have three questions. The first one relates to the ongoing discussions in MegaFon. Just want to ask you to add some flavor to how those discussions are going and if you're optimistic regarding solving this conflict during 2012.</p>
          <p>Then the second question is that historically you have been very fast in changing the guidance on top-line growth when it has moved outside of your guided range. And now, you delivered close to 3% organic growth and you have a guidance of 1% to 2%. Why don't you change the guidance and which area are you, in that case, believing that the growth will deteriorate? And then, the third reason relates to International Carrier where you made the comment that you're not pleased with the margin in that business. What is the margin that you would be satisfied with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me start. You'll get the expected answer on your first question that the conversation with the three parties are ongoing and nothing is finalized, and therefore I have no comment to make. Now, you can ask it again and you'll get the same answer.</p>
          <p>On the other one, you are right, but I think what Per-Arne and I and the colleagues in the group &#x2013; management have realized that there's difference between growth and growth, and we better be sure that we get the right growth. So yes, the 2.9% includes growth in International Carrier, very low margin; includes equipment, negative gross margin. So, it's not worth that much to me. So, that's why I used this picture when I showed you how that billed traffic revenue &#x2013; because that's where the growth must come from if it's going to mean something to us. So yes, maybe the number could be higher than SEK1.2 billion, but I'm not sure of the quality of that above SEK1.2 billion is worth it. So, that's why we didn't bother to change it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I mean, if you take the real numbers, the 1.3% for the growth is from equipment sales and that's where we are a bit cautious.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually think, over time, we will start talking only about growth in billed traffic revenue because that would drive our bottom line.</p>
          <p>Now on International Carrier, the kind of EBITDA margin I would like to see them &#x2013; they'll never get rich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll continue over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning; Sven Sk&#xF6;ld from Swedbank. What's your analysis of the Swedish mobile market in Q1 and going forward into Q2? Obviously you gained subscribers in the quarter and Tele2 actually lost some subscribers. I understand that we bounced back in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:28) in Q2, but &#x2013; I mean your performance is really, really strong. What's your view on the market?</p>
          <p>And my second question is when you now separate International Carrier, what's your view on that business? We all know that there's a lot of invested capital behind that SEK5 billion revenue and low margin. But what's the vision? What can happen with this business in a five-year perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if I start with the last one, it's no secret that we put a new management in there. And when we put new management in anywhere, they should have a reasonable period of time to see what we can do with the business. And of course, we are reviewing this business, not sort of urgently, but I made a comment on purpose that this is a very low margin business and is over-capacity. So, there are some real issues in the marketplace. And what are we going to do? We haven't made up our mind but it is a discussion ongoing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I will tell that first <mark type="indiscernible" /> (22:27) back. That's the first addition. Then we'll see how far we can counter. But &#x2013; I mean they have a fantastic volume <mark type="indiscernible" /> (22:36) and if you look at all the traffic that is coming through in the system, there is need for carriers. However the question is, how much can you earn on this business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the other hand, we have had that hope for 10 years now, right, and we've written off quite a bit of money. But I'm sure we'll come back to you when we have made up our mind what to do with it.</p>
          <p>Yes, the market for mobile in Sweden, it's a very healthy market in a way. The billed revenue for voice is not declining anywhere near like some other markets in Central Europe. That's a good thing. The adoption of mobile data is faster in this market than in many other markets. We experienced something in the first quarter that I haven't experienced since I started here. We have an outright price war started by "3", followed by Tele2 and Telenor, and we stayed out of it. I think that was good. I hope that everybody realizes that doesn't benefit anybody except maybe some people who can buy a cheap subscription for a short period of time.</p>
          <p>We are the leader in this market. I think as a leader in the market you have a special responsibility, and I think we took that responsibility. In the end, it's all about quality of networks and it's about customer service. We're working very hard on trying to improve our customer service to become world-class. And I think that in combination with our brand position, and actually I will give credit to the management as well, we have had good management in the Swedish mobile operation for quite a number of years, I think that is the answer why we are performing so well in Sweden.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, Lars. We have a very high number of questions from the line right now. So, I would ask the operator at this point to please open the line for questions and we'll take the first question from the conference line. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your first question comes from the line of Maurice Patrick from Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there; Maurice here; quick question. On the gross margin and OpEx to sales slide that you provided, it's a very helpful disclosure. I know you won't want to give that for every single quarter throughout 2011, but be helpful if you give a sense of how that has been developing over the past few quarters. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that the decline in gross margin partly started already in Q4, but you normally have a lower Q4 growth probably due to <mark type="ph" /> low (25:22) hardware sales. But I will say that the first two quarters was pretty stable and then you'll start to see sort of decline in the fourth quarter, which then &#x2013; normally then rebounds in the first quarter. It did that this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Per-Arne. We'll continue with questions from the lines. The next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Andrew Lee [Goldman Sachs]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, everyone. A follow-up question on Swedish mobile and then one on Spain, please. As the previous question stated, it was a strong performance this quarter, but I note that Tele2 has raised its revenue growth guidance in Swedish mobile and lowered margin guidance, suggesting that it expects the market to remain pretty aggressive in terms of price formations, obviously difficult to forecast. But I wonder if you could talk about how you expect the market environment to pan out through the year in terms of extra price promotions.</p>
          <p>And then secondly on Spain, the margin pressure you've seen, has this reduced since the removal of handset subsidies by TEF and Vodafone in March? And apologies, I know you get this question every quarter, but could you give us an update on your views on long-term ownership in Spain following this quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've heard that Tele2 increased their guidance for growth in Sweden and reduced the margin. I would guess that is maybe an effect of the price war. Of course, they and "3" sold a lot of subscriptions and sold a lot of phones in that period at very low margin; no margin at all, I would guess. So, I'm just guessing that's the result of the price war.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was a big <mark type="ph" /> one. We (27:06) booked that in the second quarter that would be the effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So on Spain, yes, I think it's a very interesting development with Telef&#xF3;nica announcing elimination of subsidies on hardware. Vodafone has followed. Orange says they won't. We have followed partly that if it holds it would clearly help us to improve the margins.</p>
          <p>And I have no comment on the asset in itself right now. Nothing has changed. I want to see these guys deliver the results they have promised us this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Lars. We'll continue with the line. Please go ahead with the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Peter Nielsen [Cheuvreux]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. A couple of questions, please. First one, Lars, at the Q4 results and the outlook for this year, you obviously talked about, as you've done this morning, the need for improving your whole process in terms of rolling out fiber in Sweden. You also left yourself some room in terms of spending some money on this. And I assume that your expectations in this regard have not changed over the past three months, if I sort of gathered correctly from your comments. That would be my first question. And secondly, just a question related to Turkcell and the process there. Is it your view that the process in Turkcell &#x2013; I'm not talking about the court case but the process of moving towards &#x2013; you electing three independent Board members, et cetera, is that process moving along to your satisfaction, so to speak? And thirdly, a question for Per-Arne, please. At the Q4 results as well, Per-Arne, you did mention your expectations of an improved free cash flow for TeliaSonera in 2012 versus 2011. We obviously haven't seen it in Q1, but is it still your expectation that we will have an improved cash flow for the full year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer on the first question, yes, you're correct. I've the same opinion. And then Turkcell, and not the court cases but the process to comply with the CMB, the Capital Markets Board, I would say it's going very slow or too slow. I think not everybody agrees that we should have independent &#x2013; the whole issue is that we should increase the number of independent directors. If we do that the deadlock will be resolved, which is something we would like to see so we can start focusing on the performance of Turkcell. So because of that, it's going slow. There is a deadline, end of June I believe it is. I hope they'll meet it, but that's of course the responsibility of the board of Turkcell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I won't account for the cash flow <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:55) still expects the cash flow to improve during this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. We'll continue with the line. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Terence Tsui of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I've got two questions, please. Firstly on Denmark, the margin obviously remains fairly weak at 11%. Do you think we're any closer to seeing consolidation in the Danish market, and what are your thoughts on whether this could be allowed by the regulator? And secondly, just to follow up on Spain and the elimination of handset subsidies, are you noticing any material change in the share of net adds now that we've seen a slightly different strategy by operators when it comes to handset subsidies in the market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Danish market, I think we announced the network cooperation with Telenor. I think that's a step in the right direction. On consolidation of the market, I think it's a bigger issue in the whole of Europe. We have more than 125 operators in Europe. If you compare that with United States, a similar purchase market or a similar purchasing power, they have five or four, or six or whatever you &#x2013; have you calculated. So, I think there are too many operators in Europe and I think Brussels will have to take a stand on this because Brussels is pushing very hard for major investments in the telecom infrastructure in Europe, which are required and necessary and good for EU but some will has to found it &#x2013; or fund it. And if you have four operators in a market with 5 million people and only one player basically makes money, that's not a sustainable model long term, certainly not if you want to see substantial investment in the infrastructure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right &#x2013; okay, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to Spain, I think it's too early to say whether we have seen any impact on the proposal that came a couple of weeks ago. Well, we must see what actually happens in Q2 before we really dare to say anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you; and thank you, Lars and Per-Arne. We'll move back to the room. Do we have more questions from the floor here? Yes, first row, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Andreas Joelsson, SEB Enskilda. Just a question on the gross margin; do you have any plans how to improve the gross margin and can you tell us a little bit about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean &#x2013; first of all it's a mix issue; second, it's a cost issue. And I don't think that we said it, but part of the reason why the gross margin is down is also we were a bit slow with the cost reduction in BTS but also in MT, Mobile Technologies and Broadband. There's not the market operation in &#x2013; particularly in Mobility has to be the cost savings. That's the whole purpose of it. And in Broadband, the challenge is you have a certain cost structure for the traditional classic business which goes down in revenue. Then the cost has to come down and it's not coming down fast enough. At the same time you have growth in IP, which is a good thing, but the cost can't come up as fast as the revenue comes up, because you don't get scale. So, that's the challenge. And those are the two areas that we are going to focus on to see if we can claw back some of these gross margin loss that we had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we'll continue here. Yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lena &#xD6;sterberg, Carnergie. I had a question on Turkcell and MegaFon combined, because when you announced the proposed transaction from the beginning you were saying that you needed Turkcell to complete before you saw a solution on MegaFon, but now it seems &#x2013; my interpretation at least is that you can do MegaFon without Turkcell being sold; is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think you're interpreting it a little bit too far. What we said without the &#x2013; when we made the deal is that we would like to resolve Turkey and Russia and we together would put our ownership into a holding company, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (34:02). That company was never operational as a holding company. We always had the intention of maintaining Turkcell as an independent company and MegaFon as an independent company. So, that was the &#x2013; when you say combining the companies, we were never trying to combine the company, just combining the ownership.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but every quarter you've been saying let's focus on Turkey...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I have spent &#x2013; well, yes, I think Turkey is the most urgent to resolve because it's really affecting the performance of the company and of course, we have to spend time on MegaFon as well. But I think the challenge was bigger in Turkcell than in MegaFon or maybe it was more of a deadlock in MegaFon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's not a pre-requisite to sell Turkey first before...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'll take any of them; preferably both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you. I think we'll move back to the line for a second. We'll take the next question from the line, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Barry Zeitoune of Berenberg. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. It's Barry Zeitoune from Berenberg. On the &#x2013; I know you can't about the MegaFon talks, but on the basis that you see yourself being a majority holder in asset, as key rather than the minority holder, and on the basis of &#x2013; that we might expect something to happen in MegaFon, would you favor a full exit over a partial exit of the asset? And my second question is on Finland. You've lost share in Finland for a number of quarters now and it seems to be a consistent theme that you're consistently losing share in Finland. Typically in markets when an operator loses share for a sustained period of time, then comes the issue of a back-book issue that needs addressing and the ability to recover competitive positioning. Are you concerned that you might need to be more competitive on pricing in Finland to start to recover some market share?</p>
          <p>And my third question is more of a general one. So you're cutting your subsidies in Spain, obviously not to the same extent as Telef&#xF3;nica and some of the other operators. And also in Denmark we've seen a cut in subsidies. Do you see the cut in subsidies as symptomatic of, I suppose, a market that is going through intense competition? And can you see any potential cut in subsidies in any of your other markets? Do you think this is a general trend in the industry that we're going to see subsidies cut in general throughout markets and more transparent pricing off the back of that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if I start with the last question, I think historically the operators have always wanted to cut the subsidies of hardware and they never succeeded basically. And if you ask the suppliers, they predict that it will never happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a new Board member at TeliaSonera, Olli-Pekka Kallasvuo, the former CEO of Nokia, and we talked about this yesterday on the Board meeting and he said it will never stay. Well, he is a bit colored by his background. I hope it will reduce because it is a pain for the operator to have negative gross margins on the hardware, but we should not forget the typical behavior of a customer is to go into a shop and buy a phone. I choose the phone, yeah, and I need subscription too. As long as that goes that way, I think it's going to be difficult. Hopefully, we can add more value, particularly via our customer service, what I call the world-class customer service, that people actually say, "I want to be a customer of Telia and I want to have this subscription and then I want this phone." Then I think the discussion would change somewhat.</p>
          <p>On Finland, I don't know if you noticed or saw the announcement that we have appointed Robert Andersson for CEO of Sonera. It's a bit of a change for our organization because we have a business area organization. There are basically two markets where we suffer from not having one leader potentially because we are both in Mobility and in Broadband and business-to-business and business-to-consumer, and that is the Swedish market and the Finnish market. In Sweden, that's resolved because I think I act as the Country Manager of Sweden when it's required, but we haven't had that solution in Finland. I think we've suffered from this, and after agonizing over it, because I prefer to have a very clear simple organization, we decided we will appoint Robert as CEO of Sonera in the matrix, also joining us in the Group Management. And I think that will make the drive in the organization much more efficient, because I don't think our problem is in the marketplace, I think it's more of an internal problem than an external problem. So, I'm pretty optimistic that we will give Elisa a run for their money, and I don't think price is the solution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And the question on MegaFon, would you favor a full exit over a partial exit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have no comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, and thank you, Lars. We'll continue with question from the line. So, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Laurie Fitzjohn from Citigroup. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you; two questions. On Norway, I understand part of the weakness is because of Tele2's migrating some of its traffic on to its own network. So, are you able to say how near Tele2 is to its minimum commitment on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:52) further downsize going forward or migrating some more traffic, or are they now at this level until the end &#x2013; contract comes to an end? Secondly on Kazakhstan, I mean you highlighted this is an issue, and we &#x2013; I mean &#x2013; falling from 10% to 3%. I mean should we expect growth to maybe slip into negative numbers through the rest of this year in Tele2 continue to impact pricing? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start with Kazakhstan. I don't think that we should expect this for the rest of the year. I certainly hope we shouldn't expect this for the rest of the year and I actually believe it won't continue like this. They still grow in the marketplace and I think we see some signs of sobering up. So, I'm reasonably optimistic. But on the other hand, I'm very happy that we have some other markets. And this &#x2013; if you go historically back, we've had problems in Azerbaijan for three years, low growth. We were &#x2013; compensated that in Kazakhstan and in Nepal. Then we had problems in Georgia. We compensated that by Uzbekistan. So, there's always somebody who is sort of slow for different kind of reasons. And luckily, we've always been able to compensate. We didn't have solid double-digit growth in the region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to Norway, I mean you're right. Part of the decline is connected to wholesale but it's also price pressure in the market. And yes, Tele2 is still in our network but I don't want to comment upon our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:28) to the minimum agreement. But they are still in our network, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll take one more from the line, and then we'll move back to the room. So, question from the line please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Andy Parnis from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, guys. I've got two questions. The first one is actually a follow-up on Norway. I was just wondering, when you look at the margin in Norway, it's down about 4 percentage points year-on-year. I was wondering if you could give us an idea what proportion of that has come from the price pressure maybe that's rolled over from Q4. And then other part of it which is the pricing &#x2013; the margin pressure from the wholesale agreement with the loss of the wholesale revenue from Tele2. But then the second question just on sort of the growth outlook, you guided to 1% to 2% organic growth this year. It was sort of 2% to 3% last year. I was just wondering, where do you see sort of the long-term growth in this business, and in particular, which business units do you think will now sort of accelerate in growth or topline growth in order to &#x2013; if you do expect to have sort of growth accelerating from this point? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'll take the last question. That's a very interesting question. Where is the growth going to come from longer &#x2013; medium, longer term in this industry? If you start with the Broadband business, when will the IP triple play growth compensate for the reduction in classic, that's the key issue. I have said many times that we are convinced that the only way to provide telecommunication service is to fix locations like homes and offices, is via the fixed network, a fixed network that can provide 100 megabit per second or 1 gigabit per second, which means fiber. Once you get this fiber, it's a fantastic experience. And I'm convinced that there will be a day when they cross over and you'll start seeing growth in Broadband again. When it happens, well, little bit difficult to say.</p>
          <p>In Mobility, the growth &#x2013; voice will continue to come down in revenue because the price of voice will continue to be reduced and that must be compensated by both volume and price increases of data. Our ambition is to maintain the ARPU. If you are paying me SEK300 per month for our services and we call it voice and data, I just want you to continue to pay SEK300 and not go down to SEK100, because that we can't take. So, this is the business model change that the whole industry is experiencing. In that process, which is a tricky process, I could see things go pretty wrong and we will see declines in the revenue. I could also see things go pretty well and we'll see increases in revenue, because the demand for data is unlimited. People are consuming as much as we can produce in our networks. So, it's really a tricky &#x2013; from a management standpoint, it's a tricky process to manage and make sure that we don't make a mistake. And then of course, Eurasia I think will continue to grow for many years because they're a couple of years, five years maybe, behind the more developed markets. So, they have the whole data growth coming in the coming years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to Norway it's pretty complex. Well, I <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:02) you have three parts. We have the equipment that we've mentioned before. We have the pressure on voice and we have the wholesale. And if &#x2013; actually we have tried to simplify it <mark type="ph" /> on Austria (45:14), I mean they are pretty equal in the impact on the gross margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you. Do we have questions in the room? Then we'll continue with the line. So, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Ulrich Rathe of Jefferies. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Two questions from my side, please. The first one is again with regards to Swedish mobile. I was just wondering, Lars, how you interpret the March sort of spurt in competitive activities. Is this a signal maybe for structural pricing risk, maybe prices have sort of remained a bit too high? You highlighted earlier the good voice trends in Sweden which are bit of an outlier in Europe. Or is it maybe just a tactical move, maybe one player just trying to grab share for some internal reason? That would be my first question. The second question is with regards to Kazakhstan. I was wondering whether what you are observing currently was anticipated pretty much in this way when you decided to increase your stake or whether that really sort of came from left field? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the last question on increasing the stake in Kcell, that is in line with the strategy that we announced years ago that our prime objective in merger and acquisition was to increase our ownership in current activities. I mean, I'll be using this explanation that in Kcell &#x2013; particularly Kcell, we had 100% of the work but we own 51% of the shares via Fintur, which we own two-thirds or something like that. We were actually like 38% of the reward while having 100% of the work. So we wanted to increase to a higher number, and that's exactly what we have done now. So now, we have 100% of the work and we have much more than 50% of the reward. It has nothing to do with the price or the entrance even of Tele2. We've been trying to make that deal for about three years before we finally were able to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Swedish mobile market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What was the question on Swedish mobile market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the price. Well, I don't know. Maybe &#x2013; I could be wrong, but I'm not so sure that to lower the prices the way "3" did is so smart. First of all, some of their customers who bought that subscription three weeks earlier must be pretty upset. Then you get a lot of customers that you guarantee for two years to pay a fee that you make no money on. And then what's going to happen after those two years? Are these customers just going to accept that the price goes up by 50% or are they going to go and look for another bargain somewhere? So, I don't know how successful that strategy is. And I don't think that what happened is a sign of continuous price wars in this market. As I said, I could be wrong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And thank you, Lars. We'll continue with a couple more questions from the line. So we'll continue, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Jakob Bluestone of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. I've got two fairly quick questions. Firstly, last quarter you gave some pretty interesting stats where you were talking about the development of your roaming volumes and revenues. And I think you said your roaming volumes have tripled and your roaming revenues had sort of fallen about a quarter on the back of the price changes that you'd made. I'm just interested, are you &#x2013; would you be able to maybe give us an update on how roaming volumes and revenues have continued to develop into the beginning of this year on the back of the price changes that you made last year? And then secondly, just in terms of the negative capital &#x2013; well, negative working capital movement that you had this quarter, is that something which would be reversed out later during the year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first one, I don't actually have the same numbers. I'm sure we can provide them to you after the call. I do have, I remember, a press release we went out with a couple of days ago about traffic during Easter holidays. And the traffic was &#x2013; five, six countries mentioned in the Europe and the traffic was up like 300% down to 200% up in those countries. So, I think the theory on which we based this decision that our customers want to surf the net also when they are outside of their home country and the prices that we had were so high &#x2013; or the prices that the industry had and still has unfortunately was so high that people turn off the roaming deliberately not to cause bill shocks and didn't surf. Now, when they realized that the price is reasonable and is controllable, then they do use their surfing phones also when they visit European countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to working capital, yes, I would say that they'd probably even out during the year. Of course, it is connected to timing issues around accounts payable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great; thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have any more questions in the room at this point? Okay, then we'll continue with the last two questions on the line. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of James Britton from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. I've got two questions please. Firstly, on Kcell, can you just tell us where you're going to list Kcell? And have you received any assurances on regulation following the full privatization? And secondly, on Sweden, where are you on increasing investment in customer care in this market I think on the strategy for this year? Have you started these investments or are they still yet to unfold?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the customer care, I think we are hiring more people, so in that sense we are investing. But I think there are other issues that are even more important for the &#x2013; for having the effect that we want to have, and that is to look at the training of the first line management, the location of the first line management and the task of the first line management. So, it's really an overhaul of the whole customer care organization from top to bottom and creating career path for those colleagues that work in customer care, that they feel that this is a longer-term career job to be in customer care. So, it's not just an issue of hiring 300 more people. We have to hire more people. We are in the process of hiring more people, but I would love to see those people stay a couple of years in this job or in these jobs, not just stay for six months and then go somewhere else within TeliaSonera. So, it's really revamping the whole customer care organization; that's what we are busy with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So far, we have decided to list case <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:35) no big change, and we are looking for jurisdiction, and that will be decided in a couple of weeks' time. So, not &#x2013; they <mark type="ph" /> not have a normal strike (52:40) right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about the discussions on regulation? Do you have any guarantees, the regulatory situation is going to be quite stable but is the government selling out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean in...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Kazakhstan. I guess the key debate is around termination rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing to do with the --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About that, I think it's slightly put on hold right now when it comes to the termination rates. But there has been a very intensive discussion, but it's slightly put on hold right now</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last couple of questions on the line, so please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question will come from Peter Nielsen with Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just interested, Lars, you're talking about also in your introductory &#x2013; in the results that you intend to start charging for mobile Voice-over-IP. Question is just have you any indications or expectations that you might run into some regulatory problems in this regard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know, maybe or maybe not. We're coming back to this issue of changing the business model. And the end state will be that the voice, whether it is VoIP or traditional, will be significantly cheaper or a lower portion of the total cost per month while data will be a bigger cost. Now, I think charging for mobile VoIP for a period of time during this transition is one of the solutions. And we have announced we intend to do it in Spain shortly and then we'll see how it works out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So, then we take...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...last question from the line, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Sasu Minatsky of Bank of America (54:28). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. You actually pre-answered my question somewhat and &#x2013; you mentioned in the report you're going to charge for VoIP services now in Sweden and Spain. And could you just elaborate on whether you're talking about your own branded VoIP service or OTT services, and how do you expect to combine this with the overall charging for voice services to the clients?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we are talking about mobile VoIP applications and only that, because it's voice which is a very significant part of our revenue. 80% of our revenue is charged under the heading, Voice Services, while 80% of the traffic in our network is data traffic. And that's the challenge for the whole industry. We need to reduce price in voice and we need to increase prices for data. And as I said, I think the charging separately from mobile VoIP is a transition to &#x2013; for us to &#x2013; while we transition from the situation we have today to a totally different situation where we, as I said, charge much less for voice and more for data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. So with that, I thank everybody who participated on the line. And for those of you present, please don't miss our videoconferencing demonstration on the way out or as you wait. And with that, we conclude the first quarter results presentation and Q&amp;A. Thank you very much for attending. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>