<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1226173" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2927</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m, Vice President Responsible for Group Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lars Nyberg, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Per-Arne Blomquist, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m</participant>
      <participant id="4">Sven Sk&#xF6;ld</participant>
      <participant id="5">Per-Arne Blomquist</participant>
      <participant id="6">Lars Nyberg</participant>
      <participant id="7">Stefan Pettersson</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jan Dworsky</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="10">Maurice Patrick</participant>
      <participant id="11">David Wright</participant>
      <participant id="12">Damien Maltarp</participant>
      <participant id="13">Lena &#xD6;sterberg</participant>
      <participant id="14">Michael Andersson</participant>
      <participant id="15">Soomit Datta</participant>
      <participant id="16">Jakob Bluestone</participant>
      <participant id="17">James Britton</participant>
      <participant id="18">Jacques de Greling</participant>
      <participant id="19">Lars S&#xF6;derfjell</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Very welcome to this press and analyst conference for our First Quarter of 2009. My name is Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m, Head of Investor Relation. With me today, I have our Chief Executive Officer, Mr. Lars Nyberg and our Chief Financial Officer, Mr. Per-Arne Blomquist. The format is familiar to many of you. We'll start with a brief presentation by Lars, followed by a review of the financials by Per-Arne. Then, we will open up for Q&amp;A, both from the floor and also over the telephone conference.</p>
          <p>With that, I leave the floor to Lars. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Well, good morning and welcome all of you. I suppose the number of participants in the room is somewhat smaller than we normally have, but I suppose that has to do with our results in comparison to other people who announced results today. Anyway, we're very happy that you are here. We are currently experiencing one of the worst scenarios in modern time or recessions, but I believe our performance is very strong. We reported record high earnings for the quarter driven by continued high profitability in Eurasia and at the same time improved profitability in Broadband Services.</p>
          <p>We now do see signs of changed customer behavior in several of our markets, but we still managed this quarter to grow the business somewhat. And when I say when we grew the business, I don't talk in kronors, I talk in underlying local currencies.</p>
          <p>Our efforts to reduce costs are now beginning to show. Reduced OpEx had a positive effect on margins as well as cash flow. In a turbulent financial environment, it is particularly encouraging that we managed to increase cash flow by more than SEK3 billion. I'll now talk about the different lines of business.</p>
          <p>Starting with Mobility, net sales increased in the weak Swedish krona, but underlying local currency sales were somewhat down. Sweden is still going strong with strong growth in mobile data as well as more subscribers and increased voice traffic. We also attracted more customers in Spain and grew the business. However, the Baltic countries are weak. The fall in equipment sales that we experienced at the end of last year continues, but we also now experience lower usage in the quarter. The same pattern actually starts to show in Finland with lower equipment sales and traffic revenues.</p>
          <p>Margins were down in the quarter, as OpEx in, again, local currency grew mainly due to the high customer intake in Spain. Going forward, we will focus on improving efficiency throughout the mobile business area and reduce cost to mitigate the impact of the sales decline.</p>
          <p>This quarter, of course, I'm particularly pleased with the developments within Broadband Services, where there was a considerable improvement in profitability. The main improvement comes from lower operating expense, both as result of efficiency measures and lower cost of goods sold. The cost efficiency program that we announced in February 2008 is now beginning to have visible effect, both on personnel cost and other expenses.</p>
          <p>Organic growth is still down, but it is encouraging to see that the growth of IP based services continues to be strong. These services, the IP services, now represents one-third of the business for Broadband Services.</p>
          <p>In the Swedish market, we are gradually introducing price increases for the fixed telephony to mitigate the decline in volume. Prices here in Sweden are regulated and have been flat since 2001. The change in the price regulation has made it possible to raise prices for both wholesale and retail customers. The effect on earnings will be gradual starting in April of this year. The global economic downturn is also beginning to have an effect on Eurasia where traffic continued to grow, but prices declined due to regulatory interventions and increased competition.</p>
          <p>Net sales continued to grow, although at a slower rate, and the main contributors to this net sales growth were Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan. Despite the price erosion, we managed to improve margins as a result of tight cost control and a balanced growth approach.</p>
          <p>Talking about the EBITDA margin trends, the rolling four quarter EBITDA margin for the Group as a whole improved somewhat. Eurasia continues to be the top performer with a stable close to 50% margin. Broadband Services show a positive trend shift with improved margins both year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter. The cost efficiency measures will continue and at the same time, we will focus on increased sales of IP based services. I am a bit disappointed by the development for Mobility Services in the quarter. The impact of regulatory intervention is considerable and is something that we have to live with, but the cost trend has to be reversed to safeguard our profitability.</p>
          <p>All in all, we had a good quarter, profitability improved and our cash generation was strong. To a great extent, these developments were related to our own actions to reduce cost, working capital, and CapEx.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to highlight some developments in relation to what we call our focus areas, which I have talked to you about many times. Starting with quality networks or quality in networks, that's a basic and fundamental ingredient for being a top player in this industry. In 2008, we invested in 4G licenses in Sweden and Norway. Early this year, we announced our plans to launch 4G networks in 2010 for commercial use in the cities of Stockholm and Oslo. Our goal is to become one of the first operators in the world to offer customers 4G services.</p>
          <p>To us, it is important to be in the forefront of introducing new technology that meets the exploding customer demand for mobile data and enables them to communicate at significantly higher speeds, with greater capacity and improved quality. At the same time, as we do this with 4G, we are upgrading our 3G networks by increasing speed in the Swedish network to 14.4 megabit per second, which is the highest available in the market. We now reach eight million inhabitants and at the same time, we expand the number of surf zones to 2500. This increase &#x2013; increases in capacity is to the benefit of all our mobile broadband customers.</p>
          <p>In Finland, we will expand our 3G network this year to cover more than 100 new towns and localities. It means that our 3G network will reach a larger share of the population also in the more rural areas of Finland. The buildout will continue in 2010 and 2011 depending on the market situation and the service demand. In Eurasia, we continue to invest in capacity, coverage, and higher service quality. We are continuing the network rollout in Uzbekistan and we have started the rollout in Nepal.</p>
          <p>Cost efficiency obviously is another focus area. In 2008, we worked hard to reduce cost, but saw limited effects on the profitability. This year, we are beginning to make some progress. We reduced our addressable cost base by approximately 2%, again in local currency. And since year 2008, the total number of employees have been reduced by some 600 people. We are making good progress in Broadband Services and costs within our Eurasian operation are under control, whereas in Mobility Service, I believe we have more work to do. And this is particularly important if the economic climate would worsen even further.</p>
          <p>In 2008, there was an explosive increase in the use of mobile internet, as you're all aware. We increased the number of subscribers by more than 100%, whereas the mobile traffic in our Nordic and Baltic networks increased by almost 500%. This is a change from our heritage. Normally there is a very strong correlation between number of customers and the volume of traffic. You add 10% more customers, you get 10% more traffic. Not in the case of mobile data. You increase 100% subscribers and you get 500% more traffic. That's a fundamental change.</p>
          <p>We have invested extensively in the rapid development of our networks, enabling high-speeds for users for mobile broadband. The development on new terminals, for example computer with integrated SIM cards and more advanced use of friendly mobiles such as the Apple iPhone 3G, is making internet access easier.</p>
          <p>Data usage among our iPhone customers much higher, much higher than among users of other 3G handsets. If you add then an attractive pricing plan, then you have the main reasons why the traffics is exploding like this slide shows you.</p>
          <p>The mobile lifestyle and communication will continue to grow. Therefore, as the first operator on the Swedish market we have recently introduced a new price model which reflects the level of usage. Similar models have already been or are being introduced on other Nordic and Baltic markets. So, instead of putting a cap on how data customer can download or stream, we have introduced a model tailored to different needs. The ordinary user will not be affected, but the high volume users will have to pay somewhat more for those, and for those who only surf and occasionally send an e-mail or so, we have introduced an attractive entry price level. The reason why we do this is to safeguard our long-term profitability and investment in capacity as the traffic in our networks are increasing very rapidly.</p>
          <p>Let me talk about the outlook for 2009. It's very hard to predict what's going to happen in the marketplace. Looking ahead, it's essential that we continue to reduce cost especially in a period of increased unemployment. We will also continue to scrutinize ways to reduce capital expenditure to preserve strong cash flows. However, we are still committed to keeping the addressable cost base unchanged and maintain the EBITDA margin.</p>
          <p>We did revise our outlook for the growth. We said before we would have some growth, and now we say it will be flat compared to last year. But we're still absolutely committed keeping the addressable cost base unchanged and maintain the EBITDA margin. We also expect the CapEx as a percentage of sales that it will be somewhat lower in this year compared to 2008. As a strong and financially balanced company, I believe TeliaSonera is very well equipped to meet the difficult economic environment and capture any opportunities that may arise.</p>
          <p>I'll leave the floor to Per-Arne Blomquist, and he'll go through some more details of our results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Without repeating too much what Lars had said before regarding the result, I must, however, comment upon that I think that the result that we have presented today is very solid given the market circumstances. We have a solid balance sheet. We have a good cash flow. We have improved our cost levels and we still have growth.</p>
          <p>And if I start with that, you can see that we're continuing to grow upwards here and even though we are helped by to a certain extent FX, if you take away FX, if you take away the acquisitions, we are still growing with more than 0.5%, and I think that's a strength in this environment right now. Another strength that we also have is the development of the EBITDA margin.</p>
          <p>If you go back a bit longer, you can see that we went down from close to 35% down to 31.8 and we've sort of been around that for a while, but now given the development in specialty costs we are now starting to improve this margin for the first time. We are also improving the EBITDA margin also in underlying terms, even though we are up 14% in reported figures, we are up at 2.5% in local currency. And whilst again, I think that this is a strength in this market environment. This is also very much based on the fact that we have been able to address the underlying cost in the cost base.</p>
          <p>You may have recognized discussions about the gross savings that we have been discussing before. For me and I think also for Lars, we have started this discussion more than half year ago, it's very difficult to understand the effect of the gross saving. That's the reason why we the decided to look at actually the net effect of our savings on our OpEx side. And as you could see here for the first time since well back to 2006, we actually sort of see a change in the curve. We have had a cost increases of roughly 6 to 7% underlying the years before. Now we are down on a four quarter rolling basis with half a percentage and quarter-on-quarter we are down the 2, close to 2.5%. And for me this is real savings. Obviously we're talking about real cost and this is to sort of understandable for us, it's understandable for you, also when we address these things going forward.</p>
          <p>And this is also very visible, I would say, if we then turn into the different business areas. If I start with Mobility, Lars had already mentioned that part of the downturn on the volumes  or cost issues we have addressed that I could assure you that that this is something that we have already discussed very intensely within the group. But we have also different patterns within the Mobility Services. If we start with Sweden, we are very, very proud on their growth right now, because they are growing underlying with 7%. And that's I think is a sign in &#x2013; a sort of a very much a market where we are able to deliver in the way on strong revenue.</p>
          <p>Then we have the Nordic area, where it's losing roughly 3.5 to 7 or 8% in the Norway, Denmark and Finland. Of course, that means that we need to address the cost base to make sure that we could restore the margin. We also have the Baltics, where we are losing something between 12 up to 27%, 27% in net sales in Lithuania. And we have now started to see more of sort of the FX of the economical downturns.</p>
          <p>If you look at the Baltics, you could also see that traveling is less evident in these countries and so roaming fees and so are much less today than it was just a half year ago. So, we could see the impact from the economical sort of downturn. But, going forward also cost issue, as we said in the last quarter for Mobility, we'll address that also for broadband, we'll address that also for Mobility in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Broadband shows a different pattern, starting to restore the margins. And this is due to the fact that OpEx decrease with 6% overall for the Broadband business area. We have a 10% decrease in Sweden. We have close to 15% in Finland. We are increasing in other countries, but where we have addressed the cost issues in Sweden and Finland, we are down with 10 to 15% in OpEx. And I think that shows that they actually start to work now to talk about net savings and also that the saving has effect on our result, and it also improve our margins.</p>
          <p>I think it's also important to say now -- we talk about Broadband here -- that the price increase on fixed telephony that was put in place now for the first quarter will not have an immediate effect. We have sort of long-term agreements and so I think that the full effect will be seen at the end of this year. So, this will not happen overnight. So, when you look at your Excel sheets or so on, be a bit careful with the effect starting from today. Also interesting to see that the IP based services are now selling for one-third of the net sales, so it's really started. We have talked about in our focus areas that we should have transferred from fixed telephony into IP based services and this now really starts to impact our figures as such.</p>
          <p>Eurasia has been very much discussion during the last quarter when I met a lot of investors and analysts, what will happen here. And we also said in the fourth quarter report that we started to see some slowdown which we have also seen now in the first quarter when it comes to our growth, but still we have a growth of 6%, and thus excluding the acquisitions. With acquisitions, we are up with 12% locally. And the driving forces here is actually Kazakhstan, which is important because that is sort of the biggest market that we have. Uzbekistan and Tajikistan is the ones there we are still growing. We are slightly down when we come to Azerbaijan.</p>
          <p>Eurasia and the management team of Eurasia is very good when it comes to control the cost base and that's the reason why we also maintain our high margin, close to 50% still despite sort of the weaker growth that we see today. They're also very good, I would say, in keeping control over the CapEx. If you look at the CapEx to sales rate we are now down to 27% compared to 45% a year ago. And I have also said to you before that we are working now with trying to backload the investments and not taking too much frontloaded to be short of we could mitigate in an even sort of weaker economy going forward.</p>
          <p>Cash flow is important today and I learned many years ago that cash is king and I think it's very much evident even today. I think we have had one of the best quarters when it comes to free cash flow, up with 3.2 billion compared to last year in the same quarter. High EBITDA, but also lower working capital has impacted this. And I think the impact from the lower working capital is roughly 1.7 billion, and that is a combination of less of the accounts receivable, less of the inventory, and also somewhat higher supplier invoices.</p>
          <p>But strong cash flow gives us a good way for when it comes to maintain our debt structure. And as you can see here, we have not very much of a refunding needs going forward during the coming 12 months. We actually raised &#x20AC;550 million in a bond transaction at the beginning on March. Very good prices, 250 basis points of our mid-swaps, which was one of the best transactions at that point in time. An order book of close to &#x20AC;2.5 billion, and we took out 550.</p>
          <p>And that shows that we assets from a credit perspective keeps up a very good name in the market. The market for funding right now when it comes to corporates is still open but it has worked out very well as long as you have a good name. The differentiations between weaker names and good names still remain, but we as a credit in the market is operating on a very good levels and I feel comfortable that we will be able to refund what we need to refund going forward.</p>
          <p>And we have also very good base when it comes to the different banks that we are operating with. You could also see the maturity schedule going forward, rather even until 2015, 2016. We even have something in 2024 even. It's further down the road, but we try to build up sort of a rather flat and even structure when it comes to the debt maturity schedule.</p>
          <p>If we then look at the net debt, this has slightly gone down and also the net debt relation to EBITDA now down to a multiple of 1.3. And I think that's also good sign right now in these times that we are creating some kind of freedom when it comes to the cash side.</p>
          <p>Before I close this presentation, I would like to look at what we have actually delivered compared to our guidance. We have had five different areas where we've talked about net sales first, which will be slightly up. We have reversed that now on a whole year basis. But we say it will be more at the same level compared to 2008. Today, we're still up with the 0.6%. Addressable cost base unchanged on a whole year basis, today we're down with 2.4%. The EBITDA margin slightly above last year, 32.4, CapEx to sales is lower and if you look in local currencies, we are down with 16% in relative terms and that says drop of 11% compared to 13 last year. And the number of employees are now starting to go down. We are down to roughly 31,500 and we have said that we should below 31,200 at year end. So, we are delivering on these items that we have said and presented a quarter ago.</p>
          <p>And before we close this, usually shows even though I understand it within the telecom business, you will note that usually when it comes to return on equity, coming from the bank it's sort of an important issue. But what we could see here is that we're keeping up the return on equity on a good level. We have net debt/equity ratio that I mentioned before which is very good and we also keep up the return on capital employed more or less at the same level as last year. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Per-Arne, thank you Lars. We will then open up for questions. We will start with a few questions from the floor and then open up for questions on the telephone conference. We start with Sven at the corner. Please say your name and where you work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, this is Sven Sk&#xF6;ld from Swedbank. First of all, congratulations to good figures from Sweden especially, but I was looking at the Group figures and I saw that the gross margin is declining year-on-year and q-on-q and that was improving in the fourth quarter. So, what has happened in the first quarter compared to the fourth quarter? That's my first question. And then to M&amp;A. Where do you see TeliaSonera in this phase? Will you be active buying more assets in, for example, Eurasia or will you kind of stick to what you have and focus on cash flow and so on. I know for example that you discussed Spain before. I know there are some Asian assets for sale. I think we all know that. And the Turkish and the Russian issue, of course, will be of interest as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start with the gross one, I think it's slightly down compared to previously and I think what we start to see now is also the impact from regulatory issues and roaming and so on. So, I think that's the major thing that has changed between the quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the mergers and acquisitions, I think we are still interested. Nothing has changed except the prices have to come down. I think there are two opportunities. The new countries like Nepal and Cambodia, half a year ago. There is still an opportunity. But there are still some countries that we could consider. But also, we said that also for some time that we wouldn't mind increasing our ownership in existing operations. We always believe we need a local partner. But maybe we shouldn't have 51, maybe we should have 80 or 75 or something. And if such opportunities at the right price would open up, we will be interested.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello Stefan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello, Stefan Pettersson, Nordea. I have three questions. The first one relates to Swedish and Finland broadband, where you delivered very solid margins. However, we have seen the margins fluctuate quite much over the last quarters. Is this, the strong margins this quarter, is this due to lower marketing efforts? Secondly, I would just like to have a few more comments on the development in Eurasia where you go from 18% growth in local currencies down to 6%. And according to my calculations, both Azerbaijan and Georgia has negative organic growth. Then thirdly, I think that Lithuania had quite weak development that was also visible into the two's numbers. So, can you explain what's happening in Lithuania?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start talking general first. We are obviously not in a country for the short haul, we are there for the long haul. And the economy will go up and will go down, now obviously it's going down. When it goes down, we need to safeguard our results as best as we can, and the first thing that we will give up is revenue, the second one is EBITDA in kronors or in local currency, but the EBITDA margin is the last thing I want to give up. That's very important. Because the economy will turn and we need to have the right price levels.</p>
          <p>Second to that, I'm not very keen on losing market share in any markets. So, my question is if Azerbaijan and Georgia are down, are we losing market share, and I don't think we are. I think we have to live through a cycle, and yeah, that's the way our industry is. And I'm still very committed to Eurasia. The penetration levels are low, generally spoken. The economy will turn, maybe not this year, but it will turn and then we will be well positioned to benefit from that growth. And we have the clear ambition in every market we are in, if you talk mobile, that we want to be number one. And we are improving in Uzbekistan. We are in number one in Kazakhstan for years. I feel good about Eurasia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the first question was about Lithuania.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, no, I mean we as I said in my presentation, we're obviously on a downturn of roughly 27% in Lithuania. And that's a combination of sort of lower handset sales, we see that roaming is not that evident as well down there. So it's a volume issue as well. But I mean, it's that does support sort of the economic environment right now, and I'll think for, yeah...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're losing any market share in Lithuania?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first question, the first question was about broadband fluctuation on margins...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...and I think it's very, very good question and I would be extremely disappointed if the answer was yes, it is because of marketing. And I can tell you it is not because of marketing. I know how much work we have done in Sweden and Finland taking the actual OpEx down, reducing the head count.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and I mean to be able to control addressable cost, I mean, you really need to look at the head count as well. And that's sort of what's behind the figures when we are looking at the downturn on the cost side. So, and then it might be still some fluctuations, but not depending on that we're not keeping control of the cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And I would, of course, have to say that it was really strong margins in Eurasia. 50%, impressive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just remind you when it comes to Lithuania, that there was a cut in interconnect by 20% from the first quarter of 2009 compared to last year. We'll take one more question from the floor, then we open up for the telephone. We'll start with Jan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jan Dworsky from Handelsbanken. Firstly, in terms of the addressable cost base, which was down by 2.4% in Q1, and you were talking about that you want to intensify the efforts on the mobile side, why don't you think that you can take cost down in 2009 versus 2008 than rather being flat?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know that you would ask this question. And I think that what we have said we are already committing to is to be flat this time. We will continue to work with this, of course, as much as we can, but I think we should be a bit humble. This is the first quarter. We have three quarters to go for this year and to make sure that we could still work with sort of the things we would like to do when it comes to investment and so on. We still keep, stick to the flat rate. But, if things are worsening, of course, we will look at that as well as we would look at the CapEx line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I want to say this is a &#x2013; you should see this as a trend shift. We have talked over the years here of big savings in gross numbers called CCL or whatever it's called. And the actual fact is that the OpEx went up 6% two years ago and the year after 7% in net numbers. That's the real, that's the truth. And now in the first quarter it's down. And we have made a commitment that we will have flat for the full year. That's a half a culture revolution, I would argue with you in this organization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And yes, is there any hope in Denmark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hope in Denmark...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think there is hope in Denmark. I think we have a good management team, but we have a lot of work to do in Denmark. I mean, if you talk of Mobility Denmark, you saw a significant improvement last year over the year before. But the starting point, of course, a year before was horrible. And I expect the improvement to continue. Now, this financial crisis will of course make it harder for them. But I have full confidence in the Danish market, sorry, the Danish management, that we will improve and get closer to the average of the Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We open up for questions over the phone. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question comes from Mr. Patrick Maurice (sic) [Maurice Patrick] from J.P. Morgan. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Maurice Patrick from J.P. Morgan. Two questions. First of all, the revenue profile is well explained and the profitability is very impressive given what's happening there. You've talked about head count being cut, but could you help us understand of the other cost reductions, how much you feel is ongoing cost that you've taken out and how much of it is a variable cost which is possibly more temporary in nature? And the second question is linked to it. And when it looks to the Eurasian assets where again given the slowdown maintaining margins at 50% is very impressive, what further levers do you have to take out additional costs? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start with the cost base, what we're doing here, I mean there are I think three or four different areas. First of all, sort of the personnel reduction I talked about, then we have marketing which is not that we are not marketing ourselves, but we have had huge market before. So, we are, I think we are addressing it to a more sort of normalized level number one. So, we will still be visible in the market, I promise you. Number three is the IT side where we are much tougher on the prioritization. Still having quite a lot of projects, but we have had huge projects here when it comes to SAP and other similar systems. But there we are much tougher today. So, it's nothing so that we are stopped doing things that will makes our operations to stand still.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, this is a structural change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I argued all along that we cannot have structurally higher costs and those are the costs, structurally higher costs that we are addressing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in Eurasia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well what more levers that we have. Tero Kivisaari, who runs this, is a very strong leader and he has a good team. I know they have more levers. Let's see first on what happens to the top line. I don't &#x2013; I'm slightly optimistic that we will continue to see growth in this part of the world and therefore maybe the pressure on other levers won't be that high, but I'm guessing now. And I apologize for not being more clear, but the situation in the market is so unpredictable, so difficult to describe, and to describe what we can expect that we simply don't know, which means that we have to maintain high flexibility and act early and as I said I was a little bit disappointed with the results in Mobility for the first quarter. I'm disappointed because, I think we should have acted a little bit earlier than we did. Now we are acting, but maybe we lost 60 days in acting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick followup. Are there any elements of your cost base in Eurasian assets which are still inflationary?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Depends from country-to-country, I mean, what was normally driving the inflation is the salary increases. So, but that's a country-to-country shift.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, you still are seeing some wage inflation in the markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think it's depending on the competition. It's depending on which people you have. But, I think that if you compare now, let's say with a year ago, I suppose it's much lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well if you look at the, I'm not talking about Eurasia now, we can talk about the Baltic states, we had wage inflation 15 months ago, 12 months ago, and today we talk about wage decreases. Cutting the wages and not only us, I mean, everybody is cutting wages.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We take another question from the conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. David Wright from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. A couple of questions. First of all, in Finland it looks like Elisa is very close to your heels as being the number one market share operator. To what extent, I think you said before market share is very important to you. How willing are you to take that fight to Elisa over the next couple of quarters. I think, I saw some comments overnight, a report from MegaFon, sorry an interview with the MegaFon CEO talking about dividend of $300 million being reasonable, I think he said $1 billion is being unreasonable. Can you indicate whether that's, that $300 million dividend is a level that you would be comfortable with approving as a shareholder? And then maybe just if you could give us a little bit more detail on the revenue trends in Danish mobile. Your minutes of use don't looked to have materially diverged, but clearly the ARPU and the service revenue in particular in local currency has dipped dramatically. Can you give us an indication of the market dynamics there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is Lars. Let me start with the first question. I can assure you I'm well aware that Elisa is on our heels, as you expressed it. We have in the last year, I think, been a little bit cautious in the whole group in either starting or participating in price wars. The example, I gave you on the changed prices in mobile data in Sweden where we adjust them to the volume, to the usage, and not the just a flat fee is an example of, I think, being careful with the price.</p>
          <p>We did not participate in the end of last year when there was a price war in Finland. We stood outside and probably lost a little bit of market share on it. Of course, there comes a point when we &#x2013; we don't have a choice. But we, I don't want TeliaSonera to be a price aggressive operator, leading price wars, starting price wars. At the same time, nobody should doubt that we will defend our position if really challenged.</p>
          <p>On the issue of dividend in MegaFon, that is a decision that will be taken first by our recommendation by the Board in, I don't know, a month or so is the next board meeting, and then there will be an AGM later on this spring where it would finally be decided. And I decided I will refrain from having any public comments on this issue. I would prefer to discuss that in the Board or later on in the AGM. I want to listen to also to our co-owners. I have quite a bit of, you haven't asked me about MegaFon and Turkcell, so I can say something anyway. I have quite intensive relationship and discussions with all those players. And I think the relationship is business like. And therefore, I think it is not responsible for me to stand here and have comments if I have any on the dividend policy of MegaFon. I prefer to have the discussion with those people and listen to what their arguments are and then we will together make some sort of decision and I'll be willing to comment after we've done that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, your last question was regarding Denmark and I think that Lars has commented Denmark is a challenging market at the moment. Minutes of use is still growing in the Danish market by 2% approximately, but ARPU is down by 11%. And that is a factor that we have some promotion campaigns, free minutes, etcetera. When it comes to the ARPU, I just want to remind you that we have been relatively successful when it comes to adding Mobile Broadband subscribers in Denmark and that is having a dilutive effect on the ARPU number. So, be somewhat cautious in extrapolating that trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I see. That's all very clear. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one more question from the call, then we take some more questions from the floor, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Damien Maltarp from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. It's Damien Maltarp from Credit Suisse. Just a couple of questions. Can you talk a bit about what you're seeing in the enterprise or corporate space? I guess you are seeing maybe less business travelers, but are you seeing any other changes such as delayed order completion, maybe a bit more pricing pressure. And then secondly, I guess just looking at Spain, there have been obviously some press reports about you potentially talking to Doughty Hanson about them potentially taking a stake. Any comment there would be appreciated? And perhaps in that context have you got a preference for a partial versus a complete exit were an exit to be something you would consider? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Lars. If I start with the business-to-business, my comments will primarily be based on the Swedish and the Finnish markets. We see all of what you just asked, but we also see this being one of the six focus areas a world class sales organization. I also see real efficiency improvements in our sales operation. And we did not have a bad quarter actually, but we, yes we see price pressure. We are a supplier, which provides we think better quality, better coverage and we are asking a premium for that. And it's more difficult today to get that premium than it was a year ago.</p>
          <p>Yes, we do see customers delaying decisions, postponing it and not just two weeks, but maybe two quarters for obvious reasons. Still, I'm pretty happy with the performance of our business-to-business sales organization in the first quarter. I believe that they will improve their efficiency even further during throughout this year and I think we are well underway to create a sales organization that is going to be second to none in these two markets. There was another question? Spain. Yeah, I don't want to comment, I haven't changed my mind or we haven't changed our mind. We are looking for an exit of some kind. I'm in no hurry &#x2013; I won't be pressed for time or it's got to be a reasonable deal. This is obviously not the best time to try to sell anything. That's why I'm interested in buying. So, we'll see &#x2013; we'll see. Strategically and regarding to priorities, nothing has changed. We have made up our mind, we made our decision, and we will execute it in due time and in a good way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Now, we take a couple of questions from the floor. Lena?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lena &#xD6;sterberg from SEB Enskilda. First of all, you blame roaming revenues for a slowdown in mobile sales in several of the countries. I was just wondering if you could shed some light on how much this of sales and which countries are most exposed to roaming sales? And then also on your cost base, could you maybe just say how much cost inflation you expect in the non-addressable cost base, so we know how much that is going to increase roughly? And then you mentioned that on the mobile side, you were disappointed with the cost side compared to revenues and that you're addressing that now. Should we expect that margins would be increased, because it seems you've having a rather rapid response to the decline in sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the last one, the guys can think about your two first questions. When the margin declines in the first quarter the way it did, you have to do something. You can't &#x2013; I can't accept that the margin is going to be on this level for the rest of the year. We have higher ambition, exact how higher they are, I don't want to address that right now. But clearly, clearly when the revenue actually in local currency going down, you can't have costs going up. It's just sort of basic. And the question is what's going to happen with the top line. We don't think there is going to be a strong growth or anything. So, we have to address the OpEx. Clearly, the focus on the OpEx during, let's say, the fall of last year was very much in broadband, because that's where we have the structurally higher cost. I actually don't think we have too much of structurally higher cost in Mobility, but now we are affected by the fact that we don't get growth. We get decline on top line and then you have to address the cost, not because they're structurally higher, but your business is going down. And that's the difference. There is a major difference between these two challenges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so and then if you look at the roaming, if you compare year-on-year, I would say that it means 3% units roughly. So, I mean instead of having a negative growth of 0.8, I mean we should be positive, so that actually has impact. But that doesn't take away the thing that we are discussing right now on the cost side, but it is an effect on the net sales side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But could you maybe just say which countries are most exposed to the roaming revenues? Is it the Baltics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's the Baltics and also to some extent, Finland. And just to give you some feeling for roaming revenues, it's approximately 4% of Group net sales. And of the decline that we see in roaming net revenues, approximately two-thirds are volume, or pricing and about one-third is pricing. So, there is a difference between volume and price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's say that again now, two-thirds is what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's volume, prices coming down, one-third is prices coming down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. Is that okay, I hope you understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No. No. Was it prices or volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What is it now, volume or prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Volume. Sorry, wasn't that not clear. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, volume two-thirds and price two-thirds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two-third is volume and one...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One-third is prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and volume..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we take the next question? We take Anders on the front row?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations to a very nice cash flow driven by improved EBITDA, but also CapEx down 16% in local currency year-over-year. Should I interpret your comment in the guidance that CapEx could actually decline even more than 16% year-over-year if the economy worsens?</p>
          <p>And second a follow-on question, you decided not to go together with Tele2 in the 4G venture, you have a 3G venture together with them, but not 4G. How does that tie into the ambition to lower cash flow? And finally on the same thing, cash drain from Spain, you from negative EBITDA worsen in the quarter, but you just still talk about you wanting to sell it? Should we expect that you are going to work down the EBITDA losses later in the year or why did you increase it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me talk about the network, because I've also seen some articles about the fact that two of our colleagues are combining their forces in the new network. I believe that the quality of network is one of the key ingredients in being successful as an operator. The other one is world class customer service and the third one is cost structure. You cannot have a higher cost structure than the competition. So, if you have the best network, the best customer service and comparable costs, you win. It's that's simple. Therefore, I have the luxury in this country to have a market share of way over 40%. I have 5.3 million subscribers. I think my two colleagues together have the same number. So, I understand the need to cooperate. I like to control my network. I want to be able to decide myself when I invest, when I don't invest. I want to be able to decide a quality level of the network. I don't want to be able to, or be depend on somebody else. The reason why we have a cooperation in 3G we all know, we didn't get a license, we didn't have a choice. But if I have a choice and if I'm big enough, I prefer to have my own network under my control.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to caps, I think we should look at it from a different perspective. I mean, we are first of all trying to protect our cash flow. At the same time, we are also willing to take some opportunities if this &#x2013; if they occur in certain markets. So, we still stick to the outlook that we had from the very beginning. And depending on what is happening in the economy and also combined with certain opportunities in market, we will continue to invest. So, if the question was whether we should decrease CapEx even more, if that was sort of the intention of the question, then we have done today and I'm not really sure about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Spain losses increased, are you going to address that to get losses down again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Losses increased because we had more intake or more customers than we maybe had anticipated. I don't &#x2013; of course we have to continue to try to deliver on this plan that was delayed, which was the reason why I said in September of last year, now we're going to look at alternatives. The management, Johan and his team are trying to deliver the plan to the best of their ability, which is important because if we want to sell it or sell part of it, the better the results are or the better prediction or the better the prices are or the easier it will be to make the deal. But, the increase in losses was very much driven by the customer intake. We have a huge customer intake in the first quarter. There are some real turbulence in the market in Spain right now and we are getting a lot of customers coming into us, which is sort of short-term not good, longer term very good. So, I'm, nothing has really changed for me in Spain. That's sort of, they're doing a pretty good job of the management there. But, strategically I want to see if I find another solution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have quite a lot of questions over the conference call. We take one more question on the floor then we open up again for the conference call. We take Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Michael Andersson here from Evli Bank. A question regarding the mobile margins again. We spoke about SIM only offers, mobile broadband offers also, subsidies and so on. How do you feel about that today, regards or comparable to when we stood here in the Q4 report? Or is, I guess that's a fine balance here in this current environment if you want to be more aggressive lower, to use these things more. And the other part is on &#x2013; also on the 4G buildout, you say you want to control your own networks, but are there other ways, I guess in terms of also network sharing to some extent, infrastructure, which could be done and still you would still control your network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the last question, of course I'm willing to cooperate with other players provided I maintain the control I want to have, because if I can save cost, that's great. And if they can save it too, it's good for them. You know you can share masts, you can do a lot of things. And we have lots of discussions in many markets, not only in Sweden, with the other operators to see if we can share things. But, I wanted to make the point fundamentally that, that I think that the quality of the network is a key ingredient in our strategy. And therefore I want to have that control, and I'm pretty convinced that that's a good decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to SIM only, I think in the fourth quarter there was a lot of discussion about this and it was basically driven from UK where Vodafone has been doing this for quite a while, and that was sort of a big ambition. We haven't seen this in our markets and it hasn't, has not been sort of a big marketing thing for us either. So, I think it's more UK driven right now. It has been in place for a while, but it's not a big product right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's nothing that you would like to drive yourself as...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no. No, no, no, not actually right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We take a couple of questions from the conference call. Can I please just ask you to limit you to maybe one or two questions, as there are many on the line. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Soomit Datta from New Street Research. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there, yes, Soomit at New Street Research. Can I just check in Sweden the new guidance obviously includes the line rental price increase. You said that the benefit will be sort of gradual and phased, I guess, over the course of the year. Could you perhaps quantify what that revenue uptick should be?</p>
          <p>And then as a follow-on and this is perhaps a harder question to answer, but what is your anticipation and perhaps what's embedded in your guidance for what the competitors are likely to do. So, could you anticipate the likes of Telenor and Tele2 increasing prices as well or do you think they might use the opportunity to compete further against you? I'll leave it at that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you take the fixed line business, I will say that we haven't quantified yet. But, I think you should be cautious this year to put again too much sort of additional revenues. So, I think the effect will be from next year in full. So, be careful with this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As the leader in many of these markets that we are in, I think we have responsibility to lead. That's why we were the first to introduce this variable depending on usage, mobile data pricing. We will defend our positions, I've said that before, but we will not be the one who starts price wars or we want to be &#x2013; we do not want to be perceived as a price leader, because we have added value, we have better coverage, better quality networks and hopefully better customer service than our competitors. And we are worth a premium for that, that's the fundamental belief and then you shouldn't be the aggressive price fighter. However, as I said before, we will defend our market positions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, in summary, would you expect the fixed line operators, your competitors to increase prices in the coming weeks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know &#x2013; I don't know what they're going to do. They do whatever they think is right for them. And we will see, but, I will say that this discussion we had on the pricing structure for mobile data I have read in the papers that several of my colleagues have gone out and said that they sort of support that model. Whether they're going to have a lower price, I don't know, but they support the model, they said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We take another question from the conference call. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Jakob Bluestone from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh. Hi, there. I've got two questions. Firstly, I just want to make sure I understand your guidance correctly. You've lowered your revenue guidance, but you've kept your cost guidance unchanged, but you're also saying that your percentage margin is not going to change. And I'm just trying to understand shouldn't that mathematically imply a lower percentage margin? Is that because your non-addressable cost base is shrinking or is it because that margin &#x2013; the percentage margin guidance is actually pretty broad? And then just secondly, you obviously had pretty big swings in working capital, which you mentioned during the presentation as well. And I was just wondering if you could perhaps give us some guidance for what we should be looking for for the full year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if I start for the working capital, as I said it's accounts receivable, it's the inventory and also the accounts payable. And it's, we are trying to monitor our working capital perhaps tighter today than we have done before. But at the same time, sometimes it's to be extremely precise and give you a guideline is nearly impossible. But, the only thing is this is a part of the cash flow focus that we have. So, it's difficult to give any guidance on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the guidance, on the margin guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean if we start, what we have said is that we will have more flattish net sales compared to sort of some growth. At the same time, we are also working with the cost and nothing to the interaction between sort of the regulatory issues that we have on the gross margin and also the cost savings will give us, and will leave us with the ambition to still have a flat margin. I think that's the very simple mathematics that we have right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We take one more question from the conference call. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. James Britton from Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, thanks very much. A question on the termination rate issue, which you mentioned on page five of the release. So it seems as though the rate is likely to come down pretty substantially in Sweden in the middle of the year. Do you expect to negotiate any change in the 40% cut proposal that's in place at the moment. And overall, are the termination cuts value negative or value positive for Telia given that you will be saving a lot of costs in your fixed business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, James. It's Andreas. We, first of all, just be clear that it has not been taking a decision from the PTS to lower the interconnect to that level that you mentioned. And so, we will see before the summer where the result will end up. For us as a Group, it will be more or less neutral because the loss that we have on Mobility will be a gain on Broadband Services. So, for us as a Group, it's more or less neutral.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We take one more question from the conference call. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Jacques de Greling from Natixis Securities. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jacques de Greling from Natixis Securities. Am I right to understand that your cut in CapEx you might do would be mostly related to Eurasia, the first question. Second question, what kind of impact do you expect for the publication next month of the EU recommendation on mobile termination rate? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, when it comes to the CapEx side, I think that is not just Eurasia, I think that's the responsibility of all the business areas. So, everyone need to look at their CapEx levels. And if you look at that, if you take both Mobility and also broadband, they are pretty low in CapEx to sales right now. So, this is a joint responsibility in all business areas. But of course, the ratio is higher in Eurasia than we have in the other ones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the other question was about lowering cost when you're abroad, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, my question was regarding the, sorry, my second question was about the EU recommendation to be post next month. Do you expect it will have a significant impact on the mobile termination rates in Sweden, etcetera where you are expecting a decision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Who knows that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we can just say that in average that we have among the lowest interconnect rates already in the Nordic countries. So, we are looking into that, but more on a country-to-country basis, I would say.</p>
          <p>We take two more questions, I think, from the floor. And then I think that we said an hour and I think that we break it there. Two more questions, starting with Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lars S&#xF6;derfjell, Kaupthing Bank. Yeah, one of the more long-term issue on the mobile internet side, I mean, obviously both ARPUs and margins are taking a hit right now from subscriber acquisitions. Longer term, where do you see given the changed pricing models you implemented, where do you see margins ending up compared to the traditional voice business. And secondly, just a detail. We talked about the roaming impact on revenues, how much was equipment sales impacting revenues in the quarter either, in millions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it's very hard to say, right. But, clearly the reason why we changed the pricing model is that the flat free model is not sustainable model for the industry. We need to ensure we have profitability so we can invest in further capacity increases, because I fundamentally believe there is an unlimited demand for bandwidth going forward, just as it was in processor capacity, in storage capacity, bandwidth, we'll have exactly the same situation. So, we will talk gigabit soon. And if we're going to be able to provide that, then we got to have the resources to do that. That means we have to make money on this thing. Now, the good news is I think technology and the equipment is coming down very rapidly. I know it's coming down very rapidly, and it will continue to come down very rapidly. I mean, in the IT industry, Moore's Law said same price every 18th  month double capacity, right. Something similar, I think, we will see here. Our ambition must be to maintain the EBITDA margin when we transfer from voice to non-voice and if you have a 100 gigabit per second, voice will take hardly any space. So, we'll have to fill that with something else. And that something else will be a lot of new applications, because our life's about to change in my opinion.</p>
          <p>And those applications, we might not make all the money on the application, and we come to a very strategic discussion about content and our role in content. And I happen to believe that we are not very well positioned to create a lot of applications and lot of content, but, we are very good in managing networks. So, we have to make sure that we have a pricing model whereby this bandwidth, voice or data, maintains a 30 whatever percent EBITDA margin or 35 or whatever the ambition should be. And that's why we changed the pricing model. This is the first step.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Coming back to the question about hardware and so on, and I think if you take the Baltics as an example, half of the downturn was connected to less hardware sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A follow-up question from Sven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Sven from Swedbank again. I was just wondering about the investments in 4G because a number of operators are planning these investments for the moment and how high are these investments going to be? And do you, I mean, is it going to be an increased level in mobile services coming 1.5 years now or is it going to be a cut in 2G and possibly 3G, so it's going to be a sustainable unchanged level or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I understand the question and I'm not sure we have the total answer on that question. The big investment we did was to buy the license. That was quite a bit of money. And we have also said we limit initially to two cities, Stockholm and Oslo. That will reduce the amount of money. There is a value for us being an early adopter of new technology. I want TeliaSonera to be perceived by the market as a leading company. And therefore, I put a value on that. But, I will &#x2013; the value is not that big that I can afford to boost the CapEx in 4G, and not save somewhere else. So, it's going to be a balanced approach.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Someone is telling me that there is one final question over the conference call. Let's make that the final question of the day. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question comes from Mr. Maurice Patrick from J.P. Morgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you once again. Just on network sharing and your comments about wanting to have a wider network and better network, it being valuable there for not wanting to share it. Is that a comment that applies just to Sweden or does that apply across other properties in your footprint? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question. I think I said when you have a market share of north of 40%, you have the luxury you can have this position. If you don't have a market share that high then, I think you might have to think another time whether you can combine it with somebody else. But, I still believe having control over your network is a key ingredient in your success. So, it depends very much on how that cooperation will be done. I will say soon up has worked very well for us and I think for our colleague too. So, it is possible, it is possible to do. But as our ambition is to be number one in the markets where we are in, I think in most cases we should be able to own and control the network by ourselves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much. That was the final question. Thank you for your interest. We will publish our second quarter report on the 23rd  of July and I hope to see you back then. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>