<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1269042" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2927</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lars Nyberg, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Per-Arne Blomquist, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Sven Sk&#xF6;ld</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Lars S&#xF6;derfjell</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Stefan Pettersson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Peter Kurt Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Tim Boddy</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Damien Maltarp</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Lena &#xD6;sterberg</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Michael Andersson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jan Dworsky</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">David Wright</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Ulrich Rathe</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Andrew Lee</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Maurice Patrick</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think that we are ready to start. Welcome everyone. My name is Andreas Ekstr&#xF6;m, Head of Investor Relations. With me today, I have our President and CEO, Mr. Lars Nyberg; and our Executive Vice President and CFO, Mr. Per-Arne Blomquist.</p>
          <p>Before we start the presentation, let me just remind you that the presentation is available at our webpage teliasonera.com. And after the presentation by Lars and Per-Arne, we will also take your questions both from the floor and from the telephone conference.</p>
          <p>With that I leave the word to Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andreas. Good morning and welcome everybody. If you think I'm a bit stiff it's because I've pain in my back. And if I make noises it's because of pain in my back not the numbers.</p>
          <p>I think we had again a very strong quarter, which I'm obviously very pleased with. Last year, you remember, when we talk growth we talk always organic in local currency because the fluctuation of the Swedish krona.</p>
          <p>Last year in 2009, we had flat revenue growth, which probably was one of the best results in the &#x2013; among the telecom corporates in Europe. Now, this quarter, we just think is the most important result of the quarter is the growth, local organic growth of 2.5%, which I'm extremely pleased with.</p>
          <p>You can see that we also improved our EBITDA margin; we've been doing that for several quarters. Obviously we are a little bit helped by the growth, but we still benefit from the cost savings in '08 and '09 when we compare to first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Talking about growth, this is the curve that you can see. The blue curve shows us the organic growth and we were flat up and down a little bit in the 4 quarters of last year and now we are clearly up for the 2.5%. What drives that? What is it that drives the growth in the first quarter?</p>
          <p>I'm extremely pleased with our results in Mobility in Sweden. To be the number one by a mile, with market shares over 40% and then grow in the quarter by 9%, that's pretty good, I think, pretty good. I'm very happy with that. And obviously you can see that it is mainly the data that is growing, not voice.</p>
          <p>And also it's not only consumer driven, we made &#x2013; you might not remember this, but 2.5 years ago, one of the priorities we had was to improve our business-to-business sales organization. I think we are now starting to see some signs at least in Sweden of that work. So the growth of 9% is coming not only from the consumer side, but also from the business-to-business side.</p>
          <p>It's not only Sweden that is growing Mobility. As you can see after having had declines for a long time in Finland and Denmark, we are now growing in Finland and Denmark as well in the first quarter. Only Norway is still down.</p>
          <p>In the Baltics, we've had a challenge and we continue to have a challenge. You see the numbers are in terms of revenue down, continues to be down. We had hoped during last year maybe the turnaround would come somewhere around this time. It hasn't arrived yet. As we said in the fourth quarter, this is a challenge. I think the management teams in those countries have done a super job; I said this before. They continue to be able to maintain the margin, although the revenue was down 20% or something like that.</p>
          <p>Our growth engine -- maybe I have to stop saying this is the only growth engine; when Sweden Mobility grows 9% that is also growth engine actually. But the growth engine Eurasia has now in three quarters improved our growth rate. If you remember in the third quarter of last year we grew 3.6%, in the fourth quarter we grew 7, and now we grow 12.7%. It's well spread among all the countries. The most important, and those of you who follow us in detail, you know that Kazakhstan is a heavy weight country in Eurasia, and you can see Kazakhstan growing more than 10%. That's very important. Obviously our new countries, Uzbekistan, Tajikistan and Nepal, are growing like 50 to 35%.</p>
          <p>In Eurasia, we are also integrating Eurasia much more into TeliaSonera. It's a work that has been going on for two years. It's really now a part of TeliaSonera in processes, in values, in priorities, and also to integrate Eurasia in itself, we started re-branding, because we had all different kinds of brands in Eurasia. And you can see the logo with the purple stone and we use the word Kcell for Kazakhstan, Geocell, Tcell for Tajikistan, and Ncell for Nepal. When we bought Nepal, it was called Spice Nepal. And we want our customers in Eurasia when they're traveling these countries to recognize that these countries belong together and they belong to TeliaSonera. We will continue &#x2013; all the countries will have the same logo and the same construction of the names.</p>
          <p>The only surprise I think maybe in the numbers is the CAPEX being quite much lower than I think most people expected. Couple of reasons for that; we took a deliberate decision for Eurasia to wait with the investment in Eurasia, because we wanted to be absolutely sure that we would get the growth. So that's the biggest deviation from our plans. Obviously we now have &#x2013; now we have the growth, so we feel much more comfortable to spend that money.</p>
          <p>And as I said after the fourth quarter, I do believe it's time for TeliaSonera to invest more. We will maintain, as you will see soon, we will maintain the CAPEX being just shy of 15%, whether we get there in the end we will see, but I'm clearly prepared to go there.</p>
          <p>Another reason is the fiber rollout; with the weather we've had in the first quarter, it's been somewhat slower than we anticipated. And we have also been negotiating with some suppliers. So I'm not unhappy that it's lower in the first quarter. I'm not unhappy, but I am not happy either, so we really need to see the investment pick up now in the coming three quarters.</p>
          <p>And this is old news, which is I think is good news; we maintained the outlook for 2010. Obviously I feel more comfortable with the first point somewhat higher &#x2013; net sales being somewhat higher, I said that standing here in February and obviously standing here now, I feel more comfortable with that statement and the rest is the same as before.</p>
          <p>Okay, Per-Arne, you can go through some numbers in detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. As Lars said, a solid quarter. We have been like used to be a bit boring. I don't have a problem to be boring if that's what is to be boring. Top-line growth, you can see here 2.5% in organic growth. You can also see the effect &#x2013; the FX effect is close to 7%, and I think that has been very good that we have sort of looked at this also last year so we can see what is sort of down the line business doing.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the EBITDA, was up close to 9% in organic &#x2013; local organic, EPS up with 6%, solid cash flow was up with 3.5%. But what I think is perhaps is even more encouraging is that we now come closer to 150 million subscriber in our company. And we have close to 50 million in our consolidated entities and more than 100 million subscriber in our associates.</p>
          <p>When we look at the last quarter here, our consolidated account actually increased more 2.3 million subscribers compared to 1.3 in the &#x2013; among the associates. So we continue to grow also the customer base.</p>
          <p>Mobility, continued growth, we could see that in Sweden and Spain 4.9% in underlying growth. We have a EBITDA increasing with 8.6%. If you take one of the drivers that's the mobile broadband, it's up with 60% when it comes to subscribers doubling the data traffic, the volumes. And we have today close to 1.2 million customers on mobile broadband where roughly 500,000 of these are in Sweden. And if we look at the Swedish numbers, they are growing their base with close to 35% and also doubling their traffic.</p>
          <p>Margins very solid, if we take Sweden more than 40% in EBITDA margin, Finland more than 32% close to 33, and the Baltics as we said before, even though they have a downturn they have margins between 36 to 42%.</p>
          <p>When it comes to growth in Broadband Services, we have not been able to offset the downturn when it comes to the more traditional business that we have with IP-based services, even though today, IP-based services stands for 36% of our revenue. However, we are working very hard &#x2013; continues to work very hard with the cost side, which means that we are up to close to 35% in EBITDA margin for the whole business area.</p>
          <p>Sweden has done a good job as well continue to takedown the cost as also Finland and they are between 33 and 41% in margins. You could also see that Estonia managed to be well above 30%. We see in Lithuania that we're losing there right now from 45 down to 41% in &#x2013; on the margin side. However, I think that they have done a very, very good job when it comes to the cost side. So we feel comfortable with the margin development right now.</p>
          <p>Eurasia, Lars also mentioned, and I used to sort of divide this into two entities. We have Kazakhstan, Azerbaijan and Georgia, who are sort of the big entities. There we have Kazakhstan growing with close to 12%. We then take the other entities. We have grown as we said Tajikistan 41%, Uzbekistan 50 and Nepal close to 40%. And in this area, we have also increased during the last year with 21% when it comes to subscribers. Four million subscribers has been added on to our customer base and we have today 33 million subscribers.</p>
          <p>Some comments upon some of the line items that we have, starting of course with the cost side. You can see here for the Group down with 3%, we are down on the personnel side with 9% as well as on IT, increasing somewhat on marketing. In Sweden and Finland, we're also down with 11 to 13% on personnel and also IT. Meanwhile you could see that rents going up and that doesn't mean that we have sort of hired new facilities. We have canceled certain contracts and we have taken the cost for that. So the underlying is &#x2013; cost is flat or even somewhat down.</p>
          <p>Income from associated companies down with 18%; basically we have a negative &#x2013; the main negative impact from Turkey. We've had goodwill impairment. We have also some regulatory issues hitting the result. Turkey's today is a bit tougher market to be in. But, Turkcell is the one that's actually earning money in this market that stands for a very high portion of the earning capacity. We could also see that Russia is doing pretty well more or less flattish or it was somewhat down compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Financial items down with 42%. That is a combination of that our interest rates are going down in general, we also have a somewhat lower net debt. For the time being, the Eurobond market is very, very liquid and open and very deep and we are trying to utilize this and we have done that at the end of last year and we will look at those opportunities going forward to refund ourselves in the Eurobond market. But for us as a solid company there is a very, very good opportunities to still get loans for a very, very good pricing right now and I wonder sometimes how long this could last, but we will take the opportunity on way to refund ourselves in this market.</p>
          <p>Income taxes, slightly up, and the reason for the increase in the effective tax rate is that we have less of income from our resources. We should normally have a sort of positive impact on the tax rate. You could also see here that we talked about payer taxes last year and they were slightly above four to 5% and we said that they will come up and we are now coming closer to the 80% that we talked about and that is it with the paid taxes as a share of reported income taxes.</p>
          <p>Cash flow, two parts here that more or less is equal. We have a minus on the working capital side. We have paid pretty much our suppliers this quarter little heavy investments done in December last year, which means that working capital is going up. At the same time, we have taken down CAPEX, which means that we are slightly up on the cash flow.</p>
          <p>Continue to have a solid financial position 1.2 in net debt to EBITDA, we have a good maturity schedule. We have already this year repaid close to five billion in bonds. We haven't done any major refunding in the market. But you could also see that we don't have any major refunding needs during the coming year. We could manage well with the sort of our operating cash flow.</p>
          <p>Finally, return on equity which I think will become more and more important even for this industry, slightly up compared to December, now close to 15.5 return on capital employed 15.6 and as you could see equity to asset ratio and net debt to equity ratio well above, we could say, last year and I think we are having a very, very stable finance situation right now. I stop there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then it's time for Q&amp;A. Lars, you're able to stand up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll hold to something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we start with a few questions from the floor before leaving over to the conference call. But we start with a question from Sven. Please introduce yourself with your name and company, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is Sven Sk&#xF6;ld from Swedbank. I have a question regarding Finland, and the fixed line side in Finland, which surprised me a little bit with the weaker revenue at least than I had expected, and I couldn't find the reason in the operational data, so if you could discuss Finland a little bit.</p>
          <p>And the second question is on the associated companies. Do you have a view on the outlook for the associated companies for 2010? I mean you have a very specific guidance for the consolidated part of the company, but if you could also give some highlights on the associated. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start with Finland, clearly there has been a shift much faster and much earlier in Finland from fixed to Mobility, which we haven't seen to the same extent in Sweden. And as you -- I think you know that we believe that the fixed network is going to be very important for a telecom operator going forward because of the unlimited demand for bandwidth.</p>
          <p>What drives that is video, I think. So what we call triple play is going to be important and to fixed points, the fixed network is the best solution. We just introduced IPTV in Finland. And we are expanding that and we are investing in fiber in Finland. So yes, we have a downturn that's slightly bigger than maybe we had hoped for, but I feel pretty confident that the fixed network in Finland and in Sweden and in some of the Baltic states is going to be very important for our company going forward. And that's why we invest in fiber. We talked about that in last quarter.</p>
          <p>We don't make any outlooks for the associated companies. I think MegaFon is doing very well. Of course, we are not happy with the performance of Turkcell. But, that is for the board of Turkcell to deal with and I'm not on the board. Tero Kivisaari is, though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We take the next question from Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Lars S&#xF6;derfjell, &#xC5;landsbanken. Looking at Broadband Services Sweden and EBITDA margins, two years ago we thought about this as a 30% business; a year ago it's a 35% business, now 40% business. I mean, is this as good as it gets, or do you see any potential?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next year 50, you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you talk a little bit about, I mean, how you see the margin development and what else you &#x2013; how much more you can get out of this, as the full benefits from the costs and so on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a short-term answer or a medium-term answer, and you can think about that. Well, there is a longer one I like to talk about. And that's a little bit to Sven's question. If we can provide 100 megabit or a gigabit per second to fixed places like homes and offices, I think the ARPU will go up quite dramatically. The question is, what's the margin going to be on part of that ARPU. And we are spending right now a lot of time with Malin Frenning who will take over the Broadband from January 1 because she is spending all her time on strategy and how do we get growth in this business. And I'm convinced that we'll get growth. I'm not sure when and it's not in the short-term, but maybe it's in the medium-term; it's certain in the long-term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you look at them more in such a long thing what you usually expect is to sort of increase. I mean we still have effects from a very tough cost cutting program last year which will affect us positively this quarter, perhaps also next quarter. But then it's more I think it's a question of the balance between getting growth, getting, having the right customer cares and all this stuff. So I think it, somehow it's also worthwhile to invest, but with us (19.56) being at 40% is very, very good. I don't think that <mark type="inaudible" /> is to increase dramatically from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I mean, it should decline much either from this level, no? Should we think about, about this asset 40% business going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's optimistic, to be honest with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it probably will decline and then maybe will pick up when &#x2013; in my vision, or the vision we have is coming then I think it might pick up. I would certainly, if I had to bet, I'll bet it go down; I wouldn't bet it go up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's take one more question from the floor. Stefan on the front row.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Stefan Pettersson, Nordea. First question regarding subscriber intake in Sweden which declined this quarter, and it seems to be a decline in the prepaid subscriber base. Can you just explain what has happened? Have you cleaned up subscriber base?</p>
          <p>Secondly, at least against my numbers there was a large &#x2013; your report numbers deviated to my forecast on wholesale business, and can you explain what has happened in the wholesale business leading to rather weak sales development?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start with the mobile subscribers, I think we are slightly down on prepaid, but we are actually increasing on postpaid. So I think that I don't see sort of a major shift, it's not a very big deviation. I don't know if we have done any extra things, but it's --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's part of our cleanup in our prepaid brand called Halebop that we have -- that stands for majority of that decline. So you should see it as a one-time item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But what I'll think is more encouraging is actually that we are increasing our postpaid.</p>
          <p>And when it comes to wholesale, I think they are in the business where you could see pretty tough competition &#x2013; price competition. I don't think that's affecting them right now and that's -- you might expect it not to be extremely volatile, but it could be a bit volatile from quarter-to-quarter given the mix of services that we are selling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll come back to the floor in a short while, but in the meantime, let's open up for questions on the conference call. Operator, can we please have the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question comes from Mr. Peter Kurt Nielsen from Cheuvreux, London. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Peter Kurt Nielsen from London. I have two questions for Lars, please. Firstly, Lars you, as you started out by saying the Swedish Mobile business has performed a stellar performance the last 12 months basically. Nonetheless, you've implemented some management changes in this business area and in the broadband business. Does this reflect a changed approach, philosophy or strategy to your mobile versus broadband business going forward? Anything you could elaborate on this for us, what we should expect from TeliaSonera going forward.</p>
          <p>And second question, it's now been six months since you announced the agreement with Altimo, and I appreciate there probably hasn't been much new to report. I'm sure you would have done so if there had been. But could you give us a status update on exactly where we are now and if you remain as confident now of completing this transaction as you were 6 months ago? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I have been wrong on the growth rate of Mobile Sweden 5 quarters on a row because I predicted it not to be as strong as it has been, and I'm saying to my colleagues down there, one day I will be right. The question is just when and I love to be wrong this way; I have no problem with that.</p>
          <p>The management changes that you referred to has nothing to do with a changed priority or direction in mobile. We are on a journey, we are seriously trying to change the way we operate as a company, what our values are. And one of the issues that we are confronted with is a tradition of working in stovepipes. I talk about one company and I made a number of changes in this company where I have asked people to leave because I felt they weren't really willing to work in one company. They wanted to work in their own company. And I will continue to do that if I find it necessary. I will say that I have a management team today in TeliaSonera that is better than anything I have seen or worked with. And I think that's the main reason why this company has made so much progress in the last couple of years.</p>
          <p>On the issue of Altimo, maybe the most important question or most important answer is, no, I have not changed my opinion on optimist of being able to deliver the value, because you remember I said, I think it's a very important agreement, but the value of the agreement is in the execution of the agreement. I've also said that we will start focusing on Turkey. We would like to see that being resolved. And later on, we will file a request in Russia for an authorization from the authorities to form this. And we all know that there are some players who would prefer this not to happen, but there is no need to file that request yet, because we would like to see if we can resolve Turkey first or at least partly resolve Turkey.</p>
          <p>No, and I had no details to report of progress. There is some progress, but not significant to report or confidential, so I don't want to talk about it, but there is some progress. And I &#x2013; my optimism for making the deal is as similar as it was in the fall of last year when I presented it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Peter Kurt. Let's take another question from the conference call. Operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Alex Duval from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to pass it over actually to my colleague, Tim Boddy, if I may.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alex. Yeah, I just wanted to ask about the situation in Spain. Obviously a very strong revenue quarter coming up some short-term expense. I just wonder if you could tell us more about your thoughts on Yoigo and whether the goal to break even by the end of the fourth quarter is missing an opportunity to significantly build the business in these market conditions or should be favorable for its proposition.</p>
          <p>Secondly, I wanted just to ask a little bit about the potential of a corporate domestic recovery in the Nordic markets. What signs you are seeing of that obviously we had some signs, I think in the Swedish Mobile business, but what could we look forward to if we were to see a reasonable economic recovery in your fixed business in the Nordic markets? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I believe that if you manage a company, I think you need to stay your course. You can not shift course every quarter or every half year because the 30,000 people will not follow you. I have stated very clearly, how I feel about Yoigo and I will not &#x2013; I haven't changed my mind. I'm very pleased with the performance of Yoigo. I'm very pleased that as you said we had significant growth in the first quarter that did bring some additional cost. But, we are shifting from prepaid to postpaid, and this is a very good sign for this operation. And we are still committed to deliver an EBITDA positive result in the fourth quarter and thereafter I don't want to see any red numbers. So it's not only one quarter because one quarter anybody can fix.</p>
          <p>Strategically, I have as I said, not changed my mind.</p>
          <p>What was the second question, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The corporate segment in --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The corporate segment, <mark type="inaudible" /> you want to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that we have seen some positive signs in the Swedish especially with the Mobility and I think that the business started to recover really. If you look at the lot of Swedish multinationals they have taken out an enormous amount of costs. And they now need to start to sort of take care of the business or to go for growth as well. And I think that will have a positive impact on us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can see it in the funnel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can see that in the funnel definitely in Sweden, not so much in Finland and I am more skeptical about both Denmark and <mark type="inaudible" /> They might come a bit later but I think the positive signs we see are actually here in Sweden and they are very encouraging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Tim. Let's take one more question from the call before moving back to the floor. Operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Damien Maltarp from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much. I've got two questions. Firstly, the Swedish regulators seem to be proposing your allowed rate of return on fiber should be equivalent to that on copper, I'll be interested in your thoughts on whether that is appropriate?</p>
          <p>And secondly just on Eurasia, there seemed to be some commentaries that you might be interested in fixed line operations in those markets, maybe you can just expand on the strategy there, if it does make sense to move into fixed. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the last one then. There is no difference in my view on Eurasia then to for instance our home markets. I believe the fixed network will be important in those markets too. The question is what sort of fixed network is available, and quite often it's a bad quality and so on.</p>
          <p>We are actually having discussions when if we can build and we cannot do that in every country, but in some country we can build the backhaul for the mobile as fiber. Could we split off from that backhaul and provide fixed services? That's an interesting idea. I think if we get that opportunity it's a question of regulation etcetera, I think we will be generally interested to have that dialog, because we do believe that the fixed network is important. And the first question was --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was regarding regulation on --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fiber.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know. There are two issues in regulation if you talk Sweden, when it comes to fiber. The first issue is that the regulator would like us to open up our fiber for other users. Actually, the industry is changing somewhat. You could think of the industry in three layers, you could think of the Scanova layer, the communication operator layer, and the service provider layer. And if we talk about opening up our networks for service providers, I think that's absolutely something we should do. The more traffic we have in our network, the better off we are.</p>
          <p>Although I would suggest that if we open up for others, then others should open up for us if you would like to. So that's for me a non-issue. The issue is the one you talked about and that's the return on investment. We need to be assured that we have a reasonable return on investment. And I don't want to start negotiating that point, whether it's the return on copper should be equal to fiber. I'm just repeating that if we're going to invest, I don't know what the number's going to be over a couple of years. But let's say more, at least more than SEK 10 billion. If our shareholders going to invest more than 10 billion in fiber in Sweden over a number of years, then they are demanding from the Board, and the Board from the management that they feel reasonably secure that we will get a reasonable return on that investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's go back to the floor and we have a question from Lena</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lena &#xD6;sterberg, Carnegie. Two questions if I may. First of all to return to the wholesale side, I was wondering &#x2013; you said that you had significant negative FX effects, if you can say something about the currency split of sales in wholesale, I know it's a bit of a black box, but maybe some sort of rough guidance?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is on your cost cutting going forward, could you maybe just say some of which areas you're looking into, which regions and what part of the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the last one. This is a very important question, not only for the results, but for the culture. I'm saying we are on a journey. We're trying to change this company fundamentally. And the 2008 and '09 program, where we took out 2900 people. It was finished last year and it was very successful compared to historical performance, we have never been able to reduce cost in this company. Well, we talked about it all along, but now we did.</p>
          <p>We decided in the group management end of last year that we do not want to have another big top down program, because we were not sure that will be a good thing for the company. However, we said very clearly to everybody in this company. Now you have to manage your cost. The cost for the company got to be flat and the costs are going to go up in Eurasia; that means it has to come down somewhere else. And we are following this very carefully now, because the power of TeliaSonera, if we can get the 200 top managers to own this issue about cost, and cost is not only for me going down, it's also go down here and invest that money here.</p>
          <p>I'll give you an example. Our customer service, Broadband Sweden is not performing for six months. We have answering times that are totally unacceptable to me. And I won't &#x2013; I think we need to spend some more money on it. But then the manager got to find out that money somewhere else. And if you have a company of 30,000 people and that kind of system works then you have a very strong company. And it's going to be very telling these four quarters in this year how good these 200 people are in managing costs. Because if the only way to manage cost in this company is with him and me, or the group management, that's not a good method.</p>
          <p>So, I think we will, I expect people to look for cost reductions everywhere. Do we really have to do this? Do we really have to do that? Do we really have to have consultants to this amount in this company, etcetera, etcetera, etcetera. We saw in the numbers that Per-Arne showed you that in the first quarter, we increased marketing. I'm very happy about that, because we took down marketing quite a bit last year. Because I want to increase CAPEX, I want to increase marketing, I want to gain market share, I want to grow, but I don't want to &#x2013; we don't have any free money. So you should follow the cost number these four quarters, going to be very exciting &#x2013; more exciting than watching paint dry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I take the slightly more detailed question on the FX in wholesale and we'll see if we can disclose a bit more information about that going forward, but what I can say today is about 60% is in Swedish kronor, about 20% is in euro, and the remaining is split between dollars and British pound.</p>
          <p>There you go. And we take the next question from Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Michael Andersson, Evli Bank. Margins keeps going up and CAPEX is &#x2013; keeps going down and you still &#x2013; you firmly say that we'll keep the 15% kind of target, at the same time it doesn't seem like you sound very eager &#x2013; we've talked about Broadband expansion in Sweden and so on, but still is there any regions or businesses now that you are feeling &#x2013; starting to feel kind of strained, because you reiterated your target, but it's not like you are running out today fixing things. So I don't -- in sum because this trend has been ongoing for quite sometime now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is a bit of a schizophrenic subject. I believe and I said that, I think there is a degree of automation in CAPEX decisions. I think it's an issue of culture. And I think what we have done &#x2013; what we've been able to do is to raise the focus on, is it really necessary?</p>
          <p>I made that joke, it's now nine months ago, so &#x2013; but I have to repeat it, because it tells you something about the culture. So somebody told me in Broadband Sweden that there was an request for investing in replacing 430 poles up in the north of Sweden because the old one were rotten. And the only problem was that the person who made the request didn't think, because you know how many customers we had on those poles? One, in the end of 430 poles, we had one customer Telia boss (37.30). I'm pretty sure that investment would have passed couple of years ago, obviously doesn't pass now.</p>
          <p>So, that's one side of it. We are expanding capacity and coverage in our mobile network in Denmark and in Finland, that's long overdue. I think we should have done that a year earlier actually in hindsight.</p>
          <p>We were careful in the first quarter in Eurasia. The big expansions are in Uzbekistan and in Nepal. And obviously we're going to rollout the 4G. The 4G rollout in the first quarter was very small. The rollout will be 25 cities in Sweden this year. It means all 25 will have to be delivered in the part in the second and mostly in the second half of the year and four cities in Norway. So I think we are clearly back-end loaded. But, I did say the target is still to be shy of 15, whether we get there or not is another issue.</p>
          <p>Rolling out the fiber is complicated. This is not a rollout like the copper. We are very selective. We don't even talk about parts of a city. We talk about blocks. Where do we roll out fiber and how do we roll out fiber is fairly complicated. And we have said to Malin and to Anders Gylder, don't rush to spend the money. The money will be there in January also, if you are late, no problem. But do it right now because it's such a big investment and it's so important that we do this right. So, I feel pretty good. I feel pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Jan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Jan Dworsky from Handelsbanken. Just coming back to the top line, I think some months ago or some quarters ago there was this fear that it's a bit late cyclical and higher unemployment will sort of hit you later in the year. Do you feel confident that it won't happen and that was the fear that didn't materialize?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I probably lean towards that conclusion today, unless we get a double dip of course, that changes the whole game. But, I don't see signs that are negative for the growth. That's why I said this morning that, of course I feel more comfortable now with having been able to forecast somewhat higher net sales than last year after the first quarter with 2.5%, of course I feel much more comfortable. Let's see the second quarter and then we'll have to think whether we'll say something more positive than somewhat. But, no, I think it looks good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well now, if I may add, I mean, I think you have to be a bit more specific as well because Sweden is sort of one place where we have a very strong sort of economic environment, but then if you go to Baltics, something differently where we do not really see a turnaround come here and it might be a bit later in the Nordic area. So I think you have to be a bit more specific as well when we look at the different countries when you ask that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then when it comes to cost and the head count continues to come down, particularly in the Nordic area, is &#x2013; are we at the end of that or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's coming down because the way we report it, we only report when they actually physically leave, all right, till they leave they are on our head count. So the reductions are really now a result of decisions taken earlier. The cost will be flat, we have said, that means there is certainly not room to increase the number of employees. I expect and I really hope that it will be flat, which means that the number of employees will not change up or down significantly. And I think this is more important from a cultural aspect than actually from the bottom-line aspect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just an additional question on fiber, is &#x2013; sort of a conclusion to the discussions with the regulator, does that have any impact at all on how much you would spend this year on fiber?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it could, if we would get a &#x2013; if we would conclude or at least be afraid that it looks like we are not going to get some sort of reasonable return, then we will stop the investment. That's for sure. I hope that we can conclude that discussion before the mid-year. And I hope &#x2013; certainly hope for our sake but also for the country's sake that we will get a reasonable environment to invest, let's say SEK 10 billion and I would expect it to go that way. But, you never know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We go back to the conference call where we have a couple of outstanding questions. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. David Wright from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, it's David here. A couple of questions please. Could I just, and I apologize if I have missed some previous comments, but could I just confirm what you meant when you said you haven't changed your mind strategically on Yoigo, did that mean this is still an asset that doesn't fit within the strategy of the group and that is an asset for sale?</p>
          <p>And then second of all, again you said you haven't changed your opinion on the Altimo agreement. When you first signed that agreement, did you expect the kind of shareholder objection from MegaFon that you currently have? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on Yoigo, yeah I haven't changed my mind. I would prefer to invest that kind of money elsewhere in other markets, maybe in Eurasia or speed up fiber in Sweden or whatever. So, that's my opinion. It's not an urgent issue and certainly if we reach, which I said before, I expect we will reach the breakeven point in the fourth quarter; it's not an urgent issue. If somebody wants to buy it, they have to pay a good price for it, because you cannot take away from the management in Yoigo that they have done a super job.</p>
          <p>If they come to a breakeven result with let's say 2.5, 3% market share by the end of this year then they have done it faster than most other people who tried, and that's worth something to me and to our shareholders. And so, I have no urgent need to get rid of a black hole, because there is not going to be a black hole by the end of this year. But strategically, I think the money can be invested more profitably for us elsewhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question on Altimo or the deal that we announced?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we had a discussion with what you call other shareholders in MegaFon that is Alisher Usmanov, I met him many times and we had a discussion with him. And the reason why we chose Fridman is of course very simple. Mr. Fridman and the Altimo Company are co-owners not only in MegaFon, but also in Turkcell. So by joining with Mr. Fridman we thought and still think that we'll be able to find the solution both for MegaFon and Turkcell.</p>
          <p>Of course, I realize Mr. Usmanov will be disappointed, which he has explained in different ways, several times. I &#x2013; ultimately I hope that Mr. Usmanov will actually join us in this adventure. I think it'd be beneficial for him and it will certainly be beneficial for us. We don't need him, but he would be an owner in a company that owns two operators &#x2013; MegaFon and Turkcell, I hope that would be &#x2013; should be very attractive to him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could just follow-up very, very quickly, if there was an approach from Svyazinvest to maybe run some kind of fixed and mobile operations in Russia, would that change your mind on the deal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very clear. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Quick answer, thank you David. We take another question from the call. Operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Boris Rathe from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;neral. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Ulrich Rathe at SocG&#xE9;n. Two questions please. One is in your &#x2013; in your, in the release it sounds as if you are saying in Q1, you have held back across the group not just in Eurasia, and I think during the conversation now you have already indicated that maybe in Swedish Fixed, future quarters will maybe see somewhat higher investments in terms of OPEX, I'm talking about sort of marketing investments, not CAPEX. Could you give us a sense of the geographic spread of where you are looking to maybe ramp-up your OPEX, your marketing spend, your market investments elsewhere? That would be my first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is a very short one, it's about the constant currency growth, you're highlighting constant currency growth very strongly in all your results, but of course inflation in some of those countries is actually quite high and that obviously devalues the currencies in a natural &#x2013; in a very natural way. So I'm just wondering, is this maybe not a false intent as to go for growth in potentially in countries with very high inflation, if you just look at the constant currency growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the OPEX. One of the challenges, and we've been touching upon this a couple of times in this conversation, one of the big challenges is to reallocate cost, not to add cost, but to reallocate cost. And we have three priorities in this company. The cost structure got to be competitive, the quality in networks and the customer service, a unique customer experience. That is the three priority of TeliaSonera, has been for a long time, will continue to be forever in my opinion.</p>
          <p>So how do I reallocate cost to those priorities from other sources of cost is I think the biggest challenge. So, yes, I expect us to step up in Eurasia in general terms because we are growing so much. So, Nepal, OPEX is going to go up, marketing in Nepal is going to go up probably in Uzbekistan too. As we implement fiber in Sweden or in Finland, I'm pretty sure marketing will go up for triple play.</p>
          <p>But we got to find that cost somewhere else because not necessarily is all these investment in OPEX on top of everything else. This is exactly the whole point I'm trying to make with the 200 managers, they have to manage the cost, because I cannot stand here and tell somebody in Broadband Sweden what cost should be saved and where he or she should spend it. That's their responsibility. What I'm saying, what Per-Arne and I'm saying is the cost for the group got to be flat. Now, please manage it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may then answer the second question about currency, why we emphasis this so much. I mean first of all if you remember the volatility has been very high when it comes to FX and last year when we &#x2013; in the reported figures, you could see that we had a growth, we think &#x2013; we thought it was very important to say that this is currency driven. In the same way we're doing it right now when the FX has turned in a different way. So I think that's the first statement. Secondly, if you look at the market as we're operating in Eurasia, I think that we're talking about growth rate of 40, 50% <mark type="inaudible" /> (49.52), I think that is what we are striving for, nothing else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ulrich. My colleague is indicating that there are two remaining questions on the call. Please, operator, the next one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Andrew Lee from Citi. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Just a couple of questions. Firstly on the Baltics, you said you haven't seen a turnaround yet, but Estonia is improving on an organic basis. And do you think we could see organic growth in the Estonian top lines at some point through the year? And at what point do you think you could see a turnaround in Lithuania and Latvia? Is this year too ambitious now for those two?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on management compensation, a bit more sensitive there, but you announced yesterday that salaries will be raised by 30% as a result of the board's decision at the AGM to remove the variable element. Could you give us a bit more color on this decision and do you think this will make it more difficult to incentivize your senior management team going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You start with the Baltics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll start with the Baltics. You're right. I mean Estonia is much better off than the other two countries and I visited here, it was a couple of weeks ago and also talked with some of the ministers. And I think they have done a great job when it comes to prepare themselves for the Euro-belt, and I think that they would probably join in half-year's time, if I understand this correctly. And that will of course help their internal market. And they have also created a much better stability in their own market situation, but whether that means they will come back to growth this year or next year, that's difficult to say.</p>
          <p>I think it's a completely different picture when you come to Latvia and Lithuania, they are much sort of deeper in recession still and that will take time. And especially Latvia will have a tough time talking with IMF and all these guys. I think that will take time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the compensation, I'm very pleased that we have been able to put this question into bed. We've had it open for a year and I've spent way too much time on this issue. I haven't changed my mind; I have been very clear. I -- and I think the whole group management &#x2013; I know the whole group management stands united on this. We believe in variable pay, provided the variable pay has a limit or a ceiling, is very well measured on criteria we agree on beforehand, all of that stuff we did that. You look in the last three years, we had record profit last year, and pay-out was 38.5 and the maximum was 50 and we got 38.5. I think that indicates that the criteria last year were good, so the board were &#x2013; are being capable of setting the right criterias.</p>
          <p>Now, I think it's unfortunate we'll lose this too. Do I think it's a disaster? No, I don't think it's a disaster, but I think it's unfortunate, and I hope that one day we can introduce both short-term and long-term incentive plans including the group management. It's a bit strange that the top ten people are the only ones who don't have a variable pay in this company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andrew. We have a last question on the conference call. Operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the last question comes from Mr. Maurice Patrick from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys; couple of questions, I think are quite important, not just for yourselves, but for the sector as a whole, which perhaps you could expand a bit more on what you said already. When you look at the mobile revenues in the Nordic area, you've seen an acceleration in growth and you've explained that generally been driven by mobile, broadband and smartphones. So, could you just expand a bit in terms of these drivers and talk about things such as, are you seeing ARPU falling for people who aren't taking those devices, what kind of uplift are you seeing and how far down the evolution of these products are we and how much more to go? And just on the capital expenditure side, a lot of people are very fearful that you will see higher CAPEX because of all this traffic and what steps are you putting in place, other than the LTE roll out, to manage that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the last question. I &#x2013; the first thing, we did was a year ago to put caps, flat fee with caps. Because if you have an absolute flat fee, you can eat as much as you like, that will not work when the growth is with this. The good news is that we believe that Moore's Law applies to the equipment. So we believe that we will basically get double capacity for the same cost every 18 or 24 months or whatever the time horizon is. And we can see cost for equipment coming down for the last couple of years quite dramatically. We will come back to this issue. I think we need to do a little bit more homework on it.</p>
          <p>I feel comfortable that we can handle the growth rate in traffic volume without having to spend in a significant amount of money extra in CAPEX. But it is vital that we manage the growth of the traffic volume in line with our ability for the same cost to grow the capacity of the network, that's sort of the challenge and it's a very interesting &#x2013; it's a very interesting exercise, again it's not boring at all. And I've seen this before, some of you might also have seen it in the memory capacity, in microprocessor capacity, in the '80s and the '90s exactly what happened. And I think we're seeing some similar development &#x2013; technology development in telecoms and if that is true then I think this would be a much less issue than most people fear. We are talking we will comeback little bit later on decision. Was there another question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You had a first question Maurice, if I'm right about ARPU on smartphone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Non-smartphone, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Non-smartphone, was that right, Maurice?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's just &#x2013; just to understand how about &#x2013; your overall revenues, of those you aren't taking the mobile data products, what's happening to that revenue stream and for those who are taking it, what's happening to that, I hope you'll understand what the penetration is and what the uplifts you are seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a bit of a difficult question. I think I refer you to the slide presentation that Lars has showed you, where you see the growth year-over-year where you can see that data is up by quite a lot and that is obviously smartphones and mobile broadband. The interesting thing in that growth I think is that voice is obviously up and that goes for all phones, not just the smartphones. So, I &#x2013; on your question, I'd say that it's at least not down for the people not taking the smartphone, slightly up would be my best guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think that we close it here. Thank you everyone for your questions and for you came and I'll see you back here in the summer. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>