<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1150879" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1560</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David Moneta, Vice President of Investor Relations and Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Harold N. Kvisle, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Gregory A. Lohnes, Executive Vice-President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">David Moneta, Vice President, Investor Relations and Communications</participant>
      <participant id="5">Linda Ezergailis</participant>
      <participant id="6">Alexander Pourbaix</participant>
      <participant id="7">Glenn Menuz</participant>
      <participant id="8">Bob Hastings</participant>
      <participant id="9">Russell Girling</participant>
      <participant id="10">Matthew Akman</participant>
      <participant id="11">Robert Kwan</participant>
      <participant id="12">Gregory Lohnes</participant>
      <participant id="13">David Moneta</participant>
      <participant id="14">Andrew Kuske</participant>
      <participant id="15">Harold Kvisle</participant>
      <participant id="16">Daniel Shteyn</participant>
      <participant id="17">Faisel Khan</participant>
      <participant id="18">Sam Kanes</participant>
      <participant id="19">Mark Caruso</participant>
      <participant id="20">Harry Mateer</participant>
      <participant id="21">Steven Paget</participant>
      <participant id="22">Ian McKinnon</participant>
      <participant id="23">Gordon Jaremko</participant>
      <participant id="24">Hyun Young Lee</participant>
      <participant id="25">Louis Shammy</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the TransCanada Corporation 2008 First Quarter Results Conference Call. I'd now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. David Moneta, Vice President of Investor Relations and Communications. Please go ahead, Mr. Moneta.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much and good afternoon everyone. I'd like to take the opportunity to welcome you today. And we are pleased to provide the investment community, the media and other interested parties with an opportunity to discuss our 2008 first quarter financial results and other general issues concerning TransCanada.</p>
          <p>With me today are Hal Kvisle, President and Chief Executive Officer; Greg Lohnes, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer; Russ Girling, President of Pipelines; Alex Pourbaix, President of Energy; and our Vice President and Controller, Glenn Menuz.</p>
          <p>Hal and Greg will begin today with some opening comments on our financial results and other general issues pertaining to TransCanada. Please note that a slide presentation will accompany their remarks. A copy of that presentation is available on our website at transcanada.com. It can be found in the Investor section under the heading Conference Calls &amp; Presentations.</p>
          <p>Following Hal and Greg's remarks, we will turn the call over to the conference coordinator for your questions. During the question-and-answer period, we will take questions from the investment community first, followed by the media. In order to provide everyone with an equal opportunity to participate, we ask that you limit yourself to two questions. If you have additional questions, please reenter the queue.</p>
          <p>Also, we ask that you focus your questions on our industry, our corporate strategy, recent developments and key elements of our financial performance. If you have detailed questions relating to some of our smaller operations for your detailed financial models, Myles, Terry and I would be pleased to discuss them with you following the call.</p>
          <p>Before Hal begins, I would like to remind you that our remarks today will include forward-looking statements that are subject to important risks and uncertainties. For more information on these risks and uncertainties, please see the reports filed by TransCanada with Canadian securities regulators and with the U.S. Securities Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>Finally, I'd also like to that during this presentation, we will refer to measures such as comparable earnings, comparable earnings per share and funds generated from operations. These measures do not have any standardized meaning prescribed by generally accepted accounting principles and are therefore considered to be non-GAAP measures. As a result, these measures are unlikely to be comparable to similar measures presented by other entities. These measures have been used to provide interested parties with additional information on the Company's operating performance, liquidity and its ability to generate funds to finance its operations.</p>
          <p>With that, I will now turn the call over to Hal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you David. Good afternoon everyone and thank you for joining us this afternoon. I will keep my remarks brief as many of you may have participated at the TransCanada Annual Meeting this morning either in person or via webcast. As David mentioned, our annual meeting webcast is now archived on the website at transcanada.com.</p>
          <p>At our annual meeting, I detailed our strong financial performance and shared the significant project milestones, we have achieved in our Pipeline and Energy businesses that have set the stage for continued goals and value creation in the years ahead. Our strategic focus remains clear as we pursue our goal to become the leading energy infrastructure company in North America.</p>
          <p>I will now take a few minutes to talk about first quarter financial highlights as well as three notable developments. And then I'll turn the call over to Chief Financial Officer Greg Lohnes, who will review our financial results for you in more detail.</p>
          <p>For the first quarter of 2006, TransCanada's net income was $449 million or $0.83 per share, compared to 265 million or $0.52 per share in the first quarter of 2007. Net income included a number of one-time items, including $152 million from Calpine bankruptcy settlements.</p>
          <p>Comparable earnings were $326 million, $0.60 per share for the first quarter of 2008, versus $250 million or $0.49 per share in the first quarter of last year, an increase of approximately 22% on a per share basis. Funds generated from operations in the first quarter of 2008 were 58% higher at $922 million compared with $582 million for the same period last year.</p>
          <p>TransCanada's Board of Directors declared a quarterly dividend of $0.36 per share for the quarter ending June 30, 2008 on the outstanding common shares. Shareholders that re-invest their dividends in additional common shares of the company through our dividend reinvestment and share purchase plan will continue to receive common shares from treasury at of 2% discount to the average market price.</p>
          <p>I will now expand on three recent developments from the first quarter. Firstly, Keystone. The U.S. 5.2 billion Keystone Oil Pipeline project achieved a major milestone after receiving the U.S. Department of State Presidential Permit authorizing construction, maintenance, and operations for the facility at the U.S. / Canada border, to transport a growing supply of Canadian crude oil to key markets in the U.S. Midwest.</p>
          <p>Actual field construction will commence in the next few months and we will have Keystone up in the running by the end of the 2009 construction seasons, establishing TransCanada has a major player in the oil pipeline business.</p>
          <p>We also continued to explore options to transport a growing supply of Canadian crude oil to the U.S. Gulf Coast refining market and we have made excellent progress in negotiations with both Alberta producers' and Gulf Coast refiners on a major expansion of the Keystone system.</p>
          <p>We are proposing a 36 inch diameter pipeline running from Alberta to Northern Nebraska and then south to the Gulf Coast, towards the east of Houston. The proposed routing is shown as the dotted line on the map. This would not be a modest expansion of Keystone. It would in fact be a larger project than the original Keystone. More importantly, it would provide a direct pipeline connection from Alberta to the largest of crude oil refining centre in the world, the U.S. Gulf Coast.</p>
          <p>Turing now to Ravenswood. In March 2008, we announced an agreement to acquire the 2,480 megawatt Ravenswood generating facility in New York City for $2.8 billion. This acquisition is subject to various states and federal government approvals which are expect in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>This acquisition is strong fit with TransCanada's strategy to grow our power business in markets where our assets, expertise and financial strength enable us to be a strong competitor and a reliable energy provider. The Ravenswood facility is a high quality asset that is an excellent fit which TransCanada's existing generating assets and power marketing capabilities in the U.S. Northeast, which includes the Ocean State power complex, a 560 megawatt gas-fired combined cycle power plant in Rhode Island; TransCanada Hydro, 567 megawatts of hydroelectric generation on the Connecticut and Deerfield rivers in New England; a significant power marketing and commercial office in Westborough, Massachusetts' and The Kibby Wind Power Project, a proposed 132 megawatt wind energy project in western Maine.</p>
          <p>The New York City power market is a capacity market that offers excellent long term, economic fundamentals for Ravenswood and the Ravenswood facility has a highly favorable competitive position in that New York City market. Ravenswood is an absolutely critical asset to the New York City power market and represents nearly 25% of installed capacity. We believe additional generation will be required in the region and Ravenswood also has significant potential for re-powering and expansion investment opportunities in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>We are very pleased that we've acquired 2,480 megawatts of combined base-load and peaking capacity in this critical market at a capital cost of $1,130 per kilowatt of capacity. Estimates by numerous industry consultants placed the capital cost of new base-load generations in New York City at more than 2000 per kilowatt for base-loads and the capital cost of new peaking generation at more than $1500 per kilowatt in the New York City marketplace.</p>
          <p>In summary, Ravenswood represents excellent long-term value for our shareholders. Its strategic location right in the attractive New York City market along with its revenue diversity coming from energy, capacity, and ancillary services makes Ravenswood a great addition to TransCanada's growing North American power generation portfolio.</p>
          <p>And now Bruce, last week we provided an update on the comprehensive review of cost for the Bruce A units 1 and 2 Restart Project. The review, which was completed by Bruce Power, its owners and independent experts with significant experience in energy infrastructure megaprojects, included the thorough assessment of costs incurred to date together with a complete review of the remaining work and the costs of that remaining work.</p>
          <p>The project has generally gone well. Most phases of the rebuild have been on time and within budget. Our reactor rebuild contractor, Atomic Energy of Canada Limited, did experience difficulty and delay in the reactor rebuild work, and that has caused the entire project to suffer a certain amount of delay and some extra costs. I'm pleased today to report that AECL now resolved those difficulties and the pace of the reactor rebuild work has picked up considerably. However, due to the delays already occurred, we will not achieve Bruce's original target price of 2.75 billion nor will we earn the stretch target internal rate of return of 13.5% after tax on total capital employed.</p>
          <p>We will however earn an excellent return ranging from 11.5 to 9.5%, depending on the final cost outcome. The Bruce team, with considerable help from TransCanada, negotiated a very sound agreement with the Ontario Power Authority. That agreement has assured us of an adequate return, even in the event of delays and cost overruns. We would not have proceeded with the Bruce refurbishment without that sort of cost and risk sharing arrangement. The wisdom of that agreement should now be evident. TransCanada is comfortable that we will achieve an excellent project outcome and a strong financial return from the Bruce A1, A2 refurbishment project.</p>
          <p>In summary, it is opportunities such as these and the many others, I highlighted earlier today at our annual meeting of shareholders that will continue to build long-term value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Greg Lohnes, who will provide additional details on our first quarter financial results. Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Hal, and good afternoon everyone. As Hal mentioned, earlier today, we released our first quarter results. Net income for the first quarter was $449 million or $0.83 per share compared to $265 million or $0.52 per share for the same period last year. First quarter 2008 net income included above the focused impact of both the Calpine bankruptcy settlement and a GTN lawsuit settlement, offset by a write-down of Broadwater LNG project cost and fair value adjustments of Natural Gas Storage inventory and service contract.</p>
          <p>First quarter 2007 net income included positive income tax reassessments and adjustments of $15 million. Excluding these items, comparable earnings were $326 million or $0.60 per share in the first quarter 2008 compared to $250 million or $0.49 per share for the same period last year, an increase of approximately 22% on a per share basis.</p>
          <p>The quarter-over-quarter increase is due to increased contributions from both the Pipelines and Energy business. I will briefly review the first quarter results for each of our segments beginning with Pipelines.</p>
          <p>The Pipelines business generated comparable earnings of $199 million during the first quarter, an increase of $44 million over the same period in 2007. The increase was primarily due to a full quarter of earnings from ANR and higher earnings from the Canadian Mainline and GTN.</p>
          <p>TransCanada completed the acquisition of ANR on February 22nd, 2007 and included net earnings from that date. The Canadian Mainline's net income increase was primarily related to the higher deemed common equity ratio and certain performance-based incentive arrangements.</p>
          <p>GTN's comparable earnings for the first quarter increased primarily due to the positive impacts of a rate case settlement in January 2008 and lower OM&amp;A expenses.</p>
          <p>Now some comments on Energy. The Energy segment includes our power and unregulated natural gas storage operations as well as our business development initiatives in liquefied natural gas.</p>
          <p>Energy generated comparable earnings of $149 million in the first quarter 2008 compared to $106 million in the same period last year. The increase was due to higher contributions from Western Power, Eastern Power, Bruce Power and Natural Gas Storage. These increases were partially offset by higher general administrative and support costs.</p>
          <p>Westerns Power's operating income was $78 million in the first quarter compared to $73 million last year. The $5 million increase was primarily due to increased margins from the Alberta power purchase arrangements resulting from higher overall realized power prices.</p>
          <p>Eastern Power's operating income in the first quarter was $85 million, an increase of $18 million compared to the first quarter last year. The increase was primarily due to the impact of increased generation from the TC Hydro facilities in combination with higher realized power pool prices in New England. Also contributing to the increase, were increased sales volumes to wholesale, commercial and industrial substance.</p>
          <p>Finally in power, Bruce Power contributed $37 million of operating income in the first quarter compared to $29 million last year. The $8 million increase was primarily due to higher outlook and higher realized prices at Bruce A. The Bruce A prices were slightly higher in the first quarter 2008 compared to the same period in 2007 due to the April 1, 2007 inflation adjustment for the contracted fixed price. All of the output from Bruce A in the first quarter 2008 was sold at a fixed price of $59.69 per megawatt hour before recovery of fuel costs from the Ontario Power Authority compared to $58.63 per megawatt hour for the first quarter 2007. Effective April 1, 2008, the Bruce A fixed price is $63 per megawatt hour.</p>
          <p>Pursuant to the 2007 amendment to the contract with the Ontario Power Authority, the fixed price for output from Bruce A increased by $2.11 per megawatt hour subject to inflation adjustments from October 31, 2005. Looking forward, the overall plant availability percentage in 2008, was expected to be in the low 80s for the two Bruce A operating units and in the low 90s for the four Bruce B units.</p>
          <p>As Hal stated, the capital costs of the Bruce A restart and refurbishment of Units 1 and 2 is expected to total approximately 3.1 to $3.4 billion with TransCanada's share being approximately 1.55 to $1.7 billion. As of march 31, 2008, Bruce A has incurred capital cost of $2 billion on the restart and refurbishment project.</p>
          <p>Finally, in the Energy segment, Natural Gas Storage's operating income of $48 million in the first quarter increased $18 million compared to the same period last year. The increase was primarily due to incremental income earned from the start up of the Edson facility, which was fully operational in first quarter 2008, but only in the commissioning phase in the first quarter 2007. Partially offsetting the increase in earnings from the Edson facility was a decrease in earnings from the CrossAlta facility as a result of lower realized seasonal natural gas price spread in the first quarter of 2008 compared to the same period last year.</p>
          <p>Turing now to Corporate, net expenses from Corporate in the first quarter 2008 were $22 million compared to net income of $4 million in the same period last year. Excluding favorable income tax adjustments in the first quarter of 2007, Corporate's comparable expenses were $22 million compared to $11 million in the first quarter last year. Higher financing charges primarily as a result of financing the ANR and Great Lakes acquisitions and losses on derivatives used to manage the company's exposure to foreign exchange great fluctuations were the primary reasons for the increase in comparable expenses.</p>
          <p>Turning to the cash flows base, funds generated from operations were $922 million in the first quarter, an increase $340 million or 58% when compared to the same period in 2007. This increase was primarily due to gains from the Calpine bankruptcy settlements and higher earnings. Capital expenditures in the first quarter were approximately $460 million and related primarily to the ongoing development of greenfield projects such as the Bruce A Restart, Portland's Energy Centre, Halton Hills and Cartier Wind, as well as an expansion of the Alberta System and construction of the Keystone Oil Pipeline.</p>
          <p>Finally, our financial position remains strong. At the end of March, our balance sheet consisted of 53% debt, which included our proportion of share of joint venture debt, 4% junior subordinated notes, 1% preferred shares and 42% common equity. In the first quarter 2008, TransCanada issued common shares from Treasury under its dividend reinvestment and share purchase plans totaling $54 million. TransCanada PipeLines Limited 'A' credit rating is valuable to us. We intend to finance both acquisitions and major projects in a manner that maintains our 'A' credit rating.</p>
          <p>As we highlighted previously, we will finance the Ravenswood acquisition by issuing new debt and equity in a manner that allows us to maintain our current balance sheet capitalization structure of approximately 60% debt and preferred and 40% common equity. TransCanada's existing free cash flow and debt capacity is sufficient to meet the committed $3 billion annual greenfield spending profile we have in place for 2008 and 2009. As we grow our assets, we also grow our operating cash flows and our debt capacity.</p>
          <p>As our greenfield project portfolio grows beyond the current $3 billion per year, we have a number of options to fund our capital programs including asset monetizations. We have divested a number of blue-chip mature gas pipelines to our TC PipeLines, LP and that remains a very attractive option for both TransCanada and the LP. In this way, we can maximize the strategic and operational advantages of our pipeline portfolio while continuing to grow our asset base for the long-term benefit of our shareholders.</p>
          <p>That concludes my prepared remarks. I will now turn the call back to David for the question-and-answer period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Greg. Just a reminder before I turn the call back over to the conference coordinator, we'll take questions from the financial community first, and once we have completed that, we'll then turn the call over to the media.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn it back to the conference coordinator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now take questions from the phone line. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question is from Linda Ezergailis from TD Newcrest. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's great to see that Edson's contributing so much in the quarter. But I guess, as you can appreciate, one of our challenges is visibility going forward. Can you just give us a sense of what your outlook is for your natural gas storage business for the balance of 2008 including any seasonality you might expect? And then how much in terms of contracting you've locked in for 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Linda you know, because you referenced there, there is a fair bit of seasonality in this business, particularly on the business that we are &#x2013; proprietary business, where we buy in, we inject our own gas, we &#x2013; for earnings purposes, we recognize those earnings only when the gas comes out. And obviously the gas is usually coming out during Q1 and Q4. So I think it's very fair to expect that just generally there will definitely be a bias in earnings and in Q1 and probably even more &#x2013; sorry, Q4 and even more particularly in Q1. That being said, just where basis went in the market gave us an opportunity to profitably accelerate the removal of gas that would have probably come up later in the year, otherwise. So, I think what I would say is generally a fair rule of thumb is that we're &#x2013; we probably experienced relatively close to around half of the contribution we would expect the get from the storage business in Q1 this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Half of the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what proportion in Q1 was your prop business versus your &#x2013; I guess fee for service business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to say it was probably &#x2013; Glenn, do you have that number in front of you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, from our storage business, our proprietary gas was obviously the majority of the storage business coming out of the Edson facility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think just to answer your question, we're about 87, 90% sold for '08 and we are around 60% and 35, 40% for the next two succeeding years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>60% for '09 and 35, 40 for 2010; is that calendar or gas season?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, calendar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. And in terms of my follow-up question, maybe we can move on to another part of your business. It's good to see that the government's option to elect to not to refurbish the fourth unit at Bruce A has expired. Now at what point would you expect that they might turn their attention to negotiating a refurbishment program for the B units?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's still a fair number of years left in the life of those units. That being said, I would think it's something that we'll probably begin discussions sometime in the next sort of three to four year range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would you expect to have some sort of an agreement structured similar to the A units?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we require agreements structured similar to the A units in terms of we're certainly not going to take any merchant risk and we would certainly expect to see similar provisions with respect to risk sharing on capital cost and so forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And what sort of probabilities would you assign us to not having those conversations or that sort of an outcome?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the fundamental attractiveness of the refurbishment of the B units is at any range of expected capital costs, the cost &#x2013; the price of power coming out of refurbished B units, in our view, will be very significantly below any of the other competitive supply options for Ontario, so we think that there's a &#x2013; we would be surprised if at some point in the relatively near future we are not engaging in those discussions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks so much, Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Karen &#x2013; Linda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Bob Hastings from Canaccord. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Just on the gas pipeline, you mentioned that there is some tolls increase and there's some volumes and decontracting. Shorter hauls. Can you sort of give us a little more color what's going on there and what's your &#x2013; what you looking forward going forward particularly with some of the other supply options that are coming out in coal, gas et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To start with that the first question in terms of what's happening on our mainline system with respect to tolls, year-over-year volumes were down probably in that sort of 10% kind of range. That in addition to sort of market changes, which are pushing GAAP in different directions. The demand in California's been stronger, and even in the Midwest on our Northern Border pipeline, so we've seen a reduction in flows on our mainline system and it's a cost of service tolling structure so the tolls have gone up. The math would probably take you to a number of it looks like about a 0.20 to $0.25 increase in the toll offset by a fuel decrease by 0.02 or $0.03, something like that. So, sort of in the $0.20 kind of range is the overall toll increase on the mainline.</p>
          <p>Going forward, obviously there is positive news around new discoveries, which can help offset that decline in volumes. And we'd expect sort of I guess our views is a leveling off of production in the Western Sedimentary Basin. The other factor that impacts exports is the in Alberta demand and as you know that continue to increase as well, decreasing volumes available for export. So, I guess this is something that we've &#x2013; is not unexpected for us. We expected the volumes to decline, the market will dictate, though, where those volumes actually go in the future. So, if &#x2013; the weather is cold in the northeast United States, it will continue to draw gas though our mainline pipeline system because on the margin, it's one of the only conduits that's left &#x2013; is still in that pipeline demand the gas demand on a peak day. On the other days the gas will flow down our other pipelines system into California and into the Pacific Northwest. So we monitor it on a continuous basis, but obviously those are some of the reasons that we've been very active in trying to attract new supply in Alberta, British Columbia into our pipeline system in order to offset declines elsewhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So pricing signals worked &#x2013; gas was low, we didn't see much exploration now it's starting to pick up a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now the other thing is, I wondered how that would play in with some of your other pipeline developments that you're pushing for or suggesting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's the key for producers is they want to get their gas to market and the most &#x2013; the largest increase in production in North America right now is the growth in production in the Rockies. And there's been periods over the last couple of years where the price has disconnected from NYMEX pricing, we've seen differentials of 2, 3 and $4 back to the Rockies. Obviously that's very difficult for the producers that are trying to continue drilling programs. So they want more capacity out of the Rockies and they would like to I guess take their gas to the closest liquid market that they can, making the least possible commitments that they can as well. We don't know exactly which direction the gas will want to move, which direction the market will want to move, so we've made several proposals to move the gas both east and west</p>
          <p>The eastern proposals &#x2013; the first one buys and goes from the Powder River Basin to our Northern Border Pipeline. So it can basically fill some of that capacity that's left open by declining export volume coming out of the Western Sedimentary Basins and then we have a pathfinder project which would go deeper into the Rockies Basins in Colorado and Wyoming and then further on to interconnect at Emerson which is the connection of the Canadian Mainline system to the Great Lake System, which would offer those producers several market options, both in Eastern Canada to Midwest, storage in the Midwest ,and ultimately moving the gas through our systems to the East Coast where the prices are the highest.</p>
          <p>So those are the drivers behind our new projects, and obviously if we can take the gas, the new gas, that's being developed in North America and put it into existing pipe, that the cheapest and lowest cost alternative for both us and the producers. And if we can make that work, obviously it's a good solution for declining volumes in the Western Sedimentary Basin as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the pipelines could become a growth area again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that over the last couple of years we've seen the investment opportunities in the pipeline business grow. As you know, we are probably sitting right now with about $5 billion of projects underway. And with projects like those Rockies projects and some of the potential expansion of Keystone, we see pretty healthy outlook for the next few years in terms of growth opportunities for the pipe business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I listened to the annual meeting, is there some magnitude or ballpark range you could give for the Keystone new project that you're looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that you can just sort of look at the distance on the map, how much pipe we need to build. I think if there'd be &#x2013; as Hal mentioned at the Annual Meeting, our current thinking is the design that would look at a 36-inch pipe as opposed to a 30-inch pipe. So, again a bit bigger pipe that is going to be a little more expensive and we got 20, 30% more distance to go. So, it would be a project that would be that sort of order of magnitude larger than the base Keystone project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Matthew Akman from Macquarie. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks very much, Russ. Just continuing on that theme on Keystone. Is it more economic now in your mind to build a brand new pipe than it is to try and extend the existing or first Keystone line and also how does it compete or stack up against other proposals that would simply extend off of the existing system as opposed to building new pipe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably the first one is the original Keystone design was 435,000 barrels a day to Patoka and Wood River. We ultimately thought that we could probably push about 600,000 barrels a day through that system with added horsepower through our Cushing open season, we eventually moved to a level of contracting around 500,000 barrels a day affirmed, and about 100,000 barrels a day of spot, that's pretty much filled that capacity and adding more horsepower if you will, doesn't really economically give us any more capacity. So the next logical answer is to twin the system in the most efficient way that we can. So, that's design that you saw on the slide that Hal walked through at the beginning of the conference call, you can see where it does connect with the existing system at a place called Steele City which is sort of that elbow going to Wood River and then further on to Cushing, we can share that piece of pipe. So as part of the design that would be one of the advantages that we can bring to the table, we can use a segment of the pipe which is similar.</p>
          <p>But that leads to your second question in terms of competitive advantage and how it stacks up to others is, when you are building new pipe, obviously at about $3 million a mile in the current marketplace, the shortest distance is going to give you the lowest capital cost and while we see that the competition is to adding to existing systems, there does require sort of new build right from the Gulf Coast, right through the system back to Alberta. And that's &#x2013; that distance is probably 20 or 30% longer than the distance that we've got proposed directly from <mark type="inaudible" />. The directest route we could take from <mark type="inaudible" /> through to the Gulf Coast. Taking up those synergies like I said from Steele City to Cushing but we try to go to the least distance possible and that's sort of, I guess, what I would say is our competitive advantage in the marketplace currently over existing systems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see, so your view is that I mean just to get real specific here is that Enbridge &#x2013; you're not competing just against the Enbridge, Exxon line that really is &#x2013; probably less than half the distance of the pipeline you are building, you are thinking you are competing against Enbridge building all the way back to Alberta?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I can't really speak to what their exact plans are, but in our conversations with the refining and producing community, that's the sense that we get is, is that they're mindful that they need to move in increments of probably 500,000 barrels a day, up to probably a number of 2 to 3 million barrels a day over the next, say four or five years and they recognize that ultimately you have to build new pipes right from A to B to move that incremental volume. So that's the sense that we have is, is the incumbent system has to go a lot further distance to get to &#x2013; get to the Gulf Coast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you are hopeful that you can get your hurdle returns right off the hop when you build that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, obviously we'd move, we'd try to secure sufficient barrels in an open season that would underpin base economics for that pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, Russ, I will move on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, our next question is from Robert Kwan from RBC Capital Markets, please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You have mentioned just on the Ravenswood's financing that you would like to finance it similar to the existing capital structure. You have also made the statement that you want to maintain the A credit rating. Can you comment on discussions you've had with the other ratings agencies, and S&amp;P is out of the way here, but what would you &#x2013; what have those discussions been and what would you do if they ask you for a higher equity component?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Well, we have ongoing discussions with the rating agencies obviously and we have been having a lot of discussions with them around Ravenswood and significant work is being done by the rating agencies to understand Ravenswood and understand the capacity market and all the factors that have implications to that. I think we are comfortable that the proposal we have to maintain our capital structure is sufficient to maintain our A credit rating. And I would say overall we're very pleased with S&amp;P and their ability to reaffirm our ratings and their confidence in management and in our past track record to maintain our rating and to do what we said we would do and to issue the necessary equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Greg, but if the other agencies ask you to put more equity in kind of what &#x2013; what wins the day here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ultimately, we will do what is necessary to maintain our credit rating. We do have other options other than common equity as you are aware that get us equity treatment. We have options as you saw us do last year in the hybrid market, which got us 50% equity treatment or the preferred share market in Canada is open to us. That market has mostly been a bank market recently and there is certainly demand for industrial issuers to step in. So, there are a number of options, but I would say that we are committed to the A credit rating; and as we've said many times, we will do what's necessary to maintain it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just last here, do you expect a decision from the other ratings agencies prior to your equity issue, similar to what &#x2013; to the movement of S&amp;P?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's possible, and we would certainly hope that that's the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks, Greg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Andrew Kuske from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon. If we could just get a little bit better sense on directionally where you want your power business to be, because if we think about the Ravenswood deal, there is some logic on the Northeast where you've already had exposure, but when we look at potentially projects in Arizona and some of the past initiatives that you've tried in the Pac Northwest, I am just curious as to where you look for your focus to be in the near-term and then over say a three to five year timeframe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Andrew, it's Hal. I will start and then I will let Alex add to it. First, I'd say, we like to look for markets that have attractive market fundamentals. In other words, where we can either acquire things or build things under some kind of an economic model that makes sense. And there isn't just one economic model, we see many different ones. The energy-only markets of Alberta are much different than the energy and capacity markets of New York and New England. And I would describe Ontario as the ultimate capacity market, where they just pay you for capacity and we don't take any energy cost or revenue exposure at all on projects like Portland and Halton Hills.</p>
          <p>So, first of all, we've screened markets by looking for good supply demand fundamentals, and there are some markets in North America, where the supply demand fundamentals aren't very good. There's other markets, where perhaps state controlled entities control the market and there is no reasonable opportunity for a corporate player to enter. And there is other markets, where the preponderance of very low cost coal-fired generation is so overwhelming that even in a greenhouse gas era, we don't think there will be a lot of opportunity for a new entrant. So, if we find us a market that's got attractive supply demand fundamentals, then we ask the question and what competitive advantage might we have in that market. If it's a market that's got huge barriers to entry, we'll go somewhere else. If it's got a lot of other players that one way or another constitute, I guess a barrier to entry, then we'd probably pass on that market.</p>
          <p>The southwest U.S. is very attractive to us fundamentally. We are very, very cautious. I think you'll see us continue to be very cautious on California given some of the history there, but those markets that are near California are attractive to us, and certainly the Nevada and Arizona markets are ones where we think we could build a substantial business over time.</p>
          <p>I would sort of describe the size of our current position in Alberta as indicative of the size or position that we would like to have in the market. If we are unable to get our &#x2013; an asset base that's worth several billion dollars in any particular market, it's not going to be very appealing to us. Alex, do you have anything to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that covered it quite well. I guess the only other comment I would say is that as you've seen &#x2013; we have really focused over the last several years on &#x2013; we basically describe them as two markets, although I appreciate the eastern business, the Central Canada, Quebec, North Eastern U.S. businesses; obviously there is a number of markets, but we certainly think we've been consistent in that market. And one of the issues with Alberta, we obviously have a very significant position in Alberta. And I would argue that absent significant growth of inter-tie connection with the Northwest U.S. markets, it's hard to see us really significantly increase our percentage ownership in that market over the next year. So, we have been, as you mentioned and as Hal referred to, we've been focusing for several years on the U.S. Southwest and particularly excluding California, but really being focused on Arizona and Nevada. And we really like the fundamentals of that market and we certainly wouldn't consider our foray with Coolidge as the end of our aspirations there. We think there is an opportunity to build quite a significant business over a number of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just when you look at markets in general, do you have a preference, an inclination towards really a capacity-driven market on really a rate based type concept or do you really want to have more pure merchant exposure in markets that have favorable supply demand content?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly from our perspective on what I would call the new build side of the business, the greenfield side of the business, the vast majority of that business has obviously been pursued under a sort of tolling TPA type arrangement, and in fact as you would know the vast majority of our capital expenditures in power over the last several years have been in that kind of business. But we will always keep our eyes open for merchant opportunities, where we think those assets have a very strategic bent to them, and I think an example of that would be the coal PPAs in Alberta, the hydro in New England. And we obviously feel that &#x2013; that way about Ravenswood, and certainly once we get those assets in our portfolio, we &#x2013; and even if they are merchants we usually go down a path quite quickly putting some revenue stability around those assets by a portfolio of off-take agreements, and we will continue to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Daniel Shteyn from Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes; hello everyone. I guess I would like to ask a follow-up question with regards to the route of the Keystone future expansion, future opportunity. I guess what I don't understand is, why were you not able to take advantage of the existing Keystone projects or rights of way even should you wish to have laid a new pipe as opposed to simply extending and expanding the existing system?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We definitely could have done that in all of the existing routes. So, one advantage is being in the right of way before, but you still have to go through the permitting process, it really is one of efficiency is one of our largest cost of constructing these pipelines is the steel in the pipe itself and per mile of construction. As I mentioned, we are looking at about $3 million a mile currently. So, if we can shave off 100 miles by going the direct route, that's $300 million. Those kinds of efficiencies more than offset the synergies you get by being in the same right of way. So, it does increase our workload in terms of gaining right of way, but if you look at the &#x2013; sort of the direction of that line, we will try to stay away from areas where right of way will be difficult. And that line has gone there is really just a straight line, but it obviously will have wiggles in it, as we will move around sensitive areas. But the real driver is to be competitive, we need to have the lowest possible cost that we can and that is the most &#x2013; having the most direct route we possibly can have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel, it's Hal. I would add to that, that if you look at the maps, the logical route from Alberta to Houston is something like the expansion route that we are proposing. The route that we followed with the original Keystone was a very unusual route and was only followed, because we have the ability to convert that gas pipeline to get from Alberta to Winnipeg at a very, very low cost. Now we'd be quite interested if the possibility came up in the future of converting another line along that same route. I would point out that we have two 34-inch lines there; one, which we are converting and one which remains. And in addition to those two 34s, we've got other five other pipelines that are larger diameters that are probably more than adequate to carry the amount of gas that we have to move from Alberta to Winnipeg on the main line.</p>
          <p>So we do have optionality there for the future, but it was our assessment that given the current demand for oil transport service from Alberta to the Gulf Coast, we could not realistically hope to get that other 34-inch line converted in time to meet the market demand. So rather than see that market demand go by, we came up with a new build alternative, and as Russ said, if you can save $300 million for example by adopting the most direct possible route, that's to the benefit of both TransCanada, and also to our shippers in the form of lower tolls. So, that's the logic that we have followed in selecting this route. The last comment I think is, many people have asked me why we don't just move the Prudhoe Bay gas over to a new VIC on the gas side and send it down the same pipeline? And the reality is, these pipelines are designed to run very close to full capacity. That's the way you make them as economic as possible, and just using the Northern Gas as an analogy, you couldn't run all that gas down one pipeline, you'd need two in any event and that of course the same thing on Keystone. There is no realistic way of moving more than 590,000 barrels a day through Keystone Phase I, anything beyond that should end up putting new pipe in the ground anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well. Conversion of existing pipe was actually my follow-up question, so thank you for answering that and reading my mind in advance. I guess for &#x2013; my follow-up question, I would like to talk quickly about the Alberta power market. Now the Alberta emission intensity rules are now reality; and I was I actually interested to see that you managed to squeeze out margin expansion on your power sales in Alberta, presuming &#x2013; so that presumably implies that you have been able to pass through the payments that you must now make on TransAlta, PPAs that you hold into &#x2013; in the form of higher market prices. So, is that &#x2013; is your expectation essentially going forward in the near term and in the long-term that you will be that higher power prices in the market will reflect the higher cost that your now faced with on those PPAs due to both provincial and federal emission intensity limits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think obviously, we've seen prices expand in Alberta a little bit. I think there is probably some debate as to how much of that is market fundamentals, of much of it is passing through of CO2 cost. I think what I would say, our general view on that is that particularly with our coal entitlements, we definitely are pursuing a strategy, and we believe the other coal owners are pursuing a similar strategy of passing these costs through dollar-for-dollar at times when coal is on the margin in Alberta, which is &#x2013; and in those periods, when coal isn't on the margins, the gas producers will be passing through their CO2 costs, but obviously on a per megawatt hour basis, they obviously are incurring less cost. So, our view has always been that at a minimum, we are going to collect a relatively significant amount of that cost back in Alberta, and we would expect that to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Faisel Khan from Citigroup. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On &#x2013; I think in your prepared remarks toward the end, you mentioned the possibility of being able to drop additional pipeline assets down into your MLP. Could that be used as a source of equity for your acquisition of Ravenswood?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think it's been used as a source of equity going forward, but could take some time to accomplish those transactions. So, our current intention is to finance Ravenswood with new equity as we have indicated. Going forward though, in funding our greenfield portfolio, we do not intend to issue additional equity. What we intend to do is focus on our portfolio optimization and that is around potentially dropping down assets, with include partnering uncertain assets or outright sales on certain assets for that mature portfolio where we think there is high value.</p>
          <p>On the &#x2013; from an MLP perspective, we do have a vehicle there, and we would look at our asset portfolio, we need to look at potential debt transactions as we move assets into that vehicle over time, similar to the way we use our DRIP program to fund whether our longer-dated capital spend programs for some of these large greenfield projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On your Eastern Power, Brazil, the uptick most of it in a way I understand &#x2013; a lot of that came from DC Hydro and higher realized power prices. Can you give us a little bit more detail on how much incremental generation; you were able to produce above kind of your plan at DC Hydro and the sustainability of that going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have right in front of me. Glenn, do you have that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say on a year-over-year basis, the increased volumes and prices from the DC Hydro assets, probably in the range of a couple of cents per share and then as far as whether this will continue going forward I'll leave that with Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think obviously Q2, I think it would be fair to presume that the eastern business is going to have a pretty robust quarter. There is a very significantly amount of water trapped behind those dams in the form of snow that it's starting to melt. So, I would expect you to see that. We've also seen relatively significant run up in power prices in the region over the last little while. We're in some cases probably in the range of 10 or $15 a megawatt hour higher than we probably were three or four month ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got you. Just one last question, on in terms of the material that have been procured for Keystone, how much of the pipe and steel and pumping equipment has been procured and kind of locked in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the &#x2013; for phase I that we are starting construction on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are probably somewhere around 60% if I remember correctly in terms of &#x2013; that order magnitude of $5.2 billion I think was our estimate that's out in the marketplace right now, so about 3 billion of that in terms of pipe and materials and contracts have been locked in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But as far as pipe and pumping equipment, we would have procured most of the pumping equipment for example, we have all of that. And most of the pipe....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of the pipe has been procured. There is some amount of price risk on some of the pipe, but a very small amount of price exposure left on the pipe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks for the time, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Faisel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is Sam Kanes from Scotia Capital. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I'd like to go to Ravenswood and your &#x2013; Alex, your thoughts about once you get your asset in your control kind of creating a contract portfolio mix that makes sense to you terming out, but wasn't that the very essence of why National Grid sold Ravenswood? They couldn't find a long-term contract portfolio mix because they're given that choice either you do or you sell?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yeah. I think that was even more extreme than that. I mean, certainly how I understood it was, there were &#x2013; they were given a very strong incentive from their regulator; in fact a penalty to the extent that they didn't divest of Ravenswood in. I do think, I mean if you think about it from their perspective, they would be looking at a long-term, very long-term contract, whereas we are talking about pursuing a portfolio of contracts some long, some short &#x2013; sort of in that regard. And I don't think that ever would have satisfied their regulator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the mix that you think you can get from New York. What &#x2013; can you paint a picture what you think you might get &#x2013; like one, three and five mix or something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's &#x2013; I would say I guess it's pretty early days for that, but I mean certainly there are buyers out in this market and there &#x2013; we think we'll be able to pursue portfolio of sales, not unlike the kind of sales that you see in our western or eastern business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And with respect to replacement costs, which sounds like you have a very good deal of pricing pressure. You never earn that replacement cost when you're earning on existing capacity in a regulated market, which is the essence I guess of why there is mild dilution here. Is it fair to say that the delta to your goodwill, which you'll recognize over time, because you have the best location to put in new capital that will have to obviously attract a fair return asset new capital level. If you take a while to chew up your existing premium you are paying over the previous guy's ownership of a semi regulated asset?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, Sam, it's Hal. Your statement is true with respect to the Canadian mainline for example, where in that regulated world the replacement costs of the mainline would be maybe 20 billion compared to the 8 billion of rate base. And we don't have the opportunity to earn on the real economic value in other words the replacement costs of the mainline. But in the case of Ravenswood, I don't think it's really correct to describe that it's a regulated asset, and this is effectively a merchant assets in a partial capacity market, and we will sell both capacity and energy at fair market value, not at any kind of regulated value and so, we think what will the fair market value for capacity be. It will be driven by the cost of new capacity in a market that generally needs more capacity. If the market never needed any new capacity then I could understand that maybe we wouldn't get a fair market value for our capacity or certainly wouldn't get a premium to what we pay. But in this particular case, I think, we would foresee a future in which additional capacity in New York will cost quite a bit more than what we paid for Ravenswood and we think that typical marginal price setting market as those two plans will set the marginal price of both capacity and energy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Sam, it's Alex. In fact, the way the various orders with respect to the New York capacity market work in the design of it, capacity is in fact &#x2013; the price of capacity is ultimately derived from the cost of new entry not the embedded cost of existing generators and I think I have said this earlier but we made an assumption that we are going to get something less than the true cost of new entry somewhere in the range of 75% of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. And follow-up just staying with Ravenswood; obviously, S&amp;P had used the qualitative term riskier asset relative to your mix. And you've already given us, I guess, the consolidated 60-40 debt equity framework target. If this was to be a standalone asset, which it won't, would it more like 50-50 in the eyes of S&amp;P and/or yourselves and what allowed return that 50, do you think is appropriate for the volatility of this quasi-regulated or however you want to call, asset?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sam, I think we look at our power business as a portfolio of assets, and I think we could reasonably argue that assets like B&#xE9;cancour and Portland and Halton that are covered by 20-year no commodity price wares contracts. Many of our competitors would be financing those with, for example, 75% debt. And when we acquired our Alberta coal PPAs, there were people that observed this is quite a bit riskier than existing business and I think we've demonstrated that the risk reward character of our Alberta coal PPA business is good, not bad and has served our shareholders well.</p>
          <p>Similarly, when we got into Bruce, there was quite a bit of concern that it's a riskier thing for TransCanada to do and we felt that we could manage that risk and, I think, the earnings that we have been able to generate from Bruce, even though occasionally they've disappointed us as well they disappointed you. At all times they have been economically attractive and have been a good return on the investment we made there. So, every asset has its own quirks and we a lot of these things before we buy them. We're comfortable that Ravenswood is an asset that's going to fit very well with our particular expertise and capabilities in the Northeast. It gives us many leavers that we can pull to generate earnings for TransCanada.</p>
          <p>I really don't know how you would finance Ravenswood as a standalone asset. A single plant asset like they are trying to maintain an A-grade credit, would have to have an extremely thick equity component, if it was a single-purpose company. So the fact is that by making it part of our portfolio, we're not subsidizing with another assets. It's just that we structure our capital over the whole portfolio. We've got some very stable assets and some of that have a little more volatility, and in almost every case is the ones with more volatility that also give us the significant earnings upside, which we think is, may not be important to the credit agencies, but I think it's important to the shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next is from Mark Caruso from Millennium Partners. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I just want to circle back on the financing side. You had mentioned the 60-40 split and then the S&amp;P release, they are saying is a considerable amount of equity, so I just want to kind of circle back on that as well as, you know, I am here in the U.S. and you were saying the preferred market is still open to you guys and kind of it. How is a hybrid market because I've heard here in the States, the hybrid market isn't as strong as just kind of, want to get your thoughts on that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes I'd agree with you that the hybrid market has certainly weakened off since we issued last October, and the agencies are looking for a different language, or stronger language than what we've seen in the past. So, I think we're starting to see the market turn around a little bit, certainly on the debt side in the U.S. we're seeing trends, fairly large debt transactions get done and be oversubscribed &#x2013; several times oversubscribe. There is a lot of money sitting on the sidelines right now just because of the market volatility. So, I think you will start to see some of those markets turn around and then as I say we're also looking at the LT market which we can do tranches about $250 million and on a consolidated basis. That's considered equity for TransCanada when we do an issue like that and we certainly have assets which we will be able be mandate over time to that vehicle. So we've got lots of flexibility. TransCanada on both the debt and the alternatives to equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as debt goes, do you &#x2013; the market I guess is strong enough to take a full 60, or you think you'd be able to split that 60 between straight debt and some of these sort of hybrid types of components.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't think we've got any problem placing significant debt in the U.S. market particularly. And so, we don't see that we will need &#x2013; purely on the debt side of the financing to do anything other than we would normally do with term debt. And I would say that we will have a significant bridge facility in place, which will cover the entire acquisition amount, and will have a debt tranche to it, such that we will have flexibility for a period of time, at least one year in which we will go to the market from a term-debt perspective. So we have lots of flexibility in order to watch the market and as you have seen us in the past like our issue last October take advantage of windows in the market to get the best pricing. We are seeing pricing tightening up right now and we think that it's likely to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question has already been answered. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Harry Mateer from Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I was just wondering if we strip out Ravenswood from your financing plans this year, and just look at your CapEx budget, what are you thinking right now in terms of your financing needs, just for capital spending, ex Ravenswood. Are you going to need something from the market be it asset drop-downs or debt or equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, based on our committed portfolio, we have about $3 billion a year that we can spend and we are right on top of that number without Ravenswood right now. So there really is anything that we would need to do. When we move beyond the $3 billion and look at incremental spend for new greenfield projects, first of all when we announce things, those capital cost are not immediate. They are out in the future, sometimes two or three years out. So, you wouldn't have significant additional short term costs and then, as we look at that portfolio going out forward that's then we look at asset monetizations and other vehicles in order to fund that long-term growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And at Keystone, are you planning to finance that at the project level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are not. We're looking initially to a bank facility that would be supported by TransCanada.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And whether the bank facility would be for Keystone and 50-50, TransCanada-Conoco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It would for Keystone and we're working with Conoco as to what the best way to approach the debt market is for that particular piece of credit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then in terms of asset monetizations down at the MLP, in terms of size, what you see out there right now, presumably the MLP equity market will improve at some point but it still remains a little bit weak, but the size of potential drop-downs in a given year what are you thinking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we can initially look at something in that 250 to $300 million range. The market should be able to accept that in one tranche and then whether or not you could do more than one in a year would depend on market conditions going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Steven Paget from FirstEnergy. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just a couple of questions on Keystone; looking at what is the cost of for the total line fill and capitalized interest and are those part of the 3 billion in locked-in cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At the end of the day, there really isn't line fill per se. We fill the pipeline with the initial barrels but it's the first batch is that way I kind of look at it. And those aren't costs that are borne by the pipeline, it's the shipper supply, the line fill, if you want to call it that. That first batch probably takes somewhere in the neighborhood of 60 to 90 days to move it through the pipes but then it comes out the other end and the shipper gets their crude back to sell and then from that point the timeframe to move from Alberta to say Cushing is in that 25 kind of day range, so that's a carrying cost that producers have, but we really don't have any line fill per se. And then I didn't hear what your second question was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The capitalized interest for Keystone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The capitalized interest or ACDP under construction, if you will, is a cost that becomes part of the rate base which goes into calculation of the toll that we charge our shippers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how much are you estimating that that will be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not a number that we've shared publicly, but I mean you can give it your best shot using a 60-40 debt equity structure and some assumption around what interest costs are and our construction spend over that the construction period sort of ramps up the page in 2000 but we haven't specifically talked about what that number would be. But that would give you a range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But, Steven, you can think about one of the good things about Keystone is that it's roughly an 18 to 20 month construction period in '08 and '09. So, for things are happening fairly quickly relative to say a Mackenzie Valley Pipeline where you might be accumulating interest on development costs for 10 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Matthew Akman from Macquarie. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, I just wanted to clarify your intentions on asset sales because there has been a lot of talk on it in this conference call and yet you guys have done a good job of building up a portfolio of assets which seem to fit very well within your stated strategy and many frankly better than Ravenswood. So I mean, is your intention to sell a lot of your or a significant amount of existing power or pipeline assets to pay for Ravenswood?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I guess I'd ask first Matthew whether that's the statement of factor or an opinion about Ravenswood. We think Ravenswood fits very well otherwise we wouldn't have bought it. We have assets like the GTN system that has some significant down incretion opportunities after we acquired it and also has some real strategic value to TransCanada long-term. And so, part of the attraction of our MLP is that it allow us to recoup significant capital investments while maintaining strategic control over the assets. And so in a case like GTN we can accomplish that objective without having all of our money tied up in it. And in the case in GTN, for example, we have successfully gotten through a difficult rate case and we think we've added value to the pipeline system and by doing that.</p>
          <p>So we don't have a whole lot of pipeline that we're contemplating rolling into the MLP right now. But that would be one an example not of pipeline that we intend to roll in but I'm trying to give you some sense of the kind of pipes that we would look at that we could roll in. Obviously any of our material pipelines would be candidates for that sort of thing. Now our entire interest in Northern Border, which we operate, is held in the MLP and our interest in Northern Border is held indirectly as a result of our 32% ownership in the MLP. So that's the third variable. If we did those kinds of deals, what would our ownership level in the MLP be and could we assure ourselves that we'd effectively maintain control over the assets one way or another, in terms of what happens to them in future.</p>
          <p>So, most of our focus, I think I could say to you would be on U.S. pipes that would fit well from an investor point of view within the MLP. On the power side of things, again my own criteria for rolling assets into MLP or other partnership structures, or selling them outright revolves around fully developed value. If we have done everything we can to fully develop the value of an asset and it's the good point in the market cycle, then we would consider selling it. If the assets have a lot of optionality, or a lot opportunity for us to add value in the future, then we probably wouldn't sell it and so it's kind of in that transition from a rising star asset to a fully developed cash cal that's where we think about divesting assets, whether they are pipes or power.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that answer, Hal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Matthew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Daniel Shteyn from Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. My questions are more to do now with your organic growth projects, there's been a whole whack of pipeline projects announced recently by including the Sunstone and Pathfinder projects that are, I guess, still a little bit in the conceptual stage because there has been no new capital or there is &#x2013; there haven't been any capital cost estimates announced. So, just as an order of magnitude, how big you do you believe those capital expenditures could possibly be in the future, should the open seasons actually be successful and what would be the timing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's &#x2013; you can &#x2013; the Rockies looks, let's sort of start with sort of market demand first in terms of how much capacity will be build at the Rockies. It's our view that that we'll need to &#x2013; the Rockies is sort of forecast to grow by somewhere between 1.5 and 3 billion cubic feet a day over the next say five to seven years. Our view is that they'll need one new pipe with a capacity of about 1 billion cubic feet a day by somewhere in 2011-12 range to make sure that they don't have dislocation in the differential. And then if things continue another one sort of in that 2013-14 range and that's same sort of size of about 1 billion cubic feet a day. The cost of constructing a pipeline and all of these pipeline are somewhere between, say, 700 and 1,000 miles and I think, I gave you a sort of rough rule of thumb before of somewhere around say $3 million a mile. So you are looking somewhere between 2 and $3 billion for 1 billion cubic feet a day's pipeline to one of these markets and I said, I believe that only one of these pipelines will probably get being build in the sort of 2011-12 range and maybe another one in that 2013-14 range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the kind of the ballpark pipe construction cost estimate that you provided, that I believe you were referring to an oil pipeline there. Are pipeline costs for natural gas and oil pretty much the same?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are pretty much the same. We are talking about that large diameter of pipe running from 36 to 42 inch, similar to what we are using for the Keystone pipeline. It is very similar costs, and then your laid costs are very similar. So, there is some differences that I think we can still use that rough rule of thumb for both kinds of pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and my other question has to do with everybody's favorite power plant, Ravenswood, I'm just wondering what &#x2013; if you are able to provide a sense of what sort of spark spread Ravenswood can have, is and will be able to generate for your account going forward? And I know, this could be a competitive issue, so a range is fine or historical kind of, amount of color is fine as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that obviously is something we're pretty concerned about. I guess what I would say is that the heat rate of the units there are kind of a matter of record. The combined cycle plant is about 7,300, 7,400 and the big oil, big gas oil boilers are kind of in the range of the high 9,000, mid-to-high 9000s. I mean, our view is that the market heat rates in that market are probably in the range of 10,000, but obviously there is lots of spikes in the winter and in the summer. So, it's a pretty hard for us to kind of be specific about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Daniel I'd add that, of the revenue stream at Ravenswood, a significant part of it is capacity payments and particularly when you look at the 460 megawatts of gas-fired peakers, those I think, Alex, would have heat rates in the 17,000 range and with the end result, they hardly ever run 1 or 2% of the time historically. But they do generate significant capacity payment revenue and it's a doubling up of revenues that occurs. When you're actually running the plant you do continue to get capacity payments. And in addition, you get the spark spread energy payment if that &#x2013; if there is a possible spark spread which of course in the case of gas turbine, usually there isn't. So that's why they don't run. So those are the different components I think that drive us but I just wanted to emphasize in addition to what Alex said that the capacity revenue is a pretty significant percent of the total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure and capacity payments are, I guess, they have a little bit more visibility in terms of a lot of the stuff being public for filings and so on. But to come back to my question which was regarding a sort of &#x2013; a range of sparks spreads then even given the very different nature of the different units in that plant there is still some sort of a consolidated range of numbers that maybe you can talk about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the best way for us to describe it for you is in terms of the heat rates that Alex described because to go from there to spark spread, you have to bring into an account price of gas and price of power and the conversion. So we're prepared to tell you roughly what these units convert gas or oil into electricity at but our own estimates of power price and gas price, you'd have those just as well as we would.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no more questions registered at this time. I will now turn the meeting back over Mr. Moneta. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just &#x2013; I am sorry, conference coordinator, I'll turn it back to you, just in case, I would like to open it for the media now, so if there are media questions, we would be happy to take them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question is from Ian McKinnon from the Bloomberg News. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two very short and hopefully easy questions to answer. The $3 million roughly you've been saying, is that Canadian or U.S. dollars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're about the same today, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A slight difference. And can you give me an estimate in terms of the length of how long Keystone expansion will be or how much greater or shorter than Keystone I.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's about, if I remember correctly. It's about 20% longer, somewhere in that kind of range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Gordon Jaremko from the Edmonton Journal. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question in the same area. Last time I heard you talk about this or Hal Kvisle talk about this it, you had some estimates about what the advantage to oil producers would be of getting oil sands production all the way down to the U.S. Gulf Coast. It seems to me you were talking about reducing the discount by about 50%. Is that still true a, and b, it seems to me you had an estimate of even how much it would cost to get there which was around $6 a barrel. What are those current sort of projections?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Gordon, one long running debate in the oil industry here in Calgary is whether the discount is best expressed in so many dollars per barrel, or as a percentage of the WTI price, and there are certain elements of both. But I remember back when crude oil prices were $20, at that point a $10 discount was seen as horrific and at $100 we have seen discount, I think Russ, correct me if I'm wrong, but in the order of 40 to $60. At times the discount has exceeded the value of the barrel in Alberta. So, we do &#x2013; clearly all we look at is what does a comparable barrel of crude oil trade for in the U.S. South Coast today and Mexican Mayan and certain other Venezuelan streams would be seen as the most comparable and you could do a few quality adjustments from there to figure out what you might be able to sell Alberta crude for if you could get it down there. And then offsetting that of course is the cost of moving and the net cost of moving it has got a couple of components, one is the total what we charge and the other is the cost of diluents and what you have to pay for diluents in Alberta versus what you can resell it for once you get to the Gulf Coast.</p>
          <p>The real advantage to producer is in going to the Gulf Coast is that there is huge liquidity in the market for both the bitumen component and the diluent component, whereas at various markets along the way, whether it's in Minnesota or Chicago or Cushing or whatever, Wood River there is not that same liquidity in the market. So, it's really the ability to connect Alberta directly to a very large and liquid market that's where the real benefit to all Alberta producers comes from this kind of a project. And I don't, Gordon I just don't want to be speculating on what that might be as an impact on the differential. We build and supply the pipeline service and it's the commercial people in the oil companies that are really the experts as to where differentials are likely to go or probably more correctly what range differentials are likely to be in, in the years ahead. All I could tell you is that when you do add significant capacity that interconnects a very liquid market with a somewhat constrained supply basin that's very good news for all the producers in the supply basin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You still estimate $6 a barrel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the tariff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are little more than that I think, but directionally you are in the ballpark there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what's your estimate of how much added pipeline capacity in total that oil sands industry is going to need say by the time you would build this one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the best place to go for information on that is probably CAPP and look at CAPP's forecast of increased production out of the oil sands, Russ, I don't know if you recall those numbers off hand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think that this pretty much would &#x2013; assuming that the oil sands projects sort of progress along the schedule of the CAPP forecast we would be constrained somewhere around 2010, 2011 and that's when we propose to this on and that constraint would be about 500,000 barrels a day. And then what we are looking at probably is another 500,000 barrels a day, every couple of years after that. I think the current projection is about 2 million barrels a day of incremental production coming out of the oil sands. Our base Keystone project picks up about 600,000 barrels of oil a day of that and again Enbridge picks up an equivalent amount. That leaves you with about 1 million barrels over the next say five years. If we built another project equivalent to Keystone in the next say couple of years after Keystone then I think there is room for another one, in that sort of 2014, '15 kind of range as long as sort of production continues to grow along the current forecast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you don't necessarily see yourself as in competition with Enbridge then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't like to characterize it that way. We think we are both doing the best job we can to come forward with projects that are valuable and appealing to the producers. And as long as production continues to grow I think you would likely see both companies winning their fair share if you will of the business. We want to of course win more than we don't win, and we will work hard to come up with compelling value propositions. But it's not an either/or, they are continuing to add significant capacity to their system which mostly goes through Chicago, heads in that direction. And we keep bringing forward expansions or variations on the Keystone theme. And I think those are both pretty interesting options, it just depends to which market does the producer want to go. When we came up with the Keystone routing and the Keystone destinations, we ruled out very quickly building a pipeline that would serve the Chicago market because Enbridge does that very well and they have the competitive advantage there. So, we thought about what other markets could we head for and where might we be able to configure a pipeline that would give us competitive advantage, and we think Keystone's got that.</p>
          <p>So, that's &#x2013; that will be interesting to see how &#x2013; two big things, how is production going to increase at the oil sands. Will it increase more or less rapidly, we know there is market demand for it. And the second question is to which market will that production flow including possibly the Pacific waterborne market, where people do continue to propose pipelines through DC and to the water ports on the West Coast. So, we are not into that game, we are very focused of the part of the United States that Keystone serves and that our expansion project would serve mainly the Gulf Coast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gordon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you our next question is from Hyun Young Lee from Dow Jones. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I just wanted to clarify some things where &#x2013; you said the Keystone expansion down to the Gulf Coast to be about 20% longer and, Russ, you were saying it earlier on that &#x2013; talking about the saving of pipelines by taking a more direct route. So I don't know if I am missing something there. How can you have a pipeline saving if the route is actually going to be longer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In think there are two different questions, one was how we compare to other alternatives in proposed to get the Gulf Coast and one of those alternative is to basically follow the existing Enbridge line and then from a place called Patoka extend through to Texas. It's kind of a roundabout route that kind of leaves Alberta if you will, goes past Chicago and into the Gulf Coast.</p>
          <p>And our route is more direct basically from Calgary if you will to Houston. You can think of that analogy. So that is a direct routing that is less by distance, so that was the first comparison. The second question was a comparison to our existing Keystone build which only goes to Cushing, Oklahoma. It kind of takes that quirk or jog, that can help actually go from Alberta to Winnipeg and then from Winnipeg to Cushing, Oklahoma. And then, our new pipe will go from &#x2013; it's actually from Alberta goes past Chicago right through to the Gulf Coast and that's where the distance is about 20% greater than the existing Keystone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And so, you're saying with this extra distance, you said that the cost will also increase by order of magnitude. I don't know if you can use that $3 million a mile number, but if you're looking at a 20% expansion on top of that, then costs are going to be &#x2013; I mean you are looking at least 1 billion more than the 5.2 that you've got for the original Keystone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I did use the number Lee, it's going to be in that order of magnitude of 20 to 30% a &#x2013; there's 20, 30% more steel, 20 to 30% more lay cost, 20 to 30% more expenses than the original Keystone build.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one final question is, this new pipeline you're looking at 2011 startup, was that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we don't know when that will start up, we haven't even ventured into an open season yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Process right now of scoping the route, the term and conditions under which we would ship the crude with both producers and refiners. So, there is a number of those things yet to be done and once we get the open season and when we're confident, we will be announcing sort of <mark type="inaudible" /> service date would be for that project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But if &#x2013; it's Hal here. I'd just like to clarify one thing that first of all please refer to slide number 8 in the set of slides. And you'll see that the original Keystone follows a bit of a circuitous route and I think one of the answers to your question is the original Keystone pipe makes use of a bunch of pipes that's already there, it's the old gas pipe that we converted, and that's one of the reason why it's hard to compare the lengths of the two, because the conversion costs on that existing pipe was very, very cheap compared to the costs of building new.</p>
          <p>The second is that you made the comments that the new Keystone would be an order of magnitude more expensive than the other one, that's not correct. It's not anywhere near an order of magnitude, it's a modest percentage more. It'll be a little bit more per mile because it's 36 rather than 30, means the amount of steel cost goes up. But I just wanted to make sure that we didn't leave you with the impression that's it's an order of magnitude i.e. 10 times as expensive, that's not the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And when do you plan to do an open season on that, on the expansion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If all those discussions and negotiations come together, we hope within the next month or two, we will be able to announce an open season process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Louis Shammy from Zimmer Lucas. Please go ahead</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. My question was regarding getting oil from Cushing to the Gulf Coast. Is there any possibility for a potential pipeline to just let's say more scale than this Keystone expansion or you just take the direct route from Cushing to Houston or Port Arthur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you mean converting an existing line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Either converting an existing line or building something new.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we would build something new, that would be our plan from Cushing to Port Arthur, would be a new pipeline that we would build. We have looked at other pipes and generally they are not big enough or they don't go to the right place or things like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Particularly key in getting to the Gulf Coast, I think from our perspective, from Cushing was to get critical mass to move from Cushing to the Gulf Coast and right now our deliveries off the base Keystone system at Cushing are basically all spoken for by refiners in Cushing area. So there really isn't a lot of barrels that you can sort of convert south. So if you build a pipeline to go south, pick a volume, say 300,000 barrels a day, you need to put some volume into it at the top end to get it to the bottom end. And then when you look at sort of filling the pipes at the top end, to make a project economic, you've got to come back to Alberta for 300,000 barrels a day. It doesn't &#x2013; it's not an economic proposition to come back for that small of a volume, back to Alberta and build right to the Gulf Coast, your fuel is more expensive than the other alternatives in the marketplace. So we looked a lot at an alternative that would just be could you gather enough crude at Cushing to build to the Gulf Coast and we couldn't assemble enough critical mass in our planning process to make that kind of proposal to the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that makes a lot of sense and answers my question. The other thing I wanted to ask about was regarding the U.S. Pipeline assets that you're currently holding in TransCanada that could potentially be asset monetizations in the future. Just to tick them off, I see GLGT, GTN, the ANR system and then your Southwest assets, are there any other assets that could potentially go in and what issues would surround each of those pipelines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me go through your list. First of all we today have about 46% of Great Lakes that is in our MLP. So, we've already taken steps there, and we have 100% of our interest in Northern Border that's in the MLP. So there is not much there &#x2013; no part of GPM is in the MLP, so we do think about that. But I just want to clarify that it's an illustrative option that I was discussing earlier, but GPM is certainly a candidate. The southern end of GPM serving Nevada is called <mark type="inaudible" /> and all of our interest in <mark type="inaudible" /> is already in the MLP. The North Baja line down at Southern California, we would not anticipate that going towards the MLP in the near term. We've got a lot of work and investments to do there. And pipes like <mark type="inaudible" /> if we owned 100% we might think about putting part of it into the MLP, it's a different question when we only own roughly 44%, we consider it, but I am just kind of running through them all for you.</p>
          <p>My sense on ANR, we've got a lot of work to do there, and we've got terrific investment opportunity on the storage side. We don't think projects that have execution risk or technical risk in a substantive way are appropriate for the MLP. Our business model is to deal with those tissues, take that risk within TransCanada, create value which we would intend to capture for the TransCanada shareholders. And maybe at some point in the future put a part of those assets into the MLP, but I would not want to leave the impression that any significant transfer of ANR assets is going anywhere anytime in the near future. That's the kind of asset that we keep within TransCanada.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, that makes sense. And being that the Great Lake System and the GTN system have both been in TransCanada for a while; I would expect that any kind of asset sale there would produce significant tax liability; is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it would produce a taxable gain, I think, and we don't always think those are such bad things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, well, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no more questions registered at this time. I will now turn the meeting back over to Mr. Moneta. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much to all of you for participating this afternoon. We appreciate your interest in the company. I know it's been a bit of a long day with our AGM earlier today; but once again, we appreciate your interest late on a Friday. Bye for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference has now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>