<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1281722" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1560</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David Moneta, Vice President of Investor Relations and Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Harold N. Kvisle, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Gregory A. Lohnes, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Carl Kirst</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Russell Girling</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Bob Hastings</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Harry Mateer</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Matthew Akman</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Theodore Durbin</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Robert Kwan</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Andrew Kuske</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Linda Ezergailis</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep">Alexander Pourbaix</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">Glenn Menuz</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Pierre Lacroix</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Steven Paget</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Petro Panarites</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Robert Hastings</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Justin Amoah</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the TransCanada Corporation 2009 Fourth Quarter Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. David Moneta, Vice President of Investor Relations and Corporate Communications. Please go ahead, Mr. Moneta.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, and good afternoon, everyone. I'd like to welcome you to TransCanada's 2000 fourth quarter conference call. With me today are Hal Kvisle, President and Chief Executive Officer; Greg Lohnes, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer; Russ Girling, our Chief Operating Officer; Alex Pourbaix, President of Energy and Executive Vice President and Corporate Development; and Glenn Menuz, Vice President and Controller.</p>
          <p>Hal and Greg will begin today with some opening comments on our financial results, and other general issues pertaining to TransCanada. Please note that a slide presentation will accompany their remarks. A copy of the presentation is available on our website at transcanada.com. And you can find it in the Investor section under the heading, Conference Calls &amp; Presentations.</p>
          <p>Following their prepared remarks, we'll turn the call over to the conference coordinator for your questions. And during the question-and-answer period, we'll take questions from the investment community first, followed by the media. In order to provide everyone with an equal opportunity to participate, we ask that you limit yourself to two questions. If you have additional questions, please re-enter the queue.</p>
          <p>Also, we ask that you focus your questions on our industry, our corporate strategy, recent developments, and key elements of our financial performance. If you have any detailed questions relating to some of our smaller operations for your detailed financial models, Myles, Terry, and I would be pleased to discuss them with you following the call.</p>
          <p>Before Hal begins, I'd like to remind you that our remarks today will include forward-looking statements that are subject to important risks and uncertainties. For more information on these risks and uncertainties, please see the reports filed by TransCanada with Canadian Securities regulators and with the U.S. Securities Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>And finally, I'd also like to point out that during this presentation, we'll refer to measures, such as comparable earnings, comparable earnings per share, earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization, or EBITDA, comparable EBITDA, and funds generated from operations. These measures do not have any standardized meaning under GAAP, and are therefore considered to be non-GAAP measures. As a result, they may not be comparable to similar measures presented by other entities. And these measures are used to provide you with additional information on TransCanada's operating performance, liquidity, and its ability to generate funds to finance its operations.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll now turn the call over to Hal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David. Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. As outlined in today's news release, TransCanada's net income for the year ending December 31, 2009, was $1.4 billion, or $2.11 per share. Comparable earnings were 1.3 billion, or 2.03 per share, and our funds generated from operations were $3.1 billion in 2009. Comparable EBITDA was 4.1 billion, and funds generated from operations, as I said, were just at 3.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Our 2009 financial results highlight our ability to generate strong earnings and cash flow from a diverse portfolio of North American energy infrastructure assets. In 2009, we invested approximately $6.3 billion in growth initiatives in assets that will provide our company with long-term value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the dividend, we are confident that our 22 billion capital program will lead to significant growth in cash flow and earnings over the next five years, as a number of attractive low-risk projects are placed into service. This has enabled our Board of Directors to increase the quarterly dividend on the company's common shares by over 5% to $0.40 per share per quarter. On an annualized basis, this equates to $1.60 per share. This is the 10th consecutive year the Board has raised the dividend, and represents more than a 7% compound annual growth rate in the dividend over that period.</p>
          <p>We continued to make significant progress on a number of our growth initiatives in the fourth quarter. I'd like to discuss those in more detail, starting on slide eight in our fourth quarter investor presentation. Firstly, construction of Keystone Phase 1 to Wood River and Patoka Illinois is now substantially complete. Over the past 18 months, our workforce, that at one point, totaled 8,500 men and women, worked more than 20 million hours to get the job done. During that time, we installed approximately 2,000 kilometers of new 30-inch diameter pipe, we converted almost 900 kilometers of existing natural gas pipeline to oil service, and we constructed 39 new pump stations. As a result, we were able to start commissioning the first phase of Keystone in late 2009 as expected, and this stage will continue through the second quarter of 2010. During this time, shippers will provide approximately 9 million barrels of oil to Keystone in order to complete line filling. We now expect commercial in-service to begin in mid-2010.</p>
          <p>In its first year of operation, as we ramp up the operational capability of the system, Keystone will move contracted volumes of 217,500 barrels per day, with the potential to move additional spot volumes. Construction on Phase II of Keystone, which comprises an extension of the system from Steel City, Nebraska to Cushing, Oklahoma, will commence in the second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Keystone is currently seeking necessary regulatory approvals in Canada and the United States to build and operate a large expansion and extension of the pipeline system that will provide additional capacity of 500,000 barrels per day from Western Canada to the Gulf Coast, with that coming onstream in late 2012 or early 2013.</p>
          <p>In September 2009, the National Energy Board held a hearing to review the application for the Canadian portion of that Keystone Gulf Coast Expansion. We expect the NEB's decision in the first quarter of 2010. Permits for the U.S. portion of the Keystone Gulf Coast Expansion are expected by the fourth quarter of 2010. Construction of the Expansion is expected to begin in 2011, following TransCanada's receipt of all those necessary regulatory approvals.</p>
          <p>The highly contracted nature of the Keystone system, at 83% of capacity, or 910,000 barrels per day, for an average of 18 years, clearly demonstrates the strong need for the pipeline, and Keystone's value and usefulness to both Alberta producers and U.S. refiners.</p>
          <p>Turning to our natural gas transmission business, TransCanada and ExxonMobil continue to advance the Alaska Pipeline Project by filing the open season plan in January of this year with U.S. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. That filing was made to obtain approval to conduct the first natural gas pipeline open season ever to develop Alaska's vast natural gas resources. If FERC approves the open season plan, the project will commence the open season process in April of 2010.</p>
          <p>Here in Western Canada, the Groundbirch Pipeline public hearing process with the NEB concluded in November 2009. A decision from the NEB is expected in February 2010 this month, with construction commencing in July of this year and in-service expected in November 2010. Groundbirch has 1.1 bcf per day of secure firm transportation contracts that will connect natural gas supply, primarily from the Montney shale gas formation in northeast B.C, to TransCanada's existing infrastructure in Northwest Alberta.</p>
          <p>In the north of Groundbirch, the Horn River Pipeline contractual commitments have now risen to 503 million cubic feet per day, further increasing natural gas supply from the Horn River shale gas formation.</p>
          <p>TransCanada filed an application in February with the NEB for approval to construct and operate the Horn River pipeline in the first quarter of 2010. The Horn River project is anticipated to be placed in-service in the second quarter of 2012. Work also continues on our North Central Corridor pipeline in Alberta. The first phase of this project is now complete, and the second phase is expected to be complete by April 2010. North Central Corridor will provide capacity needed to deal with increased natural gas supply in northwest Alberta, and in the shale plays of northeast B.C. It'll also address declining natural gas supply in northeast Alberta. It will serve growing markets within the Province, and it will help deliver more gas to the Alberta Saskatchewan export point.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, regulatory approvals were reached in December of 2009 for the Guadalajara natural gas pipeline project, and construction is underway with an anticipated in-service date in the first quarter of 2011. The pipeline's 25-year take-or-pay and an expected double-digit unlevered internal rate of return are a perfect fit for TransCanada as a secure cash flow generating energy infrastructure asset. We will continue to look for further opportunities to expand our Mexican presence in the future.</p>
          <p>Finally, in pipelines, our Bison natural gas pipeline project is expected to commence construction in May of this year with an expected in-service date of the fourth quarter of 2010. Bison is a good example of our strategy to commercially develop new asset investments, and it's also an example of how we continue to maximize the full-life value of our existing infrastructure. The accompanying long-term downstream contracts our Bison shippers have made on our Northern Border pipeline served to further diversify and stabilize Northern Border's cash flow in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our Energy business. Construction of the 683-megawatt Halton Hills Generating Station in the greater Toronto area of Ontario is continuing on schedule, and the facility is anticipated to be in service in the third quarter of 2010. The 575-megawatt Coolidge Generating Station in Arizona is also continuing on schedule, with an expected in-service date of the second quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>In our Wind Power business, TransCanada placed the first phase of Kibby Wind in service in October, which includes 22 turbines capable of producing 66 megawatts of power. Construction continues on the 66-megawatt second phase, and we expect that to be in service in the third quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>At our Cartier Wind project in Quebec, brush clearing work for the 58-megawatt Montagne-S&#xE8;che wind farm, and the first phase of the 212-megawatt Gros-Morne wind farm, was completed in the fourth quarter of 2009. These two wind farm projects in Quebec are expected to be operational in 2011. Gros-Morne Phase 2 is thereafter expected to be operating in 2012.</p>
          <p>At the Bruce nuclear facility, progress continues on the refurbishment and restart of Bruce A Units 1 and 2, with a focus on the reassembly of the reactors, and other related activities. The bulk of the highly technical, high risk work has now finished or is very near completion. Although a significant amount of work remains, most of this remaining work is conventional power plant construction activity. We expect that Unit 2 will be restarted in mid-2011, with Unit 1 expected to follow approximately four months later.</p>
          <p>Bruce Power continues to advance an initiative to further extend the operating lives of Units 3 and 4. Unit 4 is now expected to continue to operate beyond 2018, and plans are in place to implement an extensive maintenance program that could see the life of Unit 3 extended for a similar period of time.</p>
          <p>In summary, we continue to build our competitive position in our three core businesses of natural gas transmission and storage, oil transmission, and power generation. We have now invested approximately $10 billion, or almost 50% of our $22 billion growth program in large-scale multi-year projects, such as the Keystone Oil Pipeline, the Alberta System's North Central Corridor expansion, the Bruce refurbishment project, and the construction of three large-scale gas-fired power plants. There is significant long-term visible growth at TransCanada, with these 22 billion of commercially secured projects now in construction and an additional $60 billion of capital opportunities in development.</p>
          <p>Between 2009 and 2013, we estimate we will achieve a 12% compound annual growth rate in EBITDA, and a 10% compound annual growth rate in funds generated from operations. This will drive significant growth in earnings, cash flow and dividends per share, all leading to a superior total shareholder return in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Greg Lohnes, our Chief Financial Officer, who will provide additional comments on our fourth quarter financial results. Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Hal. Good afternoon, everyone. As Hal mentioned, earlier today we released our fourth quarter results. We also expect to file our 2009 Annual Report to shareholders tomorrow, which contains the consolidated financial statements and accompanying notes for the year ended December 31, 2009, as well as the related management discussion and analysis.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 14. Comparable earnings in the fourth quarter were $328 million, or $0.48 per share, compared to $271 million or $0.46 per share for the same period in 2008. The primary reason for the $57 million increase in the fourth quarter comparable earnings is lower interest expense from increased capitalization of interest related to TransCanada's large capital growth program.</p>
          <p>2009 comparable earnings were $1.325 billion, a $46 million increase over the 2008 comparable earnings. On a per-share basis, comparable earnings of $2.03, in 2009, a decrease, compared to 2008 by the dilutive impact of a 14% increase in the average number of shares outstanding as a result of common share issuances in the second quarter 2009 and fourth quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>The proceeds of the share issues were partially used to fund our $22 billion capital program, including the acquisition of additional interests in Keystone, and other capital projects. As a result of pre-funding during these liquidity concerns that existed early in 2009, the carrying costs and earnings per share dilution associated with our prudent approach to financing this multi-year program will continue to have a near-term impact on our earnings and cash flow per share. That being said, each project is expected to generate significant long-term earnings and cash flow as they commence operations.</p>
          <p>I will now briefly review the fourth quarter results for each of our business segments at the EBITDA level, beginning with Pipelines on slide 15. The Pipelines business generated comparable EBITDA of $745 million during the fourth quarter 2009, a decrease of $35 million over the same period in 2008. The decrease is primarily due to the negative impact of a weaker U.S. dollar on U.S. Pipelines' results, and increased business development costs related to the Alaska Pipeline Project, partially offset by higher earnings from the Alberta System.</p>
          <p>Before I turn to Energy results, I'd like to make a few comments on our Keystone oil project. As Hal said, commercial operations are now expected to begin in mid-2010. Although TransCanada expects to begin generating cash flow from Keystone in mid-2010, we will continue to capitalize the related interest costs and EBITDA until we're through the commissioning period and the facilities are capable of running at the full commercial design nominal capacity of 435,000 barrels per day. The decrease from previously discussed EBITDA announced will be largely offset by the continuation of interest during construction.</p>
          <p>Based on current long-term commitments ramping up to 910,000 barrels per day between 2010 and 2013, we expect Keystone to generate EBITDA of approximately U.S. $1.2 billion in 2013, its first full year of commercial operations. If volumes were to increase from the current contracted amount of 910,000 barrels per day to the full commercial design of the system of 1.1 million barrels per day, Keystone would generate annual EBITDA of approximately U.S. $1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Next, some comments on our Energy results on Slide 16. Energy generated comparable EBITDA of $248 million in the fourth quarter 2009, compared to $297 million in the same period last year. The decrease is primarily due to lower power prices in Western Power and U.S. Power, and reduced volume in Western Power and Bruce Power. These increases were largely offset by incremental EBITDA from the start-up of Portlands Energy Centre, which went into service in April 2009. Energy's EBITDA also reflects a higher contribution from the Natural Gas Storage business due to increased third-party storage revenues as a result of higher realized seasonal natural gas price spreads.</p>
          <p>Now looking at Slide 17. I'd like to take a few minutes to talk about our highly contracted Energy business, and how we use hedging strategies where we have exposure to spot power prices. 100% of Eastern Power sales were sold under contract in the fourth quarter, and are expected to be sold under long-term contract in 2010 and beyond. 100% of the output from Bruce A in the fourth quarter was sold at a fixed price. All of the output from Bruce B is subject to a floor price. Both the fixed price received at Bruce A and the floor price at Bruce B are adjusted annually for inflation on April 1. 77% of Western Power sales volumes were sold under contract in fourth quarter 2009, compared to 68% in fourth quarter 2008. At December 31, Western Power had six sales power contracts for 8,400 gigawatt hours, or approximately 55% of planned sales for 2010, and 6,000 gigawatt hours, or approximately 40% of planned sales for 2011. And finally, U.S. Power has entered into fixed priced power sales contracts to sell forward approximately 10,300 gigawatt hours for 2010, and 5,400 gigawatt hours for 2011.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the Corporate segment results on Slide 18. Corporate EBITDA in the fourth quarter 2009 was a loss of $28 million, compared to a loss of $33 million for the same period last year. Overall in 2009, Corporate costs were higher, primarily due to higher support service costs, reflecting a growing asset base.</p>
          <p>Now, looking at items below EBIT on the income statement on Slide 19. Fourth quarter 2009 interest expense of 184 million is a decrease of 142 million, compared to fourth quarter last year. The decrease in interest expense reflects increased capitalization of interest to finance TransCanada's larger capital spending program in 2009, primarily due to Keystone construction. The lower interest expense is also a result of a decrease in U.S. dollar-denominated interest expense due to a weaker U.S. dollar, as well as improved fair-value adjustments on interest rate derivatives.</p>
          <p>Interest income and other increased $26 million, compared to fourth quarter 2008, primarily due to higher gains from foreign exchange management, and translation of U.S. working capital balances.</p>
          <p>Income taxes were $67 million in the fourth quarter of 2009, compared to $95 million for the same period in 2008. The decrease was primarily due to positive tax adjustments in the fourth quarter 2009, including $30 million resulting from a reduction in Province of Ontario corporate tax rates, partially offset by taxes resulting from higher income.</p>
          <p>Turning to cash flow on slide 20. Funds from operations were $850 million in the fourth quarter 2009, compared to $712 million in the fourth quarter 2008. Capital expenditures in fourth quarter 2009 of approximately $1.5 billion related primarily to a number of growth opportunities, including construction progress on Keystone, and other capital projects.</p>
          <p>Now looking at slide 21. At the end of the fourth quarter 2009, our balance sheet consisted of 50% debt, 3% junior subordinated notes, 3% preferred shares, and 44% common equity. We have an 'A' grade credit rating with a stable outlook. Our working relationships with all three credit rating agencies are strong.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we raised approximately $6 billion of debt and equity capital, as favorable rates during turbulent times in the economy. At the end of 2009, we had $1 billion of cash on hand, along with committed revolving bank lines of $4.3 billion. In December, TransCanada Pipelines Limited filed a U.S. $4 billion debt shelf prospectus giving the company $6 billion of total debt shelf availability.</p>
          <p>Now turning to slide 22. Looking forward to 2010 and 2011, we expect to invest approximately a $11 billion over this two-year period. The first source of funding will be our strong internally generated cash flow after dividends. This is expected to total approximately $5 billion over the two-year period. Our dividend reinvestment plan is expected to contribute an additional $725 million over the same timeframe, assuming a historic participation rate of approximately 30%.</p>
          <p>The common equity we raised through the dividend reinvestment plan, along with retained earnings, means we have the capacity to issue an additional $3 billion of term debt over the two-year period without materially changing our consolidated capital structure. That leaves us with remaining needs of approximately 1.5 to $2 billion over the two-year period that we expect will be met through various forms of subordinated capital. We expect to raise additional subordinated capital using hybrid securities, preferred shares, healthy dropdowns for our portfolio management activity.</p>
          <p>In September 2009, we raised $550 million in a very successful preferred share offer. That market appears to be open to us, and we'll consider further preferred share issues as we move through this two-year period. In April 2007, we issued U.S. $1 billion of junior subordinated notes that received 50% equity treatment from the rating agencies. That hybrid security market closed for a while during the financial crisis, but appears to be opening up again, subject to hybrid security rating agency reviews. In July 2009, we completed the sale of our North Baja Pipeline to our TC PipeLines LP, and we continue to expect that the LP will play an ongoing role in our funding program.</p>
          <p>That concludes my prepared remarks. I'll now turn the call back to David for the question-and-answer period. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Greg. Just a reminder, before I turn the call over to the conference coordinator, we'll take questions from the financial community first, and once we've completed that, we'll turn it over to the media. And with that, I'll turn the call back to the conference coordinator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So, we will now take questions from the analysts. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Carl Kirst of BMO Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, every &#x2013; afternoon, everybody. If I could start with Keystone, please the &#x2013; the timeframe seems a little bit delayed, I guess, from the first quarter, second quarter we were originally thinking. And I guess I wanted to touch on both the EBITDA guidance that was given for Keystone in 2010 prior &#x2013; from the analyst meeting, as well as Greg, I wanted to go back to your statement on the capitalized interest. I just wanted to make sure I understood exactly what you were seeing there, which is, I guess, in short, that the interest is going to continue to be capitalized until, I guess, that Phase I, reaches full commercial operation. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's correct. Maybe Russ, you'd like to speak to the timing and then I'll talk to those other two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the timing front, we're continuing as planned. It's moving as quickly through the start-up phase as we had hoped, we've got about a million barrels in tankage right now and we'll commence line filling over the next week or two. We should have the line full within about 100 or so days, and then we'll be able to start ramping up throughput through to &#x2013; the end of the year. So, we're probably delayed by a few weeks here, Carl, but it's not substantial, I guess, from our perspective, in terms of the start-up problems that we anticipated and the kinds of activities that are going on. We're moving along the track that we thought it would be moving on. We'd set up this first year under these interim contracts. As you're aware, our long-term contracts don't kick in until the beginning of next year. So we kind of anticipated we'd have these start-up issues. But as I said, we do have about a million barrels in tankage and we'll start line filling here in the next week or so. So, we're into &#x2013; as I said, end of Q2, we'll be operational.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to comment on your two questions, one was EBITDA. So, obviously, if things move back a little bit, I think at Investor Day we were looking at something in the $150 million range on the contracted volumes. And as we finalize what the in-service date as we work through any start-up issues, that will, of course, be pushed back a little bit in &#x2013; and therefore, decrease pretty much proportionately with the change in time as we get closer to in-service.</p>
          <p>With regard to capitalized interest, until we're substantially complete and capable of running the pipeline at its full productive capacity, we've determined that we will continue to capitalize the interest, and that will largely offset any reduced EBITDA over that. So, for that same period where we're ramping up, and therefore, not collecting EBITDA, we're capitalizing the EBITDA and capitalizing the interest. So, reducing capital expenditure with the EBITDA that's being generated during start-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No &#x2013; I appreciate that clarification, and I'll jump back in queue here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Carl.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Bob Hastings of Canaccord. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sorry, just to stay on that for a minute, so the net result &#x2013; you said it was &#x2013; we should be adjusting just by a few weeks, three weeks or something? Looked a little longer than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would say that &#x2013; I would say we're around probably six to eight weeks kind of outside of where we thought we were in at the &#x2013; the third, fourth quarter of last year in terms of our time &#x2013; we're probably out &#x2013; between six and eight weeks, something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you. And Greg, what are you capitalizing the interest debt, what's the rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We capitalize it our average long-term rate, which is around 7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is that moving from quarter-to-quarter &#x2013; would that &#x2013; would it have been averaged last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's a fairly large amount of debt out there, so as we make additional investments, or issue more debt, it doesn't really move around much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good. Thank you. And you'll be using that at all your projects beyond Keystone as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All the Power projects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because that's my two questions, I'll go back. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Harry Mateer of Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, guys. Just looking for a sense &#x2013; to the extent you can provide us with more color on timing of potential financing here. I know your cash balance has been worked down from a very high level to a little under $1 billion, and it looks like you outspent cash flow during the last quarter by roughly a billion as well, so when you think about financing plans over the next couple of quarters, do you plan to hit up your bank lines first, or are you considering a possible near-term debt issuance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we've showed in the last few years that we're opportunistic, and we have our shelf prospectuses in place, and we're in a position to move fairly quickly when we see windows in the market. So, we'll just monitor that. We do have &#x2013; got lines in place, we put the new U.S. $1 billion credit facility in place. So, we have the flexibility to increase those revolvers, and look for the rate timing on debt, and then of course, always look for the right timing on subordinated capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, in terms of your capital structure, you mentioned you see room to issue about 3 billion of term debt without materially changing your capital structure, but how do you think about that in relation to potential hybrid security issuance, as well, because there is some debt component associated with that, right? Even if you have 50% equity credit, that means there's also 50% debt associated with it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, how do you think about sizing that as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we look at the overall capital picture. And we can't just look at balance sheet metrics, we also have to look at our cash flow &#x2013; the interest coverage and cash flow to total debt. And so, we look at balancing the subordinated capital with the debt. As you say, you do get 50% equity treatment on the hybrid, but it sits on your balance sheet as debt. And it's U.S. debt, which is really positive in helping us balance our U.S. asset gap. So, we look quite favorably on that type of an instrument, because of the U.S. dollar exposure. So, we'll continue to monitor that market. Right now, we're just waiting for the rating agencies to come back and determine how they're going to treat hybrids going forward, and we'd expect to hear on that in the next couple of months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and during the construction period for Keystone, you're right around five times debt-to-EBITDA right now. Is that a number you're pretty comfortable with for the time being? You don't want to go above that during the construction build-out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We look at it on an overall portfolio basis for the company as we look at what our debt structure is like, and we'll just be prudent as we manage the overall ratios going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But there is no debt-to-EBITDA target you have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We don't drive to a particular target for debt-to-EBITDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Matthew Akman of Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Greg, I was just wondering if there's increased exposure to the U.S.-Canadian dollar exchange rate? Obviously, the U.S. pipeline EBITDA moves down as the Canadian dollar appreciates, but interest expense moves down as well. It just looks to me like perhaps the EBITDA is moving down a little bit more than the interest expense, so what's the latest update on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I guess when we look at the U.S. exposure, it's obviously increasing. We're over $12 billion of assets now in the U.S. So, as we manage two exposures. One's the income exposure, the income statement, and the other one's the balance sheet exposure of the asset gap. So, as the cash flow moves around, the short-term hedging we're doing, which is basically rolling month-to-month forward, is adjusted. So, we do have natural hedges for a significant portion of that. And then, that would be &#x2013; about 80% of it is naturally hedged by interest payments. So, then we have that other 20% exposure in the $100 million range. And we've managed that through derivatives. And we ramp those up and down as we see the EBITDA unfolding through changes in commodity prices, and other impacts to our U.S. cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we should not be seeing a significant earnings impact from changes in the C dollar-U.S. dollar exchange rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. There's a bit of a lag, of course, as you're rolling. But generally, we'll try and balance that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. I just have one follow-up question, which is on the Pipeline business. I don't know if you guys are going to disclose the volumes on your Pipelines in the fourth quarter. But I was interested in the volume on the main line in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> We'll see if we can get that for you, Matthew. In the annual, we will disclose the total volumes for the year on all of our systems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Glenn's just looking for that. So, we can certainly try and follow up with you on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Those were all my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Matthew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Ted Durbin of Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, a question for you on the New York City capacity markets. With Poletti retiring, how are you thinking about where the pricing is going there? You've heard maybe there might be a change to the calculation for CONE. Maybe just talk about that market a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So, looking at the price, with Poletti off, as we had anticipated, we saw a very significant run-up in the value for capacity in Zone J for February. And we would obviously expect to see that continue moderated, perhaps modestly, by just very minor reductions in demand in the Zone J area. With respect to the calculation of CONE, that's an ongoing issue, and all kinds of parties have lots of views on that. But we're not anticipating anything very significant or material coming out of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks. And then, just, the next question is a little bit more big picture. But if you think about the Keystone Gulf Coast Expansion and &#x2013; and for the NABE you've got a tough refining environment in the U.S. And you've got &#x2013; quality differentials are down. And you've had some shipper complaints on the competitor pipeline. How are you thinking about the need for the pipeline? We're in a little bit of different environment then maybe when you first conceived of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We continue to have conversations with our shippers with respect to the timing and need. And as I've said before, pretty much all of the capacity that's on the Keystone expansion system has been spoken for by refiners who are replacing crudes from other locations, even though margins are down, whether we use a Canadian barrel or a Venezuelan barrel, unfortunately the margins are tight for them. We feel for them, but they are still moving forward with replacing those crudes with Canadian crudes; they have long-term contracts for supply. And on the producer side of things, again, the volumes that we expect to be moving on the Keystone system are either flowing today, or will be flowing by the time Keystone starts up, and those two things are being linked together. The first phase obviously is to Wood River, and ConocoPhillips is visibly trying to get their refinery ready for the crude oil that's going to come. We expect that to be early in 2011 here. And in the Gulf Cost, the same thing is happening with our contracted customers.</p>
          <p>So, from our perspective, nothing has really changed in the environment. Actually on the positive side, going forward, we've seen, with higher oil prices, a number of projects get put back on the slate. The Total-Conoco project, Suncor project, the Imperial Exxon Cold Lake project. We've seen a number of things move forward in this environment over and above what we saw at the end of &#x2013; the middle of 2009 when the market totally moved downwards. So, I'd say that we're optimistic, and nothing's really changed on our front with respect to movements of crude and the utilization that we expect to get out of the Keystone expansion in the Gulf Cost.</p>
          <p>Longer-term, there'll be excess production in Canada, and we need to move that production to a new market and the logical market to move that crude to is the Gulf Coast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Robert Kwan of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just coming back to Keystone, to make sure I'm clear, the modest push back in the start-up, that just impacts the interim contracts, there's no impact on the guidance that you gave for 2011 with the full contracts coming into place?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think as long as everything goes as planned, and we get to full operations towards the end of the year, then those long-term contracts will kick in. And the EBITDA will move up into that 6 to $700 million range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I can just ask about Western Power on the Alberta hedge side, you're pretty close to where you historically would be hedged for the current year. As you look out to 2011, if the curve stays down where it is, which really isn't that different from where the spot price is, should we be expecting to add any hedges, or are you just happy to keep the exposure high going into 2011, with the hedge level that you've got right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When I look at the forwards in the Alberta market, and I think that's where you're getting at, I mean &#x2013; I look at these prices as unsustainable in the medium to long term. So, from the incentive to add more hedges, we'll always consider contracting forward a month or two, and if we saw attractive opportunities longer term, we would consider that. But we probably are not as motivated to be selling a lot of power forward at these very low prices right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you consider buying back any of your hedges?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, we would definitely consider that. I think particularly, I'd be &#x2013; I think it is possible that 2009 could remain reasonably depressed. But 2010 and 2011, we actually hit an all-time peak demand in Alberta over the winter, and we haven't added a lot of generation capability. So, when I look at those forward prices for '11 and '12, those look to me like they're pretty attractive levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Great. Thanks a lot. Thanks, Hal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Andrew Kuske of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon. More of a big picture question for Hal, and really, when you look out beyond 2012, and you've done really the lion's share and the bulk of your CapEx program and you look across the American map, you've got a pretty big footprint as it is, but do you really look around and think you're lacking a geographic footprint in a specific area or business line that you'd like to add when you look out over a period of time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Andrew, I don't think we would see that we're lacking anything. It's more a question of where we would see significant opportunity to grow. We think that the Northern buildout potential around our existing Alberta System, bringing more gas into the Alberta hub, is pretty attractive, both for our company and the market longer term.</p>
          <p>I know everybody is very excited about shale gas these days, and we're certainly well-positioned for that with Groundbirch, Montney and Horn River. So, I expect we'll continue to invest fairly significantly to bring more of that volume into the system. But we also remain enthused about the Alaska and Mackenzie projects. The challenge for North American producers replacing annual decline is a huge challenge. We essentially reinvent the gas producing side of the business every five years. Most of the gas on production today will be gone five years from now.</p>
          <p>And so, we see the industry continually moving around, figuring out ways to replace that decline, and we do believe in the coming decade that both Mackenzie and Alaska will be part of that. So those are pretty big opportunities for us. Right now what we need to do is proceed cautiously, not spend money that can be deferred until later, and try to keep those two projects moving forward at reasonable cost, and we're comfortable with the way that's going.</p>
          <p>On the oil side, our whole strategy is focused around the oil sands, and we believe that oil sands will be an attractive source of supply throughout North America. Today there are some concerns about the so-called dirty oil issue. We think, as the facts get out about the relative dirtiness or non-dirtiness of oil sands versus any other oil, we think that there will be a greater appreciation for the benefits of supply within the continent here. And we look forward to moving more of that oil sands production to North American markets, possibly to offshore markets, but we just think the North American market is the best market for oil in the world, and that's the one that we're focused on.</p>
          <p>Power gen, it's a very big business. And we have about &#x2013; approaching 12,000 megawatts right now, which makes us a good mid-sized player, but there's lots of room for us to grow two or three times beyond that. The largest players in North America would be roughly at the 50,000 megawatt generating size, and we'd see some good running room for us to grow in a number of those areas.</p>
          <p>So, I think a good case to be made for sticking to the core strategies in gas transmission, gas storage, oil pipelining, power generation, and looking in power at further growth in wind and high-voltage transmission. Those will be the areas that I think we're focused on for the next &#x2013; for the decade ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I may just ask a follow-up, and a bit more precise, as it relates to Northern Natural Gas, and say, specifically in relation to Alaska. Can you just give us a little bit of color around the relationship with Exxon. Did they just have an unbelievable amount of resources as far as people, financial resources, et cetera? And how do you manage the relationship in dealing with them on a project which they could put on the back burner or accelerate at any point in time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on &#x2013; like, Alaska is a huge project. And it would be a very difficult thing if we didn't have a well understood and constructed relationship with Exxon. That is not a relationship that came together overnight. We've worked with Exxon for six or seven, eight years on the Mackenzie project. We've developed our understanding of each other's ways of doing things with the work that we've done on Mackenzie, and with the very challenging regulatory things that we've had to deal with on Mackenzie. I'd characterize it as, Exxon and TransCanada are two companies that have great respect for each other. We bring a lot of experience, and some very current hands-on experience in the construction of large diameter pipelines.</p>
          <p>The North Central Corridor project in Alberta, 330 kilometers roughly, a 42-inch diameter pipe, that is a challenging winter construction project, probably the closest analogy to building on the Alaska right-of-way that you'd find anywhere in North America today. And we've had a great result there, the TransCanada team has brought that very large project in under budget, significantly under budget, and ahead of schedule.</p>
          <p>So, those are the kind of things that we bring to the partnership, ExxonMobil is contributing a lot to the gas processing plant design side. And we've never put ourselves out as the leading partner on the process plant side, they're very much in the lead there, but it's a project that we're pursuing together. And we think Exxon is the best possible partner for that project, they're the largest holder of gas reserves on the North Slope, and they're the operator of Point Thomson, which is going to be a pivotal field in the whole bringing of Alaska gas to market business. So, so far, so good, but it's a big project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Linda Ezergailis from TD Newcrest. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I guess, maybe I'll start with a Power question. Volumes were down a little bit in Alberta, which I guess isn't surprising given the environment there, but when do you expect those volumes to pick up in terms of sales, and are you seeing any volume decreases along other parts of your business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Linda, it's Alex. It's interesting, I mean, volumes were down to some degree &#x2013; a very modest degree, I guess, you could call it, some demand impacts. But I think a lot more of it was availability and bidding behavior with respect to the assets. We've already seen demand in Alberta appears to be, for the most part, recovered. So, that isn't an ongoing issue for us. Obviously, I think other jurisdictions are taking a little bit longer to recover, but we don't see Alberta demand as a significant problem. We are going to lose one of Alberta's coal plants that's scheduled to shut down on March 31, which I think will further sop up any supply-demand sloppiness that's going on there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I guess across your other businesses, I guess, we'll see some of the Pipeline volumes in your annual tomorrow, but can you maybe comment on that? Just broadly, if there was any declines in volumes, even in your Canadian plants which &#x2013; or Canadian pipes, which aren't affected by volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; I think on the Canadian side, our first quarter volumes will be down year-over-year as they've been all year. So the fourth quarter, I don't think will be any change from that. That's impacted throughput on our U.S. deliveries out of Canada, probably most impacted would be Northern Border, but volumes has shifted around based on market demand. GTN was actually &#x2013; flowed a lot of volume in the fourth quarter. Great Lakes was about close to where we were last year, maybe down just slightly. So, most of it emanates from the decline we've talked about before in the Western Sedimentary Basin. And we didn't see any increase in supply in the fourth quarter that would have offset that. So, yeah, I think you could take a look at what happened in the third quarter and it'd be approximately the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Linda, I'd add &#x2013; it's how &#x2013; I'd add to that &#x2013; we have seen drilling rig utilization pick up. We have seen a lot of activity in the shales, but it underscores or corroborates what people were predicting a year ago. And we are hopefully going to see some positive changes in the Alberta royalty regime. We're certainly seeing land sales in Alberta pick up quite dramatically, as people start poking around in Alberta, looking for shale along the lines of Horn River and Montney, although probably on a smaller scale.</p>
          <p>So, I think there are some very encouraging signs in the two to three to five year outlook, but we do anticipate continuing low throughputs and continuing difficulties in the total for the next couple of years. Beyond that, we think we do see the Western Canada Basin stabilizing as shale starts to backfill some of the decline on the conventional side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Linda, it's Glenn, just to provide a couple of those numbers, and as we said, they will be published in our annual MD&amp;A. On the mainline, we're looking at 2030 Bcf for the year, which is just down slightly from 2173 last year and that's about 469 in the quarter. Alberta, we're looking at 3538 for the year, or 886 for the quarter. ANR, 1575 for the year, or 376 for the quarter, and those are obviously the three biggest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thank you. Now, just a clean-up question on your expense side. There was a mention of a drop in your Bruce lease expenses. How much &#x2013; what was the order of magnitude for that, and for how long?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it reflects an adjustment for the year. It's Glenn here. It reflects an adjustment for the year &#x2013; I don't think we're in a position to be giving out the exact numbers, but it represents approximately $0.02.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's likely a one-time item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it depends on, as we've disclosed it, it's based on the annual stock price in Ontario versus the threshold amount in the contract, and so we've looked at that each year, but this reflects for '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, another expense you have is your Alaska development expenses, how much will be reimbursed versus what you're expensing and what run rate might we expect over the next couple of years for that expense line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that the &#x2013; what you're seeing in terms of expense for the year is our share, so none of that would be reimbursable. We expect to probably stand an amount close to that in 2010, and then I would see the number post-2010 dependant upon what happens in the open season outcome.</p>
          <p>As we've said before, our cost sharing mechanism with the State at the current time is 50% for the project, and 50% for the State, and once we get to the end of the open season, that changes to 90% State, 10% the project. And within the project, we're sharing those costs with ExxonMobil. So, I think 2010, you can expect to see a number that's approximately the same. I really can't say at this point in time what 2011 looks like until after we see the open season results, and once we know what that looks like, and where the project's going, we'll be able to share with you where our expenses are going to go beyond that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to clarify, the amount that we have expenses rest of that share but that is net of any recoveries or expected recoveries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Linda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Pierre Lacroix from Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks very much. Just question on Bruce, are you keep &#x2013; you keep doing the refurbishment of Unit 3 and 4, and now you're talking about 2018. Can you maybe give us some perspective on what kind of production profile and net expense that you'll need to do in 2012 to 2015 period in order to reach that goal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I'll try to give some color on that. There isn't significant work that is required to be done in terms of capital on Unit 4. Unit 3, in order to get that extended life, we're going to take two relatively significant outages. The first outage is &#x2013; might already be taking place, but it's about an eight-week outage, and it was commencing right around now. And then there is a &#x2013; one more outage that will be done in 2011, which is about a 110-day outage. And there is some capital associated with it, but we're not talking in the $100 million range. This is mostly labor that's required. And at the end of those two outages, it is our expectation that Unit 3 should be in &#x2013; put in a position where it can operate safely till the end of 2018.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So, it means that what we can see right now in terms of plant availability for Bruce A, is it something that you'll be able to maintain through 2010 and '11?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if &#x2013; I'm going from memory here, but I think that we're probably going to do as well or better on overall availability for the A units in 2010. And obviously, it would be slightly worse because of a longer outage in 2011. You can &#x2013; those two outage numbers are good numbers for you to think about, eight weeks, and 110 days for the second one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Craig Sheer from Toy Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I think during the Q&amp;A, you had mentioned that you could possibly see over time increasing two or three times your megawatts in the IPP space. I wonder if you can comment about the regions in North America or elsewhere, and the fuel types that might be of greatest interest to you, and whether you'd kind of be thinking about individual assets, or considering a more rapid kind of corporate level M&amp;A to achieve that scale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. It's Hal here. My comment was really around the five to 10-year outlook for the company. Over the past 10 years, we've built a 12,000-megawatt power businesses essentially from scratch. We did have about a 500-megawatt position back then held through our Power LP, but we've divested that to other people. So, if you can think about it, we've grown from under 500 megawatts to almost 12,000 in a decade. And I think that we could replicate that kind of growth in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>I did mention that the largest power companies in North America have about 50,000 megawatts. And so I was providing that number as the upside target that we might get to. When we look at different kinds of megawatts, so the thing that we're always interested in is where does it sit on the cost curve, and how fundamentally attractive is it in the market in which we operate. And even when we build contracted plants under low-risk contracts to TransCanada, we still like to build plans that are fundamentally very attractive. And so a good example is the Portlands Energy Centre in Toronto, which serves a really vital need in the urban core of Toronto, and we would expect that plant to run very well whether it's covered by contracts of not. Of course, it is covered by contracts for the first 20 years under our deal with the OPA.</p>
          <p>So when it comes to gas-fired plants, we like to build essential infrastructure that's covered by those long-term contracts. When it comes to the other forms of baseload power, obviously we're interested in nuclear. We're one of North America's most successful wind developers.</p>
          <p>We look at a number of gas peaking operations, like you're seeing in the Coolidge market down in Arizona. In terms of regions, Ontario, Quebec, New York, New England is a region that has received the bulk of our power investments in the last few years. And we expect that will continue and that's a very large market region on both the Canadian and U.S. sides of the border. We like the desert states, Arizona and the states adjacent to it, Nevada. And we would continue to look at opportunities there, including the high-voltage DC opportunity that you'll see in our Zephyr project.</p>
          <p>So those are the regions. Of course, Alberta is an important market to us, but we've got a pretty big position here in Alberta, and we don't want to overgrow the market, so we'd certainly look at opportunities here, but I think that it's going to be the Eastern Canadian, Northeast U.S., and possibly a few other market regions in the U.S. where you'll see us grow.</p>
          <p>Acquisition opportunities are always interesting to us, but at this particular time, we're very focused on completing the build out of our multibillion dollar program in the power gen space, and notably, completing the refurbishment of Bruce Nuclear. Those would be our priorities today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you see a meaningful number of retirements of coal-fired generation North America providing opportunity for the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've been very involved in discussions related to carbon dioxide emissions, and the negotiations leading up to the Copenhagen Summit. And I've got &#x2013; my personal view is that the coal-fired plants will by and large continue to run till the end of their normal life, and then people will face a tough question, do they spend money to refurbish or extend the life of a coal-fired plant, or do they shut it down at that point, and replace with something else. I think that's the question that power companies are going to face, that regulators are going to face, and that the various agencies focused on CO2 are going to have to face.</p>
          <p>One thing we know for sure is that the alternatives are probably going to be a lot more expensive than running an existing coal plant. And in some ways, that's where we see the opportunity for TransCanada. We're not a large coal operator, we hold significant coal-fired output entitlements here in Alberta. But we're not a large operator of coal plants, we don't operate any at all to be perfectly clear. And so we see all of this as an interesting situation going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Steven Paget from FirstEnergy. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. My first question is regarding Great Lakes. That is a subject of a FERC hearing. If you could comment on that, particularly as it seems that going to south central Ontario via the Canadian Mainline in Great Lakes is about the same &#x2013; is roughly the same price. So that would seem to indicate that Great Lakes is relatively &#x2013; is competing against the Mainline, but that has implications for the ROE, which is the angle FERC is taking and saying that the ROE is difficult. So if you could comment on the status of the hearing, that would be great &#x2013; or investigation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Basically the FERC initiated a Section 5 rate case. They're stated reason for doing was that it appeared that the pipeline was making excess returns, because on the FERC Form 2s, which is the accounting reporting, and it appeared that we were basically making a return that was in excess of 20%. The first step in the process for us is to file our cost of revenue study, and we did that in the last couple of weeks. And I think it's &#x2013; our costs as you can probably see in that study are justified, and don't lead you to the conclusion that we're making excess returns. The FERC has yet to respond to that filing, but that would be the next step, is the FERC then responds to that filing, puts in place what's called talk sheets, which is really, in my view, the start of the negotiation process.</p>
          <p>Where we'd like to go with the process is to negotiate a settlement with our shippers, and that has already begun &#x2013; our discussions have already begun, because as I said, the goalposts have to get set out there in the marketplace, one being our cost of revenue study. The second is the FERC's position. And then from there, the parties can start a negotiation process.</p>
          <p>I believe, and this is just my opinion, but I believe that the FERC is encouraging a rate settlement or a negotiated settlement, as opposed to a litigated outcome as well. I think that process has worked well in the past, whereby shippers and the pipeline companies get together, and settle on things like rates and terms and conditions, as opposed to moving to a full-blown litigation. And that's where we're focused right now.</p>
          <p>So that's about all I can tell you at this point, Steve, is that we're &#x2013; we want to get a settlement done, but we have to get the preliminary work out the way first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for that, Russ. My next question is for Alex. And looking, just looking at U.S. coal generation, there's about 50 to 60 gigawatts, that is pretty small coal at 250 megawatts or lower, and greater than 30 years old. But most of it seems to be located east of the Mississippi River, and I'm wondering how attractive could it be for TransCanada to replace some of that old, small coal out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean &#x2013; we would think that opportunity would be very attractive. I think we have developed a great deal of expertise in building large-scale gas-fired power plants. And I think most of that coal that gets retired in the Eastern U.S. &#x2013; although people are always interested in renewables, I think overwhelmingly, the bulk of that generation is going to replaced by gas-fired generation, and we are seeing a lot of utilities are &#x2013; have been moving down the path of RFPs. Kind of not dissimilar to the kind of structure you see in Ontario. So, I mean, to the extent that there was an opportunity for us to use that expertise and that competitive advantage, and back it up with long-term contracts, I think we'd be quite interested in those opportunities, Steven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Those were my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Carl Kirst from BMO Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, just a clean-up question if I could. It looked like the Bruce B forward hedging levels were a little bit lower than what was discussed on the last quarter, and I guess I just wanted to confirm that. And if that is the case, if we did have a decline in 2010 and 2011 were any of those positions monetized, or what happened there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of those contracts were just rolling off at the end of their &#x2013; at the end of their term, Carl. I think we have considered buying some of those back, but I don't believe we've done so in a material manner at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, maybe just a follow-up with respect to some of the comments that were made about the Alberta volumes and the tariff. Obviously, a difficult situation over the next two years, but with what was struck here at the end of December, getting some of the underage put what was in effect into the rate base, was that kind of the model that, if there are stresses on the system, that is generally going to be followed, I guess, over the next two years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We'll have to negotiate that with our shippers, Carl. But I think that the accruals that what we use to achieve a settlement with our shippers for the 2010 totals will be similar to going forward. I think that obviously, we're going to do a more detailed approach. What we have told the industry is that that we would move to get them a proposal by the end of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>And then we would look to negotiate with them over the next four to five months with the hope of having something in a filing position by the end of Q3 and into Q4 for approval in &#x2013; for 2011. Now, that might be just for 2011, it might be for 2011, 2012. And part of it will be based on what people's forecast of throughput are going to be. And as Hal mentioned earlier, we've seen a fair bit of reason for optimism around the Western Sedimentary Basin here recently with land sales. And as you saw, the contracted level that we have put in place for Horn River went up in the fourth quarter. Now those volumes won't come till launch till later. But obviously those will be factors that impact where we set our totals for those years.</p>
          <p>But generally speaking, I think what we'd like to do is find a way where we can smooth our way through to the time where we see volumes starting to come back on the system. And I think that's generally what our shippers are looking forward to as well. But as I said, that negotiation will get underway as we put our proposal out at the end of the quarter, and then spend the time with our shippers discussing the various aspects of that proposal that they think can stick, and those that they don't think can stick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as the specific numbers go that are disclosed, we'll take a look at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Petro Panarites from CIBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. My question is for Alex, beyond the closure of Poletti, what are you seeing in terms of capacity additions to the New York market over these next several years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is one project, which is a 300-megawatt project associated with the Linden Power Plant. It is &#x2013; it &#x2013; basically it's just an inter &#x2013; the Linden Power Plant is in the PJM market but it's connected electrically to the Zone J market, and what they've done is they have reconfigured or rebuilt the transmission between the two nodes. And we think that will bring in about 300 more megawatts. We actually thought it would be in by now. We thought it would come in November, we haven't seen it show up; we would probably expect it to show up some time over the next six months into Zone J. That's something that we had in mind at the time we acquired Ravenswood.</p>
          <p>The other &#x2013; there is another cable project, and I'm trying &#x2013; we can get, sorry, the Hudson Cable Project, and that &#x2013; my recollection is that when we &#x2013; that was another one that we had assumed was coming in. And that seems to be a project that continues to be delayed quarter-by-quarter. So, I don't see that coming in any time in short order, but if that one comes in, that would be about another 300 megawatts. And as far as I can see, I think that's it for material capacity additions for Zone J.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the changes in capacity rates net of whatever might come on in terms of new supply, is anything there attractive enough to entice you to pursue greater expansion at Ravenswood? Or any updates on your expansion plans there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We've continued to advance our expansion thoughts at Ravenswood. We're in the middle of doing a study to determine exactly what the options are in terms of capacity additions on the site, the pros and cons of various options. But we do think there are some interesting &#x2013; there's a couple of interesting shorter-term opportunities we have that have to do with &#x2013; dealing with this A House facility, which is a lease facility, we have with ConEd onsite. It actually is a steam plant that sends steam across the river to ConEd, and we think there's probably a shorter-term opportunity to do a deal where our Unit 40 combined gas plant actually produces that waste heat and steam.</p>
          <p>So we think there's an incremental opportunity there, and then we do think there are longer-term opportunities either to put in place peaking or combined cycle opportunities on the Ravenswood site. And that would probably, once again, kind of be in the two to five-year timeframe that we'd see those opportunities arising.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Bob Hastings of Canaccord. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes. Since you started Kibby, we've seen some PPAs actually signed in that market from the local utilities. Wondering if, as that market transitions, whether you've been able to contract it up, or if you have that opportunity, what you're going to do there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Bob, we've sold a significant amount of the RECs forward already to the utilities at quite attractive rates. And we have sold &#x2013; I think we're probably around 30% of the energy we've sold over longer-term power purchase agreements to local utilities. So, that is definitely within our intention, but I mean, we &#x2013; so far, we're quite happy with the contracting we've been able to do, and particularly with respect to the RECs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there's nothing more that you can do at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we'll keep marketing, particularly as I said, I mean, the RECs, there is a really robust market in New England for the Renewable Energy Credits, and they &#x2013; frankly, more liquid right now than the energy market. So that is an area that we're going to really pursue with respect to the expansion of Kibby. But we will also &#x2013; our goal would be to knock down some of that merchant capacity with PPAs over the next year or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So can you give us some details or some kind of guidance on how many &#x2013; what proportion of the RECs have been sold, and kind of pricing or anything like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, I won't tell you what we sold them at, but what I would say is that the prices for RECs in that market have kind of been anywhere from 20 to around $50 a megawatt hour. And we've sold them in that range. Sorry, does that &#x2013; was that helpful?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just as a proportion, have you sold half or -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Yeah. I think we're probably at around 50 or 60%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, and moving back to Alberta, and I apologize I recall the fact for a second but I may have missed this . But Alberta demand was, I guess, flattish in the fourth quarter, you mentioned it might have been down, but I noticed that some of your coal-fired capacity you've been buying was down 11% in the quarter. Can you go through that a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think a lot of that is availability from the operators. Some of it would be offer strategy, and just related to demand in the market and power prices. Nothing &#x2013; there's nothing really material, that would be behind that reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but there's no &#x2013; it's down 11%, and I just &#x2013; that should have been &#x2013; I would assume was always profitable in that market, wasn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  The next question is from Steven Paget from FirstEnergy. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question, just as you work on the tolls on the Canadian Mainline, would you consider taking part of it out of General Shipper Service and contracting it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not a model that we're considering right now is &#x2013; if that opportunity arose, where there was a large, incremental body of volume that wanted to sign a long-term contract, obviously that'd be something that we can consider. But right now that large incremental volume doesn't exist, but obviously maybe going through an open season might be something that we could try. But it's not at the top of our list right now, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now open the telephone lines for media questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Justin Amoah from Argus Media. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I was wondering &#x2013; I have two questions. I was wondering if you can just explain a little bit more in detail, why the start of commercial operations on Keystone is being delayed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a number of both regulatory and permitting and start-up issues. It's a very, very complex project, as Hal outlined in his opening statement. 8,500 people and there are a number of activities going on. And to be behind by six to eight weeks, in my view, isn't a material amount. As we anticipated this, we said the long-term contracts don't kick in until the beginning of next year, and we put in place an interim contract structure to allow us to have this time period to commission the facility, and wrap it up to full volumes.</p>
          <p>Over the next few weeks here, we need to put approximately 9 million barrels a day &#x2013; or 9 million barrels in total of oil in the facility, which in and of itself, is an enormous amount of crude oil over a short period of time; have to test all the pumps to make sure that they all work. As said, there's 39 pump stations that we have to run crude through, and make sure that they all work. So, it is just a big, big complex job, and within the timing schedule, we're not out by that far. We're within, as we said, a couple of months of where we thought that we would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And my second question is, has TransCanada gauged the potential impact on costs, as a result of new measures being proposed in the U.S., such as the bill in South Dakota to remove tax incentives for crude pipelines. And a bill being proposed in Nebraska that would require pipelines to pay annual fees as compensation for affected community members and land owners?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, those are major issues that we not only track as the Keystone pipeline, but our broader scale across the U.S. And as you move into an environment of deficit financing, whether that's federal government, state government, or local governments, there's always a desire for increased tax revenue from those large industries that pass through their facilities. I guess our view would be that Keystone is a pipeline that moves crude oil across both international borders and state borders. And therefore, is in the business of interstate commerce. And therefore, should be exempt from any state-like taxes for throughput. And obviously that will be our position that we take in the regulatory proceedings and legal proceedings on that front, both as TransCanada Keystone, but also as a larger pipeline operator in the United States will take a position in those proceedings. This isn't the first time that we've seen it, and I expect it won't be the last time that we see it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if those taxes do indeed come into effect, is there any estimate as to how much it will cost the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way our pipelines work for the most part is through a cost pass through. So, to the extent that taxes increase, we would normally pass through those costs to our customers. And as I said, that's the crux of our argument, because this is interstate commerce, not a state commercial activity. And therefore, customers outside of the state would end up paying the bills for no direct benefit from the state. So, obviously, those customers are going to take a large interest in these proceedings as well, both the producers and refining customers. And on the gas side, downstream LDCs and upstream gas producers as well. These are pretty significant precedents that folks would like to set, but as I said, they haven't been successful in the past, and it'd be our hope that they're not successful going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> There are no further questions registered at this time. I would now like to turn the meeting back over to Mr. Moneta.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much. And I'd just like to take the opportunity to thank all of you for participating this afternoon. We appreciate your interest in TransCanada, and we look forward to talking to you soon. Bye for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference has now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time, and we thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>