<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1226022" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1554</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">David Reid, Non-Executive Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Laurie McIlwee, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Sir Terry Leahy, Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="3">David Reid</participant>
      <participant id="4">Sir Terry Leahy</participant>
      <participant id="5">Laurie McIlwee</participant>
      <participant id="6">Andrew Kasoulis</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jaime Vazquez</participant>
      <participant id="8">James Collins</participant>
      <participant id="9">Matthew Truman</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Kershaw</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone and welcome. Thank you for joining us today. I'd like to start by formally welcoming Laurie McIlwee to his first preliminary results meeting. Laurie's been with Tesco for some nine years now. He has a very strong track record in both finance and in operations as our distribution Director, where he was responsible for transforming our network, a tremendous achievement. His appointment shows once again how careful management succession works in Tesco and I have every confidence he'll do a great job for us as Group Finance Director and take it on from a long line of excellent Finance Directors over the years.</p>
          <p>We've also appointed three strong new Non-Executive Directors in recent months. Jacqueline Tammenoms Bakker, a former Director General at the Ministry of Transport in the Netherlands who's also held senior positions at McKinsey and Shell. Also very well known Patrick Cescau, former CEO of Unilever and Ken Hanna also joins us, a Chairman of Inchcape and former CFO of Cadbury. They bring with them a wealth of international commercial and financial experience and this will further strengthen the Board, and support our plans for the long-term growth of the Group.</p>
          <p>So today we'll follow our usual running order with Laurie covering the financial results, followed by Terry with an update on strategy and we'll then be happy to take your questions.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased to report that despite the extraordinary economic environment we find ourselves in Tesco has once again delivered a good set of results. This demonstrates that Tesco is coping well with the downturn. Despite the challenging conditions around the globe we've remained resilient, and we're growing as fast as any major international retailer. Whilst the downturn has presented many challenges it has also opened up some opportunities.</p>
          <p>As you know, we've made two very significant acquisitions during the year. In South Korea we purchased 36 hypermarkets from E-Land mostly in Seoul, which has now put us in a very strong position to challenge for market leadership in one of our most successful markets. We've also bought the remaining 50% of Tesco Personal Finance from RBS, a move which will enable us to develop our already successful financial services offer towards our objective of becoming a full service retail bank.</p>
          <p>Most of our growth has again been organic. We've opened 9 million square feet of new space this year excluding the acquisition in Korea. In August we announced our entry into India with plans to establish a cash-and-carry operation and a franchise agreement with Trent to support their Star Bazaar hypermarkets, and this complements our entries into China and also the United States and giving us access to another of the world's most important economies.</p>
          <p>Whilst many of our customers are focused on managing their shopping baskets, it's still important to them that we behave responsibly particularly in the communities we serve. We now have a plan for each country and earlier in the year we launched our community promises. These are actively supporting local communities, buying and selling our products responsibly, caring for the environment and giving customers healthy choices and creating good jobs and careers.</p>
          <p>We've made some great progress this year. We've opened our greenest ever store at Cheetham Hill in Manchester with a carbon footprint some 70% smaller than a typical store, bringing our total number of green stores across the globe to 37. And these will be used as blue prints for how we build stores in the future.</p>
          <p>Our work to encourage customers to make greener decisions is going well. Through Green Club card points we've reduced the number of single use carrier bags in the UK by 50% now and we're also finding innovative ways to use Green Club cards elsewhere. For example in Korea they're rewarding customers for cycling to our stores, very healthy.</p>
          <p>I'm also pleased to announce that in the UK we've once again broken our Charity of the Year record with an incredible 6.2 million raised for Marie Curie Cancer Care. Although it was impossible to predict the scale of the global economic slowdown, Tesco is responding well, by adjusting our business to this environment. Our 470,000-strong team are doing a great job, staying close to customers and reacting quickly to their changing needs.</p>
          <p>So I am confident that their hard work will continue as we sensibly press on with our long-term strategy, which I believe will put us in an even stronger position once the economies start to recover. That's all from me, I'll now hand you over to Laurie to take you through the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you David for that warm welcome and good morning everyone. First, I'd like to outline the main financial headlines for the Group. We've delivered solid growth in sales, profit, and earnings in a challenging trading environment. We've continued to invest in our strategy including the acquisitions of TPF and Homever.</p>
          <p>Our productivity program continues to make substantial cost savings and the business is delivering for shareholders with strong earnings growth. This is allowing for good, well-covered dividend growth. We have a strong property-backed balance sheet with no liquidity or refinancing issues. This year we plan to maintain good organic space growth whilst managing our CapEx well below our cash generation.</p>
          <p>I'll now go through the detail of our Group performance. This year has been a 53-week financial year for the UK, Ireland, and the United States and for ease of comparison and where appropriate I'll highlight the 52-week growth rates. Total Group sales for the year ending the 28th of February 2009 were 59.4 billion up 15.1%, and on a 52-week basis sales were up 13.5%. Group trading profit rose by 12.4% to 3.09 billion. Profit is stated after initial trading losses for Fresh &amp; Easy and Homever integration costs. Before these, the Group trading profit rose by 16.1%.</p>
          <p>Group underlying profit before tax was 3.13 billion, up 10% with growth being impacted by an increased interest charge. Group property profits have increased by 26% from 188 million to 236 million this year. Although conditions in the wider property market have deteriorated there remains good appetite for Tesco property and covenants.</p>
          <p>We're in discussions with a view to completing further divestments in the months ahead at attractive yields, and the proceeds from the deals we do this year will be used to pay down our debt. Some 80% of the Group property remains freehold. And we currently estimate the market value of our freehold property assets to be around &#xA3;30 billion.</p>
          <p>Group pre-tax profit is up 5.5%, and the lower growth rate is principally due to the IAS 32 and 39, effects of which move from being a credit of 49 million in 2007 into a debit of 88 million this year. The IAS 32 and 39 Standards relate principally to non-cash mark-to-market adjustments, which can be very volatile.</p>
          <p>Underlying diluted earnings per share were up 7% to 28.92 pence, with good growth despite the exceptionally low tax rate last year linked to the rebate from HMRC. Using a constant tax rate and based on 52-weeks, underlying diluted earnings per share were up 9.7%. The proposed final dividend is 8.39 pence, up 9% and this gives a full year dividend of 11.96 pence, up 9.7%. This is consistent with our policy of growing annual dividend policy in line with underlying diluted EPS on constant tax rates.</p>
          <p>I'm now going to take you through the performance of the UK. Total sales in the UK were up 9.5% to 41.5 billion. Like-for-like sales were 4.3%, new stores contributed 2.7%, the 53rd week added 2.1% and the contribution from TPF was 0.4%.  Ex-petrol, like-for-like was 3% for the year and UK ex-petrol, like-for-like in the last seven weeks of the year was 2.1% or 3.1% ex-VAT. And for the first six weeks of this year like-for-like has improved to 3.4% or 4.4% ex-VAT.</p>
          <p>We've seen inflation in our stores during the year and the falling sterling will ensure that inflation is more prolonged. Offsetting inflation in our business has been the mix effect of customers down-trading. Our physical volumes have however grown well.</p>
          <p>Last year's UK trading profit included the startup costs of Fresh &amp; Easy. This year we are reporting the United States separately within the International segment. So we've restated last year's comparative numbers. UK trading profit was 2.38 billion up 12.7% on a 52-week basis and the UK trading profit was up 10.7%. UK trading margin was 6.2%, an increase of 17 basis points on last year, and this included a small contribution from TPF in the two months since it was consolidated, and I'll come back to this in a moment.</p>
          <p>Increased investment in pricing and promotions and other improvements in the shopping trip were funded from &#xA3;540 million worth of step-change. This has been delivered through long-term productivity projects ranging from energy savings to supply chain initiatives. Apparently distribution did very well. <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Total sales were 17.9 billion, up 30.6% at actual exchange rates and 13.6% at constant rates, and international sales excluding Fresh &amp; Easy and Homever were up 26.7%. International trading profits before Fresh &amp; Easy and the initial losses of Homever integration costs were up 26.6% at actual rates and by 13.3% at constant rates. On this basis, international trading margins were unchanged.</p>
          <p>In Asia sales were 7.6 billion up 29.4% at actual rates and by 19.9% at constant rates. Excluding Homever, sales were up 23.5% at actual rates. Trading profit in Asia rose to 355 million before the effect of consolidating Homever, which was loss making at the acquisition. Trading profit increased by 28.9% at actual rates and 26.2% at constant rates. Margins were strong, driven by good performances in Malaysia and Thailand.</p>
          <p>Helped by favorable exchange rates in Europe sales rose by 29.1% to 10.1 billion, and increased by 6.9% at constant rates. We've seen some deteriorating demand in some Europe markets particularly the Republic of Ireland, the Czech and Slovak Republics. Linked to the economic environment and to an increase in cross-border shopping into neighboring countries and recently we've seen some stabilization in consumer confidence in Europe following the financial shocks of last autumn. Trading profit rose to 496 million, an increase of 24.9% at actual rates and 3.50% at constant rates.</p>
          <p>Fresh &amp; Easy, sales were 208 million with like-for-like sales growth of 30%. At constant exchange rates the trading loss was 123 million. Higher than our guidance at the beginning of the year and this was due to the severity of the economic downturn, but also our decision to maintain and not accelerate our new store openings.</p>
          <p>We're excited about our opportunities in Retail Services and we'll be organizing a dedicated services seminar in the next few months to bring you up to speed with our plans and so that you can meet the team that's actually doing the work. Total retailing services sales we 3.4 billion, up 11% on last year and trading profits were 460 million, up 21%. We're delighted to have completed the acquisition of Tesco Personal Finance in December, but clearly it's been a turbulent time for the financial services sector. But TPF has a high quality book, no toxic assets and a strong liquidity.</p>
          <p>The bad debt experience is better than the industry average and the acquisition has allowed us to make even more prudent provisions for bad debts going forward. In these accounts TPF is included as a joint venture for 50 weeks to the 19th of December, and is included for a subsidiary for the 10 weeks to the 28th of February year end. For ease of comparison and to give you a base for your numbers next year we published a TPF pro forma income statement for the year ending February 2009 and you'll find this in the press release. On this basis underlying profits before tax were 244 million.</p>
          <p>Insurance is over 65% of the profits, the remainder of the profits have come from our banking products, mainly credit cards, with a stable income stream from our ATM network. We've had tremendous success with our saving products attracting over 100,000 new customers in the last four months of the year and growing our saving book to over &#xA3;4.5 billion. We turned the year -- we ended the year with a balance sheet in net surplus and we're investing prudently in UK treasury bills and short-term investments.</p>
          <p>TPF is well capitalized; our core tier 1 ratio is 12%. That's significantly better than our banking peer group. We've provided a balance sheet in the press release if you'd like to see more detail. Profits from joint ventures and associates were 110 million up from 75 million last year. And this year's number includes 50 weeks profit from Tesco Personal Finance while it was a joint venture.</p>
          <p>Tax has been charged at 26.7% reflecting the new lower Corporation Tax rate, which came into effect in April 2008. This year we also expect the tax rate to be around 27%. Our net debt rose to 9.6 billion from 6.2 billion a year ago with an increase largely reflecting our capital outlay of 6.6 billion in the year.</p>
          <p>Last July we talked about a target net debt figure of around 8 billion. We said at the time, that this assumes stable sterling and a level of property proceeds. And, of course, we've seen significant depreciation in sterling causing a debt impact of approximately &#xA3;1 billion. We've also been careful to manage the flow of property deals into the market and reducing the levels of proceeds compared to earlier plans.</p>
          <p>And given the strength of our operating cash flow our debt is eminently manageable, but it's higher than I would like. And that's why in the current year we'll bring it back down to approximately 8.5 billion. We'll do this through a combination of lower CapEx and property proceeds and it's of course reliant upon stable exchange rates again and the success of our property sales.</p>
          <p>After the 2 billion bond issue in February, our average debt maturity has moved to 11 years. We have 2.7 billion of undrawn backup liquidity facilities and 75% of our debt is now fixed. The weighted average coupon is 5.6% and we've only 300 million of bonds maturing in this financial year. So we've no liquidity or financing issues.</p>
          <p>Net finance costs have increased to 362 million, which includes the net returns on pension schemes assets and liabilities in addition to the impact of IAS 32 and 39. The underlying interest rate charge has increased to 309 million from 159 million last year and that's driven principally by the increase in net debt.</p>
          <p>Moving on to pensions, we're proud to continue offering an award-winning defined-benefit pension scheme and our staff tell us it's very important to them. To ensure this scheme remains in good health, the trustees determine the funding using prudent actuarial assumptions. The trustees have completed their independent review of funding as part of the triennial valuation and as expected it showed a small deficit of 275 million.</p>
          <p>Following this valuation we agreed to increase the member and company contribution rates to 0.7% of salary, ensuring the scheme remains in a good position. As you know for accounting purposes IFRS requires that we re-value the pension scheme liabilities on our high quality corporate bond yield. The IFRS pension deficit is 1.1 billion after-tax, which is broadly the same as we reported in September.</p>
          <p>Group capital expenditure during the year was 4.7 billion. This was a little ahead of our expectations of up to 4.5 billion due to currency movements. Total international capital rose to 2.1 billion, comprising of 0.9 billion in Europe, 0.9 billion in Asia and 0.3 billion in the US. Total capital expenditure in the UK rose to 2.6 billion from 2.3 billion last year, and mainly as a result of the purchase of a small number of trading stores from a competitor and investment in new mixed-use development schemes in the UK. This year we expect Group capital expenditure to be around 3.5 billion.</p>
          <p>We can reduce CapEx whilst maintaining good growth in organic space for two main reasons. First the bulge in the UK CapEx we've seen over the last couple of years has gone through, and doesn't need to be repeated. Second, in this environment we can buy for less. Our CapEx can go further because site, build, and fit-out costs are all falling.</p>
          <p>Operating cash flow was 5 billion, up from 4.1 billion last year and 0.3 billion higher than CapEx. This increase is due to improved profits from our core operations and a 0.6 billion improvement in working capital, partly as a result of the improvement in stock controls. Adjusting for new investment TPF and Homever this year our Group return on capital employed was slightly up at 13%.</p>
          <p>In summary, we've delivered a solid performance both in the UK and overseas and we're confident that good profit growth will continue in the current year, particularly with the benefits of our two acquisitions coming through. Thank you. I'll now hand over to Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Laurie, and good morning everyone. Well these results demonstrate that Tesco has again made good progress despite facing into some strong headwinds. Sales and profits have grown solidly, returns have held up well, and the growth has come from right across the Group.</p>
          <p>Now, I'm pleased about that for several reasons. First, because it shows that our strategy is the right one for sustaining growth even through this downturn. Second, because our businesses are adjusting their models and approach successfully to meet the needs of a different customer, that's one with less money to spend. And third because it underlines the strength of Tesco, that we can do these things, deliver the numbers and yet still carry the substantial investment today in tomorrow's growth, whether it's in Financial Services, China, Korea, or the US.</p>
          <p>It's not been easy, but we've come through in good shape and that's not an accident. I believe we've coped well because we anticipated the challenges and the opportunities and set the business up to tackle both. Getting ahead early and staying ahead on costs finding the necessary investment to help customers spend less, seeing the openings to buy good assets well, these are I think clear evidence of the right approach.</p>
          <p>And going forward, we've got some big self-help projects this year to support our growth. We're doing more on the international buying, we're delivering sizable benefits from recent acquisitions, and we're becoming self-reliant in terms of funding our own expansion to pay down debt and drive returns as Laurie spoke about.</p>
          <p>At times like this, the most important thing for a business like Tesco to do is to stay close to customers, keep them shopping with us, make sure volumes are strong, and I'm pleased to say that's what we're doing. Of course, there is more to do and in some areas we can do better. But I'm confident that this focus will see us through the tough times and ensure that we're even better positioned for when the upturn comes.</p>
          <p>I'll begin my usual update this morning with International, where we've made very good progress overall against the background of weakening demand. Sales increased strongly up by 31% in the year. Of course exchange rates helped particularly in Europe, as did the Homever acquisition in Asia. And profits advanced well, up 22% excluding the US and margins were remarkably resilient despite the short-term effect of acquiring the Korean stores.</p>
          <p>So it's been very pleasing as an overall performance in the year, but the effects of a slowing global economy are now to be seen everywhere. Europe felt the effects earliest and harder actually, they early summer, spring, early summer last year it began in Europe.</p>
          <p>The impact in Asia was delayed, but it's there now, with the export-led countries feeling the strain from global destocking signs. Asia really started to feel it November-December through up until the present time. The US too, particularly in the western former boom states, is dealing with a sharp contraction. There too it really started in a very severe way May last year and then really took a big step-down with the banking crisis in the autumn.</p>
          <p>My message to you is that Tesco is dealing with the obvious challenges this poses for all companies. You can see from today's trading update we're still driving good growth from our international businesses. We're well prepared and we've a strong plan to deliver further growth in sales and in profits this year.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased with our performance across Central Europe. Customer numbers are continuing to grow. Market share growth has actually accelerated. These numbers show this well. They demonstrate how our market positions have been strengthening in all four countries and strategically this is important because others too of course feel the strain. Our resolve to push on through this tough period will see us emerging even stronger.</p>
          <p>In general non-food, has been a tougher market across our network internationally for understandable reasons, but in some areas we've showed what our size and global reach can deliver. For example, clothing sales in Central Europe have been very good, up 11% in a very difficult year there and indeed in the new financial year, the new ranges, sales growth has increased by 25%.</p>
          <p>Progress in Central Europe has been helped by strong results in Hungary. Now you'll remember we had big problems in Hungary there, but our strategy of investing hard in our offer for customers, keeping costs low, expanding our store base, it's given us momentum to grow sales and profits, even through a prolonged, probably three year long now, recession in Hungary. And this will be a model for how we run our European operations during the wider downturn.</p>
          <p>Czech, Slovakia, and particularly Poland, all grew strongly; helped by the growing maturity and profitability of our smaller format stores and they will be the focus of our expansion. In Poland, sales in the Leader Price stores are now up 60% since conversion. In fact our smaller format stores in Poland grew like-for-like actually faster than Biedronka in the fourth quarter, which is quite a turn around.</p>
          <p>Elsewhere in Europe, Ireland did well in a very difficult market, helped by a strong store opening program of course. Thailand achieved another impressive year, against a background of political instability. Our Talad and Express formats grew particularly strongly. We saw a promising first profit from Financial Services there too.</p>
          <p>Growth in Malaysia has again been excellent. And now just seven years since opening our first stores there, we're now highly profitable; market leading business. So we're already the market leader and the fastest growing. The Makro acquisition has been a great success. It's fully integrated now and going forward we can sustain good organic growth; seven large hypermarkets opening this year.</p>
          <p>Introducing Clubcard and Dunnhumby in Malaysia has been a key to sustained success through improved customer insight and we're, gradually as these businesses get to scale, rolling out Clubcard and Dunnhumby in other countries in China, Korea, Ireland as well as pilots in Thailand, Slovakia, Poland and Turkey. So you can see that over the next couple of years Clubcard and Dunnhumby will be a standard part of the package.</p>
          <p>In Japan the already difficult retail market has worsened. But the new team there has made good progress helped by the new benefits from &#x2013; I've got the notes the wrong way around. I was about to tell you that Japan had benefited from the new DC in Dublin. But I won't. I could have said it and you'd have just nodded. Helped by the rollout of our new 24-hour Express stores in Tokyo, Japan.</p>
          <p>China we've begun to push on with faster regional expansion, we're based in three regions now, three of the five, and we're building large freehold shopping centers. And now the first -- they're actually being built now, the first of four of those opened this year, so it's a very, very important year for us in China, and we've got a further 14 of those in the development pipeline. We're looking to involve external investors in sharing the capital required to build such a network of stores, and we believe they will be a model for how to retail profitably in China in the long-term.</p>
          <p>Flicking back through the notes, our Korean business of course, saw record sales and profits growth in the core business and despite the distraction of the integration of the Homever stores. But the Homever store conversions are complete now, they've gone extremely well, and we're seeing average sales uplifts of 50%.</p>
          <p>The slides are not quite coping with me doing the presentation beginning at the end and going gradually to the front. So our focus on building stronger positions in our existing markets mainly through organic growth will take on even more strategic importance for two reasons. First our strength means we can sustain, we can stick at it, the expansion, through these tough times when others have to give up a bit, and that helps us to make relative progress.</p>
          <p>And second, our money goes further. We can build stores far more cheaply today than just a few years ago. Capital costs per square foot of development coming down by well over 20%. So money goes further and that means higher returns. And it was the same picture in the last recession in the early 90s.</p>
          <p>We opened over 7 million square feet of new space in International this year through organic growth so that excludes the acquisitions. This year even with a slower pace in some markets, where it makes sense to slow down the rate of growth because instead of growing, the markets are shrinking, we'll still open another 6 million square feet. And that's three quarters of our total space growth that will take place in International.</p>
          <p>Finally, on International, I want to update you on CROIs. Our usual bubble chart is in the back of your pack. This chart shows the overall CROIs. Now given the impact of the economic downturn and the big step-up in CapEx right into the downturn over the last couple of years, CROIs have come down a little as you can see. I believe it's a good performance in this environment. Going forward, the economies will recover. The growing scale and maturity of our business will develop. I'm confident that we'll resume an upward path on our CROIs.</p>
          <p>Before moving on to the UK, I want to update you on Fresh &amp; Easy in the United States. Overall, I'm very pleased with the promising start we've made. We've built the business we wanted to create. I see plenty of encouraging signs. The response of customers to our offer continues to surpass expectations, of which we poll on a very, very regular basis. The latest polls are by far the best we have received even in the areas where we knew we had a potential weakness in terms of one-stop shopping and clear price communication. They understand the format. They love the fresh foods, the prices, and the neighborhood locations.</p>
          <p>Now the changed environment in the Western United States means that it's not yet prudent to accelerate the rate of openings as we'd originally planned. Essentially these were boom cities putting on population growth, growing whole new neighborhoods. They've gone completely into reverse. People are leaving the cities, as unemployment goes, as foreclosures take place. So you haven't got markets to expand into as we had planned for the moment.</p>
          <p>So, we're holding back on property. We've got plans for 60 to 70 stores this year. It means that trading losses will be similar to the year just ended. We could reduce them if we wish to, but I think it's important that we keep pushing on into the recession to keep the momentum up and that gives us a strong growing platform for when the returns -- when the upturn comes, which it will in those cities, it'll happen, but it will take a little bit of time.</p>
          <p>As usual with any new format we've changed some things based on feedback. For example, we've added some promotions. We've put some more range into some categories such as grocery, frozen. We've introduced a warmer ambiance to the stores. We're also adding bigger packs in certain categories and more affordable price points in others, such as our 98-cent produce pack for budget conscious customers. Customers like the changes that have taken place.</p>
          <p>Like-for-like sales increased by 30% in the year, and that's with very heavy self-impacts as we've build out networks in relatively confined spaces like Las Vegas or parts of Arizona. And customer numbers per store per week are increasing actually by more than that amount, across all 115 stores. Customer transactions are up by over a third compared with a year ago.</p>
          <p>So to sum up, Internationals had a very good year. I'm particularly pleased that we sustained strong growth through the economic shocks of the last year and I'm confident that we're well positioned to make further progress in the year ahead.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn to the UK, where it hasn't been easy, but where we've made progress and produced solid results. We've done good work on improving the shopping trip for customers. I'm very please about that. We've delivered excellent productivity, good margin control and I'll talk a bit more about this in a minute, because there's more to come. We've also done well I believe in non-food in a difficult market.</p>
          <p>Where we aim to do better is in our overall like-for-like performance. We've deliberately taken a different path, actually helping customers to trade down in our stores as they buy our discount and related ranges. This reduces our inflation and like-for-like in the short term, but it builds customer traffic. It retains loyalty, which will improve our relative performance going forward. It's been the right thing to do. It's kept customers shopping with us. It's reversed the trend against the discounters and it's also giving us good volumes.</p>
          <p>There's more to do, but as you can see from today's Trading Update we've seen some improvements in our like-for-like. Now going forward as always our focus will be on investing to improve the shopping trip. And I want to highlight a few things we're doing on price, Clubcard, range, service and availability.</p>
          <p>Our price position is strong. We've improved it again. We're telling customers about it with price comparison advertising and at the shelf edge. It's important to win the communication war on price. But more important than that, more important even than price is building loyalty. And in this, Clubcard is unique in its ability to reward loyal behavior. Clubcard is being re-launched in the next few weeks with a substantial increased investment behind it to reward our loyal customers and to encourage one-stop shopping.</p>
          <p>I'm delighted with our Discounter ranges. They're now in 30% of baskets and that's remarkable. In just six months for a range, that relative to all the things we sell is still a pretty narrow range. And they've made a real contribution to helping customers spend less. And at the same time sales of value lines are also up by a third.</p>
          <p>The work we've done on checkout service, which we now measure very accurately, has delivered one in front to a million more customers a week. On shelf availability improved again. In fact it hit a record high just last week. And we've achieved some of our best ever results in recent weeks. For example produce gaps have fallen 20%. We've seen similar percentage improvements on fresh as a whole on the evening availability, which is always an area that's bothered us.</p>
          <p>Our step-change program, which is into its twelfth year, funds these investments. Savings last year were 540 million. We plan to deliver similar savings this year. These arise mainly from large-scale changes to the way we do business. Examples include the reduction in distribution costs as a percentage of sales last year due to the complete reconfiguration of our UK DC network over the last three years. And that's been achieved despite higher fuel costs.</p>
          <p>Energy consumption in total fell by 8% last year, that's in absolute terms the lowest level for five years. So we've absorbed all the growth in the business over the last five years and we're losing less energy in total than five years ago. We've spent some capital to do that. So with new refrigeration systems, store lobbies, new lighting systems, we'll be saving another 100 million this year from further reductions in energy use and of course lower energy prices. So that's quite a big help to the P&amp;L in this year.</p>
          <p>We now have 3,000 employees at our global support center in Bangalore, it provides Group economies of scale on IT, admin support to our UK and International operations from software developments to managing, accounting and payroll. New checkout technology has continued to reduced costs and improve customer service; 25% of our UK transactions are now through self-service checkouts.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased with our progress in non-food against a headwind of a much more cautious consumer spending. Sales grew, market share increased, we managed our stock well, and we maintained profitability. In the UK our efforts to lower prices and to grow our business in key categories such as Electricals and Clothing and Entertainment helped sales to increase by 5%. Volume growth was higher actually at 9% driven by price decreases in certain categories.</p>
          <p>Like-for-like sales have held up well, in complete contrast of course to the performance reported elsewhere in the general retail sector. Growth was stronger in the third and fourth quarters than in quarter two, showing that, I think that things are stabilizing and that the adjustments we've made to the prevailing environment has helped improve our competitiveness.</p>
          <p>Tesco Direct saw strong growth at more than 50%. It's well on the way to becoming a substantial business, 10% more products in the new spring/summer catalogue, now 12,500 products on line. Clothing's being added later in the year. Our latest trial Homeplus store in Edinburgh and Nottingham features stocked in Direct and they've both beaten budgets, this combination of non-food only on display, but with a bigger range of stocked in Direct. They're doing well.</p>
          <p>As you know we're putting more capital and management resources behind our successful Retailing Services, with the aim of taking them to the next level in terms of scale and materiality to the Group. I believe there won't be a better time to increase our commitment to Financial Services. Consumers are looking for a better deal and that's why Tesco is ideally placed to build a bigger presence by taking TPF from a popular collection of financial products to a full service Tesco bank.</p>
          <p>We completed the TPF deal only in December, but the experienced and growing team there is getting on with the task of building our own systems platform, starting a branch network in Tesco stores and developing a broader range of products that will include a current account. Meanwhile the business is performing well. It saw a good growth in the year and the success of our new savings products, and we've been recently opening accounts at a thousand a day, means that the balance sheet is self-funded.</p>
          <p>Dotcom has also been on good form with good sales and profits growth even after the startup costs on Direct. Telecoms has had a strong year. Tesco Mobile grew double-digit in a very flat prepay market, we're the only growing prepay operator. And its new pay monthly tariffs are proving very popular; also they also like our in-store telecom centers. In fact we're adding another 60 this year to bring the total to 100, so we're rolling those out very quickly.</p>
          <p>The world around us is changing, but our focus on environment and on our communities does not. David's already talked to you about some of the things we're doing. Strategically this is important because it's still very important to our customers, and that means we'll continue to invest in encouraging green consumption, driving forward our community plans.</p>
          <p>Tesco is doing what it can to help the economy in tough times because we're growing. We continue to invest right through the downturn. We're still creating jobs both in Tesco and in the enterprises that supply us. This year we're adding a total of 11.50 -- sorry, 11,000 new jobs in the UK, another 15,000 worldwide. And in the UK alone our capital spend, 1.5 billion sustains another 7,500 jobs in the construction industry.</p>
          <p>So in summary, Tesco is about growth and our strategy for growth has given us momentum through this downturn. Our success has been based on listening to customers; as they change, we change. We're successfully adjusting our business and our approach for customers who have different priorities today. We've made a step-change with our wider responsibilities to the communities we serve, including on climate change, and our continued investment will make a real difference in tough times.</p>
          <p>We're continuing to pursue and invest in our strategy ready to grasp the opportunities that tough times present. We're seeing signs of stability in a number of markets, but it's too early to call a recovery, but when it does come, we've built the platforms internationally in non-food and in services to sustain decades of growth. Tesco is a company for all seasons and I'm confident that the business is well placed to meet the challenges which lie ahead. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Terry. We'll now open up for questions. If you raise your hands I'll signal and the microphone will come to you and if you could just help us by saying your name and your company. So, Philip from the front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. You very kindly gave us the sales numbers, the like-for-like sales numbers for the last seven weeks of the year and also for the first six weeks of this year, 2.1 and 3.4%, which shows an improvement. Can you give us the volume numbers in there?</p>
          <p>And secondly just to follow on from that, what do you think the inflation outlook both for yourselves and for the industry is in the UK this year, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terry, do you want to take that, volume and inflation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know at the minute you've got probably three components. You've got like-for-like, which is the nominal growth. What we used to talk about as volume, was really derived volume figure, a sterling volume figure once you took inflation out. What's happening at the minute, particularly in Tesco, is a lot of mix change, a lot of down trading. So what we look for is the average selling price movement.</p>
          <p>And so in terms of what's going on at the minute you've got reasonably good like-to-like, 3.3 ex-VAT, 3.4 wasn't it ex-VAT 4.4. You've got inflation, which is declining pretty rapidly now. It's come down 3% in about the last six weeks. It was delayed by the weakness of sterling, which kept prices up, such that inflation now in Tesco at any rate is barely at the level of the like-for-like, just slightly above the level of the like-for-like.</p>
          <p>Therefore when you take into account about overall about 3% mix change, you've actually got at the moment physical volume growth in Tesco. Now, as I say it's been achieved not by the same products selling more but by mix change. But that's something that we introduced into our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the decline in inflation will continue, because you hit the spike of fresh food prices, a very steep spike from about May through to about September, something like that. So you're going to pass through the anniversary of that and some of those categories will go into deflation. Whether we overall go into deflation we think not, that the weak pound will mean that we'll stay in low inflation, and we're factoring around about 2%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But given those volume numbers that <mark type="inaudible" /> been a success?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has been a success. I think that how do you measure success? First of all the customers do like it, they do understand it. They're not confused by it being another level and those sorts of things, because they see it in ALDI and Lidl, they know what it's about. And we chat to them and they say well it's saved me going down to ALDI, is basically what they're saying. And lots of them are buying it. So it works at that level and it has strengthened volumes. So it's strengthened customer transactions and it's strengthened volumes.</p>
          <p>We're a broad church in Tesco aren't we from very, very rich spenders down to people who are on very limited incomes. So there's been a big internal mix change down and this has accelerated it. That's painful medicine to take, but I believe it's the right thing to do and as you see general price inflation come out, which we've I suppose got ahead of, the relative strength of customer traffic and volumes will help us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just adding one thing to that Philip, the original reason for the Discounter range being launched was to combat the discounters, it actually wasn't to do with the recession. It was kind of a longer battle that we were having with a narrow range of discounters. And you asked for a sign of success, you see the switching data actually losing very little volume to any of the narrow range discounters now. So from that perspective it's been a really good tool in our armory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another one? <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi just on that inflation just to be clear, the &#x2013; you're now selling many more packets than cans, but -- so its basic value is what's slightly down, because you're selling many more packets than cans, is that what you're saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More packets than cans, that's right, the average selling price is down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the 2% inflation you're looking for, that includes mix effect going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. When we...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In our calculations when we talk about inflation, we just literally measure the price of a product year-on-year. It's weighted, but at a constant weighting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it doesn't take into account the mix effect of a customer choosing to buy a cheaper product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the 2% is more like the standard inflation rather than..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. And two other questions then. What progress on current accounts and mortgages and how would you fund those, what are your plans with that? Can you shed some light on that please?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on &#x2013; I notice that profits are not particularly huge in Eastern Europe at constant rates. Indications on East European currency would suggest that that's not going to get better for you. What sort of hedge do you have on that? Is there anything beyond just the natural hedge of holding debt there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Terry do you want to take comments on the current accounts, and Laurie perhaps talk about the --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Constant rates in Eastern Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the -- as I said in the notes the banking team, the new banking team really just got hold of the bank in December. They've been picking up the threads of the existing day-to-day trading of the business. They are choosing the new banking and insurance platforms that pretty much made those choices. And then obviously there's a period of migration on to those platforms of the existing products and businesses. And then we can start to add new products, which will include current accounts certainly and possibly mortgages, I think we put the possibility of mortgages in.</p>
          <p>And the timing of that we're not actually saying, because with big systems programs it doesn't do to add further pressure by saying we're going to have a product launch by a certain time. I think we've said over the next couple of years you'll see a progressive rollout of new products, and you'll see parallel to that the rollout of a branch network. So customers will feel its physically different and higher profile quite soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about funding of mortgages? How's that going to work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if we do mortgages obviously we'll have a plan for funding. <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, hedging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well there's two concepts you're talking about, one is the transaction side of foreign currency exposure; the other is the balance sheet side of the exposure. If we deal firstly with the transactional side: so most of our non-food volume actually sits in euros, so it actually sits in distribution centers in Slovakia. We've got a very good hedge from dollars, which is originally bought in into euros in Slovakia. A lot of it comes through from Asia. And then we've got about four to five months of cover between euros into all the various currencies from florins to kroners. So, in transactional side I think we've actually got a potential profit and competitive upside going forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of the balance sheet, it's very different. So when you hedge against your balance sheet all you're doing is you're taking the debt in an opposite currency and hoping that the assets and the loans or liabilities move up in the same proportion. Our policy is to hedge roughly 40% of our net assets in any country on all of our inter-company balances. And that avoids major movements in the P&amp;L; it keeps the movements in the reserves.</p>
          <p>We're pretty well hedged in terms of Hungary and Slovakia and the Czech Republic, and we've got a reasonable hedge in Poland. So, we've taken a big hit in our cash flow in terms of the hedging policy on the balance sheet, roughly a billion pounds, and a big chunk of it is to do with Central Europe. So, if anything that should come back or stay steady unless there's even more devaluation in those currencies versus the euro or sterling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Talking about, if I may, about Central European profitability. I think profits were, at a constant rate, actually down in the second half and there's no denying that it was a very tough recessionary shock that hit those countries. You remember a lot of discussion about the viability of the countries themselves. But it has stabilized.</p>
          <p>They had a better Easter, which was encouraging. And I think too, we have adjusted well. We had the model of Hungary in terms, if you remember our Hungarian profits when the recession first hit there went down. But we recovered the position, readjusted and then grew sales and profits pretty strongly in Hungary, despite the environment not improving all that much.</p>
          <p>I think Poland has been the first where we've made that adjustment, you know originally the small discounters were doing better. We've made some adjustments and now we're seeing good growth of sales and profits in Hungary. And we're doing work in Czech and Slovakia. I think Slovakia will be a bit slower because it's gone into the euro and that's created its own problems of cross-border shopping out of Slovakia into other places.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One again at the front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andrew Kasoulis from Credit Suisse. You hint in the text to some further changes in the US to come. Could you give us a bit more detail there please?</p>
          <p>And secondly, step-change, you gave us kindly 100 of the 550 million of cost savings from Energy this year. Can you give us some other broad categories and say specifically as to whether any of step-change have actually come from outside the UK, whether there'll be an international component to step-change please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to talk about step-change Laurie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those figures tend to be UK but there are parallel programs outside, all countries have their own step-change programs. I think the truth is you need quite a bit of scale really to drive out big productivity gains. But an area like Korea would be now moving into the kind of scale where you could have useful step-change programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Step-change is pretty much in the DNA of our business. Most of the plans that are being executed in the current financial year 2009 have been tested and evaluated for the last two to three years. As Terry said, Energy is a key driver, a good 100 million. There's at least another 60, 70 million to come out of distribution.</p>
          <p>We've announced the opening of at least two new distribution centers, one up in Teesport, which consolidates most of our non-food. A bit of background, obviously having a depot right on the docks means we don't get any input cost in terms of movement from docks to DC. And we're opening a new distribution center down in the southwest of the country.</p>
          <p>In terms of overheads we've been always very good at simplifying our business, making it better, simpler and cheaper. So there's a good 40 to 50 million coming out of our overheads. The rest is pretty much coming out of the store retail operations base. We've got a good program in terms of self-service checkouts, more efficient stock replenishment. In fact we've talked a lot about the Discounter range, of course you can see from the pictures it's all shelf ready, so very much more efficient in terms of replenishment.</p>
          <p>And we haven't really talked about some of the stock reduction programs. Our store managers were out for three weeks after Christmas on stock reduction programs clearing ex-promotional stock or discounted stock. Now, of course that doesn't add to step-change, but clearer back rooms and more accurate book stocks actually helps the replenishment program a lot better. So that would probably be the balance, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the US, by I hinted did you mean we're talking about ranges or range changes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned it in the press release that making further changes is still to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. The own-brand sales have gone extremely well in the US, a much bigger participation than we would have imagined at 70 odd percent. But the corollary of that is actually that branded sales haven't gone that well. And so we've been working through with the branded manufacturers as to why that is. And we're going to make some space allocation changes, put a bit more space to frozen food for example.</p>
          <p>And quite a lot of the manufacturers, despite what we said, mentally saw Fresh &amp; Easy as kind of a convenience niche and they've got a whole setup for selling into the convenience sector and certain pack sizes and ways of doing trade. And it meant in fact that we weren't getting the really the right pack size, usually a bigger pack size, at the killer price that was in the market. And so it's been a steady progress really of rebuilding in areas like breakfast cereals, frozen food, pet food, household, nappies, to get the right pack size and then buy at the right price and because we've got much lower selling costs, we can get a very, very good price. And the basis of the business as you know is much lower selling -- operating costs.</p>
          <p>We did &#x2013; and that process is going on now over the next few months. We did pet food. It was the first category we did, it's a relatively small category for us, but sales went up straight away by 35% just from a reset of these things, just altering a few pack sizes, and so it's got quite encouraging potential.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At the back on the left, take one there, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi it's Jaime Vazquez from JPMorgan. Just trying to understand better the volume growth in the UK, can you say if like-for-like traffic went up last year in the UK, if it was positive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well like-for-like traffic did go up in the UK, but of course you've got -- on the traditional measure of traffic. But of course you've got customer shopping --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Number of transactions, for example?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Huh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Number of transactions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, number of transactions, which is the traditional way of measuring traffic, went up. But they went up with every retailer last year I think you'll find, because there's been much more fragmentation of shopping. One of the features of the market at the moment is people are fragmenting their shopping. And I think it's been a combination of factors, the very big increase in food prices in that spike last year combined with a worsening economic outlook, really shocked people to say, look I've got to change behavior and look around to see if I can buy things better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then a couple of financial questions. Can you, Laurie, perhaps give us an indication for financial expenses this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In what context, you mean financial interest costs is that what you're referring to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so the financial line, what is your expectation for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry, I didn't quite understand the question. So, you've seen the debt number. I've been as bold to state what I'd like to get it through to the end of next year, or the current year that we're in. We probably won't make much of a move on that number by the half year. A lot of the positive cash generation for Tesco happens in the second half of the year. So it will probably be around about flat to where it is now by the half year, and then with a gradual decrease in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>So, I think you've got all the metrics in terms of the coupon rate. I've given you some indication of what the weighted average debt will be through the year. It will be ahead of where it is today and I'm referring to the underlying as opposed to the finance costs, which you've got pensions, and IAS adjustments in. So it will probably have a four in front of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a small question but I think worth understanding on the return bubble chart, can you explain why the Republic of Ireland would show an increasing CROI when like-for-likes were down 4%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, on the left there..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good profit performance in the year though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, good profit performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's the question. How do you explain the increase in profits when like-for-likes <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually the cost control in the Republic of Ireland was very good. We've got very high margins in the Republic of Ireland and we've continued through good volume to get good leverage of that business. We just want to get the top-line growing much faster, so it's not surprising that we're getting good profit growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I've got --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's also fair to signal about Ireland that in order to recover the position in Ireland, we won't be able to continue to improve returns. So if you like we were taking the last benefits of the boom in Ireland into the first half of the year because Ireland had very strong like-for-like growth into the early part of the year. And then it did a very sudden change around. And I think the team did a great job in managing the profit impact of that.</p>
          <p>But when you look out from here, doing the right thing in a sustainable way in Ireland, you won't be able to do that and improve returns for a period of time. It's a great business in Ireland, but you've had the shock of cross border trading taking place and you've had the shock of going from 7% growth as an economy to, I think, they're forecasting minus eight this year. And any business is going have to adjust for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Thomas at the front here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Given the help the consumers now get from low interest costs and fuel costs, do you think the worst of the down trading is behind us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly in terms of what they've got in their weekly budget it's an improvement. It's hard to know what people do group in the same kind of pigeonholes, but petrol costs less. Fuel bills are beginning to come down. Food prices, in terms of what people are actually buying, are no longer going up or they're not going up in any steep way.</p>
          <p>So -- and mortgage, the monthly-mortgage bill, for a lot of people has come down because even those on fixed now are rolling off their fixed and are beginning to be able to negotiate slightly better variable. So that's not a bad outlook. I think the thing that's just set against it is increasing fear of unemployment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think if you're in the public sector you're probably -- probably feel you could -- you're probably not down-trading. I think if you're in the private sector you may still be holding on because you don't know what your income level's going to be or whether you've got a job.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And second question, I appreciate you're going to spend a day going through TPF later in the year, and the Retail Services. But, just where are you in terms of using the Clubcard data to improve your credit scoring systems and just what is the potential there? Now that you're taking full control of the venture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we use it to a limited extent on products and indeed it affects the pricing of car insurance by between eight and 11%, or eight and 15% I think. So, which is quite significant in terms of being competitive and we use it on credit cards and so we are beginning to use it. But the feeling of the team is that 100% ownership with our own risk engine allows it to be fully incorporated. Understandably the RBS risk engine, which was tried and tested for their entire business, they were reluctant to introduce new data from another source fully into their risk pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the left here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, it's James Collins from Deutsche Bank. First question is one for Laurie, which is given the interest charge that you're talking with a four in front of it for this year and also prolonged losses in the US, where do you expect consensus forecast to be moving today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we want consensus forecast to move. You've referenced some of the downsides if you like, but I don't think people have really built in the full upside of TPF into consensus yet. You've seen from the pro forma, there is a good profitable business with lots of growth potential. And I think the UK is outperforming where people thought it would be. So I still think there's quite a lot to outweigh those couple of negatives that you mentioned James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Homever as well --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Homever, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think will be very strong in the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so we've converted all the Homever stores. Pretty much they traded up by about 50%, which has exceeded our expectations and we've got a full year benefit of that going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And one for Terry which is that in the statement you prefaced the UK commentary about the performance being good in the light of recovering competitors, which is something that's been in the statements for quite a while now. Do you still think that that's the principal driver of their growth versus your growth versus the gap in like-for-like, and how much longer can it be explained as a recovery by your competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it isn't put in there in any sense as an excuse. It's just stating the fact that in like-for-like terms some people are growing faster than we are. That's all it is. Our total growth as a company is very good. Our growth in the UK as a company is good. We can make good profits growth from that. Clearly, we don't want to lose market share to key parts of the market. As it happens our total market share has been maintained or even slightly increased this year. But we are losing market share to parts of the market and we want to put that right.</p>
          <p>The &#x2013; we've improved our price position. We have introduced a discount range, which is as Laurie said, is having the sort of strategic effect that it needs to have against the discounters, which is good. We've upped the stakes on the price propaganda war, which we were not cutting through on, and that will have a good effect. And we'll continue in terms of the weight of the tit for tat in high-low promotional pricing, because the future of the market has been a big increase in high-low promotional pricing.</p>
          <p>If you look at the proportion of ASDA's sales and Sainsbury's on high-low it's increased very dramatically. So you can't avoid that. You've got to be a part of that, but it's important that's not all you do, because in a way you then train the wrong kind of customers, and it fragments loyalty for everybody.</p>
          <p>So parallel to that it's important that we invest in Clubcard, which is a unique tool. It does build loyalty. The very fact of having and using Clubcard builds emotional and functional loyalty. And I think that we can invest in that, something only we can do really and encourage people gradually to the benefits of more consistent shopping, more one stop shopping. And I think that will be important, and not just in the short-term battle for like-for-like, but in the long-term recovery out of recession.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, last two or three questions. I've ignored the right, Clive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you, a few questions. First of all are you planning to segment Retail Services as a division in the business for reporting purposes on an ongoing basis?</p>
          <p>Secondly, in terms of inflation easing through the year, would you expect a volume impact from that and if so, is it immediate or more gradual? The CapEx this year, is that a one-off adjustment to market conditions or would you expect it to return to a four billion plus run rate?</p>
          <p>And then finally, in terms of Fresh &amp; Easy, when would you expect it to break-even and what sort of accumulated losses would you be prepared to take before you take a different decision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was that one question <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry everyone --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The questions are now gone, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I take the CapEx one and applying it to segmentation first. So as you know through the International Accounting Standards normally we have to segment by geography. TPF is a significant proportion of our profitability. So we do have to break that out separately, but there's no plan to break out the balance of Retail Services separately.</p>
          <p>CapEx, I wouldn't say it's a one-off. In fact what I would say is the two prior years, and I'm talking about organic growth, were really one-offs as we had a number of opportunities in competitor stores and mix-use schemes. So I see it returning to this kind of level, obviously we'll need to maintain our space growth as we go through the future years, but that's how I'd respond to the one-off point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terry, inflation easing and volume impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always hard to call. It's not an exact science between the two. I think what does happen is that customers do adjust, so to the extent that they trade down when there's rapid inflation, you know they'll trade back up as inflation comes off. I would hope that we'd be in a slightly better position having disinflated our business relative to the others we've got less far to fall. And we've held on to customers in some volume. So we've got the base there for trading up. Again it's not dramatic, but you should see the benefit of what we've done start to come through as you get less inflation in the market. US, what was the US question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And our Fresh &amp; Easy -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cumulative losses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cumulative losses and when's it going to break-even?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I do that one, or do you want to do that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the truth is that whilst you're in the middle of a recession of the severity of the one in the western United States, which I don't think any figures are being produced, but you could be looking at double-digit declines in those cities. It's pointless trying to predict when a breakeven will be, because you don't know the potential of the stores, and the format that's opening up into a recession on that scale, because trying to open new space into a market that's declining at that pace is extremely difficult.</p>
          <p>I remember when we opened in the UK in a recession, when I say recession, that was like -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was in the north.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2.5% contraction in a year. Stores just took no money. Yet five or six years later they were taking 400% more turnover. So there's no point trying to predict, because you'd only predict it wrongly. And the danger too is that in order to rush to breakeven, you'd slow your capability for long-term expansion, because it'd be easy to clamp down on costs and I'm reluctant to do that.</p>
          <p>So all we can do at the minute is cope with what's there, which is a severe recession. Make sure customers like the stores, which they do. Keep growing, keep learning, and we'll be in a much stronger position as the cities begin to turn. And then as they turn, we'll see what we've got there. I anticipate you'll see a very strong step-up in the rate of growth and then that will give us the opportunity to more accurately forecast when breakeven will be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have to break -- last two, keep it to one &#x2013; perhaps choose your one question you want to ask. One question, because we've got other people waiting to see Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Matt Truman from Nomura, just one question. Can you give us an idea of some of the specific cost productivity saving activities you're doing below the line, sales line internationally to show that how negative like-for-likes don't necessarily mean faltering profits? Just to give us confidence in the shape of how that business -- you've done it in Korea, you've done it in Hungary, perhaps give us a few case studies as to how we can model Europe and particularly Ireland looking forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, definitely in terms of Central Europe we've set up a central distribution system. Basically the growth of our businesses has been in various formats and channels. So that's been quite a new experience for Central Europe. We've got a lot of experience of how to deal with that in the UK both in terms of management, cover, frequency of delivery, change of ranges and stock turns. So there's a lot of learnings to come out of the UK into those new formats.</p>
          <p>And really the Express format has been a great -- or the convenience format, has been a great tool for us to give much broader demand for customers. So those learnings coming out of the UK, coming into International. China's obviously a young business with lots of overhead in terms of central and expatriate costs. So that's all leverage costs that can come through.</p>
          <p>And the Republic of Ireland is interesting; it's a business that we've run pretty much independently. There's lots of management skills that can be tapped into in the UK. So still maintaining its local independence, but leveraging off the UK in terms of management, knowledge, systems, formats.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, last one at the back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John Kershaw, Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Coming back to the UK then Terry, seeing as I'm only allowed one question. I suppose 12.5% profit growth in the UK in the second half is a stunning performance given the numbers at the top line that were posted like-for-like. So I suppose first question, I'm going to A&amp;B. First part of the question is to what extent did you need to do that to cover the admittedly higher interest costs than perhaps even your sales were expecting?</p>
          <p>And more generally on the UK, to what extent do you think you are reaching something of a glass ceiling on maturity in groceries, let's say in the food offer? It's not necessarily an issue for you, but how much longer can you keep growing the business when you've got a third of your percent market share in stunning sales policies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure what was in and out of your 12% second half, whether TPF or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>TPF would be in --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>12.5%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And backing out the US. But nonetheless it was a good profit performance in that sense. We did have sales growth like-for-like and new store sales growth through that period of time. We've got a very active productivity exercise going on.</p>
          <p>I think that we've been careful to manage the business so that we are able to stay on track with our strategic objectives and that's what the figures reveal. It's very important that in dealing here or in other countries with problems in the economy or with competitor threats, the actions that you take are sustainable. And there is a danger if you take the example of Dunnes reaction in Ireland, by some measures Dunnes may have made no profits. You won't know because they don't publish profits, but in terms of their short-term actions.</p>
          <p>The difficulty with that is it's not sustainable. And so it's very important that improving prices or developing new ranges or whatever you have to do to deal with it are calculated in such a way so what you start doing you can carry on doing. And so that has been the focus through the autumn and into this year.</p>
          <p>Now what we don't want do is lose market share. And so we've got to do more and do things more effectively to ensure that we're protecting and indeed growing market share in &#x2013; because people differ in how they measure it don't they. And we don't want to be losing significant market share to discounters, limited range discounters. And nor do we want to be losing market share as a result of high-low activity in the markets at the moment.</p>
          <p>Tesco have got a few challenges in the sense that we have by far the most loyal customers. They come from the farthest distance. So when things like high petrol prices come in, or you get a recovering competitor, or people start to fragment their shopping because of high food prices, that probably hits Tesco a bit harder than others. But you've got to deal with that.</p>
          <p>You've got to work out what that means for your business and adjust the business and keep adjusting the business until you find out a trading mix that brings the momentum, brings the initiative back to you, so that you can gradually grow the sales, grow the market share, but do it sustainably, that's the thing. And where can it get to? Nobody knows, the customers decide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you think you've done that repositioning, I suppose to end on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've made a good start. I think it's taken longer than I would have expected, but then the economy moved away very dramatically in big steps through the year. And the effect of a lot of things, one of the interesting things is there's a massively different like-for-like in our customers between people living nearby and further drive times. And it correlates very, very closely to the rise in petrol prices.</p>
          <p>Now, the good news is that petrol prices have come down, so there's a chance to repair, rebuild the customer traffic from further out. So it's taken longer. I don't think we're complete yet, but we're doing a lot and there's a lot more to come. It's all well thought out and I'm confident that taking the whole package we'll be able to regain the momentum in the marketplace that people expect Tesco to have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Terry that also includes the financial aspects in terms of &#x2013; I don't see many figures published for our competitors, but in terms of we publish our return on capital. So, what the operating margin is managing that, managing the return on capital is also part of the package, which I think the management are doing an outstanding job on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's it for today. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>