<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1466407" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-04-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1554</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Alan Philip Clarke</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Director">Laurie P. McIlwee</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Investor Relations Person">Stephen John Webb</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd.">Sreedhar Mahamkali</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">James R. Grzinic</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Panmure Gordon (UK) Ltd.">Philip J. Dorgan</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Alastair A. Johnston</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Andrew A. Kasoulis</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Geoff F. Ruddell</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Shore Capital Stockbrokers Ltd.">Clive W. Black</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Investec Bank Plc (Broker)">David V. McCarthy</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">James R. Anstead</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">Marc P. de Speville</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Espirito Santo">Caroline R. Gulliver</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Pramerica Investment Management Ltd.">Jason Molins</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning, everyone, and thank you for coming along today. After a few presentations, two from me and two from Laurie, so a little longer than would normally be the case, we'll open up the Q&amp;A which Steve Webb is going to chair. And in a minute, Laurie will take you through the main features of last year's numbers. But most of today's content will focus on our plans for the UK and on how we're tackling the other priorities for Tesco, those that were laid out a year ago at this very meeting.</p>
          <p>Since my first preliminary results announcement, I think we've acted where the strategy wasn't delivering as we'd have hoped. In the U.S., we got Fresh &amp; Easy moving towards breakeven before accelerating investments. In Japan, we announced our decision to exit after eight years. At the bank, we slowed down migration to focus on greater reliability in the future. And also in the UK, took a significant step to correct our pricing position; and then in January, acted decisively to address the underperformance at home.</p>
          <p>I've been here a year now, and the thing about coming back to the UK has been it gave me a unique opportunity. Eight years is a long time in business, and that time away meant that upon my return I could take a rather dispassionate view of the business here; at the industry, look at it from just about every angle. That led to a fundamental reappraisal of the UK. And whilst it's not original to me, I have to say that I believe in the UK this industry has been running up the down escalator.</p>
          <p>Space growth is too fast. More very big stores aren't the answer any longer. Customers are moving faster to smaller stores and to the Internet. Social media will soon be as influential as press advertising. And when Tesco does its best work, it does so by following the customer so that's what we're going to do. We're going to change our approach. And that will mean there'll be slower space growth. There'll be fewer, bigger, new stores. There'll be more convenience. There'll be more online. And crucially, there'll be more personalization. And there'll be more localization. Quite simply, we're going to build a better Tesco; a more modern Tesco for customers, for our colleagues, for the communities that we serve and, therefore, for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>The Tesco of the future will put more back in for customers. We'll get back to driving profits through sales. We'll make multi-channel a profitable reality. We'll act decisively where we see underperformance and we'll strike a better balance between growth and returns for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Over to Laurie now to take you through last year's numbers. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Phil; so good morning, everyone. I'm going to start my presentation this morning with the group headlines followed by a brief commentary on segmental performance. I'll then cover the balance sheet and cash flow position including an update on the financial metrics that I set out a year ago.</p>
          <p>Group sales for the year were &#xA3;72 billion, up 7.4%. Group trading profit was &#xA3;3.8 billion, up 1.3%; and underlying profit grew by 1.6%. Group profit before tax increased by 5.3%. Underlying diluted earnings per share increased to 37.41 p. And consistent with our policy of growing dividends broadly in line with underlying diluted EPS on a constant tax rate basis, the full-year dividend is 14.76 p per share, up 2.1%. We've held net debt stable in the year and we're pleased to report an increase in our return on capital employed, up 40 basis points to 13.3%.</p>
          <p>These results are in line with the revised market expectations post-January and do demonstrate the breadth of the Tesco Group. Thanks to strong performances internationally, particularly in Asia, we've been able to deliver profit growth for the group despite a challenging year for the UK and the impact of PPI for the bank.</p>
          <p>In the UK, we saw strong total sales growth driven by good new store performance. But our like-for-like growth was disappointing, particularly in the second half. This wasn't helped by reduced inflation from big price drop and a weak Christmas affected by substantial increase in competitor couponing activity. That said, for like-for-like, our like-for-like recovered somewhat post-Christmas.</p>
          <p>Net trading margins also reduced in the second half, and I'll return to this, and particularly the shape from half two 2011-2012 into half one this year and of course latter through to half two.</p>
          <p>In Asia, we delivered a good performance across all markets, with solid like-for-like growth for the year. The reduction in like-for-like sales growth through the fourth quarter does reflect reduced inflation in China and Korea and the earlier timing of the Lunar New Year Festival in 2012.</p>
          <p>Our performance in Thailand was obviously affected by the floods, falling from 8% like-for-like in the first half to 2% like-for-like in the second half. I'm delighted to say the country is getting back to normal and with Tesco Lotus returning to strong growth.</p>
          <p>Margins in Asia are up by over 60 basis points in the year. This is mainly due to the swift resolution of our insurance claim in Thailand, which has mitigated the profit impact of store closures. Korea and Malaysia both had a good year for sales and margin growth, although this was offset by increased losses in China. In common with other businesses, we faced a challenging year there.</p>
          <p>A resilient overall performance in Europe was impacted by two factors. The crisis tax in Hungary which had a material effect on profits was &#xA3;38 million in the year. And despite a strong performance in sales, profits in Poland were held back by significant disruption connected to the opening of our new distribution center and non-food stock write-off near the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of Hungary crisis tax, we saw decent double-digit profit growth in Central Europe and a pleasing performance in light of the broader economic issues affecting the Eurozone. Our Irish business delivered a robust performance in the context of a severe recession there.</p>
          <p>The particular circumstances of both Ireland and Hungary have led us to focus on driving trade from existing stores, and we've scaled back our investment in new space. Focusing our efforts on stores we've got has driven a strengthening like-for-like and a continued increase in market share in both markets.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the United States, Fresh &amp; Easy has delivered another strong top-line performance and we've reduced losses by nearly 18% year-on-year. This is the first full-year reduction in losses since entry.</p>
          <p>An increasing number of stores are now reaching shop-door profitability, and more will reach that point over the coming months. This chart on EBITDA, which is a good proxy for positive cash flow, shows it. The red dotted line in the middle represents the point where stores have crossed into positive EBITDA. In addition to the 30 stores on the right of the line that are already making positive cash, the two bars to the left of the line represent 118 stores and shows that a large number of stores are very close to crossing the line. Nearly half these stores are within $5,000 per week of being in positive territory, so that's a much more encouraging picture.</p>
          <p>Tesco Bank increased its baseline profitability, that is, profit before all key provisioning, very strongly. It's up by 29% to &#xA3;203 million. Fair value releases reduced significantly from &#xA3;155 million to &#xA3;22 million in the year, and going forward these will be immaterial.</p>
          <p>Trading profit for the bank was &#xA3;168 million which is after the &#xA3;57 million charge of PPI that we announced at the half year. And net provision for PPI stands at &#xA3;75 million which puts us in an appropriate position based on our claims experience to date. A decision to slow down the final stages of migration resulted in a hit to profit of around &#xA3;40 million, which will now begin to reverse.</p>
          <p>The bank's overall capital position improved again with the risk/asset ratio improving by 240 basis points to 16%. The liquidity of the bank has also improved, the retail bonds issue giving us greater diversity and helping the bank's funding position.</p>
          <p>As announced at the half year, we have treated Japan as discontinued. This results in a total charge for the year of &#xA3;142 million below the after-tax line which includes a small trading loss of &#xA3;25 million, which is similar to last year. I'm pleased to say that the divestment process is nearing completion, and we'll update you as and when appropriate.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the balance sheet, net debt remains stable for the year at &#xA3;6.8 billion. This is a little behind our guidance we gave at the half year, and that's due to firstly, the impact of Christmas, our trading results on cash flow and a lower working capital inflow linked to the higher stock levels than we planned.</p>
          <p>Group capital expenditure was slightly below the half year guidance at &#xA3;3.8 billion due to tight control of spending. And operating cash flow from retail operations is down slightly year on year to &#xA3;3.8 billion. Again, this is wholly due to the working capital inflow.</p>
          <p>Our strategy to release value from the property portfolios had another successful year, generating &#xA3;376 million of property profits from about &#xA3;1 billion worth of disposals. The launch of our first property fund in Asia completed successfully after the year-end, raising &#xA3;379 million from 17 mature malls in Thailand. We saw exceptionally strong demand with the fund pricing at the top end of the range and being 11 times over-subscribed. Since launch, it's been trading 10% ahead of its listing price, a strong indication of overall value of our operations in Thailand and, of course, elsewhere in Asia.</p>
          <p>Finally on the balance sheet, our IAS19 pension deficit has increased to &#xA3;1.4 billion, largely as a consequence of the reduced corporate bond yields and generally lower market returns. We announced changes to the terms of our defined benefit scheme last month in order to make it more sustainable over the long term. We've also made a one-off cash contribution of &#xA3;180 million to the scheme after the year-end. This is in anticipation of the forthcoming outcome of the triennial actuarial valuation which we believe gives a more accurate indication of the likely costs of future funding of the scheme.</p>
          <p>One year ago, I set out four key financial metrics which I said I would update you on at these meetings. Starting with the top left of the slide, we improved our return on capital employed from 12.9% to 13.3%. This improvement benefits, obviously, from Japan now being classified as discontinued.</p>
          <p>We held fixed charge cover and net indebtedness broadly flat. Both measures will, of course, be directly affected by the UK investment plan we've announced in 2012-2013. As you'll remember, our target for fixed charge cover is between 4 and 4.5 times with a ratio of 2.5 times to lease-adjusted net debt to EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Finally, I've already mentioned that we came in slightly under the guidance on capital expenditure of 5.3% of sales and that's right in the middle of the 5% to 5.5% range I laid out last year.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to Phil to give you an update on the year and our plans for the UK business. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Laurie. I'm going to begin with a candid assessment of the business as I see it and then focus on our plans for reinvigorating the UK.</p>
          <p>It's been a tough year. Although the international businesses performed strongly, delivering an 18% rise in profits, that just compensated for the reduction in the UK, leaving overall group profits only slightly up. That means that despite some really good things going on in Tesco last year, it wasn't one we could really be proud of.</p>
          <p>You know the background. In a difficult environment for consumers at home, we've chosen to face into the need to improving the shopping trip for our customers and tackle with increasing urgency some long-standing issues. Those decisions have clearly had important financial consequences for the year we're reporting today, for the year ahead and, of course, for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Deciding to give up some short-term profit to safeguard the long-term health of the business was a very difficult call but I strongly believe it was necessary. Having looked at the business hard since last summer and, in particular, in the light of a disappointing Christmas, I felt the pace of change needed to accelerate to get Tesco UK back where we want to see it: leading, performing and growing again.</p>
          <p>I said a year ago that I had inherited a great business built around customers and staff with high quality assets around the world and multiple opportunities for growth. I still strongly believe that. But what's clearer to me now than it was then is exactly how much we can do with the right plan in the UK. The recession hit Tesco hard and it was longer and it was deeper than we'd anticipated. We did well to maintain our growth through most of it but with results, too heavy a load was placed on the UK to support the group.</p>
          <p>We have to confront this uncomfortable truth and that's really the background to the decisive action that we have taken in the last few months. There was a need for change. Many of you saw it and now we're driving it. And we're also, as you've seen, renewing the management team in key areas to deliver it.</p>
          <p>It has three aspects. First, we had to start putting more back into the business than we were taking, and I'll come back to the UK in a minute. Second, we couldn't just wait for economic recovery. We had to reduce the drag and risk to our growth by taking action on other areas of the business that were holding back our performance such as the U.S., Japan and the bank. I think we can point to tangible evidence of progress in each of these areas.</p>
          <p>And third, and at the same time, we had to increase our focus on the long-term strategic objective at ensuring the business remains well-positioned for the opportunities and for the challenges of the Internet. This is important because we recognize that issues facing retailers today are not just cyclical, they're structural. We've already put more resources behind this and the pace of change has noticeably quickened in both food and in non-food. And that means it is right to take a different approach to allocating capital, a new approach that fits the future. Again, I'll come back to that shortly.</p>
          <p>These actions are why the priorities I set out for my team last April are every bit is relevant now as they were then. As a reminder, they're shown on this slide. These are our immediate management objectives, the things we're very focused on. I'll touch on each of these in my presentation starting with international, but I'll spend the majority of my time on the UK.</p>
          <p>Internationally, we had a good year. That 18% profit growth I mentioned would have been 22% without the impact of the Hungary crisis tax. I'm pleased with that performance because in several of our large markets like Ireland and Hungary, economic conditions remained very challenging.</p>
          <p>There are many good things to talk about with the international businesses. U.S. losses started to fall and I have more confidence now that we'll look back and say, "This was more than a turning point for losses. It was a turning point for Fresh &amp; Easy." Of course, there's a lot more to do and I'm quite sure some will say it would have been better if the reduction in losses had been greater.</p>
          <p>While sales growth remained strong in the second half, the reductions in costs that we'd achieved in the first half didn't continue at the same rate in the second. But I don't think anyone can argue this isn't a decisive change of trend after four years of rising deficits.</p>
          <p>The simple truth of it is that we're all proud of Fresh &amp; Easy and what it delivers for customers today. The stores look good. They're getting better all the time so it's not an accident that the two-year like-for-like is running at over 20%. Of course, we also want to be proud of what it delivers for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>We did plan to get to 300 stores. That's what we need to cover our overheads. But because I want to see more existing stores cross over into profitability before we push on, I think it's right to be more measured on new capital for the time being. This means we should be at or around breakeven by the end of 2012-2013 before overheads but after distribution and campus costs. And when we get close to that, when we prove that, we'll pick up the pace of new space.</p>
          <p>Another strong feature of the international performance was market share growth. You can see from this table how we've performed this year in our markets in Asia and in Europe. These numbers are representing the main good progress, continuing the improvement which we've sustained for more than a couple of years now.</p>
          <p>Our business in Thailand has had an extraordinary year by any standards. The flooding catastrophe which engulfed the country didn't do lasting damage to Tesco Lotus. Instead, it came out stronger. At the worst, about over 150 of our stores, mostly express, closed and all four depots underwater. I don't know how you feel about it but I love this picture. I've never seen anything like it in my years in the business. Despite challenges like this, we kept our like-for-likes and our profits growing although the latter was helped thankfully by having adequate insurance cover.</p>
          <p>I was also pleased with the further growth in success of our multi-format strategy. This chart shows how diverse our international space has now become. 20% of our space today is in compacts, in supermarkets and in convenience stores. The new growth, though, is increasingly in these smaller formats, 49% in this year's program as you can see from the chart. This is true across international with the exception of Turkey and China where hypers are still less developed.</p>
          <p>And despite what appears to a widespread misconception, we're not calling time on the hypermarket. The success of the extra program internationally demonstrates there's a lot more to come from these stores. The cumulative improvement in sales in the 31 conversions in Europe and the three in Asia that we've completed so far is 17%. The future of the hyper may well be smaller; it may be food and service-focused with a tight general merchandise assortment and a strong clothing offer. But in that slimmed down form, I believe there's plenty of life and growth in it yet.</p>
          <p>There were two markets in international where performance wasn't so good. First, and as Laurie has explained, we had a distribution center issue in Poland in the second half. It put a dent in Europe second half performance after an excellent first half as you all have seen. It's behind us now.</p>
          <p>Second, things got tougher in China. We're not immune from the slowing economy, from the impact of high inflation and even higher wage costs. You can see it in industry like-for-likes, and that's led us to take a more cautious stance on the market, at least for now. We've decided to hold back on an increased hyper development program for the time being. We'll open only 16 stores this year instead of stepping up as we had planned. We still believe that China can be an engine of growth, but it's constrained by the short-term challenges. It's a similar approach that I have taken in the U.S.A.: slow down, rebuild, then accelerate.</p>
          <p>Finally on international, whilst Homeplus had another great year, the changing regulatory environment in Korea towards large retailers looks like being unhelpful. We haven't yet seen how the new restrictions on trading hours; they limit 24-hour trading and require large retailers to reduce the number of trading days by between one and two a month. We don't know how they'll be implemented across the country, but our current view is it will have the effect of reducing like-for-likes modestly in the year ahead.</p>
          <p>Closing on international, that we could weather these challenges and still achieve an 18% growth in trading profit to &#xA3;1.1 billion is really pleasing. That's more profit than any of our domestic peers and a reflection of the quality of the business we've created in less than two decades.</p>
          <p>Before I turn to UK Retail, a few words on the bank. Tesco Bank is a major part of our strategy but I completely understand why people have been frustrated with the timelines. However, I'm pleased to say that the three-and-a-half-year project is almost complete. And because we've taken great care to get it right, we now have a great platform, a low-cost model, robust modern systems, good market positions; and with 75% of the business already conducted online, enormous potential for the future of financial services at Tesco.</p>
          <p>The next large new product will appear soon after migration, starting with mortgages. As we put more than three years of tradition behind us, the bank is well-placed to deliver good growth starting this year.</p>
          <p>I'm going to move on now to the main topic of today, to the UK. I spoke earlier about the background to the decision that we have taken. You know how it's been. Take a look at these charts which illustrate some of the causes. The first shows, during a period of recession and prolonged strain on consumers, how we continued to drive profit growth ahead of sales until 2011-2012 margins, that's the light blue line, were gently rising. This was despite slowing like-for-like sales, that's the red line, and the burden of incremental costs. We didn't miss a beat, but that meant we put a strain on the business.</p>
          <p>A consequence of this was that, as this next chart shows, the productivity loss of the stores was too great. This chart looks at our productivity index. We use the term PI, an expression of the hours stores are allocated relative to the very precisely measured tasks they have to do. I've said we've been running the stores too hot and this index, running well over 100 for a sustained period, is what I mean by that.</p>
          <p>The effect in the stores is that some colleagues are working too hard. Staff are being pulled around their departments too much and don't have time to look after their areas. And above all, our standards are not as consistent as we'd like. We simply haven't been giving our staff what they need to look after customers as well as they want.</p>
          <p>It was not that we were all that we are delivering a bad shopping trip for millions of customers every week. That's not it. At the core of it is that the key elements of the shopping trip, the things which influence where customers shop and how much they spend stopped improving in the small, the incremental ways they've done for a decade.</p>
          <p>The truth is in retailing, every little helps. Those small improvements are often subtle. They're as much about reliability and consistency from one trip to the next as they are about new and different things. But actually, they're the lifeblood of like-for-like growth in the industry.</p>
          <p>There were other components, of course. Non-food was more of a problem for us than for others, especially as we'd had our big surge in new space for non-food much earlier in the last decade. At the heart of it though, I believe, is we were simply taking more out than we were putting in and that's not sustainable. It wasn't that the business is blind to these issues either, but we expected the tide of economic recovery to lift us and, frankly, it didn't arrive.</p>
          <p>The shopping trip isn't broken and I think this important next chart illustrates why. Even when were at the top of our game in 2002, we never were seen to be the best of everything in respect of these key aspects of the shopping trip. Winning in the industry is having the right blend of performance on these measures and as I said before, getting back to making steady incremental improvements by putting more in for customers.</p>
          <p>I think you can see the influence of staffing here. It's all too clear and that's why it's our first priority. If they're working too hard, they're just not as helpful.</p>
          <p>And that's behind what we did in January. We know what's wrong and importantly, we know how to fix it. Whereas we thought we should fix it over three years and had developed a plan to do so, it came to me in January, it was vital to face it, to deal with it now and get on with it. Addressing the staffing issue is the biggest single component and this is where we've decided to do three years' work in one. And what we've found in the trial stores is that customer perception of all aspects of the shopping trip gets better if we sort out the hours, if we train our people. The billion pound investment plan to build a better Tesco is under way.</p>
          <p>So on to the plan to build a better Tesco. It's got six elements. Firstly, helping our people deliver great service; secondly, making our stores better places to shop and to work in; thirdly, delivering great value for money; fourthly, building the right ranges of quality products; fifthly, making sure that we get back to having the right conversation with our customers; and finally, making clicks and bricks a potent combination for customers. We're making a significant investment in each of these areas and it's the coming together of them that will build a better Tesco for our customers. I'll just take each of them in turn quickly now.</p>
          <p>First, staff and service, putting the staffing levels back in and training the staff in key departments, particularly in the fresh areas and in the bigger stores. We're recruiting, we're training, and we're equipping 8,000 staff right now, and many of them are already in the stores. This activity alone will require revenue cost investments of over &#xA3;200 million. It'll bring PI back to the index of 100 in the key areas. This is the three years' work in one that some of you have heard me talk about.</p>
          <p>All of the Extra staff are dedicated to particular departments. In the first wave, that's produce, that's meat. It's chilled convenience. It's beers, it's wines and it's spirits. In the 200 pilot stores where we've made these changes already, we're seeing encouraging results against control stores. And you can see them on this slide.</p>
          <p>It's very encouraging. First, our mystery shopping scores have improved. Second, while sales in the newly invested departments improved the overall store sales increased, too. In the initial 16-store trial which began last summer, like-for-like has improved by 1.2%. And in the more recent 200-store extension, after 17 weeks, like-for-likes are 1.1 points better so far. These results are very clear. The same changes are now being extended to all Extras and all Superstores and it'll be live in just four weeks' time.</p>
          <p>The second element is stores and formats. There's a lot to talk about here, but in essence of it &#x2013; the essence of it is we're going to love the stores we've got and the overall pace of new developments will moderate. The pace of refreshing stores has already stepped up and we're aiming to complete all the large stores by the end of 2013. We'll do 430 stores this year to improve the look and the feel, using warmer colors and materials, better lighting, improved site lines across the store and, as you see here, less functional signage.</p>
          <p>It doesn't involve high levels of capital for store because the stores generally are well invested. But it does make them look less clinical, less industrial. As you can see here, there's again an emphasis on key departments like counters, like fresh foods and bakeries. 40% of club cardholders will notice the difference this year alone.</p>
          <p>Some of you know I like to get into the detail and having examined every aspect of what we have in terms of space and what's right for the future, we're taking a fundamentally different approach. Putting down a lot of new space has produced great results for Tesco in the past, but I don't think the current race for space across the industry is the key to a sustainable future. So on development, there will be less new space overall; 1.5 million square feet this year, nearly 40% less net new space than last year. Our new space will also reflect the growing importance of our online business in general merchandise and our desire to focus on the most productive use of new capital.</p>
          <p>Sure, we'll expand in all formats but we'll prioritize expanding Express at least as fast as we are now. It already looks after a third of our customers. We'll invest more, as I've said, in dotcom-only stores. We'll build out space where we're committed to complete. And on hypers, we'll still be doing them, but as I've said earlier, they'll be smaller; food, services and clothing-focused. And that makes sense given the rapid growth we're seeing in non-food online.</p>
          <p>And just before the epitaph of the hyper is written, let me say in the UK we have just 10 stores over 100,000 square feet and only 52 stores over 80,000 square feet. The vast majority of our 750 or so large stores remain very profitable, very popular stores.</p>
          <p>Take a trip to Slough or Kingston Park or Sandhurst or <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:46) if you need a reminder. Strategically, this is much more about how we anticipate the influence of the Internet in the future than it is about dealing with a surplus of space today. It's much more about saying what we want the Tesco to be in the UK in 2020 than saying where it is now is wrong.</p>
          <p>Price and value is the third, being best all-around value for money. We made big changes to our price list with a big price drop last September. It got off to a good start but it wasn't sustained because we lost the marketing battle at Christmas. We're now more competitive; that's an important step on the journey, but there's more to do to get the blend right on price, promotions, on couponing and on loyalty.</p>
          <p>We didn't get that blend right over Christmas but we've been doing a better job since then. As it's a very commercially sensitive area, I'm sure you'll understand if I don't give you chapter and verse on our plans. But our customers are going to see more change and they're going to see it soon.</p>
          <p>Fourth, range and quality. We're picking up the pace on ranging, starting with a complete re-launch of all of the Tesco brands. Again, it's not broken but it does need a refresh. Better quality, better packaging, more innovation. This will touch over 8,000 products and 40% of our sales in the next 24 months. We've already started the work beginning with Tesco Value.</p>
          <p>Even before we re-launch it, it's growing at over 10% because more customers use it to make tight budgets go that bit further. And as you can see from the new packaging, every day value is a big improvement. Over 200 products have been reformatted using higher quality ingredients. They've all have been benchmarked and passed against their equivalent.</p>
          <p>We're also starting to use the capability we've already deployed with success in Express to make our ranging more store and more format-specific. I think there's a big opportunity here. Of course, Tesco will always have broad appeal. But having the same range in Alfreton and Amersham isn't doing all we can for the different needs of customers in those stores. So that's changing, too. There'll be more personalization. There'll be more localization.</p>
          <p>This is where dunnhumby is playing a very important role. We've brought them right back where they belong, to the heart of the business. They help us by taking insight from Clubcard to make the customer experience at Tesco more personal, more relevant. And this is a very substantial project for the UK in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>Fifth, brand and marketing. We've already made changes in marketing. I'm pleased to say that Tim Mason is heavily involved in the work. Only last week, we began our creative agency review, the first in well over a decade. Quite simply, we need a different conversation.</p>
          <p>Finally, part six; making clicks and bricks a compelling combination for customers is how I see Tesco remaining one of the long-term winners. It's a key part of the building a better Tesco plan because of that. Sure, we have to fix some things in the UK business right now, but we'll also keep a clear focus on the strategic opportunity of the Internet for a business with our scale, with our reach, and with our capabilities.</p>
          <p>By 2020, every person under the age of 21 on the planet will have been born in the digital age. It's already changing the way people live their lives and the way that they shop. Right now, I, you, could order a non-food item on your smartphone from Tesco Direct and have it delivered tomorrow by 3:00 in the afternoon to a local express store for no charge. I believe we are very well-placed to prosper in the digital age.</p>
          <p>Food was first. We're making money. We have a model no one can match in our international markets. I'd rather be coming at this from a strong base in food than from anywhere else. The challenge for everyone, of course, is making money in non-food online.</p>
          <p>In total, our online businesses grew sales last year to over &#xA3;2.8 billion and increased their profits despite a strong development cost headwind. And in the UK, the online businesses are doing very well.</p>
          <p>It's not bad, really, if you think, a 47% market share at Tesco and still growing. Tesco Direct is also going through a big step change in our offer right now. Starting with grocery, sales grew 13% and profits increased. Extra investments in the business adding capacity, delivery slots, more flexibility on delivery charges, including a monthly fee for multiple orders, were well-received where we offered them to customers. They also really like food Click &amp; Collect. It's now in 45 stores and adding to our growth rates.</p>
          <p>With the opening of Enfield dotcom-only store, we've almost completed our London network, enabling much more range to be offered across the very diverse London market and giving many of our large, high-density stores a bit more room to grow.</p>
          <p>The last two London-focused dotcom-only stores will open before the end of 2013 and this model will then be applied more widely, with stores penciled in for Oxfordshire and the West Midlands after London is complete. Obviously, this isn't all about the UK either; developing the operating model once and applying it everywhere is a great example of our applying group skill and group scale.</p>
          <p>Internationally, in Ireland and Korea, the operations are doing well. In Korea, the business is already the size of more than two of our largest hypermarkets and it doubled its profitability in the second half, helped by the developments of the inventive mobile apps and the now-famous virtual stores in subways. We made a strong start in Prague with sales ahead of plan and the starts not far off in Warsaw. I don't have to tell you, that's a different approach to capital productivity.</p>
          <p>In non-food, Tesco Direct began launching its new online platform that will bring much more content for customers; a new website with much more functionality, a doubling of the range plan this year from 40,000 at the beginning of the year, 80,000 now, to 200,000 by Christmas, thanks to Marketplace where third-party vendors can sell through tesco.com. That began the first stage of its phased launch just three weeks ago.</p>
          <p>Click &amp; Collect in non-food is now in approaching 800 stores. It takes 70% of our non-food online volume. The 70 Expresses we put in it are doing very well and because this is one key area where we're developing a competitive edge, we'll have 700 Expresses offering this by the year-end. 700.</p>
          <p>Few people are more than 10 minutes from a Tesco in the UK. That ubiquity, that convenience for millions of customers should be a big advantage for Tesco. There's a lot to do here, but we're already very profitable online. We have a uniquely strong global supply chain and an unrivaled store network that can give us compelling advantage in fulfillment for customers. That's why we're pushing on fast with our Clicks &amp; Bricks strategy.</p>
          <p>So that's the essence of building a better Tesco plan. Clearly, we expect each element of it to contribute to the improvement in like-for-like sales. We'll do a lot in year one, but some elements will take a bit longer.</p>
          <p>I've got the team I want to drive through this plan. Here they are. Many of you know them from our international investor trips to Europe and Asia. Every one of them has worked in at least one of our overseas businesses in the last five years. They've brought back new ideas, new energy and bags of experience.</p>
          <p>In summary on the UK, we know what the issues are. We know how to fix them and our early work gives us encouragement. So we're getting on with it and good execution is, of course, now essential. That's why I'm applying more of my time to it and I know that's not ideal, but because getting the UK back to form is so important to our shareholders, so important to the business, it has to take priority right now. With a good, hand-picked team, we're confident we can get the business back where we all want it: leading, performing and growing.</p>
          <p>Those are my definitions of success, but it starts with doing a better and more consistent job for customers week-in, week-out. And if we do that, they'll reward us with sales growth again. It'll take a bit of time; we're very confident we'll get there.</p>
          <p>I'm now going to hand back to Laurie. He'll take you through the financial consequences of the UK reset, the changes to our capital plans and the outlook for returns and for cash generation. Laurie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Phil. As Phil said, I'll take you through the financial implications of the UK plan before describing the financial strategy which supports the changes that Phil described in terms of CapEx, space, returns, and cash.</p>
          <p>So first, on the plan, we're comfortable with the guidance we gave in January as been appropriately reflected in the range of market forecasts for both the UK and the group. And for the avoidance of doubt, these forecasts show an average trading margin for the UK of around 5.2% for the years 2012-2013.</p>
          <p>The shape of margin progression from the second half of 2011-2012 through 2012-2013 merits explanation, particularly as we expect the level of margin to be broadly flat in 2012-2013. And that's between half one and half two.</p>
          <p>The second half margin of last year was down 60 basis points year-on-year and that was driven by three factors. The &#xA3;500 million investment we announced in September was, and we said at that time, part funded by Clubcard; but just over one-third of it was new money. There was an initial overlap between big price drop and double Clubcard. Thirdly, we took a significant hit to margin for non-food stock and clearing it at the end of the year. These issues were partly offset by a reduction in the accrual we had built up for short and long-term bonuses; the level of which, of course, changes in line with the performance of the business.</p>
          <p>The issues I have mentioned do not repeat in the first half of 2012-2013. The balance of big price drop is now fully funded through the realignment of promotions and supplier funding. There's no double running of Clubcard. The obsolete stock is now being cleared or provided for and new and better ranges are arriving.</p>
          <p>The margins in the first half of this year are expected to be down year-on-year. And this is wholly due to different reasons. The main drivers are the staff and refresh investment effects. And these effects do, of course, continue in the second half, resulting in a broadly flat shape for the whole year.</p>
          <p>The financial strategy which support Phil's plans, as laid out, is one of increased capital, discipline and restraint. As a result of our future plans, included is a reduced level of group capital. It's down to &#xA3;3.3 billion in 2012-2013 and beyond that, comfortably less than 5%.</p>
          <p>This is just not making a virtue out of necessity. We've moved into a new phase of growth for the group. Beyond the diversification and the expansion phase, we're gaining critical scale and exploring new opportunities were the prime objectives. Today, all of our businesses compete for capital on the basis of balance of growth and returns for each investment in that what they can deliver.</p>
          <p>More importantly though, the new plan and the shape of our growth leads to further significant changes. Across the group, more of our capital is growing into smaller, higher-returning formats. We will be investing less overall capital in our UK business, driven by a 38% reduction in net new space. We'll be opening many more stores in the UK, but they will be smaller and more focused on food than non-food. The lower capital expenditure also absorbs the &#xA3;200 million enlarged Refresh program in addition to an increase in our online investment of around &#xA3;150 million.</p>
          <p>We've already embarked on some of this work in the UK and it's bearing fruit already. Higher returns on new space that we've opened are showing that. The stores included in the 2010-2011 opening program are ahead of target and I'm pleased to say they're already delivering in excess of a 10% CROI even though most of them are open for less than two years.</p>
          <p>The level of capital work-in-progress in the UK balance sheet now stands at &#xA3;2 billion as a consequence of the front-loading of our investment and our pipeline near the end of the last decade. Burning off this pipeline, principally by building out stores faster than we put new sites in, will be a key contributor to the UK space growth over the next few years. The completion of mixed-use schemes within WIP balance will play a significant role in bringing down to a more appropriate level, although the construction phase on these schemes will add to the balance in 2012-2013; and then a rapid reduction thereafter. In some instances, we may also dispose standalone sites that do not meet our new, more rigorous returns hurdles.</p>
          <p>So what does that mean in terms of cash outlook for Tesco? With an overall reduction in group capital expenditure, our return to growth in cash contribution from the UK business, the international businesses making an increasingly positive contribution, and a return to strong working capital inflows, the outlook is increasingly cash-generative.</p>
          <p>To scale this for you, in 2011-2012 we held net debt broadly flat supported by the release of &#xA3;1 billion worth of proceeds from our property transactions. In the next few years, our internal plans move us quickly to a position where these proceeds at first create and then form just part of a significant positive cash inflow.</p>
          <p>Of course, capital restraints and improved cash generation by definition result in improving return on capital employed. When we laid out our commitment last April to improve ROCE to 14.6% by 2014-2015 we showed you this chart, highlighting the current levels of returns across various cohorts and describing some of the levers we would use to drive overall group number forward.</p>
          <p>In the short term, our investment plans in the UK make achieving this target more challenging. Indeed, it's likely that we'll see a small reduction in 2012-2013 as a result. However, we described last year a number of significant opportunities to increase returns such as driving growth in the bank, benefiting from the regional scale in Central Europe, and moving the U.S. to profitability, in addition to the structural benefit of our maturing international business. As such, we didn't need all of the parts of the plan to come off to reach the target. These opportunities still exist and indeed our decision to divest the Japanese business has already made a contribution.</p>
          <p>It is true that we now have fewer options by which to deliver the targeted improvement but we are helped by a much smaller drag from our new capital over the next three years, for the reasons I've already outlined.</p>
          <p>So to conclude, the financial strategy I've described is one of capital discipline and restraint. It supports a more sustainable level of growth, a growth that focuses us on getting more out of the businesses that we currently have. It benefits from a less capital-intensive form of investment: less new space, more focus on existing stores, more new small stores, and more into online. It reduces nonproductive capital and applies higher hurdle rates to new opportunities. In turn, this drives higher returns and a higher level of cash generation.</p>
          <p>The plans that Philip has outlined clearly make Tesco better for customers. I believe the financial strategy supports those plans and will make Tesco better for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thank you. I'll now hand back to Phil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a few words to close before we invite questions. I think in the end, it all boils down to this. First and foremost, this is a great business with a special place as the UK's biggest retail company. And the results we've announced today show record group profits. And whilst there's lots of work to do in the UK, I'm incredibly confident that together this team can get the business back to where we want it to be.</p>
          <p>How will we do that? Put simply, by doing what Tesco has always done best: innovating, changing, adapting, developing to meet our customers' needs. Now we have to show leadership in a new era of retailing.</p>
          <p>So in the 12 months that I've been in this job, I've looked at every aspect of this company and I mean everything. No part of the business is bigger than the Tesco brand. And the conclusion I've come to, after all this looking and all this listening, is quite simple. I'm not interested in finding new places to plant more flags. We don't need to chase the future. We need to focus on what we have.</p>
          <p>That's what today's plan is all about. This is about making sure every part of the business is successful, is strong, and is growing. It's about making the right calls about margins and services and space. Above all, it means giving the customer value for money. It means putting the customer first. It's a plan for a better Tesco; better for customers, better for our colleagues, better for the community to be served, and ultimately better for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now, of course, these changes won't all be easy. It's a tough ask and it's going to take a huge concerted team effort to get where we want to be. But if we get this right and make it happen in the next 12 months, then we will build a better Tesco; a better Tesco for today, and a better Tesco for tomorrow.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your patience. It took about an hour. We've now got an hour for questions and I'll hand over to the master of ceremonies, Mr. Webb, who will lead that process. Over to you, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Phil. We'll conduct it in the normal manner. If you can raise your hand if you want to ask a question; the microphones are in the back of the seats. Before we do so, I should acknowledge a debt to Mr. Darren Shirley for the Thailand photo. He knows me well enough to know that the check is not in the post.</p>
          <p>Who wants to ask the first question? Sreedhar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The microphone is in the back of the seat, Sreedhar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:40)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:45)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You need to press the button, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:58)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, UK like-for-like, you talked about 1.2% improvement over the control estate. Are you able to tell us what are the actual like-for-likes of these stores and a bit more in terms of &#x2013; are you happy with it? Is that in line with your expectations? Are you disappointed? And also, what level of like-for-likes you need to see for you to recover the additional investment in the stores? That's the first question, please.</p>
          <p>And secondly, you also talked about consensus margins actually understanding the message in the UK reset for 2012-2013. Is it also your view that consensus is actually getting it right with a small margin improvement in 2013-2014, a year out?</p>
          <p>And finally in terms of the UK delivering results, in the release, you talked about delivering results in the next few months. So should we actually be starting to expect Tesco like-for-likes starting to come in line with industry level growth? What is your timeline basically? That's it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sreedhar. On the first one, I think, Phil, you should answer that one. And on the second one, that's naturally Laurie. On the third one, I think we can probably all have a go at that.</p>
          <p>I think I should say, before we start getting into lots of questions about timing, that we will not be drawn on timing. So I understand why you would ask that question. It's a perfectly reasonable question to ask. But we're not going to get ourselves pinned down this morning on the timing of overall like-for-like improvement. Although, of course, what we're doing with the business is intended to improve like-for-like performance. Phil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My first phone call this morning was with Reuters, and they said can we have the first question. I don't know if you were listening, but they asked three questions just as you did.</p>
          <p>On like-for-like, I think it's a good start. I think the 16 stores gave us confidence; we did 200. We started them only 17 weeks ago. They're already above 1%. But there's more to come. And what we can see is steadily these stores build. So as you said, Steve, we're not going to give any false precision right now. It's very, very early days.</p>
          <p>We, of course, don't need to get it to cover the cost as we've set our margins because we're reflecting that what we need to do is make the shopping trip better for customers, make all those other changes you see in the plan. And then we should see an improvement in our relative performance in the market, and that's what we're aiming for. But first and foremost, customers will tell us, and the store performance will follow.</p>
          <p>On margins, Laurie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Profit growth is much more orientated toward sales growth than margin growth, so there may be an opportunity to improve margin in the future, but it won't be an end in itself. It will be as a result of the virtuous circle getting back working in Tesco with strong volume growth to be able to be invested into improving the shopping trip again. And ultimately, if that does mean that margins can improve, they will improve but not by a lot, I don't think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. It's James Grzinic from Jefferies. I wonder whether you can talk a little bit beyond current year on CapEx and space in the UK. You seem to suggest that there'll be a further step down in 2013-2014. Is that a right reading of the situation? And can you perhaps tell us, out of the &#xA3;3.3 billion, how much is UK? Do you have another &#xA3;200 million going to refurbs next year, I presume, and then that drops off? Can you help us with those mechanics, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So do you want to start then pass it over to Laurie or me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the first question was of the &#xA3;3.3 billion, how much of it is going into the UK? Was that the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the CapEx for the current year that we're in is about &#xA3;1.3 billion. And that absorbs the increase in the Internet investment, which is &#xA3;150 million; and as you said, the Refresh program, &#xA3;200 million. And that will be the new base. And as you say, we'll be refreshing in 2013-2014 as well.</p>
          <p>What was the rest of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I presume &#x2013; you seem to intimate, I mean, the mixed-use schemes, for instance, are going to be reduced and perhaps, in some cases, even sold off after this year. So presumably, that means that CapEx in new space addition in the UK reduces further from next year, from 2013-2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't made any decisions to sell anything off, James. It's simply an option. I think in terms of the new space going forward, I think, Phil, you should deal with that one here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. &#xA3;2.4 million last year, &#xA3;1.5 million this year. We're starting at a new level. That's about where one should be expecting it in the future. But we have got some mixed-use schemes that we are beginning to build out. For instance, Monday, we begin demolishing Gateshead, by which I mean most of the town center.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:01:26) will never be the same, by the way, for those of you who remember. And we're going to build a 100,000-square-foot store there with a shopping center with some mixed-use residential, and we'll do that over 18 months. It's going to open probably the beginning of 2014. So there is that still to come, but in terms of where we are starting now, we're saying &#xA3;3.3 billion is where we start. It's not going to be &#xA3;4 billion next year. It'll be &#xA3;3.3 billion.</p>
          <p>We do want to put more into the stores that we have. We want to <mark type="ph" /> love that (1:01:57) a bit more. We think they've got to keep on refreshing, and 1.5 million square feet feels about right, but more convenience and always more online, more dotcom-only stores, more in creating digital capabilities. Great thing about those is the way we build them. We build them once, and we deploy them many times. So the systems and the processes that we use in Prague and that we use in Korea are the processes that we build in Bangalore and that we use here in the UK. So we create group assets, which is good because we can use them in more places.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I got a shock there. Philip Dorgan at Panmure. Playing devil's advocate for a moment, if I may, if you look at the performance in the UK over the last four or five years, the increase in turnover is roughly what you spent in capital expenditure. So you're not &#x2013; clearly, something has gone wrong over the last four or five years, not just the recession. So are you investing enough? Is &#xA3;0.5 million a store enough?</p>
          <p>You invested &#xA3;500 million in price last year, and your sales went down. Is the amount you invested in price this year enough to really fundamentally reverse the business's performance? Product offer, you got &#x2013; obviously that Everyday Value range looks promising but there needs to be a lot more than that so surely you need to be investing more. So the question really at the bottom of it is, is really the hit this year enough and aren't we really going to see another hit next year as you realize you haven't done enough?</p>
          <p>And secondly, the U.S., what has to happen for you to close or dispose of it? It's not hitting its profit target. Why don't you just come out and say you're keeping it forever and draw a line under it, because that seems to be the implication of what's happening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Philip.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you run out of paper? I did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think they're for you, Phil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, for me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Good. Well, this building a better Tesco plan has been thought through for about nine months. And all the things that you said that we need to do better at, we're planning to do better at. It all starts with putting more staff in the stores so that we get the products on the shelf in the right way, in the right quality at the right time.</p>
          <p>And you saw what happened to the like-for-likes of those stores where we did it. That's a good start. But you're absolutely right. We've got to build better brands. Everyday Value, we didn't just dream that one up last week, Philip. We've been working on that one for five, six months. The new formulations and new packaging for the Tesco brand aren't just things that we might do. They're things that we are doing right now. You'll see them coming through in 2012.</p>
          <p>The Venture brands are building. We've now got more than 12. We had none two years ago. They're doing very nicely, thank you. The investment in the online &#x2013; in fact, the whole of the plan is designed and costed to get us back to where we want to be. We're comfortable with the way people are steering, the consensus. And it'll all be shown in time whether it is enough or it isn't but we feel that it is enough, or else we wouldn't be here today with the enthusiasm that we have got about it all. And this isn't a plan that we're going to start tomorrow. This is a plan that we started last year.</p>
          <p>And I suppose the one thing that hangs out there is, well, what are they going to do on price? If you look at the chart that we showed, the chart on value for money, it actually talks about more than just price. It talks about the right level of couponing. It talks about the right amount of investment in loyalty, because these are very important things in the mix. It's about value, value for money.</p>
          <p>On America, I can quite understand why you want me to say that which you say I should. But I listen to investors, and I understand their frustrations with us if they are frustrated, but it's quite a unique business, this. And in just four years, it's getting more stores across the lines of profitability. So I could run ahead and do 100 and maybe we get there or I could just do half that number and get more stores across the line and convince myself, and then convince the investors there is value for the future. And that's why I won't say we're staying and I won't say we're going. What I'll say is we're absolutely focused on delivering shop-door profitability.</p>
          <p>It would have been great if I were standing here reaffirming that which we said 18 months ago, and you all know I'm not. But the reason I can do it with a little bit more confidence, and unapologetically, is where we made changes, customers reacted. We've got more stores making profit. There is such an opportunity. I don't want to say we're there forever. I don't want to say we're going tomorrow, because I don't think we're there yet. But we'll get there in the next year or two, and we'll have a business, I confidently expect, which people will say it was worth staying with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Al.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I need to have a microphone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's one in front of you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:07:24) Two questions. The first question is on international space growth, because I noticed that in square footage terms, the reduction of international space growth in the year ahead will be greater than in the UK. So how much CapEx saving is being made in international relative to the UK in the year ahead? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question again is on Fresh &amp; Easy. We're four or five years in or whatever and minus 24% margin. Can you explain what the overhead cost actually, is because you've disclosed the depreciation cost, I think, yeah, 6%, 7% of sales or whatever; but what are the costs at the center which are causing these margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think those are two for you, Laurie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the international space growth; Europe is basically down, similar to the UK in terms of reduction. And, of course, we've said that most of the big hypermarket expansion, probably with the exception of Turkey, is pretty much done. A lot of what we're doing now is infilling with lots of smaller stores.</p>
          <p>In Asia, less so; the reduction is about 20%. We've pulled back China, going much more carefully in China, a little bit of capital discipline and restraint in there. Thailand, within that, still growing at a similar pace; Korea still growing at similar pace. Pullback in Malaysia, not really by our doing. It's just much more difficult to get planning permission for big hypermarkets in Malaysia now. And the U.S. is actually increasing its space year-on-year.</p>
          <p>The second, what's in the overhead? Well, all of the things that you would expect. So the IT, the central office, the support teams that run the stores, some of the overhead that runs the campus and the distribution center; but it is management. It is, as you'd normally describe, admin expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just in terms of pounds billion, what's the reduction of CapEx in international we should expect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the group's going down from &#xA3;3.8 billion to &#xA3;3.3 billion. And the UK is going down from &#xA3;1.6 billion to &#xA3;1.3 billion. So it's &#xA3;300 million for the UK, &#xA3;200 million for international.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Yeah. Andrew Kasoulis from Credit Suisse. I've got a question on the return on capital outlook, if I may. Firstly, can you give us a bit more of an indication about the sustainable level of growth in terms of sales? You talk about a more sustainable level of growth. We used to assume the UK could grow mid-single digits and international could grow kind of mid-teens, and overall blended that was about 10%-ish. Presumably there's a lower number now that you're basing your return on capital calculation on.</p>
          <p>And what else in the numerator has got to improve a lot to still hit your target? I accept that there'll be a bit of a dip in year one, but to get to year two and three numbers, presumably, there's got to be a significant contributor to the numerator. So what is it of the various different levers? Is it UK like-for-like? Is it the bank? Is it the U.S.? Is it Europe? Is it less losses in China? How can you prioritize those, please, to grow that numerator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're not looking at me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Laurie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andrew. What I said in my speech, ROCE will go back a little bit in this year because of the big investment that we're doing in the UK and you've reflected I think pretty closely our year profit growth for the group in the consensus.</p>
          <p>But going forward, if I just pulled out, let's say three exceptions that will help the ROCE improve so much. So the U.S. getting to breakeven, now that all the bank provisioning is kind of out of the way and migration is pretty much out of the way, getting the underlying growth at 20% year-on-year, which you can see the baseline profitability is growing by that already.</p>
          <p>The Hungary crisis tax, which is &#xA3;38 million, it's a significant amount for Hungary. That's got a sunset in 2014. If you just took those three like exceptions, they add 100 basis points to the ROCE. So that would take it from 13.3 to 14.3.</p>
          <p>And, of course, a lot of the discussion and plans that we've laid out today is a far lower capital-intensive growth both for Europe and for Asia and, of course, for the UK. So I'm pretty sure that the remaining 30 basis points that would take you from 14.3 to 14.6, we should be able to do. Now, before we reset the UK and set a lower level of growth then there were much more avenues of getting to 14.6% so it is more challenging but we believe still doable.</p>
          <p>Your question about what's the blended growth rate, used to look at double digit; it will be below double digit. We see it as high single digit but, of course, it will be at a much lower level of capital. So healthy growth but, more importantly, healthy returns as well &#x2013; not more importantly, as important, healthy returns growth as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, is it okay if I add something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It'd be good if we got an economic tailwind for once. We've had headwinds for five years. Consumers have never felt it more strongly than they do. Think about the winter of high fuel prices, greater job insecurity, of higher levels of inflation. I think when we sat here 18 months ago, we were thinking that was a thing in the past, too, but it isn't.</p>
          <p>So Laurie is absolutely completely right. Good single digit, not double digit; but if you get an economic tailwind, particularly in the developing markets, that can change very, very quickly. That would be the thing that I would add to your brilliant answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question? Geoff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Geoff Ruddell, Morgan Stanley. Laurie, you mentioned in your presentation that you had taken much lower accruals for staff bonus payments. I just wondered if you can quantify it for us? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So on the staff bonuses, the profit share that we pay to our frontline staff, there's no change to that. That will be the same as we've paid in normal years. But, obviously, our management bonus scheme, the 5,000 that get a performance related bonus in Tesco. It's a very transparent set of targets which, of course, we've missed our own internal targets.</p>
          <p>Not only have we missed the annual targets, but when you look at our three-year targets there were some schemes we just can't get to based on the last two years of growth. So it's been quite significant. The benefit to the second half has been over &#xA3;100 million of bonus accruals released. Some of that does come back in the 2012-2013 year; not all of it because as I've said, some of the multiyear schemes just won't pay out now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. That's very clear. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clive next and then Dave, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two or three questions, if I may. Firstly, Laurie, in terms of becoming a more cash-generative business, do you think that allows you to say anything about future dividend policy and also the possibility of return to share buyback down the line?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, in terms of Tesco being a portfolio of businesses, but perhaps coming back to Phil Dorgan's question on the Fresh &amp; Easy, but also maybe the bank and even you as an Asian business, do you see the prospect of shareholders getting some form of reward for their loyalty in terms of potential listings or potential realizations for the business that you've created? Could you list Fresh &amp; Easy in the States? Could you list Tesco Asia in Hong Kong? Could you list the bank somewhere else or whatever? Is that part of your thinking in terms of generating value for Tesco Plc and its shareholders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Only two, Clive. You said three.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a bit depressed because <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:16:02) lost to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:16:03) last night, so I forgot the third one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you are right to point out to me my emphasis on cash generation because I do think it's a very positive aspect of the flight path for the business. Eight of our 12 international businesses, if you exclude Japan now, are all cash generative. They can either support their own CapEx and growth or they can return cash to the group. So that's quite a change. The bank is at the end of its investment through migration and we've shown you what we're doing in the UK vis-&#xE0;-vis lower CapEx, but it's always been a very cash-generative business.</p>
          <p>Now that's the plan, and there's a lot of heavy lifting to do between now and that coming in. When it comes in, that's the right time to have the conversation vis-&#xE0;-vis shared buybacks or dividend policies or whether we've got a better idea of investing that money for you in a better returns way. So if we could part that, we'll come back to it when we show that it can be done.</p>
          <p>On the plans for listing, we don't have any separate plans for listing any parts of our business. As you saw with the Thailand PFPO, there is a big appetite, from Asian markets really, for the strong businesses that we've got in those various countries. So the only plan that we've got at the moment is, if you like, returning that to you via property profits, getting our underlying profits going, which then feeds through to dividend. And it will help us build this cash agenda that I've been talking about, but no plans currently to separately list.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think at this point, our real focus should be on an improvement in the UK business. That's so important. That's where we deliver the best value fastest for the shareholders. When we get beyond that point, we can think about other things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's Dave McCarthy at Investec. A couple of things; first of all, the chart you put up which showed the return on capital you put up a year ago; showed the UK business as having roundabout an 18% return on capital. Of course, when you put that up the UK margin was 6.2% approximately, and now you've said the long-run margin is going to be 5.2% and may get some growth. So you've talked about the areas of the business where returns are going to go up, but are you now saying that long-run returns in the UK will be below that level? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>Second one, you're pulling back on the &#x2013; on your space openings for the UK; new stores. What would you do if the competition accelerated their openings because the price of sites goes down and greater availability for them? Would you just carry on and allow them to strengthen their strategic position or would you reconsider your own opening program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the long-run returns, I think Laurie should answer that, although I would preface it by saying you should also realize that that bar in that chart which represents the UK has &#xA3;10 billion of capital employed in it and in that &#xA3;10 billion is &#xA3;2 billion of unproductive work in progress, which will become productive. So without making a forecast, there is a significant positive out with a trading element to it in terms of the UK return.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I get that, but the question is about the &#x2013; maybe I didn't phrase it right, is the mature element of your business rather than that. So ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...your mature element must be doing greater than 18%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, Laurie, do want to deal with the returns questions and then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:20:10) part of the answers didn't he then? So you're right. It's more challenging to hold 18% ROCE, certainly in the short term for the UK and it will come down a little bit. The aspects that will make the return on capital employed go back up, of course, while margins coming down, the numerator is a combination of quantum profit and margin. And our objective going forward is to grow profits in line with sales, not grow sales a little bit but margin a lot. So it's merely a &#x2013; over the long term, it's a switch of that strategy. So that should hold the ROCE.</p>
          <p>There are other smaller elements within the UK P&amp;L. For instance, the Tesco Direct business does lose money at the moment, and our plan is to turn that into profitability come over the next two to three years. So that will be an important contributor to the numerator as well. And then Steve's point is a very important one; halving &#xA3;2 billion of capital employed is pretty significant to the denominator in that calculation.</p>
          <p>The final bit is, as you know, George Osborne has been dropping the corporation tax for us. So the ROCE that we've shown you is after tax. And the tax, as you know, has dropped from 28% and it's going towards 23%. So that will all be accretive to ROCE in the UK and help us a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Phil, on space?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't &#x2013; well, we won't change our view, Dave. I think that the &#x2013; as I said a little earlier, on space for the UK going forward, I'm thinking much more about the business we need to be in five and 10 years' time: a sustainable, profitable returning business. And I'm reflecting both the change &#x2013; structural change in the way the customers are living their lives and the way that they're shopping and the capability that you need to build online in order to service that as much as I'm reflecting the fact that they're going towards convenience.</p>
          <p>So I really like the store portfolio I've got in the UK. I really love where those stores are located. I can see, as I said a year ago, that there are places where Tesco isn't and it could be. I think that actually in the future, they won't be 80,000 square feet. I think they'll be where there's demand, but they'll be smaller because we'll do more of the non-food online. So if our competitor &#x2013; if the property values do reduce, which I'm not sure they're going to because there's very short supply and very complicated planning regulations that get in the way, it's not a completely free market here, as you know.</p>
          <p>If that were to happen, I think we'd stay where we are because then we're doing the right thing for Tesco, for our shareholders and for the business in general; which is making a change to be a clicks and bricks retailer at home.</p>
          <p>Sure, we've got an execution problem. I talked about that last year. Fixing the execution problem will improve our performance of our existing stores. But actually, what I'm really seeing now is you can service people with products that they want online. You can increasingly do it efficiently. This click and collect thing is quite a change. Two years ago, we were delivering to people from a warehouse to their home through a courier who charged us quite a lot. Quite often, when they tried to deliver the customers weren't at home, so all they got was a bit of cardboard. Now 70% of them pick them up in a shop.</p>
          <p>So it is quite a change, and we thought long and hard about this. We've looked at every scheme we've got in our planning machine, and we've thought about which of those we should carry on with, and most of them, we should, but smaller and more online, more digital. Not the death of the hypermarket; just fewer, newer, bigger and more focused.</p>
          <p>And I don't know how the competition will react, but I think because of our ubiquity, we're ideally placed. And I just think giving more to existing customers will get us back to generating more value for shareholders at home.</p>
          <p>I should just close, just a very important point for me, by saying the inheritance that I had was extraordinary. We've got the best network of stores in the UK. We've got the best network of stores in Thailand and in Malaysia and in Korea. And we've got the best network of stores in Hungary. So we're ideally placed, but you can see the shift now. It's more to convenience in the UK. It's more to online. That's going to be the way it's going to be for the future. That's more capital productivity for us if we can trade the right digital assets and so much of our effort these days goes into that. Much more of it, though, goes into improving the UK which I know is dear to everybody's hearts, not least mine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James Anstead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. James Anstead from Barclays. Just two questions. The first one of which Philip answered in part, I think. But on real estate, unless I've missed it, it's the first time in several years you haven't updated us on the value of your real estate portfolio, so I wonder if you could let me know what that is at the moment?</p>
          <p>And also, whether having told the market that you're less enthusiastic on opening big stores going forward, whether that's affected the appetite of investors to take that property off your hands? And whether &#x2013; finally on real estate &#x2013; whether you're planning at all to change the pace of divestments you highlighted this time last year in that ROCE plan?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on Asia, clearly your Asian margins expanded very nicely again, and that's been a big help to the group profits. But short of turning around China, which doesn't sound like it's going to happen in the very short term, do you think we can expect that Asia margin to improve any further, or is it starting to top out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if &#x2013; we should deal with the margin point first. Do you want deal with that, Phil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Asian margins were amplified in the year by the fact that we didn't hit our sales in Thailand because all those shops were shut, and we put in the insurance claim that offset the damage. So I think that is an artificial inflation of the percentage margin, but not the cash margin. So percent margin will probably ameliorate a little in the year that we're in, but I think you'll still see expansion because you've got a lot immature assets, James, that are coming through.</p>
          <p>You make a good point about China. We hoped that we would see it turn positive. We're still investing in overhead. And the consumers found it very tough, and all retailers have. So we still see opportunity for margin expansion, not rapid, from Asia.</p>
          <p>On real estate...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think this one; calling your question right, James, it was enthusiasm amongst investors for big stores?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You've said that you were less &#x2013; not committed, but less enthusiastic about big stores, so I wonder whether the people that are buying from you were <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:27:46)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is I don't think so, but I'm sure Laurie can answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The sale-leaseback program in the UK is still delivering yields in the kind of mid 4.5's to kind of 4.75, so very healthy. And of course, appetite is partly attributed to value, but also to the inflation that you've got on rent and the company's underlying ability to pay the rent. So that kind of drives the value just as much. The value of our property &#x2013; I mean, I'll say what I think it is, and then we should just double-check. But the market value of the group's properties is about &#xA3;26 billion, and the net book value of it, I think, is about &#xA3;18 billion. So we've still got a significant market value excess over net book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the things about these stores, I think &#x2013; I mean, look, James, is looking a bit confused there, but ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:28:58)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the total value of all of the assets that we've got so that adds back in malls, distribution centers, other assets, the WIP. Or if you wanted &#x2013; I thought your question was specifically about trading property.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:29:16)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let's clarify that. We did look at that. I mean...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:29:20)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I was going to say about stores is that great locations are <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:29:26) assets. And so that creates its own market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marc de Speville.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Marc de Speville at Redburn. Just two questions. Firstly, can you give a bit more detail then on where you think the profitability of non-food online could or should get to, and what's needed from you to do that? In fact, from your smile I'm wondering do you have a clear enough view yourself of what's needed to get there so maybe a sort of range currently where you think the profitability both in terms of margins and ROCE could get to and what's needed &#x2013; what you need to do to get there and the sort of &#x2013; some sort of outline of the timeframe? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second, just your view on the current margin environment in the industry; overall in the UK the overall level of competitiveness that it would seem from the recent food price inflation, it seems to be a bit stickier as insofar as prices have been going down recently. How sustainable is that going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to deal with the second one first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do I?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as the topic du jour.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think it's still a very competitive market. Of course I do. And I see the pressure of inflation in pricing continuing and retailers working hard to press it down. But as we've said, we're calling our operating margin in the way that we are because we've given ourselves some room to make sure we remain competitive. And you would see for me competitiveness isn't merely price it's a price, quality, value equation.</p>
          <p>Our inflation rate is slightly below the numbers that get externally reported because we did that big correction to prices last year so we feel pretty good actually about how we're delivering value to customers. And you'll see some changes in the near future to that.</p>
          <p>Does that answer your question? You're looking blank at me, which suggests...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, that was my best attempt at a cunning look, but no. That's the normal reaction I get. Phil, I was asking more about the general industry environment. And we have noticed if you look at just straight ONS, CPI food against BPI food, the CPI, the retail price inflation has been staying up higher; in fact, ticked up in March going to ONS yesterday whereas the input costs are still coming down according to that particular measure. And other retailers seem to have suggested that the overall margin is not quite as tough, let's say, as it was back end of last year. Ex what you're doing, do you recognize that sort of overall comment from the industry? And if so, is that something that could sustain through the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would have thought even a casual look at the tabloid press would tell you that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was in Metro this morning, actually, so it's a very silly old question, yeah, I knew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Profitability of non-food was your second question as well, wasn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Non-food or non-food Direct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Non-food Direct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Non-food online; multichannel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So, I understand why you kind of asked that question. We're all going to get drawn on our profitability for the online business, but if I could just describe the components that improve profitability, hopefully that will give you the wherewithal to make your own judgment.</p>
          <p>So the current business that we finished with last year, its mix orientation towards electrical is too high. And that depresses the gross margin of that business though we finished last year with, I think, 38,500 SKUs. If you went online now, and we've just relaunched; the Direct website's far more functional, far easier to use from a mobile perspective you saw in Philip's presentation, that's already moved to 80,000 SKUs. And by the end of this financial year, pre-Christmas, we'll be up to 200,000 SKUs. Some of that comes from marketplace, a lot of it comes from our own ranges going online; and they are much more gross margin accretive than the electrical business that we have.</p>
          <p>The second aspect is we haven't been leveraging Tesco's scale in terms of distribution. And that's the biggest cost that a pure play has. They have to get it from their warehouse to the customer. We've given you a couple of KPIs today but we deliver already to 2,400 stores around the UK every day so that's already baked-in cost. We're going to leverage that system.</p>
          <p>And because customers want to pick up from our stores and they've surprised us how much of our order choices are just picking up from a local store. At the moment, of the 770 Click &amp; Collect stores, 70 of them are Express. We double that by Christmas. It gives us an 80% coverage of the UK in a five-minute drive time so very extensive coverage. And as I say, costs that we're currently paying to a third party operator to do it for us gets leveraged off our own cost base.</p>
          <p>Then I think the third piece which is also a leverage scale, we've got 33 buying hubs around the world buying non-food for us. You've heard us talk a little bit about bringing all of that together for the group. That will help us in terms of buying margin as well; not just for the UK, but for all the other dot.com businesses that we're doing around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could just add a bit more color perhaps. Our toaster broke at home a couple of weeks ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is strategy, this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm getting into the detail. So I went on my smartphone; I bought a Tricity red &#x2013; Liverpool supporter, you see &#x2013; toaster and kettle. The Tricity brand is owned by Tesco. It's manufactured in one factory in China. It's bought through our buying hub. It's sold in every business we own in the world apart from Korea because of some legislation about electricity I don't quite understand. It was delivered to my Cuffley Express store the next day after I'd ordered it on my smartphone.</p>
          <p>Two years ago, had I gone online &#x2013; wouldn't have been able to use my smartphone; I'd have ordered it, it would have been delivered to my house. It wouldn't have been Tricity because we didn't have the brand then. It wouldn't have been made for the group. It wouldn't have the basic margin that it had. It would come to my home, it would go through a courier, it wouldn't go through the Tesco supply chain, all that costs.</p>
          <p>So as you were saying, Laurie, absolutely right; it's the 33 buying hubs, buying once for the group, developing a product that's got some intellectual property in it, some real value. Getting it to the UK into our Middlesbrough DC which Laurie built a few years ago, then moving it through our store network to the Express store takes out a lot of costs. So you've got bigger gross margin at the top, you've got lower costs at the bottom. And then as you rightly said, when we began with Tesco Direct online, it was mainly consumer electronics. And there's little margin in flat screen TVs, particularly if the way that you sell them is high-low pricing.</p>
          <p>If you think about the way retailers work in brick stores, they high-low. It's one price then it's discounted. Online, because of pricing transparency, you have a different way of doing it. So you're buying with the selling price in mind. You're using Web analytics to realize when you've got to shift prices. All these capabilities we've been developing, learning from some of the best.</p>
          <p>And so then you add Marketplace, because with Marketplace, you suddenly get a view of what actually is selling because all we know is of the things we're buying what's selling. We've got analytics; you know all the things that we aren't selling or others are selling, what's selling. And you decide whether you want to sell it or not.</p>
          <p>So you &#x2013; as a retailer with so many years experience, Tesco is able to create value and then use its superior logistics network to take cost out of every link in the chain; and then make it more convenient for customers. And the best thing of all this, the toaster worked.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Caroline, and then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:37:48)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Is that working? Yes, it is now. It's Caroline Gulliver from Espirito Santo. Two questions, please. The first is on your marketing strategy in the UK. Can you give us a bit more color on sort of why dunnhumby was deemphasized and now it's being reemphasized? What's actually going to change? How can we have confidence that you're actually going to get it right effectively from now on? I'm assuming you're going to talk about more personalization for the consumer. But sort of the &#xA3;5-off-&#xA3;40 shop doesn't seem to be that. So what's going to change and how can we have confidence you're going to get it right?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is really a clarification on your definition of success. You've obviously got the return on capital target. You've made lots of points about growth, successful. In the UK, given that you said you're making all this investment in online and in the stores, and you've talked about sales growth leading profit growth, does that mean that your definition of success includes market-leading like-for-likes and not just market being in line with the pack?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think both of those are for you, Phil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very kind of you. Yeah, personalization; dunnhumby; marketing in general. The fastest way to get a sales uplift, if you're running around looking for sales, is &#xA3;5-off-&#xA3;40. And you saw what happened in the industry in the &#x2013; at Christmas, saw that we weren't there. I don't like doing that very much. But when it's done to me and without the ability to have any other immediate reaction is when it's the right thing to do.</p>
          <p>What we are doing in increasing amounts of personalization already you'll only know about if you're a Clubcard customer and you shop regularly with us. And we have other ways of maintaining and building the loyalty of our existing customers, and dunnhumby is right at the heart of that. And what you have to do is take some of your promotional investments and move it out of &#xA3;5-off-&#xA3;40. Move it off 6 p off a liter of petrol if you spend &#xA3;50 or more. Move it off high-low promotions. Move it into targeted promotions, personalization; and that's what you'll see us doing. And in our plan for the UK, some of our investment is just that way.</p>
          <p>He's passed me something that I don't really want to say, but go on then I'll trust you because you're good at numbers.</p>
          <p>Three weeks ago, we mailed 7 million customers. I don't think you know that. We mailed 7 million of our most loyal customers with a loyal customer mailing. And we know that's going to improve loyalty. We'll take that much, much, much further because we'll start to tailor ranges in stores.</p>
          <p>I don't want to talk about why they weren't at the heart of it. I think we were doing quite a lot, but the truth is we can do a lot more, and do a lot a more we will be doing. I don't know if you follow the blogosphere any, but when we did the first loyal customer mailing, I well remember one customer saying, "At Tesco, they know me so well. They've sent me hair removal cream vouchers and loads of money off chocolates." And that's an example of how you &#x2013; because you understand how customers behave, you can give them a reward. That really means something for them. And that's what I mean about personalization.</p>
          <p>You then asked about success. I'm not going to be drawn on that, really. I understand why you have to ask it, but I listen to what customers say and I get a feeling for whether we're doing the right things or not. And I'm determined that's what we do. We've laid out a very ambitious plan. We're very confident of its delivery, but it does require executing and that's what we're in the process of doing. So I'm sure you'll get the opportunity to ask that question time and time again, and I'll answer it when customers are showing it in like-for-like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:42:25) at Oriel. Just coming back to the online grocery business, can you say for the stores that actually have that facility what percentage of sales that is now up to for the stores in question? And whether for those online orders, how much more profitable is it to get people to come to the store and pick it up for those online orders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To pick it up, yeah. Well, Click &amp; Collect &#x2013; our Food Click &amp; Collect in-store is clearly more profitable than having to deliver it to a customer's house. I'm not going to say by how much but it clearly is. What's fascinating about it is for certain housekeepers who have very active lives and children to look after, it's amazingly convenient because they haven't got to stay home. They may be taking their children to school in the morning. They may be doing something in the middle of the day. They may be picking their children up in the evening. At weekends, they may be out engaged in family pursuits, and they can just come to a Tesco store. Within a certain number of hours, they're free to choose and pick up the groceries so it's good for them. They like it and we like it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for two more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you asked if &#x2013; the first part of your question was how big is it. Well, in some stores, it's too big is the truth because we've got more people in the store taking things off the shelf to deliver to customers' homes than we have putting it on the shelves. And so that's where the dotcom-only stores come into their own. Because by the time you've created such a powerful sales participation in a hypermarket, you can pull that into a dotcom-only store. You're just shifting the trade from one unit to another, and you then free that store up to do a better job for its customers. And that's when we do a dotcom-only store.</p>
          <p>There are obvious ranging and productivity implications for the business from doing it. But actually, there's a big benefit because it just gives the stores a bit of room to breathe and to focus on the bricks and mortar customers. So that's another angle to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two more questions. <mark type="ph" /> Edward (1:44:39)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning. <mark type="ph" /> Edward Oban (1:44:42) from Morgan Stanley. Just to come back on the international, in the fourth quarter, when I look at your like-for-like volumes in your international market, it looks like they were down in eventually all of your markets. And, in fact, in recent years, like in the UK, you had like-for-like volume contraction in a large number of your international markets, again, if you deflate from CPI while margins have increased in Asia and in Europe. Aren't you running the risk that the margin could start going the other like in the UK with the contraction in volume? Do you identify that as a risk on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well &#x2013; you okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you're right. At the moment, consumers are feeling the pinch and so they are not spending on the big ticket discretional items that usually drive the top line underneath that. That's a very different picture between what happens in food and what happens in general merchandise and clothing. So it's dangerous looking and it just that one level, <mark type="ph" /> Edward (1:45:42).</p>
          <p>So we take great solace from the way in which those businesses perform in their different categories. And then, of course, they're young businesses that are growing in their maturity in economies that, if we get a bit of tailwind rather than the headwind that consumers have been facing for more than a few years now, then we think that we'll be able to maintain our sales growth, get back to volume growth and maintain margins at where they are today if not improve them.</p>
          <p>Then Laurie is &#x2013; you heard him just mention in the answer about the Internet, increasingly leveraging the skill and scale of the group is what we need to do. My example of the toaster and the kettle is not an isolated example. Most of the general merchandise that we buy for Europe now comes to the UK and vice versa. So we're buying it once, and we're improving our buying capers and doing the same in food.</p>
          <p>So there's a lot more to come in terms of our own productivity without just taking it straight from the customer because we know giving value back to the customers is what matters most, particularly at these difficult times for them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason Molins, Pramerica Investment Management. Just in terms of your balance sheet structure, given the margin weakness together with obviously an increase in your pension deficit and lack of deleveraging, how important is retaining your A minus rating? Obviously Moody's have you on review and downgrade at the moment and maybe will review post these results so maybe if you can give a bit of color on that, that would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the credit rating, it's important to us. We've given it a lot of focus. Moody's have put us on negative outlook. To be honest, their feedback to us is it's not as a result of our financial performance, the strength of our balance sheet, how we're making progress and all of those financial metrics which has been pretty good, really, since 2008 where for instance RCF to adjusted net debt was just below 16%. We're coming up above 19% now, nearly in the 20% category which is a safe A rating haven.</p>
          <p>What they're concerned about was more the reaction to our profit warning and how strong the UK franchise was. That &#x2013; we were given very positive marks on the strength of the UK business as a market leader producing reliable profit growths. So it's more of that that's made them put us on negative outlook.</p>
          <p>Deleveraging, I mean our gearing is going down quite quickly. Our gearing is about 38%. I've given the balance sheet a lot of discipline in terms of fixed charge cover so even the adjusted net debt and the level of indebtedness. The level of indebtedness target we're getting very close to. We've got more work to do on fixed charge cover but we're just below like kind of 4 to 4.5 at the moment. But overall, I think we've done some very good work on the balance sheet. It's much more disciplined than it ever was. And of course, this new phase that we're moving to in terms of lower capital-intensive spend will help the balance sheet a lot as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. The IR team will be around for the rest of the day if you have any more questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>