<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1219854" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>41</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Douglas Shapiro, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jeffrey L. Bewkes, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">John K. Martin, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jeffrey Bewkes</participant>
      <participant id="6">John Martin</participant>
      <participant id="7">Douglas Shapiro</participant>
      <participant id="8">Michael Nathanson</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jason Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="10">Anthony DiClemente</participant>
      <participant id="11">Tuna Amobi</participant>
      <participant id="12">Michael Morris</participant>
      <participant id="13">Douglas Mitchelson</participant>
      <participant id="14">Richard Greenfield</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jessica Reif-Cohen</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and thank you all for holding. Hello and welcome to the Time Warner First Quarter 2009 Earnings Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Today's conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
          <p>And now I will turn the call over to Doug Shapiro, Vice President of Investor Relations. Sir, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and sorry again for the delays. This morning, we issued two press releases; one detailing our results for the first quarter and the other reaffirming our 2009 business outlook.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, there are a few items I need to cover. First, we refer to certain non-GAAP financial measures. Schedules setting out reconciliations of these measures to the most directly comparable GAAP financial measures are included in our earnings release and trending schedules. These reconciliations are available on our website at timewarner.com/investors. A reconciliation of our expected future financial performance is also included in the business outlook release that's available on our website.</p>
          <p>Second, today's announcement includes certain forward-looking statements, which are based on management's current expectation, actual results may vary materially from those expressed or implied by these statements due various factors. These factors are discussed in detail on Time Warner's SEC filings including its most recent Form 10-K and Form 10-Q. Time Warner is under no obligation and in fact expressly disclaims any obligation to update or alter its forward-looking statements whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise.</p>
          <p>Finally I'd like to point out that the updated trending schedules that were posted on our website this morning include recast financial information for 2007 and 2008.</p>
          <p>Thanks and let me now turn the call over to Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug. Good morning, everyone. I hope you can hear us. I'll just jump right in. This quarter, we completed the cable spin, a big step forward in reshaping Time Warner. So today we're a much more content-focused company. And with the advantages of our brands and our scale, I think we're firmly on track to achieve our key goals: to make Time Warner the leading content company in the world, and to improve our stockholders' returns.</p>
          <p>We performed about in line this quarter with what we anticipated despite the obviously challenging economic environment. Advertising at AOL and Time Inc. especially is proving even tougher than expected when we last talked a few months ago. Home video has improved somewhat since the fourth quarter, but remains challenged. Nevertheless, we posted relatively solid growth from our content businesses in the quarter with content group adjusted OIBDA up 3%. And this morning as you saw, we reaffirmed our outlook for the year.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to the longer-term, we need to do four things to drive the company forward. First, leverage our brands and our operating scale to make the best content. As consumer entertainment choices increase, we're seeing hits growing in their value. And of course nobody can make only hits, but the scale of our operations helps us to achieve better economics from the content we make, and those superior economics coupled with our strong brands helps us to attract the best projects and the best talent.</p>
          <p>Second, we need to operate our businesses as efficiently as possible. Last year, we took major cost-saving steps at New Line, Time Inc. and Corporate. This year we're taking further measures at AOL and Warner Brothers. And those are well underway. This isn't just a matter of one-time reductions. We will remain as you have seen us do over the last 18 months focused on improving our efficiency and our productivity across the entire company.</p>
          <p>Third, we need to expand our presence internationally with a particular focus on certain key regions. Last month, for example, we announced an investment and a channel partnership with CME, one of the premiere media companies in Central and Eastern Europe. This deal is a natural extension of our efforts to expand our networks globally because CME is ideally positioned to benefit as the economy there rebounds, and as the TV business in those countries continues to develop towards multi-channel.</p>
          <p>And then fourth, we need to develop new business models that exploit changes in consumer usage and in technology. We get a lot of questions about how the economics of our content businesses will evolve. We've always used our leadership position to advance models that improve our economics, and we will continue to do that.</p>
          <p>I'd like to give you just a few examples. Turner was one of the first cable programmers to foresee the convergence of offline and online inventory. And so Turner pioneered the idea of multiplatform buy.</p>
          <p>According to Nielsen, CNN is by far the most integrated brand on TV. That's the largest audience of combined television and online users of any network, whether it's a broadcast or a cable network, and this broad reach enables CNN to attract more advertisers across more categories than any of its competitors, and to sell more multiplatform ads than anybody.</p>
          <p>Or consider HBO, which has been consistently innovating since its launch in 1972. It was the first cable network to broadcast on a satellite, the first to offer multiplex channels, the first to offer high definition, and then first to offer on-demand programming. So that today HBO On Demand is the largest and most viewed on-demand network, and it has reduced churn significantly.</p>
          <p>A few weeks ago, going in that chain of development, HBO unveiled something called HBO Go, which is an online extension of the HBO service for HBO subscribers. It will use a quick and easy authentication process and offer over 650 hours of programming. That's about three times as much content as is available through HBO On Demand.</p>
          <p>HBO Go is an example of an important initiative that we call TV Everywhere. The idea is simple. If you subscribe to a TV channel at home, you can watch it for free on broadband from any provider, wherever and whenever you want, on demand. With over 90% of U.S. households already paying for television, programmers will be able to give consumers even more for their money. There is a tremendous level of interest in TV Everywhere across the industry, and we're working with several distributors on a trial slated for the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>Warner Brothers is also continuing to lead the industry and developing new businesses. When Warners pioneered the idea of DVD sell-through, other studios balked. It became the largest source of profits in the film business. The other studios also balked when we championed VOD day and date, as a way to offset the maturation of standard DVD. Now it's one of the fastest growing and most profitable segments of home entertainment. And the other studios are starting to follow Warner's lead.</p>
          <p>Over at Time, Inc., we are certainly feeling the effects of a difficult magazine advertising environment, but we aren't assuming that this is all cyclical and will automatically come back when the economy turns. We've been aggressively moving to right-size our cost structure and focus our resources. At the same time, Time, Inc. has been the most aggressive publisher in moving its content to the web. Today it gets 15% of its domestic ad revenue online. That's more than any of its peers by a pretty significant margin.</p>
          <p>Shifting away now from our content businesses, AOL faces different challenges and opportunities. This quarter we hired Tim Armstrong as AOL's Chairman and CEO. Tim is one of the most highly regarded executives in the internet sector, and he's ideally suited to lead AOL. He started just three weeks ago, and we will have a lot more to say in coming weeks and months about his plans. But it's fair to say that Tim wouldn't have come to AOL if he didn't see a lot of upside in the value of AOL's brand, in its products, and in its inventory.</p>
          <p>Among Tim's priorities getting AOL back to industry-level growth rates is to substantially improve the yield management and make AOL once again a must buy for premium advertisers. He's already moving quickly to refine the company's strategy, its areas of focus, and its organization. Tim will also play a key role working with us to determine the best structure for AOL. We intend to announce our plans about that very soon.</p>
          <p>Before wrapping up, I'd like to finish and touch on the balance sheet. Our separation of cable not only increased our strategic and operational focus, it also significantly enhanced our balance sheet in terms of both the strength of the balance sheet and our flexibility. We know how important capital allocation is to the value of our stock. And we take that very seriously in this era that we're all in. To remind you of our priorities, we start with reinvesting in our businesses, which usually provide us the highest return opportunities. We also look to return value directly to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>As you know, we've decided to maintain our dividend after the cable separation, so it now represents a significantly higher payout ratio. We aim to grow the dividend over time as free cash flow grows.</p>
          <p>We have 2.2 billion remaining on our stock repurchase authorization. We intend to restart our buyback as soon as we can, conditions warranting, after we announce our plans for AOL.</p>
          <p>As an ongoing discipline, we will also of course look at potential acquisitions that can improve our businesses' competitive positions, but we know that most M&amp;A in the media sector has not created value. So, any deal we do will have to be compelling strategically and will have to clear our financial return hurdles.</p>
          <p>It's tough out there in the economy, no question. But I feel very good about how we're positioned. We have powerful, enduring brands, industry-leading scale, and a strong management with a long record of innovation. We've increased our focus on efficiency and our balance sheet is extremely strong. We're just as eager as you are to improve our stockholder returns, and I'm confident that we're on track to do just that.</p>
          <p>Again, thanks for joining us today. And I'll now hand off the call to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff, and good morning, everyone. There are slides that are now available on our website to help you follow along with my remarks. And let me begin by mentioning two basis of presentation points. Because the separation of Time Warner Cable was completed in March, Time Warner Cable's financials are presented today as discontinued operations for the current and prior-year quarters. In addition, on March 27, we completed a one for three reverse stock split, which is reflected in our per share results and our business outlook.</p>
          <p>So turning now to the first slide, which presents our consolidated financial highlights for the quarter. As we expected, the operating environment was difficult. In addition to the tough ad conditions, we faced significant headwinds from the continued decline of AOL's access business, the stronger U.S. dollar, and higher pension expense.</p>
          <p>In fact, while revenues decreased about $500 million in the quarter, roughly three quarters of this was due to just two factors, the decline in FX and AOL's access revenues. Looking at OIBDA growth in the first quarter, FX was about $70 million drag, and pension expense was up $30 million year-over-year, so the two together reduced OIBDA growth by approximately 600 basis points.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding these headwinds, we were able to maintain flat margins relative to last year through careful cost management across all of our divisions. On an aggregate basis, we reduced operating expenses by 7% in the quarter or about $400 million. Costs were lower at all of our divisions other than Networks and at Networks they were up only low single digits. And as Jeff said, we remained very, very focused on cost control, and we plan to continue to drive efficiency gains.</p>
          <p>And if you in the quarter look at just the Content Group as Jeff said so we're not including AOL in the numbers here, adjusted OIBDA grew nearly 3% with both Film and Networks up double digits. We consider that to be pretty encouraging in light of the current environment. We had another strong quarter of free cash flow, converting 83% of adjusted OIBDA.</p>
          <p>Now please turn to the next slide for our EPS results. In the first quarter 2009 diluted EPS was $0.46, and that was flat to last year. Adjusted EPS, which excludes certain items that affect comparability, was $0.45, and that was down $0.03 from the same period a year ago.</p>
          <p>Turning to free cash flow on the next slide, it was about $1.3 billion in the quarter. And as I mentioned that was a very high 83% conversion ratio. This ratio does tend to be higher in the first quarter. And that's due to positive swings in working capital, primarily in our film division as well as timing of interest and tax payments. Nevertheless, it's a really terrific start to the year, and it highlights the relatively low capital intensity of our content businesses. CapEx, for example, was less than 2% of total revenue in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the next slide, we ended first quarter with $10.4 billion in consolidated net debt. That's half the level we ended with at the end of last year. And this reflects the $9.25 billion special dividend that we received from Time Warner Cable as well as more than $1 billion in free cash flow generation. With the separation of Time Warner Cable now complete, our leverage ratio is about 1.6 times, and that's based on the last 12 months adjusted OIBDA. That's also exactly where we expected it to be.</p>
          <p>In March, we used the proceeds from the special dividend to repay our $2 billion term loan facility, and we paid down the $2.5 billion outstanding on our bank credit facility. So we ended the quarter with a little more than $7 billion of cash on hand, and nearly $7 billion available on our revolver. Obviously that's very significant balance sheet capacity, more than we intend to operate the company with on a longer term basis.</p>
          <p>In the near term, one thing to remember is that the degree of excess capacity will depend in part as to what our decision is with respect to AOL's structure among other things. And I'd also want to point out that with Time Warner Cable being able to raise debt in the current quarter to repay its bridge loan, we are no longer providing them with a supplemental loan facility. So that's good news.</p>
          <p>Looking now at our divisional results, moving forward in the presentation, beginning at our Networks, we had solid revenue and double-digit OIBDA growth in the quarter. Subscription revenues were up 9%, and that's due to higher affiliate revenues at both Turner and HBO, as well as the impact of consolidating HBO Latin America.</p>
          <p>Advertising revenues declined 2% over the prior year, and that was primarily due to softness in our international networks at Turner, which were down mid-teens. And about half of that was due to unfavorable foreign currency. Our domestic networks were about flat in the quarter reflecting a slight decline in entertainment and a small increase at news.</p>
          <p>Margins expanded nearly 200 basis point year-over-year, as a result of a very small cost increase. And this drove OIBDA up 11%, well ahead of revenue growth. Key cost drivers here was modest growth in programming expenses and lower news-gathering costs. The consolidation of HBO Latin America also contributed to growth in the quarter on the OIBDA line.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead into the second quarter, scatter market pricing is about flat to upfront levels, however business is getting booked very close to air date which somewhat reduces our visibility. And second quarter cancellation levels are up over last year. International advertising at Turner is also tracking the decline in the second quarter and when you add these two together, we're currently expecting advertising revenue to be down somewhere mid-single digits in Q2, and just a reminder, last year's second quarter, we had very, very strong ad growth, so a tough comparison year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Moving on to our Film Division, Warner Brothers also posted solid OIBDA growth in the quarter. Revenues declined 7% due mostly to tough comps in both home video and theatrical, as well as unfavorable foreign currency. This was partially offset by higher TV licensing revenue as compared to the WGA strike last year.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter of last year, we had 13 key home video releases led by I Am Legend compared to only five this which included Body of Lies and Nights In Rodanthe. First quarter theatrical releases this year included Watchmen and the carryover from Gran Torino and Benjamin Button and this compared to 10,000 B.C. and Fool's Gold and carryover on I Am Legend and The Bucket List, last year.</p>
          <p>OIBDA in the quarter was up 10% and that's despite the decline in revenues and that was driven by lower P&amp;A due to the fewer releases, lower restructuring charges, and lower overhead following the reorganization of New Line. This was offset by higher TV production expenses, again as compared to the strike-affected quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Looking into the second quarter, we have very high hopes for two theatrical releases: Terminator Salvation and The Hangover. However, please keep in mind that we once again will have difficult home video comparisons as we anticipate five key releases compared to 10 last year. We will also incur additional restructuring costs, and those will be related to the previously disclosed initiatives and that compares to essentially none in the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Publishing, where both first-quarter revenues and OIBDA were down pretty substantially year-over-year. Total advertising revenues declined 30%, reflecting lower print advertising, unfavorable FX at IPC and a decline in online advertising. Eight of Time Inc.'s top ten advertiser categories experienced year-over-year declines, in particular: food, pharma, and auto. And I point out that the decline in print was almost entirely driven by volume, which we think will help revenue rebound once demand comes back into the market.</p>
          <p>And in addition, I've mentioned that based on PIB data, Time Inc.'s, domestic advertising share actually grew modestly in the quarter. Subscription revenues were down 16%, about half of that was due to unfavorable FX, and it was also affected by disputes we had with two of our wholesalers during the quarter, which did disrupt the supply chain. We also did start to see some softness in subscription renewals due to the economy, but this only had a very small effect in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The OIBDA decline was due to a number of things, the decline in revenue, offset by reductions in the cost base following all of the restructuring efforts that were previously put into effect. And Time Inc. also incurred an $18 million increase in bad debt reserves related to a newsstand wholesaler.</p>
          <p>It's worth noting that costs for Time Inc. are incurred relatively evenly throughout the year, but that advertising is very seasonal with the first quarter traditionally being our smallest quarter of the year. I mention this because it makes the first quarter our lowest margin and highest operating leverage quarter, and we would not expect a similar level of either OIBDA margin or year-over-year OIBDA percentage declines for the remainder of the year even if the ad market did not improve from Q1 levels.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, second quarter print advertising remains challenged. And it's pacing similar to Q1. And again, as a reminder, visibility here remains limited. But with easier comparisons in the second half of the year, we clearly hope trends begin to improve.</p>
          <p>Turning to AOL, where the first quarter results were also affected by the continued downturn in advertising, total ad revenues were down 20% to $443 million. I'm going to briefly walk through the three components here. Display on the AOL network was down 17% to $158 million. As has been the case in recent quarters, yield declined as more inventory was monetized through lower priced sales channels, which carry lower CPMs. Unlike in recent quarters, however, we also started to see some pricing pressure on our reserve inventory, and key categories remain challenged such as finance, consumer products, autos, and telecom.</p>
          <p>Paid search revenues declined 12% to $152 million, and that was due primarily to lower query volume and to a lesser extent, lower revenue per search query on certain AOL properties as well as lower click-through rates offset by increases in cost per click. And as we began to discuss with you last quarter, we do expect search revenues to remain pressured this year due to the continued migration of domestic users to aol.com and away from the client, as well as algorithmic changes put into place by Google that reduce our effective cost per click.</p>
          <p>Looking at the last component of advertising, third-party revenue declined 29% to $133 million in the first quarter. The absence of one large customer, Apollo, and this is probably going to be the last quarter we refer to this. But the absence of Apollo contributed about $16 million to the year-over-year decline, that's about one-third, and since the agreement was terminated in the first quarter of last year, this should be the last quarter of any meaningful comparisons for Apollo. Excluding Apollo, third-party network revenue was still down 23%. This reflected lower demand for both performance and branded advertising on the network, and retail and autos were particularly soft.</p>
          <p>Moving over to the other side of the business, AOL's access business lost 570,000 subscribers in the quarter, and that's actually down a little bit sequentially from losses we experienced in the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>OIBDA was about $255 million in the quarter. That's down 37%, as the decline in revenues more than offset lower TAC and G&amp;A costs. And as I mentioned last quarter, we expect that AOL will incur up to about $150 million of restructuring charges this year. And in the first quarter, we incurred about 58 million. So looking ahead, advertising revenues thus far in the second quarter are tracking down about the same level we saw in Q1 in percentage terms.</p>
          <p>And before I move on beyond AOL, I do want to make two more quick points. First, we recently received and successfully completed a consent from the holders of about $12 billion of our debt. And that provides us with much more flexibility with regards to AOL's structure going forward. So we view that as good news.</p>
          <p>And second, I point out as we highlighted in our 10-Q filing today, we have notified Google of our intent to acquire their 5% stake in AOL. So while we remain open to other potential solutions, working it through with them, the next step in the process is an independent valuation of AOL and the process will likely take a few months.</p>
          <p>The next slide briefly touches on our corporate expenses. They were down 22% year-over-year. Last year we lowered corporate costs by about $80 million on a run rate basis and the steps that we took a year ago are still benefiting us in the first quarter and obviously we're continuing to look hard at our costs everywhere, but here at corporate, as well.</p>
          <p>Moving on to our business outlook, last quarter we said that we expected our 2009 adjusted EPS to be about flat. The $0.66 in 2008 which I went on further to define as a few pennies, about 5% up or down. Taking into account the 1 for 3 reverse stock split, our 2008 base has now been adjusted to $1.98. We still expect adjusted EPS this year to be around flat compared to last year. And I think it's fair to say that a likely range of outcomes is still plus or minus 5%.</p>
          <p>Regarding our quarterly results, I'd remind you that our comparisons are meaningfully more difficult than the first half to three quarters of this year. So our assumption of around flat adjusted EPS reflects expected declines in the first three quarters which would then be offset by growth in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of the progression throughout the year, we expect that the second quarter will be our most challenging from a growth perspective. The outlook for ad growth is relatively similar to Q1 and our home video comparisons at Warner Brothers are expected to remain challenging.</p>
          <p>The second quarter is also our most difficult comparison period in terms of restructuring expenses, and we should also expect higher programming costs at our Networks Division based on amortization.</p>
          <p>So that really covers the review of the first quarter. And obviously we're trying to provide you some context on what we see for the second quarter and full year. We appreciate you listening in and your interest in Time Warner.</p>
          <p>And with that let me turn the call over to Doug so we can start the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Could we please get the Q&amp;A started?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question is from Spencer Wang [Credit Suisse].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. Two questions, I guess the first is for Jeff. Jeff, you alluded to the maturation of the DVD business. Yet digital has been a little bit slow to develop. I was wondering if you could just talk a little bit about how you can or plan on accelerating the transition to digital over the next, call it one to two years to smooth out the transition from DVD?</p>
          <p>Then John, you mentioned cost savings a lot and the focus on cost. Can you just talk a little bit about where you see incremental opportunities to take out costs both at the corporate level and maybe divisionally? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Spencer. Let me start with DVD; strategy first and a couple of points on what's happening. We're number one in the fastest growing parts of the business, which are Blu-ray and VOD and electronic sell-through. We happen, I think, to by usually at the top on the old standard DVDs too, but in those new areas having a pretty big slate and the scale of distribution that we have globally, not just in the U.S. really helps us to get our products featured and get very good terms for it.</p>
          <p>We're pretty strong in catalog because of the size of the library. And then adding the product not just from Warner but some TV product from HBO and Turner and the Warner TV slate, which is large in addition to its film slate, is essentially the starting building block for how we're doing this. And as I mentioned in my prepared remarks, we always try to be at the forefront, to your question, of leading the new model.</p>
          <p>So if you look at moving into Blu-ray or iTunes, the margin improvement there &#x2013; it's 70% up in margins on electronic rental as we move to day-and-date and VOD, it's 40% or so in moving to iTunes or electronic sell-through. So that's really why we're going first on all of these transitions. And it's &#x2013; and the results that we're getting, we think are going to bring the rest of the industry with us as they have in the past. So, that's basically how we're approaching it to speed it up. I'll leave it for follow-up, if there's more to that question.</p>
          <p>And John, you have the other question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So as it relates to costs and I guess the way that we like to think about it is it's not just cost cutting, it's trying to wherever we can identify areas to improve the efficiency of our operations and redeploying the capital to more productive uses. So, just quickly looking across the company, I mean, if you look at what the studios are doing out at Warners, they're in the midst of implementing and executing on a very material shared services project that will affect any number of functions. It's resulting in a material and meaningful reduction in work force, and it will take some time to complete the implementation. But we believe once it's completed the payback will be within 24 months post completion, so a very, very high ROI.</p>
          <p>If you look at our publishing business, we're going to benefit this year from the material restructuring that was put into place last year. That essentially reorganized the company from top to bottom in terms of being much more clustered around magazines that make sense. And we said that we expected the benefits this year to be $175 million. I suspect that we'll probably even do better than that. And we're obviously continuing to look at where we can save money given the challenging environment that our publishing business is operating in.</p>
          <p>At AOL, we're focused on continuing to rationalize the cost base against the revenue opportunity. On the web business, I know what Tim is really focused on, where we need to make the right investments to drive product development and make sure we're making the most with our investments there and we're looking at focusing and rationalizing our facilities across the country.</p>
          <p>Even our Networks Business, which we don't talk a lot about, Phil Kent and the team there as well as Bill Nelson and the team at HBO have done a really good job of holding down costs and redeploying it to more productive areas like programming. And so that's one of the reasons why we expect we're going to see nice margin expansion there in that line of business.</p>
          <p>As far as corporate goes, we've really significantly reduced corporate already. And I think the function that corporate is going to play going forward is trying to work collaboratively with our divisions to look at ways that we can across the company save additional moneys by leveraging our scale in any number of areas. And you'll be hearing more about that in the coming months.</p>
          <p>So, I think there are opportunities across the entire company. I think we've done a good job. It's one of the reasons why our results are, we believe are relatively resilient versus the rest of the industry. But obviously we're going to continue to work hard on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks for the question and I meant to say: please try to hold yourself to one question so we can accommodate as many people as possible. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Michael Nathanson [Sanford Bernstein].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I have one for Jeff, and then just a quick one for John, Doug; I'm sorry. On the cable network side, I wondered, what percentage of revenues are now from international markets? And what's the strategy to increase scale in those markets from the HBO perspective and the Turner perspective?</p>
          <p>And John, if you spun AOL, would your target leverage ratios change in terms of where you want to be? So that's the two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe &#x2013; to jump in there, Jeff, just in terms of percentage revenues from international, just rough justice is around &#x2013; think of it being around 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. How we are going &#x2013; let's do HBO and then Turner. On HBO, we have been buying in partner shares in South America and HBO Asia and HBO South Asia. And that's essentially not only improving or increasing our financial exposure, it's also increasing our ability to direct what happens with HBO in those regions, and it has made possible future coordination between HBO network activities and some of our other networks at Warner, Turner, and even local ones like Claxson or CME that we are becoming partners with. So that's one general direction in the case of HBO.</p>
          <p>It's worth noting wherever HBO is operating overseas, it's number one in its market usually, maybe only one exception to that.</p>
          <p>At Turner, I mentioned CME, but the &#x2013; there's very strong position for CNN in the international English language news business both on TV and online. There are some countries in which we have it in a local language. The real speed grower in Turner networks overseas is Cartoon Network, which in certain key markets like India and Brazil that we've identified as important, it's the leading market in those populations, and those are huge future kids populations.</p>
          <p>So we continue to both, extend the programming strength on those networks, CNN, Cartoon Network, and then do the things that you saw us talking about today whether it's beefing up partnerships with strong networks like CME, whether it's buying Claxson's group of thematic networks in South America, and then operating them in a suite of channels where you have not just the Turner Networks that you know in the States, but some of the ones that are specifically purposed overseas. Another one comes to mind &#x2013; REAL network in India, which Turner and Warner really work on together and which just launched a general entertainment network in India. You'll see us doing more of that if we find good opportunities to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Michael, on your leverage question, just as a quick reminder, our stated target leverage is about 2.5 times, notwithstanding the fact that we're currently operating at around 1.6 times. I wouldn't suspect if the decision is made to separate out AOL, I wouldn't anticipate, that it's going to result in any material change in our view as to the stated target leverage. But obviously if AOL is on its own footing, the remaining Time-Warner would no longer benefit from the earnings and free cash flow generation from AOL.</p>
          <p>So depending on how AOL would be capitalized which obviously no decisions have been made there either, you could see leverage go up at TWX somewhat. And I would sort of end by saying that we all recognize that we enjoy very significant, meaningful capacity, and it's one of the reasons I wanted to mention it in my remarks which is that we have more capacity right now than we intend to operate the company with on a go-forward basis longer term. But if were to separate out AOL, we would anticipate and expect that Time-Warner would still have very adequate and attractive financial flexibility and capacity going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Jason Bazinet [Citi].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just have a quick question regarding the disclosure in the Q about potentially buying the AOL stake from Google. Does that reflect your interest in the asset, or is that just to give the company more flexibility regarding timing given the provisions that Google has?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean as you know there's a process that Google started off. And it could result in them registering their stake or us buying it back. And our interest in the property would obviously depend on valuation. And we're going to start to move down that path. It's not a material amount of money one way or the other. I don't think it's an &#x2013; it's not a huge &#x2013; it's not a huge or material event for Time Warner in total and as I said in my remarks, there's still some conversations we'll have with Google and we're open to other suggestions. But at this point the disclosure in the Q, just wanted to make sure that we said that we're moving down the path that could result in us acquiring back the stake.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I &#x2013; can I just ask one follow-up housekeeping question? I guess on the trending schedule we used to get the international ad numbers at AOL. Can you give those or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Jason, this is Doug. We can talk about that offline. I mean basically it's usually about one-third, two-thirds: international, domestic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Anthony DiClemente [Barclays Capital].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, just one question for Jeff. I was hoping you could continue to elaborate more on TV Everywhere, the authentication concept. And just thinking about this potential solution, how feasible is it that you can get the distributors and the programmers together on this both in terms of the technical aspect and then the actual incentive for a cable programmer, be it a small one or a larger conglomerate? What would the incentive be for them to &#x2013; to become a part of TV Everywhere or not to? Thanks for your comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. I think the whole thing is very simple. You've already got a billing system running efficiently through the current providers of video, which would be the cable MSOs, a couple of satellite companies and telephone companies. They're currently providing multi channels TV networks to over 90% of American households. So all the billing and all of the authentication is done already. They've all got it, it's pretty simple.</p>
          <p>Given that we're all talking about letting viewers, 90%-plus of Americans watch programming they've already paid for, having a check-in software that simply asks did a given consumer pay for this by pinging the cable operator, satellite operators and phone operators is a very simple instantaneous thing. It's much more simple for example than an iTunes billing activation for buying something online or for a Google search algorithm. And the incentive for all of the distributors to join and help this to occur is that it supports all of their video revenue. And so it seems pretty simple.</p>
          <p>From the network's point of view, it's also pretty clear, any multi-channel network that's got dual revenue streams has clearly got a benefit in making that channel and brand loyalty move across any platform or device, because if I just speak for our company, it's good for TNT or HBO that if you've got it in your home, you can watch it out of your home and on VOD, and that we can then maintain the subscription payment you're already making and the ad sales cross platform ability that's really exciting in media.</p>
          <p>So the system is simple. It's not hard. It doesn't present any blocks for consumers and it's clearly in the interests of all cable multi-channel networks and all video providers. There's really absolutely &#x2013; there's nobody that it isn't in the interest of, really. And the outliers at this point seem to be broadcast networks, which are in a clearly different position and have different problems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Tuna Amobi [Standard &amp; Poor's].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. So I wanted to ask about any update you have, Jeff, on the Bebo re-launch, and when you think that the user metrics overall at AOL will begin to converge with the monetization initiatives there? Or you expect Tim Armstrong to be focused on in the next year or so?</p>
          <p>And if I can have a separate question quickly for John. Do you foresee any instance where, for example, your so-called content oriented adjusted EBITDA could decline this year and still hit your EPS targets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, John second, Bebo first. Since the Bebo acquisition, we keep re-launching key parts of Bebo. The social inbox was launched in early December. It includes integrated email, aggregated social feeds. In February, we launched a new home page, which had a profile on it. It had your timeline experience. And it had our aggregated feeds platform, which is called Lifestream.</p>
          <p>Over the next couple of months, phase two of the Bebo rollout will happen with an introduction of products in the United States, including a new desktop client. On usage of Bebo, overall comScore uniques are up 5% year-to-year in the first quarter to about 24.5 million. That's driven primarily by the United States activity. But we've also seen growth in Australia, New Zealand, and Ireland. The uniques at Bebo did decline 15% in the U.K. due to Facebook competition. And page views have been down across the board.</p>
          <p>So that's on Bebo. Quickly transitioning to your AOL question, what will Tim do? It's a little early after a couple of weeks, but basically, as I said in the remarks, he's working hard, as is the team at AOL, to better capitalize on our existing products and content, and to build into a few of the white space areas that we see emerging that fit AOL's core strength, some of which we'll keep to ourselves until we occupy them.</p>
          <p>It's a little early to talk about targets. But we feel strongly, and Tim does, too, that AOL has to hold itself to being a leader in the growing space of its competition with the other big companies. And we have to have metrics that reflect that growth.</p>
          <p>We have put up, as you saw us announce, some room in an envelope for additional restructuring, and we're moving pretty quickly, as we also said, to refine the organization and the emphasis in our operating resources commitment to those areas that are growing and pulling them away from those that that are not growing. We do think we've got the building blocks, though, for the turnaround at AOL, which we see underway in both usage and monetization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll be quick. And unfortunately I'm going to refrain from giving any specific OIBDA guidance. It's one of the things we decided to do coming into the year with the difficult operating environment. We thought we had enough leverage to manage and be able to deliver about flat adjusted EPS, and as a result of that, I just don't want to get into any more specifics on OIBDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Michael Morris [UBS].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Can you expand a bit on the trends that you are seeing in network advertising, especially as we head into the upfronts? In particular it seems that demand is clearly a bit softer, but pricing has remained flat. So there's a couple things I'd like to try to figure out, is one -- as you compete with the broadcast networks, where are your CPMs on some of your key programs or your offering there? And what's your value proposition heading in this year?</p>
          <p>And then number two, how do you view the risk of maybe some aggressive price competition given that it appears that demand is a bit softer heading into the second quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the second one, we're probably not &#x2013; I'm not and John isn't going to give tactical responses to how we're going to handle price competition. But just in general, we are in a very good position on television advertising competition at Turner. Because we have the scale, reach, ratings and quality program environment that are &#x2013; the advertisers want on TV. And then we have the final weapon, which is very attractive pricing in relation to broadcast.</p>
          <p>So the CPM gap is again starting to close. If you have TBS and TNT in the top three, you've got Adult Swim number one in the adults 18 to 34 group, CNN's total day ratings continuing to grow, and with the CPMs at about two-thirds of broadcast, that's a very good environment for us. And if you just look at what's been happening recently, in the last year's upfront, our price increases were the highest across any network group in television, whether it was broadcast or cable.</p>
          <p>And so in general to your question, cable is taking viewership at an accelerating pace. If you look at just the first-quarter '09 versus '08 last year, cable's up over two million total viewers this year versus last. In this year's season to-date, cable was up 3%, broadcast is down 5% in Primetime. The Primetime share of cable is 60% versus broadcast at 40, and yet the ad dollars are 30% for cable and 70 for broadcast. So that's a huge, huge hunting reservation to go out &#x2013; off to.</p>
          <p>And you've got broadcast off to the worst start that it's had in a decade. It's down nearly 2 million adults, 18 to 49. And its season starts are off 7%. More than three quarters of the shows returning to broadcast are down this year in ratings.</p>
          <p>So if you look now at the upfront, which is starting to come into play, it's hard to predict with a lot of certainty, but we are very well positioned, given what we just said about the reach and quality and ratings of our networks. And with broadcast getting into those kind of problems and having that much exposure on its pricing, we think that advertisers are going to be continuing to look at TV as a total picture, and making economic decisions about where they can get the bang for the buck in a good environment, in terms of programming environment.</p>
          <p>So that's how it looks to us. We really can't go into our tactics of how we're going to use those advantages.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Doug Mitchelson [Deutsche Bank].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. So Jeff, as you consider your options with AOL, I'm wondering if you have concerns regarding any loss of synergies between your Content Group and AOL. I guess I was not surprised but still amazing that you noted in schedule six where you breakout AOL and Content, and then eliminations between the two, that there's only $8 million of eliminations for revenue and none at all for EBIT. So that implies there's essentially no synergies between AOL and Content. Is that right?</p>
          <p>And the second part of the question is just the 10-Q said management's committed to spin-off all or part of AOL. What are the factors that are going to drive your decision on AOL, since you don't have board approval yet? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first, in terms of synergies, you can't just look at synergies from financial eliminations. They tend to arise when you're selling things through different parts of your company in a supplier-customer relationship. And that's not the only way that you can get an advantage as a branded media company with TV networks, magazines titles and so forth; putting them online and having the giant audience of something like AOL, and potentially ad sales coordination. So I would say having said those things, we have joint ventures like TMZ, and a number of showcases and traffic movements that occur between our publishing company, our networks, and our studio, back and forth with AOL, which is a huge repository of uniques and page views.</p>
          <p>Having said that, that doesn't necessarily turn into commercial and accounting postings, because those are promotional in some cases, or audience building and image building, they're not sales. And that really speaks to what portals and online services like Yahoo and AOL are. They're not rights holders. They don't buy and exhibit rights, by and large. So from the point of view still on synergy of what use can branded media products like Harry Potter, HBO, TNT make of the AOLs and Yahoos and MSNs of the world &#x2013; they can do that by essentially getting all of their audiences' exposure to those branded products on all platforms, which would include not just AOL, but the others.</p>
          <p>And that I think gives you a clear idea of where AOL will compete, because it will compete on that basis with the Yahoos and MSNs. And all of them will be useful traffic and new form of media augmenters for things like network TV and branded franchises like Harry Potter.</p>
          <p>When you go to the &#x2013; you're asking, I think, about the process, and what factors we put into making our decisions on spin or not. Basically, if you ask the question what is the &#x2013; what are the arguments or reasons why, theoretically, you would separate a company like Time Warner Cable, which we just did, or in this case AOL, the obvious goal was to &#x2013; whether you can improve the value of both sides: the entity that goes out, if it goes out, and Time Warner, which would be answered by &#x2013; you'd have to answer the question, do you improve the strategic focus and strategic options of both AOL and Time Warner, if they were separate?</p>
          <p>And do you, moving more specifically to AOL, improve its ability to attract and retain talent? And would that AOL business as it goes forward be better capitalized and more appealing to a specific shareholder base that might be different than the one that is investing in the Time Warner media company? When we answer those questions to the point that we can explain them to all of you, then we will then take action. And we anticipate that will not be too long from now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Rich Greenfield [Pali Research]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Question &#x2013; when you look at your Film business, there's a comment in the 10-Q that you took back ownership of four films at least temporarily, and maybe more films later this year. Wanted to know what films were those that are no longer being co-financed? And given the fact that they won't be co-financed, were these profitable films, and therefore, will you book more revenue and profit because of this, or less? How does that play out?</p>
          <p>And then a follow-up for Jeff about the whole TV Everywhere thing. CNN is not just about videos. Could you envision charging ISPs for access to sites such as CNN or TMZ, such as ESPN 360 does, especially as broadband ARPUs appear to be on the rise with higher speed broadbands rolling out? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. On the four films, John will answer it, and we'll come back to that. There was another question in there before the &#x2013; before the TV Everywhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He wanted to know who the co-financing was with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh. Do you want to start? Okay, I'll do TV Everywhere. First of all, Rich, I think you've been writing some great stuff on the other companies. So that's great.</p>
          <p>I don't think that, if you take the specific case of CNN, while I'm not right now going to give an absolutely firm answer that we wouldn't have some layer of service at CNN that you might not have reason to charge for, having said that, in general, we think that when our viewers or network watchers have paid for a network like CNN, TNT, HBO, that that programming ought to be available on all platforms on demand. And we have basically if you look at our record on this done precisely that with HBO when we put it on VOD. We've moved it to kind of a uniform availability. Some of our distributors haven't, but that's what we've basically done.</p>
          <p>So we don't really envision having broadband being a charging mechanism. It's not really the way broadband currently works. It's not likely to be if you moved in that direction an advantageous trade to move to charging over broadband versus what's currently existing. And it's not particularly consumer friendly to do it what that way. T</p>
          <p>The way we're talking about is making it free, making it easy for people to use so that they don't have to worry about whether they're walking in their house and looking at their TV on the wall, and then they walk out the door with their laptop or their handheld. They ought to be able to use the network, TNT, CNN, HBO the same way in all those environments and on all those devices. And the simplest way to do that is just to rely on what's already built which is they've already paid for it and it's already been collected and the mechanism is simple and reliable to do that. So that's why we believe this is a simple way to evolve the industry very quickly because speed is important, to get this out and in consumers' hands as quickly as possible. And not have them have to worry about whether they're getting it this over TV streaming versus Internet broadband delivery. John's going to answer the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'll take the other question. Look, just by way of quick context, Warners for a long time has been entering into co-financing relationships with partners. They have a diverse portfolio of wholly owned films, JV films, acquired films and distribution deals, and those are specifically designed to minimize financial risk of maintained upside. And our existing financing agreements typically cover multiple films that are produced over a multi-year timeframe.</p>
          <p>It is true as we disclosed in the Q that one of our largest co-financing partners has not been able to, up until now fund its share of production costs on certain films, and as you mentioned its four films. They are still in the process of trying to obtain their financing. If they do, great. We've had a long-standing relationship with them. I would prefer not to mention who it is specifically because I'm not sure that they would appreciate that. And I'd prefer accordingly not to mention the specific films, but as we said in the Q it's four films.</p>
          <p>It will not have meaningful impact to our P&amp;L one way or the other. It would in the near term have more impact on cash because we would recoup some of the cash that we've been fronting. But if for whatever reason they can't obtain financing, we're also not that concerned about our ability to finance films going forward given all the flexibility and given our position in the industry. So hope that's enough on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's take the last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Jessica Reif-Cohen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I was wondering if you could comment, probably for Jeff, how do you see your asset mix changing longer term? It's clear you're on path of &#x2013; or AOL is on the path of being separated. Is publishing a critical asset for a content company? And despite your comments on M&amp;A historically, you are different management team now than you were when you bought AOL. So I guess another way -- you're the only company in the industry with a cash position. Is that not a competitive advantage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is a competitive advantage but only if you use it well. In terms of the complexion or proposition of Time Warner and your specific question, is publishing a core business, there are a lot of thing that are attractive about publishing even if it's experiencing a tough ad market right now. And for one thing, like our other Time Warner businesses, it is a branded content business. And it &#x2013; and it can go across multiple platforms like our networks.</p>
          <p>Time Inc. publishing has lead scale in its business domestically and in the places where it's operating overseas. It has a very high cash flow generation. We think it can grow and readership is up in a number overall and a number of the brands more than others.</p>
          <p>Now having said that, there are obviously some questions which are -- is the situation in publishing, magazine publishing specifically, cyclical or secular? And, how does it compare to what's happened in the cousin business of the newspapers? We think that's a very different business than newspapers. And if you take some of the key differences, magazine readership is growing, whereas newspapers were declining. And the percentage of Americans that read magazines is twice the number percentage &#x2013; 85% versus 48% reading newspapers.</p>
          <p>And then a very critical set of differences, magazines are national, not local. And they are not relying on classified ads. So that's -- those are some of the positive points on print and magazines.</p>
          <p>Some of the questions, of course, remain -- there's been a fairly long pressure on the ad market. There are pressures on key advertising sectors that have traditionally supported things like the news magazines business. There are clearly differences between magazines that are frequency, weeklies and biweeklies are much healthier than monthlies. Style, fashion and magazines that appeal to women have been much stronger and more prone to growth and to cross platform success than others.</p>
          <p>So, there are definitely a lot of questions about how that specific business works overall. But &#x2013; and there will probably be a further shakeout in that industry. And so there's a lot of things to address. And I'm not going to go off solely on magazines. But we're very focused with the magazine management on those questions and how to make our publishing company the most successful amongst its competitive set. And then as &#x2013; assuming that we continue to do that, we then have to determine what is the best financial structure for that business in the long run.</p>
          <p>Back to the rest of Time Warner, which may well include publishing, but we're not making a religious statement about it either way at this point. Clearly, the lead that we have in worldwide film and television production and distribution and television-branded networks not just on TV but online is a significant business opportunity. It's growing around the world. It's growing due to digital. We have advantaged position, and it's something we know how do. So those will be the guiding focus points of Time Warner going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>With that, I think we're a few minutes past the hour. I apologize again for the technical delay at the beginning. And thanks a lot for listening in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That does conclude today's conference, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>