<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1165149" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>41</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Douglas Shapiro, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jeffrey L. Bewkes, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">John K. Martin, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jason Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jeffrey Bewkes</participant>
      <participant id="6">Douglas Shapiro</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jessica Reif Cohen</participant>
      <participant id="8">Benjamin Swinburne</participant>
      <participant id="9">Tuna Amobi</participant>
      <participant id="10">Richard Greenfield</participant>
      <participant id="11">John Martin</participant>
      <participant id="12">Michael Morris</participant>
      <participant id="13">Douglas Mitchelson</participant>
      <participant id="14">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="15">Anthony DiClemente</participant>
      <participant id="16">David Joyce</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello and welcome to the Time Warner Second Quarter 2008 Earnings Call.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Today's conference is being recorded.  If you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn the call over to Doug Shapiro, Vice President of Investor Relations.  Thank you, sir; you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and thanks and good morning everyone.  Welcome to Time Warner's 2008 Second Quarter Earnings Conference Call.  This morning, we issued two press releases, one detailing our results for the second quarter and the other reaffirming our 2008 business outlook.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, there are a few items I need to cover.  First, we refer to certain non-GAAP financial measures. Schedules setting out reconciliations of these historical non-GAAP financial measures to the most comparable GAAP financial measures are included in our earnings release or trending schedules.  These reconciliations are available on our website at TimeWarner.com/investors.  A reconciliation of our expected future financial performance is also included in the business outlook release that's available on our website.</p>
          <p>Second, today's announcement includes current forward-looking statements which are based on management's current expectations.  Actual results may vary materially from views expressed or implied by these data due to various factors.  These factors are discussed in detail in Time Warner's SEC filings including its most recent Annual Report on Form 10-K and quarterly reports on Form 10-Q.  Time Warner is under no obligation to and in fact expressly disclaims any obligation to update or alter its forward-looking statements whether as a result of new information, future events, or otherwise.</p>
          <p>Finally I'd like to draw your attention to Time Warner's new quarterly investor newsletter, inFOCUS, which features news and operational highlights from our businesses and we think you'll find it helpful.  It's now available in the Investor Relations section of the company's website.</p>
          <p>With that covered, I'll thank you and turn the call over to Jeff.  Jeff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug. Good morning everybody.  With half the year behind us, today is a good time to take you through what we've achieved so far and what we're working toward in the months ahead.  If you boil it down, our goal at Time Warner is to create, package, and distribute high quality branded content across multiple platforms and all around the world, and doing all of that at the highest returns possible.  When you hear that word platform, you tend to think of it as an organized beach.  For us, it's basically TV screens, computer screens, movie screens, magazine pages, anywhere that media content goes in the world and whichever one is most important in the country where you live.</p>
          <p>At the beginning of this year, we laid out three key objectives to help us reach this goal: first, to make sure we have the right businesses in the right structure; second, to improve the competitive position and the operating performance of all of our businesses; and third, to actively manage the balance sheet.  So as we've been doing, I'd like to start with the first of these priorities, our structure.</p>
          <p>I think we've made substantial progress since we last got on the call.  In May, we announced the terms of our separation from Time Warner Cable.  This is the right step for both Time Warner and Time Warner Cable stockholders because it will increase the long-term strategic, operational, and financial flexibility of each company.  It also marks an important step in the continuing transformation of Time Warner.  Since May, we've made a lot of progress towards the cable separation and we still expect the deal to close around year end.</p>
          <p>Still on the structure area, turning next to AOL; we've now made the key financial and strategic decisions that will enable us to operate the access and audience businesses separately.  First, we classified all of AOL's assets and liabilities into one of three groups: access, audience, and a shared service group that will support both of the operating groups.  Second, we're finalizing operating agreements among these groups so that they can operate fairly flexibly. And we are pretty clear that implementing these decisions in the coming months should enable us to begin running these businesses separately in 2009.  So with the progress we've made on that to date, we have the necessary flexibility to do something strategic with either of these businesses today.</p>
          <p>In the film area, still on the question of structure, we also essentially completed the reorganization of New Line Cinema.  We still think that the cost savings and revenue improvements will produce benefits in excess of $140 million annually, starting next year.  And then last, our effort to streamline our corporate cost is running ahead of our target of $50 million in annualized reductions this year. That was all the structural moves that you know that we've had underway.</p>
          <p>Let's move to our second key objective, improving our operating performance.  Overall, we're delivering results in line with our plan and in line with our guidance, as you saw this morning, despite the tough economic climate.  Some of our businesses are tracking ahead of expectations. Some are essentially on target, and some are behind.  Let me start with the businesses that are performing ahead of expectations this year, Networks and Film.</p>
          <p>At Turner, we posted another quarter of very strong financial results with 11% advertising growth and double digit subscription revenue increases.  Ratings remain strong at our largest networks. Beginning with CNN, delivery was up better than 20% in the key prime-time demos compared to last year.  The election season is helping of course but we're also taking share.  Consider that CNN is also up almost 20% from the second quarter of 2004 and that was a comparable period in the last presidential election. Each of the broadcast networks' news divisions and our key cable news competitor are down double digits over the same period, so that's essentially the news sector inside Turner.</p>
          <p>In Turner's entertainment networks, also posting very strong growth, TBS up 33% and TNT up 8% in the key prime-time demos, and TNT's original programming strategy which we've been talking about on these calls continues to gain momentum.  Last month the premiere broadcasts of The Closer and Saving Grace captured the number one and number two highest rating cable debuts for this year.</p>
          <p>We've long maintained that our entertainment networks are broadcast substitutes and this position has increasingly resonated with advertisers as we've continued to enhance our brands, our programming, and our reach, but never more so than during this year's upfront.  On average, our entertainment networks posted CPM increases in the high single digits and dollar volume increases well into the double digits. These increases mark the top end of the entire TV universe; that includes both broadcast and cable.</p>
          <p>Subscriber supported television, after a pause last year, HBO is on track to again grow its OIBDA by double digits this year. That's driven by solid affiliate fee growth and a very predictable, well managed program expansed base. Underscoring its continued success in attracting top talent, HBO received the most Emmy nominations of any network for the eighth year in a row, 85 nominations, 23 for John Adams alone. And if you saw John Adams, he was alone a fair amount of the time.  In recent months, HBO has accelerated its production of pilots for original series, and it now has more in development than at any time in its history, with the goal of having new seasons of original shows on every quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let's go to Warner Bros.  Warner's has had an extremely successful run this year.  Unless you're living in the Batcave itself, by now you know that you are aware of the record breaking summer of the Dark Knight, which is now on track to become the second highest grossing film of all time.  And who knows, we might make it to the top.</p>
          <p>Some view the film business as unpredictable.  It has not really been our experience at our company because viewed through the prism of a multiyear time-frame, the Dark Knight is no fluke.  Our studios have now produced eight of the top 15 grossing films of all time, and no other studio accounts for more than two.  This success reflects our scale and our strategy, the machine we've built up around tent poles from development to production, marketing and distribution particularly, manufactures hits, and turns them into a hit over a multiyear period and has done so consistently.  It's the film business, so occasionally we misfire as we did with the Speed Racer, but our hits far outweigh our misses, and you can see it in the consistency of our financial results in film.</p>
          <p>It also reflects our ability to mine our intellectual property.  You're familiar with three of our most successful franchises, Batman, Harry Potter, Lord of the Rings.  These three are already among the top six highest grossing franchises ever at the box office worldwide.  And there are more films yet to come from each of these franchises.  And please, keep in mind that we have yet to exploit much of our DC Comics' portfolio or our vast TV library.</p>
          <p>For example, our most successful theatrical release in this second quarter &#x2013; remember, Dark Knight is third quarter, in the second quarter were Sex and the City and Get Smart, both originating as TV shows.  And the success of Sex and the City, just to pick one, was particularly gratifying because it's a property that touched so many parts of our company. It had its inception on HBO. It was syndicated with great success on TBS, then became a film produced by New Line. And finally was marketed and distributed worldwide by Warner Bros.  So that would be one.</p>
          <p>Another example that we are very excited about coming up, Star Wars Clone Wars.  This will be the first CGI Star Wars theatrical release.  It will be released by Warner's next month in theaters. And after that, we'll debut the Clone Wars TV series on Cartoon Network. And then it will have a rebroadcast on TNT.</p>
          <p>Now Warner Bros. also continues to lead the industry in the most promising growth areas in the film business.  Two of these are Blu-ray and VOD.  As you know, since our decision to embrace the Blu-ray format exclusively, industry sales have accelerated significantly.</p>
          <p>We've been the most aggressive studio also on the VOD front.  For example, next year every release with the exception of Harry Potter coming out of Warner's, will be released to VOD day-and-date. And in both Blu-ray and VOD, we have the highest sales of any studio, substantially over- indexing relative to our theatrical share.</p>
          <p>Now still in the film segment is the games business, and our games business is also ramping up.  LEGO Indiana Jones was the top-selling video game in June, and we have high hopes for LEGO Batman, as you can imagine, which we're releasing in September.  Over time, we expect games to become an increasingly important part of Warner Bros. business.</p>
          <p>So moving from there, now I think I'd like to move over to the business that performing essentially in line with our financial expectations, but it's actually ahead on subscriber growth, and that's Time Warner Cable.  As you heard on its earnings call earlier this morning, Time Warner Cable posted another quarter of very strong RGU net additions. It was the best second quarter in its history.  And that's in pretty stark contrast to concerns about the impact of competition, whether from phone or satellite, and the economy.  So the company remains on pace to achieve the key elements of its full year financial outlook.</p>
          <p>Turning last to AOL and publishing, these are both tracking behind our expectations this year, but for different reasons.  At AOL, there continue to be encouraging signs about the underlying health of the business. In particular, it continues to post strong usage growth, which is accelerating from last quarter.  Total page use, for example, during the quarter on the AOL network were up 6% over last year, powered by almost 60% growth in our content protocols, which shows the success of all our recent relaunches there.</p>
          <p>In addition, as John will outline, our third-party advertising business continued to deliver solid growth, even in a difficult ad environment, which highlights the competitive position and the value of platform ads.  But as anticipated, display advertising declined in the quarter; it was down 14%.  We saw pull-backs in some ad categories, notably autos, financial services, telecom, and travel. But we believe this performance was also due to the continuing effects of the acquisition integration issues that we discussed in our last earnings call because, as you remember, we put a lot of pieces together over the last year.  And as we cautioned then, we did not expect to reverse those trends in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The good news, or the better news, is that we've made substantial progress since then, particularly this month. During the recent period, Platform-A is now fully integrated.  That's across sales, marketing, operations, and engineering.  And we fully integrated Dakota and Quigo targeting technologies, which we can now offer access to across the AOL network inventory and across, of course, the third-party network. We remain optimistic, as we said last time, that we're going to see the benefits of these organizational changes starting in the second half.</p>
          <p>And then moving last to publishing, which as I said, is behind our targets.  Of all our advertising driven businesses, Time Inc. felt the greatest impact from the difficult advertising environment.  There was softness in the quarter across many of the same categories, including pharmaceuticals, autos, cosmetics, and financial services.  And that drove down advertising revenues by 9% year over year in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Online ad revenue continued to grow rapidly, but this quarter it was not sufficient to offset the decline in print. There are a number of bright spots in our publishing business. Time Inc. continues to drive traffic to its websites. Unique visitors are up more than 30% year over year in the quarter across all of its sites, according to Nielsen.  And magazine readership growth also remains strong.  We have about double the growth pacing of the rest of the industry in the second quarter.  And our publishing company continues to manage its cost structure aggressively.  So we don't know when the ad market will turn, but we are confident that Time Inc. will be well positioned when it does.</p>
          <p>I'll close by touching on our third primary objective, which is actively managing our balance sheet.  We define that as maintaining a level of leverage that supports a solid investment grade rating for our businesses while balancing opportunities to invest against returning capital to stockholders.  Our first priority in using our financial capacity will always be to continue investing in the growth of our businesses, but this is unlikely to use much, certainly not all of our excess capacity.</p>
          <p>We will also pursue acquisitions, those that improve our competitive position and our growth prospects in our existing operations, but only in a disciplined way.  And that means the expected return on investment must be better than alternative uses of our capital, including repurchasing our own stock. Of course, with the current price of our stock and earnings multiples attached to that; that is a high hurdle to meet in acquisition assessment.</p>
          <p>And we do believe strongly in the merits of returning capital directly to stockholders.  You may notice in our press release that we didn't buy back any stock in the quarter.  We do consider the stock extremely attractive at current levels.  But in light of all that we have had going on, we decided it was prudent to stay out of the market.  As you know, a key element of the cable separation is when it closes around the end of the year, Time Warner Cable will pay a special dividend to all of its shareholders, including 9.25 billion to Time Warner. That step will better optimize the balance sheets at both Time Warner and Time Warner Cable.  And post-close, it will provide Time Warner with a lot of flexibility.  We regard that as an important advantage, but we recognize that it also has raised questions about how we intend to use this capacity.  We just want you to know that as we assess our capital allocations options, we will continue to adhere to the disciplined framework that I just outlined.</p>
          <p>In sum, I'm proud of how well we performed so far this year.  We've made significant progress on our key objectives.  And on the whole, our businesses have proven resilient in a tough economic environment, as evidenced by our ability to reaffirm our full year business outlook.   The resilience stems from the strength of our brands, from the expertise of our people, and the scale of our operations, which we believe give us a sustained advantage in creating, packaging, and disturbing the most compelling content worldwide.  It's something Time Warner has always done extremely well and it's why I'm excited about both our continued transformation toward an even more content focused company and about our long-term growth prospects.  Certainly a lot more to do, but we believe we are taking the steps to deliver the most value to shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thanks for listening and now, I'll turn over the call to John Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff, and good morning.  I'm going to briefly provide some additional context around the second quarter results. And as usual, there are slides now available on our website to help you follow along with my remarks. So jumping right in, the first slide shows our consolidated second quarter financial highlights.  There were a few takeaways to what we believe was a pretty good quarter overall.  First, revenues were up 5% year over year or $575 million and adjusted OIBDA grew 4% or $115 million.</p>
          <p>As you know, we've been increasingly thinking about our businesses in three buckets, and they are cable, content, and AOL. In the second quarter, it's interesting to note that Time Warner's results, when you exclude the impact of both cable and AOL, so effectively just the content businesses which we're defining as Networks, Filmed Entertainment, and Publishing, plus corporate expenses and eliminations, those revenues grew high single digits in the quarter, and adjusted OIBDA was up 11%.</p>
          <p>The second takeaway is that our adjusted earnings per diluted share increased a solid 9% compared to the year ago quarter.  And third, we have now generated $2.9 billion of free cash flow year to date, which is a terrific start to the year and it represents a very high OIBDA conversion rate of 46%.</p>
          <p>The next slide shows a little bit more detail related to our EPS figures.  Diluted EPS was $0.22, which compares to $0.25 for the second quarter of 2007.  Both quarters, however, had notable items affecting comparability.  These are highlighted in broad groupings on this slide and in greater detail in our earnings release.  Adjusting for these, the quarter's EPS was $0.24 and the 9% growth rate was due to both higher adjusted OIBDA and a smaller outstanding share count due to our buyback program.</p>
          <p>Turning to free cash flow on the next slide, as I mentioned, year-to-date free cash of $2.9 billion is up considerably over the first half of last year, almost $900 million in fact. Much of this difference is due to a positive swing in working capital so far this year but we do expect at least a portion of this to reverse in the back half of the year. Our cash interest expense is relatively flat and CapEx is also flat or approximately flat over last year with 83% of our capital at the cable segment year to date.</p>
          <p>It's interesting to see that when you exclude Time Warner Cable, the company's CapEx represents only about 2 to 3% of our revenues, which is very, very low. I'll also add that Time Warner has been delivering significant free cash flow on a very consistent basis.  In fact, for nine of the last 10 quarters, our free cash flow has been close to or above $1 billion.  And I believe in the eight of the last ten quarters, our conversion of OIBDA has been in excess of 30%.</p>
          <p>Turning to the next slide, we are reaffirming our full year business outlook and echoing what Jeff just said, we're encouraged that our business performance has proven resilient overall.  And I think it's fair to say that the economic environment is clearly more challenging than we anticipated when we first provided our outlook at the beginning of the year, and that's particularly true for the ad environment.</p>
          <p>In this outlook we focus on three measures. First, we reaffirm that adjusted OIBDA growth should be in the range of between 7 and 9% this year. As I indicated last quarter, based on current trends we continue to expect to come in at the low end of the range. And recall please that this includes an estimated $140 million of restructuring charges at New Line, which we also didn't incorporate into our original outlook, and that represents about one full percentage point of growth.  So when you take that into account, we'd actually be tracking right in the middle of the range. Given our first half actuals, that also means that we do expect our second-half OIBDA growth rate to improve versus the growth rate we experienced in the first half.</p>
          <p>Next, in addition we reaffirm that free cash flow should be at or above $4.5 billion. And in light of the very strong conversion levels so far this year, we're extremely confident that we'll be able to achieve this.</p>
          <p>Last, we also reaffirm that diluted EPS should be in the range of $1.07 to $1.11.  Accounting for items that are affecting year-over-year comparability, this reflects solid double digit growth over last year. I'd also point out that we're reaffirming both EPS and free cash flow outlooks despite the higher financing and other separation related costs that we are incurring this year tied to the cable separation.</p>
          <p>Turning to now to our balance sheet; next slide.  We ended the quarter with $34.6 billion of net debt. That's about flat compared to where we were last quarter.  Year to date, net debt is down about $1 billion. That's due to $2.9 billion of free cash flow generation, offset in part by about $1.3 billion in acquisitions and $450 million in dividend payments.</p>
          <p>As you know, in June Time Warner Cable completed a $5 billion bond offering.  This allowed them to reduce the amount of bridge financing required to pay the planned special dividend. And importantly, that offering also reduced the size of the supplemental loan commitment Time Warner provided to Time Warner Cable beyond the term of the bridge facility. That commitment goes from 3.5 billion to $2.5 billion, so we're very pleased with that.</p>
          <p>I'm going to move now to briefly cover the key highlights of each of our divisions and so continuing through the slides, beginning with our cable company. As you know, Time Warner Cable held a call earlier this morning to discuss its impressive second quarter results.  I hope you were able to listen into that. OIBDA grew 9% in the quarter and the company continued to generate very strong levels of free cash flow.  And as we outlined on the next slide, subscriber metrics were very strong across the board.  As Jeff mentioned, it's the best second quarter ever in terms of RGU new net additions at 650,000. That's up 20% from the 546,000 it added in last year's second quarter.  And it also posted better year-over-year net ad performance in every key RGU category.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to mention with regard to the important high-speed data product, Time Warner Cable added more than 200,000 net subscribers in the quarter, which is more than the net adds of the top two telco companies combined.  Overall, these are very, very strong results showing both Time Warner Cable's economic resilience and continued ability to compete effectively.</p>
          <p>I'll move over now to the content businesses, starting with our Networks segment.  Our second quarter performance here is very, very encouraging and it's evident that our strategies here are working very well. Adjusted OIBDA rose 15%, boosted by another quarter of double digit subscription and advertising revenue growth.  Subscription revenues were up 10%, reflecting solid growth in affiliate fees at both Turner and HBO and subscribers at Turner. Turner has now had five quarters in a row of double digit year-over-year subscriber revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Turner's ad business is also strong, climbing 11% with double digit growth in both the entertainment and news segments. This growth was driven by healthy audience gains, as Jeff mentioned, as well as higher CPMs.  And Turner has now posted double digit advertising growth four quarters in a row.</p>
          <p>In terms of the advertising outlook looking out for the rest of the year, keep in mind that our growth comparisons will become more difficult in the second half compared to the second half of a year ago.  So while continuing to deliver double digit gains may prove increasingly difficult, we do feel very, very good about how things are pacing at Turner. The current scatter market is healthy. We're still running ahead of upfront pricing levels, and we continue to see upfront cancellation rates at normal levels. We also continue to anticipate that HBO and Turner taken together will deliver strong adjusted OIBDA growth this year and will likely post the strongest growth rate of any of our segments.</p>
          <p>Moving to Film, where we posted another impressive quarter and things look very good for us here for the rest of the year, OIBDA rose 13% in Q2. This is due in part to the DVD performance of I Am Legend, The Bucket List, 10,000 BC, and Fool's Gold. The quarter also benefited from higher TV contributions and solid box office results from Sex and The City and Get Smart. The quarter did also absorb the disappointing results of Speed Racer; and as Jeff said, please keep in mind The Dark Knight was released after the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking to the remainder of the year if you were to look through or exclude the New Line restructuring costs, we are very confident that we will be posting positive year-over-year growth from the Film segment and this will obviously be bolstered by the phenomenal performance of The Dark Knight.</p>
          <p>OIBDA growth in the second half of the year should be weighted more towards the fourth quarter as our third quarter results will be impacted by difficult year-over-year TV and home video comparisons. And by contrast to that, the fourth quarter will benefit from the home video releases of The Dark Knight, Get Smart, and Sex and The City.</p>
          <p>Turning to Publishing, revenues declined 6% in the quarter as a 1% increase in subscription revenue was more than offset by a 9% decline in ad revenues. OIBDA declined 11%, potentially due to the decline in ad revenues offset in part by lower expenses.  And as Jeff said, and I'd like to underscore, Time Inc. continues to aggressively manage its costs in an effort to both weather the current economic environment and make sure it is well positioned to capitalize fully when it turns.</p>
          <p>We continue to see softness in print ad demand, particularly in pharmaceutical, auto, toiletries and cosmetics, and finance categories. That limits our visibility somewhat into ad growth for the rest of the year. And right now, I would mention that third quarter print advertising is actually pacing somewhat below where our second quarter performance was. As a result, we think it will be challenging to achieve OIBDA growth in this segment for the full year, but please keep in mind that our current business outlook already takes this into account.</p>
          <p>Finishing up with AOL, the dynamics this quarter were very much consistent with what we saw last quarter. In the audience business, we saw very strong usage trends and continued strength in our third-party ad network business.  But as expected, display advertising was impacted by the acquisition related integration issues as we discussed with you last quarter. In the access business, the rate of subscriber declines continued to moderate as did the year-over-year decline in subscription revenues. Adjusted OIBDA was down a comparable amount year over year as we saw in Q1. But as I'll explain, we do believe the second quarter is the low water mark for adjusted OIBDA this year at AOL on both an absolute dollar and a growth rate basis.</p>
          <p>Focusing first on advertising here, total ad revenues were up 2% to $530 million. Just as a reminder, advertising at AOL consists of display, paid search, and third-party network revenue, each of which makes up about a third of the total. Walking through the components quickly, display declined, down 14% to $191 million. That reflected more units sold at a lower effective CPM, driven primarily by a mix shift away from higher priced guaranteed inventory to lower priced non-guaranteed network inventory.  And as Jeff said, the decline in display was to due to the integration issues that I just mentioned as well as softness in certain key advertising categories.</p>
          <p>Paid search revenue improved 10% year over year to $172 million, due largely to new search products and higher revenue per search.  And the performance of AOL's third-party network remains strong. Revenues were $167 million in the quarter; that's up 15%.  Keep in mind that this figure includes acquisitions and the change in the Apollo relationship that we've been discussing with you. Excluding the impact of the acquisitions, which contributed $40 million to the year-over-year growth, and Apollo, which was down $43 million, third-party network advertising revenues were actually up 26%.</p>
          <p>Looking into the second half of the year, we expect both the overall advertising and display advertising growth rates at AOL to improve from the pace we saw in the first half, as we encounter easier year-over-year comparisons and we'll begin to benefit from the organizational changes made during the first half of the year at Platform-A.</p>
          <p>Moving into the access business for moment, AOL lost 604,000 subscribers in the quarter. This does represent the smallest subscriber decline in any quarter since the company announced its strategy shift two years ago. AOL had 8.1 million domestic subscribers as of June 30.</p>
          <p>Its adjusted OIBDA in the quarter was $350 million. That's down 28% versus the year ago period.  That was due to both difficult comparisons in the quarter in our access business and continuing advertising mix shift toward our third-party network, which has resulted in higher traffic acquisition costs or TAC.  We expect to see an improvement in the rate of adjusted OIBDA growth in the second half as comparisons get easier, advertising revenue growth improves, and we continue to tightly control costs.</p>
          <p>Finishing up with a quick look at corporate spending on the next slide, as you know, corporate is an area where we have committed to reduce our overall level of spending.  During the second quarter, corporate overhead declined 13% year on year. And as Jeff just mentioned, we are now tracking ahead of our target of reducing corporate expenses by $50 million this year or about 15%.  Beyond this goal, we're keeping a tight rein on expenses, and that will continue to be a way of doing business for us.</p>
          <p>So thanks.  And let me turn the call over to Doug as we'll start the Q&amp;A portion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Candy, we can turn to the Q&amp;A.  Please try to limit yourself to one question so that we can get to as many callers as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have our first question from Jason Bazinet, Citi. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much. You mentioned that you've completed the economic split between the access and audience business, opening it up to strategic options.  I just had a question on the access part of the business. I think most investors contemplate the dial-up business essentially merging with another dial-up provider and then doing a spinoff. I was just wondering if you could articulate any alternative to that strategic path that the Street is focused on as the most likely outcome.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, Jason. We have said that, and of course, we will assess all of the options.  And I think all of you have written or read about pretty much every conceivable one.  One that ought to be thought about really as a benchmark against any kind of strategic change in our position in access would just be operating it and seeing if the cash flow from that operation is superior to any deal we can get, putting it into alignment with some of the usual suspects that get mentioned.  So we are just going to do it objectively as a business question. What we're really trying to say is that we've now organized it from an operational point of view to number one, provide the best competitive results out of the access business, assuming it operates under its current structure; and then number two, to give us the flexibility to do whatever is in the best interest to maximize the value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next, Jessica Reif Cohen, Merrill Lynch, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Jeff, in the beginning when you mentioned your goals in multiple platforms globally, I'm just curious, given your balance sheet, what areas of interest on a global basis would you have for acquisitions? I mean it seems like a lot of cable networks will come up for sale domestically, but how hungry are you for something outside the US?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, Jessica, we don't like to use the word hungry when we eat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, bad terminology.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we talked about acquisitions because I think we were pretty clear about how we look at those, if you just work from our strategy, we're already one of the leading branded content distributors in the world. That's probably &#x2013; which I sense your question is more from an international perspective, a lot of that is seen if you are living outside the United States in our branded television or online networks.  However, we do have a fairly large film business that supplies a lot of networks everywhere.  And those are the best &#x2013; if you look at the weight of Time Warner right now, so that's the weight of most of our international business.</p>
          <p>There are network &#x2013; I don't want to call them just television networks because they aren't any longer just that.  But there are television networks, online networks, and content production, branded content production capabilities that are at scale all over the world, and we will look at those to, as we said, from not just a financial point of view, but think of those areas in which you can put us in a superior competitive position.  We can't really be more specific than that. We're fairly large and fairly global. And anything that comes up, you'll hear us obviously in a disciplined way looking at it.  But it doesn't mean we're going to necessarily go and do any particular thing that comes up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Next we have been Ben Swinburne, Morgan Stanley. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. I wanted to ask, Jeff, about the home video and electronic delivery business.  You guys give a decent amount of disclosure in the Q.  First half of the year both on the television and the theatrical side, that business is growing in the teens. And you disclosed also your DVD units that I think are down globally year over year.  So obviously, there is a lot of stuff going on in that revenue line which is, I believe, a very high margin line in the Film segment beyond just DVD units. Could you talk about that? What's driving this growth?  Is there something that's specific to just the releases you've had and the success recently?  Or should we look at this business as this is a double digit growing business on the top line going out of the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to give it a try. As you can see from our schedules and what John was relating here, year to date our home video sales overall are up about 6%.  The overall industry is about flat year to date.  We think that the industry will be flat or slightly up.  We think that between the combination of standard definition and Blu-ray sell-through, the market will be up modestly next year.</p>
          <p>On the DVD shelf space, the question of what &#x2013; if this is part of what you're thinking, many of the major retailers have increased the shelf space for DVD, and they've added incremental shelf space for Blu-ray High-Def at the expense of music and accessories. So just in terms of how the distribution at retail has gone, it has run up store displays and the circulars have also not decreased at all. That's essentially our outlook if you take High-Def and combine it with standard def.  You may want to ask something about international.  But that's our overall look.</p>
          <p>If you then go off the packaged home video into VOD, the margins are quite a bit better.  So we think those are secular reasons why the margins would go up and the earnings can go up over time in home video.  And if you add the final point, which we were making in our organized remarks, our relative competitive position out-indexes for any given level of slates how everyone else does.  So we essentially plan and we design our operations to outperform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next, Tuna Amobi, Standard &amp; Poor's Equity Group, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much, I guess my first question for Jeff. Can you reconcile for us your film strategy?  On the one hand, you seem to be squarely focused on the event film strategy.  Yet, you're trending down on the specialty arm.  So how does the New Line and Warner Independent and Picturehouse restructuring tie together into your film strategy in terms of number of films, et cetera?  And that's the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Basically, we and I think most of the other studios have pursued directionally the same strategy.   We have at Warner New Line consolidated operations. That's why we put New Line together with Warner's to essentially be more efficient and a cross-fence so we didn't have dual infrastructures. And secondly, to be more efficient in driving revenue by using &#x2013; by number one, taking the New Line films and keeping international rights; and number two, putting the New Line films through the Warner distribution internationally, which is stronger than where they had been going before.</p>
          <p>To your specific question on film output, we basically have focused the release slate to about half &#x2013; it was running if you put New Line and Warner's together up between, let's say 40 or so films.  And now, it will be aiming more in the 20 to 25 side, much of it Warner's with a very big focus for the economic reasons we told you, on tent poles because those are fairly economically powerful and efficient.  We know how to do them.  And we've set up both the production pipeline, the intellectual property of title in the pipeline, and the distribution position to maximize what we do.  But we also, of course, have a full film company in terms of all the types of genres of films. And what we're going to do with New Line is essentially have that focus on the genres that it has been successful with over time. Other than that, that pretty much covers what you can say about the range of film development without going &#x2013; I mean I get lost in title by title kinds of things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot. I'll take my other questions offline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Can we have the next one, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next Rich Greenfield, Pali Capital, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, a couple questions related to AOL.  In the first quarter, you said that AOL ad revenues would improve as we go through the year.  Obviously that didn't happen in Q2.  I'm just curious why you feel so comfortable about restating that it's going to improve from here.  And then two, you've made somewhere around I think $2 billion plus of acquisitions on the Internet front supporting AOL. I was wondering if you could give us some sense of what your ROI looks like on those investments that you've made over those 18 months.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start, this is Jeff, and then John will pick up.  The general reason why we think it will improve is that we look at usage as a leading indicator. And as we said, we were giving some of the usage patterns in the key areas, AOL owned and operated content sites, third-party, and how that's trending in economics, pricing, and so on.  So that's essentially the short answer and John may want to add some detail to that.</p>
          <p>On the ROI on acquisitions, it's a fairly complicated thing. Most of the acquisitions or a large part before Bebo were acquisitions to fill out the ad platform and Platform-A.  We bet that that is still coming on stream in terms of current dollar yield that has made Platform-A a very successful competitor and a very strong asset in terms of the valuation of Platform-A.  On Bebo, we have a lot of plans and as we said we're going to integrate it and take advantage of the traffic that we have in AIM and ICQ. But certain of the plans we have for Bebo, we're not going to trumpet before we do them and you're going to be hearing a lot about that over the next few months. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just a small bit to add to each and I apologize, I'm part choking here.  Rich, with respect to the advertising, you're right. We did expect them to improve and frankly Q2 versus Q1, it did improve although albeit the improvement was modest.  Looking ahead, I think there are a few things to think about on the advertising side in addition to what Jeff said.  We also will benefit from just frankly easier comparisons, so that underscores our confidence there.</p>
          <p>The only other thing I would add with respect to the ROI taken as a whole, and Bebo just closed in the middle of May. So obviously as Jeff just mentioned, we're in the very early stages of our integration plans and development plans.  But there is a lot going on there.</p>
          <p>As it relates to the platform, assembling Platform-A with just under $1 billion of acquisitions a year and a half ago and putting that around Ad.com, which was acquired for almost $0.5 billion in 2004, we would submit that the ROI in terms of the value of what Platform-A is worth right now in today's marketplace is very significant.  And so there's the operating side of it, which is still coming online and we're integrating and we're putting all those assets together, but there is the scarcity value of having an at-scale, online, digi-display ad platform which we think those acquisitions were very, very prudent for AOL.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next, Michael Morris, UBS, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, a question regarding video games given that you refer to its importance to the company.  Can you talk a little bit about where you are right now in terms of your ability to develop or produce video games with respect to staffing and capacity versus where you would like to be?  Is it something that you can grow organically, something you'd make small or large acquisitions on?  And then along those lines, what do you see Time Warner, the existing Time Warner company bringing to the video game business?  Why as an investor do I like the concept of Time Warner owned video game investment versus a pure play video game investment?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.  We're pursuing basically two significant changes in the games business.  One is we're going to push to establish ourselves as a third-party distributor, which we've already done fairly successfully in the home video business for other people's product, but it's less common right now in gaming.  And second, we are using some film-type financing to manage the risk, some of which we got for example out of Abu Dhabi.  But what we're doing strategically is we're leveraging our own IP of the titles coming out of Warner. We're developing some new IP in partnerships with other games companies, some of whom we have either distribution arrangements with or some we have minority equity positions with, and some we have majority in.</p>
          <p>We acquired TT Games, which was the maker of LEGO Indiana Jones and LEGO Star Wars and Batman's coming up, as I mentioned.  We got the North American distribution rights for Codemasters, which is a UK-based video games publisher.  We have a small interest in something called Brash Entertainment, which is a video game publisher. And I mentioned we have the arrangement with our strategic partner in Abu Dhabi who is funding up to 250 million to co-finance the development of up to 75 games over the next seven years.  We also have an investment in SCi-Eidos, which is a UK games developer and we distribute all of these.  So there's co-development, there are game companies that we have different degrees of ownership in, all of it focused on getting the scale and distribution.</p>
          <p>And to your question of whether we have &#x2013; what we need in terms of human talent and our organization inside the company, it's something we work on all the time.  We're developing at a pace with the size of our distribution presence and we feel that we're in reasonably good shape.  If you're asking whether we can attract talent that we need, we think we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Doug Mitchelson, Deutsche Bank, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I'm just interested in John's comments on the mix shift at AOL display from guaranteed to non-guaranteed.  How far along are we in this mix shift?  And how much do you think it impacted display ad sales in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, it's John. Actually tough to tell, and I think it's in part because we have so much going on at AOL. And there was so much organizationally happening at Platform-A this year &#x2013; this quarter rather, excuse me &#x2013; that it's difficult for us to ascertain how much of it is being driven by the market versus how much of it was happening just as a result of the organizational progress that we're making. So we're going to be looking closely at this in the back part of the year and trying to understand better the organic trends and trying to improve our overall sell-through rates on the guaranteed part of the inventory, so more to come on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then can I just follow on, any concern about the pace of TAC expense increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think so. I think if you look at TAC as a percent of ad revenues, it has held pretty constant at around a third or about 35%. And we've got a decent amount of visibility on that and obviously we've got our own projections as to how fast the third-party network is going to grow, and there's an associated TAC along with that.  But I think we've got decent visibility on how that's progressing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Imran Khan, JPMorgan, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, thank you for taking my question, one question about network business.  Could you please give us some color what kind of margin improvement opportunity you see in the network segment, and where do you think that margin improvement will come from, domestic versus international, Turner versus HBO?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we think margins will continue to improve at the networks.  To your question, where will it come, we continue to invest in original programming. And so essentially what happens, and this varies a little quarter to quarter and even slightly year to year, is when you have a hit, there's a question of when the hit TV series let's say goes into syndicated or aftermarket sales.</p>
          <p>And then when that happens, you have a big revenue slug coming in and it increases the margin. That is on top of basically a secular margin increase that occurs because the revenues from affiliate fees, both at Turner and HBO and then from ad revenue growth at Turner, which we described as double digits, outpace the planned cost base increase.  Essentially we've been having costs growing in the low single digits and we've had secular subscription revenue, affiliate revenue, and ad revenue going quite a bit faster than that.  So that's potentially a margin increase and an earnings growth driver before you even get to content profits from hit series.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could just add on some of the number mechanics and I probably should have mentioned this even in my proactive remarks. I think it is worthy of a mention that in the second quarter, particularly at Turner, our margins tend to be lower than the rest of the year because we do carry the NBA playoffs and we carry a significant amount of sports programming amortization in Q2.  To put that in context, half of our sports costs get amortized for the year in Q2, and I think two-thirds of our NBA costs hit in Q2.  And I think we saw the same trend last year.</p>
          <p>Looking out to the rest of the year, and we've got good visibility with this, despite the increased investment or the continuing investment in original programming, we're going to be comping against investment in original programming last year too, so we've got good visibility on that. And we feel good about the potential for margin expansion in the back half of the year.  And at CNN, margins have been and are continuing to expand there. And the performance of CNN I think we've mentioned in the past, it has been the fastest growing network in the Turner portfolio now for some time and that's coming on the domestic as well as the international side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Candy, I think we're just going to take two more questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next Anthony DiClemente, Lehman Brothers, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the question.  This is for Jeff.  Jeff, you talked about how Warner is most aggressive on day-and-date release. Next year you're going day-and-date with every release.  Now, last night on the News Corp call, Jason asked Peter Chernin about day-and-date and he said that he remains concerned that day-and-date could cannibalize the existing DVD business. He stressed the need to protect the overall margins of the DVD business.  That implies to me that VOD margins are actually lower than DVD margins so maybe he's seeing different unit economics.  So even if those margins are up, clearly contribution dollars per unit on VOD are lower. So it would be really helpful to me if you can help clarify some of the unit economics math there and how your strategy on day-and-date could be incremental to film profits and whether or not next year when you go day-and-date, are you worried that at that point retailers might start reducing shelf space?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have not seen cannibalization so far. I don't think it's right to think that the margins are lower. In fact, they're higher by a lot on a rental obviously.  And it may not be the right way to look at really the profitability of a film as it goes through DVD in terms of either physical copy or VOD, in other words per user.</p>
          <p>So we think that since we haven't seen cannibalization on sell-through that it's going to increase margins and profitability going to day-and-date, and we think it will improve the position of our company and frankly the whole industry, which we believe will follow on piracy.  This is fairly similar in terms of the different views other studios have.  From what we did in DVD sell-through, which if you'll recall, we led the same way, we got to the same result. And we are sitting today, is why we're able to say that we out-index every other studio in DVD performance, essentially because we committed to it, developed the distribution relationships early, and went to scale early on a global basis.  We think pretty much the same here and we essentially don't agree with the overly cautious view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question, please, Candy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, we have David Joyce, Miller Tabak and Company. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  I was wondering if there are any significant cable network affiliate contracts coming up for renegotiation to think about, and also if there are any differences in your upfront selling in this environment on the cable networks.  For example, are you selling more inventory in the upfronts?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all on big affiliate agreements, they come up fairly regularly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We tend not to disclose them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't talk about them and we don't see &#x2013; but I wouldn't flag any particular different situation or concern about that.  In fact, we feel very good given the strength of the networks, the performance of the ratings, the ad sales, everything that we mentioned in our remarks in terms of affiliates.  We renewed all our carriage agreements.</p>
          <p>On the upfront, the results &#x2013; I think we said it, but if we didn't, please ask us if we don't answer it, if we haven't fully answered the question. We were at the top end of the entire TV universe.  The CPMs were up in the high single digits, dollar volume up in the double digits. The current market is pacing ahead of where the upfront was in varying degrees of strength. It's healthy. We saw the same amount of inventory, a very key point, as we did in last year's upfront in order to get those pretty significant gains, so that was the upfront. The scatter is moving up from there, not quite as much in the entertainment side as it was in the second quarter, but still up.  So it's a pretty good picture and Turner particularly is performing I think relatively better than pretty much all of the competition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And with that, thank you very much everyone for participating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>