<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1322686" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>41</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Douglas Shapiro, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jeffrey L. Bewkes, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">John K. Martin, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Douglas Mitchelson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Doug Shapiro</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Michael Morris</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Anthony DiClemente</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Jason Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">James Dix</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Richard Greenfield</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Thomas Eagan</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Time Warner, Inc. Second Quarter 2010 Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Doug Shapiro, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and good morning. This morning we issued two press releases, one detailing our results for the second quarter and the other updating our 2010 full year business outlook. Before I begin, there are two items I need to cover.</p>
          <p>First, we refer to certain non-GAAP financial measures. Schedules setting out reconciliations of these historical non-GAAP measures to the most directly comparable GAAP measures are included in our earnings release and trending schedules. These reconciliations are available on our website at timewarner.com/investors. Reconciliations of our expected future financial performance are also included in the business outlook release that's available on our site.</p>
          <p>And second, today's announcement includes certain forward-looking statements, which are based on management's current expectations. Actual results may vary materially from those expressed or implied by these statements due to various factors. These factors are discussed in detail in Time Warner's SEC filings, including its most recent annual report on Form 10-K and quarterly report on Form 10-Q. Time Warner's under no obligation and in fact it expressly disclaims any obligation to update or alter its forward-looking statements whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise.</p>
          <p>Thank you, and I'll turn the call over to Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. Thanks for joining us. We just completed another very strong quarter capping off a great first half of the year. Our revenue grew 8% and that's our highest rate in two years, with advertising revenue up 11%, its highest rate in almost six years.</p>
          <p>Adjusted operating income rose 15% and our adjusted earnings per share climbed 35%. As you saw in this morning's release, we've raised our outlook for the year. We now expect adjusted EPS to increase at least 20% in 2010, up from our prior guidance of at least mid-teens growth.</p>
          <p>Please keep in mind that that's after growing adjusted EPS by 29% last year.</p>
          <p>Our results this year have benefited from an improved ad environment, from our continued cost controls, and more than anything else, the appeal of our content and the strength of our brands. As I've told you before, one of our key objectives is to leverage our scale and brands to invest in and create the highest quality content. That in turn strengthens our brands, attracts audiences and increases our scale. It's a virtuous circle and a key competitive advantage for Time Warner.</p>
          <p>Across the company this quarter you can see our commitment to this strategy and you can see the payoff. I'll start with our networks. There's no doubt that the quality of Turner's content and the appeal of its brand helped drive its 14% advertising growth this quarter and that's the highest in years. The scatter market was healthy in the quarter, which helped our performance, but our advertising growth was so strong in large part because advertisers increasingly want to associate their brands and products with ours.</p>
          <p>Our success at this year's upfront also showed the appeal of our content and brand. Turner's entertainment networks led their broadcast and cable competitors in pricing gains and they increased volumes by double digits. In particular, we saw extremely strong demand for Conan O'Brien. In fact, we were able to achieve parity with broadcast CPMs for the show.</p>
          <p>Also, we were especially encouraged by the performance of truTV. As you know, tru recently broke into the ranks of top 10 cable networks. In the second quarter it delivered more adults 18 to 49 than MTV, Spike, Syfy and Lifetime. And tru was treated like a top 10 network at the upfront, achieving CPM increases comparable with our other large entertainment networks for the first time. So advertisers are recognizing the growing value of our programming and brands. We're confident that our affiliates will also recognize this increasing value over time.</p>
          <p>As we head into the back half of the year, we're feeling very confident about Turner's slate of original programming. One of our new shows, Memphis Beat, premiered in June as the top rated new cable series of the quarter. And last month in July, another new series, Rizzoli &amp; Isles, launched as the highest rated ad-supported debut in the history of cable. And we just brought back The Closer, which remains the number one show week after week on cable and it's up over last year.</p>
          <p>Other hit shows returning in the next couple of months include Dark Blue, which is premiering tonight, and Ray Romano's Men of a Certain Age, which is coming back in the fall. And then, of course, we'll launch Conan's show in November. This same focus on content and brand is the driving force at HBO. As you know, HBO not only has the best slate of recently released movies, but it also has the best original programming on TV.</p>
          <p>Just a few weeks ago, for example, HBO received 101 Emmy nominations, the most of any network for the 10th year in a row. Viewers agree with the critics. For instance, we recently debuted the third season of True Blood to a 40% bigger audience than last season's debut. It's now averaging about 13 million viewers per episode, rivaling the final season of The Sopranos. HBO subscribers love our unmatched selection of movies as much as ever, but our consumer research shows that original programming is an increasingly important factor in their decision to subscribe. We're working hard to build on this momentum with more new series in development now than at any time in HBO's history.</p>
          <p>Next month we'll debut Boardwalk Empire produced by Martin Scorsese, which we think will be HBO's next breakout hit, and we just green lit Luck, that's a provocative look at horse racing from Michael Mann and David Milch and starring Dustin Hoffman and Nick Nolte.</p>
          <p>Turning from HBO to our studio, last week Warner Brothers became the first studio to cross the $1 billion mark at the domestic box office for the 10th year in a row, another validation of our strategy. We expect to extend this success with a strong slate in the second half and next year. We're off to a great start. Our summer blockbuster, Inception, has led the domestic box office for three straight weeks and is easily on track to exceed a half a billion dollars at the global box office.</p>
          <p>Other major releases planned for the rest of the year include Harry Potter and The Deathly Hallows &#x2013; Part 1, Legend of the Guardians from Zack Snyder, who gave you 300, Due Date, from the writer and director of Hangover, Todd Phillips, Hereafter from Clint Eastwood, Life As We Know It, with Katherine Heigl and Josh Duhamel, and Yogi Bear in 3D.</p>
          <p>As we outlined in our recent Investor Day, we plan to release six event films again next year in 2011, including Green Lantern, The Hangover 2, Happy Feet 2, the next Sherlock Holmes film, and last but not least, the final in the Harry Potter series.</p>
          <p>Warner's Television Production business again delivered an industry leading upfront with orders for 15 returning series and 11 new series from the broadcast networks. That makes us the number one provider of network TV programming for the fourth time in the past five years. We're experiencing extremely strong demand for our products in the syndication market. We saw very competitive bidding and a record price for the off network rights to Big Bang Theory in May and that was coming on the heels of last year's record sale of The Mentalist. Demand for these shows is a great indicator about the value of our syndication pipeline over the next couple of years.</p>
          <p>Time Inc. is also outperforming its competitors, again, a testament to the strength of its brands and to its editorial content. Time Inc. widened its industry leadership in advertising revenue during the first half of the year, gaining more share than any other publisher. And the growth was broad-based with 15 of our top 20 titles showing increases.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, these brands will continue to lead the industry as it expands into evolving digital platforms such as tablets and the richer online environment that is enabled by HTML5. I hope you've had a chance to see the Time, Sports Illustrated, Fortune and Entertainment Weekly apps for the iPad. Over time, very shortly, we anticipate that our subscribers will be able to enjoy the same amazing experience on every tablet.</p>
          <p>So in short, we're committing more resources than ever to strengthening our content and our brands. It's paying off in our results and it's a big part of the reason why I'm so confident about how we're positioned for the rest of this year and the years after that.</p>
          <p>And so with that I'll pass it off to John Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff, and good morning. There are slides that are now available on our website that will follow along with my comments. Let's begin right away on the first slide where there are a few high level takeaways from the quarter.</p>
          <p>As we discussed with you before, our goal is to deliver superior shareholder returns through a combination of operational growth and direct returns of capital. In this quarter we continued to execute on that plan. As Jeff described, we delivered our fastest revenue growth in two years, led in large part by the strength of our content. At the same time we remained focused on operational efficiencies, which enabled us to grow both adjusted operating income and EPS at considerably faster rates than revenue. Our performance so far this year has given us the confidence to raise our full year outlook again. Growing at least 20% this year comes on top, as Jeff said, on top of the 29% adjusted EPS growth in 2009. Think about that we're on track to deliver north of 50% adjusted EPS growth in just the last two years. Of course this is in the face of what has been clearly an extremely challenging recession and what continues to be somewhat of an uncertain recovery.</p>
          <p>Turning to capital deployment for a moment, our free cash flow generation in the first half, as well as some recent refinancings that we've done, have further strengthened our balance sheet and we've used some of this flexibility to increase our returns of capital. We've spent over $1.5 billion on dividend and share repurchases during the first half of the year. And that's more than twice the level of what we returned in the first half of last year.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide which shows consolidated second quarter financial highlights, revenues were up 8% with subscription advertising and content revenues all up over last year. Advertising was particularly strong, increasing 11% in the quarter. Adjusted operating income was up over 15% with margins increasing 120 basis points year-over-year. This was the sixth consecutive quarter of year-over-year margin expansion.</p>
          <p>As we've talked to you before, we continue to try to keep a lid on SG&amp;A where we can so that we can reallocate resources toward more productive areas like programming, TV and film production and marketing. Continuing to walk down the P&amp;L, we grew adjusted EPS by 35% and this strong result was helped by our operational growth, a lower effective tax rate and a lower share count as compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the segment highlights and let me begin with our networks where we achieved another strong quarter of revenue and operating income growth. Advertising revenues here were up 14%. We're still above 10% if you eliminate the impact of international transactions and this performance was driven by growth across our networks. Our domestic networks continue to benefit from strong scatter demand with pricing up 20 to 30% in the quarter as well as ongoing yield management. Domestic entertainment networks, including kids and young adults grew advertising in the high single digits and there was a high demand for the NBA playoffs on TNT despite four fewer games than last year due to shorter series. And domestic news posted double-digit year-over-year advertising growth.</p>
          <p>At our international networks, organic advertising growth was more than 30%. And I'd also point out that adjusted operating income for our consolidated International Network businesses grew by more than 50% in the quarter and we achieved 200 points of margin expansion year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, domestic scatter pricing remains robust and it's still up more than 20% over the upfront and trends internationally look relatively consistent with the second quarter. So while it may be difficult for us to maintain quite the pace of this quarter's growth, we do expect another quarter of strong advertising growth in the third quarter. So we feel pretty good about that.</p>
          <p>Subscription revenue growth here of 9% primarily reflected higher rates and international expansion. Remember that this is a very big revenue stream for us and we continue to see subscription revenues as being one of the largest growth opportunities for the company. We are continually investing to increase the value of our networks to our viewers and distributors and we expect this value to be recognized over time in our affiliate fees.</p>
          <p>Operating income was up 14% in the quarter and margins expanded approximately 100 basis points year-over-year. Consistent with our plan, both marketing and programming costs grew more quickly in the second quarter than in the first quarter and that was tied to the timing of new original programming.</p>
          <p>As you know, increased investment in originals is a key element in our strategic plan for both Turner and HBO. And we have a particularly strong lineup of originals and running during the third quarter and it's the shows that Jeff mentioned just a few minutes ago, those include both returning and new shows. Shows such as The Closer and Leverage on TNT and new series Are We There Yet? on TBS, Rizzoli &amp; Isles and Memphis Beat on TNT and Boardwalk Empire on HBO to name a few.</p>
          <p>Due to this large slate of originals, we expect our third quarter margins to compress somewhat compared to last year's third quarter, but they should once again expand in the fourth quarter. And for the year, we continue to expect relatively modest programming cost growth in and around the mid-single digit area. So given the strong top line performance to date and encouraging trends that we've experienced, we think that this will all translate into very strong profit growth at our Networks division this year.</p>
          <p>Let's turn now to film. Adjusted operating income in the quarter was relatively flat, but it's still up significantly year-to-date and we saw significant increases in both theatrical and television revenue in the quarter, but we also had higher film costs and P&amp;A due to a larger number of high-budget theatrical films and the shift towards international self-distribution for New Line releases. In addition, a greater percentage of our television revenue came from lower margin new series.</p>
          <p>Over time we're confident we can continue to push margins higher in this division by focusing on operational efficiencies and accelerating the transition to digital consumption, particularly in home video. Our home video revenue was down 8% year-over-year in the quarter, but that was mostly a function of a previously disclosed return reserve adjustment, which helped last year's results. Industry trends have shown some improvement in recent months with home video sales for the industry close to flat in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Digital growth remains quite strong. Warner Brothers grew video and electronic sell thorough over 50%. And on a combined basis, these revenues are now quickly approaching 20% of our total home video business. As you know, that revenue has a much higher margin attached to it. So that's both important and encouraging.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to the second half of the year, we obviously have very difficult comparisons against last year's theatrical and home video releases of Harry Potter and The Half Blood Prince and The Hangover, and while Cats and Dogs 2 which we recently released underperformed our expectations this weekend, we are nevertheless very, very pleased with the great performance of Inception and we're optimistic about the rest of this year's theatrical release slate, as Jeff described. We also expect to benefit from our TV syndication pipeline and we have very high hopes for our fast growing games business. Our late June video games release, for example, LEGO Harry Potter, has already sold nearly 3 million units. So we remain confident that Warner Brothers will once again deliver very strong results for the full year.</p>
          <p>Moving onto our Publishing division, revenues were essentially flat in the quarter. Advertising revenues were up 4% year-over-year, and excluding the impact from magazines we closed in the past 12 months, domestic print advertising was up even stronger, up in the high single digits. Digital advertising was also very strong, up in the high teens year-over-year.</p>
          <p>The majority of Time Inc.'s top advertising categories grew in the quarter led by beauty, food and beverage and financials. Looking across Time Inc.'s three primary operating units, led by solid growth at People the Style &amp; Entertainment Group grew advertising double digits and ad revenues at the Lifestyle and News units were up nicely in the quarter. Even though advertising growth comparisons here get more difficult as the year progresses, we see a continuation of positive trends in the back half of the year. Advertising should be up again in the third quarter and for the full year.</p>
          <p>Subscription revenues at Time Inc. were essentially flat in the quarter as favorable domestic newsstand comparisons were offset by lower domestic subscription sales. Looking forward, we continue to see some pressure on subscriptions and our newsstand comparisons become a little bit more challenging in the back half of the year. We think subscription revenue could be down somewhat on a year-over-year basis for the rest of 2010.</p>
          <p>Operating income was up 50% in the quarter. Margins were up nearly 600 basis points year-over-year and that's the highest level that they've been in almost two years. So that's good. That growth was due largely to cost actions with total expenses down almost $50 million from a year ago.</p>
          <p>We expect to see ongoing benefits from the restructurings we undertook in the fourth quarter of last year as well as the recent changes we've made to our pension plan. So as a result of that, we continue to anticipate that costs will remain lower than the prior year for the rest of the year here at Time Inc.</p>
          <p>Up next, let's look at the outlook for the rest of the year for a moment. Obviously just to repeat what we've already said, we had terrific results in the first half of 2010. Our content is performing well. We're seeing sustained growth in our networks, subscription revenues and we're benefiting from an improvement in the advertising environment and we're delivering strong growth in an environment where we're not playing defense. We're playing offense. We're investing more in programming and production to push our competitive advantage and to make our company stronger for the future. This strong execution gives us confidence to once again raise our full year outlook and that's despite what continues to be somewhat an uncertain economic environment. We now expect adjusted EPS to grow at least 20% over the base of $1.83 from a year ago.</p>
          <p>We anticipate continued healthy revenue trends in the back half of 2010 and we expect the fourth quarter will be much better than the third in terms of year-over-year growth comparisons. As I mentioned, as part of our annual plan, we'll be spending more programming and marketing at the networks in the third quarter. We also have tough comparisons in our Film division against the theatrical performances of Harry Potter and Hangover from last year.</p>
          <p>Let's continue to move ahead and look at free cash flow for a minute on the next slide. Year-to-date, we generated about $1.2 billion of free cash flow. That's down a little year-over-year due to primarily higher cash taxes and an increase in accounts receivable tied to higher revenue growth. However, it still represents a meaningful amount of free cash flow and a high conversion ratio.</p>
          <p>So let's move to our final slide, which looks at net debt. We ended the quarter with a little more than $12 billion in net debt. That's up about $800 million compared to the end of last year. That's a result of us spending more than 100% of our free cash flow year-to-date, or about $1.5 billion, on share repurchases and dividends.</p>
          <p>We've also spent about $0.5 billion year-to-date on acquisitions. And about 80% of the acquisitions have been on international cable networks with the majority of that related to our acquisition of additional interests in HBO's international operations. It also includes our acquisition of Turbine, which is an online gaming studio to further enhance Time Warner's capabilities in the video game space.</p>
          <p>So with half a year now complete, we're on track to achieve our capital plan, priorities and objectives. So let me remind you quickly what those are. First, we're going to continue to invest in our businesses to improve their strategic position and drive long-term growth and that's evidenced by the increased investment in programming, production and marketing that we talked to you about.</p>
          <p>Second, we're committing to providing direct returns to stockholders through dividends and buybacks. And as I previously mentioned, in the first half of the year, we spent $1.5 billion, including about $1 billion in share repurchases. We still have about $2 billion outstanding under our current share repurchase authorization.</p>
          <p>Third, we're focused on our capital structure and carefully managing debt maturities. This year, for example, we've taken full advantage of the current credit markets to effectively extend the maturities of $5 billion in debt including $3 billion just last month. This has allowed us to improve our maturity profile at very, very attractive interest rates. We now have no more than $1 billion in debt coming due in any year through the end of the decade. So that's good. We consider this strategic flexibility that we have to be a real competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>Our leverage ratio is now about two times and that's somewhat closer to our long-term target of two-and-a-half times, but yet still leaves us with plenty of flexibility.</p>
          <p>So thanks for listening, and let me turn the call back over to Doug to start the Q&amp;A part of the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks. Let's get the Q&amp;A started. Please try and keep yourself to only one or two questions so that we can get to as many callers as possible. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Doug Mitchelson from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much. If I could just ask two, both of those really quick: on the home video marketing improving, is there any measurable benefit from the Netflix and Red Box deals where you pushed back their home video window? Now that we're sort of the second quarter in maybe there's more experience there and that was part of it.</p>
          <p>Separately, Jeff, you mentioned affiliates will recognize increasing value over time. And John emphasized it as well. Can you help us out with the timing part of that increasing value over time? Typically these deals are five years or so, so a fifth comes up every year. Is that the layout? Would you just expect 20% of the deals a year or is there a bigger year in '11 or '12 we should think about? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Basically the results from the Netflix, Red Box window moving back is quite good. As I think you all know, the intent of the move of the window is to boost demand for DVD sell-through and for VOD. While it's early, the results indicate that that strategy is work, quite well particularly on big titles. Two that I would cite which are the biggest ones since we moved there, Blind Side is one and Sherlock Holmes is another. We saw considerably higher sales in the weeks say two to four than we used to see in kind of week-by-week distribution of sales.</p>
          <p>The joint cable and studio-marketing program to promote Video-On-Demand helped. One of the things that I think we're going see as we move along, you still have a fair amount of upside room for activity and effort in VOD. VOD marketing effort, the kind of ability of the cable, satellite and telco infrastructure to do VOD is still increasing pretty fast. And so we think that this is working already. And it's going to work better as we go along.</p>
          <p>We have seen other studios following that plan in terms of that window. And we've seen the titles that come from studios that are not using that window structure underperform. So that's what we know so far on those windows.</p>
          <p>In terms of the affiliate fees, we are extremely confident of our outlook for affiliate fee growth, as you obviously in the premise of your question, the majority of the revenue that we have is under multi-year contracts and it's not quite right to say that it rolls over at the rate linearly that you were saying. I'm not going to, I'm sorry. I'm not going to give exactly the timing of our maturities. But as you've been watching what we've been doing, not just at Turner, certainly in Turner's original programming success which we mentioned in our prepared remarks, but also the big programming deals, whether it's for sports, the basketball, Conan's deal, some of the strength of new shows at HBO. We really think that we're improving our position and our future outlook on the affiliate side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Are you willing to say at all whether we'll start to see some of those benefits soon or should we think about that as a long term driver?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Spencer Wang from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. One question for Jeff and one for John. For Jeff, just a follow-up on Doug's question. Can you just talk a little bit about how you're thinking about Netflix since it's a customer of Warner Brothers but also potentially a competitor to HBO?</p>
          <p>And then for John, could you just update us on your thoughts on capital allocation in terms of potentially accelerating returns of capital to shareholders versus potential acquisitions like say MGM. Thanks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On Netflix, you're quite right, it's a customer for our output. And it is a potential competitor to networks like HBO. Although so far it's been more of a complementary service to HBO than a competitor. So one thing I would tell all of you is that as we look at that, in any of these companies, Netflix not being the only one, we are quite organized together between Warners and HBO and Turner in how we look at those. And so what you see us doing is something that comes out of a fairly coordinated approach.</p>
          <p>In terms of HBO's view, HBO's very used to competition and does it by providing a great product, which you can focus either on the superior movie supply that they've got that goes major releases out many a year or on the original programming, which is unique to HBO. Really in both respects, both the movies, the Hollywood movies and the originals are unique to HBO and exclusive when they're on HBO. Where Netflix has gone essentially, everywhere Netflix has subs, HBO out indexes in terms of its penetration, retention and performance.</p>
          <p>As you look into the future, I'm not going to really clarify exactly how the programming strategy will work over time. But suffice it to say, I feel very good about that, both on the movie side and the original programming side. And I really would call everyone's attention to what you're about to see. And you already see it with our biggest distributors, Verizon and Comcast, which is HBO On Demand, not only on your TV set, which is already a huge success in grading and in competitive relative position for HBO versus all other networks but you're soon going to see it, HBO on all your broadband devices because you're a subscriber to HBO.</p>
          <p>If you take the killer lineup that HBO's got on originals and movies, and you put it available on demand on all broadband devices, which you're already seeing at Comcast and Verizon, that's going to be the big marriage for this next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Spencer, on capital allocation, we don't have a specific target level for returns, but I think our actions would suggest that we clearly believe that direct returns to shareholders should be a significant component of total return and it's an important part of our capital plan. And we continue to believe in a balanced consistent approach. And we believe in using a combination of dividends and share repurchases and obviously our share repurchase activity suggests that we have a lot of confidence in the value of the stock in the company.</p>
          <p>So we've been repurchasing shares, around $500 million a quarter. We did raise our dividend 13% this year. As I mentioned in my proactive remarks, our returns on a year-to-date basis are basically at double the level they were a year ago. I don't know, Jeff, if you want to make a comment specific about MGM or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I do. From what we read in the papers, it sounds like they're moving in a different direction and it sounds pretty inept to us. All along we've said that we didn't need this. We feel comfortable of course with our strategic position. And MGM could have made sense when we went and as everyone knows because we announced it, or they did, we made what we thought was a bid based on what information we had at the time. We haven't really had the kind of discussions that would enable us to confirm whatever the value of MGM is, because we'd have had to go into a more constructive process than we've been invited into. And so I don't know &#x2013; we don't know whether that is in fact worth the full bid that we gave it at the time. And at this point it does look like they're going off in another direction. We'll see how they do. I think it's pretty widely known that some of their key movie assets, one of which is The Hobbit is something that we may be quite involved in. And so we have an interest in them having some constructive course going forward. But it's not clear whether they do have that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Michael Morris from Davenport.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks guys. Two questions for you. First, as some of your broadcast competitors are becoming more vocal and more active in generating retransmission fees through their owned and operated stations, can you just share what your outlook is for the competitive environment for content going forward? Whether you anticipate that they'll become more aggressive both as competitors, also maybe in terms of demand for Warner Brothers content? What's your expectation there and how are you positioning yourself?</p>
          <p>And then on the syndication side, you mentioned a robust syndication pipeline in the back half of the year. Can you be a little more specific with respect to what's in that pipeline? And as a point of clarification you did have a slide on your Investor Day showing in the Warner Brothers section showing some titles coming up in 2010. It included Entourage and Curb Your Enthusiasm and I was curious, are those &#x2013; do they make contribution to Warner as well as HBO or will that completely be in HBO? Thank you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, starting with &#x2013; what was the first one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Retrans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We think the retrans situation is developing in the way we actually thought it would. We think it's on the whole, desirable. We do think of broadcast as competitors of our cable network. They've always received a form of retrains, usually not in cash for their broadcast network but in other kind of ancillary networks. And so to the extent that as they get it more direct from the broadcast network and to the extent they get additional cash, we still think that the stronger cable network, which will be the group we're in, will prosper as they in the broadcast side bolster their economics.</p>
          <p>We think that basically because all of our networks are must have networks, must have programming. The originals are that, the sports that we have are that, the movie lineup as well. So we're actually kind of happy that broadcast is revitalizing their programming because there's really two reasons. The easy one to see is that we have a very healthy leading business at Warner making TV series for the broadcast networks. And them bolstering their health going forward is actually good for that business. But the second effect that was related to that is that the successful shows that come off broadcast networks, many of which we make at Warner, are then available for the leading cable networks like TNT and TBS and they're a pretty important part of the ecosystem.</p>
          <p>As we've said before, that is &#x2013; that kind of synergy relationship in terms of Warner supplies hit shows to broadcast across all four broadcast nets and then having those hit shows available to the highest bidding cable networks, which happen to be ours due to their lead position, is a very beneficial kind of a cycle for the industry and for us.</p>
          <p>If you go now to the syndication question, we think that the &#x2013; I think John mentioned in the second quarter, the sale of The Closer to TNT was already in there, it's not that large. We think the product line is very strong for the rest of the year. For the rest of this year, we have Two and a Half Men for cable, we have The Closer coming for cable and weekend broadcast &#x2013; the weekend broadcast window. We have The New Adventures of Old Christine available for cable and off net. And then looking after 2010 into next year, we've already sold Big Bang Theory for 2011 and The Mentalist for 2012. We have Gossip Girl and Chuck coming in 2011. Fringe is available in 2012 and the shows you mentioned on HBO are Entourage...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Entourage and Curb, which from an accounting standpoint that gets reflected in HBO's line of business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not Warners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. The DVD sales get distributed by Warners, but the syndication licensing is at HBO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we go to the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Anthony DiClemente [Barclays Capital].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking the questions. One for John and then a related one for Jeff. John, you know, with a lot of the conversation around growing demand for TV syndication content, I'm just wondering if structurally as you smooth out your film entertainment division over time, is the composition of revenues and EBITDA from TV versus film changing over time? I know you don't report them separately within film entertainment, but just wondering. And then I have a follow-up for Jeff. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't report them separately, Anthony. One of the strengths of Warners and one of the reasons why they're probably less volatile than most of the competition in terms of earnings performance is because we have a very, very big and very, very stable source of profits from our TV production business, which includes licensing, syndication, barter and it's global. And I think we had mentioned that with the growing syndication pipeline that we would expect to see growth on a go forward basis from that television business beginning this year.</p>
          <p>And so I mean that's probably &#x2013; I mean the mix sort of can go up and down in any one particular year. But we have a very, very big component of profits coming from each of the theatrical and the television side. I think we've disclosed in the past that TV in any given year can represent nearly half of the profitability of Warners. I think it's a strong business. I think secular trends are moving in its direction which is good and we expect to be very successful going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, that's helpful. And a related question for Jeff which would be the deal that Warner Brothers announced with Netflix on TV content, I just thought I would ask, on the face of it, this looks like it's a really good deal because it seems like these are incremental dollars that are flowing to WB for TV content. I'm just wondering, is there a tradeoff between these dollars from Netflix that you're getting and the value that you're accruing in the syndication window that you're speaking of? I know those are not exclusive deals, but I'm wondering is there a balance that your syndication division has to weigh in terms of whether or not a deal with Netflix trades off with the deals for TV syndication in the domestic market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we always look when we're selling product in a window. Let's say it's anybody, in this case Netflix, whether it conflicts with anything that's more interesting to us. In this case, because what we're talking about is a fairly small deal with some programming &#x2013; Nip/Tuck series, which wasn't picked up in syndication. So frankly had there been anybody buying it in syndication, we would have sold it to the syndication market. The same is true of &#x2013; there was a small movie package in there that's quite old movies, which is really the kind of movies Netflix has. So basically we don't see so far and we haven't seen too many other cases where other companies have sold things to Netflix, but essentially &#x2013; there are a few where it cannibalizes business that's actually better than what Netflix is able to represent. We basically traded off, whether it's with our current networks or with our syndicated clients. Remember that the syndication market generally is very, very strong, which I think John mentioned. So what you're talking about here is products that nobody wants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we get the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anybody there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jason Bazinet [Citigroup].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...decision on HBO GO to make that only exclusive to existing HBO customers via your paid TV distributors...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, would you start over? We didn't hear anything for ten seconds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've had long lapses of silence on our side, so we apologize, but if you could start the question over, that would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd be happy to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions on HBO GO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have you made a definitive decision to limit the availability of HBO online, if you will, to existing customers of HBO via the paid TV distributors as opposed to making it available to non-HBO subs over the web?</p>
          <p>Second, have you made a definitive decision regarding the content that would be available online? In other words, is it only the content that's available on the multiplex channels of HBO as opposed to the deeper library content that you have access to? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me do the second part first. HBO GO as you can all read in the press releases, we'd be happy to give you more info, if you call in we'll give it to you. HBO GO has considerably more product from HBO. Hello? Can you still hear me? We've got some interference, but I'll just keep talking. I hope you can hear. So HBO GO's programming from HBO is even more programming than what is available...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the operator there? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a mess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello? Hello? That's a good idea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we go back to &#x2013; do we have everyone &#x2013; is Jason still there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start over. So HBO GO's programming from HBO is more hours, considerably more than what is available on HBO VOD. And so that's how there's essentially more and it's quite a bit more. So it's going to be a very impressive product. I do think over time what you'll see on the VOD side, the television streaming side, is a more robust product as the cable/telco operators beef up their VOD. But basically think of it as eventually as much as what HBO has coming to you as a subscriber.</p>
          <p>Go to your first question which is what are we doing with subscribers? At the present time what we're doing is we basically are launching HBO to our subscriber base. You have 30 million subs that deserve to get HBO On Demand on every platform including on broadband. You paid for it, you should have it and we're going to have our distributors who are very important partners in doing this in putting up the plant that allows you to do this, be part of the equation. The question of whether we should then in the future offer a subscription separately from that is not something that we're ready to do now.</p>
          <p>Of course we could do it if and when it would become reasonable. But the one thing that we're quite interested in and I think every content company should be, is in supporting the economic infrastructure of video streaming, video delivery and broadband ISP delivery, because if you think carefully about the broadband video distribution infrastructure, it needs to become more robust. It needs investment and the companies that do that are the ISPs. And so you have to think carefully about keeping those economics related as you take products like HBO, and the Turner networks and you make them available on broadband devices. I think we're working quite progressively to have the whole system function optimally. And the key to it all is to get our subscribers not just for our TV networks, but on other venues to be able to enjoy their products over all broadband devices as soon as possible because they already subscribe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we go to the next question, please? Operator we're still hearing long periods of silence here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of James Dix from Wedbush.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Just two questions. If you could give any more color on the outlook for growth at WB Interactive Entertainment, especially with the strong performance of LEGO titles. Do you have a sense that the games division is somewhat outperforming your expectations for the beginning of the year?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on cost, I was just wondering if you can give more color on the increase in SG&amp;A in the quarter at the networks. Were there any components to that growth related to acquisitions or any stuff that's not organic? And what should our expectations be for that growth for the full year there at the networks? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On games at Warner, we're basically now up to more than $0.5 billion in revenue and growing reasonably fast with healthy margins. And we're really doing two things. We've brought in some in terms of acquisitions, we've brought in some companies like Midway, Rocksteady, that bring us &#x2013; Eidos, etcetera, to bring us IP to bring us titles like Lord of the Rings, Arkham Asylum, Mortal Combat and then secondly, we have as you all know, pretty big titles or IP inventory in the Warner and Time Warner characters and film strategies.</p>
          <p>So we're essentially building from our position of both distribution related to DVD and all that and IP that we have in our programming. And we're working towards a global video infrastructure which goes adjacent in games. So we think that we're making steady progress. We've moved into the top 10. We see it as a growing percentage of Warner Brothers' revenues. It's actually one of the fairly high growth areas inside Warner Brothers. And we believe the margins should improve as we increase our scale and further leverage the infrastructure. On the cost side, John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the cost side, I think your question was specific to networks, SG&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the bigger year-over-year increases in SG&amp;A in the quarter was marketing, and marketing around obviously supporting new programming launches. So that's one of the more meaningful components of that. And just to put a little bit more context around it, this is the sixth quarter in a row where we had year-over-year margin expansion at the networks division. And I think if you look at the absolute margin in networks in the second quarter and if you go and compare that to history of the second quarters of all the prior years, I think it's the highest margin at the networks for as long as our data goes back for.</p>
          <p>So my point being is that we are carefully managing the investment in the cost base. We are trying to be more efficient where we can and I often mention that we're trying to keep a lid on SG&amp;A but marketing is a component of that. That is directly tied to revenues because it's supporting the investment that we're making in our programming. So we're working hard and we continue to see positive margin attributes as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Richard Greenfield from BTIG</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Rich Greenfield. Two questions. One, just could you comment on your thoughts related to theatrical pricing? Jeff, if you went down to the AMC Lincoln Square right near your offices, you would pay $13 to see Inception and you'd pay $17 for Cats and Dogs 3D. And just wondering how you think about that and whether that makes sense from a pricing standpoint?</p>
          <p>Then two, you talked a lot about HBO GO. There's been a lot of questions about it. And just wondering, your deal with Comcast forces everything in broadband to go through their Fancast interface, which seems at least to consumers I've talked to, to be vastly inferior to your beautiful HBO GO interface and just wondering whether that will change going forward or whether that's something that's set in stone forever? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rich. On the pricing, I'm not sure if I get your question. There's a long-standing question about whether the ticket price for movies that people think are big hits should be the same as the ticket price for movies that let's say are controversial as to whether they're hits and I believe you mentioned one that could fall into that category. And then your related question is what do you think of the gap between 3D pricing and regular pricing. Look, revenues in theatrical box office have been reasonably healthy. Admissions have stayed at least flat. I don't think the industry, meaning the distribution, retail theater industry, they don't really believe that it's all that elastic in terms of volume of admissions to ticket pricing. And I think they believe that the place to have some kind of revenue growth that keeps pace with inflation is on ticket pricing and whether it's for standard stuff or whether it's for 3D.</p>
          <p>It's clear that 3D represents an opportunity for higher ticket prices and it probably will remain a question of legitimate interest as to whether this title in 3D justifies whatever that ticket price is versus some other title in 3D. And I think it really gets down to the whole issue that ticket pricing whether it's standard or 3D experience, the fact that it's been standard across really good titles versus weaker titles is the source of the question. I think the question will remain and I think even though you can't answer satisfactorily, the proof is in the eating of the pudding. Revenues in theatrical are quite healthy.</p>
          <p>And one of the things I wouldn't underestimate is that in the health of the box office, even coming from 3D price support, what that does is it develops a real interest for ancillary viewing whether you actually see the movie in your home on a standard basis even &#x2013; you may have watched it in the theater on 3D or in the future maybe you get it on 3D for your home viewing. So I think it's all positive in terms of the industry and the film economics at least for the producing sector.</p>
          <p>If you go to GO and you're on Comcast or on the interface, I agree with you on something. I agree with you on actually a lot of what you're saying there. I think the interface for HBO GO that HBO developed is superior to basically any interface out there. And so we are encouraging everyone, all our affiliates, whoever they are, to take advantage of that interface and use it, which they could.</p>
          <p>I think that what will happen is any distributor who has an interface that's really not able to perform as well as what the HBO one does, you can end up adopting it. And if your question basically asks, okay, well, that's what your question has as a premise, then shouldn't they do that quickly, I agree with you. Yes, they should.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we go to the last question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tom Eagan [Collins Stewart].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just a question on international cable networks. I guess if you can provide maybe some more color? If I missed it, I apologize, on the top line, on results and then on the outlook, how much of it is coming from increases in ad spending, same store, so to speak? And how much of it is coming from expansion whether it's new channels or new markets?</p>
          <p>And then on the margin, what was the actual margin on the international side? And how high can that go? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll start and John will finish &#x2013; I mean as we discussed in some detail on investor day, international is now and is going continue to be a key driver of growth, including our unconsolidated HBO ventures, our International Cable Networks business and the very closely related content sales generates over 400 million of adjusted operating income just this year in 2010 and we think that there's tremendous growth going on both on the ad side and the affiliate side.</p>
          <p>In both Turner and HBO international is growing faster than domestic. And I would just emphasize before John gives some of the numbers on it, we do not have a plant the flag strategy. What we have is a strategy where we try to identify the right growth markets for secular growth, demographics attractiveness, rule of law, hospitality to what we're doing and an ability to build to a reasonable scale so we can have good marketing and distribution efficiency and reasonable infrastructure efficiency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom. I'll just add a couple of numbers. Our international reported growth was north of 80%, but that did include the impact of some acquisitions as I said which sort of contributed close to 400 basis points in the quarter. So on an organic basis, year-over-year, international was still up over 30 and there, if you look at back at last year, international under-performed domestic and we've seen a stronger recovery in almost all territories where we've got meaningful presence as it relates to advertising. So that's very, very encouraging.</p>
          <p>We don't specifically disclose the absolute margins, but in my proactive remarks I mentioned that margins were up 200 basis points year-over-year. And we have said in the past that international margins are still meaningfully lagging our domestic margins. So we think we've got runway for improvement as we move ahead. So appreciate the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, everybody, for tuning in, and we look forward to talking to you in a couple of months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation in today's conference. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>