<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1531115" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>631</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Caroline P. Stewart</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Executive Officer">Sergio P. Ermotti</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Financial Officer">Tom Naratil</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Huw J. van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Derek A. De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Fiona M. Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Matt P. Spick</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca SpA (United Kingdom)">Christopher J. Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Vontobel Equity Research AG">Teresa Nielsen</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good morning. Welcome to the UBS Fourth Quarter 2012 Results Conference Call. I'm Stefanie, the Chorus Call operator. I would like to remind you that all participants will be in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The conference must not be recorded for publication or broadcast.</p>
          <p>At this time, it's my pleasure to hand over to UBS. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to our Fourth Quarter Results Presentation. This morning, our CEO, Sergio Ermotti, will present the highlights of our full year results. Then, our CFO, Tom Naratil, will present our fourth quarter results in detail. We'd then be very happy to take your questions and we'd like to take questions from the telephone first. After that, we'll take questions from the room.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Sergio, I'd like to draw your attention to this slide, which contains our cautionary statement with regard to forward-looking statements, and I'd ask you to read it carefully.</p>
          <p>Now, let me hand over to Sergio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Caroline, and thank you for joining us. 2012 was another challenging year for the banking industry and one where we had to address our own challenges. Weak macroeconomic conditions and geopolitical issues affected clients' confidence despite equity markets performing well. But our employees met these challenges by maintaining their focus and commitments to our clients and I want to thank them for their efforts during 2012.</p>
          <p>In 2012, we made substantial progress towards achieving our strategic objectives on capital, costs and operational risk control. At the same time, we made solid progress across our business divisions and our strategic transformation. On capital, we exceeded our targets for risk-weighted assets reduction and strengthened our industry-leading capital ratios. On cost, we are making headway with our efficiency programs. And on operational risk, we also continue to strengthen risk controls as well as remediating Legacy issues and addressing the missteps of the past.</p>
          <p>We also demonstrated that what can we do through hard work and execution of a forward-looking strategy. Based on these achievements, particularly in relation to capital and as a sign of our confidence, we are recommending a 50% increase in our dividend for 2012. Our progress on balance sheet reduction has also allowed us to launch a tender offer to repurchase debt of up to approximately CHF 5 billion. This program will help lower our funding cost in the future and Tom will discuss in more details later.</p>
          <p>Our strategy is a journey that we set out on just over a year ago. And in October last year, we announced an acceleration in the transformation of the Investment Bank and further cost reduction across the group. We are reshaping our business to better serve clients, deliver more sustainable performance, reduce risk and enhance value and returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our strategy has been well received by our clients, shareholders, and bondholders, and we are pleased with the strong share performance since &#x2013; with &#x2013; in absolute and relative terms.</p>
          <p>Overall in 2012, we recorded a net loss of CHF 2.5 billion driven by goodwill impairments and restructuring costs as we executed our accelerated strategy. We also incurred significant legal and regulatory costs as well as material own credit losses.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter, we reported a net loss of CHF 1.9 billion which included CHF 2.1 billion of expenses related to litigation, regulatory, and similar matters. As you are aware, we also resolved a number of LIBOR-related matters in the quarter. This experience is a stark reminder of what can happen if we fail to maintain the highest ethical standards in our business.</p>
          <p>As our regulators noted, we have already made significant progress to strengthen our operational risk controls. I'm firmly committed to ensuring that we continue to put our reputation and risk control first every day and in everything we do.</p>
          <p>Implementation of our accelerated strategy will allow us to unlock the full potential of our franchise. In 2013, we will use the achievements of the past year and continue to decisively execute on our plans.</p>
          <p>On capital, we continue to make excellent progress, adding 460 basis points to our phase-in Basel III common equity Tier 1 ratio. Our fully applied ratio stood at 9.8% at year end with 2019 Swiss regulatory requirements of 10% now within striking distance. We achieved this by reducing Basel III risk weighted assets by over CHF 120 billion including over CHF 80 billion from the Investment Bank. We also made good progress in reducing our funded balance sheet down almost CHF 90 billion mostly from the Investment Bank.</p>
          <p>On costs, our underlying program is good with CHF 1.4 billion of net savings delivered since the summer of 2011. Our industry-leading capital position continues to be a source of competitive strengths. It has allowed us to restore and improve client confidence while we execute our strategy and address the past issues. At the same time, it has allowed us to increase capital returns. In 2013, we aim to strengthen this position even further, in line with our plans.</p>
          <p>Our Wealth Management businesses continued to perform well in 2012 despite unusually high client risk aversion. Overall profits increased and net new money inflows accelerated to CHF 47 billion, reflecting the efforts of our advisors in bringing the best ideas, advice and execution to clients across UBS. It also &#x2013; it is also a clear signs of the trust of our clients continue to place in us.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management Americas had its most profitable year since we acquired Paine Webber. Our financial advisor productivity also reached an all-time high and we attracted very strong net new money. Our strategy here is working and the team has done an excellent job in turning this business around. For our Wealth Management businesses outside the Americas, we saw an acceleration of net new money driven by continued strong performances in APAC, emerging markets and ultra-high net worth individuals.</p>
          <p>Growth in these areas affected our margins, but low activity and client confidence, record high cash balances throughout the year and folding interest margins were also important factors. A recovery in confidence, activity levels and interest rates are needed if we are to see this business deliver margins within its target range. But regardless of markets, our clients' needs remain at the center of everything we do.</p>
          <p>In our own market, Switzerland, we continue to win back market share and deliver solid profits. In a mature business operating in a strong but low-growth economy, we reported net new business volume growth of almost 5%. Deposit inflows totaled CHF 14 billion, and we saw the highest net new clients' inflows from retail clients since 2001. While clients have been critical of our past missteps, this is a clear sign of their loyalty and growing confidence in UBS.</p>
          <p>We are also making sizable investment to support our strategy. We had great success in refurbishing branches, as we have seen a 25% increase in new customers in these locations. We also invested in our community, with over 80,000 children enjoying our Kids Club events and almost half a million people benefiting from our partnership with Swiss Tourism.</p>
          <p>I'm very proud of the achievements here in Switzerland and I'm convinced that the benefits of our investments will increasingly be recognized not only by our employees, clients and shareholders, but also by all other stakeholders in Switzerland.</p>
          <p>In Global Asset Management, we delivered stronger investment returns to our clients with profits up almost 20%. Our fixed income and alternative businesses continue to deliver excellent performance and over 60% of our collective funds showed first or second quartile performance.</p>
          <p>In the Investment Bank, 2012 was a year of significant change and we made real progress in a number of critical areas. Risk-weighted assets are down over CHF 80 billion, our balance sheet is over CHF 200 billion smaller and we have 1,100 fewer staff.</p>
          <p>The core IB also outperformed its full-year risk-weighted assets, operating with a Basel III risk-weighted assets of CHF 64 billion, so within the targets that we set of CHF 70 billion for this business. Despite this sharp reduction in resources, our staff continued to put our clients first, which is evident in the results they delivered.</p>
          <p>In IBD, revenues were up over 16% as we gained share in equity and debt capital markets and globally &#x2013; and global syndicated finance.</p>
          <p>In Cash Equities, we increased exchange market share in EMEA, particularly on alternative trading platforms and also across APAC. In effect, we invested to sustain our leading position and our cutting edge e-trading systems enabled us to grow volumes significantly while overall market volumes declined.</p>
          <p>Our Rates businesses delivered a steady performance and Credit had a good year with revenues up 27%.</p>
          <p>We are on track with the transformation of the Investment Bank. The changes in the IB strategy have been very well received by clients. In Wealth Management, our clients recognized the value of the services and the execution provided by our Investment Bank. Our corporate and institutional clients have also embraced the changes and since then, since the announcement, they have continued to reward us from &#x2013; for our long-term commitments.</p>
          <p>As part of our commitment to deliver sustainable performance, we have further aligned our compensation programs to pay for appropriate performance and ensure we can continue to attract and retain top talent.</p>
          <p>We have made a number of significant changes. For example, we have extended vesting periods and multi-year performance conditions. We have introduced a new deferred compensation plan which broadly replicates the feature of UBS loss absorbing capital we issued to external investors in 2012, but has a higher trigger set at 7%. This plan counts towards our total Basel III too big to fail capital and awards in this plan will take losses ahead of our low-trigger notes. And finally, we have also reduced the immediate one-year cash cap for individuals by 50%. Taken together, these changes are another important steps toward ensuring that compensation is better aligned to medium- and long-term performance and our shareholders' interest.</p>
          <p>I believe they will create the right reward for those who execute our strategy effectively and efficiently and deliver attractive and sustainable returns to our shareholders. In 2012, we focused and made significant progress on three key objectives: capital, cost and operational risk remediation. But we have more work to do and these objectives are just as relevant for the next stage of our journey. Each milestone we reach frees up more time and energy to focus on reinvigorating our growth in our businesses and improving our performance.</p>
          <p>As for 2013, market has performed very strongly in January but we all see what happened in the first couple of days in February. Therefore, we need to remain realistic. The global economy is still fragile and many important economic and structural issues remain unresolved. We are focusing on what we can control and while we would welcome any tailwind, we are not counting on them for our execution.</p>
          <p>We are determined to achieve the targets we outlined in October and I'm confident that clients and our investors and shareholders will continue to recognize our efforts.</p>
          <p>Now, I hand over to Tom, and then we will come back after the presentation on the Q4 details for Q&amp;A. Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sergio, and good morning, everyone. As Sergio noted, for the fourth quarter we reported a net loss attributable to shareholders of CHF 1.9 billion and adjusted pre-tax loss of CHF 1.2 billion. These results include CHF 2.1 billion of expenses related to litigation, regulatory and similar matters.</p>
          <p>Despite the headline losses, our businesses continued to make progress in the execution of our objectives and the accelerated implementation of our strategy is on track. Our capital ratios remain the best in our peer group and we strengthened them further in the quarter as we continued to reduce risk weighted assets.</p>
          <p>This is the last time we'll report Basel 2.5 capital ratios. But as we say farewell to them, we note that we ended this era with Basel 2.5 &#x2013; with a Basel 2.5 Tier 1 capital ratio of 21.3%.</p>
          <p>Balance sheet reduction in the quarter was significant. Lower funding needs will allow us to buy back debt. And today, we announced tender offers to repurchase up to approximately CHF 5 billion of senior unsecured debt.</p>
          <p>Several of our business divisions performed well in the quarter. Wealth Management Americas reported strong pre-tax results and very strong net new money. Retail &amp; Corporate's performance remained resilient and we continued to regain market share with net new business volume growth of over 4%. Global Asset Management also did well with improved investment performance and higher pre-tax profits.</p>
          <p>Our Investment Bank made good progress on its restructuring, reducing Basel III RWAs by 19%, funded balance sheet by CHF 72 billion, and head count by approximately 800 positions.</p>
          <p>In Wealth Management, we continued to see strong net new money growth in our focus areas of APAC, emerging markets, and the ultra-high net worth segment.</p>
          <p>Concerns around the U.S. fiscal cliff were at the forefront of our clients' minds in the fourth quarter and led to an overall reduction in activity levels across our businesses. Despite this, equity markets rallied in the second half of the quarter, albeit on relatively low volumes.</p>
          <p>The franc remained stable against the euro, while it appreciated against the U.S. dollar and the British pound, generating foreign currency translation losses in other comprehensive income.</p>
          <p>Our CDS spreads tightened during the quarter continuing the trend seen in the third quarter and leading to own credit losses of CHF 414 million.</p>
          <p>Our adjusted pre-tax loss of CHF 1.2 billion in the fourth quarter excludes the own credit loss and restructuring charges. We recorded restructuring charges of CHF 258 million versus the expected CHF 500 million we announced in December. The variance is mainly driven by the Investment Bank where voluntary leavers replaced redundancies or were delayed to later quarters.</p>
          <p>Fee was also lower than expected and we also deferred some redundancies in Wealth Management until the first quarter. The total restructuring charges booked in the fourth quarter represent notifications of 1,900 redundancies. Throughout the remainder of this presentation, I'll refer to adjusted figures. The adjusted results do not exclude legal provisions and expenses totaling CHF 2.1 billion, nor the UK bank levy of CHF 124 million. Despite a loss in the quarter, we posted a tax expense of CHF 66 million and we've concluded the year with an effective tax rate of negative 26%.</p>
          <p>Following the acceleration of our strategy, including associated restructuring costs, we expect our tax rate to be in the region of 25% to 30% for the first half of 2013, as non-core and Legacy losses that may be incurred in some entities may not be eligible for a tax benefit. Also, the full-year 2013 tax rate may depend on the extent to which deferred tax assets are revalued during the year and on other adjustments affecting Swiss-taxable profits.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management's pre-tax profit was CHF 415 million, down from the third quarter, reflecting both lower revenues and higher expenses. Revenues declined as a result of lower client activity levels and net interest income, resulting from the continuing low-interest rate environment. Expenses increased, driven by several factors including the absence of one-time credits that benefited the third quarter. General and administrative expenses included higher provisions for legal and regulatory matters and higher costs for marketing and communication.</p>
          <p>Net new money was positive with faster growth in the emerging markets, another strong performance in APAC and continued growth in ultra-high net worth. Europe recorded an increase in outflows as clients responded to the developments surrounding the Swiss-German tax treaty in December.</p>
          <p>The gross margin declined to 85 basis points as revenues declined and average assets increased slightly. These margins remain outside our 95 to 105 basis point target range. Client risk aversion and the resulting low trading activity, increasing preference for advisory over discretionary mandates, persistently high levels of cash in our clients' portfolios and interest rates that remain stubbornly low are all putting pressure on gross margins.</p>
          <p>As we have indicated, material improvements to economic and geopolitical issues will be necessary for a meaningful improvement in client sentiment and engagement. We should reach our target range when market conditions improve.</p>
          <p>This slide provides greater detail on the regional trends that are driving our Wealth Management results. For Wealth Management as a whole, annualized net new money growth was 1.2% for the quarter, which is below our target range, and 3.5% for the year, which is within our range. Emerging markets, APAC and the ultra-high net worth segment should improve net new money growth.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we saw increased outflows from our offshore business and we expect this to continue in the coming quarters. We also saw slight outflows in Wealth Management Switzerland after three consecutive quarters of net new money growth.</p>
          <p>In terms of gross margin, the factors that I previously mentioned affected all regions, although not to the same extent. APAC was more affected by lower transactional and trading activity including lower revenues from fund fees as well as structured products. Switzerland felt a greater impact from the ongoing interest margin pressure on deposits as well as lower recurring fees and lower activity in FX. Improvements in our net interest margin require better global growth than we experience currently.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management Americas recorded a pre-tax profit of $219 million and a record profit of $872 million for the full year. And as Sergio mentioned, it was the most profitable year for this business since UBS acquired Paine Webber in 2000.</p>
          <p>Revenues beat last quarter's record by 7%, driven by strong recurring income, which included higher mutual fund and annuities fees resulting from a change in accounting estimates, and higher net interest, partly offset by lower realized gains from the available-for-sale portfolio.</p>
          <p>The net credit loss expense was $16 million, solely attributable to our securities based lending business, compared with a recovery of $2 million in the third quarter. We continued to make progress in our banking and lending initiatives, recording 16% growth in average mortgage balances and 3% growth in securities based lending. Expenses increased 9%, mostly due to higher litigation provisions.</p>
          <p>Net new money inflows were very strong at $8.8 billion, driven mostly by advisers with the firm for at least a year and benefited from large year-end liquidity events and other inflows related to U.S. fiscal cliff concerns. Including dividends and interest, net new money increased to $16.7 billion due to larger seasonal dividend payments in December.</p>
          <p>Adviser head count remained broadly stable, around 7,000, which is the upper end of our target range. We reported new all-time highs in our key adviser productivity metrics, with annualized revenue per adviser surpassing the $1 million mark.</p>
          <p>In the Investment Bank, we made an excellent start implementing the accelerated strategy we announced in October. Once again, we were very successful in reducing Basel III RWAs and we achieved a reduction of CHF 31 billion mostly in Credit and Rates and FICC. These actions also led to a reduction in FICC revenues, which in light of the exceptional RWA reduction, was a good performance overall. The Investment Bank reduced its funded balance sheet by approximately CHF 72 billion. Average VaR decreased further to CHF 23 million and ended the quarter at just CHF 15 million, which is seasonally low in our view.</p>
          <p>Headcount declined by approximately 800 and we recorded CHF 224 million in restructuring costs. Excluding these costs, we recorded &#x2013; we reported a pre-tax loss of CHF 333 million on revenues of nearly CHF 1.7 billion.</p>
          <p>IBD revenues improved meaningfully and it recorded its best quarter in 2012. Advisory revenues were up 8% and we participated in three of the top 10 announced global M&amp;A transactions.</p>
          <p>Equity capital markets performed well with a 12% revenue increase, with a particularly strong quarter in APAC where we ranked number one in fees. Fixed income capital markets revenues improved on stronger performance in leveraged capital markets where revenues almost doubled. This improvement was partly offset by a decline in debt capital markets fees as we concentrated our efforts on target markets and products, in line with our strategy.</p>
          <p>In the Americas, global industrials, financial institutions, energy and real estate each had a strong quarter, aided by continued good performance in Wealth Management driven products such as master limited partnerships in Energy and closed-end funds in FIG.</p>
          <p>In EMEA, we saw strong performances from media and telecoms, FIG, infrastructure and GIG.</p>
          <p>In APAC, we continue to enjoy a leading market share in the high-margin areas of high yield and equity capital markets as well as connecting strategic capital across geographic borders. Our franchise and strategy continues to attract top tier talent and our investments in Energy and FIG paid off as they both showed significant growth versus the prior year.</p>
          <p>It was a slow quarter in the industry for Equities with low volatility and low market volumes. Despite the environment, Cash Equity's revenues increased sequentially on stable client activity and improved trading particularly in EMEA and APAC.</p>
          <p>Our Derivatives business suffered trading losses following high market volatility in Japan. Revenues in prime services decreased despite increased balances as funding revenues declined on lower spreads.</p>
          <p>Our plans to reduce the scope of activities in Credit and Rates led to an expected reduction in FICC revenues. In addition, there was a CHF 170 million increase in negative debit valuation adjustments as our credit spreads tightened.</p>
          <p>In macro <mark type="audio gap" /> (28:40-28:45) time gain of CHF 88 million on the sale of an equity investment. Revenues in Rates declined significantly as a result of our focusing and reshaping of that business. Credit performed well despite an expected drop in flow trading and structured credit revenues as we reduced risk-weighted assets in those businesses, and it benefited from a solid quarter in Real Estate Financing and Corporate Lending.</p>
          <p>The pro forma information shown on this slide reflects the estimated full-year financial performance for 2012 of the core Investment Bank and for the non-core activities we're exiting, as announced in October. At this point, these figures represent our best estimates of the historical performance of the Investment Banking business based on our new structure. We may refine these in our annual report for 2012 as we provide additional information including quarterly breakdowns of the pro forma estimates.</p>
          <p>As you can see on the chart, we've separately identified Treasury related activities that in the past were managed by the Investment Bank on behalf of the group. In 2012, these activities generated approximately CHF 400 million of revenues and CHF 300 million of profits.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we've centralized all of these activities into Group Treasury within our corporate center. At the same time, related repo activities were reduced significantly and will continue to be further reduced. As a result, the revenue contribution from these activities will decrease in the future. Consistent with our allocation of Treasury revenues, business divisions other than the Investment Bank, most particularly Wealth Management, will see an increase in Treasury revenues allocated to them.</p>
          <p>Global Asset Management had a strong performance. Pre-tax profit improved by 30% to $164 million on higher revenues driven by Global Real Estate and the Alternative and Quantitative business as well as lower expenses. The cost income ratio improved to 67%.</p>
          <p>Investment performance was very good for the majority of our traditional strategies and we had a particularly strong quarter for Alternatives. We saw net new money outflows of CHF 3.3 billion while strong performance has been a positive factor in third-party institutional net new money, it was outweighed by liquidity needs, portfolio realignment and general de-risking by Wealth Management and other wholesale clients.</p>
          <p>Retail &amp; Corporate's performance remained resilient with a CHF 362 million pre-tax profit. Despite continued low interest rates in Switzerland, the business posted increased revenues, reflecting increased fees from corporate finance activities.</p>
          <p>We also saw an increase in credit loss expenses as we raised provisions for a small number of workout cases which was partly offset by a decline in our collective loan loss allowance. Expenses were higher mostly in the G&amp;A line including higher legal provisions for litigation, regulatory, and similar matters.</p>
          <p>Net new business volume was again strong and above our target range, driven by growth in net new client assets from corporate and institutional clients, and deposit inflows as we continued to regain share in our home market. As Sergio mentioned, our performance in the fourth quarter enabled us to achieve the highest net new client assets from Retail customers since 2001.</p>
          <p>Corporate Center core functions reported a pre-tax loss of nearly CHF 1.5 billion, driven primarily by litigation provisions related to LIBOR. Reported operating income was a loss of CHF 271 million, driven by an own credit loss of CHF 414 million on the tightening of our credit spreads, partly offset by a CHF 112 million gain on the sale of properties in Switzerland and a hedge ineffectiveness gain of CHF 37 million.</p>
          <p>We've reduced corporate center head count by approximately 1,000 in the past year and 6,000 since 2008. As we continue our efforts on our cost reduction program, we expect restructuring charges for the group of approximately CHF 300 million in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Corporate Center Legacy reported a loss of CHF 501 million, driven by litigation provisions related to mortgage-backed securities. We reported a CHF 91 million gain on the revaluation of the SNB StabFund option. Since the creation of our Legacy portfolio announced at Investor Day in 2011, we've reduced Basel III RWAs from CHF 80 billion to CHF 38 billion and the funded balance sheet declined by CHF 9 billion to CHF 20 billion.</p>
          <p>Adjusting for currency fluctuations, we've achieved CHF 1.4 billion in run-rate savings since we announced our original program in the summer of 2011 primarily through head count reductions of approximately 3,100, which have resulted in lower personnel expenses. These savings, however, were more than offset by higher litigation and regulatory provisions. In view of the current regulatory and political climate affecting financial institutions and because we continue to be exposed to a number of claims and regulatory issues arising from the financial crisis of 2007 to 2009 and other matters, we expect associated charges to remain at elevated levels at least through 2013.</p>
          <p>The performance awards pool for 2012 was CHF 2.5 billion. Following a decrease of almost 40% in 2011, partly to reflect the unauthorized trading incident, we reduced the pool in 2012 by an additional 7%. The IFRS expense for the performance year was CHF 1.7 billion, which excludes approximately CHF 800 million of deferred awards for 2012 as they'll be recognized in the future.</p>
          <p>Adding the expense for 2012 to the CHF 1.3 billion of amortization for prior-year awards, we arrive at the 2012 IFRS expense of CHF 3 billion, which is 17% lower than 2011, excluding restructuring costs.</p>
          <p>We reduced awards to be amortized in future periods by CHF 700 million or 31% year-over-year to CHF 1.5 billion. This reduction includes CHF 1.3 billion of awards for previous years amortized in 2012 and CHF 200 million of awards forfeited, partly offset by CHF 800 million in awards granted for the 2012 performance year. We expect to amortize CHF 600 million of the CHF 1.5 billion in unrecognized awards in 2013.</p>
          <p>We reduced Basel III RWAs by CHF 43 billion in the quarter closing the year at approximately CHF 258 billion. Since the third quarter of 2011, we've achieved a total reduction of 35%. I'd like to emphasize that 84% of the reduction has come from sales and exposure reduction.</p>
          <p>At year-end, the Investment Bank had CHF 131 billion in Basel III RWAs. In the first quarter, we transferred approximately CHF 67 billion of RWAs from the Investment Bank to the Corporate Center. On a pro forma basis as of year-end, the Investment Bank Non-Core and Legacy would have represented approximately CHF 105 billion while the Investment Bank would have been CHF 64 billion, below our target of CHF 70 billion.</p>
          <p>Future RWAs will be impacted by FINMA's decision to apply a bank specific multiplier for banks using the internal ratings based approach. This applies to new and renewed Swiss residential mortgages. The multiplier will be phased in over the next seven years. Based on our current portfolio, we expect the multiplier to cause a CHF 2 billion to CHF 3 billion increase in RWAs for Retail &amp; Corporate and Wealth Management combined for each year from 2013 through 2019.</p>
          <p>We maintained our capital leadership and grew our ratios despite the quarterly loss and the negative CHF 900 million impact of IAS 19R and other adjustments to our capital calculations.</p>
          <p>Our Basel III common equity Tier 1 ratio stood at 15.3% on a phase-in basis and 9.8% on a fully-applied basis at year end. In future quarters, we'll see volatility in our fully applied CET 1 ratio as a result of IAS 19R related movements.</p>
          <p>This quarter, we've accrued in our capital account for high-trigger loss-absorbing capital as part of our 2012 compensation programs. Over the next five years, we could build approximately 100 basis points of high-trigger loss-absorbing capital from these programs.</p>
          <p>We reduced our funded balance sheet by CHF 76 million in the quarter to approximately CHF 840 billion, about a third of our overall targeted reduction. The remainder of the reduction will come from businesses we're exiting as our core Investment Bank already operates within its funded balance sheet target of less than CHF 200 billion.</p>
          <p>Our Basel III liquidity coverage and net stable funding ratios remain comfortably above minimum requirements. Our RWA and asset reductions give us more flexibility to accelerate the reduction of the liability side of our balance sheet as well.</p>
          <p>This slide shows a list of outstanding preferred securities treated as hybrid Tier 1 capital. As you can see at the top of the table, the &#x20AC;995 million issue has a first call date this April. As a result of our lower funding needs, we'll exercise our option to call this instrument on its first call date. We do not expect to attribute profits to non-controlling interests in the first quarter but we expect to attribute CHF 200 million of profits to preferred noteholders in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Today, we have announced cash tender offers to repurchase up to approximately CHF 5 billion of senior unsecured debt. You'll find more details about these offers in today's announcement. Our actions to prudently manage the composition of our liabilities will lower interest expense in the future. Please note these actions could lead to a tightening of our credit spreads, and as a result, we could see significant own credit charges in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>We made meaningful progress during the fourth quarter in the execution of our strategy by reducing RWAs and our balance sheet. In challenging markets, our businesses have performed well and the transformation of our Investment Bank is on track. These achievements and our confidence in the future have allowed us to propose a 50% increase in capital returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Sergio and I will now take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question from the phone is from Mr. Huw van Steenis from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Congratulations on the deleveraging. It looks to me you're about six to nine months ahead of your, the &#x2013; as per the targets you put out in the market. And so on that, I suppose two questions. First would be with the CHF 5 billion of senior debt you're buying back...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. <mark type="indiscernible" />  (41:09). I have a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, what happened in your Wealth Management unit in the fourth quarter? Yesterday Julius Baer reported that December was the best month in the entire year. And you have net new money below expectations and margin declined. And furthermore, concerning the money outflow from Western European countries is that due to the tax issue with Germany because Germany is the biggest country there? So perhaps you can elaborate a little bit on that.</p>
          <p>Second question concerns the bonus pool. Perhaps, observers might think that the reduction of 7% is a little disappointing and I've calculated that the compensation rate is in 2012, about 57%. That's much higher than Deutsche Bank or your American peers. Perhaps you can elaborate on that too. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the last question and then Tom will take the Wealth Management one. I think that when we look at 2012, our people have worked extremely well in executing our strategy both in terms of capital accretion, in terms of reducing cost and taking risk, controlling risks in many areas of our businesses as we just say, that we achieved record profitabilities. Last year, our performance pool was down 40%. It was affected by the unauthorized trading incidents. So when we look at year-on-year performance, one has to look into this strategic and objectives that we achieved.</p>
          <p>The other very important point I have to say is that when you look at our compensation framework, we have introduced more stringent conditions for &#x2013; to make sure that a big chunk of this compensation will be deferred over time and is subject to sustainable performance achievements. And last but not least, I think that comparing our comp ratio to the one of large commercial banks is like comparing apple with oranges. And I think that's, compensation framework I do think reflects the strategic objectives we have in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So then on your question on the gross margin and activity levels in the fourth quarter in Wealth Management, so one thing that I think, looking at the gross margin development that we need to take into account first is net interest margin. And we've made a choice specifically in our replication portfolios not to extend duration in a low interest rate environment in order to try to chase yield. And we think that's a better long-term decision for our shareholders and we're taking a little short-term pressure on the net interest margin to preserve the capital of our shareholders when interest rates eventually rise again.</p>
          <p>Second, if you look at the activity levels of clients in 4Q, in particular we saw a decline in transactional activity in the funds area in APAC, and also in the structured product areas, primarily in FX-related structured products as implied volatilities dropped in the fourth quarter. And we also had the seasonal effects of the holiday period in the last two weeks of the year.</p>
          <p>As we look out in terms of the &#x2013; some of the comments that have been made about activity levels of Retail investors potentially picking up as market levels rise, I think it's important for us to point out that there's &#x2013; that that behavior does not necessarily correlate with what you see with Wealth Management clients, and that we've found that high net worth and ultra-high net worth clients in making their portfolio shifts from cash assets, where in our advisory accounts in Wealth Management, we have about 28% of our clients' money in cash today.</p>
          <p>That shift from cash to riskier asset classes will become a multi-year process, not a multi-quarter process. And further, it requires us to see better progress on the global fiscal issues in a number of countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, let's move to Huw van Steenis on the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. van Steenis, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. So congratulations on your deleveraging. It strikes me you're about six, maybe nine months ahead of the targets you put out. So I have two questions. First, in terms of the CHF 5 billion of senior bonds that you've highlighted today, I couldn't see the cues as to which particular securities you're buying back. Is there any indication you could give us to potential savings in net interest income, and obviously if they're a par or over par potential capital hit? And then secondly, with the acceleration in &#x2013; successful acceleration of rundown of risk-weighted assets, how does that govern the way you think about the dividends for this year and for next year, and potential dividend increases? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On dividend, Huw, I think that as we stated before, we will introduce progressive capital return policies but the substantial steps will be done once we achieve our 13% targets, which we still have in light &#x2013; in sight of delivering by the end of 2014.</p>
          <p>At that point in time, we have committed and we will commit to at least 50% capital returns policy, but between now and then, I think that it will be marginal. And Tom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I'll take that one. Thanks, Sergio. So, Huw, on the tender offer, we have details in the tender offers that we've put out in the various jurisdictions where they're active. If you look, there's &#x2013; first, there's a U.S. tender offer that's for a purchase of up to CHF 2.5 billion across seven note issues of senior unsecured securities. There's CHF 12.6 billion in total outstandings in that pool. When we look at the European tender, it's for a cash tender of up to &#x20AC;2.25 billion across another seven issues of senior unsecured where there's a total of &#x20AC;8.1 billion outstanding. Trying to calculate what we're going to save is obviously a little question on how we're trying to anticipate investor behavior in each one of the issues.</p>
          <p>I would say the best way to think about it for us, we see it as neutral within the first 12 months of the year and something that has &#x2013; should have a range of roughly a 4% to 4.5% payback over the life of the notes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Derek De Vries, Bank of America. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I have a couple of questions if I might. First of all, in Wealth Management on the cost line and &#x2013; so your revenues were down slightly on Q3, but your comp costs and your non-comp costs are both up with the non-comp being up pretty significantly even stripping out restructuring charges. I was wondering if you could give us a little more color on that. Is that just seasonality or is there something sort of notable in there?</p>
          <p>And then I was also wondering if you can quantify the impact, still on Wealth Management, of moving the Treasury out of the Investment Bank and reallocating it to the divisions, if you could give us the impact that will have on gross margin in basis points? And then just sort of related to the gross margin there, I saw you made a comment, Tom, on the &#x2013; on Bloomberg about not being overly concerned about the margin. Is that related to the Treasury or is that just kind of in the long term, you think you'll get there, or is there anything else that makes you not overly concerned despite the big miss versus your target there?</p>
          <p>And then just one last question, I guess. In the Investment Bank, you've now had three months to further sort of execute your strategy. I was wondering if you had any sort of shift in, on the margin in terms of businesses that you are exiting or maintaining? And then I guess, still in Investment Banking, on the VaR &#x2013; I'm sorry, not on the VaR, on the risk weighted assets, the CHF 64 billion, that's on a VaR based sort of methodology, do you have any sense as to where that might be in the new methodology, the sort of stress losses methodology, or expected shortfall I guess, the new methodology, where that CHF 64 billion might go or is that just broadly the right number? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. So starting first with your question on Wealth Management and cost. There actually are two types of seasonals that are affecting that, the first was we had some one-time benefits that hit us in the third quarter that weren't repeated in 4Q. We also did see some upticks that are slightly seasonal, for example, in the T&amp;E line in the fourth quarter. We also saw, we started a new marketing campaign around our product capabilities, so we incurred the expenses for the development of that program, the initial rollout of that in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The other things I think I would note, we did, as I mentioned in my remarks, we did postpone some head count notifications that we had intended for the fourth quarter to the first quarter. So we do have some future actions in place to start to take down the cost base. And then the other thing I'd note, that our long term strategic cost reduction program across the group will certainly benefit the Wealth Management business because our drive outside of the consolidation of the on and offshore businesses in Europe, our desire is not, certainly not to touch the front office portion of the businesses.</p>
          <p>And in terms of your questions on the reallocation of the income to Treasury and how we would &#x2013; I'm sorry, from Treasury to Wealth Management, I think the best way to think about it is the &#x2013; certainly the majority of the revenues will be going to Wealth Management. But as I noted, the amount of repo activity we're going to have with the free cash generated by Wealth Management will certainly be lower than it was last year. So I'd say a rough estimate to use is in the &#x2013; roughly around the CHF 100 million range, which is certainly a variable number depending on markets.</p>
          <p>In terms of gross margin and my comment that I wasn't overly concerned with it, that's because we actually see, as I mentioned, certain short-term effects on the gross margin that actually aren't indicative of what we believe the future potential of the business is. I think it's important to note that we, as I mentioned in response to an earlier question, that we are positioning ourselves conservatively based on our view on &#x2013; ultimately a rise in interest rates. So we may be taking some short-term pain on the gross margin, but ultimately we believe that's better for our shareholders overall.</p>
          <p>Second, what I mentioned about the timing in terms of how long will it take Wealth Management clients to adjust their asset allocation from liquid cash into riskier assets. And I would say that they intend to be, especially with the help of their client advisers, more disciplined about that transition rather than hair-trigger in their adjustments in their portfolios.</p>
          <p>So we still believe the 95 to 105 basis point range is an appropriate target, but we certainly need to see resolution of the fiscal issues across the globe as well as improved global growth to achieve that.</p>
          <p>On the Investment Bank, after the three months of experience, how do we feel? We certainly feel that Investment Bank has done a fantastic job in terms of getting the group positioned and started on the acceleration of our strategy. We have the core IB underneath its RWA target, underneath its funded balance sheet target and we've had a good start to the reductions in our cash positions, certainly in the non-core portfolio.</p>
          <p>I'd also point out we did have some favorable tailwinds in terms of market conditions in the fourth quarter. We like to take advantage of those, which we obviously did. But we feel that we've had a good start, but as Sergio mentioned in his remarks, that's just the beginning of again, of a multi-year process for us, but we feel good about the momentum we have early on.</p>
          <p>Regarding the RWA question. I'd point you to really two things, Derek. I think first, with our VaR down to CHF 15 billion at year-end, the amount of delta that we're really going to have on our market risk in terms of a standardized approach has probably been significantly minimized from when the issue first came up before we had changed our strategy back in 2011.</p>
          <p>Second, in looking at the BCBS study that was recently released, we find ourselves falling in the middle of the pack in terms of looking at the results, which is where we thought we would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot for taking my questions, I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Jon Peace from Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I've got three questions, please. The first one relates to the risk-weighted assets run-off you saw in the Legacy portfolio in the Investment Bank in the fourth quarter. Just wondered if you could comment on the P&amp;L from the reduced exposure, whether there were any exit costs and how that makes you feel about forward-looking exit costs as you continue to run those positions down?</p>
          <p>The second question is although you're well ahead of targets in RWA reduction, I see you haven't changed your 2013, 2015, 2017 targets overall. Is that conservatism or is that because you're anticipating this FINMA multiplier?</p>
          <p>And then final the question relates to that helpful slide 17 where you give us the picture of the new Investment Bank revenue profile. I guess as we look to 2013, you would hope to grow the Investment Banking and Equities pieces but the fixed-income piece is still sort of rolling off. So I don't know if you could just help us at the highest level what you think the revenue and the mix of that business might look like in one, two years' time? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe I'll tackle the second question and then Tom can address the other two. I guess, of course we are focusing very much on our targets and reviewing them on a regular basis, but I think it would be inappropriate to change target on a quarterly basis based on a couple of weeks of favorable market conditions. So I think that we do think that, considering all the problems that are still out there unresolved, it would be not realistic for us to change targets.</p>
          <p>Of course, we feel very good about the momentum we had in the fourth quarter. We feel good about our path and execution &#x2013; in executing the strategy, but we want to be realistic. In respect of multiplier of FINMA, as you saw in our chart, there is an increase in our &#x2013; in the blue bar in the Retail &amp; Corporate business that goes from around CHF 95 billion to CHF 105 billion over the next years, which is embedding these kind of changes and some growth and also optimization that we will run through our portfolio. Therefore, I think that there is no need to change our target based on these FINMA multiplier introductions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Sergio. So, Jon, on your first question on the RWA reductions and costs of exit, as you can tell from the P&amp;L we obviously saw minimal exit costs during the quarter. In terms of a forward look on that, I'd repeat what I said about having a favorable environment. We certainly look to take advantage of that. But it's also a long path.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we do have the &#x2013; we are in a position that I noted when we announced the third quarter results, that we meet our capital ratio targets merely by allowing in particular the over-the-counter book just to roll off. And any time that we look at accelerating our reductions in our portfolio, it's only if we believe we're going to generate additional shareholder value by doing so, and we measure that by taking a look at the cost of equity to support those positions during the time period we would have to carry them versus the acceleration time period.</p>
          <p>In terms of the pro forma questions and how you should think about it. So, one, I think the first thing is I mentioned we'll have more information in the annual which will show you a quarterly breakdown which I think will be quite helpful because my overall comment on the year would be obviously when you look at these revenues, these revenues were generated with a much higher average RWA than the utilization that we're going to have in the core Investment Bank going forward.</p>
          <p>I do think, your focus on what do we want to grow and where do we think the performance will come from, we certainly are looking for an improved performance from Equities in the year. Our IBD division is already performing well and we'd expect to see that continue. And obviously, FICC, which includes some of the Treasury revenues previously plus almost entirely 100% of the RWA reductions that we've taken, I think that that's probably the best way for you to start to think about it and I think the quarterly time series in the annual will help you get there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mrs. Fiona Swaffield from RBC.  Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I had a couple of questions. One was you mentioned the FINMA multiplier but I've been reading about the potential for a countercyclical buffer on real estate. Could you talk about what impact that could be and how that could change your core Tier 1 target?</p>
          <p>The second issue is on fixed income going forward, I mean I was quite surprised how strong Credit was. Are there any one-off positives in there from derisking, or I mean what's the long term strategy or expectation of remedies from Credit, because I thought that was there the RWAs were coming out?</p>
          <p>And lastly, just to understand on the gross margin, you talked about foregoing higher revenues from net interest income because of the strategy on interest rates, but the weakness in the margin in Q4 was only partly due to interest rates. So should we expect some seasonality? Q1 is usually a good quarter, and could you talk about potential seasonality in Q1 2013? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I'll just tackle the one on the introduction of any counter-cyclical buffer. Of course, this will not change our target, 13%. I think that, as we outlined last year, I think that we do intend to have an additional buffer in our capital days that hopefully we can control on a proactive basis. We will see how the regulatory framework changes, but we &#x2013; in any case, we would not change our targets based on any introduction of additional buffers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Fiona, on your question on FICC and the result there, I'd say first, I think our teams in Credit and Rates actually handled the reduction of the positions in the portfolio extremely well and as a result of that I think some of the outperformance is also in reducing positions in a very smart way during the course of the quarter. So there may have been some flattering benefit too as a result of that.</p>
          <p>Second, we also, when we announced the acceleration of our strategy, also indicated that we wouldn't drop in-flight client transactions; that we'd complete anything that was in the pipeline. So we had a couple of more advisor-related types of roles in structured solutions and in real estate where those had already been set up and we completed those transactions with our clients during the course of the quarter.</p>
          <p>So I think in order to get more visibility on that certainly will be helpful when you see our first quarter results, which then in a way takes us to the next question, was on Wealth Management. So what about the &#x2013; is there a seasonality 4Q to 1Q, what should we anticipate? Certainly, the fourth quarter saw a reduction in transactional activity and structured product activity related to the holiday season itself, and also due to some of the factors like decreased implied volatility in currencies.</p>
          <p>As those conditions change as we move through the first quarter, that could certainly change our clients' views of their &#x2013; of how they'd like to interact with us during the course of the quarter. But overall, I'd repeat what I said about net interest margin and the fact that we are deliberately not extending duration in this environment and so that will have a continuing drag on the gross margin. But we ultimately think that's the best solution for shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Kian Abouhossein from JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I have a few questions. Just coming back to the margin, slide 12, net &#x2013; you mentioned that there's the liability spread margin pressure. Can you tell us how much more in terms of basis points or in terms or revenue impact, assuming no interest rate changes we should expect from margin pressure? And in terms of trading activity, we have seen a material improvement in trading activity, both in Retail and Institutional. For January, shouldn't we assume that that's a good indicator for what's happening in your business and that's I think what Julius Baer was referring yesterday. I'm just wondering why you are more cautious than what we heard yesterday from one of your peers.</p>
          <p>The second question is related to slide 17. The revenue loss on your non-core, does that relate to slide 26, your roughly CHF 65 billion of &#x2013; CHF 67 billion of non-core? And in that respect on slide 22, can you explain to me the CHF 1.4 billion of cost savings, are they realized or are they annualized, these numbers? Just I'm not clear from the slide.</p>
          <p>And the last one is on tax rate, your tax rate is &#x2013; you mentioned 25% to 30% in the first half, what is it for the full year and what do you expect for next year? I have to say, I was hoping to get a bit more detail on the new divisional breakdown and hence a lot of detailed questions as it's not possible to do the model with the slides that you're giving. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Kian, let me tackle the first question. I think that of course as you are rightly pointing out both in the fourth quarter and the beginning of the year, we see a little bit more activity particularly by Retail clients globally, but this cannot be a proxy for how our Wealth Management clients, particularly high net worth and ultra-high net worth clients behave, therefore, to use that as a proxy could be misleading. But maybe I want to go back a year ago. You remember that a year ago, it turned out that we were coming across a little bit pessimistic because we weren't so bullish about how January develops. So I have to say that story repeats itself.</p>
          <p>We cannot multiply January 2012. And January is not a good proxy of &#x2013; on how a year works. We do believe that there is still a lot of challenges out there, a lot of issues are unresolved. In Europe both microeconomically and in respect of the entire financial systems, there are unresolved issues in the U.S. in terms of the fiscal cliff issues and for sure growth is not something I would say can be taken for granted in the global economy.</p>
          <p>Therefore, we have to manage our business according to what we expect to happen over the next 12 months. It's not being too cautious, it's just being realistic about what we have been seeing the last few years, learning the lessons and making sure that we also fully understand that the opportunity cost for us of being wrong and being cautious is fairly limited compared to the risk we take if we are overly optimistic in positioning our business going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Kian, to go back to one of your questions where you asked about liability, sort of the pressure on our net interest margin and how you actually should think about that. I think the pattern excluding the effect of the strategic investment portfolio in looking at 2011 versus 2010 is a reasonable basis upon which to model 2012 versus 2011 declines in margin, assuming there's no change in interest rates.</p>
          <p>Obviously as interest rates are changing during the course of the year, we're re-rolling, replicating portfolio tranches, to the extent that interest rates rise somewhat, we may have an opportunity to improve on that. But to the extent that the environment becomes more challenging, that would continue to compress the margins, but nevertheless obviously since a lot of these replicating portfolio tranches could have been put on a few years ago, we're reinvesting at lower rates than the original tranches had been put on.</p>
          <p>But I would emphasize though, it is a net interest margin calculation. And so rather than focusing on duration as I mentioned, an extension of duration, we're spending a lot of our time looking at the optimization of the liability structure, so reducing costs to the divisions in terms of our overall liability mix, which is why we announced the Hybrid Tier 1, our intention to call the Hybrid Tier 1 today and also our announcement of the debt tender. So there are two different ways for us to approach this issue and we're spending a lot of time focusing on the liabilities side of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>On your multi-slide question, so this is from 17 and I guess 22, 17 and 22 and how you bridge those. The first one is the non-core in terms of what you should think about &#x2013; not 22, maybe 26, sorry &#x2013; in terms of the way you think about it, that non-core section is related to the Corporate Center non-core CHF 67 billion in RWAs that you see on the pro forma post transfer, except when you think about the revenues that were generated in 2012. Remember that those were generated on the substantially higher RWA base throughout the course of the year of 2012.</p>
          <p>I do think it highlights for you some of the things we told you in the third quarter though, which was when we looked at the businesses we put in the non-core and you looked at the total costs of operating these businesses and the costs of complexity, what you see in that pre-tax result, rather than just focusing on the revenue, is the fact that reduction of these non-core assets is what allows us to take out complexity costs in our business.</p>
          <p>And so when you think about it, acceleration of our non-core asset portfolio reduction will put us in a position where we're able to take out costs, albeit with a lag, because some of those structural costs take some time to move out.</p>
          <p>In terms of the tax rate question where we &#x2013; we talked the about 25% to 30% for the first half of the year, if you assume, and that's what my comment alluded to, which is no change in terms of deferred tax asset revaluations, obviously we'd be at the same rate for the full year and that's currently the way we're thinking about the full-year tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the slide 17, clearly that slide 17 on non-core implies CHF 1.3 billion of costs. And it's good that you say there could be a bit of mismatch of revenues and costs. But on the CHF 1.3 billion of costs, can you tell me how many staff members are part of the CHF 1.3 billion? And just of the CHF 1.4 billion of costs that you say you've realized &#x2013; is this annualized, the CHF 1.4 billion on 22, slide 22, or is this a real number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think that &#x2013; sorry, on the &#x2013; I forgot to comment on your slide 22. I wouldn't combine slides 22 and 17 together. The slide 22 is the net cost savings, going back and looking at our cost program that we announced at the end of the second half 2011, and those are the realized run-rate savings from those initiatives, which as I mentioned, was a reduction of 3,100 personnel since the announcement of that cost savings program.</p>
          <p>I think when you look at the non-core piece, the real piece of work that we have to do on the cost base, as I mentioned, is the complex infrastructure that we have supporting those complex businesses. And so the better that we're able to accelerate the reduction in particular of the OTC book, that will allow us to take out some structural costs more quickly. But I do have to tell you that that's the stickier part of the balance sheet reduction. It's also the stickier part of the cost reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just, sorry, on the CHF 1.4 billion, you say it's the run rate, so what is the real realized cost savings? And it looks like it's not the new cost savings, as I understand it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's separated from the incremental savings program that we announced in the third quarter. The progress, we announced that in October, so we obviously, as I indicated, we notified 1,900 personnel of redundancy in the fourth quarter, that's what the restructuring charges in the fourth quarter represent. So we began the improvement in our cost base from that point.</p>
          <p>Those personnel will come out of those staff roles and thus off the payroll primarily in the first quarter and the second quarter. We had a slight reduction in the rolls in 4Q and there will be a slight reduction in 3Q [sic] 2013 (1:13:41), the bulk of which will be 1Q and 2Q.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Kinner Lakhani from Citigroup. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. So firstly, just wanted to come back on the capital point where you basically told us that over time, the high-trigger CoCos could build up to about a percent of risk weighted assets. How does that change the shape of the capital structure, i.e. would it substitute for common equity or would it substitute for lower trigger CoCos?</p>
          <p>Related to that, just wanted to get an update on measures you're taking to improve resolvability, which I guess will over time also help you to reduce your end game capital target, and whether you have any kind of comment on subsidiarization including kind of the recent Fed proposal that we've had on U.S. subsidiaries?</p>
          <p>And finally, just on funding, it wasn't clear to me the interest expense that was saved on the CHF 5 billion buyback &#x2013; I know you gave us some guidance but I didn't quite follow &#x2013; but equally importantly, how we should think about further reduction in wholesale funding of your balance sheet over time? Should we relate it to the LCR ratio being 113%, NSFR at 108%, and obviously, a further reduction in your balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe I'll tackle the first question on &#x2013; the first two questions in respect of what this additional 100 basis points of high-trigger notes means for our capital base. I think that for sure it's introducing a degree of flexibility in how we manage high-trigger and low-triggers, and how we manage what we always said, we want to have an additional buffer above the 13%.</p>
          <p>But the most important issue in addition to this benefit is that we have basically created an instrument that while recognizes compensation also creates a value for shareholders. And there is as much as a message to our shareholders and bondholders about how we want employee to be aligned with their interest and vice versa than there is just the pure issues about creating capital.</p>
          <p>So in a nutshell, I think this instrument creates flexibility in terms of contingent capital options, not in respect of our targets of 13% and is a message about creating sustainability with our shareholders. Of course, when we go into the resolution, we are working on the resolution, we are working on different ideas on how to speed up the process of subsidiarization of some of our activities outside Switzerland, but remember that &#x2013; the eligibility, we've got to make sure that we are eligible for further capital reduction, but this is going to be a subjective assessment of the regulators in respect how much additional rebate we will get.</p>
          <p>So what we showed you last quarter was a change from the 19% to the 17.5% which is based purely on our reduction of balance sheet, and this is a factual element of our calculation. The further reduction is a subjective assessment of our regulator in respect if we are allowed to get it or not. And all &#x2013; and it's going to take time to develop all these changes in our core corp. structure in order to get the eligibility to be there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Then Kinner, on your last question, talking about the funding and how I evaded disclosing the actual number, I think that would take some of the fun out of it for you. I think if you look at the tender offer, you'll be able to see based on the issues that we have and the caps that we have on the total purchase we think you'll be able to work back to what that is.</p>
          <p>I think the guidance I gave you will help you to do that by saying pretty much assume one for one over the 12-month time period in terms of the initial expense for us relative to the savings in a year and then think about it as a 4x to 4.5x on the cost in year one as the life-to-date savings over the maturity profile of the instruments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And should we expect kind of further buyback optimization on the wholesale funding part, every time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way I'd describe, I think overall we obviously have set out based on our 2015 targets, a 2015 target liability structure and we've laid out our funding plan for this year including changes in that mix and the way we'd like to see that develop. I think as you see our first quarter balance sheet relative to where we are at year-end and you start to do some of the comparative work, I think you'll see how we're beginning to shift that mix. But obviously as we noted at the 3Q announcement, we're certainly shifting where deposits are a higher percentage over time of our mix but it's a part of our mix. We want to make sure we've got a diversified liability structure, one that's both optimized on cost and tenor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Matt Spick from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have three questions if that is possible. The first was on retrocessions and there is some disclosure on pages 22 and 98 of the full report but I just wondered if you could remind us what percentage of your client AUM's in discretionary mandates and whether retrocessions was one of the contributing factors to perhaps being a bit cautious on the gross revenue margin in 2013.</p>
          <p>The second question is obviously it's very difficult to forecast revenues for the pro-forma Investment Bank but I wondered if you could update us on roughly the head count that will be in that business during the first quarter. I'm working with an assumption it might be 9,000 to 10,000 total, of which about 1,000 people would be fixed income front office. So I wondered if you thought that was reasonable estimate?</p>
          <p>And then finally just on the Equities business in 2013, obviously we all hope it's a lot better. But the margin pressure in cash equities is obviously still there, and I think margin pressure is picking up in Prime Finance. So I wondered if you had any comments on how you felt your Prime Finance business was positioned for 2013, whether you saw that margin pressure as well, and whether the rescaling or descaling of the balance sheet have any impact on Prime Finance more generally. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Matt, thanks for those questions on the retrocessions, what percentage of the assets have been discretionary, it's 12.8% of the assets that we have. In terms of the next &#x2013; could you repeat your third question on &#x2013; you had mentioned something about margins and volumes. I just want to make sure I got the intent correctly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the question is really just Prime Finance, very high Retail Equity business. Historically, it had a lot of market concentration and I think margins are under quite a lot of pressure there. You've got quite a big Prime Finance business, do you see margins under pressure and how do you feel about that business for 2013 given the shrinkage of the balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so certainly as you look at 2013 Equities, the Equities business overall is one of the Basel III friendly businesses, certainly is one in its various areas, that has increasing competition. However, one of the reasons why we accelerated our strategy and positioned ourselves with greater focus on, for us, a key area of equities overall is to make sure that we have the investments, the sufficient investment that we need to make in order to make sure that we are as equipped to handle our clients' business, and in particular our execution, as efficiently as we can going forward and in the most up-to-date methods that we can from a technology perspective.</p>
          <p>So first, I think the changes that we've made strategically reinforce some of the investment needs that we see as a result of your thesis about what's happening in the industry. I think exactly when you're, I think, believe you were specifically talking about the prime brokerages and &#x2013; prime brokerage and balance and spreads, we look at that as an additional component of the products that we have for our clients and not just a standalone business on its own. It's part of what we do, as we concentrate our investments in our, in a key area like equities, we also want to make sure that we're allocating balance sheet to those clients who actually feel that we're providing the appropriate amount of service and that they're presenting us with the order flow associated with that.</p>
          <p>And then sorry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Sergio's mentioning, also all the work that we're doing on the liability optimization on the balance sheet certainly will help to put us in a good position going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, Mr. Christopher Wheeler from Mediobanca. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, everybody. Just a few questions. First of all, perhaps you would give us a little bit more detail of the issue you had with derivatives in Japan and exactly what the story was there because obviously that's obviously had an impact against what seems to be a fairly good cash equity performance?</p>
          <p>Second, couple of questions on litigation. Tom, I think you talked about staying at high levels of cost into this year, I assume you're relating that to the CHF 449 million of Legacy issues. And related to that, in Wealth Management Americas, you talk about litigation, there's something like a 39% increase in non-comp cost which suggests maybe CHF 60 million or CHF 70 million of litigation. Perhaps you could clarify whether that was the case.</p>
          <p>And then finally, really on what Kinner was asking, I'm just now getting my head around the high-trigger, loss-absorbing capital and it doesn't seem to me, I mean, Sergio talked about the flexibility that gives you, but you didn't seem to talk about how that could mitigate the additional 3% above the 10% which has always been the issue around why you don't like high trigger CoCos. But I would've thought the high-trigger bail-in bonds would've fulfilled that part of that 3% requirement, and why you wouldn't try and utilize that?</p>
          <p>And perhaps related to that, could you give us some clue on the structure of the bonds that you're giving to staff? In other words, can you give us a clue on what the coupon will be? But also, I'm hearing that it may be five year cliff vesting. I just wondered what are you doing about loading up the coupon, how that will work, and perhaps also how you will calculate your redemption cost? Will be at par, or will you calculate it based on maybe the direction of your core Tier 1 ratio weight of the 7% trigger? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Christopher, thank you. You sound like an employee.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that a job offer, Sergio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not &#x2013; very interesting, very interesting questions. Actually to your question, the coupon, we're going to sell the coupon and taking in consideration the yield of the outstanding low-trigger instruments, therefore the yield to maturity. So we do not take a conservative view on that, and therefore I think it's a fair assessment on where the coupon will be. It will stay the same for the entire five-year life, and will be repaid at par unless of course we have an event coming in.</p>
          <p>In respect to why we are not using it against the 3% buffer, the 3% high-trigger buffer, it's purely because we do believe that we want to have our capital strength in full equity at this stage for sure. We want to have a 3% &#x2013; the 3% buffer being used with pure equity and not with contingent capital. In any case, as we say before, we do think that we're going to need an additional buffer in the future, and therefore we can use that flexibility.</p>
          <p>In respect of the big difference between this instrument, I guess, I don't know if I got exactly your question, but we are against CoCos because we don't want to introduce potential dilutions to our shareholders, and this instrument doesn't necessitate the issuance of Treasury shares which potentially could dilute shareholders. And it's purely obtaining the same results, but a write-off of the notional.</p>
          <p>So we do continue to believe we don't like the CoCo concept. We've talked about CoCa because it's contingent capital and not contingent convertibles. So it's fundamentally a completely different instrument from our standpoint of view in respect of taking away a huge dilution problem for shareholders and something that, in my point of view, could also disturb the normal market dynamics of the stock trading if an event happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I totally agree with you on that. And obviously, Barclays and other banks do as well. Would you actually think about issuing more high-trigger bail-in bonds because it does seem to make a lot of sense in terms of the kind of capital structure you're looking to achieve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's our plan is to go first with our low-triggers, building up our low-triggers and building our 3% core equity buffer, and then using the high-trigger through the employee plans. But, Christopher, over time, we make changes, not in the foreseeable future but we can see it as being an option for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Chris, if I could just add on to what Sergio said about the question. I think as you know, we've talked about how do you manage so you have your certain targets, but then how do you manage your capital during the course of the year? And so obviously, if you think about a 13% target where you've got a 10% plus 3% requirement, you've got to manage above that 13% level.</p>
          <p>One of the ways to do that is to introduce the high-trigger that we've introduced as part of the compensation program and that will give us more flexibility in terms of managing during the course of the year specifically, when we talked about the management counter cyclical capital buffer or how we manage our capital when we look at potential stress events that could occur.</p>
          <p>Going back and then addressing your second question, which was about the Wealth Management Americas historical litigation items, you're in the ballpark in terms of sizing the effect. I would just note that there were two lumpy issues in the course of the quarter, rather than a series of individual small events.</p>
          <p>Finally, you asked about what exactly happened in derivatives in Japan. This wasn't a major item. We just saw some trading losses in Japan, in our Japan's structured product book, hence volatility increased during the market rally in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I just wondered whether that CHF 449 million of litigation in the non-Legacy was the sort of benchmark against what you were saying, you expect similarly high charges in 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So the litigation in the Legacy book specifically deals with RMBS issues. I'm not sure about the sizing, if that's the correct way for you to look at that and extrapolate that going forward. But certainly, the pressures, if you look at a year-over-year comparison and stripping out the LIBOR issue as an event, we certainly see a rising &#x2013; an increasing cost per event of operational risk in those categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now many thanks for everybody for joining on the webcast. We now close the webcast sessions and we open for questions here in the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:30:56). How much are the outflows from the Swiss divest management in the fourth quarter linked to the sales tax deal with Germany and did this continue this year? And second question is do you stick with layoff of 10,000 jobs and will most of them go this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First off, what I think that so we are not releasing exact figures about outflows. But I would say that it's not just a matter of the sale tax treaty resolution but also many clients were preparing for any outcome and the outgoing flows are, the vast majority is people basically also now self declaring and having the outflows due to the fact that they need to pay the taxes upfront within few days, they need to go and pay taxes and deposit the taxes due.</p>
          <p>So I think for sure, there are ancillaries consequences across other countries in Europe that are looking. We see clients who are self-declaring themselves or taking other ways to address this issue, but we are working with our clients to address this issue. We want clients over time to understand that, how the paradigm has changed and how they should take these opportunities to address their tax matters. But I wouldn't call it a consequence of the failure of the tax treaty, something that we saw developing during the quarter rather than just in December.</p>
          <p>In respect of the 10,000 jobs, as you remember, what we mentioned is that those efficiency programs will take time, so you will see a big chunk is already went out in the last quarter. You will see more of this happening in the first six months of the year, but we are not expecting the 10,000 jobs to be reduced during 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Over there. You're first and then microphone there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Peter Holfield of the Blake Group (01:33:12). In what way did the future referendum on salaries in March influence the setting of the bonus pool?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we have been looking at our performance. We have been talking to our shareholders, we have been looking at the strategic objectives we've set. We have been talking to all our stakeholders. I think that we are not taking this as the reason why we should review our compensation policy. I think that we are trying to strike a balance for what is good for shareholders, our investors, bondholders and our employees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:34:00). Just two questions. Could you give us a breakdown of the net new business volume that you have told about in Switzerland, that 4.9%? Where does this growth come from? Is it the Mortgage business or the Corporate? And the second question is I would like you to share with me the slide number 24. I honestly don't understand this slide at all. It's &#x2013; the information I'm looking for is simply, can we see from this slide how much of bonus awards that have been granted in the past have actually been cancelled? Can we see that from this slide somehow? And if not, maybe you can give us this information in another way. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure. So if I take your questions in reverse order, looking at the slide 24 which shows the deferred compensations of the awards that we had to amortize as of last year's end &#x2013; I'm sorry, in 2011 year-end versus where we ended up at 2012 year-end, and what were the movements.</p>
          <p>So first we have the natural amortization of the awards. The second bar &#x2013; I'm sorry, the third bar that you pointed out which is the forfeited bar, which is forfeitures which could be forfeitures for a number of reasons. It could be employees who departed of their own will and left awards behind. It could be employees that we terminated for cause, for example, who would have forfeited awards as a result of that, or any formulaic forfeitures that occur &#x2013; could occur in any one of our plans.</p>
          <p>Taking your first question on the net new business volume, if we look at the breakdown of activity, first we've seen improvement in net new client assets deposit growth from our Retail clients. In terms of the loan book, actually in terms of the Mortgage book our market share in Mortgages has been declining as opposed to increasing as we continue to have that strong focus on the credit quality of our portfolio. But we did see in the other part of the net new business volume component strong growth in the Corporate part of the portfolio in terms of when we look in particular at custody mandates and other items like that where we have won back share that we actually had lost in the crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Teresa Nielsen from Bank Vontobel. I have a question regarding the gross margin. Of course, as you have stated, there is a volatility from seasonal impact but don't you believe that retrocessions could pressure further the gross margin, the whole theme about retrocessions, and that we could see further downside on the gross margin from that? And secondly, can you give some indication how many basis points approximately you believe that the gross margin will be positively impacted by the shift in Treasury revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On the retrocession issues of course, what we need to do is clearly tackle this challenge in respect of offering to our clients retrocession fee &#x2013; free products but on the other hand, we will absolutely need to re-price our services.  I mean it is absolutely critical that we understand that this is, cannot and will not be a downfall in profitability for the bank. And therefore, we're going to have to go through in re-pricing and looking at what client needs and come out with the best solutions for clients and for the bank in order to fairly compensate for the services we do for clients.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And then, Teresa, I'd just highlight, in addition to Sergio's answer, page 22 in the quarterly report. We have a piece that talks about how we see some of our product offerings changing in terms of what our clients are actually looking for, in terms of how they'd like to see their mandates structured in the future. And as Sergio said, there's a pricing component to that. And as a result, we will be phasing out receipt of retrocessions, and then looking at the introduction of the products, so there'll be a delay. So we'll be foregoing revenue.</p>
          <p>You'll certainly see a decline in our revenue during that time period. And then you'll see an uptick in terms of pricing that could recoup some or all of that fee. So you'll certainly see over the course of the next few quarters a little drag on the gross margin.</p>
          <p>To your question in terms of on the net interest, the Treasury piece, as I noted, isn't a very material piece in terms of the reallocation because the number was CHF 300 million last year. I stated because we're taking down the repo book, it's going to be less. I think the best way to think about net interest margin and things that we can do to improve it, again, it does take a look at pricing. We have to look at pricing in this environment but also the work that we're doing in terms of optimizing that liability structure, I think will be a far greater beneficiary over time to Wealth Management gross margins than just the reallocation of Treasury issues from one activity.</p>
          <p>&lt;Q &#x2013; [00F8X1-M Florian Hamann]: Florian Hamann from eFinancialCareers. I have only two short questions concerning your compensation. One is you mentioned a reduction of the cash bonus cap per head. Could you figure out how much is it, where is it now?</p>
          <p>And the second question, I've seen that your personnel expenses raised dramatically in your Investment Bank in the fourth quarter, is this due to severance pay or what is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the, on your second question, it is due to the severance pay. So it's the restructuring costs associated with the reduction of personnel. And then your second question on the cash cap was where was the cash cap previously?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The cash cap on compensation before. Per head, no, I mean, it is difficult per head because we had a maximum cash compensation of CHF 2 million. We reduced it to CHF 1 million, but...</p>
          <p>&lt;Q &#x2013; [00F8X1-M Florian Hamann]: So one...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The average per head.</p>
          <p>&lt;Q &#x2013; [00F8X1-M Florian Hamann]: No, the maximum per head.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's the maximum. So we reduced it from CHF 2 million to CHF 1 million. That's the maximum cash out immediate. To compensate for that and in addition, we introduced component of our deferred compensation that we will start to vest after three years and the deferred compensation plan that we cliff vest after five years.</p>
          <p>So those &#x2013; I guess this is the maximum, of course is not applicable. I think that the most &#x2013; but if you look at, another interesting way to look at it is how the compensation vesting has shifted. Basically we doubled the vesting periods for our compensation plan to more than two years now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you look at the compensation fact sheet that we posted, it'll also help you take a look at the mix going forward because obviously Sergio described the maximum and certainly the effect on most employees is a cash amount that's significantly below that because of the deferrals that we have in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:42:33). I have two questions, first about the retrocessions. You have booked litigations about CHF 2.1 billion for the fourth quarter. How much of this CHF 2.1 billion is for the retrocessions? And the second question is about kind of new normal maybe that I can see. If we add up all the benefits before taxes of the different divisions with leaving away the corporate center and the Investment Bank, we come up with about CHF 5.5 billion more or less for the year. Is that more or less the figure, the grand figure you see for the future of the bank? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So <mark type="ph" /> Lucas, (01:43:13) in terms of your question on retrocessions, as you noted in our litigation note 16, we did indicate that we do have a provision on the balance sheet for the retrocession issue but we're not disclosing what that is. But we believe we're appropriately reserved based on our assessment of the issue and the IFRS accounting standards surrounding litigation provisions.</p>
          <p>In terms of your question in terms of how you should think of the business, ex the Corporate Center and ex the Investment Bank, when that's where we have the bulk of our risk weighted assets and the bulk of our balance sheet, is a little interesting in terms of a thought process because I don't think you could just disaggregate that. Obviously, a certain amount of the Corporate Centers reporting those, is supporting those other businesses, those costs get allocated to them. The Investment Bank we believe, based on the targets that we've set, will return a pre-tax return on attributed Equity of 15% going forward. So I think if you want to think of the profile of UBS, excluding the Investment Bank would exclude something that will be a significant contributor in future years.</p>
          <p>And then finally on the non-core piece that's in the Corporate Center, we've got to complete our process. I mean, we started and made great progress in terms of balance sheet reduction, RWA reduction. We still have more to go. And as we indicated at our third quarter announcement, there'll be costs in terms of us getting out of both the infrastructure in the form of restructuring costs as well as potentially costs of exit on some positions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, just a quick one on the clawback, I didn't understood your answer, please. So just the number. From the bonuses that UBS promised to its employees in the past, how much of that has been cancelled in 2012? Can you just give that number, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's on the slide. Very well defined. Forfeited CHF 200 million.</p>
          <p>No more questions? Many thanks for attending and have a nice day. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference is now over. Thank you for choosing Chorus Call and thank you for participating in the conference. You may now disconnect your lines. Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>