<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1308987" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-05-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>631</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Caroline Stewart, Global Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Cryan, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Huw van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Derek De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jernej Omahen</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Matthew Clark</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Fiona Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Georg Kanders</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to our First Quarter Results Presentation. My name is Caroline Stewart and I'm the Head of Investor Relations here at UBS.</p>
          <p>This morning, John Cryan our Chief Financial Officer, will present the first quarter results. After the presentation, we'll be happy to take any of your questions.</p>
          <p>Before we get started today, I'd like to draw your attention to this slide. It contains our cautionary statement with regard to forward-looking statements. I'd recommend that you take a few moments to read it in detail.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to hand over to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. It's my pleasure to take you through the results for the first quarter of 2010. This morning, we reported a pre-tax profit of CHF 2.8 billion for the first quarter in line with the announcement we made just prior to our AGM last month.</p>
          <p>The net profit attributable to shareholders was CHF 2.2 billion, equivalent to diluted earnings per share of 58 Rappen and representing an annualized 21% return on average equity. The improvement in our revenues on the fourth quarter was attributable mostly to a significantly better result in our fixed income, currencies and commodities unit. This was achieved with no significant increase in risk taking. In fact, we continued to reduce our exposure to legacy risks during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Risk-weighted assets at quarter end were only marginally higher than they'd been at the start of the quarter and the average market value at risk was flat on recent quarters. We continue to build our financial strength, increasing our capital primarily through profit retention.</p>
          <p>Our tier 1 capital ratio at the end of the quarter was 16% and our core tier 1 ratio was 12.5%. Net new money remains a key focus of management. Although each of our asset gathering divisions saw continued outflows in the quarter, the level of outflows did fall substantially.</p>
          <p>This chart shows the first quarter performance by division. I'll go through detailed results for each division as usual, but at this point let me make some general remarks on the overall result.</p>
          <p>Our revenues in the quarter totaled CHF 9.3 billion before own credit effects. This brings us close to our medium-term revenue target of over CHF 10 billion per quarter. Revenues were positively impacted by the strong trading environment in the fixed income markets, especially in January.</p>
          <p>Personnel expenses across the group do show an uptick on the level we reported in Q4. You may recall that for the 2009 performance year, we increased the proportion of variable compensation awarded in the form of deferred share grants. This change was booked in the fourth quarter with a cumulative adjustment for prior quarters and had the effect of deferring into future periods, the recognition of a greater proportion of the overall cost of variable compensation in our accounts.</p>
          <p>The personnel expense charge in this quarter reflects a return to a more normal level of compensation accrual. However, variable compensation is determined annually, so you should bear in mind that the rate of bonus accrual could change through the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>The own credit charge for the quarter was just under CHF 250 million, so that at quarter end we held a net life-to-date gain from own credit of just over CHF 650 million.</p>
          <p>The tax charge of 603 million represent an implied tax rate of 21.5%, in line with what we currently expect our long-term normalized tax rate to be.</p>
          <p>The vast majority of the charge, some 565 million was a deferred tax expense as Swiss tax losses, for which we previously recognized deferred tax assets, were applied against profits for the quarter. We also incurred tax expenses of 125 million mainly on profits in APAC. And finally, we were able to re-measure our U.S. deferred tax assets and increase them by CHF 87 million.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the group net profit progression quarter-on-quarter. The improvement in the bottom line result was just short of CHF 1 billion, but the top line improvement was nearer to 3 billion. This was offset by an increase in personnel expense of 1.2 billion and a net increase in tax expense of almost 1.1 billion, given that we took a significant tax credit in Q4 after we re-measured our deferred tax assets at year-end.</p>
          <p>There was relatively little allocation of profit to minorities in Q1. The vast majority of our minorities are represented by the holders of our hybrid tier 1 capital. Net profit is attributed to minorities when events occur that trigger mandatory payments of dividends on our trust preferred securities. We expect dividend payments in an amount of up to CHF 300 million to be triggered in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>On this slide, we've sought to analyze the drivers of the revenue improvement in the first quarter by business division. The top graphic is a straight comparison with Q4's numbers. You'll see that the main driver of the 48% increase in revenues is the improvement in fixed income. The bottom chart shows the same analysis, but this time against the average quarterly performance for 2009 and the turnaround in FICC is again the principle driver, this time with a 59% improvement.</p>
          <p>Total operating expenses grew by 20% quarter-on-quarter, to CHF 6.2 billion. This chart shows Q1 versus the average of the quarters in 2009. The principal component of the increase in expenses was the accrual we made for variable compensation, which includes amortization of the deferred compensation we awarded to staff for 2009 and earlier years.</p>
          <p>Our underlying expenses, excluding bonuses but including grid based compensation for financial advisors in the USA, remained below our target run rate for 2010 of CHF 5 billion per quarter. While on the subject of expenses, I should mention that we expect that the second quarter's result will be impacted by the bank payroll tax introduced in the UK's Finance Act 2010, which was enacted in April.</p>
          <p>We have a preliminary approximation of the cost of the levy, which is CHF 300 million, though this amount is subject to further detailed assessment. The levy will be charged as a personnel expense and will mainly impact the Investment Bank.</p>
          <p>Headcount fell by 940 in the quarter overall. Starting from this quarter, all head count in the shared services and control functions of corporate center, together with their related cost base, is allocated to the business divisions.</p>
          <p>The chart on the left-hand side shows the head count development, including the effect of an additional allocation of around 1,250 corporate center staff to the respective divisions. On the right, we show the underlying change in each division.</p>
          <p>Now we've made a number of changes to our financial disclosures this quarter. These are aimed at providing you with a more comprehensive understanding of the component drivers of our reported revenues.</p>
          <p>We provide you once again with the full P&amp;L for the Wealth Management business, separate from the Retail and Corporate Banking business, whilst we retain the revenue split between Swiss and non-Swiss clients of Wealth Management.</p>
          <p>I will also show you a new cut of the overall divisions' revenues, supplementary to the recurring versus non-recurring split we continue to provide in the quarterly pack. In Global Asset Management, we've replaced the wholesale versus intermediary &#x2013; sorry, wholesale intermediary versus institutional split, with income and selected value divers shown by business line. This better reflects the way that John Fraser and his team manage the division.</p>
          <p>We also show, separately, new additional information on the Fund Services businesses that sit within that division. Finally, in the Investment Bank, we've provided a much more detailed breakdown of the revenues generated by our sales and trading operations, setting a new standard of disclosure.</p>
          <p>So, turning to Wealth Management in Swiss Bank. Here is the new cut of revenues generated by the overall division in the first quarter and by quarter over the past two years.</p>
          <p>As I just mentioned, we've retained the old disclosure of recurring versus non-recurring income. But I thought this view would be helpful in explaining some of the drivers of the overall revenues of the division.</p>
          <p>So starting with the blue bars, you can see what effect the flattening of the yield curve has had over the past couple of years. In particular, declining returns on the reinvestment of our deposits have been a major driver of the overall decline in net interest income.</p>
          <p>Revenues in Q1 were down almost CHF 200 million on the corresponding period last year, almost entirely because of this effect. The gold bars by and large measure the portfolio management fees we charge clients on the balance of their invested assets.</p>
          <p>These fees are predominantly driven by the volume of invested assets, as can be seen by the effect on these revenues of the steep fall in the markets in the second half of 2008 and early 2009. This is an area of management focus that I will touch on in a bit more detail soon.</p>
          <p>The green bars give an indication of client activity levels from the brokerage fees we charge on non-discretionary accounts and trading revenues we make by crossing bid offer spreads. Here, we saw early signs of a pick-up in revenues.</p>
          <p>You'll note that credit loss expense has not been a major feature in our experience of the crisis. Retail and Corporate saw a steady improvement in performance quarter-on-quarter with an increase in revenues and a significant reduction in G&amp;A expenses. The cost income ratio was held at around 52.5%.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management reported a 6% improvement in revenues in the first quarter on higher gross margins. Non-recurring revenues were particularly strong, impacted by a lower valuation adjustment on our property fund. Expenses increased 7%, but this largely reflected a more normalized level of accruals for variable compensation.</p>
          <p>Cost cutting measures taken last year, continue to have a positive impact on non-personnel expenses. As with all other divisions, disclosed expenses are impacted by the incremental allocation of costs from corporate center. If we had applied this allocation in 2009, Q4's operating expenses would have been 32 million higher and the pre-tax profit correspondingly lower.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the gross margins across Wealth Management for Q1 and each quarter for the past two years. In the quarterly report, we also show the margins for Swiss and International clients separately. At our Investor Day in November last year, we set out some of the measures we intended to take to grow our gross margin back to over 100 basis points. Key amongst these, were the four measures shown on the slide and I can report that we already see some signs of these actions having an effect on our results.</p>
          <p>We've seen an increase in the penetration of discretionary Wealth Management mandates on the back of the reconfigured product suite. Better and more proactive engagement with clients and increased client confidence have boosted activity levels. We've seen a pick-up in Lombard lending balances in the past two quarters. And finally, we've shown greater discipline in pricing and have re-priced selected services, especially in offshore markets.</p>
          <p>Overall, these measures have underpinned a pleasing improvement in the annualized return on invested assets to 93 basis points, although 2 of the 5 basis points of improvement in the quarter related to non-recurring income.</p>
          <p>The first quarter saw some improvement in net new money flows but they were still negative. The overall division recorded net outflows of CHF 8.2 billion with 8.0 billion in Wealth Management.</p>
          <p>We continue to see net inflows in Asia Pacific. And this quarter saw some of the important European markets turn net positive. We saw net inflows from the ultra and high net worth client base.</p>
          <p>We're tackling the drivers of outflows and inflows. With outflows, consumption levels are still running at relatively high rates, especially in certain markets. Client advisor attrition is clearly a continuing factor for us. And in Q1, we saw increasing price competition.</p>
          <p>We're determined to focus on attracting profitable new money and to shun opportunities to buy market share on unattractive terms. In the first quarter, we saw continued attrition in client advisor numbers, with a net reduction of 148 or 3%. This partly reflected the late stages of the adjustments we made in 2009 to client-facing staff numbers to right size the business.</p>
          <p>We're now actively seeking to hire advisors on a selective basis but we do still expect net client-facing staff numbers to continue to decline slightly in the second quarter. Thereafter, we would expect to grow the number gradually towards our medium-term target of around 4,700.</p>
          <p>Invested asset balances at the end of March stood at 827 billion, up marginally in the quarter, as strong investment performance outweighed negative net new money. The average volume of invested assets per client advisor reached 200 million, marginally short of our effective medium-term productivity target.</p>
          <p>At Wealth Management Americas, Bob McCann and his new team are making discernible progress, although the first quarter pre-tax results slipped to 15 million from 178 million in Q4.</p>
          <p>The result was impacted by an increase in deferred compensation awards to financial advisors and by the introduction of Growth Plus, a new FA loyalty program. We also took restructuring charges of around CHF 20 million as we continued to right size the division's infrastructure and staff complement. The division's results were also impacted by the allocation of around 25 million of additional charges from corporate center.</p>
          <p>The number of financial advisors fell by 3% or so to just under 6,900. The business had been configured figure to support 10,000 advisors. So, we still have some way to go to achieve the right level of our operational gearing.</p>
          <p>I expect to have to take additional restructuring provisions, primarily in relation to real estate rationalization of potentially up to CHF 150 million. And this is likely to be charged against the division's results for the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Net new money outflows in the quarter was CHF 7.2 billion, down from 12 billion in the fourth quarter, in line with the slow rate of financial advisor departures. We're now back in the market, hiring financial advisors on a selective basis.</p>
          <p>We're pleased to report that we had positive same stores sales, i.e. positive net new money from financial advisors, who've been with us for more than 12 months. This is the first time this has been the case since 2007.</p>
          <p>We're holding our annual Financial Institutions Investor Conference in New York City next week. Bob McCann will be presenting on behalf of UBS and he will unveil in some detail his strategy and plans for the division.</p>
          <p>Global Asset Management's revenues fell slightly quarter-on-quarter, mainly due to lower transaction fees in global real estate. Other management and performance fees were largely unchanged. Personnel expenses doubled from their unusually low level in Q4 to 279 million, as we increased variable compensation accruals and the division was impacted by additional costs allocated from corporate center.</p>
          <p>We extended our run of strong investment performance. We saw net new money inflows from third parties of 2.1 billion. These were however, offset by net outflows of 4.7 billion through our Wealth Management channels.</p>
          <p>In traditional investment, net new money was flat for the quarter, excluding money market flows. Fixed income saw strong net inflows of 4.4 billion, mainly into Swiss Passive bonds and emerging markets debt. The overall picture on net new money showed a significant improvement over the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>The Investment Bank reported a profit for the first quarter of CHF 1.2 billion compared with just under 0.3 billion in the prior quarter. The biggest factor driving the increase was the huge improvement in fixed income, which more than quadrupled its revenues to almost CHF 2.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Revenues for the division as a whole were almost double those at Q4, reaching CHF 3.9 billion after credit write backs of over 100 million and an own credit charge of almost 250 million.</p>
          <p>Expenses for the quarter were CHF 2.7 billion, compared with an average quarterly run rate in 2009 of 2.3 billion. The increase was again mainly attributable to higher variable compensation accruals. The cost income ratio improved to 71.5%, close to our medium-term target of 70%. The improvement in performance was achieved with no significant increase in risk utilization. Risk-weighted assets increased only marginally, and average 1-day VaR was flat quarter-on-quarter. As a consequence, the annualized return on risk-weighted assets improved significantly to over 12%.</p>
          <p>Revenues and equities increased by 32% to CHF 1.3 billion. Cash revenues benefited from higher commission income and better trading income. In derivatives, we saw a good recovery to almost CHF 0.5 billion, with stronger performances in structured product issuance and in equity linked trading.</p>
          <p>Prime services was flat on the fourth quarter, notwithstanding the higher ETD revenues. PB revenues saw some decline as continued spread compression offset higher client balances. In comparing our results from equities with those of our principle competitors, you might bear in mind that unlike U.S. GAAP preparers, we show rate recessions and the like as contra revenues and not as business expenses. On a comparable basis, our revenues would have been approximately CHF 0.25 billion higher.</p>
          <p>FICC had its best quarter since early 2007. All of the segments improved after a lackluster fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Revenues were well diversified. The Credit business performed well. It recorded over 750 million of revenues. Client flows was strong in Europe. In the U.S. we traded well in investment grade and distressed asset classes. Structured credit also contributed strongly, partly driven by a number of restructuring trades.</p>
          <p>Macro performed well despite difficult market conditions. We built volumes in FX and money markets and the benefit was &#x2013; but the benefits was largely masked by continued spread compression in the short-term highly liquid markets.</p>
          <p>Rates saw improved client flows, though its performance overall was dampened by slow markets. Emerging markets revenues recovered to just under a quarter of a billion with good performances in Latin America and in Emerging Europe.</p>
          <p>We continued to work on our residual risk positions in the quarter. We sold or redeemed student loan auction rate certificates for proceeds of over 2.3 billion, and a net gain of over 100 million.</p>
          <p>The return of some liquidity to the structured credit markets helped to raise the prices of many CLOs and CDOs. This positively impacted our legacy negative basis trades, where we were able to release around CHF 300 million of CVA held against the monoline insurers, as replacement values fell and the insurers' credit spreads generally tightened.</p>
          <p>Investment Banking revenues fell 19% on a seasonally strong quarter. Sorry, on a seasonally strong fourth quarter. Advisory revenues were down 11% in a quiet period for M&amp;A activity. Capital markets revenues fell 19%, but  DCM was up 15%, ECM fell by 35% in very quiet markets, enough for a strong fourth quarter. Risk management charges on our franchise lending book remained stable. Overall, we improved our market share in M&amp;A and DCM although on very low volumes, we did slip a little in equity capital markets.</p>
          <p>Turning finally to the group's overall capital position. Our core tier 1 capital ratio improved by 60 basis points, 12.5%, as did our overall BIS tier 1 ratio to 16%. On the FINMA's calculation basis, our leverage ratio is now over 4%.</p>
          <p>From the 30th of June 2010, we come under a new set of liquidity regulations imposed by the FINMA and the Swiss National Bank. These will require us to maintain excess liquidity, to cope with a model set of prescribed 7-day and 30-day severe stress scenarios akin to the liquidity coverage ratio proposed by the Basel committee on banking supervision. We've met this test at the end of March and would expect to do so at the end of June and into future periods.</p>
          <p>With that, Caroline and I would be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question from Mr. Kian Abouhossein, J.P. Morgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. The first question is relating to compensation ratio. I mean, you have a target medium-term over a cost income of 70% for the Investment Bank. And I just wanted to see how we should think with the current revenue environment about the cost income ratio for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, at the moment our cost income ratio on a reported basis is running at around 53%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. But when I strip out all the one-off items, I get a cost income ratio which is significantly higher and then clearly I make some adjustment for seasonality of the revenues, especially in fixed income which I assume will come through the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I mean, you're free &#x2013; you're obviously free to strip out whatever one-off costs you think. The one point I would make on compensation, if you're comparing us with some of our U.S. competitors, is that they obviously show their revenues and expenses in a different split. So, I would encourage you to add back the contra revenues. I think on that basis we come down to a level that's comparable with the U.S. investment banks, around the mid-40s or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I ask the question differently, because I get to 73 for the IB clean, but if I ask the question differently. If I take the 20 billion that you're indicating in terms of cost run rate, if I clearly annualize it now, I get to about 25. How should I think about the compensation impact or the bonus impact basically, which is not including the 20?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well the 20 billion includes personnel expense. It includes the fixed element plus the broker company in the U.S. So the difference between your 20 and your 25 would be the bonus we've brought for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The second question is related to your pick-up value and the equity value of the SMB fund value. I mean, the value of the fund is going up which you record but how should I think about that in terms of realization? I mean your value is continuously going up, but in realization terms, is that realistic to &#x2013; because I'm bit questioning the value that is created on paper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the way we calculate the value of the option is to use cash flows that we' receive from the staff fund. It's not based on market values of the underlying assets nor is it based on the carrying value in the SMB's books. So it's a separate exercise that we perform and it takes into account the cost of the option, the strike price of the option and the present value of the cash flows that we model that we receive from the fund's administrators.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you're expecting ongoing increases in default or you take current default levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we model it on a whole range of scenarios. We model it in a fashion that's somewhat akin to the way that we calculate the value of the BlackRock loan we have. So we build in a whole range of factors. It's a complex model and we come up with a range of outcomes and then select a value on the basis of that. But it's predicated obviously on exercising the option at some stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And last question on regulation, and especially the Dot Lincoln reform bill. How do you see that impacting your investment banking business and your medium-term targets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, at the moment what we set out on the Investor Day was predicated on the set of regulations that was enforced at that date. There could clearly be a whole range of changes in regulation and it's difficult to speculate on which direction they may move in and what impact it would have on our business. So at the moment we're almost in a holding pattern, waiting to see what regulations are actually introduced and then it's easy for us then to comment on actual rather than mooted changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks and thanks for the IB split.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Huw van Steenis, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I was just following-up on Kian's question on the SMB vehicle. Is there any update on when you would like to buy back in and what the financial consequences would be if you did it this year versus next year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Well, it is something obviously we have to look at from time-to-time. The option has value and as it has value, there is no point in exercising it right now. At the moment, we look at the fund in a number of ways. It would clearly add a number of risk-weighted assets. It would increase our stress loss and it would be a drain on some of our cash capital because there is a lot of the content of the fund is obviously highly illiquid. So I think at the moment, we are waiting to see, we are in no rush to exercise the option.</p>
          <p>The markets underpinning the assets in the fund seem to be improving. They seem to be continuing to improve. The SMB I think, is reporting on the staff fund in a couple of weeks time, so you'll see the March numbers there. And they underpin the increase in the value of the option that we took in the quarter. But it is something we monitor but we're in no rush to do it and at the moment, I think we've taken the view that it's still larger than we want to take on as a form of risk concentration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And it doesn't have any impact net operationally on your ability to compensate people appropriately this year, though?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't at all, no, it's a clean sell to the SMB. It's an option that we have to acquire the fund at some stage. We don't have to exercise the option, obviously. We'd have to write-off the carrying value of the option in our accounts if we didn't. But for that reason, I do think at some stage we will exercise the option. We intend, wherever possible, to repay the loan in its entirety to The National Bank. We don't want to leave risk with The National Bank if we can possibly avoid it. But the timing of the exercising the option, I think, we'd probably leave for some time now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Jon Peace, Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Good morning, John. Two questions, please. The first is on your fixed trading revenues, obviously ahead of the 2 billion medium-term target. Now, I know seasonality obviously helps at the start of the year, but I wondered to what extent have you been able to generate some kind of prop revenues? And if you could give us any idea of kind of what you think a sustainable run rate might be for 2010. Do we think by the end of this year we could still be ahead of your 2 billion target, or do we still need some more quarters of investment to get up to that goal on a sustainable client basis?</p>
          <p>The second question is just on you outlook statement about net new money outflows expected to be at relatively moderate levels in the near term. But the steps you've taken should be effective. What's your current thinking in terms of when we might see those outflows turn positive? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well on the FICC trading revenues, the reason we feel more confident that the 2 billion or so is a reasonable run rate &#x2013; obviously, the larger trading revenues, so you can never predict them with any great certainty. But the revenues in the first quarter were really very diversified across the different units within fixed income. And the boss has the view that 2 billion is now not really ambitious. So we're under a lot of pressure from him to increase the amount.</p>
          <p>But I think 2 billion, to be realistic, is in the context of where the business sits at the moment is, is an okay run rate. It will move around because it's predicated largely on trading revenues so far. We are still building out the business. We're still building out the sales and distribution element of fixed income in particular and we are also bringing fixed income closer together with some of the better practices that we've had in equities. You may have read that we've essentially brought together our research functions, for example, between the two elements of the securities and trading operations.</p>
          <p> So I thought 2 billion is a reasonable base from now on. It's not a short-term profit earning, but we feel fairly comfortable, given the diversity of the sources of revenues, that on average over the next few quarters, that that should be where we're coming out. There'll be some pluses and minuses, but that's a reasonable medium.</p>
          <p>On net new money, a lot of effort, a lot of management effort is going into addressing this. As I said, we're looking at the gross outflows and the gross inflows and trying to tackle both because they're separate drivers. There is also, I think, a bit of a sea change in the perception of UBS. Now that we're back reporting some profits, I think clients can have more confidence in us and there are definite signs of that being the case. That has the positive effect of boosting the morale of the client advisors, because their lot just becomes all the more easy. And therefore, I think there is just more impetus behind that business.</p>
          <p>A number of the external factors that were impacting us, the obvious one is the Italian tax amnesty, have now essentially run their course for us and so they're not weighing on us to the extent they were in the fourth quarter, in particular. So we're in a better place. We still are not satisfied, we still have net outflows.</p>
          <p>We are seeing gradually, market-by-market, some improvement. It's not that solid yet clearly and there's still a lot of work to be done. On the timing of when the inflection point comes and we become beneficiaries of net inflows, is very, very difficult to say because it's driven by factors that are somewhat outside of our control. But we'd like to think it was sometime by the end of the year. We hold that we would like to see the inflection point still this, sometime this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Derek De Vries, Bank of America. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, a few questions, if I may. I'd like to return to Kian's question on OTC derivatives. And I understand your unwillingness to kind of quantify the number, but maybe to help us make some stabs at it, could you just give us a sense of what percent of your sales and trading revenues in the normalized world, or in your targeted world or whatever you want, would come from OTC derivatives? So just ballpark, what percent of your sales and trading revenues come from OTC derivatives, would be very helpful for us as we try to understand the impact.</p>
          <p>And then switching over to the Wealth Management business. You gave some pretty clear guidance in terms of the head count of the international client advisors and you said it will be down again in Q2 and then you hope Q3 will show an increase in client advisors. And I was wondering if you'd give a little more color. What's the delta there? Is it suddenly more hiring, or is it a less departure? Is this going to drive that delta Q3 on Q2?</p>
          <p>And then in terms of the people you are hiring, maybe you can give some color either by geography or, perhaps more interestingly, where these people are coming from institution-wise; maybe not specific institutions, but just what type. Are these ex-UBS people that are coming back? Are these people coming from the sort of global competitors you have, or are they coming from smaller shops, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, on derivatives, I think we have to go almost business-by-business. In equities, we've essentially shown you the revenues that were attributable to the derivatives business, 0.5 billion, and a proportion of those would be OTC. Difficult to gauge how much. In equities, we don't write as big a proportion as OTC. The big area of OTC derivatives is in rates, where the swap options business is essentially an OTC business.</p>
          <p>In credit, as you will see from our disclosures, you know we are not a huge credit derivative writer. We do have notionals of over a trillion, but we are not anywhere near the top ranks of the market, but we do write credit default swaps as we buy them and we trade them actively. But the big pool of OTC derivatives is clearly in rates, where we write a very large volume of interest rate swaps. So, amounts for roughly half of our replacement values on both sides of the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'd been able to work that much out myself, I was hoping maybe you could kind of say 40%, 50%, 30%, something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in rates it's -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The vast majority.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vast majority, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but in terms of equity derivatives <mark type="inaudible" /> don't really have a clue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In equities, well a big source of equity derivative issuance would be derivatives embedded in our structured products business. And that's a sizable business. You can see the MTN balances on the balance sheet. There the ones held &#x2013; fair value, liabilities in the balance sheet. So, that's a sizable business and we would, that's a core business for us. And it's a business which deals with two of our core client bases, the hedge fund clients and the high net worth individuals, so that would very much be an area of growth for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the Wealth Management side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Wealth Management side, I think you mentioned international Wealth Management client advisors, and I am not sure that we'd necessarily be growing those, particularly. I think our focus has as much been in onshore markets. In Asia for example, there is very little scope for us to hire senior client advisors. We already employ quite a significant proportion of the whole population of client advisors in APAC. Our next competitor has a fraction of the number that we have and so the opportunities there for hiring are relatively low.</p>
          <p>In Asia, we coped with that by establishing a University where we train, and essentially create our own advisors. I think generally speaking, the delta in the number of client advisors would be some hiring in the European markets. There would be a point &#x2013; creating new ones essentially through our universities and through our training programs, and a reduction in departures. And we are expecting a significant fall-off in the number of departures that were non-voluntary, because the measures we took in 2009 have pretty much now expired. There will be some residual effect in Q2, as I mentioned, but then after that we would be &#x2013; we'd be flat on redundancies. Caroline, you don't think there's anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I just wanted to point back to the information that we provided to you on Investor Day. It's slide 21 on the Wealth Management presentation, it gives you the breakdown of how we expect the client advisor numbers across Wealth Management to increase over the next couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question from Mr. Jernej Omahen, Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, there. It's Jernej here from Goldman. Just a few very brief questions. The first question is on the net new money into your Wealth Management businesses. You're mentioning Lombard loans for the first time in a long time. And I was just wondering if you can update us as to what the contribution to net new money was in Q1 '10 from these Lombard loans and maybe also remind us what the total outstanding is currently.</p>
          <p>The second question again, just a numbers question. The CVA release was 300 million, so &#x2013; on the monoline, so I think there's 2.5 billion left. As things stand now, I guess, would you be willing to &#x2013; I guess give us a forecast of how much of that you think is realistic to be released into the P&amp;L over the course of this year? And finally, just on FICC revenues, again a huge number. And I was just wondering if you can maybe just shed some light on how much of the improvement in FICC &#x2013; and I believe that the previous commentary was that the run rates in 2009, the underlying run rates, were around 1 billion a quarter or so. We are now at above 2, or just below 2 if we strip out the monolines. And I was wondering, how much of that result or improvement do you actually think is down to operating actions taken by the UBS management and how much of it is down to the better operating environment? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first one on Lombard loans. The balance we disclosed is 40.6 billion and the net new money contribution from Lombard loans in the first quarter would have been about 1 to 1.5 billion or so. That's the volume &#x2013; the net volume increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the monolines, there are two stories on the monolines, just to remind you. The monoline exposures are largely in relation to these negative basis trades, where the long end of the trade is generally a series now of CLOs. The CDOs have, as you can see from our disclosures, have by and large been either written off or restructured. Those long assets are, by and large, held in our books as loans and receivables. And so when the market value of those increases, which is what's happened over the past few quarters, we have not been able to take a write-up in our trading account, because they're not held in the trading account. There is over time an improvement in the effective interest rate attaching to those positions. But there's no immediate write-up.</p>
          <p>However, from the perspective of the CDS, from the monoline, that's a derivative and we have to mark that to market. And that takes into account the market value of the long limb of the negative basis trade. And so the replacement values have been shrinking. And as the replacement value shrinks, that's a mark-to-market hit to our P&amp;L. Now against that, we had credit valuation adjustments. And as the CDS loses its replacement value &#x2013; so our receivable, the PRV reduces, we can reduce the credit valuation adjustment, all other things being equal. So there's a bigger hit because there are &#x2013; the credit valuation adjustment's not 100% of the receivable. So there's actually a net hit to our P&amp;L from an improvement in the underlyings.</p>
          <p>Now in addition to that, there's been a market perception of an improvement in the financial health of the monolines. So the spreads on monolines have come in, and they are the principle driver of the credit valuation adjustment. So we've reduced the credit valuation adjustment by more than the proportion by which the CDS value has come in, because the monolines are healthier.</p>
          <p>So there has been a release of CVA to the P&amp;L for that reason too. But the big change is the change in the value of the underlyings. And that doesn't come through as an increase in the carrying value of the CLO, because they're held in loans and receivables. So you have this slightly asymmetric and ironic accounting impact that, as the value of those things that we hold as assets go up, we actually have a hit to our P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>Now whether that comes through in time would depend on your view of the long-term value of the CLOs. My view would be more positive than the carrying values. I think they will accrete back towards par. The CDOs we hold, which are relatively small, I'd be much less confident about. And we haven't had great experience with those.</p>
          <p>We are still proactively looking to work out those positions and we are looking, where we can, to restructure those trades and then sell the contents of the CDOs once they go into default. So I think the answer, it's a long answer, but it's some of the amount will come back into the P&amp;L, but I wouldn't be confident that absolutely all of it did, but some will.</p>
          <p>On the FICC revenues, I think the &#x2013; your question was whether they had essentially improved because the market had improved, or whether they had improved because of actions we'd taken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I fairly strongly feel it's the latter, because I do feel actually that first quarter last year, for example, was stronger than the first quarter this year. And we were on the sidelines and we missed four relatively strong quarters, or three quarters &#x2013; the first three quarters of last year, which were strong generally in the fixed income markets. And we essentially just watched them happen from the sidelines.</p>
          <p>And it wasn't until third and fourth quarter when we'd installed new trading capabilities, new people and started to build out our sales and distribution capability, that we became participants in those markets. So we're very much a late re-entrant, in the credit markets essentially an entrant. We weren't really there before. And I think therefore it's more the fact that we have a presence than &#x2013; versus not having had one before than the fact that the markets were strong.</p>
          <p>Having said that, January was particularly strong and was in my view almost as strong as two other months. And so there's a degree to which potentially we had four months worth of revenues and three of expenses in the first quarter. But as I said to Huw or Jon or whoever it was earlier, I do think that there will be some stability in the FICC trading revenues. It will be &#x2013; it will continue to be trading and therefore it will move up and down. But I think the 2 billion mark as we said at the Investor Day, is where we feel fairly confident we can generate revenues. And it's not particularly market leading in any way. A lot of our competitors are doing twice that much, so not entirely ambitious as our boss keeps reminding us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, can I just ask a follow-on? Yeah -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just very quickly, I mean you'll understand why this is just somewhat confusing for, I guess the followers of UBS stock. And if we just go back to your medium term target and the Investor Day in November of last year. I think you laid out very clearly, here's the operational plan. And I think the time spans given were anywhere from 12 months up to 24 months and more. So when your explanation is, this is due to essentially management decision or successful management implementation, that's fine. But then is the answer also, we have by far exceeded the implementation of the program we've presented to you just four months ago? Or is the answer something else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think the answer's something else. I think I was &#x2013; I've been relatively clear that in fixed income in particular, where you have a trading operation, once the traders are installed and they're at their desk and they have their risk limits and their funding, then they're up and running. And you either- it's almost binary. You're either in business or you're not business. So I think we said in relation to the trading areas, we would expect to see, pretty pronto, some serious improvement which so far we've seen. In some areas, for example in Wealth Management in the turnaround in the net asset position, the net new money position, we said that that was a much more intractable problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's more difficult problem for us. It goes to some extent to the reputation of the bank and it would inevitably take much, much longer to achieve. And so you're right. Our medium-term was never a particular specified period. But there were always going to be some of our businesses that would immediately come on-stream because if you have a trading operation, it works or it doesn't work. And in our case, it appears now to work. But with Wealth Management, it will take much longer and it may take &#x2013; to get it back to where we wanted to get, it may take a number of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Matthew Clark, KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, two questions, please. Firstly, on slide 17, I'm just wondering if you could maybe talk us through how you see the delta between the first quarter 2010 equities trading revenues and the target level. What's going to drive that improvement? And is this management levers or is it just the broader market?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, thanks for the same store chart for the Wealth Management U.S. I was wondering if you could give us some guidance on what same store would look like for the traditional Wealth Management division? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On equities, I think in terms of cash, there's a little bit of room for improvement. I think we've essentially regained the market share we had pre-crisis. There may be a percentage point or so to go, but in terms of cash revenues, I think we are somewhat beholden to the market. We saw slightly stronger trading revenues in the first quarter than we'd seen in the fourth and we saw higher commission incomes. But in cash, I don't think there's much room for us of doubling, I think that's a gradual improvement, but not much else.</p>
          <p>In derivatives, is where I would expect to see quite a lot of improvement. As you may know, we -our derivatives business pre-crisis was very heavily focused on our Wealth Management client base. And though it's a bit rude to say that it was mono-client, it was really skewed towards servicing the high net worth individuals in our Wealth Management business.</p>
          <p>I think in derivatives, we will continue to build out our sales and distribution capability including in equities. And there will be a lot scope for us to work between equities and the fixed income businesses to build out derivatives capabilities. Our structured products business has room &#x2013; plenty of room to grow. And then in prime services, I think there is room to grow there. Client balances have continued to increase, but we are seeing a lot of price competition and a bit of spread compression, but generally speaking I think the outlook is okay for equities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On same store sales, I'm not sure that concept works necessarily in our core Wealth Management business, particularly the Swiss business. The difference being that in the U.S., the financial advisor is to some extent also a client of ours, and he in turn would have his client base. And so essentially there, we're looking at branches and/or client advisory operations &#x2013; the financial advisor network and looking at their performance period on period.</p>
          <p>In the Wealth Management business elsewhere, in Asia and in Europe, our clients as much bank with UBS as they do with an individual advisor. And so the concept of tracking advisors' performance in terms of net new money is not as straightforward. And so, I think it's less meaningful which is why we tend to look at in U.S. but not anywhere else. So it's actually not a number we particularly track internally as management team. If it were, we'd be more inclined to show it, but I don't think it has the meaning that it has in U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Kinner Lakhani, Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good morning. Yeah, I've got three questions actually. Firstly, on the Wealth Management revenue margin, if we strip out the 2 basis points of one-offs, the kind of remaining 3 basis points improvement that you're saying &#x2013; you're seeing, I just wanted to understand, what part of that is kind of UBS assets? And what part of that is clients actually regaining confidence to do business?</p>
          <p>Second question on capital. I've notice there is a 60 basis points hit from, what I believe is securitization. Just wanted to get some more flavor on that, you know and whether this could continue going forward? Also, if you could add a quick word on dividend policy in the context of the 60 basis points improvement that you've seen in your core tier 1 ratio in this latest quarter. And finally, on kind of the usual kind of litigation issues, post Goldman Sachs actually, on the structured credit side, what your sense is as to how UBS is positioned there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Wealth margin, the two basis points I described as non-recurring. So I wouldn't dismissed them entirely as one-offs, although the fact that they were non-recurring suggests that they may be less dependable than the three which come from the portfolio management fees.</p>
          <p>I would &#x2013; you may say I'd like to do is, but I would like to suggest that the improvement does come from UBS's efforts. There has been something of an uptick in the amount of brokerage commission as you saw, which is reflective of an increased confidence in clients in attacking the markets. But I think the portfolio management fee improvement really was driven by the three, or four factors that we identified. In particular, the increased mandate penetration because the margins on mandates are higher than the combined margin from an advisory and brokerage type arrangement. The lending does help and that's double leverage generally and then improved pricing. And I think it's the pricing discipline that was at the heart of the improvement. And clearly there that is within our control to a large degree. And we have re-priced, as I said, in selected markets and I imagine you can guess which markets are the selected markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I mean, could you just elaborate on the two basis points, if it's not completely one-off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The two basis points is a whole mish-mash of tiny things. None of them is particularly noteworthy, otherwise we'd have mentioned them. But it's sort of in &#x2013; it's mixed in the overall trading account, this property fund we've been taking provisions on now for 4 or 5 quarters. There was a big improvement there, a 60 million quarter-on-quarter improvement. We took a 88 million charge in Q4 and it's down to 28 in Q1. But it's not &#x2013; there's nothing other than just a whole array of small things that are going to the mix in the revenue line.</p>
          <p>On your securitization point, you're right. This was a range of assets we held in the securitization framework for regulatory capital purposes. And the rule is that if the credit rating assigned by internationally renowned credit rating agencies falls below BB level. Then they're no longer a net &#x2013; allowed to be held as risk assets in that framework. And instead, they become deductions from total capital. And the way that it works is that half of the deduction comes from tier 1 and the other half essentially from tier 2. And in the quarter that amounts to 1.2 billion, which fell &#x2013; where the credit rating migration was so negative as to take them below that BB level. So, 600 came from the tier 1 and then another 600 million from the total capital line from tier 2. And it can continue to happen unfortunately. It's driven unfortunately, by rating agencies. And therefore, it's outside of our control. It can happen and it's a phenomenon across the industry. It has actually been happening. It's just more noteworthy in the first quarter than it has been in some of the previous quarters. We, just so you know in managing the investment bank's risk weighted assets, we manage them on an effective risk-weighted asset number, which grosses up that deduction for capital on the notional tier 1 ratio. So that we do take it into account when we're managing the business. That deduction from capital we add back is an effective risk asset.</p>
          <p>Dividend policy, there is not much to say, I'm afraid. Given where regulation &#x2013; capital regulation is moving and where the FINMA in particular, which has already issued its capital decree to us, is we are going to have to retain earnings as I said at the Investor Day for quite some time to come.</p>
          <p>And although 16% tier 1 ratio gives us a very strong capital ratio compared with some of our competitors, there's still quite some way to go before we meet the medium-term capital requirements. So, it's unlikely that we will be declaring a dividend in relation to this year's profits and if we do, it would be extremely modest. I think I used the world symbolic back on the Investor Day.</p>
          <p>And then on the litigation issues in relation to structured credit, I think there &#x2013; all I can say there is I obviously can't comment on the Goldman Sachs issue because we're not a party to it. We were in that business. We're not particularly in that business anymore. And we were included in what I think is being called the street sweep by the SEC when they contacted most of the major investment banks, whenever it was 18, 20 months or so ago. And we would obviously be cooperating there with any enquiries they make, but so far we've no further information we can give you on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mrs. Fiona Swaffield, Execution. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good Morning. Just two things. Firstly, on the personnel expenses. Obviously at the end of the year you talked a lot about deferred compensation costs coming in more in 2010. I just wondered, how much coming in Q1 and whether we should see a ramp-up in Q2 as well? I think there was something like 1.5 billion delta.</p>
          <p>And then the second area is on the outflows, the 1.8 billion, so slide 12.And I was surprised that number is a little bit higher than &#x2013; I wondered if you talk a bit more about that? But also about Germany and whether there were net outflows in Germany? And what's happening there in terms of clients presenting themselves. So I think that was something you were relatively concerned about. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On personnel expenses, we did change the structure of the compensation plans in Q4 and as a consequence you're right, we deferred 1.5 billion into future periods. And I think I said at the time, the majority of that hits the 2010 accounts. And we would sort of accrue that relatively even across the quarters.</p>
          <p>On the &#x2013; on Germany, I don't think we say anything specifically about individual countries, but Germany is one of those contiguous countries we highlighted at the Investor Day. It's the one that has the biggest volume of cross border business for us and so it is a market that we have special focus on and it's obviously an element of our outflows. I don't what proportion it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's not in the 1.8 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not. No, It's not. It's not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question for today is from Mr. Georg Kanders, WestLB. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, I have a question on the corporate center on this &#x2013; my revenues. One is this &#x2013; the subfund option but I wonder what &#x2013; there was also this gain from the property stake in New York. And what are the other elements for the revenues there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well corporate centre has, within it, the treasury operations. So the treasury profits that we make, which are profits on an accruals basis are credited to corporate centre still. The core book in the Wealth Managed &#x2013; in the Swiss Bank in Wealth Management stays there and the investment bank has its own secured funding operations and obviously its own treasury operations, but the group treasury operations remain in corporate centre. Now, I don't think there are any other items of particular note in corporate center. It was particular &#x2013; the two big items were the subfund option, and then the sale of our stake in the company that had an interest in 299 Park. This corporate center will continue to take for example, foreign currency translation, account wash charges or credits from time to time but there's nothing in particular &#x2013; additional, it's material.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But overall in normal times, this would be a negative revenue contribution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it shouldn't be because the expense base is now very, very low. The expense base is now truly corporate center. It's the expense of the external board, the group board, for example, that sort of thing that is not justifiably attributed to the businesses. And there ought to be some revenues on a normal basis from our treasury operations at center. But both numbers should be very, very small and not particularly meaningful in the context of the group and that's the way we've designed it. But that essentially all of cost base of the group is attributed back to the divisions, which generate the revenues to cover those costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that looks as though that's all the questions. So from Caroline and from me here in Zurich, thank you very much for watching.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>