<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1229662" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>631</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Philip Higson, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Cryan, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="4">John Cryan</participant>
      <participant id="5">Matt Spick</participant>
      <participant id="6">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="7">Derek De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="8">Huw van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="9">Philip Higson</participant>
      <participant id="10">Christopher Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="11">Fiona Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="12">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="13">Jernej Omahen</participant>
      <participant id="14">George Kanders</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Starts Abruptly] Good morning and welcome to UBS First Quarter Results Presentation. At today's meeting, we will have one presentation by Group CFO, John Cryan. This will be followed by the usual Q&amp;A session for our telephone audience. Here is an important disclaimer regarding the forward-looking statements. Please take a few moments to read it.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Philip, and good morning to you all. We've made a fair amount of progress already this year in the regeneration of UBS. We've a new Chairman and a new Group CEO at the helm and we've appointed new leadership in the Investment Bank. And we now have a Group COO to drive our strategy built around the integrated bank model.</p>
          <p>At April's AGM, Oswald Gr&#xFC;bel affirmed our strategic direction. We will retain and grow our four principal businesses, the Wealth Management businesses, our domestic bank in Switzerland, our Asset Management operations, and our Investment Bank. Moreover, we will integrate these businesses, centralizing and streamlining where we can to maximize their value. Ulrich K&#xF6;rner, our new COO, has already begun to attack our cost base. All of our divisions are rescaling their operations to match the recessionary environment and already considerable progress has been made. We plan to reduce our annual costs by 3.5 to CHF4 billion by the end next year, compared with 2008.</p>
          <p>Regrettably, we must also shed staff. At the AGM, we announced a reduction in our overall head count by a further 8,500 or so from the 76,000 staff we employed at the end of March. The work we still need to do is likely to require a further provision for restructuring and severance costs in the second quarter. I currently expect that this charge will be approximately CHF650 million.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet remains exposed to some legacy risks. We therefore need to continue to reduce our exposure to these positions. However, we are now committed to the task of rebuilding our trading revenues and have already taken steps to facilitate greater volumes of flow trading. Finally in April, we announced that we'd reached agreement to sell UBS Pactual.</p>
          <p>Our financial performance in Q1 was overall disappointing, but there were a number of bright spots. We made a net attributable loss for the quarter of a little under CHF2 billion. This compares with a restated loss of CHF9.6 billion in the fourth quarter of 2008. The first quarter loss is in line with the amount we forecasted at the time of our AGM. However, the results have since been impacted by two effects. The first relates to the conditional sale of Pactual, which resulted in a goodwill charge of CHF631 million in the first quarter, offset in part &#x2013; offset in part by the release of a related accrual for deferred tax liabilities in an amount of CHF243 million.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we've restated our 2008 accounts to correct for certain accounting errors that were identified in the first quarter. These errors are not material to the annual or quarterly financial statements for 2008. But that correction in the first quarter of 2009, we believe, would have been material to these accounts. The total impact of all restated items on the 2008 results was an increase in the net loss of CHF405 million and reduction in equity of 269 million, and a full description of the restatement is contained in the quarterly report.</p>
          <p>Our Tier 1 capital ratio at the end of March was 10.5%. Pro forma for sale of Pactual, the ratio would have been 11%, in line with the figure at the end of 2008. We saw overall net client money outflows in the quarter. Until mid February, we saw stabilization of flows with net inflows for the Group as a whole. In the second half of the quarter, however, we experienced net outflows. This change coincided with the announcement on the 18th of February that we had entered into a deferred prosecution agreement with the U.S. Department of Justice and a consent order with U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission in relation to the provision of certain cross-border private banking services to U.S. clients. The following day, the Department of Justice filed a civil petition for enforcement of the pending John Doe summons, which seems to have further contributed to some destabilization of our client base. Invested assets, at around CHF2.2 trillion, ended the quarter flat or where they had begun it.</p>
          <p>This slide details the performance of our divisions and highlights some of the significant items that impacted the divisions' results. In our Wealth and Asset Management divisions, revenues were adversely impacted by the fall in the value and the change in the composition of clients' invested assets in the fourth quarter of 2008. In Wealth Management, we experienced further credit loss expense relating to ongoing closeout costs from lombard lending losses incurred in Q4.</p>
          <p>In the Swiss Bank, we began to see an increase in credit loss expense against exposures to small and medium-sized Swiss companies as the Swiss economy slowed down. The Investment Bank suffered from severe losses on its legacy exposures. Losses on its monoline positions alone cost almost CHF2 billion. Its Global Syndicated Finance portfolio including leverage lending also adversely impacted results, generating negative revenues in relation to those positions held in the trading books and credit loss expense for those positions reclassified to loans and receivables, are now considered permanently impaired. The core trading businesses of the IB generally had a good quarter, and made satisfactory contributions, with the exception of credit trading.</p>
          <p>There were a number of significant items that impacted these results. In the quarter, we transferred to the SNB's custodian the remaining positions earmarked for sale in the agreement with the SNB. The total value of assets sold to the SNB Fund was $38.7 billion net of pricing adjustments. These pricing adjustments meant that the overall purchase price for the portfolio was approximately $1 billion lower than the market value we had assigned to those positions at the 30th of September 2008. We recognized the final $300 million of this price adjustment in Q1. This was offset by favorable foreign exchange movements in the values of the non-U.S. dollar denominated assets, so that the net charge for the quarter was CHF232 million.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding the pricing adjustments, continuing pressure on valuations, particularly on those assets exposed to the real estate markets, led to a reduction in the fair value of our option to acquire the StabFund. This generated a mark-to-market loss in the quarter of an additional CHF302 million. The charge in the first quarter arising from our arrangements with the SNB in aggregate was therefore CHF534 million.</p>
          <p>The MCN issued in December to the Swiss Confederation include embedded equity and derivative components. These are bifurcated and the derivative components are all treated as one and accounted for at fair value, where changes over time in the fair value are recognized through the profit and loss account. The fair value of the complex MCN derivative at March 31 was negative CHF513 million, compared with negative CHF1.058 billion at the end of December. After charging interest expense of around 22 million on the MCN, the net amount of 524 million was credited to the profit and loss account in Q1.</p>
          <p>We also marked-to-model at the end of Q1 our valuation of the put option granted to our clients to sell to us their holdings of auction rate securities at par plus accrued interest. This negatively impacted our results in the quarter by CHF306 million. We also impaired 631 million of the total of CHF1.4 billion of goodwill held against UBS Pactual to reflect the agreement we reached in April to sell the business. That charge mainly impacted the IB and Global Asset Management.</p>
          <p>Also in the quarter, we took a charge for a further CHF184 million for closure and severance costs, mainly in the IB. We thought &#x2013; what we sought to do on this slide is to provide you with an assessment of Q1 revenues by business activity. The more stable sources of revenue, fee and commission income, and interest margin totaled some CHF5.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Treasury income, partly resulting from our introduction of a rigorous allocation of the Group's funding costs to the trading desks, was strongly positive. This more than compensated for the continuing negative revenue contribution from our trading operations, where legacy risk positions continued to weigh on the overall performance.</p>
          <p>Reported Group expenses were flat on those for Q4, but this picture is misleading. Adjusting Q4 for three major non-recurring items, the cross-border settlement costs, restructuring charges, and ARS-related charges, produces an adjusted expense base in Q4 of CHF4.4 billion. Adjusting Q1 for the Pactual goodwill impairment charge and severance costs produces an adjusted expense base of CHF5.7 billion. This is 31% higher than in Q4. However, the increase is largely explained by the fact that in Q4, we released over CHF1 billion of bonus accruals whereas in Q1, we have resumed accruals. Otherwise, G&amp;A expenses were lower across all categories quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the impact of our announced cost saving measures on our underlying business expense base, and on head count. By the end of 2010, all other things being equal, we would expect our annualized run rate of costs across the Group to be lower than CHF20 billion, before variable compensation costs. As mentioned earlier, we expect to expense approximately CHF650 million of restructuring charges and severance costs in Q2.</p>
          <p>Following steep falls in market values in Q4, the average invested asset balance was significantly lower in Q1 than it had been in Q4. This is relevant, because this is an approximate driver of recurring fee income going into Q1. The balance of our clients' invested assets was largely flat in the first quarter. Balances did fall as a consequence of market value movements, but this effect was more than offset in all divisions by FX movements, mainly by the appreciation of the dollar against the Swiss franc. The best divisional performance was in Wealth Management Americas, where net inflows of new money contributed to an overall 5% increase in balances.</p>
          <p>As I've already mentioned, until mid-February, we had seen a stabilization of net new money flows with net inflows for the Group as a whole. In the second half of the quarter, however, we experienced net outflows. Net new money outflows in Wealth Management and Swiss Bank in the first quarter amounted to CHF23.4 billion, a huge improvement over Q4, but nevertheless disappointing, especially given that the quarter began well. Of the total net outflows of 23.4 billion, some five billion or so are attributable to client &#x2013; continued client deleveraging, as can be seen by the change in lombard loan balances, and a further two billion relate to the closure of the U.S. cross-border business.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management Americas saw good flows each month and recorded net inflows of over CHF16 billion for the quarter as a whole. Of the 7.7 billion of net outflows in Asset Management, about 90% of the total was related to clients of Wealth Management. The asset mix continued to evolve ,with strong inflows into our money market funds.</p>
          <p>And so turning to the balance sheet, trading assets including cash collateral trading balances ended the quarter at just over CHF600 billion. A significant proportion of this balance was accounted for by our liquidity buffer and our mandatory collateral holdings pledged to central banks and exchanges. The gross replacement value of receivables under derivatives contracts fell by CHF100 billion to 754 billion, largely in FX forwards and options. On a netted basis under Swiss GAAP, PRVs fell by 28 billion to CHF174 billion. We still have some way to go to bring down all of our legacy positions, but over time, this will lead to a reduction in our PRVs and the size of our trading portfolios.</p>
          <p>We estimate that the negative carry associated with our liquidity buffer was an approximate CHF800 million in Q1. Since the end of March, we have reduced the size of the buffer by 20% and intend to bring it down by a similar amount over the next few months. This will manifest itself in a reduction in our cash collateral trading balances.</p>
          <p>We're working on refining our netting and counterparty risk management. Over time, this should lead to a reduction in the positive and the negative replacement values we carry on our balance sheet, and the notional value of our derivatives portfolio. All of these measures taken together should mean that we increase our earnings capacity significantly while reducing our overall balance sheet risk exposures.</p>
          <p>This is the familiar chart that traces the movement in regulatory capital ratios from quarter end to quarter end. We have restated the opening balance to reflect the correction of minor accounting errors and timing differences that I mentioned earlier. In the quarter, we made good progress in bringing down our risk weighted assets balance. This remains a key objective in the coming quarters. The reductions in Q1 were primarily the result of reductions in credit exposures, the positive effects of extending the application of the AIRB approach in subsidiaries and improved recognition of CVAs as risk mitigants.</p>
          <p>Please remember even though we continue to de-risk our balance sheet, we cannot be assured that the total risk weighted assets balance will fall. We do remain exposed to credit rating migration, to foreign exchange risks, to operational risk charges, and to calculation methods that influence RWA amounts that are not necessarily under the control of UBS.</p>
          <p>Tier 1 capital fell to 29.2 billion at the end &#x2013; at the quarter end, about CHF4 billion lower than the restated figure at the end of December. This largely came about because of the IFRS losses in the quarter adjusted to exclude the effect of 650 million of gains on own credit. This is also adversely impacted by a debit of 1.1 billion mainly related to the gradual withdrawal of the concession from deducting treasury shares from Tier 1 capital where those treasury shares are held for future satisfaction of obligations under deferred compensation plans. Pro forma for the announced Pactual sale, the Tier 1 ratio would have been 11%.</p>
          <p>Now turning briefly to the divisional performance, revenues in Wealth Management and Swiss Bank fell by 8% on the previous quarter. Pre-tax profits fell by around 26% quarter-on-quarter excluding the charge in Q4 for settlement of the U.S. cross-border case. This decline is partly explained by the high reported profits in Q4 because of the reversal of bonus accruals.</p>
          <p>We applied rigorous controls on G&amp;A expenses in the quarter and reduced them by 26% quarter-on-quarter. Personnel expenses, on the other hand, increased by 26%, despite a reduction in head count by 720. The increase was largely attributable to the resumption of bonus accruals in the year. In the pure Wealth Management segment of international clients, the gross margin was stable at 89 basis points.</p>
          <p>Credit losses amounted to CHF119 million. Approximately two-thirds resulted from our rising credit losses from exposures to small and medium-sized companies. The remaining credit losses were due to ongoing collateral closeout costs against lombard loan impairments that were incurred back in Q4. In Q1, we did not experience any further material net losses from lombard loans.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management Americas reported a pre-tax loss of CHF35 million compared with a profit of 273 million in Q4 adjusting for the impact of the auction rate security settlement. Q1's result came on the back of lower fee levels on managed accounts and lower levels of interest income related to lower spreads. A charge of CHF19 million was incurred as a goodwill impairment arising from the sale of Pactual.</p>
          <p>The division will no longer carry the risks, nor enjoy the rewards of the auction rate security settlement related positions, as both the short put option and the inventory are now carried by the IB.</p>
          <p>On an underlying basis, operating expenses increased 8% quarter-on-quarter largely as a consequence of the resumption of bonus and other performance related compensation accruals. Underlying G&amp;A expenses, however, decreased by CHF93 million, or 29% due to lower general provisioning and lower travel expenses.</p>
          <p>The gross margin on the invested assets rose by three basis points to 86 basis points in the quarter. This increase was mainly attributable to a 10 basis point increase to 36 basis points due to transaction related income, offset by a seven basis point decline in the recurring income margin to 50 basis points.</p>
          <p>Global Asset Management recorded a loss for the quarter after taking a goodwill impairment charge of CHF191 million on Pactual. Absent this charge, the pre-tax profit would have been a CHF132 million, down 44% on Q4.</p>
          <p>Operating income rose 5% to CHF502 million, primarily due to higher performance fees in the Institutional segment, mainly in the alternative and quantitative investments. Wholesale revenues fell. G&amp;A expenses fell by 22 million to CHF95 million, mainly due to reduced IT costs, professional fees, marketing expenses, and T&amp;D expenses.</p>
          <p>Excluding the Pactual goodwill charge, the cost income ratio was approximately 74%, which compared favorably to the peer group, and inflows into money market funds have remained strong throughout the quarter. This contributed to a slowdown in the net outflows to 7.7 billion, 6.6 billion of which were in wholesale intermediary in a range of strategies.</p>
          <p>The stronger investment performance that began in 2008 in the division's major equity capabilities compared with previous years continued in the first quarter. Changes made to the investment teams in equities and fixed income are now showing good results, and a large number of these strategies are outperforming their benchmarks.</p>
          <p>The Investment Bank is on the mend. Its results of a pre-tax loss of CHF3.2 billion mask a good sales and trading performance in the equities, rates, and FX money markets business. Capital markets revenues were strong in comparison not only to Q4, but also to Q1 '08. FICC reported negative revenues of two billion, down from almost twice as much in Q4. And once again this quarter, FICC's results were heavily influenced by our legacy risk positions.</p>
          <p>Here are some of the issues that FICC had to contend with in Q1. First, there was the monolines where we took a further CHF1.9 billion credit valuation adjustment against our PRV under credit default swaps from eight monoline insurers. Our net CVA taken life-to-date on our book of negative basis trades now amounts to over $7.8 billion representing 63% of the gross receivable under the credit default swaps.</p>
          <p>Second, in Global Syndicated Finance, including leverage loans, we incurred further credit loss expenses on positions we designated as loans and receivables and recognized trading losses on loans retained in the trading book. Of the CHF1 billion or so of credit loss expenses in the first quarter, 828 million related to loan positions which were entered into with the intent to syndicate or distribute, but where we were unable to do so.</p>
          <p>Third, FICC now assumes the costs related to the auction rate security settlement. The charge for marking the short put option on ARS was a hit of CHF306 million in Q1. Fourth, FICC absorbed a price variation adjustment on the third wave of assets to transfer to the StabFund's custodian of an amount of CHF232 million, net of positive currency translation effects.</p>
          <p>And finally, in addition to the losses sustained from identified risk concentrations, the cost of exiting business, including our legacy credit arbitrage trading business, amounted to in excess of CHF1 billion.</p>
          <p>In IBD, M&amp;A and other advisory fees were down 38% on Q4 reflecting slow markets. Capital markets revenues rose significantly especially in the debt capital markets, which were up over 50%. Equities recorded positive revenues in all of its trading businesses, but cash and ETD revenues were a little slower than they had been in Q4.</p>
          <p>Revenues from derivative sales and trading advanced in all geographical markets, particularly in Asia and Europe. FICC revenues, especially in emerging markets and in rates, were very satisfactory and FX money markets produced another good performance this quarter.</p>
          <p>And so to sum up, considerable progress has been made in de-risking the balance sheet. Stability seems to have come into asset prices, and there's a reasonable volume of client flow trading to enable us to build our revenues. However, trading in complex structured products remains illiquid and pricing remains uncertain, and the real economy has continued to deteriorate. Accordingly, we remain cautious on the immediate outlook for the firm, but are confident that we're taking the right measures to returning the Group to sustainable profitability.</p>
          <p>That concludes my presentation on the first quarter results, and so with that, I'd like to open the call for questions and hand you over to the conference call operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question is from Mr. Jon Peace, Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good morning everybody. Just <mark type="inaudible" /> three quick questions please. Firstly, on the private bank, you've given a slightly different presentation this quarter and I see you split up the gross margin for international clients, but I just wondered if you could comment on the gross margin trends, as we would have known it, for the Swiss business included?</p>
          <p>The second question is just on Pactual. Could you just give us an idea of the underlying P&amp;L of that business, just how much it has contributed, how much you were expecting it to contribute, so we can take that out of our models? And then finally, just wrapping together your guidance with the restructuring charge and the comments you've made on credit losses, do you think after the Q1 loss, you'll be in a position to post a profit for the full year? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jon. On the &#x2013; the reason we shared the gross margin for the international clients is because that's a pure &#x2013; it's a pure Wealth Management business. The Swiss clients business contains the retail client base in Switzerland, and so the number there is less meaningful. You can obviously disclose for the Swiss clients, the high level revenues, so you can sort of work it out, but it's a less relevant number to compare the Wealth Management businesses.</p>
          <p>Pactual was the largest component; in fact, pretty &#x2013; just about the majority component of our emerging markets revenues.</p>
          <p>And on the profitably, I think we abide really by the outlook statement that we've made, which is that we do remain a bit cautious. I think given that there is a lag effect on credit loss expense when entering into these sorts of recessionary environment, I think we feel that we would rather remain cautious in our outlook statement, clearly we're working towards profitability, but there are a number of one-off factors, the restructuring charges that I mentioned in the presentation. We have something of the order of 3.8 billion of life-to-date accrued own credit. In April, you'll know that our senior debt curve has tightened, and as a consequence, we'll be giving back some of that own credit.</p>
          <p>On the MCNs, we have this rather bizarre accounting under IFRS for the complex options within the MCNs. And when our share price goes up, that has a negative impact on our profitability through IFRS. It's not a negative impact on capital. It's a wash posting through capital, but it hits the P&amp;L account. So, still a number of one-off items and so we'd rather abide by our statement that we just remain cautious overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Matt Spick, Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I just had a couple of quick questions. One was on the very helpful disclosure on the liquidity buffer. Does the fact that you're rigorously charging out the costs of funding mean that the benefits from removing part of that liquidity buffer will be distributed over the divisions or will it be concentrated in one division in particular like the Corporate Center or the Investment Bank?</p>
          <p>And a second question is on the Tier 1 ratio. I just think I got a bit confused about why the impact from own shares was quite negative when your treasury shares actually sold during the quarter, that's probably just me not understanding, but any clarification you can give there would be really helpful. And then thirdly, I think we all know that we don't know &#x2013; none of us can know whether UBS will make a profit this year or not, and the outlook is challenging. How constrained would you feel in paying investment banking bonuses as the Group is loss making again in 2009, and is that something that concerns you? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the liquidity buffer, you're absolutely right, we do allocate the cost of the liquidity buffer across actually the five divisions because we include Corporate Center. And I can tell you the way that we distributed it in the first quarter; we distributed on the basis of our structural liquidity flows and about 65% of it is charged to the Investment Bank. There's only about 25% charged to the Corporate Center and the Group treasury. And then Wealth Management Americas, I think, got charged something like 1.5%, a tiny amount, and the Swiss Bank got charged about 8.5 in Q1. And I wouldn't imagine those allocations would vary very much from quarter to quarter, but we try to do it slightly more dynamically based on our structural liquidity flows.</p>
          <p>The Tier I ratio, you're right, the own shares deduction, it is own shares and others, so there are some other things in there. But the own shares deduction is a concession. The reason it's &#x2013; it's a removal of the deduction, because this is a concession from deducting treasury shares from Tier I. And the treasury shares are deducted at a price, which relates to a pooling arrangement we have depending on the prices at which we bought the treasury shares. That price has come down and the number of treasury shares we hold has come down, and the concession is rolling off over time. And the impact of all of those factors is a slightly counterintuitive hit to the Tier 1 in the manner that we showed, but within that number of 1.1, there are some other effects as well.</p>
          <p>On bonuses, the fact is that if you're going to be in businesses like Asset Management and investment banking, then we have to pay the market rate for the staff we employ. And if we were to retain and attract talent into those businesses, we have to be competitive, and competitive we must be. Now, we're striving clearly to improve profitability, but we did in the first quarter feel it necessary to resume bonus accrual provisioning, notwithstanding the fact that in the first quarter we did chalk up a loss, but bonus payments are part and parcel of the overall remuneration package of many of our staff, and we can do &#x2013; clearly the market for remuneration has changed and there are some other things we can do to incentivize, retain, and attract staff, but bonuses I think will remain an element of the overall remuneration package and we will continue to have to pay them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. That's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Mr. Kian Abouhossein, JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. First of all, your capital increased in the Investment Bank and you indicate the rationale for this, and what do you see as your cost of equity for this business? I think Mr. Johansson indicated 14 to 16% pre-tax in the past. Has that changed especially with the capital increasing?</p>
          <p>The second question is on your fixed income line, you mentioned excess of one billion of trading related losses, and you talk about OTC and counterparty risks. This seems to be an ongoing issue. Can you tell us of the exposures that you have in the fixed income trading line?</p>
          <p>And the third question is on credit losses. How should I look at it from a normalized basis if I strip out leverage finance? You're still running at quite a high level and I get the impression that level is increasing. How should I look at legacy assets where the issue is that you need to provide further provisions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can start with the allocated capital point, the &#x2013; we did increase the allocated capital to the Investment Bank by two billion in this quarter. That's an allocation of additional capital to support flow trading and that was a measure of support to boost the revenue earning capacity of our core flow trading businesses. In fixed income, you're right that there were trading losses that arose out of our OTC and counterparty risk positions. It's difficult to quantify those. We breakdown the PRVs as between their component parts, and a large proportion of those would arise in FICC. And then there's of course other counterparty trading on balance sheet, but a large measure of that would have been in the receivables under the derivatives in FICC.</p>
          <p>On credit losses, you're right, there is an increase in the level underlying. I don't think it's surprising. I think it's &#x2013; we're starting to see some of the impact of a more general recessionary environment. There was less in the way of credit impact arising from liquidity constraints and more pure credit impairment, and I would expect that to increase slightly. As our balances have come down, the base on which we will be charging the write-offs would be smaller, but it's likely that the rate of charge-off would increase temporarily as we go through the next few quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to follow-up on the questions. allocated capital, is this &#x2013; what specific area do you see capital increasing and can you also refer to what you see as cost of equity in the Investment Bank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry. I did forget the cost of equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We allocate capital basically on the basis of the capital sitting in the division, so to the extent that there are subsidiaries holding capital, we allocate capital against goodwill, and then we allocate capital on a risk adjusted basis against the needs of that division. Now, we are calibrating the Investment Bank for its activities, so we want to grow the flow trading operations. It doesn't necessarily mean growing balance sheet particularly or may manifest itself in that. We've taken the balance sheet, the tight balance sheet constraints off the flow trading businesses in the IB, recognizing that the inherited positions will continue to come down over time as we work them out and as they simply mature, and we can replace that, that headroom that's released, with flow trading businesses and flow trading positions.</p>
          <p>We felt that the IB required more capital, partly because we're moving towards the leverage ratio, so that becomes more and more of an impact on the capital that needs to be allocated, but also we just thought generally given the additional losses, we ought to allocate some more capital to it. Now what that means in practice is that we ask the IB to make a return on that capital. And you're right, yes, this number that we have allocated internally was to target a 14% return on capital. Whether that was pre or post tax, the point is, at the moment, is rather moot, because we have the largest number of offsetting items that would require us to &#x2013; that would not require us to pay taxes on time. In the longer term, we'll be looking obviously for an after-tax return because we'd be looking for real economic profit. But at the moment, the target is 14% and it's pre and post.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on FICC, can you be a bit more specific what the billion markdown is related to? You had this for several quarters now. You specify now the size. But I get the impression you have assets that you're cleaning up, and I would be interested how big these assets are or what we're really talking about, because I don't see why would you clean up on counterparty risk in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's asset cleanup. It's not as though we weren't attending to that before, but it's a wide variety of things. It's the fact that we carry &#x2013; still carry considerable basis risk in a number of our books in fixed income, and it is the fact that we have a very large volume, as you know, of receivables on the derivatives contract, and we are hedging the counterparty risk and that comes at a cost. And in the first quarter, the sum total of those was a considerable sum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Derek De Vries, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I was wondering if you could give us a little bit more clarity on the large drop you saw in client advisors in the quarter? First of all, I think when you changed the &#x2013; when you changed the disclosure, the Swiss client advisors dropped out, so I'm wondering if you could give us a like-for-like number with the 5,755 that you reported in Q4 and then also provide some clarity on the 8% or over 8% fall in client advisors we saw Q1. Do you anticipate that's going to be the worst of it or do you see a sort of residual falloff similar to this level?</p>
          <p>And then finally, presumably as the TOAs come in, do you have a sense as to where these people are going and maybe you can give us some clarity, are they going to other large private banks, i.e., Credit Suisse, HSBC, or are they going to some of the smaller players in the market?</p>
          <p>And then the &#x2013; I just wanted one follow-up question on the fixed income revenues. I mean you sort of encourage us to strip out a lot of numbers in the fixed income where you say that the business was negatively impacted by a lot of different functions. Am I doing the math right, if I sort of add back all of those things you sort of say are non-recurring or exceptional? I get to a fixed income revenue for the quarter of 2.3 billion, and is that kind of what you're guiding to at an underlying Q1, in a very good quarter of sustainable fixed income revenue sales and trading?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Derek. I'll take the client advisors point first. The point on client advisors is that we actually cut capacity in the first quarter. These were not necessarily regretted departures, and we are continuing to cut capacity. As a general point, what happened over the past five, six, seven years, as we built out the Wealth Management business, particularly the onshore businesses, was that client invested assets went up and we took the client advisors number up, and if you plot the two graphs, they sort of match. But the number of clients that we acquired didn't go up by quite so much because we were winning share of wallet and we were actually creating value in our Investment Bank for our Wealth Management clients. And so what happened is that because we grew our client advisor numbers in line with invested assets rather than number of clients, we tended to have ended up with slightly excess capacity given the environment and the client volumes of invested assets have fallen full. And so we're suffering negative operating leverage. And so we've deliberately reduced the number of client advisors across all of our Wealth Management businesses, and would, unfortunately, continue to do so as part of our announced restructurings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So maybe you want to give us some clarity then in terms of the regretted departures, what you estimate that is of the 8% half? Certainly, anecdotally, the story's coming out of your Wealth Management business, there's lots of people leaving of their own volition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the regretted leavers were stable on the previous quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the fixed income, your number of 2.3 &#x2013; I don't have, maybe you've added back a few more of these unusual items than I had. I would come up with a number that's somewhat lower than that, in the range of 1.5 to two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, what I did &#x2013; just tell me where I shouldn't. I added back the monoline loss, I added back the revenues on the <mark type="inaudible" /> 828 million, I added back the 306 million of ARS, I added back 232 million on the Swiss National Bank through that STB transaction. And then you said there was a billion related to cost of exiting businesses. So I just added back all those numbers and added that to your -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If that's about &#x2013; that will be about right. There's a bit of leverage finance, the point I didn't mention was, in the trading book, as opposed to the loans we reclassified. In the trading book, there's some negative revenues arising from what are effectively credit impairments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, yes, fine, yes. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Huw van Steenis, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. Two questions, first on flows, you mentioned that a lot of the outflows came around the time of the U.S. shenanigans. As you've got further away from that distance in Q2, can you give us any sense of stabilization of flows, or have some trends continued? And then secondly, if we just go back to the increase in provisions, how comfortable are you with the allocated allowances, net of flat or around 61% in the Investment Bank, given the comp &#x2013; the type of tone you're talking about, of continued write-downs on facilities? Do you feel that you need to accrue that off as the quarters go on, and we should continued further increase in provisioning level, above and over the underlying deterioration in credit? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the only insight I can give you to net new money flows is, there appears to be a correlation -- which at least I've observed -- between, as you call them, shenanigans and the associated commentary in the press and general media coverage. And when that's negative, we seem to have, with a very short lag, negative experience in relation to flows. And then when things stabilize and subside and go quiet again, then we tend to see some sort of reversion. So if that's sufficient indication of where we feel we are now, I hope you can read between the lines.</p>
          <p>On our provisioning, I think we have to say we're very comfortable at the levels that we posted at the end of March. We're not allowed to make general provisions against the general deterioration due to economic factors. But I think, yes, we would expect to be accruing up other credit losses. We think there is a headwind in the credit markets, the lag effect from the recessionary environment. But in relation to the positions on the book at the end of March, we're very comfortable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just lastly, are there any other syndicated loans which are stuck, which we should expect to come off the 180 days as we go into Q2, or was that now &#x2013; that effected now, largely in the numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'll give you a nerdish response here, I think it's page 140.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the annual report. I don't think we show this quarterly, do we, Philip?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. 140.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is 140, here we go. On that page, we show the Investment Bank's so-called banking products, and then we show the volume of products held for distribution, spilt between investment grade and sub-investment grade, and the sum is roughly 5.5 billion, the 3.7 or so investment grade, 2.8 sub-investment grade. And as I mentioned, we lost 828 in the first quarter and I don't know to what extent we did successfully distribute, I'm sure it was some, and there would be hardly any new additions to those balances. But there would still be positions on the books, which we are still holding as temporary positions, in the hope of being able to distribute them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question from Mr. Christopher Wheeler, MainFirst Bank. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, John. I hope this question doesn't sound rude, but when you announced the Swiss Bank being created in February, I think we all understood the optics of that. However, I don't think what we did expect was for you to put together the Wealth Management business, the biggest wealth management in the world, with the large retail bank and create a consolidated set of numbers, which obviously, given the fact that historically wealth management businesses have enjoyed something of a higher rating then retail banking earnings, does seem a little bit odd. I think it's also a little bit odd -- yes, this is your core business, your Wealth Management business, excluding perhaps the Americas, and you must be one of the few companies in the world who is actually not showing us the detailed earnings of your core business.</p>
          <p>And again, given your efforts, your pretty aggressive efforts to win back shareholder confidence, I find that a little bit surprising. And I know you did touch on with John's question, the Swiss business is a little bit different, but it's one-third of your invested assets in Wealth Management. So, would you &#x2013; I just wanted you to comment on why you chose, having created this new vehicle, to just literally lump everything together and whether you think that this is something that you may change going forward? Thank you, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, rather than comment on why it happened, because I'm not entirely sure I know why it happened, I would say that your point is well taken. So, the point is on board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Ms. Fiona Swaffield, Execution. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have three questions, if that's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The first was on the reclassification of financial assets, page 78, sorry to go into accounting, but I'm just trying to understand why you would avoided further write-downs, as in what asset class it is vis-&#xE0;-vis classified, and how you see this playing out over time, because there's quite a big difference between the fair value and carrying value, and I can't quite get what assets this relates to, and I think you saved 1.2 billion in the first quarter? Your results would have been 1.2 billion lower if you hadn't done this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, the second area is the cost number on the slides, the less than 20 billion in the small little blue bit at the top for bonuses, it's very difficult to know just what the bonus is, but could you talk about accounting and your malus and deferral plan, and whether that makes a significant difference in how bonuses would be recognized by 2010, i.e., it will never be where it was previously?</p>
          <p>And then on the third area, just on risk-weighted assets and the incremental risk charge, I was a bit uncertain as to whether you've given any guidance on how that could affect the risk-weighted assets going forward, i.e., we've seen a very big positive now, but we could see a big negative in terms of more growth from the incremental risk charge over time? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We &#x2013; you're right, we did give some disclosure in the Q4 in relation to the reclassified assets, and of the assets we reclassified, we did take impairment charges in the course of Q4 and we've gone on to take them again in the course of Q1. The difference between the fair value and the carrying value is, of course, the fair value is meant to be a market representation of how much we could sell those positions for, which would contain a considerable liquidity discount, even at the end of March. What the assets constitute is a bit of a mishmash. There were obviously positions that were originally in the trading book. They were, by and large, loans that we had acquired with the objective of distributing them. So it's, in large measure, our leverage finance and acquisition finance books. And the impact in Q1 on the write-downs was largely attributable to four of these larger positions, which continued to impact us.</p>
          <p>Philip just kindly showed me the chart from Q4 -- you're right, it was $1.2 was the impairment charge. I think it worked out at CHF1.4. But there isn't any particular large category of loans in here, and there are some student loans, which are now- when we acquired them, are classified as loans and receivables and will not go into the trading book. Originally, when we acquired student loan auction rate securities, when the auctions were failing, we put them in the trading book in the hope that we would trade them out, and in the end couldn't, so we reclassified those. I think that's the single largest concentration, but it doesn't &#x2013; it's a mishmash of credit style trading positions, which we just reclassified to loans because they were suffering liquidity discounts.</p>
          <p>On the cost number for bonuses, you're right, the accounting for bonuses under IFRS 2 is driven in part by the forfeiture provisions that are built into the compensation plans. And they would have an impact of slowing down the recognition of that expense, because at the moment, we have leave loosed our provisions embedded in our new plans. And the final point, Philip, I think if you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it was on the risk weighted assets, and whether or not market risk assumptions might go up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The market risk charge will go up. There's almost no doubt about it. It will go up, not because necessarily a time series being fed into the regulatory VaR, although that will be a contributory factor. It will go up largely because regulators across the globe and the BIS have been debating changing the algorithm that converts regulatory value at risk into a notional risk weighted assets charge. And so, inevitably, that will go up, and the guidance I've been giving is that I wouldn't be surprised if that didn't end up, in the course of the next couple of years, I think the BIS proposals, whether they'd be introduced by 2011, but I would not be surprised if that didn't result in a doubling of the notional volume of risk assets that comes out of the transformation of market risk and regulatory VaR into Tier 1 calculations. So, our 28.2 at the end of the period could quite easily go up to 50, 60.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Can I just have a quick follow-up on the liquidity buffer, which I forgot to ask? When you talked about bringing it down, I think you said 20%, I just wanted to &#x2013; you said it'd come down 20% Q2 versus Q1, and what determines the pace which should bring it down? Why &#x2013; and also is it the net benefit to the P&amp;L pretty much the whole thing, or would &#x2013; are bonuses accrued or &#x2013; does that mean the result would have been double underlying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the liquidity buffer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you said 800 million cost in Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's right. The 800 million is spread across the entire buffer. The way the buffer works, is that it's a reasonably homogenous set of positions. We borrow in the markets relatively long and we target something like nine months, and then we invest that in largely government securities. So, Japanese government bonds, T-bills, that sort of thing, and then we reverse repo those, overnight or two nights. And then to even out the accounting because we end up with mark-to-market on the left and accrual on the right, we tend to enter into OIS contracts, Overnight Interest Swap contracts, which the Investment Bank in particular, but also the Swiss Bank, use to hedge the cost. Each one of those steps obviously has some frictional drag, and there's generally a negative carry. And so the cost of our buffer in Q1, which is obviously volume and negative spread related, was about 800 million.</p>
          <p>So the point I wanted to make was that if we bring it down by 20, and then another 20 during the course of the remainder of Q2, then you're looking at a volume contribution, at least 60% of 800. And hopefully, the spread will start to contract over time as the markets recover; particularly the liquidity markets are recovering a bit. So we should see a reduction in that. But I have to tell you it was causing my colleagues in the investment banks to squeal, the amount we were charging them, because they too have a negative carry on a number of their positions because they have to hold collateral against a broad range of requirements from central banks, our Euro Bank model in London, and against exchanges. And they generally, these days, would also have an attaching negative carry that wouldn't have quite such a wide spread, but nevertheless would impact on their results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Kinner Lakhani, RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, a couple of questions. Firstly, on the follow-up on the missing parts in fixed income, just wanted to find out if you did have any benefit in the first quarter from what one of your peers has called rebound revenues from the fourth quarter? Are you in &#x2013; some of the basis risk came back from the wides that we saw in the fourth quarter? And my second question is, on the monoline side, I wonder if you could make some more general comments about where you think things go from here, and the scope for commutations and what you might get cents on dollar, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer on the rebound was that we did, and we were &#x2013; we're not a huge credit trader, but we did see some benefit from the narrowing of the negative basis on cash versus derivative, particularly in January, and also on the monolines as a matter of fact, and it was one of the reasons why the year started so propitiously. That has underlined a little bit in the course of the next few months, but we did benefit, but not to the extent of many of our competitors, simply because we're not so big in the credit trading markets.</p>
          <p>On the monolines, the general comment &#x2013; you may know that in Q1 we had a couple of events, one monoline led to a compromise of the monoline insurance. So, when you look at the CVA of 1.7 billion, you don't necessarily see it in our tables, and that's because one of the monolines fell out of the table, because there was a commutation of the insurance into direct access to the underlying collateral. There's, very recently in the last week, there's been a default, approved by ISDA, in relation to one monoline, which will have an impact &#x2013; won't necessarily have a negative impact on us because we feel that our provisioning levels on the monolines, and we've seen where our competitors have disclosed their provisioning levels, and ours do appear to be at the conservative end.</p>
          <p>Whether that proves to have been a self-inflicted wound, who knows, but we have been very conservative. And so far, on the two monolines that we have &#x2013; we've seen either commutation or default, and we've actually seen some giveback, not substantial, but a modest amount of giveback on our CVAs. And on the big one, that was the mid-February event, the other big event in the middle of February that turned the tide for us a bit, we were heavily exposed to that one and that cost us quite a lot, and that was the &#x2013; that was sort of half or so of the 1.7 billion of additional provision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The VIA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think I'm not allowed to mention it by name for some reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Omahen Ganesh (sic) [Jernej Omahen] , Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's the other way around. It's Jernej Omahen here from Goldman Sachs. I just have three very, very straightforward questions. The first one is on the announced cost cuts or targeted cost cuts of 3.5 to four billion. I was just wondering what's the associated revenue number with that, and can you give us a sense of what proportion of that revenue you expect you've already lost in a sense, because I'm assuming some of the revenue attrition would have been front-loaded?</p>
          <p>The second question is on market shares, which your competitors talk a lot about these days, and I was just wondering can you give us a sense when you look at your &#x2013; as you called it positive momentum in your equities business, some of the other flow businesses, et cetera, what is your estimate or what's your gauge of what UBS' market share in these businesses has been doing over the past quarter?</p>
          <p>And finally on accrual, on accruals, I think I found the word mentioned very frequently on this call both by you and people asking you questions, but I haven't actually heard the number yet, if I'm not mistaken, so I was just wondering if you're able to share that number with us as well, i.e., how much has been accrued so far this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, and that last question, how much it was been accrued so far this year? Is it bonus accruals, did you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh sorry, I don't think we're disclosing that separately. So I better not say, otherwise I'll get myself into terrible trouble. On the first question of the costs, many of the costs actually don't come out of front office. Many of the costs really are just streamlining the business for what has already been impacting us, which is this negative operating leverage where our revenues have fallen and our expense base hasn't, so most of it is catch-up, and then most of the attendant revenues from the streamlining will have already been impacted us on our accounts. So I don't think there's a great deal of additional revenue attrition that would derive from the cost cuts, and that's even where we are cutting back front office positions because we're effectively just cutting them back to bring that capacity into line with the market.</p>
          <p>Our market shares, we have some information which comes from third parties by and large, but in cash equities, for example, it looks as though over the quarter, our market share increased by 0.6%. And in IBD, we've got the Dialogic data where we rank number five globally with a 5.8 market share &#x2013; 5.8% market share, which was the same as in Q1 '08. We're number five. So I think generally we feel that most of our core businesses and the ones that we are more associated with being strong in, we are at least holding our own, but we continue to be hamstrung by these legacy positions, which we're just outsize originally, and it's taking some time for us to wash them out of the system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Forgive me. Just to follow-up on question two, so if I understand you correctly, you expect the bulk of the cost cut as it was announced to flow through to your pre-tax line essentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The bulk of it, yes, by all means, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because we're downsizing to meet the already apparent fall in our revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks a lot, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question is from Mr. George Kanders, WestLB. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, I have a question on the Corporate Center. Even adjusting for the extraordinary items you have mentioned here, there's a positive revenue contribution of 300 million in the Corporate Center. This is, first of all, what kind of revenue is this, and the other question is, is this more or less sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the Corporate Center is obviously a little bit of a catchall for some Group items, and there are two main positive contributors to the Corporate Center. The first was that 524 million that I mentioned, which was the write-up in the value of the MCN, the second MCN, the one with the Swiss Confederation, which was simply a result really of a slight change in the volatility assumptions of our shares, but mainly a result of the fall in the value of our shares over the quarter. The Corporate Center is then hit by, I think, it was by 302 million, which was the impact of the change in the value of the option to acquire the StabFund, the SNB fund.</p>
          <p>And then the final number was a number which our Group &#x2013; our Group Treasury released a very strong return in the first quarter. Some of that, to their credit, was very good trading. Some of it was our new method of charging the front-end of the business, mainly the trading desks in the IB with the Group's cost of funds plus a markup. And the final point, I think, was a one-off, which I think we did announce during the course of the quarter, where we bid back some of our subordinated debt, some debt that counts as Tier 2 capital under the current regime, and we made a gain, a one-off gain on that buyback exercise of CHF304 million.</p>
          <p>And so, I think, those are mainly one-off items that show the Corporate Center in a positive light in the quarter. Obviously, some of those are not recurring. The MCN number, I suspect, given where our share price today is, certainly would this quarter-to-date, have shown a massive giveback on that number, if not eradicated the entire 525. So it is the recipient, unfortunately, of some extremely volatile movements in these one-off items that &#x2013; well, they are not one-off because they do recur, but they recur in unpredictable fashions until such time, for example, as the MCN converts and then it just goes away. But it mainly is a consequence of one-offs and a good contribution from the Group Treasury.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so the remaining result was a good contribution from the Treasury, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Treasury had a very, very strong quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you John. So that concludes today's webcast of UBS's first quarter results. If you have got follow-up questions, please don't hesitate to speak with the IR team or the media team, and thank you for joining us. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>