<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1450152" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>631</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Caroline P. Stewart</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Executive Officer">Sergio P. Ermotti</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Financial Officer">Tom Naratil</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Huw J. van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Royal Bank of Canada Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Fiona M. Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Derek A. De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst Schweiz AG">Kilian Maier</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Analyst, Bank Vontobel">Teresa Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca SpA (United Kingdom)">Christopher J. Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Thomson Reuters Corp.">Katharina Bart</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good morning. Welcome to the Fourth Quarter 2011 Results Conference Call. I'm Stephanie, the Chorus Call operator. I would like to remind you that all participants will be in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>At this time, it's my pleasure to hand over to UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and welcome to our Fourth Quarter Results Presentation. This morning, Sergio Ermotti, our CEO, will present the highlights of our full-year results and the fourth quarter results. Then Tom Naratil, our CFO, will present the fourth quarter results in detail. After that, we'd be very happy to take your questions, and, first of all, we'll take questions from analysts and then from journalists.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Sergio, I'd like to draw your attention to this slide, which contains our cautionary statement with regard to forward-looking statements, and I'd ask that you read it carefully.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to hand over to Sergio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Caroline. Good morning, and thank you for joining us. At our Investor Day in November, we outlined a strategy for UBS that centers on our preeminent Wealth Management businesses and our Universal Bank in Switzerland and that builds on the strength of a more focused and less capital-intensive Investment Bank, as well as our diversified Global Asset Management business. This strategy is supported by our industry-leading capital position and requires us to significantly reduce risk-weighted assets, which ultimately will enable us to deliver increasingly attractive returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>2011 was not an easy year for the industry nor for UBS. The European debt crisis, U.S. budget issues and weak economic growth put pressure on markets and on the confidence of our clients. We also faced our own challenges, with the unauthorized trading incident. Despite this, we have made real progress in a number of businesses and delivering in the strategic objectives we set out at Investor Day.</p>
          <p>Let me outline our five key achievements so far. First, we maintained our position as the best capitalized bank in our peer group. We ended the year with a Basel 2.5 tier-1 capital ratio of 16%, up 330 basis points in the year. Our phased-in Basel 3 common equity ratio was 10.8% at the year end, and this is a firm basis on which to build towards our 13% target.</p>
          <p>Our determination to increase our capital base in 2011 also led to an increase of 16% in our book value per share, at CHF14.29, and a 20% increase in our tangible book value per share. Despite the stresses associated with the macro environment, our funding and liquidity positions also remained strong throughout 2011.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we decisively reduced risk-weighted assets. We reduced Basel 2.5 risk-weighted assets by 10% over the year, and in the fourth quarter, Basel 3 risk-weighted assets were cut by about CHF20 billion, to CHF380 billion. In total, the Investment Bank reduced risk-weighted assets by CHF26 billion. Around CHF18 billion of the reduction was in our legacy portfolio, mostly reflecting sales of student loan auction rate securities and the remainder of the reduction came from the core Investment Bank businesses. This means we are well on track and on our way to achieving the risk-weighted asset target we set for the Investment Bank in 2012.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, we attracted CHF42 billion of net new money, an improvement of around CHF55 billion on the previous year. Our Wealth Management businesses drove most of the improvement, attracting over CHF35 billion of net new money compared with outflows in the previous year. Global Asset Management also attracted increased net new money, including CHF12 billion from third parties.</p>
          <p>Let me also highlight that in our Retail &amp; Corporate business in Switzerland in 2011, we attracted the highest level of net &#x2013; of new client assets from our retail customers since 2007. All of this is a testament to the loyalty and the trust of our clients, the recognition of our financial strength and the hard work of our employees.</p>
          <p>Fourth, profitability. Today, we announced a net profit attributable to shareholders for 2011 of CHF4.2 billion, diluted earnings per share of CHF1.10 and a pre-tax profit of CHF5.5 billion. Let me highlight the progress we have made in our Wealth Management businesses and Retail &amp; Corporate in Switzerland, which are central to our strategy. Together, these three businesses increased their pre-tax profit by 29%, to CHF5.1 billion. This is an excellent performance in a year characterized by low client activity levels and low interest rates.</p>
          <p>Global Asset Management contributed over CHF400 million in pre-tax profit, down 17% in a year where many of our clients chose the safety of cash instead of actively invested funds. Global Asset Management continues to be of vital importance to the implementation of our strategy and to our clients around the world.</p>
          <p>For the full year, the Investment Bank recorded a pre-tax profit of CHF304 million, down from CHF2.2 billion in the prior year. The financial performance, however, does not tell the full story, as the business made strategic improvements that, unfortunately, did not get the attention they deserved because of the unauthorized trading incident.</p>
          <p>Fifth and lastly on costs, as you know, we are currently implementing our CHF2 billion cost reduction program announced last July. Head count was down by over 1,100 in the fourth quarter, and we expect to see consequent reduction in costs over the course of 2012.</p>
          <p>In 2011, our cost base fell CHF2.1 billion, or 9%. Two-third of this reduction was a result of lower compensation expenses, mostly reflecting cuts to bosses, in particular in the Investment Bank, reflecting weaker performance and as a result of the unauthorized trading incident.</p>
          <p>Tom will go through the detailed numbers, so I will speak to the headline figures. Our 2011 bonus pool is down 40%, and this compares to a 13% decline in our operating income. I believe this is a clear illustration of our efforts to ensure that rewards are better aligned with performance and to balance the interest of staff and shareholders both in the short and the longer term.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we expect continuing weak economic growth and macro issues to influence global markets, and clients will look to us for advice and solutions. Although markets are challenging, they present us with significant opportunities to deliver our expertise and capabilities, provided we stay close to our clients, understand their needs and deliver on the full promise of our strategy.</p>
          <p>This is the absolute priority of the year for the banking in 2012 and, to do this effectively, we must leverage our superior capital position and our overall financial strength. Markets will, to some extent, dictate what wealth is created and the speed at which net new money can be delivered. Regardless of market condition, we will maintain our discipline on gross margin and we will not seek inflows at any price.</p>
          <p>There are two areas where we are determined to drive further improvements, on cost efficiency and the reduction of risk-weighted assets to further improve our capital position. On cost, as I said, we expect to see more of the benefit of our CHF2 billion cost containment program later this year.</p>
          <p>We will continue to actively monitor markets and, if conditions deteriorate materially, we are prepared to take action to reduce our cost base further. But as I say at our Investor Day, our capacity to further cut costs in a tactical way is limited, so we must focus on strategic changes which go to the heart of our organizational design and structure, consistently improving efficiency as to become part of our corporate DNA. And we are working on the next phase, which will reshape our cost base in the years to come.</p>
          <p>As you have seen, we have already made clear progress on risk reduction and we aim to maintain our momentum over the course of the year. 2012 is a year of transition for the group and, particularly, for the investment bank, as we fundamentally reshape our business. Building on our capital position is, therefore, a priority for 2012, and we are determined to meet our risk reduction target in full and on time.</p>
          <p>One of the key commitments we made last November was to drive improved returns in the business and make UBS more attractive to our shareholders. Although we expect markets to remain challenging for the foreseeable future, I'm confident that we can achieve the targets we have set. Underscoring my confidence, I want to close by reiterating our intention to propose a dividend of CHF0.10 per share at our AGM this year. This will be a starting point for a progressive return policy we intend to implement as we execute on our strategy.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Tom, I'd like to reiterate the key achievements of the bank for 2011 and on the fourth quarter. We remain the best capitalized bank amongst our peer, with a sizably reduced risk-weighted asset particularly in Q4, and this provide a good basis for delivering our risk-weighted assets target reduction for 2012.</p>
          <p>Net new money for the year improved CHF55 billion and all our asset-gathering businesses had positive net new money in the fourth quarter. We recorded a pre-tax profit of CHF5.5 billion for the year, with a 29% increase in the combined profits of our Wealth Management businesses and Retail &amp; Corporate. We reduced costs by over CHF2 billion and, lastly, we intend to propose a CHF0.10 dividend for the year.</p>
          <p>With that, I thank you for your attention, and I will now turn it over to Tom Naratil to take you through the quarter's result in more details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sergio, and good morning, everyone. It's my pleasure to take you through the details of our results for the fourth quarter of 2011. We recorded a net profit of approximately CHF400 million and a pre-tax profit of approximately CHF600 million in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Despite the challenging market conditions, we were encouraged by a number of positive developments this past quarter. To name a few, we continued to attract net new money in our Wealth Management businesses, Retail &amp; Corporate had a resilient performance and Global Asset Management profits were up nearly 50% quarter-on-quarter. In the Investment Bank, we saw another quarter of strong performance in our macro and advisory businesses. As Sergio said, we continued to make progress in risk-weighted asset reduction, implementation of our cost reduction program is on track and our capital, liquidity and funding positions remain sound.</p>
          <p>Before I get into the details of the results, I'd like to make a few important points on the environment in the fourth quarter. Despite continued uncertainty around the Eurozone sovereign debt crisis and a consistently weak economic outlook, equity markets experienced lower volatility, particularly at the end of the quarter. Market conditions continued to weigh on client confidence, leading to low client activity levels and a significant reduction in trading volumes.</p>
          <p>Most major indices closed at higher levels compared with the end of the third quarter, which had a positive effect on our invested assets. The Swiss franc depreciated against the U.S. dollar and the British pound, continuing the trends seen in the third quarter after the Swiss National Bank's decision to set a minimum exchange rate in early September. This positively impacted our invested asset levels, improving fee income and other revenue streams in non-Swiss franc currencies. While this depreciation was helpful on the revenue side, it had the offsetting effect of increasing our cost base.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, we focused our efforts on reducing risk-weighted assets, in particular in our legacy book. We are ahead of the plan we outlined at our Investor Day and we're confident our success so far puts us in a position to meet our targets. This chart illustrates the progress we've already made.</p>
          <p>Before I comment on the specific reductions we achieved, let me remind you that these figures are on a pro forma Basel 3 basis. Also note that as we finalized the composition of the legacy portfolio in December, total legacy RWAs were revised to approximately CHF80 billion. This is approximately CHF10 billion higher than the estimated number we provided to you earlier and is offset with a reduction in the core Investment Bank.</p>
          <p>The total for the group was reduced by CHF20 billion to approximately CHF380 billion despite the weakening franc against the dollar. This decrease does not include the anticipated net CHF17 billion benefit from the roll-off of the market-risk RWAs related to the unauthorized trading incident, as we'd already deducted it from the pro forma numbers at the beginning of the period.</p>
          <p>CHF18 billion of the decrease is related to a reduction in our legacy portfolio, mostly the result of a sale of CHF1.4 billion of U.S. student loan auction rate securities at or near our marks. The remaining reduction of CHF8 billion was in the core IB and was a result of lower market risk in our trading book. With this, we've already achieved one-third of our planned reduction for 2012.</p>
          <p>There were clearly offsetting increases, the most significant of which relates to increased CVA charges related to the counterparty credit risk on derivatives transactions, as our model takes external credit rating inputs for the credit quality of the counterparty. In the fourth quarter, we witnessed several downgrades of sovereigns and financial institutions, which increased the CVA charge by approximately CHF5 billion.</p>
          <p>We ended the quarter at CHF212 billion, and our target is to reduce to CHF190 billion by the end of 2012. There may be some fluctuation as we deploy risk in a disciplined way in the core IB if market conditions improve. However, we expect a more sustained reduction as we make progress exiting inventory in some of our less attractive businesses.</p>
          <p>Reduction of Basel 3 RWAs is one of our key strategic initiatives. We remain focused on disciplined execution, particularly in the legacy portfolio. We transferred this portfolio from the Investment Bank to the Corporate Center in the fourth quarter. More details are shown on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Starting with the first quarter of 2012, we'll report the legacy portfolio as part of a separate segment in the Corporate Center. IB assets transferred include auction rate securities, monoline-protected assets, asset-backed securities and some long-dated rates positions totaling approximately CHF27 billion of balance sheet assets and CHF23 billion of positive replacement values at the end of December 2011.</p>
          <p>At the end of the year, this portfolio accounted for CHF62 billion of pro forma Basel 3 RWAs, CHF7 billion of which related to U.S. student loan auction rate securities. We've also transferred all contingent liabilities associated with legacy assets and businesses, as you can read in our quarterly report.</p>
          <p>In addition to the assets transferred from the Investment Bank, this segment will include our option to buy the equity in the SNB StabFund, which is currently valued at CHF1.6 billion. Half of this amount is currently deducted from Tier 1 capital, but will be converted to approximately CHF20 billion of RWAs under Basel III.</p>
          <p>On this slide, you'll find a breakdown of our results by division. I'd like to comment first on the Corporate Center and then move on to the business divisions. The Corporate Center reported a loss of CHF273 million, mostly due to a loss of CHF129 million related to the revaluation of our option to buy the SNB StabFund's equity. Expenses were CHF121 million after allocations to the business division. Our tax rate for the quarter was higher than expected, at 32%. However, the effective tax rate for the year was 17.5%, which is in line with our guidance. I'll provide more details on our tax expense later in this presentation.</p>
          <p>Both of our Wealth Management businesses saw a continued net new money inflows in the fourth quarter, which, coupled with higher equity market levels at the end of the quarter and currency movements, led to higher invested assets. At the end of the year, invested assets stood at CHF1.5 trillion. Our scope and geographic diversification enable us to weather continued uncertainty in the markets relatively well, as demonstrated by the resilience of our revenues despite low client activity. This is a clear testament to the strength of our unrivaled franchise.</p>
          <p>Additionally, Wealth Management Americas maintained its number one position in invested assets and revenues for a financial advisor, which is a function of its high net worth and ultra-high net worth focused client strategy. Wealth Management reported a pre-tax profit of CHF468 million compared to CHF540 million in the third quarter, excluding CHF433 million in gains from the sale of our strategic investment portfolio as well as CHF85 million in restructuring charges in the third quarter. I'll exclude these items for the remainder of the commentary.</p>
          <p>Revenues of almost CHF1.7 billion were 4% lower than last quarter due to lower client activity as well as lower interest income previously generated by the strategic investment portfolio. The loss of these revenues more than offset the positive net interest impact of higher loan and deposit volumes, which were driven by the strengthening of the U.S. dollar versus the franc. Net fee and commission income declined due to lower client activity and a shift of client assets into cash and cash-like products as clients sought safety in an uncertain market environment.</p>
          <p>Trading income, adjusted for the reclassification in the third quarter, decreased about 7%, mostly due to unusually high levels of client FX trading in the summer months. Expenses were roughly flat after adjusting both quarters for restructuring charges booked for our cost reduction program. Our client advisor head count decreased slightly in the quarter, partly due to our efforts to trim underperforming advisor ranks. However, we did and will continue to hire client advisors in our strategic growth areas of APAC and the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Net new money inflows were CHF3.1 billion, as we benefited from several large flows during the quarter. Net inflows continue to come from our key growth areas of Asia-Pacific and the emerging markets, as well as globally from ultra-high net worth clients. Our European onshore business reported net inflows which more than offset net outflows in the offshore business, mainly from countries neighboring Switzerland.</p>
          <p>Our European net new money result also includes the CHF600 million in outflows we had previously flagged related to the departure of client advisers who joined the firm as part of a past acquisition in Germany. These outflows are now complete. In Switzerland, we saw net outflows of CHF1.8 billion, partly reflecting seasonally higher consumption-related withdrawals.</p>
          <p>In a weak environment for client activity, our gross margin declined to 91 basis points. When we published our results last quarter, we flagged that we expected the margin to be impacted by roughly 2 basis points due to the absence of income generated by our strategic investment portfolio.</p>
          <p>As lower trading revenues were offset by slightly higher interest income, the remaining decline of 4 basis points came mostly as a result of lower transaction-based fees. The negative effect on the margin was exacerbated by a significant increase in invested assets at the end of the quarter, increasing the average invested assets used to calculate gross margin. For the full year, gross margin increased to 96 basis points from 92 basis points in 2010.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management Americas remained the industry leader in financial adviser productivity among our large competitors, reflecting our ability to attract and retain the most productive financial advisers in the industry. Our pre-tax profit of CHF114 million compared with CHF139 million in the third quarter. While revenues rose 2% in francs, they declined 5% in dollars due to lower fees on lower invested asset levels at the end of the third quarter and a decrease in commissions reflecting lower client activity.</p>
          <p>In addition, net interest income declined as the third quarter benefited from a reclassification related to mortgage-backed securities in our available-for-sale portfolio. Excluding this, net interest income increased, reflecting higher balances in client securities-based lending and mortgages. Costs, adjusted for restructuring charges, decreased 2% in dollars, as we saw a $14 million decline in litigation provisions and lower legal fees.</p>
          <p>We added 54 financial advisors in the quarter. A combination of targeted recruiting of experienced advisors, selected hiring of new financial advisors and continued low attrition levels. Net new money inflows were CHF1.9 billion compared to CHF4 billion in the prior quarter, driven by recruitment of experienced financial advisors. Including dividends and interest, net new money was consistent, at CHF7.9 billion.</p>
          <p>WMA continued to make progress on its strategic banking initiatives, with the majority of the growth in lending balances coming from credit lines to our targeted high net worth and ultra-high net worth client base. Net interest income when adjusted for our third quarter reclassification related to mortgage-backed securities in our available-for-sale portfolio increased 2% in dollars on higher client balances and securities-based lending and mortgages as we continued to grow banking product balances with appropriate risk-adjusted pricing.</p>
          <p>In a challenging environment, the IB reported a loss for the quarter of CHF256 million. This included a loss on own credit of CHF71 million and a CHF106 million charge for the UK Bank levy. Adjusted for these items, the loss was CHF79 million. Despite reporting a loss, the Investment Bank's underlying performance included bright spots in a number of areas, especially given the difficult market environment in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>In light of such market conditions, we took a prudent approach to risk taking and focused our efforts on risk-weighted asset reduction. During the quarter, we successfully reduced the overall risk in our core Investment Bank. Our average value at risk for the quarter was CHF36 million, the lowest level in the last three years. At the same time, the revenues per unit of VaR were the highest since the second quarter of 2010, reflecting more efficient deployment of risk in our trading businesses.</p>
          <p>While revenues excluding own credit and the unauthorized trading incident increased quarter-on-quarter, they were down approximately 30% year-on-year, both in francs and dollars, reflecting lower revenues across all business areas.</p>
          <p>Adjusted for restructuring charges and the UK Bank levy, operating expenses decreased 7% year-on-year. This mostly reflects the favorable effects of the strengthening Swiss franc, as well as reduced variable compensation and our cost reduction program.</p>
          <p>Revenues in equities declined 26% year-on-year in Swiss francs and 21% in U.S. dollars. Cash, derivatives and equity-linked revenues were all affected by a significant reduction in volumes and client activity in all regions. In cash, we held up market share despite a decline in revenues. Trading revenues were difficult to generate, although we did see a strong performance in Asia-Pacific. Prime Services had another solid quarter with improved revenues, particularly in the clearing business.</p>
          <p>Other equities revenues were $65 million, driven primarily by proprietary trading revenues. We're planning to exit this successful business line, as per our strategy announced on Investor Day, and we're currently exploring ways to realize its value, including as part of Global Asset Management.</p>
          <p>Our overall performance in equities was broadly in line with that of our competitors and we maintained our leading positions in most areas. We remain focused on this business as we build on our strengths, and we aim to grow market share as we leverage the knowledge gained from our experience in building our successful electronic FX platform.</p>
          <p>In fixed income, revenues rebounded from a very weak third quarter when we recorded losses in credit in emerging markets. Year-on-year revenues decreased 13% in Swiss francs, or 8% in U.S. dollars. Combined revenues in Macro, Credit and Emerging Markets increased 36% year-on-year in U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>Our Macro business delivered another strong performance. Revenues more than doubled from the fourth quarter a year ago. Rates revenues increased fourfold, driven by high volatility and our favorable positioning, particularly at the short end.</p>
          <p>In FX, increased volumes on our enhanced electronic trading platform benefited our revenues. Our platform continues to help increase our market share, as we saw volumes in algorithmic trading of spot FX triple since the first quarter of 2011, outpacing general market growth. We believe we've strengthened our top-tier position in FX, as evidenced by client rankings. We also performed well in options and precious metals.</p>
          <p>Our Credit business continued to be impacted by market uncertainties, resulting in reduced client activity and increased illiquidity. This is also one of the areas where we actively reduced our trading-risk exposures. We recorded lower mark-to-mark losses than in the third quarter, but higher than a year ago. We saw positive contributions from Structured Credit, Leveraged Capital Markets and Corporate Lending.</p>
          <p>Emerging Markets revenues were stable year-on-year. We saw good results in Credit and Structured Products in the Latin America region and also in Foreign Exchange in Europe and in Asia. We reported negative revenues of approximately CHF450 million in other FICC. This included a loss of CHF160 million on our residual risk positions, mostly due to increased credit valuation adjustments on tightening credit spreads on monoline CDS hedges. Also, we recorded a negative debit valuation adjustment on derivatives of almost CHF200 million. Commodities revenues increased versus the prior year.</p>
          <p>IBD revenues before risk management charges were $574 million this quarter. Low market activity levels globally continued from the third into the fourth quarter and were significantly lower than a year ago. Led by strong performances in Asia and the Americas, our Advisory business performed well, with slightly increased revenues year-on-year in an environment where the overall fee pool declined. This performance was supported by our private funds group revenues, which increased significantly. These revenues are not captured in Dealogic market share calculations. Notable transactions in the quarter included our advisory role for Peabody Energy's acquisition of Macarthur Coal and advising Suramericana on its purchase of ING Latin America's pension fund asset.</p>
          <p>Capital markets revenues declined due to very low levels of activity. Equity capital markets revenues roughly declined in line with the overall fee pool, as we participated in 7 out of the top 20 deals. In addition to low volumes in general, fixed income capital markets revenues were impacted by our selective participation in leverage-financed deals. We believe the fee pool will be driven by the macro environment in the near term and we feel that we are well-positioned for when the markets fully open and confidence returns.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Global Asset Management. Profitability improved nearly 50%, to CHF118 million compared with the third quarter. Revenues improved 16% on higher net management fees, driven by improved market valuations and currency effects, as well as incremental revenues from the acquisition of ING Investment Management's business in Australia. Performance fees were CHF15 million higher, primarily in alternative and quantitative investments, which recovered well following a difficult third quarter.</p>
          <p>Nearly CHF18 billion of funds in A&amp;Q, out of a total of CHF26 billion which are eligible for performance fees, were within 5% of their high-water marks at the end of the year. Under more normalized market conditions, we believe there is scope for an increase in performance fees in this business. Operating expenses were 7% higher, mostly due to higher personnel expenses on the division's improved performance and the ING acquisition.</p>
          <p>Gross margin improved to 34 basis points from 30 basis points due to the higher performance fees I mentioned. Net new money inflows from third parties, excluding money markets, were CHF300 million compared to CHF1.5 billion in the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Also excluding money markets, total net new money outflows of CHF800 million were recorded from clients of our Wealth Management businesses. Outflows were partially offset by CHF2.9 billion of net new money related to the transfer of investment responsibility for private equity fund-to-fund assets from WM&amp;SB which are now recorded as invested assets in both business divisions.</p>
          <p>Retail &amp; Corporate had a resilient performance considering the operating environment. Excluding the CHF289 million gain from the sale of our strategic investment portfolio in the third quarter and restructuring charges in both quarters, the pre-tax profit remained stable. Operating income in the quarter held up on an adjusted basis, as lower credit loss expenses offset the decline in revenues due to compression in our interest margin. Operating expenses remained stable when adjusted for restructuring charges.</p>
          <p>Deposits grew in the quarter to CHF118 billion, while loans declined to CHF135 billion. Our interest margin fell 8 basis points, driven by the absence of revenues related to the strategic investment portfolio as well as lower rates on our replication portfolio, due to the persistently low interest rate environment.</p>
          <p>Now that I've covered all of our business divisions, I'd like to spend some time on costs for the group. Group operating expenses were down slightly in the quarter, due to lower restructuring charges. Excluding restructuring charges, non-personnel expenses rose 22%, mainly due to the CHF109 million expense for the UK Bank levy, higher professional fees and currency effects.</p>
          <p>Excluding restructuring charges, personnel expenses remained flat, as the reduction in variable compensation expenses was offset by currency effects. Year-over-year, costs were down over CHF2 billion, aided by the strengthening Swiss franc, lower personnel expenses due to lower accruals for variable compensation and our cost savings program. As can be seen from this chart, all of our main operating expense lines were lower in 2011, except for amortization of prior year awards, which increased slightly.</p>
          <p>The bonus pool for 2011 was CHF2.6 billion, which is a 40% decrease from 2010. Most of the decline was in the Investment Bank, which saw a reduction of approximately 60%. The IFRS bonus expense for the performance year 2011 was CHF1.8 billion. This excludes approximately CHF700 million of deferred awards for 2011 which will be recognized in the future. Adding the bonus expense for 2011 to CHF1.6 billion of amortization for prior-year awards, we arrive at the 2011 IFRS expense of CHF3.4 billion, which is 17% lower than 2010. It highlights the challenge of reducing current year total variable compensation expenses.</p>
          <p>As of the year-end, the total amount of deferred compensation to be amortized in 2012 and later years was CHF1.7 billion. Furthermore, we intend to grant special plan awards to selected personnel in key areas of strategic focus in the Investment Bank. These awards will be share-based, vest after three years and contain even stricter forfeiture conditions upon departure than existing equity plans.</p>
          <p>Including these awards, the total deferred compensation to be amortized in the future is CHF2 billion, compared with CHF2.8 billion at the end of 2010. We reduced the amount of amortization of deferred awards by CHF0.5 billion, from 2011's CHF1.6 billion to CHF1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>We had a higher-than-normal tax rate in the quarter and recorded a tax expense of CHF189 million, of which CHF105 million are related to taxable profits. We recorded a tax expense of CHF99 million with respect to the amortization of previously-recognized DTAs in Switzerland. We also recorded a tax expense of CHF41 million in the quarter, following a reduction of the corporate tax rate and changes to loss offset rules in Japan, which led to a remeasurement of our DTAs in that country.</p>
          <p>As you'll recall, we had a number of adjustments due to the annual DTA remeasurement we conducted in the third quarter. We had already booked the majority of these adjustments in the third quarter and the remaining CHF56 million net benefit was booked this quarter. For 2012, we expect an effective tax rate in the range of 20% to 25%, excluding any potential effects from the annual DTA remeasurement process in the second half of 2012.</p>
          <p>This slide shows a summary of our exposure to sovereign, local governments, bank and other counterparties in Eurozone countries rated lower than AAA by at least one major rating agency, including France and Austria, which were downgraded in January. Our exposure to Italy increased slightly from the prior quarter, mainly due to the UniCredit rights issue underwriting, where we acted as a joint book runner. This transaction has been successfully completed. Our exposure to Spain also increased slightly from the prior quarter. This was mainly due to a more conservative representation of the risk for certain collateralized loans for the purpose of country reporting.</p>
          <p>With respect to France, regardless of the change in its credit rating, we're not concerned about our exposure, given the strength and scale of its economy and the quality of our corporate client base. Overall, the vast majority of our exposure in all these countries are in traded products and tradable assets, which are carried at fair market value. Our disclosures reflect our ongoing and careful monitoring of country-risk exposures and we hope you find the expanded information we have provided to be useful. Additional details can be found in our Quarterly Report starting on page 42.</p>
          <p>As a result of both increased capital and reduced RWAs, our Basel 2.5 Tier 1 ratio improved nearly 300 basis points, to 16% at the end of the year, with our core Tier 1 ratio at 14.1%. On the right-hand side of this slide, as we showed you at Investor Day, you'll see updated pro-forma Basel 3 common equity Tier 1 ratio estimates, both on a phased-in basis and also as if the Basel 3 rules of 2019 were fully applied today.</p>
          <p>Under the phased-in scenario, we would have finished the year with a ratio of approximately 10.8%, already above the regulatory minimum requirement of 10% in Switzerland and advancing towards our own targeted level of 13%. This ratio also highlights our strong capital and competitive positioning. In line with the plans we presented at Investor Day, in the near term, we'll begin our program to fill the gap of up to 6% of the 19% Swiss total capital ratio requirement by issuing a form of low-trigger, loss-absorbing capital.</p>
          <p>In summary, we reported a net profit of CHF400 million in the fourth quarter. While it was a modest result in a very challenging quarter, there were several bright spots, including the continued positive net new money from our Wealth Management businesses, Retail &amp; Corporate's resilient performance and Global Asset Management's improved profitability.</p>
          <p>And our Investment Bank, Macro, Advisory and Prime Services performed well. We made good progress on the execution of the strategy we announced at our Investor Day, as we reduced RWAs significantly with limited P&amp;L impact. Our cost reduction program is on track and we remain vigilant on cost. Our capital liquidity and funding positions are sound and we remain one of the best capitalized banks in the world.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And Sergio and I will now take questions from analysts, first on the phone and then in the room, before moving on to journalists.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>First question from the phone from Mr. Huw van Steenis, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks a lot. I'm just interested to probe a little bit further on your risk-weighted asset reduction program. Obviously, you've refined your thinking over the last three months. You've been able to take down the longer term target and move faster. Do you think there's further potential for you to move faster and further and that maybe in six months' time we might have an even lower target?</p>
          <p>And then related to that, number two. As Sergio, as you think about the potential for dividends, at what point do you feel comfortable to make a material increase in dividends? Do you think it could be potentially within the schedule this year or it's more likely to be the next year or beyond that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I think that when we look at our risk reduction program, it's clearly highlighting our determination to progress and take any opportunities. Having said that, it would be extremely dangerous to extrapolate the work we have been doing in the last quarter into the foreseeable future. So we keep our confidence in our ability to execute our plan. I think it's premature to talk about an acceleration of this because as you know, market condition and economic consideration are factors that we need to take in consideration.</p>
          <p>In respect to dividend, again it's premature to talk about that. If we are able to make progress, we will review our policy. But as we stand, it's premature. I think that's again, we want to highlight our determination about restating our policy of dividend, returning capital to shareholders, but it's absolutely premature to talk about changes on what we announced in November.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Kian Abouhossein, JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Few questions, first of all, on restructuring. To me, it looks like based on slide six, you only have another CHF17 billion of risk-weighted asset reduction to come and on cost cutting. So I'm just trying to see, should we assume that the CHF45 billion could be actually much larger in terms of risk-weighted asset reduction already in 2012?</p>
          <p>The second question is on cost cutting. Your CHF2 billion target as of August 23, I would like to get an update on how much you have achieved already because it looks like you have already roughly 30% of the staff targets have been reduced.</p>
          <p>And then if I also may, a question on top-line growth. You're very cautious in your outlook statement for the first quarter. I'm just trying to understand how we should read this, considering the 91 basis point top-line margin because, clearly normally, it's always the weakest quarter and should we see it that way?</p>
          <p>And lastly, if I may, the boring old tax rate question, 20% to 25%. I recall we've been more like guided towards 17% because you use deferred tax assets. I know that you might make an adjustment later, but just try to understand how we should think about our models here. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Kian. I'll take I guess the first, second and fourth, and Sergio indicated he'd like to answer the third one.</p>
          <p>On the restructuring, taking a look I think on the risk-weighted asset reduction in the legacy portfolio that you were pointing out, again we made good progress in the quarter on the reduction that we made. However as Sergio said, we wouldn't straight-line that success of the past quarter going forward, and we're not thinking of changing the targets at this point in time. However, to the extent that we can get ahead of our plans, we will certainly do so and we remain focused on RWA reduction primarily.</p>
          <p>And second, in terms of the cost-cutting program as you noted, we did have &#x2013; we did start to see the reduction in the head count, the notifications that we made earlier in the year actually coming through as staff left the rolls at the end of the year. The CHF2 billion target was by 2013 on our run rate, a substantial portion of which should be seen and recognized in 2012.</p>
          <p>Finally, on the tax rate question, you're correct. We had guided around 17%. Our tax rate for the year 2011 was 17.5%. At this point in time, we believe the best guidance to give looking forward is 20% to 25%, with our usual caveat about the DTA remeasurement in the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to follow-up on that, the CHF2 billion, can you give us an idea of how much has been realized as a run rate so far of the CHF2 billion cost savings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We should start to see in excess of 15%, sorry, 50% as we start the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>From January 1, as a run rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and if I look at the tax rate, when you say remit, you mean how much profits you make in the U.S. and then you decide how much you can use? You have a better idea in the second half? Or you mean, the change the way you calculate deferred tax assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the remeasurement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we've indicated in the past, yes, the remeasurement has to do with each year when we do our five-year strategic planning process, we use the results of that five-year strategic plan to calculate the valuation on the DTA going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you just remind me, at the Investor Day you indicated that I think you took a 30% haircut to a number. I can't remember what the base was on the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in the discussion we had on DTAs at Investor Day, we had described a previous method we had used, to use the haircut methodology, of 50% on the revenues of the IB in the Americas and 25% on the Wealth Management business in the Americas. Our methodology now is less rules-based and is more subjective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll take the question on top line. Of course, market conditions in the fourth quarter were extremely negative in terms of client risk appetite. As we enter into the year, I think that we have to be very realistic about the environment that is surrounding the world, major economies and particularly what's going on in Europe. We are taking a very cautious stance on this. We are advising clients to be cautious. And that's the reason why you see that outlook.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, to clearly, as we look into the best way to manage our business, we remain very focused on our cost base. We remain very focused on our balance sheet and capital position to offset and to drive us through this period. So I suspect risk appetite by clients, not only private clients, but also institutional clients and corporates about any kind of activity will remain quite volatile and uncertain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the comments that you make are nothing to UBS specific. They are industry trends. Is that fair to say? You don't think that you're seeing anything else that other players shouldn't be seeing, either on Wealth Management or Investment Banking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't see any characteristic of our client base being less keen to take risk than any other industry player.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mrs. Fiona Swaffield from Royal Bank of Canada. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Could we go through the gross margin outlook? Because, obviously, you've got a target of improving gross margin and you're talking about the base being 96, but I think that's going to include some of the income from the treasury portfolio maybe in Q1 to Q3. So I wonder if you could talk about what you think in terms of the moving parts from repricing and lending for 2012. And also in terms of the Swiss outflows, could you just &#x2013; I think you talked about consumption, but that outflow looked a bit bigger than normal. I don't know if you could just revisit that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we mentioned on margin, we have a target of 95 basis points to 105 basis points. If you look at 95 basis points being the low range &#x2013; the lower end of the range in particularly difficult market conditions. So we try to close this gap by clearly broadening our offering base by, where appropriate, repricing for services. But, clearly, as we &#x2013; as I just mentioned before to your colleagues, there is limited capabilities to &#x2013; we don't want to push clients to do unnecessary activity if we think that they have to stay prudent and conservative in their environments.</p>
          <p>We are confident we can rebuild that gap between the 91 basis points and the 95 basis points in the foreseeable future and actually drive us toward the mid-range. But, as we said before, the situation remains very, very challenging in terms of market condition. Tom, I don't know if you want to expand on this CHF1.8 billion outflows?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Fiona. How we had characterized that, we believe that that CHF1.8 billion outflow is mostly the result of seasonally higher consumption in the fourth quarter around the holiday periods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe we can underline that despite all this, as I mentioned in my remarks before, the assets that were coming into our Retail &amp; Corporate business have achieved a number that was equal to 2007. So I think that this is a remarkable improvement compared to where the bank stood a couple of years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Jon Peace, Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, morning. I had two questions, please, around capital. The first one is on market risk-weighted assets, did you see some particularly strong seasonality in Q4 as clients' activity declined and should we anticipate a sort of bounce-back, a bit of a normalization, in the first quarter as activity hopefully recovers?</p>
          <p>And the second question is about your plan to issue loss-absorbing capital. Can you give us some ideas around how much you plan to issue and what you think the cost of that might be? Or in particular, the incremental costs net of any other hybrids you might be able to retire? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'll take the first question and I'll let Tom take the second. Clearly, the Q4 risk-weighted values, it was very low, reflecting a lack of activity. We do expect a little bit of a bounce-back but, as we mentioned before, as we change our business model in a more client-driven, client facilitation business model, we don't expect a big increase of this number going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon, the question was &#x2013; excuse me, a question on loss-absorbing capital. As I mentioned, in the near future, we will commence our program of issuance on non-dilutive loss-absorbing capital. I would say, for a first transaction, it's most likely that we'd be considering a dollar-denominated issue, a size in excess of CHF1 billion. And, as far as the other terms and conditions, we will soon sound out our perspective co-lead managers as well as investors on the structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Derek De Vries, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I have three questions, two sort of detailed questions and one bigger picture. First of all, on the slide 24 where you give us the deferred or awarded but not expensed compensation and you show how the CHF2.8 billion has fallen to CHF2 billion. I think in the Annual Report last year you also gave us the awarded but not expensed compensation for the Wealth Management business. I think that was actually a bigger number than the CHF2.8 billion. I think it was about CHF3.5 billion. So I was wondering if you could give us a comparable number for the Wealth Management, the comparable number to the CHF3.5 billion last year? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question in Wealth Management, you talked about several large inflows in the quarter, and I'm wondering if these were wealth creation events, or were you taking business from a competitor and, just also, is it fair to assume that they were in Asia?</p>
          <p>And then the last question is on the outlook. You had a very cautious outlook statement, and I'm just wondering &#x2013; I mean, that's a very different tone than some of the investment banks in the U.S. and even Deutsche Bank have been sort of ringing. So I was wondering is that driven by risk appetite amongst your retail clients and your January in Investment Bank was sort of in line or slightly worse than last year, or is that across the board that you're being cautious?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I start taking your last question. I think that our statement is a realistic assessment of the situation nowadays and I think that we have to manage that reality instead of trying to pretend that things are going to improve. And if things improve, we are totally prepared to take advantage of the situation, but our modus operandi right now is stay focused on the current environment and what we know and not what we hope for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think the investment banks were suggesting that their January was slightly below January of last year. Is that a different result than you've seen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not making comments beyond the outlook that we reported on our January or quarterly numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but you're not suggesting that they're lying, certainly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not suggesting that they are lying, for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But, Derek, going back to your question, you were asking about the compensation advanced balances related to the recruiting of financial advisers in Wealth Management Americas. That balance remains at approximately &#x2013; or slightly higher than the number you mentioned, the CHF3.5 billion. It's at CHF3.6 billion at year end. And, as you may know, those advanced balances come with nine-year service requirements. Your second question, I don't know if I exactly got that one, could you repeat that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think in the text on wealth management it talks about your inflows in the quarter and talks about several large inflows. And I guess they were noteworthy since you sort of wrote them down. I was just wondering was that like a wealth creation event or was that you taking business from a competitor? And then, given the reporting you had, is it fair to assume that those inflows come from Asia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first, the overall general comment we did say during the quarter, good inflows, Asia, EM and ultra-high net worth globally, specifically in the comments that we made, that's a taking share rather than a wealth creation event item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Kinner Lakhani, Citigroup. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, that's fine. So I have a few questions on the Investment Bank. Your Macro business, in particular, appears to be much stronger in the second half as opposed to first half of last year, which seems to be different to the trends we've seen across the industry. So I'm wondering if there was anything special going on in the first half of last year.</p>
          <p>Second question on the Investment Bank again. Clearly, the value of risk has been brought down, market risk, RWAs, have been brought down. To what extent is this sustainable? Was this just de-risking towards the end of the year? So should we expect a rebound at the beginning of the year, as maybe one of your peers has suggested?</p>
          <p>And, finally, just on the amortization of prior year awards, the CHF2 billion number, I might have missed this, but just wanted to figure out what part of that CHF2 billion you expect to be expensed in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Kinner, why don't I take one and three? I think Sergio wants to comment on the second one. In terms of your question on the amortization, out of the CHF2 billion, we expect to amortize CHF1.1 billion in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's CHF0.5 billion reduction versus the expense that we have for amortization in 2011. Going back to your question on Macro, I think that we've had a stronger performance, certainly in the second half of the year, as you mentioned. We've seen, in particular, in the FX side of the business, our e-trading platform's success has increased each quarter as we've moved throughout the year. So that's something that we see as a positive. And then I'd say we did have good positioning in both short and long-term rates in this past quarter. So I think it's more about how we've been able to manage the business in an improving fashion over the course of the last two quarters than anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As for VaR usage, clearly as I mentioned before, Q4 cannot be a reference point. We do see we have room to increase our VaR usage, but it's not going to be on a major increase. As I mentioned before, we are changing our service model. We may need to take more risk, no problem with that. Actually, I don't think that's the real issue. But it's not going to be a substantial change in the number.</p>
          <p>So now, maybe before we move on to the next question, I would like to ask any analysts here in the room if they have any question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Kilian Maier, MainFirst. Just a question on the accounting changes for pensions. You mentioned several effects, positive and negative. What will be the net impact on your regulatory capital of IAS 19 and if you have pension accounting changes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you for that question. I think your &#x2013; is your question in reference to the announcement we made on the Swiss pension fund today? The effect of that is an increase of CHF1.5 billion in the deferred pension expenses. And then in 2012, there's a benefit to income that offsets that increased liability of the CHF1.5 billion, of CHF485 million, roughly CHF485 million. And then there's also a potential benefit that also shows in equity of CHF250 million during the course of the year. For the total IAS 19, we're due to update our disclosures with the Annual Report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, any other questions from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Teresa Nielsen from Bank Vontobel. There has been European Central Bank liquidity increase in December LTROs. Have you seen any impact on your business from this liquidity increase and do you expect there to be any impact from the February liquidity also from the European Central Bank's LTROs? Is there any impact because you're a Swiss Bank, so I suppose you don't have direct access, but what you believe is the impact of these measures by the European Central Bank for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well actually, I think the LTRO was a very successful operation, and that was instrumental in taking down the tension in interbank and the funding markets. I think so we see that as a result, implied result, that clearly some of the banks that were under severe stress in order to streamline very quickly their liquidity and funding position have now been able to come back and to on a selective basis be, gain competitive in other areas of the business.</p>
          <p>I do expect the February auction to reinforce the strength, although at the end of the day, the fundamental long-term funding and issues of some of the banks in Europe is not really changing. As for UBS, we do have access through our subsidiaries and affiliates in Europe. We are not using the LTRO, but we have access if we want. But we don't think this is necessary for us because our funding position and financial position doesn't require us to access that probably.</p>
          <p>Now, if I may move to the next one on the phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Christopher Wheeler, Mediobanca. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, everybody. A few questions. First of all, obviously some good trends in investment banking revenues, but the thing that stuck out obviously was DCM. I think if we look at your big competitors, they probably saw DCM I think up about 15% in the quarter, and you fell 18%. Tom touched on the leverage loans, but is this something we should see as an ongoing trend, given obviously that you are derisking the fixed income business as you laid out on the Investor Day? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>Second one the equity prop. I think you said most of the CHF59 million in other equity revenues in Q4 were down to equity prop. Can you give us a flavor for what the number was for the year, given that you are obviously talking about how you're going to move this business, and perhaps tell us what would the obstacles be to putting it into Global Asset Management department, John Fraser? And if you can't put it there, what will you do with it?</p>
          <p>And then the other couple of quick questions is you did give us very clear guidance that the tax charge for the second half would be close to zero, and it's about CHF150 million. Was that just not being able to use the DTAs which led to that?</p>
          <p>And then finally, I think the CHF11 billion reduction in the student loans, obviously which is really pleasing, I think Carsten sort of insinuated this was going to be a single transaction. Can you give us any flavor on that? That would be very helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I take the first question on DCM. As you rightly point out, there has been a little bit of an anomaly. We have being very selective particularly in the areas of the LBO, where we are more than happy to exchange market share and fee base for yield mark-to-market losses on the inventory and on the syndicate positions.</p>
          <p>I do think that this should not be an indication of our strategy to dramatically reduce this segment of the business. This is a very important segment for us to stay focused on client needs and refinancing and playing the role of intermediation between corporates and capital market. So I don't think this quarter can be taken as a proxy of our change in strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Chris, on the questions on the equity prop, the entire result in the other equities revenues of CHF65 million is due to equities prop, and that is a reasonable estimate of the level of production of the business over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>On the tax rate, on a lower pre-tax base, obviously some of the swings that we had had a larger percentage effect. The change in the Japanese corporate tax rate was clearly something that was unanticipated. But we took the same portion of the benefit from the DTA revaluation that we did in the third quarter in the fourth quarter that we had anticipated. So there's nothing extraordinary that went on there.</p>
          <p>Finally, your question on the reduction of the RWAs in the legacy portfolio, specifically, the student loan transaction, that was a sale of $1.4 billion in a single transaction. I think the transaction highlights some of the comments that we've been making about why we think this isn't a trade that's crowded out, why we're all attempting to do the same things at the same time. That transaction was one where we were working on that in negotiations for a period of 9 months to 12 months.</p>
          <p>And so, I think as we're speaking today and we talk about the rest of that legacy portfolio, there are a number of items in there where we're working with potential parties to a transaction with us. And depending on the environment, it is a diversified portfolio, we may decide to accelerate or pause a bit, depending on our views about the success of completing the transaction on terms with which we're comfortable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just in terms of the prop desk, I did ask whether or not &#x2013; what the timing was, what would stop you from moving the prop desk to Global Asset Management and what other options you had?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, sorry. So obviously, we'd like to keep that within the UBS group. We think there would be some good advantages for our clients to have access to our capabilities in the way that we believe we can manage money on an equity prop basis. So at this point in time, our main focus is on integration with Global AM.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what timing is that, is that this year, obviously?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's within the coming quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Any other questions from analysts here in the room? It doesn't look to be the case. Therefore, I think we can close the broadcast. We will continue on the phone and here with media. So many thanks for attending the broadcast, and we'll see you in early May for the first quarter results. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This year, will the actual program to reduce cost be sufficient to get that number down? And if not, what are the actions that you are preparing? You said that strategical cost reduction efforts were limited, now that you're considering technical ones. Could you be a little bit more precise on that? For example, does that mean that you could raise the number of staff you would reduce? First question.</p>
          <p>Second question concerning the risk-weighted assets, you said that the decreasing of that number just had a limited impact on the profit-and-loss numbers. Could we have the number of how much &#x2013; what extent were the costs on that, because this is the question, how much of it cost to reduce risk-weighted assets in such dimensions? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think, as we announced, our target for the group in terms of cost-income ratio will be in the range of 65% to 75%. Of course, we are very focused on understanding the nature of the top-line developments. We think that this is a temporary situation. If we get signs that the Q4 environment is likely to become more of a secular change, of course, we're going to need to tackle, first of all, cost by addressing general and admin expenses issues, compensation issues, maybe staffing issues, anything that we can do from a tactical standpoint of view to react to this situation.</p>
          <p>But most importantly, we will go through the process &#x2013; we are going through the process of understanding how can we fundamentally change the cost base of our organization regardless of top-line developments. So in a structural way, to create a capacity to face headwinds in this situation, but also if it's not the case, to create a competitive advantage and value for our shareholders. So it's going to be a combination.</p>
          <p>I don't think we can rush into conclusion right now being just &#x2013; not even in the first part of February, about tackling the situation. We want to assess the situation. We are confident in our CHF2 billion cost measure containment program is well on track. But as I said, we will not be afraid to tackle these cost issues proactively if we see a major change in terms of trends in the industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the question on the risk-weighted asset expense. Yes, it's really immaterial, plus or minus CHF50 million on the total reduction for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:18:43) from Reuters. First question, just to get it right, you said CHF1.2 billion was outflow in Switzerland. Did I get that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CHF1.8 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One point, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CHF1.8 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>CHF1.8 billion. Second question, could you give us a bit of flavor or information on cross-border Europe, Wealth Management and the cross-border business with Europe, outflows or the money coming?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in terms of our cross-border and overall business, I think we are seeing still inflows of money, I think also onshore. Clearly, I think clients are starting to realize the strength of the bank in terms of capital position, in terms of competitive position. I think the appreciation of the Swiss-ness of the group is clearly helping us to attract inflows of both onshore and offshore. So clearly we are leveraging this capital position and strength in terms of European cross-border businesses.</p>
          <p>And the first question? Any questions from the phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no questions from the telephone conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And so we can go on here on the room, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:20:11). Could you just elaborate a little bit on the argument we have heard from your predecessors that sharp bonus cuts are not possible with the ambition to retain the best people in the bank? From what you're doing now, I have the impression that this argument is no longer so valid as it seemed to be one or two years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to go through debate in public with my predecessors on how to assess the industry. I think that basically profitability in the industry will dictate our ability and the ability of the industry to pay for compensation. I don't see how compensation should stay the same or go up if the profitability of the bank or the industry goes up. So it's very simple.</p>
          <p>We may have to take that risk. We are trying to strive to a situation in which both shareholders and employee can have a win-win situation over time. So if we lose people, I think I know we have a lot of people who are very focused and loyal to the bank and are here and think about compensation over a cycle rather than over one-off year. These people think that they should be always make whole of anything that happen out there. I have to be very honest that I think this is not something that I think fits into how the bank should be run and in any case how the environment is developing. So it's not a realistic expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to come back to the overall picture for the sector. So I mean, you resented in a way to be called negative or have a negative outlook, but you certainly are cautious. I mean, what's your main worry, so to say? Do you think the Eurozone crisis, was that the main factor behind that the Eurozone crisis is almost here to stay, or it will take quite some time or quite long to get to a higher level to get to improve it somehow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well look, I don't know. I think it's maybe a subjective situation. I didn't want this, our outlook, to be called negative. I think that I like to call it a realistic assessment of the situation. We all agree that what's going on in Europe is clearly a modeling through phase which creates uncertainty. And you know that what human being hates the most is uncertainty. And clearly, investors and clients are affected by that. So I think that I'm not so concerned about the problems and the issues we know. Personally, I think that social tensions and escalations on that front may be the surprise, not necessarily the fact that maybe a country needs to go through a restructuring and actions needs to be taken, and you will have a downturn in the economy, but rather what is unexpected. So clearly, it's a realistic assessment of the situation. I think that as we work through all these problems, maybe the situation improves. That, I would say, is our approach. There was a question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:24:22). I have two questions. One, the cost side, you say it may come to the end of tax interventions and strategical methods. Could that mean the end of the one-bank concept if you talk about strategic cost measures?</p>
          <p>And the second question is about Adoboli. What is the main takeaway from your internal investigation? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think that being at the end of our &#x2013; almost at the end of our tactical &#x2013; our flexibility in order to address the costs in a tactical way means a major change necessarily of our business model. I think that as I mentioned before, that's the reason why we are already thinking about how to create the next buffer. In a more structural way, industrialized processes share best practices within the organization and learn from other industries that have been able to tackle this issue of reducing the cost base regardless of what's going on on the top line.</p>
          <p>I don't think that, clearly, we cannot respond to tension on our top line simply by saying we should sell or exit or lose some things. We are in a job to address the problems and fix the problems, not to get rid of problems or buy some things to fix a problem. That's what we are focused on.</p>
          <p>On Adoboli, our wish was clearly to try to be more transparent and talk about what happened. Unfortunately, as you know, the investigations and the criminal proceedings are still open. So our ability to talk about this issue is absolutely limited by this. So we will not go into any discussion and points other than saying that we have identified the issues internally that may have created some of these issues and we addressed them and we are proactive in tackling all the situation. We are cooperating with any further investigation that goes on. So we feel comfortable that the situation is under control, but unfortunately talking about it is not something that we can do in public. Okay, over there, the lady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have another question. This is Katharina Bart at Reuters. I had a question about compensation, specifically in the investment bank, which is going to go down 60%. And I wanted to ask actually you a personal question whether you had thought about your own compensation for 2011 or whether maybe the leadership at the investment bank had thought about their own compensation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought about my compensation but somebody else will address it. So it's not up to me to talk here. In respect of the investment bank, Carsten Kengeter approached me late September, early October, to tell me that no matter what the board will decide going forward about his compensation, he would forfeit any rights or any award that we may or may not grant to him. So he took a proactive stance in saying that he thought that after what happened, he should not be eligible for any compensation. So we accepted his decision and that's what happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:28:32). I have a question on page 17 about M&amp;A. Do you see for this year a better result in M&amp;A blockbuster deals or normally, in general, you can see more of them at the end of the year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have a good pipeline and actually the pipeline was also good in Q4. The difference between having a pipeline and executing a pipeline is the market environment. The market environment is still very volatile and, clearly, that may put some pressure. So I think that our confidence level on our ability is to create &#x2013; originate pipeline, is there. The execution is more dependent on external factors that we cannot necessarily control.</p>
          <p>Actually, one of the issues that is also not really reflected in these statistics is the fact that last year we have been having a bigger share of defense mandates that are not part of &#x2013; if they are successful, they are not part of the league table, for example. That's also a dynamic that we need always to take in consideration, balance between reported market share versus fee-based business that is also M&amp;A-related but is not counting in the league tables.</p>
          <p>There was a question up there. Yes, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:30:10). I have a question regarding the special plan awards you have on page 24. Who will benefit from this new plan and &#x2013; well, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as we pointed out, we have identified areas of the business within the Investment Bank that are core and strategic for our future. And a selective number of people within the Investment Bank that are involved in those areas will be getting these special awards. So it's a selected number of people and it's not across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, there are no more questions. Many thanks for attending and, as I said before, we'll see you in May.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference is now over. Thank you for choosing the Chorus Call facility, and thank you for participating in the conference. You may now disconnect your lines. Goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>