<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1171983" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call - Follow Up</title>
    <date>2008-08-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>631</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Marcel Rohner, Group Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Peter Kurer, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michael Hecht</participant>
      <participant id="5">Marco Suter</participant>
      <participant id="6">Marcel Rohner</participant>
      <participant id="7">Philip Lofts</participant>
      <participant id="8">Marten Hoekstra</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon. This is the Chorus Call conference operator. Welcome and thank you for joining UBS U.S. Earnings Call Second Quarter 2008 Conference Call exclusively for analysts and investors. As a reminder all participants are in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for attending the 2Q results for UBS, the U.S. time zone call. And today we're going to be represented by Peter Kurer, Marcel Rohner and Marco Suter. And I think we're going to start with Marcel providing a short summary of the key points that he went through in results meeting held this morning. Over to you, Marcel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as we have announced and as Peter Kurer has explained this morning, there are really four things we do.</p>
          <p>Before I comment on the result, just a summary, we do reposition the bank to create strategic flexibility; we bring in new people; we change the way we run the firm; and we are on a tight change program over the next 18 months. And these four steps should bring us back to produce reliable profits and to become again a source of dependable value creation.</p>
          <p>The results really have two aspects. It has the positive aspects of problem solving, and it has the disappointing aspect of net new money outflows, and I would like to comment on both parts.</p>
          <p>First, on problem solving, we really addressed a number of substantial issues. One, we have substantially reduced our risk exposure. It came down in the core part of Alt-A and sub-prime from 55 billion at the end year to 13 billion now.</p>
          <p>It's particularly important that you also look at the P&amp;L associated with the various risk buckets. As it highlights, there we have actually found levels of trading and activity and price which allow us to dispose and risk-manage the positions.</p>
          <p>Second, we have strengthened the capital base. It's basically back to where it was prior to the crisis. We have a Tier 1 ratio of 11.6% and are, therefore, one of the best capitalized banks in the world.</p>
          <p>Third, we have resolved the auction rate securities issue, and we have substantially increased the credit valuation adjustments on monoline.</p>
          <p>Fourth, we have reduced the number of staff by nearly 2,400, primarily in the IB about across the group.</p>
          <p>Fifth, when we look at our cost base and we take out the 900 million auction rate securities settlement provision, we are at CHF 7.2 billion quarterly run-rate, which is actually very close to the next year's target run-rate we announced only three months back.</p>
          <p>Last we have reduced the balance sheet by another 150 billion. The nominal reduction from mid last year to now year-on-year is about 460 billion. When we look at the trading asset position, it reduced by more than 600 billion over the years, which we consider very, very relevant to bring us back into a stable position.</p>
          <p>The disappointment is net new money. It should, however, be clearly dissected into its various parts. First of all, the institutional part, Global Asset Management, is clearly very large and disappointing. However, what we can say is that the institutional outflows are actually half. And the other part was driven by the lack of money market inflows, which amounted to 10 billion last time and also some outflows, which are not common effects from the Wealth Management part.</p>
          <p>Looking at the Wealth Management outflows of 17.3 billion, they divide into 8 billion U.S. Wealth Management and 9.3 billion Wealth Management International and Switzerland. The 8 billion in the U.S. is without interest rate and dividends. So the normal market comparison in the United States already includes dividend and interest on the assets, and that brings it to two billion down, which compares favorably to most of the core competitors in this market.</p>
          <p>When we look at the 9.3 billion outflow in Wealth Management International and Switzerland, 5.5 billion are in Switzerland and 3.8 billion, the balance is for Wealth Management International. If we compare it to the asset base, we see that in Switzerland we've lost 2.3% of the asset base. That's where we were hit hardest, and that's where we had a most serious challenge.</p>
          <p>On the 900 billion asset base in Wealth Management International, the outflow amounted actually to just 0.4%, which shows clearly where the problem is. We have occurred most of this in April with an improvement throughout the quarter.</p>
          <p>What we can say, however, is that on the client advisor side, we see an only slightly increased turnover rate. We are essentially flat. Outside the U.S., we have around 11 client advisors. We would usually hire between 150 to 200. We think that this number would have come down in the second quarter generally due to the environment. It might be slightly lower than it would normally be, but it's not a substantial change. So we still hire successfully into our Wealth Management franchise.</p>
          <p>In Wealth Management U.S., the number of financial advisors went slightly down by 129.</p>
          <p>So this basically summarizes the results. When we look at the resilience of the profits, it's high in Global Asset Management, it is high in Wealth Management, the asset base has actually increased a tick. So a small currency move offset &#x2013; more than offsets the losses of assets.</p>
          <p>In the Investment Bank, we see a very strong IBD showing &#x2013; we see a disappointing equity result, but that is driven by the derivatives business, which is where we have a stronger exposure or a stronger business than others in Asia, and that's the one which has been coming back. Very strong results in prime brokerage, very strong results in cash equities.</p>
          <p>In fixed-income, you can back out. If you just add back in the provisions to the fixed income results, you arrive at something like a 600 million result of the fixed income division. What we should say is that this result also carries an extraordinary large liquidity position, which we always have in the challenging market environment, and this obviously has a negative carry, which affects the results.</p>
          <p>So when we take this out and other market-related operations and look at the strong performance of FX rates, short-term interest rates, we actually do believe that we are also gradually coming back outside the legacy position to run-rates as we have seen them about two years ago. So that basically summarizes the results.</p>
          <p>In terms of management and governance changes, the fact is, we have already said at the AGM, and we reiterate that and now translate it into an organizational structure that are no cross subsidies. The business can only prosper, if all these individual parts develop well and deliver shareholder value without explicit or implicit or hidden cross subsidies.</p>
          <p>We also believe that the management can react quick and fast to market developments and manage the plays generally more efficient if they have control over the allocated capital infrastructure and financial resources. That's basically the management perspective.</p>
          <p>We have one departure from the Group Executive Board. Marco Suter has offered or asked for his resignation, which we have accepted. I'm obviously very, very grateful to Marco that he stepped in when I needed him most last year, and I thank him for his outstanding contribution over the years.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased at the same time that I can announce two new additions with Markus Diethelm, the Group Chief Legal Officer of Swiss Re. We have a very strong new General Counsel, who brings very highly relevant experience to the new function, and with John Cryan, who is currently head of our Financial Institutions Group. We have the CFO who will be very instrumental in bringing in his insights and expertise in our task to restore the value of UBS.</p>
          <p>We are going to run the change with a change program. We have asked our current Chairman and CEO of UBS Latin America, Juerg Haller, to run this program. And it consists of seven streams, which address the relevant changes we will go through.</p>
          <p>First, we will look into our incentive system to reward divisional management and staff for the shareholder value their business division is creating.</p>
          <p>Second stream is that we will enhance the funding framework such that the costs and the structure of liabilities of each business division will approximate those of stand-alone competitors, very relevant point of the new positioning.</p>
          <p>We obviously adjusted &#x2013; third, the executive governance structure to reflect all the changes.</p>
          <p>We will develop targets and performance indicators, which are consistent with the business division, as a fourth point.</p>
          <p>Five, we will reduce size and scope of Corporate Center, in line with the re-allocation of some process ownership to the divisions.</p>
          <p>The sixth stream is the review of all the intra-divisional servicing, revenue &#x2013; and revenue sharing and referral arrangements, very relevant that we can establish a clear framework for the collaboration &#x2013; to drive collaboration where it is a realistically dependable source of value creation.</p>
          <p>And seventh, we'll obviously continue with the ongoing strategic cost reduction program.</p>
          <p>That's the summary of our announcement this morning, and I will hand it now over to Peter Kurer with respect to the Board announcements and strategic positioning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marcel. Very briefly before we turn to questions, we announced four additions to the Board. It is first Sally Bott. Sally Bott is presently a member of the Executive Committee of BP and is responsible there for human resources. She has a long-standing career both as a HR manager and before as asset bank manager with a number of financial institutions, in particular for a long time with Citibank.</p>
          <p>Rainer-Marc Frey is the second addition. Rainer-Marc spent the first part of his career with two leading investment banks and learnt more or less the whole offering of investment banks. He then formed his own hedge fund, RMF, which he developed successfully and finally in 2002 sold to Man. He remained with Man for a while and now has set up his own asset management firm again, Horizon21. He will add to the Board in particular risk management capacity and knowledge, as well as general banking strategy, and we envisage to add him to Risk Committee and the Strategy Committee.</p>
          <p>Sally Bott, I forgot to mention this, she will join the HR and Compensation Committee where she can bring in her particular HR knowledge, as well as her deep experience with change projects.</p>
          <p>The third addition is Bruno Gehrig, who looks back on a long career as banker, academic in financial sciences as a regulator and more recently as Chairman of Swiss Life, which is a large Swiss Life insurance company. He will join the Audit Committee.</p>
          <p>And then finally, Bill Parrett, who is an outstanding auditor, who was for many years head and CEO of Touche Deloitte and Tohmatsu; he was CEO there, and he headed their Financial Services Group. So he has also an in-depth knowledge of the financial services industry. He will also join our Audit Committee.</p>
          <p>All-in-all these candidates bring back &#x2013; bring with them a vast experience, but they also have a common denominator that they had extensive exposure to the financial industry and in particular to risk. So I'm very glad that we have these people onboard. They will considerably contribute to the further transformation of the firm.</p>
          <p>I think the second announcement, which we made was on the repositioning of the bank to allow maximum strategic flexibility in its future development. In a nutshell, we separate our business divisions into three autonomous units, invest them with increased operational authority and accountability.</p>
          <p>We will align incentives for management and staff of each of these units directly with its financial results. This obviously will promote profit generation within, however, an appropriate and rigorous risk framework that fully recognizes the risk/reward profile of different activities.</p>
          <p>We will, in particular, continue to invest and develop our Global Wealth Management business, which is our core asset. We think that the new structure will result in more transparency on the sources of value creation. It will also impose strict standards on the availability and usage of capital, reward management for sustainable value creation and will provide maximum strategic flexibility to capture shareholder value in the future.</p>
          <p>We will continue to run all operations under one brand and under one roof, but we will no longer call it a one bank integrated model strategy.</p>
          <p>So this is in a nutshell how we're positioning, and I think with this we probably can turn to questions now. Thank you for listening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Mr. Michael Hecht, Banc of America. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, thanks for taking my question. I just wanted to, I guess, come back, it seems like there is still some confusion over the announcement around the strategic review and kind of splitting out the three businesses as separate units. I guess, on one hand, I guess you guys don't want to signal any kind of specific transactions or divestiture intentions prematurely for obvious reasons. Is it safer to assume that today's announcement kind of opens the door to bringing UBS closer to being able to structurally separate its three business and suggest that this is at least something still being contemplated by management and the Board as a way to unlock value?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you for the question. I think this repositioning basically has two pillars. The first one is more a business orientation, I think as has been described by Marcel and myself. We think that this creates more agility for our respective business groups. This industry is in a very uncertain situation. We do not know how things evolve over the future. We do not know where globalization will go. We do not exactly know what the final end will be for the regulatory environment. And we hope that in this situation, we are better when we have units which are more autonomous and with this more agile to address the upcoming issues.</p>
          <p>The second one is what you have mentioned. Whilst we have no specific plans at this point in time, we want to put ourselves in a situation where in the future we can react quickly and catch opportunities if and when they come up in a way which would allow us to capture shareholder value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fair enough. And then my second question is more about your strategy from here to further reduce risk positions. As you guys said, you've reduced a lot this quarter. But do you foresee more sales like the one to BlackRock, or perhaps if you could talk about the demand you're seeing from different distressed pools of money to buy some of the remaining assets? And then, are you considering structures that might allow UBS to participate in some of the upside, assuming markdowns are appropriate and maybe even have overshot in some cases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to the risk reduction, the most relevant part is when you look at the composition of the P&amp;L, is that there were actually buckets such as the sub-prime which contributed zero to the write-downs &#x2013; to the negative P&amp;L over the quarter. CDOs was down 800 million. The bulk came from the monoline insurer credit valuation adjustment. And that actually explains probably most where these markets are from our perspective. We clearly continue to sell paper, and what you can see is that it's actually possible to do so when we reduced over and above the 15 billion sale to BlackRock. We reduced our position with additional disposals very substantially, and this will continue.</p>
          <p>There might be other one of this type of transaction. Clearly by definition they are now smaller in size because there is less left, but there can be more of them. We also had, as you see in the CDO side, actually quite significant reduction. We had a 4 billion notional, 1 billion market value reduction, almost exactly at our mark, and that's why we feel that we are well on the way there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I just follow up on the monoline exposure, which I mean I agree, you guys have taken significant credit valuation adjustments. Yet at the same time it seems like you still hold your monoline exposure at a higher valuation than when we saw the clearing market prices in like the Merrill transaction, which, worked out to like $0.10 or less on the dollar.</p>
          <p>So given the spread movements for the monolines and issues here, I mean how do we get comfortable with where your marks are today? And should investors use the Merrill transaction as a blueprint for how to think about the ultimate value of your remaining exposures there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think I disagree with the Merrill comparison. On the one hand, we value the underlying pool of assets or the conditions with everything else. And, as I said before, we were trading at our marks. And secondly, the second part concerns the credit valuation adjustment. I think we always have to compare both parts &#x2013; what is actually the underlying quality of the paper and where it's marked and what is the valuation adjustment.</p>
          <p>I'll hand over to our Deputy Chief Risk Officer, Phil Lofts, who is here, who can give you a bit more color on how we see the situation around the monoline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what we've done consistently throughout the quarter is make sure that we use publicly available identified prices in valuing the reserve. So we've used observable CDS imputed from that probability; as the default, we've used observable recovery swaps to obviously the other part of the equation. So the reserves we take are based on public side information, and we've been consistent in that across all our counter parties that we have monoline exposure to.</p>
          <p>Clearly there are a number of ongoing restructuring discussions which have taken place which are private side. We have entered into confidentiality agreements surrounding those. Those obviously may or may not have an impact ultimately on some of the reserves we carry, but that's as much driven by the nature of the underlying exposure that may or may not be subject to commuting under those restructuring agreements.</p>
          <p>So the way in which the reserve increased during Q2 was a direct reflection of market observed price widening for particularly ones like AMBAC, MBIA and FGIC, where spreads widened significantly, particularly for the first two during the month of June.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks, guys, I'll get back in queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> A follow-up from Mr. Michael Hecht, Banc of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, guys. I guess you exhausted everything in the European call. I just had a follow-up on I guess getting a little bit more color on the flow trends on the International Wealth Management side. I mean, obviously the 9 billion in outflows internationally concentrated in Switzerland mostly. I was just hoping to get a little bit more color on the delta that you guys saw across Europe versus the APAC region in the second quarter? I mean, it seems small overall, but I just wanted to see whether you're seeing more in Europe versus the Asia-Pacific, where maybe it's holding up better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the one thing I can say &#x2013; we obviously don't break it further down in all precisions into the composition. But what we can say is that actually the &#x2013; let me put it that way, the faster growing regions are those where we actually have positive numbers on Wealth Management <mark type="inaudible" />, obviously underneath the bad message is a good message.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just to follow up on the commentary you made on the fixed-income business or FICC. I mean the run rate I guess excluding marks and some of the other things you mentioned around 600 million, and that I mean I guess as we kind of get through a number of the near-term kind of cyclical challenges, you expect to go back to a level of just a couple of years ago, which I think would put it at around 8 billion or something like that. The way I was kind of thinking about it was that because securitization and some of the structured product areas are likely to remain diminished probably for some time that we might actually go back to some level pre that, closer to the maybe 2001, 2002 kind of timeframe. I'm just trying to clarify what's the run rate we should think of for FICC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the very relevant point first is the Swiss dollar exchange rate. That has given rise to a lot of confusion. It was at 1.70 or something like that like three years ago or 1.50, and it's now at 1.05, and that is a big translation. I think we should always basically refer to it, if we make a historical comparison, in dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And what we actually have seen and what we referred to is the dollar run-rate we had two, two and a half years ago of around 13, $1,400. That's what we basically saw, and we believe it is realistic to assume that we can get back to that run rate. We have said that actually at the last quarter's earnings call already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I remember. I just wanted to make sure nothing has changed. Okay. And then on the equities business, I guess a similar question in FICC, the 21% decline quarter-over-quarter, 42% decline year-over-year. That's certainly not the worst that we've seen out there, but it seems like it stacks up versus the low end of the peers. And it's a little bit tough to understand. It just seems like you guys talked about decent results in cash and prime brokerage, and I think even better results in prop versus a year ago, so really mostly on just weak derivatives results. I guess just a little more color on what was the driver of the weakness in the quarter? I mean more of the flow business or on the exotic side, or what was really the driver there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's more on the flow business. And, as we have said, the activities in Asia have slowed down quite substantially, and there were also on the year-on-year comparison some one-off items included, which have further I would say inflated the last year's results. So clearly below our expectations, but we do feel that there is room for recovery back to more normal run rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just the last question more on the U.S. Wealth Management side, the decrease, the 129 reduction in brokers you mentioned. I mean is that just &#x2013; obviously it's a combination probably of a pickup, but I'm just trying to get a little more color on the pickup in attrition versus are you guys just kind of slowing down your recruiting and kind of what you're willing to pay out there? Just any sense of a change in the underlying dynamic or demand for brokers in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have Marten Hoekstra on the call, the head of Wealth Management U.S. who is the perfect man to answer this question and give you more color and also to put the Wealth Management U.S. results into context. Marten, can I hand over to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is my line coming through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Marten. How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thanks. Yeah, essentially the negative 129 reflects underneath a positive net flow on producers who generate over $1 million in revenue and a negative flow of greater than 129 on people under 250,000 in revenue. So, when you put all the mechanics together, what it amounts to is people at the high-end of the range continue to join &#x2013; we've had some washouts at the low end. And I think on the private wealth initiative in particular, now that we have nine private wealth offices open, we feel pretty good about our ability to add at the upper end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks a lot. Just last question, trying to understand I guess a little bit more the allocated capital or the equity attribution framework you guys have after allocating capital to each of your segments. It left you an average equity capital deficit of 16.7 billion in the second quarter. I guess that was down from around 22 billion. Is the way to think about this basically the amount of capital required at the group level if each of your segments was to be adequately capitalized on an independent level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marco?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Marco Suter speaking. First of all, when you look at the chart, keep in mind that what we show is average equity and not quarter-end equity, and obviously, the average equity we had there was still suffering from our low points in the equity at March. So, by now the equity we allocated, the equity we had is roughly the same.</p>
          <p>The way we allocate equity to the business group is we are looking at a number of indicators. The first indicator when we allocate equity on that indicator on a one-for-one basis is goodwill. Then we are looking at three balance sheet risk type of indicators. One is our internal capitals risk model. Then we look at risk-weighted assets, and we allocate to our Wealth Management businesses equity, which will be commensurate with the 15% Tier 1 ratio, and we allocate to our Investment Bank business at which it will be commensurate with a 10% Tier 1 ratio.</p>
          <p>And the last element you are looking at is a balance sheet leverage. It's an adjusted balance sheet leverage. I'm not going to go into the details. If I look at the first two components actually, we would allocate less equity to the Investment Bank. But, this &#x2013; really the key driver of the current demand of equity allocating to the Investment Bank is still at the balance sheet. For the other businesses, it might be a different one.</p>
          <p>So that number should not be extremely volatile. It has scope to come further down for the IP, but it's not going to be of very big significance for the time being, at least not quickly. So, it's not a purely formulaic way. Obviously, the formula for goodwill one-to-one is pretty hard. The others are input parameters we looked at, and then we use management discretion and judgment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There are no more questions on the line. So, thank you very much for participating in the call. It appears that we have comprehensively covered all the issues. If there are further questions, please contact Investor Relations. Thank you very much, and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference call is now over, and you may disconnect your telephones. Thank you very much for joining. Good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>