<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1176445" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>631</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Thomas R. Hill, Chief Communication Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Peter Kurer, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Marcel Rohner, Group Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Marco Suter, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="5">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="6">Marcel Rohner</participant>
      <participant id="7">Marco Suter</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jeremy Sigee</participant>
      <participant id="9">Julia Werdigier</participant>
      <participant id="10">Peter Kurer</participant>
      <participant id="11">Christoffer Malmer</participant>
      <participant id="12">Huw Van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="13">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="14">Matt Spick</participant>
      <participant id="15">Derek De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="16">Fiona Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="17">Matt Czepliewicz</participant>
      <participant id="18">Peter Thorne</participant>
      <participant id="19">John O'Donnell</participant>
      <participant id="20">Elena Logutenkova</participant>
      <participant id="21">Haig Simonian</participant>
      <participant id="22">Claude Baumann</participant>
      <participant id="23">Kilian Maier</participant>
      <participant id="24">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and welcome to UBS's presentation of Second Quarter Results. As you have seen, in addition to the results, we have also announced today a repositioning of the Bank. So, for this reason, I would like to welcome the Chairman of UBS, Peter Kurer to the podium.</p>
          <p>We also want to give you all enough time to answer &#x2013; to ask questions. So, after the presentations by Peter, Marcel and Marco, we will first take questions from people on the line, on the phone, on the webcast and then from the live audience here in the room.</p>
          <p>Before we start, here is an important disclaimer and please just take a minute or two to read it. So, I would like to hand over to Peter Kurer, Chairman of UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom. Good morning. When I was elected Chairman of UBS a little more than 100 days ago, I promised four things. First, a new system of corporate governance and this was announced on the 1st of July; second, a review of the firm's strategy; third, changes to the membership of the Board; and fourth, a review of our incentive systems.</p>
          <p>Today's announcements fulfill the second and the third of these promises, and I will give you details on this in a few moments. First though, I will make a remark on today's figures. The result is a loss which obviously is not satisfactory. But the provision relating to auction rate securities is included in the numbers.</p>
          <p>As you know, we settled the case globally on Friday. Most important, however, we have made real progress in a number of areas by shrinking first, personnel costs, second, risk positions, and third, the balance sheet total. The task of doing this falls to the executive management and I congratulate Marcel and his team in taking what are difficult, painful but necessary measures to stabilize the firm's franchise and its financial position. I know there will be and must be more of these measures, painful as they are. We are, by no means, at the end of the road to full recovery but based on our progress in the second quarter, I believe we have at least some important milestones. Now, let me explain the outcome of our strategy review. We will reposition UBS to give us maximum strategic flexibility.</p>
          <p>Our objective is that we will be the Bank that produces reliable profits and is a dependable source of value creation for the shareholders. For that purpose, we will separate the business divisions into autonomous units and each division will be incentivized to drive divisional results within a clear risk framework. In the past, I believe we created elaborate processes and modeled objectives in the pursuit of the one firm approach. Now inter-divisional collaboration will come about as a result of internal market forces, constrained by appropriate internal incentive systems.</p>
          <p>This will allow us to shrink the corporate overhead back to what it always should have been, the home of essential corporate functions not a shared service provider. This decision will lead to improves- improved cost performance across the whole of UBS. It will also establish clear governance based on accountability. It will create full transparency on the contributions of the various units. And finally it will give us the flexibility to capture shareholder value in an appropriate way at the appropriate time.</p>
          <p>Our review includes changes to the executive management structure. We will have a new executive committee consisting of the Group CEO, CFO, Chief Risk Officer and the General Counsel and this will be surrounded by a broader Group Executive Board. This will, among other things, encourage more flexible and objective analysis of the progress of all parts of the firm and quicker decisions to adjust our route if conditions demand. This setup will also allow a concentrated and targeted group level control of finance, risk, legal and compliance matters.</p>
          <p>These measures will stimulate a period of profound organizational change. This will in time show in the figures, but it will also be visible in a change in the culture of the firm. I expect UBS to appear realistic, practical and business-like. We will complete the transformation of UBS by the end of 2009. The Strategy Committee of the Board will closely supervise the transformation and I will personally oversee it.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, we are making changes to the membership of the Board of Directors. We proposed four new candidates for election to the board who are all experienced professionals and will bring a vast skill set to support our plans and the transformation. Sally Bott is Head of HR of BP and has extensive banking experience. She has a deep knowledge of leading organizational change. Rainer-Marc Frey has extensive experience in the Investment Bank and hedge fund industry. He has built up a number of highly successful financial services firms.</p>
          <p>Bruno Gehrig has made an outstanding career as a private banker, regulator, academic and as Chairman of Swiss Life. Bill Parrett is one of the most highly regarded auditors.</p>
          <p>He was a successful CEO of Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu and has, in particular, in depth knowledge of our industry having led the firm's Financial Services Group. I'm very pleased that we have these people with us.</p>
          <p>UBS is a firm with proud history. It is a source of dismay and shame for all of us, that the results have been so badly damaged in the last 12 months. We have made a thorough root cause analysis of the events. We also have started a growth remediation program.</p>
          <p>We are committed to operate our business at the highest level of integrity, compliance and risk control. These measures show that we have learned our lessons. Moreover, the events over the last three months have proven that we solve our problems, even the big ones, one after the other. I'm convinced that each of our businesses has a tremendous franchise and I'm also convinced that we have the capacity to control our own destiny now. I thank you for your attention and now I hand over to Marcel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Peter. As Peter has said in his introduction, we create strategic flexibility, we bring in new people, we change the way we run the firm. We run a tight change program and with all of that, we create a firm which delivers reliable profits and is a source of dependable value creation. So, I'd like to address four topics. First, I will comment briefly on our overall results, second, I'll go through our achievements in addressing the crisis of the second quarter, and third, I will go into more detail about the management and governance changes we're making and how we're going to manage that change. Finally, I will talk about our expectations for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>UBS incurred a loss of CHF358 million in the second quarter of 2008. Clearly that loss was the result of a fourth wave of the financial market crisis. The fourth wave I'm referring to is this time led by the deterioration of the market sentiment towards the monolines.</p>
          <p>A tax credit helped to substantially mitigate the impact. This tax credit resulted mainly from the U.S. real estate related losses and markdowns. But even when we look at the result without the crisis related write-downs, it is not satisfactory. While we have businesses that are doing well, we have lost market share overall. That's not really a surprise when you look what's happened but it means we have got to work even harder and faster to resolve our outstanding issues.</p>
          <p>Apart from the tough realities of our results, I also see some positive and encouraging elements. As we have explained at the presentation of our first quarter results, the market for residential mortgage-backed securities is now at levels where substantial trading activities are restarting. This allowed us to reduce our risks &#x2013; our risk positions substantially.</p>
          <p>We are also now in a position to better hedge and manage the remaining risks, and consequently the impact of these positions on our earnings will continue to diminish. The second important positive sign is that the results contain two significant elements which help us to substantially address other challenges. First, the provision for our future costs related to the auction rate securities settlement is included. Our settlement is structured so that all groups of clients benefit from the solution. The provision covers the risks and costs for future purchases of paper as and when necessary and it takes into consideration the markdowns on clients' positions. Second, we have dramatically increased the credit valuation adjustment for our monoline exposures. Whilst the situation around the monoline exposures is complex and dynamic, it's clear that we are much closer to a solution and the remaining risks are therefore much smaller.</p>
          <p>There are important achievements in the second quarter I referred to a minute ago and they relate to our crisis management. First, we have substantially reduced our risks in the core U.S. subprime and all daybook down to USD 13 billion from USD 55 billion at year-end. Our risk-weighted assets are down CHF 10 billion.</p>
          <p>Second, we have strengthened the capital base and brought it back to the very strong level it was before the crisis began. With a Tier 1 ratio of 11.6%, we are one of the best capitalized institutions in the world.</p>
          <p>Third, we have resolved the auction rate securities issue, and substantially provided for the monoline exposures. Fourth, we have reduced the number of staff by 2,400, primarily in the Investment Bank, but also across the Group. Fifth, taking out the 900 million auction rate securities settlement, we have reduced costs to CHF 7.2 billion for the quarter, which is close to our next year target run rate, and last we have reduced the balance sheet by another CHF 150 billion.</p>
          <p>With these achievements, we have laid the foundation to move ahead. Peter has already addressed some of the key considerations and conclusions of the strategic review. I would like to make a few further comments.</p>
          <p>As I've already pointed out at the AGM this year, our success as a group depends on the success of all of its individual parts. In particular, I emphasized that we will not allow excess free cash flow generated by Wealth Management to fund the capital growth of the Investment Bank.</p>
          <p>Today's announcement and repositioning is a vital further step in bringing the Group back on track for success. Our aim is to create maximum transparency of the shareholder value being created by each business division. By positioning our business divisions more autonomously, we will increase both the responsibility and accountability of the business Groups and where required we will align the incentives of management and staff a lot more closely with their results.</p>
          <p>We want to clearly distinguish between the bottom line responsibility for each separate business and the group-wide responsibilities. Having both, the business Group CEO with individual personal bottom line responsibility and at the same time the Group Executive Board with a collective responsibility undermines the accountability of all the managers involved. The full GEB will focus on group-wide interests, in particular the Group Executive Board will manage the shared services and the group leadership development. It will grow cross-divisional revenues, it will oversee the regional governance, and it will review proposed changes to the business portfolio.</p>
          <p>The Executive Committee which consists of the Chief Executive Officer, the CFO, the Chief Risk Officer and the General Counsel will decide on the allocation of the Group financial resources to the business divisions, i.e., the capital, the terms and parameters and availability of funding, and the risk capacity and parameters. Finally, the Executive Committee will set as well as monitor the performance targets for the business divisions.</p>
          <p>Divisional CEOs will be tasked with leading their business in a much more autonomous way. They will be accountable for their dedicated capital resources, their people, their infrastructure and ultimately the value their business creates for our shareholders. Regional CEOs will drive cross-divisional collaboration. Again, the objective is to generate dependable value for UBS shareholders. They will assume group-wide regional regulatory responsibility and represent the Group to the broader public in their regions. In order to fulfill the regulatory responsibilities, the regional CEOs have all encompassing veto power over all business activities in their respective regions. Corporate Center will be responsible for providing best-in-class Group level control in the areas of finance, risk, legal and compliance. The Corporate Center will devote significant attention to strengthening and empowering the support functions throughout the firm.</p>
          <p>I would now like to announce one departure from our Group Executive Board as well as two additions. Marco Suter has been a key player in starting our process of change over the last year, but Marco has expressed his wish to step down from his current role as Chief Financial Officer of UBS. I respect and accept his wish and I would like to take the opportunity to thank him for his outstanding contribution during an extremely difficult year. I would also like to express my deep gratitude that he was willing to step in without hesitation when I needed him most. Marco will support the new CFO in the handover and in specific projects of the coming organizational transformation.</p>
          <p>At the same time I have the pleasure to announce two new additions to the Group Executive Board. Markus Diethelm, currently Group Chief Legal Officer of Swiss Re to be Group General Counsel. Markus brings highly relevant experience in managing a global legal function in a sector whose complexity is comparable to the banking industry. His involvement in the strategic development of Swiss Re over the recent years will be instrumental in the next steps we will be taking at UBS.</p>
          <p>John Cryan, currently Head of Financial Institutions Group, UBS Investment Bank, as Group Chief Financial Officer. John is a widely respected banker who has specialized for many years in advising financial institutions around the world. His insights and expertise will be extremely valuable in our task of restoring the value of UBS.</p>
          <p>We will only achieve the change of UBS business model with a centrally managed change program. That program will cover structural, legal, financial aspects of the transformation. I'll personally oversee this critical process and I have asked Juerg Haller, our current Chairman and CEO of UBS Latin America to lead this effort.</p>
          <p>The seven streams of this program, which will start immediately and will be led where appropriate by line management are: one, revised incentive systems to reward divisional management and staff for shareholder value creation in their own business division. Two, further enhancements to the funding framework so that the costs and structure of liabilities of each business division approximate those of stand-alone competitors. Three, adjustments to the executive governance structure to reflect the above changes. Four, development of targets and performance indicators, consistent with the repositioning of business divisions. Five, the reduction of the size and scope of the Corporate Center, in line with the reallocation of process ownership to the divisions. Six, review of intra-divisional servicing, revenue sharing and referral arrangements. And seven, the continuation of the ongoing strategic cost reduction program targeted at increasing the efficiency of the Group.</p>
          <p>I intend to complete the change program by the end of 2009. We are not done with our work, but we have taken a number of significant steps to address the remaining critical issues. We have still outstanding legal matters, and we are allocating significant resources and attention to seeing them through. We have also risks, which we still consider inconsistent with the way we intend to run the firm, and we are going to further reduce those risks, but with the all the steps and measures we have already taken, we are getting closer and closer to normality.</p>
          <p>I realize that we have asked a lot from our staff to get us where we are today, and I'm now asking for even more commitment, but I am convinced that the steps we are taking, will clarify the direction our firm takes into the future, and will benefit our clients, our people and our shareholders.</p>
          <p>I'd like to thank you for your attention, and hand over to Marco Suter, CFO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Marcel, and good morning. As Marcel has already said, we closed the second quarter with a net loss of 358 million. Resilient operating income, in all of our businesses, has again been overshadowed by realized and unrealized losses from our legacy risk positions. In aggregate, dispositions had a negative impact of the USD 5.1 billion on our results. The key contributing factor, as Marcel has already said, was a 2.9 billion increase in our credit valuation adjustments for our monoline exposures.</p>
          <p>As you will see later in my presentation, this was due to a significant widening of credit spreads for the monolines towards the end of the second quarter. Our results for the second quarter also include a provision of USD 900 million for the auction rate security settlement. This provision represents our estimate for the total costs that will result over time from this settlement.</p>
          <p>Tax credits for the second quarter amounted to CHF 3.8 billion, and helped us to offset some of our losses. These tax credits were ultimately higher than what we had anticipated at the time of the preannouncement. This was partly due to the incremental provision charge, but it also includes a release of approximately CHF 600 million of existing tax provisions following successful closure of tax audits of prior years in multiple jurisdictions.</p>
          <p>As already has been said, we obviously cannot [be] pleased with these results, but these results, nevertheless, do provide concrete evidence, that we are putting many of the problems behind us. Let's look at the specifics.</p>
          <p>After two consecutive quarters of negative operating income, Group operating income for the second quarter has turned positive. This constitutes a very significant turnaround, compared to the fourth quarter of last year, and the first quarter of this year, when we experienced large negative operating income. And I would like to point out that, contrary to the first quarter of this year, our operating income line did not benefit from one-time gains during the second quarter. You will remember that in Q1, we recorded a onetime gain of CHF 3.9 billion in the Corporate Center, resulting from the MCN, mandatory convertible note valuation, and 2.1 billion gain in the Investment Bank from own credit.</p>
          <p>During this last quarter, own credit adjustments actually resulted in a small debit to our result. You can clearly see the financial progress in our results, and this will certainly help to regain confidence of investors and of clients. But what will prove to be of even greater importance on our road to recovery, and for our future success, are the critical achievements that Marcel has already touched on. Let me summarize them again, in no particular order, before providing you more concrete evidence on each of these very tangible and visible accomplishments.</p>
          <p>First, we have reduced our legacy risk positions by almost CHF 30 billion during this quarter, particularly our U.S. subprime and our Alt-A exposures. While we cannot exclude the possibility of future losses from dispositions, we are clearly approaching the final innings. Second, we have again reduced our balance sheet during this latest quarter alone by a CHF 150 billion.</p>
          <p>Third, we have successfully completed the rights issue, which net to fees and commissions, has contributed CHF 15.6 billion to our equity base. Besides rights issue, our euro one billion hybrid issue, and the reduction in our risk-rated assets has allowed us to rebuild our capital ratios to the very strong levels that we had prior to the outbreak of the crisis.</p>
          <p>We have also reduced our head count very significantly and we are well on track to achieve the targets that we had communicated at the occasion of our Q1 result presentation. As you will see, this has led translated into a lower cost base, but the full effect of these decisive cost measures will only fully come through in future periods. As Marcel already said, we have reached a settlement for claims relating to auction rate securities, and we have already provided for the expected costs in our second quarter result.</p>
          <p>This crosses one more item off the list of open issues. As you will see, many of these measures have caused additional pain to our profit and loss account during the second quarter, but they were absolutely necessary for us to move forward. Market factors are not likely to recover quickly. We actually expect them to remain difficult over the short to medium term. Therefore, our focus has got to be making sure that we are bringing costs down further to respond to this difficult environment. We are confident that we have taken the right steps to address these challenging market conditions. Before looking at the expenses in more detail let me comment briefly on personnel reductions during the quarter.</p>
          <p>We reduced our personnel by 3% or 2,387 people. That brings the total to 81,452 at the end of June. Most of this reduction occurred in the Investment Bank, where we reduced staff levels by 1,695 and where we are well on track to meet the 2,600 reduction target which we had announced at the occasion of our Q1 results presentation.</p>
          <p>In Global Wealth Management &amp; Business Banking, the objective is to reduce personnel through natural attrition as much as possible, and to improve the front office to back office ratios. This is exactly what we have achieved in Q2.</p>
          <p>Out of the 750 reductions in this quarter, only 140 were financial advisers, of which 129 were in our U.S. operation, the remaining 610 head count reduction was in non-client facing units.</p>
          <p>Moving to operating expense, the headline number increased by 3% to CHF 8.1 billion, but this view is distorted by two important factors. First, the material increase in our legal provisions to account for the 900 million estimated cost of the auction rate securities settlement, and second, by a goodwill impairment charge of 341 million due to the closure of our institution Muni business in the Investment Bank. Adjusted for these factors, operating expenses were actually down 8% in the quarter. We reduced our personnel expense by 662 million. Here, we benefited from the lower head count level and from a change in the forfeiture provision for our share-based compensation plan.</p>
          <p>These more stringent forfeiture provisions mean that share-based comp for future vaults is no longer accrued in the current period but instead will be amortized over the resting period. That has resulted in a reversal of approximately 250 million Swiss francs of Q1 accruals and equally in a lower level of accruals for the second quarter.</p>
          <p>If you take out our legal provisions and the goodwill impairment charge, the other non-personnel costs have increased slightly. While cost measures have been effective in most cost categories, our professional fees went up, not surprising. We are pleased with the cost reductions achieved to date but we cannot be complacent. Our cost base has got to come down further as the full effect of the cost initiatives will come through gradually.</p>
          <p>Net new money for this quarter was disappointing but not surprising given our recent situation and intense negative publicity we have attracted as a result. In fact, most of the total outflows of 17.3 billion in our wealth management business occurred in the month of April. In addition to performance challenges, it appears that reputation issues have had a growing effect on our global asset management business by constraining new inflows and by accelerating outflows. That said, gross inflows in the June quarter remained at strong levels.</p>
          <p>The measures we have announced today will not fix our reputation challenges overnight. Therefore, we expect pressure on net new money flows to continue in the short term.</p>
          <p>Our investor asset base on a quarter-end comparison basis was broadly flat. Currency gains offset net new money outflows and the impact of negative market performance. In Global Wealth Management and Business Banking, this resulted in a slight improvement in our invested asset base whereas the favorable currency development was not able to fully offset the outflows in Global Asset Management but when we compare the average invested asset base quarter-on-quarter, this shows a reduction. This is the result of the very sharp decline we had experienced in Q1 which, as you will remember, was largely currency and market performance related.</p>
          <p>The average asset base declined 80% in Global Asset Management and 7% in Global Wealth Management and Business Banking and this largely explains the somewhat lower revenues across our Wealth Management Businesses as we will see in a minute.</p>
          <p>This slide illustrates the stable trend of our gross margin in our Swiss and International Wealth Management Businesses and you can see an improving trend in our Wealth Management U.S. operation. Taking into consideration the turbulent market environment, this is a very strong testimony to the revenue stability of these Wealth Management Businesses.</p>
          <p>I've already said in my opening remarks that they've reduced our balance sheet by a further 150 billion Swiss francs during this latest quarter alone. This now marks the fourth consecutive quarter where we have delivered on our promise to reduce our balance sheet. Over these last four quarters, the total reduction amounted to over 460 billion Swiss francs. Clearly that was not an easy task when you take into account the market environment that existed for most of this time.</p>
          <p>The reduction during this latest quarter would have been even higher had it not been for the appreciation of the U.S. dollar against the Swiss franc.</p>
          <p>More important than the mere reduction in our balance sheet, however, is the fact that we have reduced further our risks as evidenced by the decline in our risk-rated assets and the very substantial reduction in our legacy risk positions.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the individual business groups, headline numbers for Global Wealth Management and Business Banking show a sharp decline in pre-tax profits as expenses increased significantly and revenues were affected by lower average invested assets. However, adjusting for the auction rate securities provisions taken in Wealth Management U.S., costs were actually down 5% on the previous quarter. On that adjusted basis, overall profitability in Global Wealth Management and Business Banking would have declined by 5% in the quarter which is a respectable result. We expect further efficiency gain in these businesses in the coming quarters as our focus on cost control continues and the full benefits of the current head count reductions will materialize.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management International and Switzerland contributed a pre-tax profit of 1.27 billion Swiss francs for the quarter. That represents a decline of 11% compared to the first quarter of the year. Operating income was down 6% compared to the prior quarter. The lower average asset base caused recurring income to fall by a 137 million Swiss francs, lower client activity prompted non-recurring income to fall by 59 million.</p>
          <p>Operating expense was down only 2% and has decreased at a slower pace than revenues. Effective cost management in most directly controllable cost categories has been somewhat offset by higher charge-backs from other business units.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management U.S. recorded a loss of 741 million Swiss francs. If you take out the U.S. $900 million provision for the auction rate security settlement, the underlying pre-tax profit was 178 million which represents a decline of 3% compared to the prior quarter. Revenues were down 3% as we experienced reductions in both recurring and non-recurring income. Recurring income was affected by lower managed account fees related to lower invested asset levels in U.S. dollar terms. In Swiss franc terms, however, invested assets in this business rose slightly to 712 billion Swiss francs. The 3% depreciation of the U.S. dollar against the Swiss franc during this period was largely offset by negative market performance and net new money outflows which for this business amounted to 8 billion Swiss francs for the quarter.</p>
          <p>The outflows again were most pronounced in April, partly a reaction to our reputation challenges and partly due to seasonal asset withdrawals of clients to settle their annual income tax payments in the United States.</p>
          <p>Business Banking reported a solid Q2 pre-tax profit of 598 million Swiss francs. That's well above last quarter and also ahead on a year-on-year basis. The somewhat lower level of operating income was more than offset by the very substantial reduction in operating expense. This is predominately a result of our increased cost efficiencies in this business but it also partly reflects an increase in cost charge-outs to other business units.</p>
          <p>Asset management increased its pre-tax profit contribution by 7% Q-on-Q to 352 million for the quarter. Top line revenue was advanced by 2% as our higher performance fee in our A&amp;Q business more than offset declining revenues resulting from lower average invested assets in our traditional mandates.</p>
          <p>Operating expense declined by 1%. Net new money outflows were particularly pronounced in our wholesale intermediary segment. The improved pre-tax profit contributing Global Asset Management cannot mask the disappointing net new money performance this unit now had for a couple of quarters but it's worth recognizing that we have managed costs very effectively in this business and that our cost to income ratio remains among the best in the industry for this business.</p>
          <p>Please also note that in Q3 of this year, we will book a positive revenue item of approximately 160 million Swiss francs from the sale of our stake in Adams Street Partner. This transaction was closed on August 6.</p>
          <p>Now to the Investment Bank. Here we have experienced a pre-tax loss of 5.2 billion Swiss francs for the quarter. The results were dominated by 5.1 billion of write-downs and losses related to our legacy risk positions. Markets were challenging for the industry as a whole. In light of these conditions, we are satisfied with the performance of most of our core client franchise businesses, particularly cash equities, prime brokerage, and investment banking as you will see in a moment.</p>
          <p>Efficiency measures remain a key priority. Operating expense in the IB was down 14% on the prior quarter, and 36% on the prior year. The head count &#x2013; the head count reduction plus the reversal of previous EOP accruals largely explain this favorable development. Non-personnel cost in the quarter increased by 4% compared to the first quarter. This really to change in future quarters as the effects of our cost measures will come through.</p>
          <p>Here, you need to take into consideration that Q1 included large legal provisions, whereas Q2 now includes, as I have already mentioned, a 341 million provision for goodwill muni impairment charge. So, this number operating cost for this business clearly should come down very significantly in future quarters. Looking at the specific business areas within the IB compared with the second quarter results of last year, which was a record quarter, IBD's performance was negatively impacted by declining fee pools and reduced market activity.</p>
          <p>But compared with the first quarter of this year's &#x2013; this year results for IBD are up markedly, thanks to improved equity capital markets, continued strength in debt capital markets and a recovery in our M&amp;A advisory fees. In this business, we actually gained market share and we currently rank number four according to Dealogics. That's up from the number five rank we had in the first quarter of this year and equally the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Equities declined both on year-on-year and Q-on-Q basis due to market turbulence and slower derivatives activity. This said, we gained market share in cash equities and also achieved strong results in prime brokerage &#x2013; I think it was the second best quarter ever. FICC continue to be impacted by credit market dislocation which as you will see has caused further losses on our legacy risk positions. Outside of these however, we have seen positive results in some of our core businesses, with good performance in foreign exchange and money markets, strength in structured products and year-on-year growth in our rates business.</p>
          <p>Before taking you through our risk positions, I'd like to take a look at the development of some of the key credit market indicators during the second quarter '08. The fundamentals of the U.S. residential housing market continue to deteriorate. Remittance data such as delinquencies and foreclosures showed continuing weakening and the key ABX indices have continued to decline. This has triggered some further losses on our U.S. residential mortgage assets in Q2. For student loans, credit spreads of AAA rated paper was volatile during the quarter, but ended the quarter at somewhat better levels.</p>
          <p>While market sentiments for high rated paper had slightly improved during the second quarter, our additional write-downs for these assets were caused by positions in lower rated and monoline wrapped paper, bare spreads had actually risen throughout the quarter.</p>
          <p>And finally, Europe sales credit spreads for monoline insurers widening to extreme levels at the end of the quarter. This explains why we have increased our credit evaluation adjustments for these exposures so substantially during the quarter. Against the backdrop we have experienced realized and unrealized losses of $4.8 billion in the quarter on positions related to U.S. residence &#x2013; to the U.S. residential mortgage market.</p>
          <p>This compares with $17.6 billion of losses from these positions in the prior quarter. We have again provided you same level of risk disclosure as in prior quarters, this can be found in the appendix to today's presentation slide, and I will be happy to answer questions on those slides during the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>As already highlighted earlier the US$2.9 billion increase in our monoline credit evaluation adjustment was the single largest contributor to this quarter's losses. You will see on the detailed monoline slide in the appendix that our credit exposure to monoline insurers did not change materially over the quarter. What has changed materially however, is our reserving level against these exposures. In order to determine the appropriate provision level, we inline with general industry practice, are guided by market observable credit spreads for the monolines.</p>
          <p>As these spreads had widened very materially during the quarter, we have more than doubled our credit evaluations adjustments from previously 2.6 billion to now US$5.5 billion. The average reserve level now stands at 58%, ranging from 20% for the best performing monoline to 100% for a monoline that had already defaulted on us. As a result of this increase in our CVA &#x2013; Credit Value Adjustment, our net exposure has decreased from previously $6.3 billion, now down to $4 billion.</p>
          <p>UBS, like many other banks, is involved in restructuring discussions with a number of the monoline insurers and you need to understand the confidential nature of these discussions. This prevents us from commenting on the potential outcome at this point in time.</p>
          <p>With respect to our U.S. sub-prime, Alt-A and prime positions, we are pleased with the very significant progress we have made in the quarter. As you can see from this and the supporting slides, we have reduced these exposures by over 50% during this quarter alone. The biggest contributor was the BlackRock transaction, which reduced our sub-prime RMBS exposure by $6.7 billion, our all day exposures by US$7.4 billion and our prime exposure by US$900 million.</p>
          <p>You will remember that in the BlackRock transaction we sold assets with a notional value of approximately US$22 billion for a price of approximately $15 billion, and that price was in-line where we had marked those assets at the end of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>In addition to the  BlackRock sale, we also engaged in a number of smaller transactions. During June for example, we were able to exceed several super senior RMBS CDO positions in a single transaction. That transaction was again done in-line with where we had marked those positions in our books.</p>
          <p>Our U.S. reference-linked note exposure was also reduced by 1.1 billion during the quarter. The losses we have experienced here mainly relate to the sub-prime and Alt-A components. Similar to previous quarter's writedowns were only partially offset by fair value gains on the remaining credit protection we hold for these exposures.</p>
          <p>Moving on to other risks positions, our inventory of student loan exposure decreased from 10.4 billion to US$9 billion during the quarter. Our auction rate security settlement will not result in this number going up quickly in the short term because most of the student loan exposure subject to the settlement are with institutional clients, where our repurchase commitment only starts in June 2010.</p>
          <p>We also further reduced our leverage finance exposure, the majority of the reduction came from the successful distribution and the minor part of the reduction came from hedging. Our average marks for these exposures now stand at 90%.</p>
          <p>U.S. commercial real estate did not contribute to our losses during the quarter. Here we actually recorded a profit of US$318 million. You will remember when you see it in the footnotes of the slides that our net exposure in U.S. commercial real estate consists of longs and shorts, which does pose some basis risk, a risk, which we actively managed throughout the quarter. Exposure increased at the quarter end to 8.2 billion. At the end of July however, our exposure has again been reduced and now is again back to levels below those reported at the end of Q1 as well as below the exposure reported at end of Q2.</p>
          <p>As we have already said more details on the remaining exposures and debt characteristics in terms of marks, ratings and vintage information can be found in the appendix. To summarize, we are pleased with the progress in risk reductions but we acknowledge that the remaining exposures are still not at the levels we would like them to be. Therefore we will continue to actively manage and further reduce our remaining risk positions.</p>
          <p>Finally, let's look at our capital position. As you already heard from Peter Kurer and Marcel Rohner we have very significantly strengthened our capital base. Our Tier-1 capital now stands at 37.5 billion Swiss francs, up 14.6 billion from March end and our total regulatory capital is now above CHF 50 billion. Our Tier 1 ratio is back to 11.6% and our total capital ratio now stands at 15.7%. These ratios are now inline with the very strong levels that we had prior to the outbreak of the credit crisis, and they compare extremely well with those ratios of our competitors.</p>
          <p>Our total equity position has also received a very significant boost during this latest quarter. In addition to the increases from the rights issue and the hybrid issues equity has increased by a further CHF 12.4 billion due to the reclassification of the mandatory convertible note from a liability instrument to an equity instrument. Overall, total equity increased by almost CHF 30 billion during the quarter, and now stands at CHF 52.3 billion</p>
          <p>In closing, I would like to stress that also we clearly have a long way to go before we deliver truly satisfactory results, it is clear that we are doing what is necessary to get UBS firmly back on track. These actions are already delivering tangible benefits as we have seen throughout this presentation, but the full impact is yet to come. We will continue focusing on cost controls, risk reduction, capital strengths and operational efficiency.</p>
          <p>With this I will hand over to Tom, but not before thanking you all for your support and the trusts that I have personally experienced from you during my one year tenure as a CFO of UBS. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Marco, we're now going to move on to the question and answer session. We're going to take questions from the webcast and telephone audience before accepting questions from the in-room audience. So, could we have the first question on the line please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>First question is from Mr. Kian Abouhossein, JP Morgan. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I &#x2013; I have three questions. The first one relates to FICC, you mentioned that core FICC is very different from FICC ex write-downs which I get to about 500 million. Your run rate historically is about 1.5 to two billion. So, can you explain to me the difference between core FICC and the FICC that you are showing here in the numbers?</p>
          <p>The second question is on targets, historically you mentioned IB 20 billion roughly of capital, four billion of pre-tax profit. Can you discuss these targets in light of your restructuring of the different businesses that you're undergoing, is that still achievable?</p>
          <p>And the third point is on Tier 1 capital, can you tell me the cost of the hybrid and secondly your Tier 1 was impacted by the godfathering of your deferred share employee shares, I think it's roughly two billion. How much of these shares do you have left on a Tier 1 basis? Thank you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will address the second question, and then hand over to Marco Suter for the first and third question. The targets with respect to the Investment Bank are obviously more, more valid than ever. We do believe that we are on the right track in particularly if you look at reduction in balance sheet size and funding requirements, we believe that the positioning of the IB will put it in a position to deliver on those targets and deliver attractive returns to our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You tried to get to the delta of our FICC business by deducting the losses from the results we have seen. What you also need to consider, there were some additional losses that we had in FICC, I cannot quantify it, resulting from our accelerated balance sheet reduction.</p>
          <p>And then we also have a precautionary measure which is affecting the results of FICC, which has to do with the precautionary very large liquidity position, which we hold and liquidity obviously comes at a cost, because we have it invested very short-term and we are financing it with term money, so there we have a negative carry. I will not be able to break the number to you, but I guess you will get back to levels which would be more in line with levels we had seen a few years ago for FICC stripping out those effects. Not all of them are going to go away immediately but certainly one or two of them the write-downs hopefully soon and you know, the first asset reduction as well.</p>
          <p>On Tier 1, yes, there is a two billion accrual for share based comp. While we do not have to accrue share-based comp through our P&amp;L, we still have to accrue it for regulatory purposes. So, we need to make some assumptions. It's the amount of share-based comp we will hand over to our employees next year, it will depend on the share price of UBS at that point in time which allows us to calculate the number of shares we think we need and then we have to multiply the number of shares by the average share price at which we hold our treasury shares which is in the order of magnitude of CHF 60 rather than the current level, and that makes the number rather the higher of two billion. So do not deduct from the two billion number that this equates two or three plan to pay in share-based comp. I think this answers that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The hybrid capital cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was it LIBOR plus four, I think in that order of magnitude, you are talking about the euro one billion hybrid issue, is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we will have to get back to you on that, I'm not 100% sure but I think it's that order of magnitude it was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I can just follow up on, if I look at your IB business and if it's going to be &#x2013; if its capital is going to be allocated on a standalone basis. And if I look at your hybrid costs, which looks like it's roughly 8, 9%, is it fair to say that we're looking at &#x2013; at a cost of financing for the IB closer to 15?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that it's &#x2013; it's more between 13 and 14, that's were we would see the cost of capital on a blended basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on a blended you mean for the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, across the capital structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Weighted average cost of capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Jeremy Sigee, Citigroup. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, good morning. Just two questions please. One is on the outflows, which from your descriptions sound like they were most severe in April and then got better, but at the same time there are press reports of advisors leaving and your own comment is a cautious net new money outlook. So I just wondered if you can talk a little bit more about how you see that playing out. Are we past the worst or are there still tricky patches ahead of us?</p>
          <p>And then, second separate question, you've reduced total assets here, and you've gone a long way towards your original target of asset reduction, and I just wondered if you could give us an update on whether you will be setting additional reduction targets beyond what you had initially envisaged, particularly with the regulators focusing on leverage ratios?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. On the outflows I think, we have to first dissect the Wealth Management number, the 17 number into two pieces. One is Wealth Management U.S. where we actually in competitive terms, including dividends and interest rates look comparably good and then we have the Wealth Management International and Swiss part which is 9.3 billion.</p>
          <p>The 9.3 billion is split into two pieces, 5.5 Switzerland and 3.8 at Wealth Management International and that shows you where the center of gravity of the problem was which was clearly here in the home country, where it's basically 2.3% of the asset base whilst in Wealth Management International it's only 0.4% of the asset base. When we look at the sources and flows, we see actually growth areas which still contribute positive in this Wealth Management International part.</p>
          <p>Where does this go? We feel that we have to address and resolve all the problems until we can say we are firmly getting back on track to previous levels. When we look at what the advisor count is you can see that we have lost 129 advisors in the Wealth Management U.S. business, where we have more than 8,000, so it is relatively a small number. Wealth Management International &amp; Switzerland we had negative client advisers count of eleven just eleven people less than in the previous quarter. And when we look at the fluctuation rate, it's only slightly higher.</p>
          <p>So, all in all what we see is that we are stable on client adviser, financial adviser, we expect that this is continue to grow albeit clearly in a difficult environment a bit slower than previous quarters and we have lost primarily assets from clients which were also diversifying their holdings away from UBS. The net acquisition from new clients is still significant. So, I would say the worst is past but it still takes time until we get back to the levels which we had before.</p>
          <p>Then in terms of the total asset reduction, we have already surpassed the target we have set ourselves. And, therefore, we have set additional targets because we feel that we can do more and when you read &#x2013; what we really aspire to get to is a liability structure, as I have explained in how we want to run the business, which is comparable to standalone competitors. Of course that comparison is tricky, there are substantial accounting differences to come from one to the other, but we do believe we have still some room to go and this will be consistent with industry levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that includes on leverage ratios, tangible equity to total assets, those kind of metrics are now part of your framework?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These are part of our framework already how we allocate capital as we have drawn the conclusion a few quarters back that as the balance sheet grows equity base also has to grow and that's basically expressed in such a ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ms. Julia Werdigier, New York Times. Please go ahead Madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just a few months ago, you hailed the advantages of having a fully integrated franchise. I was just wondering whether you could explain a bit more what brought you to this announcement today that you are separating them? And then also could you maybe go into more details as to what your strategy for the Investment Bank is and say whether you've tried to sell it? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Madam, I will take the first question and Marcel will take the second question. The first question is that &#x2013; the answer to the first question is that we made a thorough analysis both of the situation which we are in and of the industry. The industry and environment of the industry is obviously in a very uncertain situation, and the basic idea is that in this uncertain situation, we create increased flexibility. And flexibility means two things, first is that we reckon that our businesses in this environment can exploit their solid franchise better if they are agile, if they are more independent they can react faster. And the second one is because we do not know where the industry will go in the long-term but we sense this uncertainty it's very important that we create the situation where we can capture shareholder value at an appropriate time in an appropriate form.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Following the Investment Bank, which was your second question we have no intention whatsoever to sell our Investment Bank or any of our businesses. What we have said is that the success of the Group depends on the success of its individual businesses, and one of our issues was cross -- cross subsidies within the firm. The value of all the business together is primarily in the cross divisional flows, that's primarily a revenue issue.</p>
          <p>There are three sources, our clients want to do business with more than one business division. There is &#x2013; the second source is if one division gets business from another division, for example if we execute transactions at the Investment Bank, which originates in Wealth Management. And the third one, is if one business provides a service to the other business. What we intend to do is manage these three sources of value very explicitly and very deliberately. And that's why we review inter-company servicing, referral and revenue sharing arrangements. We do believe that we can A) make transparent of the value of each individual business to the shareholders, and B) what the dependable sources of value are by having these businesses interacting. And that's what this set up will bring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just have one follow up question on that? How long do you give your Investment Bank then in order to turn around?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have said, clearly what the performance targets are in terms of pre-tax profits, in terms of cost and revenue run rates and that's what we expect the Investment Bank to deliver.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What are these targets? I mean time-wise, how, if you're saying that you are completing or are expecting to complete the separation by the end of 2009, going on from there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you can assume that, first of all what we have said, we have the 2008, 2009 costs run rate 20 billion translating down in the IB business into the 4 billion pre-tax in a normalized environment, we do believe the 2009 will be a normalized environment where we can achieve our pre-tax contributions and that's what we abide by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Christoffer Malmer of Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, good morning, actually. Two questions following up on two of the previous questions. First, when you say that the worst is past on the inflows in Wealth Management, should we interpret that as you're  back to an inflow, positive inflow number or are you now stemming the outflows?</p>
          <p>And second question just in relation to the question that was just answered, you said no intentions whatsoever to sell Investment Bank or any of your other businesses. Considering you've just conducted a review and you are saying you've seen some weaknesses with the integrated model and you're now taking actions. Why would you categorically rule out any changes to the Group structure, not just referring to the Investment Bank, but more broadly? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the first question, and the Chairman takes the second one. On the first question the outflow, what we said the worst is over and we are cautious and that means that, it's anywhere north of where we are and the second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think we have no intention to sell any of our businesses, what this is all about it's about flexibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Huw Van Steenis, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. I was wondering if you could just give us any color on your current views on the proposed leverage ratio, and what that may mean for future returns and balance sheet size. I realize it's very draft but how have you started to think through these issues? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know that there are confidential discussions going on, on that issue. We believe that the fundamental notion that a growing balance sheet should go along with a growing equity base has merits. And that's why we believe that directionally, these discussions make sense. We do believe it's too early to say what the outcome is. There are many variables, which are highly relevant in terms of this question and over time, we do believe that we will get to an acceptable outcome for us as an institution, but also in terms of the revenues and the returns we generate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. And for the moment the sort of mid-term goal of a balance sheet of 1.7 trillion or there or thereabouts, is that still concerned by the recent review or with the recent review perhaps even look for a greater shrinkage over time? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think you can assume, as I said the 1.75 was Investment Bank balance sheet, we have now a total balance sheet of CHF 2 trillion. We have already a smaller amount than 1.75 in the Investment Bank as per the end of the second quarter. So, you can assume that there is more room to go, because we think we did not optimize it yet, for a number of reasons, structural reasons, the way we book the business, the complexity of the structure. And these are exactly elements which we will address when we position our businesses in a more autonomous way, as we have said. It will also allow us to bring the balance sheet to competitive levels for the IB and for the rest of the business. So, we think we can actually further reduce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Jon Peace, Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Two questions please, the first one is, I can understand how the structure changes today have increased flexibility in 2010, if you decide to break up the business. But if you decide to keep the integrated model as you are clearly saying today, I wonder haven't you in a sense undone some of the funding and cost synergies to the integrated model that maintain the reputational risk of keeping the Investment Bank and Private Bank under one brand. I really just want to understand how duplicating some of corporate center's shared-costs in each business line, could lead to an overall cost improvement.</p>
          <p>The second question is just with regards to your auction rate securities. About two-thirds of the 18.6 billion you've repurchased is student loan-backed. I understand that's trading at a discount in the market of about 15 to 30% of face and the provision that you have booked this quarter is about 4% of face. Have you assumed that very little of this actually gets put back to you. And why are you so confident of that? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start with two and make a comment on one. And the Chairman will answer one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One auction rate securities, we have marked our client portfolio the same way they have marked our own portfolio. So, these are mark-to-market position and this depends heavily on what the paper &#x2013; actually in detail is. What we can say is that the portfolio our clients hold is of a much better quality than the portfolio we hold ourselves. The second point is that we have made quite aggressive assumptions with respect to exercise of the put option the clients have. The bulk of the student loan as Marco has said in his speech, comes with institutional clients where the put option period actually starts in the middle of 2010.</p>
          <p>And then on the integration, I should say once more, the real issues are not costs, are inter-divisional business, are revenue flows that's what really creates value. And the funding advantages or these advantages depend on the risk profile and also the liability structure and that's exactly one of the benefits we actually do create by the much more autonomous positioning that we have a much more balanced liability structure and a much more competitive balance sheet on the Investment Bank. And that will indirectly obviously mitigate also the impact it has on the other businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you said everything. If you look at the press release, we make a subtle difference, I think we step away from the integrated model, we rather will separate business units and we will operate them under one roof and under one brand</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Matt Spick, Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, I just wanted to come back to the balance sheet and you've had quite big reductions so far. I wondered if you could comment on the breakdown of that reduction between reductions in customer financing. And I'm not just talking about loans, I mean all forms of customer financing, whether in the repo book or whatever. And reductions in positions that might be termed to your own risk, like the match book, within the repo book. And what part has come from, if you like, quick wins from enforcing master netting agreements? And if you take those three mechanisms for reducing the balance sheet, how you think the balance sheet reductions in the future will come from. Have you exhausted the quick wins? Will it mostly be actual customer financing you reduce from hereon? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, one comment and I then I hand over to the CFO. First of all on the high level what we see is that if you deduct the PRV from the whole balance sheet, you see that actually and it's on one of the slides, 622 billion came from the trading asset, portfolio which is a very sizeable reduction. And with respect to the various sources, I mean, you've obviously addressed how we can go about such a reduction. Marco, want to comment further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, really confirming what you just said. Look it all &#x2013; none from financing, none from master netting agreements, we would want the master netting agreements to take on more speed, which is obviously creating a huge balance sheet pressure for IFRS Banks, our balance sheet is inflated by at least 400 billion or roughly 400 billion compared to a U.S. GAAP filer, we have not reduced client financing so it's all trading positions and match book activity, and obviously the PRVs as Marcel has already mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Can I ask if there are any match book left?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would you comment on how big that is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's still a very significant market participant, one of the most significant one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Derek De Vries, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Derek from Merrill's. I have got three questions if I might. The first question deals with costs and you have previously mentioned this approximately 28 billion cost target for '09. The most recent consensus data you sent out indicated it's forecasted at 29.6 billion. And I was wondering if there is any particular area where you think there is a big delta versus consensus in your internal cost targets. And if you give us some idea for the annual pre-tax profit impact from the new streamlined Corporate Center that you talk about?</p>
          <p>The second question deals with the legacy assets, in JP Morgan's Q2, 10-Q they have stated that in the third quarter to-date spreads on mortgage-backed securities and loans have sharply widened. And they kind of guided the market to expect a big mark in Q3. I was wondering if that's consistent with your view of what's going on with your legacy assets, and if it's not consistent, what's different?</p>
          <p>And then finally, the third question, it deals with your strategy of the three separate business units. I believe Mr. Rohner stated that cash flow generation in Wealth Management wouldn't be used to fund capital growth in the Investment Bank, but is there going to be a separate legal entity for these business units to ensure the capital destruction in one business unit doesn't have to impact the other business units. Or are they still going to be &#x2013; how is it going to work from a legal perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with Q3, that's a simple one, we don't want to give any Q3 specific updates or guidance at this moment in time.</p>
          <p>The cost target of 28 billion '09 just to make clear that this was a CHF28 billion at the March U.S. dollar Swiss franc exchange rate, which was about 1 &#x2013; 101 &#x2013; 102, so you have to factor in a dollar currency fluctuation if you want to update that. And as I have said in Swiss franc terms outside of the provision for the auction rate securities settlement of U.S. $900 million, the number was actually CHF7.2 billion for Q2, so we are relatively close to our &#x2013; to our set target and when we project the head count reduction as we have outlined them between now, the end of the year and then 2005, we believe that we have &#x2013; that we are very well on track to get to that run rate.</p>
          <p>With respect to the autonomous unit, the real driver is to optimize the structure such that we have the best way to fund the business going forward. For example, we have a model to operate in Europe with Eurobank called U.K. Ltd., which is fully collateralized and requires a huge amount of collateral to be provided to backup these activities. Such structures which will clearly consider if we want to continue with them and they would actually, if we would remove that into a different structure, that could help to substantially use the balance sheet. So it will be a question of optimization and not a question, which is driven by a leap consideration as it could be rather a consequence of it, if it's serving the purpose of running it more optimum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is no definitive plan to separate the capital base of the Investment Bank versus the capital base of the private bank i.e. protect the private bank from future potential losses in the Investment Bank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that operating out of a parent bank with a subsidiary or all of the parent bank will protect anything if it is in one group. So the real question is not protection question, the real question is which structure will allow us to optimize, in particular the funding structure and the liability structure of the bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I don't know if it is a detailed question, but any, given the sort of significant changes you are flagging in the Corporate Center, any guidance for us on where that pre-tax contribution should be going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, this is too early now &#x2013; this is going to be worked out in the change program as we have said over the next month to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Ms. Fiona Swaffield, Execution. Please go ahead madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have a few questions. The first thing was on write-downs. I just wanted to understand what you had said explicitly, I think I heard someone say that write-downs should diminish from here currently you haven't said anything explicitly about Q3, but could you just clarify that point?</p>
          <p>The second area is on the Tier 1 capital. I am just a little bit confused about this 2 billion treasury shares, because I think in Q1, you said you had a complete &#x2013; you had total 4 billion kind of holiday from deducting those treasury shares. So could we see another 2 billion reduced?</p>
          <p>And then the third question is on the assets and the fact that the balance sheet could go down further. Does that also apply for risk weighted assets, because they have obviously been much slower to reduce than assets? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will answer one and three and then hand over to Marco to speak to the treasury share issues. On write-downs, you have an extreme detailed description of what dispositions were &#x2013; which we were left with at the end of Q2. And you have also a very detailed description of how much we have provided for in the cases of the monoline credit exposure, which actually hasn't changed that much over Q2. And I think with these data points and everything else you observe, you can come to your own conclusion, what the impact will be. We can say that at this, levels of risk are substantially very significantly reduced.</p>
          <p>Then on the assets clearly it is always &#x2013; you reduce faster the balance sheet than you reduce risk weighted assets. I think that is &#x2013; these two functions over time are not the same, depending on the nature of the underlying assets and what you're actually do. But you can expect that the risk weighted assets will continue to diminish, because we are continuing &#x2013; we will continue reducing risks and we will continue to optimize the usage of our capital and funding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The treasury share accrual for EOP compensation plans, obviously we have accrued 2 billion to reflect what we thought was the right number to accrue for six months, so all other things equal you should see further accruals going forward. But let me caution you, because the accrual very much also depends on the share price development of UBS. If the share price goes up, we have to accrue less. If the share price were to come down, we would have to accrue more. But I cannot exclude further accruals. I would be surprised if the accruals are of the order of magnitude of 2 billion as you have seen them so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. But can I just ask to follow up on deferred tax because we haven't really discussed that. But the decision to take the 3.2 billion, I'm just trying to understand the different jurisdictions, because you've got a lot of tax loss carried forwards remaining that you haven't used. Is there any scope for those coming on balance sheet or if that requires the Swiss &#x2013; or the Swiss authorities to allow you to offset the losses against Swiss profits even though they are I think U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 3.2 is entirely a Swiss deferred tax asset. These losses happened in the U.S., but those losses in the U.S. have resulted us at the parent bank to have to write-down our holdings in our U.S. subsidiaries; and that's how they have become Swiss losses. In the U.S., we have some very old remaining deferred tax assets. We do not think we currently have the capacity of booking deferred tax assets higher in the U.S. So no don't expect any more deferred tax assets absent further losses, which we don't hope are coming through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Matthew Czepliewicz, HSBC. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Actually I have two questions on the restructuring into the three parts and then one on goodwill. And on the restructuring you said one of the objectives was increased transparency and I think the spirit of that observation was increase transparency on the real economics of the Group. But would it have implications for change in disclosure &#x2013; greater disclosure of the divisions or at Group level or a different format of disclosure?</p>
          <p>Second question relates to what Derek alluded to a moment ago and that was when you said the wealth management cash flow will not &#x2013; will no longer fund capital growth in the Investment Bank. Now that might not imply a pure segregation of these cash flows, but you did indicate in one of your releases that you will continue to invest in wealth management. And I am wondering if you look out a bit further to when the markets do stabilize, would some of your targets in wealth management maybe intensified a little bit, such as the 5 to 6% net new money growth over the course of this cycle?</p>
          <p>And then just a small third question, on you took a goodwill impairment charge on the closure of the U.S. muni business, I guess it was 340 million? If the markets remain turbulent like this, when we get to the end of the year, is it possible that we will see other goodwill impairment charges for others units in the Group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with the three &#x2013; the goodwill impairment Marco, and then I will then will answer to the other two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this muni business was part of PaineWebber when we acquired PaineWebber and then we allocated the muni business to the IB and that's when the goodwill was transferred, and since we exited that business that was goodwill allocated to that. The rest of the goodwill is not at risk of impairment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but there are no other, say small acquisitions in the Group that have been made when you feel that there is a risk of impairment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not for the time no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now first on excess cash flow wealth management. The real issue is that what do the shareholders expect from us and what do the individual business and what should the individual's business do. And when we look at where the cash flow should go from the wealth management business then we believe that once an IB platform is fully established, it should first and foremost generate enough cash that it can fund its own growth. But it's not &#x2013; but that's really what we are asking for. To have an Investment Bank, which funds its own growth from where it is, that's what it needs to deliver to make it a valuable part of the entire Group. The wealth management cash flow is clearly directed to the shareholder or directed to organic growth in wealth management, which we will clearly continue to do.</p>
          <p>And in that sense that translates into these growth targets you have referred to, which we'll clearly maintain. And I think these are medium and long-term growth targets, which are driven by our global market position and by the expected growth of the assets of wealthy individuals through the cycle.</p>
          <p>Then in terms of disclosure we do not expect that we do have to change the segments which we disclose. What might happen over time but that would also leave that to these streams which have &#x2013; we have very clearly outlined is that we're more transparent about what we actually do in terms of business flows between the divisions, we might be more transparent in terms of funding costs, funding arrangements and our drive to a standalone liability structure and as we have also said, we will continuously and we'll now revert the performance indicators to reflect those changes over the next three months to be introduced in 2009, that's the kind of additional transparency about the value of the individual businesses and the value of the flows within the Group, which we believe we can make much more transparent in this structure on top of the flexibility, which structure will ultimately create. So this is now, that was the last question from audio queue and we will now go to the audience here in the room to answer questions. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Thorne at Helvea; two questions. Firstly, could you give some indication of the &#x2013; your exposure to the European asset backed residential mortgage market in Spain, Italy and &#x2013; Spain, U.K. and maybe Ireland?</p>
          <p>And secondly, I mean &#x2013; I'd just ask you on your strategic review, you do, quote, 'and we'll provide maximum strategic flexibility to capture shareholder value in the future.' I mean can you just say what you can imagine that might be in terms of the joint ventures or whatever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let's start with the second one. Again, I think flexibility means two things. One is how we operate the businesses and we think that this will provide our business groups with agility given the uncertainties in the market. So, this is a value in itself. On the second one, we have no specific plans at this point in time. We create flexibility to capture shareholder value. And, therefore, I can't comment more on this, we have no plans at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to the risk disclosures, we have said in Q1 that we have made a very accelerated and rapid reduction in this asset category. We've continued to do so. And it is now way below the levels we would have to disclose under IFRS 7 risk disclosures. That's why you don't find any of them in the risks disclosure section.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, John O'Donnell is my name from Reuters. If perhaps you could comment on the new capital requirements, which are going to be introduced here in Switzerland for the big Swiss Banks later on this year. And what it means for Investment Banking. And if Investment Banking needs to be reduced in size, which are the parts, which are fundamental and important for UBS in the future, perhaps you could identify the priority areas to keep and the areas, which are perhaps capital intensive and maybe could be reduced.</p>
          <p>And also with the share price, where it is &#x2013; would management entertain a serious offer for the Group were it to be made from somebody interested in a merger or takeover. And then yeah, that's &#x2013; they are my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the first and last part of your questions. The first one you have seen at the EBK has made known its ideas about the new capital regime, both in terms of Tier-1 and leverage ratio. We are right now in discussion with EBK; these discussions for obvious reasons are confidential and we do not take a public position at this point in time.</p>
          <p>The last one, I think, we are not for sale as a Group and there is no bid for our Group at this point in time. Marcel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on the, on the Investment Bank, I think the reality is that where we are really strong are those businesses where we need comparatively less of a balance sheet and maybe with an exception of some financing businesses, Prime Brokerage where we have a very strong position, but when we look at that part in &#x2013; in terms of the whole balance sheet is actually still competitively small. So, we have a real opportunity basically to position ourselves going forward even in an environment with increased capital requirements because of who we are and where our strengths are.</p>
          <p>We have said before that we want to be an Investment Bank which is client driven, which has the faster client driven growth. And we have a number of businesses with very, very strong client flows as you have seen our Investment Banking department has done very well in an exceptionally difficult market environment, where the overall fee pools and transactions levels have come down massively. We have seen the prime brokerage cash has done well. We have obviously not done yet in derivatives, but derivatives are a self-funded business if it's run well. We have a very strong business in foreign exchange and short-term interest rates, where we can also do it with much reduced balance sheet level. So, we believe that the positioning we have chosen for our Investment Bank is consistent with where we see the main developments in the market and is also consistent with the capital regime which might be tighter than the one that we were used to in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have three questions. First, on the last issue just explain can you give a target on the balance sheet, you are trying to have by end of 2009 and not this is to end of 2009?</p>
          <p>Then referring to equity you give this MCN 12.4 billion which has changed from a liability to equity. I quite &#x2013; I don't understand how that can happen. Can you explain on how that works.</p>
          <p>And second can you tell us more about the situation in the U.S. regarding Mr. Liechti and the problems you are trying to solve there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, let me, want a timely balance sheet target of 2009, I think we leave it at the moment with the general statement that we want to have the divisions with a liability structure which compares to stand-alone competitors. And this implies that it will be smaller than today. You can assume that we will increase further beyond the target we have set for this year but the precise number and the precise target, we did not set yet I think that's coming out of the change program and the review and &#x2013; we have. We see that we will &#x2013; we will only by the end of 2009 approximately, we will have a liability structure and the funding management for the Group in place which is consistent with what we have said.</p>
          <p>On the MCN, this is a result from deliberations of the accounting professionals. The MCN had an upper and a lower conversion price. And that meant that the number of shares was not fixed, it could have been a little bit more or a little bit less shares into which the mandatory convert converts. Now with the adjustment of the upper price down to the lower one, it is clear how many shares we are going to receive and that means in accounting terms if you take it from a hybrid instrument into an equity instrument. So that's &#x2013; that.</p>
          <p>Then with respect to the last one as we have said before this is an issue we take very seriously with devoted substantial resources and work together in this intra-governmental framework and that's all we can tell you at this movement in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I &#x2013; Hello this is Elena Logutenkova from Bloomberg. I have two questions please.</p>
          <p>First of all in the Investment Bank, can you talk a little bit about your equities business there, whether you are satisfied with the performance so far, and outlook for remainder of the year, with regards to equities trading and equity capital markets?</p>
          <p>And the second question to Mr. Kurer, you said that that you have not received any offers for the Group. Have you received any offers or indications of interest for any part of your business? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the IB equity business we are clearly not satisfied. It is our core franchise. It has &#x2013; it had elements which have done really well and we haven't done as well as we think we should on the derivative side. That's because our derivatives business is Asia heavy, and in Asia the activities have slowed down more. So, that's why that has not performed to our expectations, we think this will improve in relative terms if the general conditions remain the same that this will improve for the remainder of the year and the capital markets business obviously is heavily driven by the activities in this particular area which have been coming down quite substantially now in this difficult environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the second question, this is obviously a time where a lot of people have interesting ideas, how they can buy assets at low prices. But I can confirm that we have not received any formal offer, which would come near to anything what I would call capturing shareholder value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Regarding the new structure, I was wondering whether you can say, Mr. Kurer, whether you are conducting a business review until the next shareholder meeting and what your strategy team in the Board is doing from now on and to the cost reductions, Mr. Suter, you might &#x2013; could you maybe outline where the next reductions come from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think we did the business review, we did the strategy review and this was a very elaborate process where we took outside views, where we talked to our business leaders. And where we built our own opinion, a comprehensive opinion where the critical question was, and this led to today's announcement. Going forward, the strategy committee will essentially do two things: first it will as I said supervise this process of the implementation which is in the hands of the executive management and establish a view whether or not this goes in the right direction. And then in a longer-term the strategy committee will review regularly the strategy of the Group to adjust it to the ever-changing environment.</p>
          <p>Your second question as to the costs I will turn to Marcel in a moment. But first I would like to express my view and convince that the separation and establishing autonomy and tying the incentives of the business group management to their own bottom line will obviously lead to a lot of additional efforts to create efficiency and maybe, Marcel, you can expand on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>CFO, receive the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On cost reductions you should see personnel cost reduction comes through in all business groups, we have given 5,500 reduction target under personnel you have seen part of that executed and it has some delay mechanism until that comes through. So, that is a cost item that should come down in all business groups; G&amp;A should come down in all business groups. G&amp;A has a lag effect to personnel reductions, for example rental expense, and it doesn't come down as soon as you exit the building. It's only once your rents actually expire, your contacts expire.</p>
          <p>So, you should see G&amp;A expense comes down and then we have a $900 million in a legal provision in this quarter. Obviously, and we had approximately 400 million legal provisions you have seen it in my slides, because I showed the delta for complete different cases. In Q1, those are the difficult costs to predict and I think you have to really filter them out to come to a normalized run rate to achieve the 28 billion level that Marcel has said. But I think we are clearly on track there, but it's clearly G&amp;A and personnel expense which are the key drivers. Personnel expense is always 75% of our costs, so that's where the gains are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Marcel, thank you. Haig Simonian, Financial Times. Can I just come back to the U.S. and the SEC and DOJ investigations, I've just got one question, could you confirm that Martin Liechti still is a UBS employee, and if that's the case could you tell me how that's consistent with Mark Branson's statement before the Senate Committee that UBS will provide the fullest possible cooperation given that Mr. Liechti decided to take the Fifth Amendment and not testify for fear of incriminating himself? Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Haig, I think, this is an obvious question, but for obvious reasons, I can't comment on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Claude Baumann on Weltwoche. You have announced the introduction of a new incentive system for the staff. Could you elaborate a little bit on what exactly are the main changes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we have said one of the purposes of this setup is to align incentives with the results what do we really mean, I think first of all, we felt also from experiencing the past as an institution but also from competitive comparison that it is very important in a risk-taking business that incentives are aligned with results, in order to balance risk, reward decision in an appropriate way, which we believe is very important from a shareholder perspective.</p>
          <p>And the second part is how to run a large, very complex group in a very efficient way. You can either pull everything up and have a very complex global functional model. So, have every function represented on the top, or otherwise you decide that you form the business units which are to some degrees self-contained and serve specific groups of clients. That's what the business review has clearly resulted in. These units they have all very relevant franchises, they can all grow and be successful; but that means that we should also control the resources within their remit in an appropriate way. So, aligning incentive structures with business result will therefore lead an increased efficiency within the businesses. So, these are the two objectives and how that will be structured in detail is one of the streams which we feel we can complete over the next approximately three months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'd take two more questions from the room and two more questions on the line. So, whoever comes first, yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Mr. Rohner could you perhaps explain how you want to keep referrals up in the new structure of the group, because generally that tends to be a problem area that banks have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're absolutely right. That's why I believe the way we want to set it up is exactly one way to approach it. So referral means a client wants to have business for more than one unit. And the reality is that managing these &#x2013; called in English term franchise overlap. Two businesses serving the same client is that we need a dedicated management of that and we need to have &#x2013; and that's in the remit of the regional CEOs in each region.</p>
          <p>That means at the end there is a lot of roll up sleeves work, identifying all those clients throughout the group, agree who is the key relationship manager, define what kind of services you want to provide and then, work down the list. That's very hard work, very systematic work, which we have already embarked on, but which we believe that we can further drive it if we also incentivize it appropriately and make it transparent, and set very explicit targets with respect to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there was a question over there, the lady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Handelszeitung. I have three questions for Mr. Rohner. The first one would be when do you expect to be profitable again, if it's possible on a quarterly basis. And then I would be interested in how long it will take to stop the net new money outflow in wealth management. And if you can give an indication how the situation was in July. And then, just a question &#x2013; if I understood it right, you don't have the intention to sell now some of your businesses, but you don't rule it out in long-term? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on profitability, you can assume that I personally have the highest desire of all in the room that we reach this moment as rapidly as possible. <mark type="inaudible" /> has asked me about three or four months ago, outside this room, if next year we will be profitable. And I said, of course, next year will be profitable. So, she asked me that in 2008. By the way, we didn't say that 2008 will be profitable, we had said in a year, we will be profitable.</p>
          <p>I think that's consistent with what the Chairman has said in terms of we have these problems resolved by the end of the year. And there is always a bit uncertainty around that. It can be a quarter earlier, a quarter later, but that's what we believe is the target to build the business back on track.</p>
          <p>Net new money outflows, look, it's always hard to say how long it takes until you're back. It's clearly related to your first question because I think profitability is the source of confidence building and that will bring all the businesses out and we'll be back on track. And we work very hard, we think we can create certainty with respect to risk, we are very close there, we created a lot of certainty with respect to the capital position, which is now as strong as before the crisis. Yet we are much less risky than we were before the crisis. That's an important element to bring the trust of clients back.</p>
          <p>We work extremely hard on all fronts with our clients, which is our main and key focus and concern at the moment. And that's why I do expect that this is a short-term phenomenon in its nature. We don't want to start to give mid-quarter update on the first month net new money flows, I think it is already a short-term look at net new money if you look at it quarterly. So, let's leave it with that and we will report on that at the end of the next quarter.</p>
          <p>And then in terms of the intention, I think the Chairman has said it several times, we want to create flexibility. But we do not intend to sell. And that &#x2013; these are exactly the two cornerstones of the statement. One more and then we go to the audio queue again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, can I ask to Mr. Rohner, will there be more personnel costs &#x2013; will personnel staff be more reduced than this 5,500 that you have already announced? And which will be the biggest, or most risky positions in the U.S. market, let's say, the general U.S. difficult positions in real estate and so on, where you still see some possibility or risks of write-downs? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all with respect to the personnel, we have announced at the last quarter results presentation that we do expect by mid-2009 a reduction of 5,500 people. We also said that we have &#x2013; we tried to manage that largely through attritions, but we might have redundancies here in Switzerland in the order of magnitude of 200. It might be when we do the review of what we can do in the repositioning that we have a slightly higher number here in Switzerland than this 200, I do not know exactly where it is. Not materially higher, but a bit higher. The overall numbers should not change materially over this period of time. We will know more as and when we run out through the change program.</p>
          <p>With respect to the risk exposures, on one hand we have our risk concentration disclosure in the report, that's the IFRS 7. Basically &#x2013; it's an assessment of what could happen in certain circumstances drives it. When we look at the narrower set of exposures, I can only say last quarter I said the big open issue is on the monolines and the remaining risk positions. Monolines we have done a lot more in terms of providing for, a lot more, and the risk provisions have been reduced very substantially over time. And that leaves us actually, from a qualitative point, saying these are what they are. But they are obviously much, much smaller now than they were before. Marco?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Less on risk position, but P&amp;L volatility, you will remember that we had 2.1 billion of own credit Q1 of this year, maybe 600 or so million Q4 of last year, and then 122 million debit actually second quarter of this year. But this means we have own credit sitting out there in the order of magnitude of 2.6 billion.</p>
          <p>So, if you see credit spread tightening on UBS that could have the biggest P&amp;L impact in any given quarter. So, what was a credit could come back as a debit. It will not affect tier 1 capital, because the credit was never allowed to credit, be taken into credit on tier 1 capital, but it can cost P&amp;L volatility. And it could frame our road on recovery, because on the recovery road, we should see credit spreads coming in and there is some P&amp;L cushioning sitting out there, which will start the P&amp;L recovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, I propose that we now take two more questions from the audio queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Kilian Maier, NZB. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, two short questions, the first one on your organizational structure. You're kind of reintroducing &#x2013; or introducing a matrix structure. Matrix has not been a huge success at other institutions, what does make you confident that it will work for UBS?</p>
          <p>And the second question on hiring of Relationship Manager, you said there was a pattern on net new a &#x2013; net new assets with the worst outflows being in April. Did this pattern also apply to the development of Relationship Manager?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On your first question, I think this is a misunderstanding; we are not introducing a matrix structure. A matrix structure would be where business lines and geographies would have equivalent powers. We have, clearly, a business line organization. However, in order to address a number of issues such as regulatory coordination, appearance in certain markets, and public policy, we will have regional CEOs as we have them now. And they'll be vested with certain powers. In particular, they will have a veto power on transactions in their jurisdiction if they think their reputational or other risks are too high. But it's not a matrix structure in the proper sense. I think I would agree with you that matrix structure is not the appropriate business model for a business like ours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of financial adviser movements, we actually have seen, as I said to you, a very stable development of financial hirings &#x2013; financial advisers, client adviser hirings and departures of &#x2013; I've told you that the fluctuation rate only slightly increased over the first part of the year. So, we don't see a correlation in the pattern between the client's reaction and the financial and client adviser hiring in the firm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Kinner Lakhani, ABN AMRO. Please go ahead, sir. Mr. Lakhani your line is open, you can ask your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I've got three questions, actually. Firstly, in terms of your total compensation expense at the Investment Bank, is down 50% year-on-year for the first half. And I guess the bonus accrual would be down even more aggressively. So, how do you feel you're positioned versus Street?</p>
          <p>Secondly, in terms of the deleveraging of the Investment Bank, what you've already done and what you intend to do? What do you &#x2013; how would you quantify the total kind of revenue and pre-tax impact?</p>
          <p>And finally, could you give us an idea about the risk exposures that might exist outside of U.S. RMBS and outside of the U.S? So, here I'm referring to U.K., Spanish RMBS CDOs, but also looking at auto loans and credit cards in the U.S?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First of all, the total comp had three elements. First of all, there is a significant staff reduction under way, which obviously brings down accruals. Secondly, we have had the effect on EOP, which has been explained by the CFO. And then thirdly, we have the general performance effect. And we believe that we compare very competitive to the Street, because that's what drives it &#x2013; be competitive and we want to be competitive there.</p>
          <p>Deleveraging impact, we've already quantified, we have given a target, the pre-tax of U.S. $4 billion pre-tax contribution from the Investment Bank. And this target is commensurate where we see the balance sheet going. And I think that's the way I would phrase it.</p>
          <p>And then in terms of risk exposures, I really refer again to the risk concentration section. That's where we make a determination what we believe is a risk concentration and the conclusion from that is that if it is not there, it is not the concentration. And all the exposures you have addressed would be considered immaterial concentrations in our risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, with that we are at the end of the section. Thank you very much for your attention and the questions you've asked. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>