<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1285060" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>631</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Caroline Stewart, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Oswald J. Gr&#xFC;bel, Group Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John Cryan, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Haig Simonian</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Jacques-Henri Gaulard</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Kilian Meier</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Teresa Nielsen</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Fiona Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Derek De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Huw van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Jernej Omahen</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Matt Clark</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Matthew Clark</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and welcome to UBS's Fourth Quarter Results Presentation. My name is Caroline Stewart and I'm the Head of Investor Relations for UBS.</p>
          <p>During today's meeting, we'll have two presenters. First of all, our CEO, Ozzy Gr&#xFC;bel will present to you briefly on the highlights of the fourth quarter results and also on our achievements over the course of 2009. After Ozzy, our CFO, John Cryan will present the results to you in detail. Then we'd like to take your questions in the normal format, first of all, analysts and investors and then journalists. Following a short break, we'll resume with Q&amp;A for journalists in German.</p>
          <p>Before I get started &#x2013; before we get started today, I'd like to draw your attention to this slide. This slide is a disclaimer with respect to forward-looking statements, the presentation today will include forward-looking statements. I'd recommend that you read this slide in detail at your leisure and with that, I'd like to hand over to Ozzy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Caroline. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen and good morning everybody on the web.</p>
          <p>A year ago nearly, in April at the general meeting of UBS, we set out some goals and we told our shareholders that our priorities are to increase our capital ratios, to reduce our risk positions, to bring the Bank back to profitability as soon as possible because we know profits are essential for winning back the trust of clients and I think that are the main &#x2013; had been the main tasks we had during last year. And we are pleased to say that at least in the fourth quarter of last year, which was not a very exciting quarter from a trading point of view, we were able to be profitable in all our divisions. Now that is only a first step. We cut costs last year by 3 billion and, which was necessary not only because of the contraction in banking but also because of our special situation.</p>
          <p>Also, what is satisfying for me doesn't get repeated too much in the paper is that we were able actually to produce an operating profit for 2009 of 1.4 billion and that is after we also paid a bonus of 3 billion for 2009 to the more than 65,000 people we have all over the world. We also restructured our fixed income department and which will enable us to, or is a first step actually, to be profitable in Investment Banking going forward.</p>
          <p>So in general, let me tell you things are going according to plan as I have told you in the previous quarters as well. Naturally we had to find out that nearly 12 months is a very long time for anybody to keep his patience and to trust us that we actually can deliver on what we said before. One of the sore points is, and which everybody pointed out so far this morning, clearly is that we still are losing assets partly to the competition and partly to market changes.</p>
          <p>We do know that we have to stop that and that we have to, as a first goal, cannot be worse than our peers and we're working very hard on that. One of the first steps is clearly to return to profitability which we have done now, but certainly it's not only a quarter we have to be profitable in all, say, following quarters as well to get the trust and the reputation, so trust in UBS and the reputation of UBS Bank with our clients.</p>
          <p>We have done some measures in regard to that. So we are integrating the Bank to have a better client offer. We are becoming more efficient in execution, what we can offer our clients and that combined with the profitability should in time bring us back to a trusted bank and also to stop the asset outflows. Part of the outflows, and we will see that when we see the results for other banks, is clearly is a special situation of the Swiss financial center or financial marketplace and which is changing and changing more since in the last year 50 years than in any time in the last 50 years. And we will see what will develop there.</p>
          <p>UBS has, I think, a big competitive advantage because we are not only still in Switzerland the biggest wealth manager, we are also in many countries in Europe onshore one of the biggest foreign wealth managers there and, which we have built up over the last 10 years and that will be of more value going forward as things develop now.</p>
          <p>Now for the detailed figures, I will give over to our Chief Financial Officer, John Cryan and I'm looking forward to your questions later after the presentation. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ozzy. And good morning, everyone. It's my pleasure to take you through some of the details of our results for the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>As Ozzy just mentioned, we are delighted to be reporting a net profit attributable to shareholders of 1.2 billion for the fourth quarter. It's equivalent to diluted earnings of 31 Rappen per share.</p>
          <p>Equally pleasing as he mentioned, is the fact that during the quarter all of our business divisions reported pre-tax profits. And it's the first time we've seen an overall Group reported pre-tax profit since before the crisis hit.</p>
          <p>Operating results that although somewhat weak, held up comparatively well considering market conditions drove our profits, whereas we saw costs come down fairly significantly.</p>
          <p>We continue to build our financial strength, increasing our capital through profit retention and further reduction of our legacy risks in the investment bank. Our Tier 1 capital at the end of the quarter was 15.4%.</p>
          <p>One area where we do need to do more work is on the clients' invested asset flows in all three of our asset gathering divisions. Each one saw continued outflows in the quarter and it shall remain a key focus for management into 2010.</p>
          <p>This chart shows the fourth quarter performance by division. All of our business divisions report significantly improved quarter-on-quarter results and the IB has reported a pre-tax IFRS profit for the first time since Q2, 2007.</p>
          <p>We'll go through the detailed results for each division as usual, but at this point let me make some remarks on the results overall. In all of the divisions, the results were boosted by the accounting impact of our decision to bring staff compensation into line with current industry practice and regulatory guidance by increasing the proportion of variable compensation to be distributed in the form of deferred share grants. This has had the effect of deferring into future periods, the recognition of a greater proportion of the overall cost of variable compensation for the 2009 performance year.</p>
          <p>The own credit charge for the fourth quarter is just 24 million versus 1.4 billion in Q3. We've reallocated around CHF 700 million of negative revenues from prior period own credit and DVA in Investment Bank to the corporate center, where it's reflected as negative trading income.</p>
          <p>The reallocation resulted from a number of adjustments we've made to the way that we calculate and book the impact of own credit effects on our derivative positions and on the medium-term notes we measure at fair value. The overall impact of the change on the Group's results was immaterial, a net charge for the quarter of just CHF 6 million.</p>
          <p>And we've re-valued our deferred tax assets at the end of the year in light of our latest internal profit forecasts and we were able to write-up the asset related to tax losses in the U.S. by CHF 467 million and so is the principle driver in the overall tax credit of CHF 480 million.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the pre-tax result for the whole of 2009. In the first three quarters, we adjusted our numbers for a handful of significant items so as to better explain our underlying performance. And to give you an overall view, I've now adjusted for these items on a consistent basis for the full year.</p>
          <p>We finished the year with a reported pre-tax loss of just over CHF 2.5 billion, adjusting for the own credit changes in the fair value of our liabilities, the net charges related to the sale of Pactual, restructuring charges and the net gain on the MCNs, we show an underlying pre-tax profit for the year of CHF 1.4 billion.</p>
          <p>To the right of the chart you can see that the asset gathering divisions all contributed positively to the result, whereas it was not until the third quarter that the Investment Bank started to make a positive contribution.</p>
          <p>This slide shows a quarter-by-quarter summary of our revenues. You will see that income from interest margin businesses and fee and commission income continued to be stable into the fourth quarter. The improvement in overall revenues was driven by a reversal of fortunes in trading income over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>Costs fell 18% quarter-on-quarter, though this was attributable to the deferral of variable compensation costs to future periods. Non-personnel expenses increased, mostly on the back of increased legal provisions and professional fees and some further restructuring costs.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the breakdown of our annual costs by type and shows you the split between the fixed, variable and non-recurring elements. We set ourselves a target of lowering our fixed cost base to an annual run rate of CHF 20 billion by the end of 2010. And you can see that we've essentially achieved that goal in 2009. Non-personnel expenses fell by over CHF 2 billion across all major categories. And we would expect to see costs continue to reduce on an underlying basis into 2010.</p>
          <p>Variable compensation accruals in 2009 totaled just less than CHF 3 billion. This number includes the IFRS accrual for the variable compensation we proposed to pay in respect of the 2009 performance year plus the amortization of other effects related to the previous years.</p>
          <p>The overall amount of deferred compensation for 2009 and for prior years, with under IFRS requirements is carried forward into 2010 and later years is CHF 3.2 billion. Staff numbers fell by over the 5% in Q4, just under half of that reduction was the result of the sale of our Indian Service Center in Hyderabad. Over the course of 2009, head count fell by over 12,500 and ended the year a little higher than the target of 65,000 we set ourselves for achievement in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the divisions. Wealth Management and Swiss Bank produced a solid performance in the fourth quarter despite weaknesses in client activity levels. Headline profits were up 40% quarter-on-quarter, principally reflecting the changes to variable compensation. Even excluding this effect, we saw a slight improvement in performance, reflecting management's actions to offset continuing pressure on operating margins with efficiency gains.</p>
          <p>Revenues basically held up, recurring fees were flat on Q3. Interest income on client deposits and on the credit books continued to decline but this was largely offset by lower internal funding charges. Brokerage and sales commissions fell largely as a result of a very quite December.</p>
          <p>Invested Asset balances at the end of December stood at 960 billion, down 2% in the quarter. Net new money was disappointing. We saw net outflows from Swiss clients of CHF 5.9 billion, not withstanding the positive contribution from corporate and institutional clients. Net outflows from international clients increased to over 27 billion from around 13 billion in the prior quarter.</p>
          <p>This segment seems to have been particularly affected by the current discussions regarding banking secrecy in Switzerland and the impact of further proposed tax treaties between Switzerland and other countries. More positively, the Asia Pacific region as a whole saw net new money inflows in the quarter and outperformed our other international Wealth Management businesses.</p>
          <p>On this slide I've shown the picture on net new money over the past four years. Although the net outflows in 2009 were lower than those we saw in 2008, the situation with client flows remains a primary focus of management. The conditions at the end of 2009 reflect a numbers of special factors.</p>
          <p>Invested assets amounting to 22.8 billion were affected by the Italian tax amnesty. We retained 63% of this balance within the Bank but suffered margin erosion on the overall amount. We also lost invested assets of over CHF 5 billion as a result of the sale of Pactual and in 2009 we saw outflows of around 6.3 billion as a direct consequence of our decision to exit certain businesses, most notably the offshore business with east &#x2013; west clients.</p>
          <p>Approximately a quarter of the 90 billion of outflows we suffered in 2009 seem to have been the direct result of client advisor attrition.</p>
          <p>Invested assets of international clients remained stable throughout the year as market performance offset net outflows. Average invested asset balances in 2009 were 22% lower than those of 2008. The number of client advisors fell by 25%, impacted by management action to resize the business.</p>
          <p>We've now launched initiatives to hire additional new client advisors. Though in Q1 we would expect the overall number of advisors to be slightly lower than it was at year-end. We have seen efficiency gains in client coverage. The average balance of invested assets managed by client advisor, has increased to just under CHF 200 million.</p>
          <p>For Wealth Management Americas, the fourth quarter was the best of the year with the division reporting a pre-tax profit of 178 million. Revenues increased and expenses, other than direct financial advisor compensation, fell. Revenues did include a non-recurring gain of 35 million from the close-out of a portfolio of replication swaps and matched funding transactions, as a result of our decision to transfer into this division an investment portfolio from the IB.</p>
          <p>Invested assets fell by CHF 4 billion in the quarter to 690 billion, largely due to 12 billion of net outflows. Invested assets were also negatively impacted by around 4 billion due to the sale of branches.</p>
          <p>Personnel decreased by 750 or 4%. Of these, 200 or so were financial advisors and a little over a third of whom left the bank as result of the branch sales.</p>
          <p>Despite the improvement in profitability, FA recruiting and the net new money generation remain challenging. However, Bob McCann has put a new leadership team in place and we're optimistic for the longer-term prospects of the business.</p>
          <p>Global Asset Management's pre-tax profit more than doubled quarter-on-quarter to 284 million. The improvement was cost driven, as revenues were impacted by lower performance fees and by the sale of Pactual. The expense reduction was driven by lower personnel costs following the group-wide decision to increase significantly the proportion of deferred compensation.</p>
          <p>Here net new money was disappointing with outflows of CHF 11 billion, some 7.2 billion of which were originated through the Wealth Management channels. There were however some encouraging signs of increased gross inflows across a number of asset classes and investment performance across a wide range of strategies remains very impressive, with a large proportion of our core funds out-performing their benchmarks. We would expect the out-performance that we saw in Global Asset Management in 2009 to have a positive impact on net new money in 2010.</p>
          <p>The Investment Bank reported a profit for the fourth quarter of just under CHF 300 million, compared with a loss of just under 1.4 billion in the prior quarter. The biggest factor in the improvement was the reduction in the own credit charge from over 1.4 billion in Q3 to just 24 million in Q4.</p>
          <p>Expenses for the quarter were CHF 1.8 billion, down from the previous run rate of around 2.5 billion as again &#x2013; as a consequence of the decision to defer variable compensation to a greater extent than had been previously assumed in the year-to-date accruals. The IB continued to de-risk. The division's risk-weighted assets finished the year 37% lower than they'd been at the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>The IB reported revenues of over CHF 2 billion in the quarter on an operating basis increased revenues in IBD, were offset by lower trading income in both equities and FICC. Also as I mentioned earlier, the fourth quarter charge for own credit was impacted by the re-allocation of own credit effects amongst the DVA impact on trading income, treasury income and own credit.</p>
          <p>The impact of the tightening of our senior debt curve on the 24 million of reported own credit for Q4 was 544. The difference of 520 million was the volume effect, and all but 37 million of that was the result of the re-allocation to the corporate center. I know it's a bit complicated and I'd be happy to take details &#x2013; questions later but there are details of the changes set out in note 11-B in the Fourth Quarter Report.</p>
          <p>Consistent with previous years, the fourth quarter 2009 advisory revenues were up on a seasonal basis, recording a 17% increase. Capital markets were down &#x2013; capital markets' revenues were down 12% to CHF 590 million despite an overall improvement in the debt capital markets. Risk management charges against the franchise-lending portfolio more than halved quarter-on-quarter, in line with stabilizing credit market conditions.</p>
          <p>Total sales in trading revenues in the fourth quarter were just short of CHF 1.5 billion compared with over 2.1 billion in Q3. In Equities, revenues declined 18% to just under 950 million, as the business was affected by subdued volumes and a general slowdown in client flows, especially towards the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>In FICC, revenues declined 50% to just under 500 million. Credit revenues held up and were in line with the previous quarter. The rack macro revenues particularly in rates saw a significant drop in client driven volumes. We saw fewer trading opportunities and a tightening of bid/offer spreads. Emerging Markets revenues were flat in Asia, but declined elsewhere.</p>
          <p>The FICC revenues continued to be impacted by some of our legacy risks. We saw net negative revenues of approximately CHF 300 million from those positions, not withstanding a positive contribution of around CHF 200 million from our remaining monoline insured negative basis trades.</p>
          <p>The underlying run rate of revenues from what we might term our core FICC operations was therefore 800 million for the quarter, which is still some way short of our medium-term target of around CHF 2 billion.</p>
          <p>I won't dwell on the final two slides for too long. Our capital position remains extremely strong. Our core Tier 1 capital ratio is 11.9%. And our overall BIS Tier 1 ratio is 15.4%. And on the FINMA's calculation basis, our leverage ratio is now just short of 4%.</p>
          <p>Turning just to the balance sheet, footings in the quarter fell by CHF 135 billion or around 9%. In year as a whole, we brought the balance sheet down by a third. And we now run a funded balance sheet excluding the IFRS replacement values of a little over CHF 900 billion.</p>
          <p>And so to wrap up, we finished the year with a return to profit and in an optimistic frame of mind for 2010. Clients now have every reason to place full confidence in UBS. We look forward to serving their needs whilst delivering improving returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And with that, I think we have some time for some questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We take the questions first here in the room in English and later we will take them in German and after the room we go to the web. Over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry to be a bore. Haig Simonian, Financial Times. I'd just like to clarify please a small procedural point. A couple of years ago, the Bank foolishly decided to split the audience into two groups of questioning and take questions from investors first and then from media. That's of course entirely your decision. You then wisely reversed that and allowed us all to be treated on the same basis. Mysteriously in your introduction you implied you'd reverted to the first and second-class citizen basis. I'd be most grateful if you could clarify that, because certainly now that you webcast these events, there is no point whatsoever for local journalists to attend at this early time if you are going to spend two hours speaking to another group first. We can just turn up when it suits us. Please, be so kind as to explain what you'd like to do. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a procedural issue and we would like to take questions, be it from journalists or be it from analysts in English first and then we're taking them in German. And first we start with the room here, so you can ask, as you just did, in English and then we go on the web and afterwards we take them in German. That satisfactory? And we would never class society in Switzerland, we're not one of these countries. Should we go ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Jacques-Henri Gaulard, I'm an analyst and I work for Autonomous Research. John, a question about the own credit and what is the overall rationale for effectively the change and the transfer? I had a look at note 11-B and maybe &#x2013; does it mean you're going to change a little bit the guidance? I mean until now it was fairly easy on own credit. It was depending on where the spread of UBS was and you were aligning the forecasts accordingly. Is this now changing on the back of what you've done?</p>
          <p>The other two questions would be on Private Banking. In light of the outflows at, I would say, at the end of the year, does it mean you're going to have to change somehow your targets for Private Banking or does it mean you're starting from obviously a lower point? Is it disappointing versus what you were expecting internally? And I would say on the Administrative Tribunal courts, can we easily make the link between the 10,000 accounts that have to be given to the IRS, and of which 4,400 having to come from UBS, basically? And again maybe, you know your confidence as to when this thing is going to be sorted because I think it's a very big drag on just on press at the moment. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer first the Private Banking questions or Wealth Management questions. And about the deliveries and the case between the UBS and the Swiss government, at the time when the understanding was which between the U.S. and Switzerland, it clearly also was talked about that the courts could put a stop to the whole thing and that's why we and &#x2013; have a responsibility to deliver the data to the Swiss courts, and who then will decide what is happening afterwards. And we as UBS had certain responsibilities, very well defined responsibilities what we had to deliver to the Swiss courts and that we did. And that's all we can do at UBS and nothing else.</p>
          <p>Now in the DPA, there is a line which says that everything is coopted in the 10,000 cases from UBS accounted at the Internal Revenue Service, and that is, to the best of our knowledge, not yet the case. And &#x2013; but still I cannot see what it changes, provided the whole case stays open, but we did whatever we had to do. We are not a fault at anything and we will see how the negotiations now between the U.S. and the Swiss will conclude.</p>
          <p>On general, the asset outflows we see are certainly as disappointing to us as they are to you, as analysts, or to the public. And now we had years before very strong growth and stronger growth than most of our competitors, and that might be a reason that we attracted assets which we are losing at the moment again. But we should not, and I said a year ago, not underestimate the reputational damage we engineered for ourselves and it takes some time to get over that. And we have a delayed effect of the client advisors, which left the Bank so that will go on for a few months more.</p>
          <p>Then you have the market change here in Switzerland, I think that's probably the best word to express what is going on all over the place. And I think all along, we are as I said before in a good position because we are the biggest bank and strongest bank in any onshore businesses outside Switzerland and that is a strategy we will continue to develop and become &#x2013; grow stronger there.</p>
          <p>We see exception in East Asia where we actually are not losing any assets every quarter. We are actually winning there and which is satisfying but so does everybody else as well, I presume. So we think with a few more quarters of profitability and by doing what we &#x2013; what we said we will be doing in the Bank by integrating certain services, by offering an integrated advice to our clients, by having an Investment Banking which is working much closer to guest service, the other divisions and by being also much better going forward because we had to rebuild huge parts of Investment Banking as you know. That will help to get across the picture of more competence and the picture of reliability of UBS and will bring back with the profits also the trust. It needs patience unfortunately and I know neither you nor I have it, so but never mind, we have to wait a little bit longer there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want me to do the own credit question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think it is -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More likely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>more likely than if I do it, because he doesn't want to be confused anymore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Jacques-Henri, the first thing about own credit, if I give you a 10-second refresher. We fair-value these liabilities they're &#x2013; they're mostly MTNs and they're issued out of Jersey, and the money is used in the Investment Bank by and large. It's used within the Group, but the money goes back into the Investment Bank. And Jersey hedges itself with a swap with the relevant debt in equities or fixed income, so that it is not exposed to whatever exotic return is paid on the MTN. So, it's standard stuff.</p>
          <p>Now, before own credit existed, before IFRS 7 came in, you used to have to bifurcate those MTNs into a debt host and a derivative contract and value them separately to park that. In Q4 2007 we &#x2013; own credit was introduced and we applied it. And that values the MTN as a whole, and you fair-value it through the P&amp;L. And you adjust it for the UBS credit spread. Now, we've been doing that consistently for several quarters. This quarter we've made some adjustments which are prior period adjustments which we pushed through this quarter, the net effect of which are immaterial, 6 million debit to P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>But, within the quarter, in the disclosures, there is an own credit. So, if we go back to Q3, to give you a comparable number for Q4, remember own credit is two-dimensional. It's the credit spread and then it's the volume effect, as we call it. The MTN changes fair value for reasons other than our credit spread. The impact in the quarter for our credit spread was 544 negative, debit, which you'd imagine is about the right number, it was 1.436 in Q3 and our credit spreads tightened by about a third as much in fourth quarter. And the volume effect was a credit, happened to be of just 37. So the number would have been minus 507 and it's in the accounts, it's there. It's just masked by the fact that an adjustment of 483 as a credit which comes in from the treasury which is the net number of 24. And the reason that 483, the net number comes in from the treasury is that when you break up these MTNs &#x2013; there was a little bit of a calculation error to be honest, in the way that the treasury and the IB were interfacing. And the way that the treasury hold itself harmless from the exotic return on the MTN is that it entered into swap and the treasury was supposed to pay a funding spread to the IB on that swap, on the pay leg. And it hadn't been factored in, so actually we were not crediting the IB with enough in the past and we were taking too much treasury income and so we just re-allocated it.</p>
          <p>Now it's quite a conservative re-allocation because we have actually taking treasury income which counts for example as capital and converted 483 million of it into own credit which doesn't count as capital. And so it's 20 odd basis points of capital that &#x2013; our 15.4 would have been 15.6 plus, 15.7 even. So it's a relatively conservative change, the net impact is six so. The other 201, if you are looking for the difference, is a transfer into the DVA, into the derivatives in the IB and that's a sort of nil other effect. But the own credit is in there and the number you should probably use as a comparable number to the 1.4 billion of Q3, is 507 which is the net of the credit spread effect plus the volume effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Kilian Meier, NZB Neue Z&#xFC;rcher Bank. Two questions. In your outlook, you mentioned some margin pressure going forward potentially. Could you probably elaborate on the reasons for that? And the second question is a regulatory one. Here in Switzerland, the potential introduction of automatic data exchange is very much in the news. Maybe you can give us the UBS view on that and also tell us how such an introduction or regulatory change would impact your business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The margin pressure is coming from the yield curve that corporate rates are very low and that yield curve is flattening probably going out and therefore margins, especially in the mortgage market will clearly contract and that was mainly what our &#x2013; corporate and retail business was referring to.</p>
          <p>Now with automatic information exchange, I think we are still a long way away from that and regardless what was said in the last two weeks on heated comments and either from certain government ministers or in the public. And I think what has to happen and it looks like going that way that Switzerland will talk to the EU or to the main states within the EU to find an agreement how to go forward. Because even inside the EU, Luxemburg and honestly I have to find way of going forward because they are not yet on the information &#x2013; on the automatic information exchange. So we have to see how that is playing out. How does it affect us? I think it affects us less than many other banks here in Switzerland mainly because we are a global bank, mainly because we have hundreds of billions of assets in Wealth Management outside Switzerland and are onshore in many European countries and that will be clearly from today's point of view, a market which will grow stronger looking forward that it probably was in the past. And what we have built up in the last decades here I think will become quite profitable looking forward. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Teresa Nielsen, Bank Vontobel. Could you give us some insight into UBS exposure to government debt in Greece and in Spain? My second question is on the gross margin in Wealth Management International Clients fourth quarter was down to 82 basis points, what are the measures that you are going to take or that you have taken in order to increase it to your mid-term target of 100 basis points? And the last question is regarding the Investment Bank business. Have you continued to hire high quality people, senior people in the Investment Banking trading businesses in the fourth quarter and in January in order to improve the profitability? I know that you did it in the summer. And are you hiring mainly for emerging market business or is it also for developing market business? Can you give some insight into the possibility of increasing your profit through hiring in the Investment Bank? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Investment Banking, we are hiring selectively in the areas which we have to build out and there Emerging Markets is clearly one of the area, but we concentrated very much on the Fixed Income area. And hopefully going forward in the next few months you will see results &#x2013; that as a result that has in Wealth Management, we did say on Investor Day that we want to improve our gross margin there and you're correctly saying it's going the other way at the moment which is why they are like interest rate movements and have an influence there, but that journal article of increasing that much we just strongly believe can be done regardless of what the market environment is and we should be able to over time get to a margin of 100 basis points, as we said. Unfortunately we can't tell you how long it will take us to get there, but we are working in Wealth Management and within the Bank on that indication a better client offering, better execution is a part of that, and so we'll discuss it obviously in the coming quarters. Can you take the rest?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the exposures to European countries are subject to our normal country credit limit caps and they are in line with the size of the relevant economies. We have no particularly large exposures to any of the European economies, the emerging economies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the mic switched on actually or -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, is that better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The variable comp in 2009 was 3 billion, could you indicate roughly what it would have been had you had the same portion of fixed and variable in the fourth quarter as you had in the first part of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the answer to that is we obviously only pay bonuses once a year so, the accruals that we make during the course of the year are essentially estimates of where we might end up. When we set the bonus structures at the end of the year, we essentially look back to see how much we have accrued year-to-date and then true it up for what we need for that annual bonus round. We were accruing at a higher rate than we needed to accrue in Q4 obviously because the accrual came down, but it's hard to say what we would have paid because we didn't. We only set up the structure that we've finally agreed as our management team. It would have been higher but it's impossible to say how high it would have been because we didn't actually have different bonuses, we only have these ones. But it obviously would have been higher because the effect of deferring pushes forward the accounting recognition of that expense into future periods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question, please. Are there any questions in here anymore in English? Fine, then &#x2013; there was one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Concerning the planned reforms in the banking sector and specifically the requirement on capital and liquidity. How will these reforms affect your mid-term goals, return to growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is clearly depending on what will be introduced. There had been some suggestions by the Basel committee going forward, but there is not yet any agreement. Certainly not on the banking side and also not the governmental side who &#x2013; which countries will participate, will the rules be changed or the proposals be changed and in what direction. So there we really have to wait what finally is coming out. Can we &#x2013; yes, sorry, here was a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, <mark type="inaudible" /> from the newspaper, La Libert&#xE9;. Regarding the two data client lists that have been offered to Germany, could you please tell us whether there is any UBS client that might be concerned by these two lists? Second question, all that has been going recently with Germany so these lists and additionally the so-called Carlsmeir case, do you feel any impact of these discussions on your business there? And then thirdly, about the stolen data problems, what can a bank such as UBS do to protect oneself from these kinds of thefts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do not know if any UBS clients are on any disc, which is apparently offered or allegedly offered to anybody and especially to German local government, because this &#x2013; we have no knowledge that we have a reason to believe that any of our employees delivered any data to anybody outside the Bank. Generally, it is a problem, I think we have to realize if governments are in the market, and it seems that certainly is the case with Germany, of buying illegal data that changes the world. And &#x2013; if that is going on. And we will see how &#x2013; what the outcome of that is in the months to come. That is a general comment, I think, because if you induce people through high payments to steal data, whatever data and, yes that changes an environment, which is very clear, which you know as well. And we don't see how do the developing. But as I said before, the big banks here in Switzerland are probably because they're much more international in their business and not only Swiss-centered are less affected then some others. Can we take some questions now from the web and can we please start with the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question from the telephone conference is from Mrs. Fiona Swaffield, Execution. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just a question on slide 12, the buy off on client advisor attrition, I think is around 22 billion, which was very helpful disclosure. I just &#x2013; could you talk a bit about whether that was more in the second half than in the first half? And then how much you're retaining when a client advisor leaves, that you're retaining less than you normally do. I think my gut feeling is you often say you retain about 70, 80%, is it lower? And so could I use that 22 billion to assume you could have similar kind of client advisor impact in 2010? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we certainly do not hope that that trend is continue and we have also so far no reason to believe that the normal rate &#x2013; normal percentage rate client advisors when they leave for another bank are taking around 30 to 40% of the clients they had before with them. And so at the moment, we have no reason to believe that that has changed and we clearly hope and working on it, that that is changing for us to the better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But just to check, the 22.5 would have largely been a second half issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it increased a little bit over the year, obviously as the number of client advisors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just trying to understand the time lag.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Who left.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, most client advisors were either fired or left the Bank in the middle of the year, and they are on three to six months, depending on seniority, notice period, and so that is one reason probably why we had in the fourth quarter the biggest impact so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. <mark type="inaudible" /> Barclays Capital. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, good morning. Just three quick questions please. Firstly, continuing on that slide 12 disclosure, which again is very helpful. In the bottom orange segment that you highlight, it concerns about banking secrecy et cetera, et cetera. Could you talk about the geographic skew within that? I mean is that &#x2013; and in particular do you see particular problems in say Germany and France where you've had the governments actively seeking account data? Second question, could you comment and hopefully quantify January flows from the Private Bank? And then last question, I think you said you deferred 3.2 billion of comp from '09 into future periods; could you give us the corresponding figure for the previous three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 3.2 billion are for all our deferred number, they are not for '09. That would be nice if they were for '09, but they are all -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you're saying that's the cumulative -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is cumulative for all the years in the past and going into the future, so including '09. Then on the outflows, there is no specific trend that we see that the outflows are to Germany or to France and there is no big repatriation trend to make out at the moment, but clearly the discussions, the media attention will have an effect on the clients, on some clients and so we will have to see what will happen in the next few months. What was the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The January first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The January number --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't like giving day-by-day updates on our net new money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Can I then come back just on the deferral question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If the 3.2 is the cumulative, could you say how much out of the '09 comp is deferred and then also as I say what out of '08 and what out of '07?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't disclose that, Jeremy, but we do disclose in the Annual Report the amount of compensation each year that is deferred into the future. So -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The equivalent of the 3.2 in the past three years you'd be able to get from the Annual Report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I know the numbers but I am not going to guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not going to risk it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeremy. And the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Jon Peace, Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, morning. In the Investment Bank you said that the January run rates of client activity had been very strong. I just wonder if you could clarify that a little bit more, maybe in relation to for example your 2 billion target run rate in Fixed Income. And secondly, could you have a go at quantifying the potential impacts of the Volcker proposal to ban prop trading, et cetera? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Starting with the last one, the Volcker proposal has none or very negligible affect on UBS as far as we can see at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think that's right. We've got a small segregated prop trading business in Arizona, but it doesn't feature very heavily. On the January run rate, again we don't like giving up to the minute updates on where the business is going. I think we've obviously been looking at what some other banks have been reporting. And they all seem to be indicating that particularly in the Fixed Income markets, the operating environment has being fairly propitious, as I &#x2013; the word I used earlier. And therefore the amount of client flow business has been fairly attractive. And the low credit spreads have moved around. They contracted and then widened and contracted again, and volatility has moved up and down. That's quite a good operating environment for a trading business. So it's &#x2013; so far it's a lot better than Q4 is all we're saying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But January always is, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Kinner Lakhani, Citi. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. I've got two questions actually. First on Wealth Management, where we've talked about the net flows. Could you talk to the gross inflows over the past eight quarters actually, how those have generally trended? Second question, on the Investment Bank, how far are you down the road of making the hires that you needed to to re-build the various businesses and what market share trends do you see across the key businesses such as cash equities, FX and the primary side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On cost inflows, I think on Investor Day we only go for an inclination that they exceeded 20 billion each quarter, and all I can tell you there is no change since then, but otherwise we do not say more about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the IB, we once ran the IB to gain market share and it didn't really work doing that, so we run the IB now to make a profit. And as a consequence of that, we have been hiring people into areas where we think we can make a profit, where we've had gaps which are important gaps for our clients. We made some important hires in the course of January. Now we can never say we've stopped, but most of the major roles are now occupied by people.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Derek De Vries, Bank of America &#x2013; Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, this is Derek. I had two questions if I may. The first one I think Mr. Gr&#xFC;bel said that the delayed impact of private bankers leaving on net new money would continue for a few months more. And I was wondering if you &#x2013; does that imply that the amount of private bankers leaving is kind of done and then you'll see the outflows continue? Is that what's meant by that comment?</p>
          <p>And then my second question comes to liquidity. I think throughout the crisis you've maintained a very strong liquidity position. And I was wondering if you'd be willing to quantify what your stable funding ratio looks like under the Basel II or Basel III proposals, recognizing that a lot can change by the time they are implemented.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, first the outflows and the connection to the client advisors. As I said before, most of the client advisors were either fired or moved in the middle of last year. So if they found immediately new jobs, if you assume that they would have found by the end of last year all new jobs. And that is the reason probably or one of the reasons why we had stronger outflows in the fourth quarter. That can go on for quite a few months and now and all we can do against that is to try to improve our offer to clients and try to increase our credibility and so on as I mentioned before. When it exactly will stop &#x2013; it will stop when no client advisors leave anymore and but most of the adjustments that had been done in the middle of last year. Though things going forward hopefully look better if there are no other reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on liquidity we haven't given any information on our stable funding ratios under the proposed BIS rules. Safe to say that the disclosure we do give our liquidity shows that we have at the moment on a funded balance sheet of 900 billion or so, about 200 billion within that of excess cash and that's a combination of our excessive deposits over loans and the cash collateral that we received net from our Securities Lending business and from our Repo business. In addition to that we've now provided disclosure on our liquidity buffer because you remember we moved it to the corporate center and we hold it in a cash free on the balance sheet called financial assets available for sale and you'll see that it's at the end of the year it was a tad over 80 billion. So liquidity is not something that concerns management anymore we &#x2013; we're awash with it. It's the deployment of it for a decent margin that's the challenge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to follow-up on that, I mean I understand everything you just said and it sort of seems sensible and I'm trying to reconcile that with a range of estimates that I've seen now in the marketplace on your stable funding ratio that don't necessarily &#x2013; and they're not necessarily consistent with your comments on a very strong liquidity ratio and so I was wondering if you could just maybe give us some guidance on that? Just sort of put to rest some of these concerns that people have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm at a slight loss as to how to emphasize that we have an excess of funding and liquidity. I mean there are issues with our funding. We'd like to increase the term of it but there really is no shortfall of liquidity and no liquidity constraint within the Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, you are pretty comfortable you will be above 100% on the Basel III stable funding ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If it comes in, in the guise in which it's being proposed at the time it's supposed to come in, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. That's perfect. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Derek. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Huw van Steenis, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions. First if I could just return to the topic of client advisors, it appears that about just over 200 client advisors left in the fourth quarter. So, whilst I take the point that some of the people who left in Q2 and Q3 may have already been washed through, if I assume that these private bankers have about 200 million of client assets under management, that you maybe retain 60%, there's at least another 16 billion to go just from the Q4 outflow. So is there any way you could dissuade us from the possibility that there is still going to be quite heavy outflows in the first half? And then secondly, if I just come back to costs, would it be fair to say that your new target is, is it the sort of 20 billion of cost or below, there is 3 billion of bonuses at least which we should add on. And then it strikes me that the compensation deferred is probably in the order of about a billion, looking at the accounts today. Would that billion probably be later on in '010 or would it be more spread across '010 and '011? So we &#x2013; actually there is an extra half to 1 billion of cost we should think about per year going forward. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The attrition of client advisors and you are correct, went down in the fourth quarter and third quarter more than 200 so that might have an effect in the months to come. But it is certainly slowing down and really hopefully even out in the next few quarters and probably even increase again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that reduction about half were people who left the Bank involuntarily and we wound up the coach program, the out-placing program in the fourth quarter and they obviously probably wouldn't manage as much as 200 million of client assets and they probably wouldn't take as much with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, the bonus, on the deferred bonuses, well, the amount carried forward to future periods from all prior periods is 3.2 and the amortization of that is a bit frontloaded, but it is over quite a long period of time and it stretches out over five plus years. But it accretes every year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there another question? Okay. Thank you very much. Can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Jernej Omahen, Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. It's Jernej here from Goldman Sachs. I'd like to ask you two relatively straight-forward questions. The first one is on compensations, sorry, if UBS pay its employees what UBS wanted to pay its employees initially. I &#x2013; we were reading reports in the press which seemed suspiciously detailed that there was an intervention from the regulator as in regard to UBS's bonus pool. And I think the follow-on question to that one is, in case you answer that there has been intervention, is whether you believe UBS employees today are paid or compensated in line with, I guess, the best of its peer group and what the impact that has on the business, potentially. And I guess the second question is and I'm just I guess struggling to let go of this margin development in your Private Bank. The target is a 100 basis points but the margin is down 10 basis points over the past four quarters. Can you just explain in a bit more detail, how UBS gets the margin up by 25% to 100 basis points? How that happens over a reasonable timeframe? And what you plan to do that you're clearly not doing now in order to get that margin higher. I guess that's it. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Jernej, coming to the bonus clearly we have to pay our people comparably to the industry and reduce the same job and through our successful as in the industry. Overall obviously, in the Bank and clearly visible as well in our results in Investment Banking, we were not yet as successful as most of our peers. But I'm confident that the top performers are paid to stay, clearly we know that we have to do that. And I think in general, with this, we will get very well along with our bonus pot there.</p>
          <p>And the reason is also that when you have, not like your company too much money and you have just enough tailored, enough money you have to be much more careful that you actually deploy it correctly to the right people, which we are doing. There was speculation in the press, and but I can not remember a single day during the course of the last year when there wasn't any speculation in the press about us and normally as you know with speculation and you have your fair share as well about that, so half is right and half is fantasy or wishful thinking. There was no interference as such from the outside or from the regulators. Regulators do want to know about the bonus pots these days and clearly they are informed and but that is all.</p>
          <p>On the margin together up to 100 basis points, I know that is again one of these things since you can't do it from today to tomorrow or from one quarter to another, it is very difficult to believe and with all the areas where we have to improve that very clearly is one of the areas how we want to do it. I said at the Investor Day or hinted at the Investor Day, it has something to do with advising our -your clients better and because you are advising them better they will turn over their portfolio more often and therefore you get more basis points on the assets.</p>
          <p>But it is not a scheme so to force people to turn the over their portfolio more. You have convince people in &#x2013; it depends also on the market that in the certain market that the instruments they use are the right ones and are probably, slightly orientated within a year then going over a period of a year. So also the market as I see it going forward is more a trading market where the so called long-term investors have probably more difficulties. One has to take the advantages the market gives during the year and which I think with the right advice and with the right profitability for the client will induce also the client to trade more than in the past. But that you will see of many quarters and as we develop in the next 12 months or so.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. Can we have the next question, please, and the last one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question from the telephone conference is from Mr. Matthew Clark, KWB (sic) [KBW] . Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Matt Clark at KBW here. Just a question on the tax credits, if you continue to make progress towards your three to five year profit target, what kind of scope for further creation of deferred tax assets do you see? Or to put it another way, what do you expect your effective tax rate to be in 2010 and the next couple of years? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the effective tax rate in 2010, if we are in line with the sort of targets that we gave at the Investor Day should be around about 20%. If we out-perform that and in particular if we out-perform that in the U.S. then the tax rate, effective tax rate will come down. And if we under-perform that, then the tax rate could go up a little.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In terms of the &#x2013; when you say in terms of the guidance you gave in 2010, are you referring to your three to five year profits or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as long as we are in line roughly to meet our medium-term goals and if the tax rate ought to be 20 to low 20s percent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And with that we close the telephone lines and are back here in the room. And please, we are open to any question we have here in the room. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>By the participation of the Swiss State in UBS, would you be happy if the Chinese bought participation small or big in UBS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not aware that the Chinese want to buy stake in UBS. It's something new to me. Anyway, they haven't talk to me and as far as I know, also not to our Board. Now, the conclusion that the dark orange is dark black as you said is wrong. It's simply wrong. On Investor Day, we gave you an indication and coming back on that where we said on how much &#x2013; how many assets we have in Switzerland from the countries bordering Switzerland plus the U.K. and the numbers there I think was around 140 billion and we also gave an indication, I think we've said that we think in the worst case is something like up to 50 billion might be moving. Next question? William. You also can ask in German in between. <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. I'm just wondering, you're back in profits again and you're feeling strong enough, so I just wonder whether you will make a new effort to buy back the former liquidated funds from the stabilization funds of the Swiss National Bank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will not say anything to that anymore. I'm always getting in trouble when I say something to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Including with me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>End of story. The last word you heard from the National Bank and they said they want to keep it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>