<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1474344" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7874</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Federico Ghizzoni</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Francesca Tondi</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Marina Natale</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Italia SIM">Matteo Ramenghi</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Alberto V. Cordara</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Corporate &amp; Investment Banking">Jean-Pierre Mustier</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Autonomous Research LLP">Giovanni Carriere</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Risk Officer">Karl Guha</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Carlo Digrandi</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Azzurra Guelfi</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Equita SIM SpA">Giovanni Razzoli</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods Ltd.">Ronny Rehn</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Anke Reingen</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca SpA">Andrea Filtri</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Andrea Vercellone</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Pramerica Investment Management Ltd.">James Hyde</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Domenico Santoro</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. This is the Chorus Call conference operator. Welcome, and thank you for joining the UniCredit First Quarter 2012 Group Results Presentation. As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Federico Ghizzoni, Chief Executive Officer of UniCredit Group. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good afternoon and welcome, everyone, to &#x2013; thanks for joining us on this call to present our first quarter 2012 results.</p>
          <p>Let's go straight to slide four. But before going into details of the results, I would like to give you a quick overview of the key highlights of the quarter. I will not give you this time a specific update on the progress of the strategic plan. Remember we talked about that 45 days ago. I will highlight some specifics of the plan throughout the presentation, and then in August, when we present the half year result, we'll give you more details.</p>
          <p>Going through the quarter, it's not a secret to anyone that the first quarter, despite of the LTRO which is significant the liquidity in the market, it's not a secret that it was a very volatile quarter, especially in the second half with the general deterioration of the macroeconomic condition and sentiment all across Europe.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, I'm pleased to say that we saw quite solid operating results in the quarter with a stronger contribution from our trading activities. Actually, our net profit ended up at &#x20AC;914 million, was boosted by one-off gain of &#x20AC;477 million from the successful buyback that we had in February of Tier I and upper Tier II securities, as well by a very good trend result in trading profit.</p>
          <p>The adjusted net profit came to &#x20AC;444 million, is up 80% quarter-on-quarter, but down 45% year-on-year, primarily due to the exceptional strong trading revenues that we recorded in the first quarter of 2011. On the cost side, total cost were more or less flat, both quarter-on-quarter and year-on-year. Actually, year-on-year, we declined 0.5%. We will go more in details during the presentation.</p>
          <p>Another important point, our loan loss provision improved further to &#x20AC;1.4 billion. Cost of risk, therefore is down 7 bps year-on-year and 5 bps versus last quarter, ending up to 101 bps. This is partially due to very good, let's say, situation in Germany, strong improvement in Central and Eastern Europe and Poland, which had offset that increase in cost of risk in Italy and in Austria.</p>
          <p>The funding plan is well on track, ex also LTRO. With the funding plan completed already 44% at the group level, more than 50%, 51% for Italy. In Italy, let's say we are doing well in this respect. As I said, we have raised more than 50%. In particular, we had a good return in term of performance of our network on the deposits side.</p>
          <p>The capital side, thanks to the very impressive, let me say success of the &#x20AC;7.5 billion right issue, Tier I and upper Tier II buyback was as well successful. This hit has to add up 10 bps to our capital, together with very active, positive risk-weighted asset management that dropped by &#x20AC;4.3 billion in the quarter. Thanks to that, our Core Tier 1 ratio under Basel 2.5 is now at 10.31%. I think is a very good result, well above the EBA requirement.</p>
          <p>And also looking at the Basel 3 fully loaded target, we have a position today well above the 9%, towards our strategic target number &#x2013; strategic plan target. So, in terms of capital, the performance looks quite strong.</p>
          <p>Let's go now to slide five and we start the presentation. You can see the breakdown of our net profit and net operating profit. We saw, as I've said already, an excellent rebound in trading activities in the first quarter of this year. However, it's difficult to compare this quarter 2012 with the extremely good first quarter 2011. At the time, we ended up with results of &#x20AC;750 million in the trading business. This time has been &#x20AC;535 million. This explain the decline year-on-year of the net profit. But nevertheless, as I said, it's up quarter-on-quarter. Actually, quarter-on-quarter, if we look at the adjusted profit, we are at &#x20AC;477 million, with a jump of 80%.</p>
          <p>The net operating profit reached &#x20AC;1.2 billion compared to &#x20AC;800 million in the previous quarter and almost to &#x20AC;1.6 billion in the same period of last year. Let me say that in spite of the very good performance of trading, the impact of buyback, et cetera, the operational performance trend is stable. And this is very good in the situation, and the market is quite difficult.</p>
          <p>Slide six, let's take a quick look at the net operating breakdown. As already mentioned, revenues stands at &#x20AC;6.4 billion quarter-on-quarter, excluding one-off. Total costs are flat quarter-on-quarter, net of non-recurring Q4 staff-related items. Remember, we had very low results in this respect, long-term positive sense obviously, in the first quarter. And now we have a situation it is going to be normalized. Loan loss provisions are down, thanks to improvement in Germany, Central Eastern Europe and Poland. Offsetting as lightly was the situation in Italy and Austria. We will go back to this point later on.</p>
          <p>Anyway, I think that the key things to retain from this slide is that all our key geography have positively contributed to the increase in net operating profit, in particular CEE and Poland was up both on a quarterly basis, plus 5.4%. And looking on annual basis, we see Western Europe improving &#x20AC;606 million from a low base of &#x20AC;267 million at the previous quarter. So, overall, the performance has been positive in all geographies.</p>
          <p>Slide seven, no need to go too much in details. Revenues including the buyback gain was up 2.5% year-on-year and 16.6% quarter-on-quarter. Once again, a strong rebound in trading revenues in the quarter in Western Europe with the opposite trend in Central Eastern Europe and Poland. Fees have been in particular in Central Eastern Europe affected by seasonality effect. The first quarter has been weaker than expected, in particular also due to the very bad weather condition that in some countries have basically blocked the activity for almost one month. This for Central Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>Net interest, slide eight. Net interest was flat in the quarter despite of a 45 bps drop in the three months Euribor. And despite of the fact that we had one calendar day less in the quarter, it equated at the end of the day to 1% drop internal revenues. One calendar day less means &#x20AC;40 million less. In parallel, net interest line was obviously supported by trading-related elements in the quarter. But overall, again, net interest income considering once again the difficult market condition has reacted pretty well.</p>
          <p>We are seeing, in particular, a positive impact in Italy where the repricing action is ongoing. Meanwhile, we have more &#x2013; a bit more criticality in Germany and Austria due to the exceptionally low-rate debt levels seen in the last few weeks. Net interest in Central Eastern Europe and Poland is stable, thanks to Turkey in particular, Russia, Poland and Croatia.</p>
          <p>We have prepared a slide, number nine, about Italy in particular. This slide gives you detailed overview of the net interest income in Italy. I would like simply to reiterate that the ongoing repricing effort is offsetting higher cost of funding, as you can see, and also lower volumes. So, so far, the activity on the commercial side is really giving a good result. We are very effective in repricing both on the deposit side and the loan side, as we said, offsetting a combination of volumes substantially flat, and cost of funding for Italy, obviously, increasing following market conditions.</p>
          <p>Volumes, confirming what I was saying, we have loans substantially flat, a little decreasing of 1.1%. Good news on the deposit side where we are growing almost 2% quarter-on-quarter and 1.1% year-on-year. Once again, considering the condition of market especially in Italy, I think, has been a very good result especially on the deposit side. It is contributing quite a lot as we will see on our &#x2013; the reduction of the funding gap for the group. Different trends in Central and Eastern Europe, we have loans increase of 2.5% versus Q4, 9.3% versus one year ago. So, the trend is completely different.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 is about fees. There is a drop in fees year-on-year primarily is due to a slowdown of customer bank financial products due to the market volatility. It's clear that customer tend to be short and do not invest their liquidity. On the other side, we see a good increase in fees from investment services that are growing 6.8% quarter-on-quarter after a 19% year-on-year drop, thanks to a very strong effective market activity.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, the environment is still very volatile, nevertheless, we see an increase of 2.8%. Negative is the trend has been for this quarter in Central Eastern Europe minus, as you see, 8.7% partially justified by a change of regulation in Turkey. As you know Turkey is for us, extremely important in Central Eastern Europe, in term of contribution.</p>
          <p>Simply what happened in Turkey has been that upfront fees related to lending activity, were now being spread all across the life of the loan, so just for a change of regulation is impacting more or less 50%, and explaining 50% of the decrease versus the previous quarter. The rest, as I said, was mostly related to a very bad weather condition in the middle of the quarter that have affected the results. My expectation is that we'll have definitely a better quarter looking forward.</p>
          <p>Operating cost, slide 12, as we said already, substantially we have a flat trend quarter-on-quarter minus 0.5% year-on-year. As you can see, it's a combination of staff expenses growing 6.1% quarter-on-quarter. But this is explained by the one-off of the fourth quarter. Deducting one-off, we are definitely moving in the right direction. The other expenses are down 4.3%, a very good result with the action in place to reduce cost that clearly are generating good results. Overall, let's say, a positive trend, as we said, year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Page 13, about FTE, also in this case, the good trend is there. We are decreasing 1,000 people quarter-on-quarter, 1,400 year-on-year with the mix coming from different countries. So, we have countries where we keep investing like Turkey, so people are growing. Country, where we have a much more conservative and prudent approach, like Ukraine or Kazakhstan with decrease trend. CIB and the corporate centers, the major contributor in Western Europe for this reduction.</p>
          <p>Let's move now to cost of risk, slide 14. As you can see, cost of risk is down overall both in the quarter and year-on-year. Today, the level we have reached is 101 basis points. So, trend is down. This is due to the improved situation in Central Eastern Europe, where we have &#x2013; we moved from 172 basis point to, down to 124 basis point, so very good results, 108, including Poland. Good result also in Germany; a slight increase, as we've said already, in Italy and Austria. Let me say that, particularly for Italy, we start to have, as well, good result coming from the old activities and actions, decision taken on the collections side, we have improved a lot. In this respect, we have the system in place, a dedicated structure focused on the loan restructuring. And also, the very strict policy in terms of origination is helping to achieve good result in terms of cost of risk.</p>
          <p>Impaired loans, this is a slide to be examined with attention. As you see, gross impaired loans are growing, 3.8% at the group level quarter-on-quarter, with a coverage ratio that it goes down from 44.6% to 43.8%. There is an explanation also technically linked to regulation here. In particular, for Italy, we have an increase of past due, due to the change of regulation. Now, all the non-performing over 90 days are classified past due with respect of being very strict in applying the regulation on our side, before it was 180 days. So, this was impacting more or less &#x20AC;1 billion, if I remember correctly, on the trend of the gross impaired loans.</p>
          <p>This has affected also the coverage ratio. In reality, the coverage ratio, if we look &#x2013; if we consider, sorry, the impact of past due, plus the fact that we have, also, in this quarter, writing off a quite substantial amount of loans, yet, if we consider the two factors, the coverage ratio is substantially aligned with the previous quarter. I'm sure I will get, in any case, questions about this point later on.</p>
          <p>So, let's move quickly to the balance sheet, slide 16. As you see, our total asset are stable. Good news for the tangible equity. It is improving quite a lot to &#x20AC;46.1 billion. Thanks to the right issue, the improvement in our revaluation reserves due to lower spreads. Good news also, the leverage ratio that goes down to 18.5%, I think is one of the lowest level in Europe, confirming our very prudent approach and the fact that the risk profile of the bank is really low, in line with what we said during the presentation of our strategic plan.</p>
          <p>Balance sheet structure, not too much to say in term of security issue, so substantial stability. There is a significant improvement of the net interbank position. Also, this is in line substantially with the target of our plan. It's due mostly to very good position in term of liquidity, and this is due to the fact that we have an improvement coming from LTRO from ECB.  But overall, it's impacted positively. As I said, a good trend in term of deposits and liquidity.</p>
          <p>Financial investments, &#x20AC;4 billion more than the previous year, mostly linked to an increase more or less equivalent in government bonds, reaching at &#x20AC;40 billion level that has been, all the time, indicated as our level from the risk management turnover taking &#x2013; in term of buying &#x2013; or to keep in our portfolio of Italian government bonds.</p>
          <p>Good news also from the medium-long-term funding, as I said already, we have done 44% of the plan, 51% is for Italy. I am on page 18. 51% for Italy. Yeah, the good news is that we have, as I said already, a good trend in term of deposit and the retail bond in the network, especially in Italy. It is enough to remember that out of &#x20AC;13.9 billion of bond issued, &#x20AC;6.2 billion are coming from retail bonds. Nevertheless, we have still a very low level of penetration. It's only 6.9% of retail bonds on total financial asset confirmation that we are not stressing our customer base. And we have a space eventually for further growth in this segment.</p>
          <p>We are clearly, constantly looking to opportunities in the market, not easy these days to find a proper window, but I want just to remember &#x20AC;1.5 billion of senior bond issued in Italy &#x2013; for Italy in February. And more recently, &#x20AC;500 million in Austria, covered bonds.</p>
          <p>Okay. So overall, comfortable position. Capital, as well, I am pretty satisfied of the result that we have achieved. Here is about risk-weighted asset, as you see, are going down from &#x20AC;460.4 billion to &#x20AC;455 billion. So, a decrease of 1.1% quarter-on-quarter, another strong signal of the capability of the group to really manage productively risk-weighted asset.</p>
          <p>I want to underline in particular the result in markets. I think we are one of the few banks that are going down in this respect despite of the new regulation from &#x20AC;31.5 billion to &#x20AC;27.2 billion. And once again, I want to remind that the very well-diversified composition in our portfolio in terms of risk-weighted asset, 35% is Italy, 26% is Germany, the rest is Poland, CEE and Austria. So, very well-diversified situation.</p>
          <p>Page 20, we have the capital ratio. As I said, thanks also to the capital, the rights issue plus risk-weighted asset optimization, we moved from 8.40% to 10.31% Basel 2.5. In terms of Basel 3, fully loaded. We have a situation better than what was envisaged in the strategic plan, is above 9.2%. So, we are ahead from our plan. Let me say that I think the group has a very strong capital position right now.</p>
          <p>Final slide is about Italy, and the slide, it should become familiar, is confirming &#x2013; this is Italy, let's say, famous <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:43) perimeter. So, Italian commercial business, as you see here, the results are positive and encouraging. In term of revenues, we are growing 4.2% in spite of the last quarters particularly difficult in the country. Cost is an impressive minus 4.7%, so the restructuring of the operation is definitely ongoing. Gross operating profit, 17% increase. Loan loss provisions are stable, and the profit before taxes rose from &#x20AC;73 million to &#x20AC;276 million. This again is confirming the restructuring of the Italian business operation is ongoing.</p>
          <p>Just to conclude, a few remarks, a few points from my side. I would like to sum up the situation of today saying that, first of all, our capital ratio is really rock-solid. We're already exceeding as I said our 2012 fully loaded Core Tier 1 Basel 3. The target was, once again, 9%. We are now above 9.2%, not only thanks to the right issue but also thanks to our very good proactive and stringent management of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Our liquidity position, and I think in these days it's extremely important as a point for banks, is strong. We have been very attentive and opportunistic in how to further reduce the commercial funding gap, result I think are good. So, in the case of the liquidity position is stronger. We have completed in this respect 44% of our funding plan, more than 50% in Italy. This proved the capability of the group to tap the market and to leverage on our network.</p>
          <p>The adjusted net profit reflects a &#x2013; quite good, let's say, start of the year on market activities, and is positively impacted by the turnaround in Italy that is ongoing, the repricing action that proved to be, so far, effective and the tight cost control.</p>
          <p>We are in line substantially with our target, I'm referring to the strategic plan. In some case also, as I said, the internal capital ratio and the risk-weighted asset optimization. So, overall, a picture of a good quarter. We know that, looking forward, the market situation will be not that easy but we feel confident we can go through and navigate properly in this not easy and rough let's say space.</p>
          <p>So, thank you very much, and now, we can open the floor for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. This is the Chorus Call conference operator. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Ms. Francesca Tondi of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon to everybody. Thanks very much for the explanation on numbers. Three questions from my side. How do you look at your funding gap, is it loan-to-deposit, loan-to-deposits and then some retail funding? I see you have a slide you mentioned that you're actually &#x2013; you're looking at reducing it. Where is your target? What do you have in mind of how you want to achieve it? And in a way linked to that, do you still see some need for selected loan reduction, and if yes, where?</p>
          <p>Well done in Italy on cost, I think it's a great reduction, what does it take, you think, to actually see a more substantial reduction at a group level because I think where we are is still pretty much flat and I think in the difficult times, and it will be great to see costs coming down more at the group level. Do you see any chance for some of the investments, some of the hiring that you're doing actually reducing them as well elsewhere in other regions?</p>
          <p>And as a third point, on government bonds, if I took the number down correctly, you've now got &#x20AC;40 billion I think, and your portfolio was about &#x20AC;32 billion. I'm trying to refer to the Italian government bonds. Do you think that your capacity for purchasing bonds has pretty much reached the limit, and also are we going to see some margin benefit coming from some of these purchases, or ultimately depending on the level this impact is going to be able to see minimal? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I forgot to recommend a couple of question maximum, so we can have more people interacting. But I will be pleased to reply. So, the loans deposit is improving. Loans deposit ratio was 140% is now down 136%. So, it's improving. I think that &#x2013; the intention of the bank is to keep working on reducing the funding gap.  If you remember, this was one of our target in the strategic plan, and we continue to work hard in order to reach our targets. So, it's in a good trend and, hopefully, will continue. Loan reduction, if you ask where...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you remind us what your target was on this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was &#x2013; I was just &#x2013; sorry, I was thinking if it has been communicated. I don't think we have communicated the number to the market. But let's say it was definitely a continuous positive trend all across the plan.</p>
          <p>Just to give you an idea. Six months ago, our funding gap compared to today has improved &#x20AC;34 billion. So, I'm not obviously thinking that this will continue with the same pace looking forward. But we want to reach a level of equilibrium in the group without the dependency from external market. This was supposed to be all across &#x2013; to be reached at the end of the plan 2015. Let me say that considering the difficult market condition, probably also in this case, we are ahead of the plan. So, we have not given the number, but we'll continue this effort to reduce, let's say, the gap and to improve the loans-deposit ratios. Loans reduction...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Some banks in Europe seem to indicate at the level of 110%, 120%. Do you think that kind of makes sense for your business mix or is that too aggressive given that you also have retail bonds on the side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>110% is too aggressive. Probably, it doesn't make even sense from a business point of view. But definitely, we want to improve 136%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Loans reduction, where it can come, let's say, we have in place a number of targets per segment and per geography, obviously. We have identified with risk management a number of sector where, if the opportunity will come, we can think to increase, but also sectors where we want to reduce our exposure. Typical, if we look, for example, to retail in particular, real estate is a sector where we want to decrease our exposure.</p>
          <p>We have also the policy to be very selective in terms of rated classes. We tend to lend also to the best-rated classes of customers, and also in term of pricing. We want to be very, let's say &#x2013; let me say, strict. If I look, as I did this morning, our sales versus the average of the system in Italy, I was pleased to see that we have better rates in term of lending. And we pay average less in term of deposits. So, again, there is a policy in place in term of sectors. There is also quite a disciplined approach in terms of risk-weighted asset, in term of origination and pricing.</p>
          <p>I think that the situation here is under control. Cost at the group level. As I said, the minus 4.7% to Italy is Italy, let me say, commercial banks. So, we are making further effort in Italy with reference to their corporate center, that was not included in that slide. So, we have a space in the corporate center here. As you remember, maybe there is a plan called the <mark type="ph" /> THOR (35:41) to reduce just in terms of number of people, more or less, 20% and it's a plan that is ongoing. Plus, we have other initiatives at the group level that should kick in gradually and allow us again to reach the level indicated in the plan, that for me, has been all the time, the minimum we should reach, but it's not forbidden to try to do better and is what we would try to do.</p>
          <p>In terms of investment, we have not taken any decision this moment so far to cut investments. Coming to Central Eastern Europe, we are still opening branches in Turkey because we have a very positive expectation from that market. We saw a &#x2013; some slowdown in the first quarter in Turkey, but we see already a recovery starting from the current quarter. So, the investment for a while, they are confirmed. Clearly, should the market condition change, this is an additional tool to gain something in terms of cost control should we stop investments that are ongoing.</p>
          <p>On the government bonds, our level was &#x20AC;37 billion, &#x20AC;38 billion of the Italian govies, and today, we have a &#x20AC;41.8 billion. Substantially we increased &#x20AC;4 billion and we said constantly, every time we got this question that &#x20AC;40 billion is substantially our level, billions more, billion less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Francesca, you were asking about if there is any margin benefit from the additional purchase. Let's say these are the net contribution, &#x20AC;4.5 billion, some of our govies matured and we bought a bigger amount with a higher rate, so a higher yield. So, I was going to get benefit from a P&amp;L standpoint as a result of maturing old purchase and the kicking  in, let's say, yield of the new one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that is going to come from probably second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will see &#x2013; we bought in the first, so we will see the carry for all the remaining quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what do you say is the order of magnitude of the benefit for group net interest income?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No comment on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Matteo Ramenghi from UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon to everyone. I have a question on Italy and then one on the breakdown of maturities. On Italy, I see on slide nine a very encouraging trend in terms of customer margin and just I was wondering if you could clarify whether that could actually continue in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>And then on slide 21, it's clearly a very strong positive development, and I was wondering if we should look at the gross operating profit of &#x20AC;1.2 billion in the quarter as a potential run rate with provisions of &#x20AC;900 million which progressively normalize and come down?</p>
          <p>And then on the breakdown of maturities on page 28, which I think is quite useful, as it looks like you are running with a large liquidity base, with a very liquid balance sheet. What do you think is the cost of holding this, let's say, liquidity insurance and let's say, in a year time, markets are more normal and you don't need to keep such a liquid balance sheet, what could be the long-term boost for you? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Matteo. So, with respect to customers' margins, so far, as I said, they've been able to almost offset the flat volumes, the increase &#x2013; inevitable increase of cost of funding for Italy with the re-pricing, both on the loan side but also on the deposit side. We continue in a sense that the instruction given to the network and to the branches are very clear. And we see &#x2013; we are monitoring the direction, and we see the branches very, let's say, focused on all of these. So, I can simply say that re-pricing, there is a space, and it will &#x2013; is an action that will never stop.</p>
          <p>Then you put a question about if I remember, the normalized profit for Italy. What would be &#x2013; what we are expecting, it's impossible, I would say, to make a number. I think that for Italy, it's better to work hard day by day in this period of time. Situation is certainly not particularly good, where GDP is declining. So, rather than making forecast about normalization, I think it's important to put in place all the actions in order to limit the effect, the negative effect on our P&amp;L coming from the very difficult current situation in Italy. So, I will reply to this question next time, but not now.</p>
          <p>On the liquidity side, it's true that we have a buffer in some way in terms of liquidity. Also, our position in ECB is indicative in this respect. I'm not asking myself what is the cost. I think that, again, this is a moment you have to choose whether to be a safe bank and to have some buffers or not. Let's keep in mind that we have also potential downgrade coming for many European banks. If I'm not mistaken, Moody's is looking to more than 100 banks in these days. So, I think we have to sacrifice something in terms of P&amp;L but we have to be sure that in terms of capital and liquidity, we are strong. And this is our current policy. Then if market condition will ease, we will be maybe more prone to better invest our liquidity. But at this moment, I'm happy with this situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Alberto Cordara of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. A couple of questions. The first one is on deposits. We saw a good trend, good recovery in customer deposits quarter-on-quarter. Just wanted to ask you if you can elaborate a bit more on this, which geographies you see the trends to be more positive, why, and if possible also if you can give us a breakdown of the quarterly deposit between current accounts and time deposits and repos and other deposits?</p>
          <p>And the second question is on trading, year-on-year, the result on trading is, well, is less excited than what we have seen in Q1 2011. Do we need to read something into it? Is the volatility of the trading line is lower than what it used to be? And if you can give us an idea of the trends that we should expect to see in Q2? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry. First of all, when we talk about deposits vis-&#xE0;-vis, let's say, the presentation, we put inside the deposit what we call customer deposit or side deposit, then we put inside term deposits to this, and finally, retail bonds. The trend, overall, as you can see, is positive. They are growing. The results of the quarter is growth for all the three segments, meaning side deposit or customer deposit, slight improvement for Italy, better on the term deposit side even though the amount compared to side deposit is very small. We have 140 &#x2013; &#x20AC;150 billion of customer deposit and we have &#x20AC;7 billion, &#x20AC;8 billion of term deposits. In any case they are growing quite significantly. And finally retail bonds, as well I think, if I remember correctly, during the quarter growing three, is it two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We issued &#x20AC;6 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We issued &#x20AC;6 billion, yes. So, overall the trend is good because we are not losing this important side deposits. I'm eager and would like to see a growth also in side deposit, but in this moment I'm happy to see the big picture.</p>
          <p>What is important to say that the customer base proved to be very resilient. We have not lost substantially deposits of customer in the last six months. Also as important to say that we have not increased rates substantially since the beginning of December. And that we have a space to place further bonds should we need to do it. So, we can rely on our customer, in this respect.</p>
          <p>On the trading I think the two quarters, 2012, 2011, we are not comparable. We are in a different world in some way. So, the tension we have seen on the sovereign side this quarter are not comparable with the previous one. We have also a more cautious trend over sales. Overall, our VaR limits have been reviewed down during the last months. So the approach is more conservative. But I think, overall, the result has been definitely good for this quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking at the future quarters traditionally, the first has been, all the time the best. It's also the previous year. So, I don't think we can repeat the current quarter &#x2013; the same results of the first, but this is in line with our, let's say, budget and expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But we shouldn't expect, let's say, a trading loss in Q2, for instance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Jean-Pierre Mustier is online.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the trading side, clearly, the first quarter was a very good quarter held by the LTRO which put more liquidity. If we are going into the second quarter in an environment which is, less favorable, but so far, we have lower run rate of our profit, but we don't expect the market condition to remain where they are today. We'll expect something which will be closer to what we have in a normal quarter. And we have to assume that the first quarter was an exceptional quarter which, seasonably, is always higher than what we have in the rest of the year. So, I think we should have a seasonal impact, but nothing different from a seasonal impact, at least at this stage, as we can see the environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Giovanni Carriere of Autonomous Research. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. I have a question. If you could please add a few comments on slide 27, particularly on the net inflow of impaired loans, which, if I read this correctly, increased from &#x20AC;1.3 billion to &#x20AC;1.6 billion net of the regulation. If you could confirm and also comment whether we should expect any further increases going forward.</p>
          <p>And number two, in terms of your provisions, I've noticed in the commercial business in Germany, a big drop from &#x20AC;215 million to &#x20AC;82 million. Is there any writeback that had been in the past? And likewise, within CEE, I also saw some writebacks in Hungary. I mean, is there in general any one-offs within your provisions and would it be right to annualize this number for the rest of the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, with respect to the first question, as I said, the change of regulation has contributed for &#x20AC;1 billion. The rest is coming from deterioration of the portfolio. We are very strict and careful in classifying the portfolio. Looking forward, I would say that &#x2013; and maybe touching also the second question about Germany, we see the situation under control outside Italy, definitely in Germany. And the 27 basis points I recognize is a low level but doesn't come from writebacks. Writebacks, we have only in Hungary this quarter. So, it's a real cost of risk in Germany in our bank, in this moment, we think substantially can move some bps but is substantially stable because the quality of the portfolio is very good.</p>
          <p>On the Italian side, we may expect some pressure on the cost of risk. This is almost inevitable, looking at the macroeconomic conditions. It's too early to say what will be the level of impaired loans for the second quarter, but I think the situation is under control. And as I said during the presentation of the slides, we have in place a number of actions aimed to mitigate eventual negative impacts, in particular, we have reinforced a lot the activities on the customer in bonds to try to anticipate the problems rather than reacting afterwards. So, overall in the group, Italy to be watched carefully. The rest of the group, I think still showing good performances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And was there any particular reason for the drop in the size of your generic provision, or was it just related to the size of the loan book which has gone down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Karl Guha will reply to the question, the drop about general provisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's not reasonable to expect a drop in general provisions. I think that, first of all, if you look at Italy in itself, the number that you get is a headline number &#x2013; I'm sorry, it's a net number, so the headline number and net number. So, effectively, at the gross level, it's more or less at &#x20AC;1.5 billion and the writebacks have been also materially higher. So, what you're looking at as a net number is lower, but I think in Italy, given the overall sort of deterioration of the macroeconomic environment, it's reasonable to expect that this will continue. In fact, your preceding question about &#x2013; on page 27, in particular, is indicative of that. So, I think you should be prudent in your expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You asked about Hungary. Here, we have the ERP impact. So, this didn't have an impact and has been neutral on the bottom line for the first quarter while P&amp;L items have been impacted at different levels. So, we had an impact on trading level, on the other administrative expenses and on write-downs, on loans. As a result, the cumulative impact as of today is &#x20AC;34 million including the third and fourth quarter 2011. And on write-downs for the first quarter 2012, we recorded a positive impact of &#x20AC;22.6 million, which is a release of provision resulting from the shift to balance when losses occur on performing loan, based on this specific program. So, if you like, we can go more in that on a cycle on the specific program. But this has been the driver of the writebacks for Hungary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Carlo Digrandi of HSBC. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I have two questions, if I may. First of all, on the &#x2013; looking in the balance sheet, I don't see any signs of deleveraging. Yes, it is true that the leverage ratio has improved mostly &#x2013; probably because of the rights issue. So, the question is, do you think that in the future we will be seeing some deleveraging or you aim at keeping, more or less, assets flat and eventually taking opportunities if there is any growth in Italy?</p>
          <p>The second question is on the net interest income, probably one is the product of the other. Net interest income is flat in Europe on slide 12. To some extent, you did explain the reason why, but it doesn't look like there is any LTRO impact there. The repricing in Italy is probably not strong enough yet or has been kind of offset by the higher cost of funding. So, I was trying to establish more the reasons why of this flat net interest income in Europe and what do you think we should expect during the course of the year, i.e., something like this again over the next quarters or a marginal improvement? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as it's concerned, the balance sheet and the deleveraging, if you remember, we have put on an offer, &#x20AC;48 billion of risk-weighted assets. This is ongoing, and we are on track. My impression is this is different, I think we have &#x2013; we're ahead of our plan in term of deleveraging and in term of risk-weighted-asset optimization. We have to remember also the impact coming from Basel 2.5 in this respect, risks for the commercial business but also for credit risk and also market risk. It's clear that we are looking to any opportunity to accelerate, but we feel to be in this respect, on track.</p>
          <p>In terms of net interest income, there is a different situation between, once again, Italy and Germany and Austria in particular. Germany and Austria seems a paradox, but they are suffering more in the sense that the 45 bps drop in the three months Euribor gives not &#x2013; with rates alone doesn't give enough space or it creates more difficulties in term of re-pricing to both countries.</p>
          <p>For Italy, let's say, the real point of reference is now the spread on Btp, so this gives a space to the network to be very effective both on deposits and lending side. And in particular, I think we are successful also because having a good capital position and a good liquidity position, we can, in some way, choose customer to continue to do lending, even though on a selective basis, and at the end of the day, to negotiate the price. Once again, we have, more or less, 50% of the portfolio in Italy that is medium term. So, the repricing process is a long process, by definition, because you can touch only what comes to maturity or anytime there is a possibility by contract to review the rate. The short-term lending is done all the time at the current rates, or in alternative, we don't do it. So, we are very disciplined in this respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe on the deleveraging on the CIB side, Federico mentioned we have a one-off portfolio which is a mixture of loan reduction, as well as risk-weighted asset reduction on the market activity. If we look at the risk-weighted asset reduction on the CIB side, between the first quarter and the first quarter, we have &#x20AC;8.8 billion of reduction, &#x20AC;3.6 billion coming from credit risk reduction. It's mostly a loan effect. Overall, our loan-to-customers decreased from &#x20AC;215.7 billion to &#x20AC;212.8 billion, so a &#x20AC;3.9 billion reduction.</p>
          <p>We have operational risk which decreased and which impacted risk-weighted assets in terms of reduction by &#x20AC;1.1 billion because the scenario for 2008 came out of the calculation. And we had the market risk reduction of risk-weighted asset of &#x20AC;4.1 billion, where we had a mixture of running off a certain number of provisions, mostly on the structured equity side, as well as a low contribution from <mark type="ph" /> all of that (59:24). So, all in all, the reduction of risk-weighted asset is ongoing. We are on-track for our one-off portfolio. And we have as well reduced because of lesser client demand, our loan exposure to clients as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ms. Azzurra Guelfi of Citigroup. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. I have two questions. One is again on deposits. Sorry if I come back on this point. About the corporate deposit, if you look at the Italian division, corporate deposit has increased significantly. And I was wondering whether this is due to improving sovereign condition in Q1 or is this due to actions that you have put in place but you're spreading it and it doesn't seem to suffer significantly under deposit spread given the market condition. So, this could be a genuine return of deposit in the Italian subsidiary.</p>
          <p>And the second one is on fees. Could you provide us any indication on how is the fee income going to develop especially in the second quarter on the non-investment service related part mostly? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On the deposit side, there is an effect coming from the clearing house. So, reality, deposit on the corporate side, they are not growing so much as you see in the numbers. We are doing, by the way, since some time now quite strong and continuous commercial effort to look also on the deposit side. Traditionally, the level of corporate deposit in the banking sector in Italy has been much lower than what we see in other countries, for example, comparing Italy to Germany. But there is a space, I think, to recover. Overall, I'm quite comfortable with some statistics, they're not referring to us, but to the market, we have seen yesterday afternoon from Bank of Italy, that shows some recovery in the quarter versus the previous one on the deposit base. So, promising, but again, the number you see is not reflecting in full the reality because there is the effect of the clearing house.</p>
          <p>On the fees side, let's say, the only things I can say is that I'm expecting a recovery in term of fees on Central Eastern Europe for two reason. One is because, traditionally, the first quarter has been weaker than the second one and the third one and because the first quarter we see has been particularly down also for the reason I have explained. So, in Central Eastern Europe, I'm quite &#x2013; I'm looking forward in a positive way. Western Europe, I will say stable situation. We have to see once again what will be the condition in the market especially on the investment side. That is very much impacting the volatility versus the behavior of customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Giovanni Razzoli of Equita SIM. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon to everybody. Two questions, the first one is again on the cost of risk in Italy. I've seen that the significant &#x2013; was an expected trend in the corporate and investment banking division on the quarter-on-quarter basis. I wonder &#x2013; I mean, you already provided some outlook for the cost of risk going forward. My question is what's the downside compared with this level especially in the corporate and investment banking division cost of risk in Italy given the expected worsening of the macro outlook? And overall, if you can also provide some flavor on this, on the overall cost of risk in Italy, which, if I'm not mistaken, was 146 basis points in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The second question is more of, let's say, a strategic flavor. If I'm not mistaken, looking at your Pillar III data, you do have something like &#x20AC;190 billion of loans, which are still running under the foundation model, with something like 80% risk-weighting. I've seen that in the press release you mentioned a 10-basis point improvement in the Core Tier 1 which is related to the improvement in the market risk. I wonder if we can expect from this area, a release of capital if you are working on migration on part of this portfolio to the internal model and if you &#x2013; any of these benefits are included in your business plan targets? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question then I will give &#x2013; I will ask Marina to reply with the precise number for the second one. So, cost of risk of Italy, once again, I'm repeating myself I think for some time. I think that the situation we are currently today, for sure the cost of risk will be under pressure. It's very difficult to say how much, but not just to hide myself. It's difficult because I think it would be very much linked to the length of the recession. In other words, if we start to see some, even a slight recovery in the second half of the year, the situation will be different; if opposite, the recession will continue for more quarters. So, we have to really wait and see.</p>
          <p>What is important also to remember is the fact that there is a clear cut between companies that are pure domestic-driven and companies that are export &#x2013; they have a business that is export-driven. The second segment is in a better situation compared to previous one. It's clear that UniCredit is focusing on the second segment. It's easy to say many banks are trying to do that. But here we have some advantage coming from our international network, so we can serve this customer in a better way and to have a better penetration in their business.</p>
          <p>But again, we have to wait and see. It's too early to say or to try to imagine what would be the final cost of risk for Italy year end, because it will depend on the trend in the second &#x2013; in the third and fourth quarter mostly. For the second question, Marina will give you the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Advanced approach on the weight out of the total risk-weighted assets is 55%, and we are under standard for 45% of the total risk-weighted assets out of the &#x20AC;455 billion. Here is &#x2013; without &#x2013; we have a clear roadmap whereby we foresee the rollout of advanced model in each country and business. But I will not go through the detail, only to mention that Poland, leasing in Italy, Central Eastern Europe must be rolled out in the future, and since they don't have any application on the advanced model. While for the commercial bank in Italy, still, I would say, two-thirds done, one-third left to be rolled out. For HVB, we are well advanced, and we will complete it during 2012 in order to reach the target of 92% as required by the local regulator. So &#x2013; but, we have a clear roadmap, in some cases, for Central Eastern Europe countries, Turkey, Croatia, is going to kick in on the retail portfolio, but the completion will take place in 2014. So, we have a very long roadmap for the completion of the migration for all the portfolios across the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, I wonder if the potential benefits of these actions are already included in your 2013-2015 business plan targets? I think they are, isn't it, they are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Here, the issue is how to assess the potential benefit. Don't forget, at least, that shortfall is something that is going to kick in because today, for the standard we don't apply while when we are going to have the advance model, we have to report for the capital purpose also the shortfall. And so, we need to have a fairly assessment of the benefits, taken into account also in COGS. Anyway, we didn't have &#x2013; if any upside will materialize as a result of these progressive rollout, we are not going to &#x2013; it's not yet reported in our industrial plan figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Super. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Ronny Rehn of KBW. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks for taking the time for this call. I don't know how many questions I'm allowed to so I'll just shoot then. And first on the NII in Germany...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Four. Fantastic. First, on the NII...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two. I said two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two, you said, okay, sorry. I need to combine them. Okay. Then, I ask the most important ones. In Italy, could you update us on the NPL or the total impaired loan level and the coverage in this quarter? That's the first point.</p>
          <p>The second one would be on the Moody's downgrades, particularly when it comes to short-term ratings. Could you share some thoughts as to what the impact might be? Obviously, of course, a lot of noise in the markets. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. On the Italian side, you want to know the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The bad loan ratio and the coverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the coverage. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:10:48)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. In Italy, the coverage ratio or the headline number looks like it's gone down, but in reality, it hasn't because it's a combination of three factors. The first is that there's a write-off in sofferenze. So, that actually lowers the base. The second is the migration of the &#x2013; or the change of classification in terms of the 90-day rule. So, when you combine those two factors and adjust for it on a like-for-like basis, the coverage is exactly flat. And I'm sure Simone, in due calls, will give you the exact number. So, there's no change. And the headline looks different because of the numbers that have gone back and forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any case, the number is looking to the commercial bank inside. So, it's &#x2013; for gross impaired loans, it's 12.7%. And the coverage ratio, in total, is above 30%. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just to clarify, because there are lots of numbers here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So actually what you are looking at is if you're looking at sofferenze as the last class, for the Italian perimeter in its totality, it's roughly about 56%, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, that number I gave to you, we have put inside also past due, so total impaired loan past due, they are provisioned 10%. So, clearly, the average is different from NPL that is 57%, as Karl said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Clear. And what is the &#x2013; last quarter, you gave us a 16% number, I think, for Italy, as a regional impaired loan level. What would be the comparable number today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ronny, what do you mean by 16%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a 16% number, I thought, for Italy as an impaired loan level in the fourth quarter. I mean, unless I'm completely mistaken there, that's why I thought you gave a regional breakdown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ah, okay, okay. Okay, sorry. Now I understand. You mean the total...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the total. Yes. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...<mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:12:57) loans. That number is more like 18% at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>18%. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>17.8%, 17.7% thereabouts, was 16%. I see Simone fretting there. 17.2%, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, 17.2% and the coverage on this? Sorry, just to close this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The coverage, I already covered, so there's nothing more to add.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:13:30)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I apologize. Madam, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Just one second. We need to answer to the last &#x2013; the second question about Moody's possible downgrade. We know that there is this ongoing review of all European banks. Our understanding that the timetable is such as that we will get it next week. I don't have the precise timing for UniCredit Group and for the subsidiary. But my expectation is that first, we will get Italian in the context of the review of the Italian banks and subsequently we get the possible downgrade for our subsidiary.</p>
          <p>We are already equipped in order to face the potential outcome of a downgrade. So, we have already, I guess, that we appreciated the effort done on the liquidity side and the path that we managed to create over the fourth quarter, since year-end. And based on this, we will be able to face the potential impact of the downgrade which might come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ms. Anke Reingen of Royal Bank of Canada. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon. I just had some small follow-up questions. When you said the corporate deposits increased largely with respect to &#x2013; on the back of the clearing houses, just to confirm, this is not impacting your &#x2013; this is not also included in your 2% growth in customer deposits in the quarter?</p>
          <p>And then I just wondered if you can give us a bit more color in terms of how deposits and securities issued, sort of, like developed and the breakdown on the retail and the corporate divisions, so in corporate, basically how does the improvement breakdown in deposits and securities issued and the same on the retail division. So is the increase on the retail side or development on the retail side largely been helped by securities issued or there was decline on deposits?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, again, on the &#x2013; when we give a number, in terms of total deposit growth, it's a number that reflect the commercial activity of the bank. So, it's a real number. So, it's not including other effects. And the question about how much is deposit, how much is securities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for the breakdown, we come to you, a few seconds. As we said, the major growth, comes from retail bonds in the quarter, &#x20AC;6.8 billion in total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Securities went up &#x20AC;1.2 billion during the quarter, and I can give you the breakdown, &#x20AC;5.5 billion are in the retail network while only &#x20AC;1.1 billion corporate investment banking. So, overall, business division went up &#x20AC;7.8 billion, corporate center down &#x20AC;6.6 billion. So, as a result, the net to net impact is &#x20AC;1.2  billion in terms of growth of security which has supplemented the growth in deposits from customer which is &#x20AC;7.9 billion, coming to the &#x20AC;9 billion we reported before as growth of the direct funding. We call direct funding the sum of the two, so deposits from customer plus securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Andrea Filtri of Mediobanca. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. You're almost one year ahead in terms of capital generation versus your plan. If at the end of the year you reach capital levels above your targets, will you increase the dividend payout?</p>
          <p>The second question is just the contribution in the quarter from LTRO. And the third one, Bloomberg is reporting that the CEO of Pioneer is resigning today, can you please update us on the strategy on the asset manager of the group? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Starting from the last question. That is very fresh. I was not surprised, Mr. Yates, he communicated to me some time ago this idea. He's gone exclusively for personal reason, as it is in the statement. He will continue to serve in the group and in Pioneer, as a board member. The successor will be Mr. Pierri. Mr. Pierri is coming from Pioneer, so it gives a signal of continuity in what they are doing. He was already Deputy to Yates, has been selected because we think he's a CEO that can guarantee positive &#x2013; he can guarantee the implementation of the strategic plan of Pioneer and he can guarantee continuity in the company. So, this not a surprise from our side, nothing, I think, dramatic.</p>
          <p>On the dividend, sorry, but we are only mid of May and I cannot make any forecast about dividend. We will discuss when time will come. It's really too early and we will discuss another time.</p>
          <p>LTRO, the issue here is very simple. It goes back to question put at the beginning of this conversation, meaning today is important, in my opinion, to have maybe some inefficiency in the utilization of liquidity but to be liquid. So, LTRO has been partially, if you wish, utilized for buying up some bonds, as we said, &#x20AC;4 billion. Partially, but very limited amount, goes to lending because lending at this moment is not growing. So, it's a buffer in some way, we discussed but is a buffer at this moment I'm very happy to have in the bank, as I am very happy to continue to make efforts in order to improve liquidity. If we discussed before Moody's, this is one of the way to be safe in present of event, like downgraded in this period, but can come any time. So, I think I have replied to all three questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, on Pioneer, can you just update us on what the role of the company is in your mind within the group? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pioneer has presented recently, I think, it was three, four months ago their strategic plan. Pioneer is a company quite unique in Italy in the sense that it's doing a captive and non-captive business. The non-captive is growing faster than the captive one. It's a company that is enjoying a full independency from the bank. Clearly there is a very good cooperation with the network. There is a distribution agreement in place, but I think that if you want to keep Pioneer as we've decided to keep Pioneer, Pioneer has to develop its own business also versus institution, as it cannot rely only on the network side.</p>
          <p>So, we are happy about the result of the quarter if you look at the result of the quarter, quite positive. The good news as well is that the outflow that we have seen in the last quarter is now much, much less. The situation is stabilized, outflow in particular was referring to the captive business. So, we are looking further with some, let's say, positive view on the evolution of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Andrea Vercellone of Exane. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good afternoon. Two questions on my side. The first one is on dividend, but I'm not going to ask you whether you are going to pay a dividend. I just want to know if the capital ratios in Q1 included any accrual for a possible dividend.</p>
          <p>The second question is unencumbered eligible assets. You always update us with the number of liquid assets, but you never tell us how much of these liquid assets is encumbered versus unencumbered. So, I'd like to know if you can share with us, at the end of the quarter, what was the amount of unencumbered assets? And also, if you can give us your best estimates as to how much this number could go down by, if your short-term credit rating gets downgraded by Moody's? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first question, we have embedded in the current numbers a dividend for a total of &#x20AC;550 million. It is a number that doesn't &#x2013; is not related to any decision versus dividend 2012. It's just, if I remember correctly, the average of the dividend payout of the last two or three years. So, it is an accrual that is done just to not show zero, but what will be the real dividend will be decided, as I said, before year end. For a while, &#x20AC;550 million. On the unencumbered assets, we are coming &#x2013; and Marina will give you the number for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, here, the collateralized funding, we had overall an amount of collateralized funding amounting to &#x20AC;160 million approximately. But this does include a significant amount of repo, so &#x20AC;80 million approximately. So, I would not look at the overall amount but only of the component minus the repo, which means that less than 10% of our total liabilities is used as a collateralized funding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Excuse me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That wasn't the question. My question is as of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As of the end of the quarter, how much assets can you still pledge at the ECB? It's most important...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't get it. Okay. It's &#x2013; out of &#x20AC;117 billion of counterbalancing capacity, we are using &#x20AC;29 billion while we have available the remaining portion, &#x20AC;88 billion. So, this is the two elements, the component which is used and the component which is free and available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And would you share with us an estimate of how much of this &#x20AC;88 billion, which you can do whatever you want with, may decline if your short-term credit rating gets downgraded?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't &#x2013; we don't expect to have an impact since we have a liquidity buffer, so we don't see any impact on these as a result of the downgrade.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you don't think you're going to have to post more collaterals for derivatives, swaps and so on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't think that we are going to increase, let's say, we are not going to increase the counter-balancing capacity if this is the question. And we will &#x2013; since we have a liquidity buffer, we will have the cash if needed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. James Hyde of Pramerica. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's exactly the previous question but taking it a bit further with fixed income investors. Just looking at now what I know is &#x20AC;88 billion of what you call counter-balancing capacity. And comparing that to the disclosure on page 28, of short-term liabilities which I assume are wholesale of &#x20AC;259 billion, this would compare very poorly with most European banks and even some Italian banks. So, I'm just wondering, do you not think you have to either term out a lot faster than you have been or hold a lot more liquidity?</p>
          <p>Moody's, I know, looks at this over a 12-month period and so I'm just wondering does your liquidity management not have to change drastically given these figures? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, could you mind to repeat because I think that you are mixing up two different types of things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Right...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the balance sheet and you were referring to the counter-balancing capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, okay, let me explain. Fixed income investors and rating agencies look at what happens to you in a one-year period of non-access to wholesale markets. Now, you've got what you just disclosed as &#x20AC;88 billion of repo-able assets, you got &#x20AC;9 billion of cash on the balance sheet, that's on the asset, liquid asset side. Now, if we take short-term liabilities on page &#x2013; slide 28, that's &#x20AC;259 billion as a gap, I mean, this is a very large gap for French banks have brought this to near zero or no longer a gap, and I'm just wondering, do you not have to take heed of this given what happens to markets regularly &#x2013; that is to say, freezing up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just to understand, are you suggesting that we have a &#x20AC;250 billion-odd in the short-term end, so if things go wrong, that's the basic gap we have to fill, is that what you're suggesting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what slide 28 would suggest, that's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No, it doesn't suggest that, but that's flat wrong. The &#x20AC;80 billion &#x2013; I'm sorry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's &#x2013; sorry, the slide, you have to difference &#x2013; this right side of the slide is a breakdown by maturities regardless of the counterparties. It's not only wholesale market or interbank position or repo, as you &#x2013; let's say, or you have breakdown by counterparties on the left side and breakdown by maturities on the right side. On the right side, we have also customer business, short-term and we have also, say, deposit, which, by the way, here we are reporting the state of maturity so the contractual maturity which is a factual element that our side deposits which are amounting in Italy to report a number which we are very familiar with, so &#x20AC;120 million, show a resilience so high that we can attribute duration of these side deposits in excess of two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, because if you look into the structural definition of liquidity of the balance sheet, basically, we're 95% match funded. So, you're looking at a very, very small component of the balance sheet that is open to other forms. Against that 5%, we have this &#x20AC;88 billion. So, the side deposits, effectively when you do the stickiness of the underlying repo &#x2013; is the replicating portfolio, it's almost closed down in three years.  So, it's the wrong conclusion that you're drawing from the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, okay. Then let me ask it the other way around. Okay, so you've got &#x2013; so we agreed that you got &#x20AC;88 billion plus &#x20AC;9 billion cash on balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Forget about the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the asset side. On liabilities side, how much is coming up within a year? You've got &#x20AC;26 billion of longer term rolling off, what is the short-term wholesale funding on top of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James, it's Federico here. I think that the best is maybe if we put you in touch with our treasury and our CFO. So, we can go more in details because I think there is a different interpretation probably of the items and the way we see things. So, we feel to be very strong in terms of liquidity. So, we don't have &#x2013; we don't feel what you are  thinking, but the best in my opinion, considering that for you, this point seems to be very important, is if we get in touch with you and we go you whole details, so you can understand the point to have a better evaluation maybe...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...if you agree.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Domenico Santoro of Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Just to find a clarification. First of all, out of this &#x20AC;406 billion customer deposits, can you tell us how much is side deposits, term deposits and how much is repo with the clearing house?</p>
          <p>And on the release of the generic provision for &#x20AC;190 million, which was the division actually that benefit from this? You probably mentioned Italy before. I just want to be sure about that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One second. We are looking for the breakdown because I remind Italy by memory but not clearly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Here, out of the &#x20AC;406 billion, the pure &#x2013; what is real commercial business, or we call commercial, is &#x20AC;332 million. While we create a sort of internal cluster but it's not stated in the accounts. So, it's only for the purpose of managerial analysis, where we put market counterparties, the corporate center as &#x2013; let's say, a corporate center of the holding company and the intercompany. And overall, this is amounting to &#x20AC;74 billion. So, this is the amount which in order to split, but these are going to be only managerial information. So, the clearing house is lower and I will let you the number of line later because I need to find out among my figures. Sorry. There was another question of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Domenico, just to give you an idea. To stay with Italian side, is I think is the most critical in this moment. Most of the deposits are side deposits. As I remember, the number should be &#x20AC;149 billion customer deposit, meaning side deposit. The term deposits at the end of March were only &#x20AC;7 billion. So, again, &#x20AC;149 side, plus &#x20AC;7 billion term deposits, &#x20AC;43 billion network bonds, this for the Italian business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up. Do we have an idea of out of the &#x20AC;330 million, how much is side, how much is term, roughly, or the commercial part?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Out of the commercial part, there is &#x2013; here we have a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We cannot give you a precise number. But anyway, the take cash interest in Europe and Poland but the proportion is very similar to Italy. Most of the deposits are short-term. But for the other countries like Turkey, you don't do more than one month, anyway, even if you go to term deposits. And Germany, Austria is a bit more on term compared to the proportion in Italy. So, large part of the deposit are cash &#x2013; side deposits, substantially with a very, very high, anyway, stickiness, because again, if I look, again, on the Italian side, that has been the much more stressed in this period of time, the end of June and there was quite mild economic situation, the level of deposit, side deposit was &#x20AC;150 billion, was &#x20AC;149 billion at the end of March, with very difficult let's say situation. So, as you'll see the stickiness is pretty high.</p>
          <p>And there was a question about the utilization of &#x20AC;190 million of generic reserves has been the beneficiary of this release. <mark type="audio gap" /> (1:36:48)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Gentlemen, Mr. Ghizzoni, there are no questions registered at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Also for the second question, again, we don't have the numbers now with us. It's a small amount that we don't remember. We will give the numbers to you later on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. This time there are no more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, I think we can close here. Thank you very much for your question, for listening to us, and we'll talk again the beginning of August for the half year results. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for joining. The conference is now over, and you may disconnect your telephone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>