<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1377332" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-03-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7874</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Federico Ghizzoni, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="analyst">Domenico Vinci</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Marina Natale</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Karl Guha</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Andrea Scauri</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Jean Pierre Mustier</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Francesca Tondi</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Alessandro Roccati</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Roberto Nicastro</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Marcello Zanardo</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Ronny Rehn</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Domenico Santoro</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Giovanni Carriere</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Paola Biraschi</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Jeremy Sigee</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So we can &#x2013; I think we can start. Good morning and welcome also on behalf of my colleagues today to our premises. Sorry for my voice. It's a bit down, but two minutes before during a TV interview a lady told me that it is more sexy, so at least &#x2013; feeling better now. So I hope it will contribute to the success of the day.</p>
          <p>Let's start with our numbers, if I can go through the presentation. As usual, I will go through and then we will open the Q&amp;A. There was a recommendation coming from Simone that each of you should <mark type="indiscernible" /> two questions so that we can reply to many of you and then if we have time we start the second round. This is a recommendation coming from the organization.</p>
          <p>Results, fourth quarter, &#x20AC;321 million of net profit is a quite special, let's say, quarter because we have a quite good trend in term of revenues and costs. In spite of the fact that we had a very difficult quarter in term of trading income due to the problem for southern <mark type="indiscernible" /> in South Europe and a number of one-off, below the line which we will explain later on, but as you can see quite positive trend in term of gross operating profit.</p>
          <p>Revenues, as I said, up 0.9% quarter-on-quarter with a stronger contribution in term of net interest and fees and commission.</p>
          <p>Very positive is the trend in term of costs. They are down 4% quarter-on-quarter with an improvement of the cost/income to 57.3%. Operating profit is &#x20AC;2.8 billion, is growing 8.4% versus the previous quarter. And we see &#x2013; we're seeing for the first time quite a good, strong contribution coming from all divisions &#x2013; business divisions.</p>
          <p>Loan provision, slightly up versus third quarter. We have &#x2013; improving trend year-on-year, typical, let's say, year-end peak, I would say, is the result of this quarter, but I have to stress also looking forward that the trend is positive and we see a decreasing trend inside the group.</p>
          <p>The leverage is improving 21.5%. A very solid funding and liquidity structure is confirmed, we will see during the presentation. And what is important to leave as a strong message since now is that we have a cost of funding substantially impact very little, by the fact that by the increase of spread in South Europe. So UniCredit, compared to other Italian banks, thanks for the geographical mix, is not suffering that much in term of increase of cost of funding.</p>
          <p>Core Tier I, 8.58%, slightly down, 3 bps. We will see the reason later on.</p>
          <p>I don't want to go to long time with this slide. We already touched some of the number. As you can see looking at other non-operating items, more than &#x20AC;1 billion is out there one-off that we will see later on. Same, the income tax for the period is positive for &#x20AC;495 million. The same story we will explain in the next slide.</p>
          <p>Cost of risk, as you can see, is 126 bps, nine bps higher versus previous quarter, but again looking forward we think that the positive trend year-on-year will continue.</p>
          <p>One-off, again, we will give you a quick snapshot then we will reply maybe to your questions. There are substantially three, four major items. Goodwill impairment in negative is &#x20AC;199 million coming once again from Kazakhstan mostly, &#x20AC;197 million.</p>
          <p>Then we have quite a significant amount in term of provision for risk and charges related to a single name in Germany, &#x20AC;125 million. <mark type="indiscernible" /> is the largest wind park in Europe under construction. It started a few years ago. We have done an impairment for risk and charges because the cost of construction are increasing due mostly to the underestimation of the adverse, let's say, weather condition in the Baltic Sea. This is a wind park that's 100 kilometers far from the coast. So just to simplify what we have covered is the difference between the additional cost for completing the park and what was the original level of investments. So we have covered this amount, but then I will give more explanation in detail later on.</p>
          <p>Integration costs, &#x20AC;254 million, the one-off related to One4C only this year. I will not touch in positive and negative, the &#x20AC;118 million up and &#x20AC;116 million negative because they are referring to the same item and substantially is on different accounting way about the same investments.</p>
          <p>And finally, in term of taxes, we have a positive effect of &#x2013; from DTA in Germany and once again in Italy due to one-off that is impacting positively for &#x20AC;495 million on the P&amp;L. For sure we can give you more detail later on.</p>
          <p>So substantially it is a quite, let me say, extraordinary quarter, because of this one-offs in positive and negative coming all in the same time. Even though then the effect is almost neutral because there is a &#x20AC;43 million negative effect on the P&amp;L. What I think is important is to look anyway up to the gross operating profit, which is definitely a positive trend.</p>
          <p>Here more information about the main operating trend. Net interest last plus net commission, as I said, definitely up. The quarter is one of the best &#x2013; actually the best since the second quarter '09 is a positive trend. Again, maybe my colleagues think I'm too optimistic, but I think this is the trend that we will get also in the following quarters.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses, down. As you will see, we have also some one-off, but also cleanly from one-off, the trend is very positive in term of costs.</p>
          <p>Net write-downs of loans, as we discussed already, there is a peak year-end, but trend year-on-year is positive.</p>
          <p>Net interest, net commissions, trading income; net interests are moving up. Here we start to see some positive effects on the spreads of deposits especially in Retail and Private Banking. Also thanks to the fact that we have the Euribor moving &#x2013; Euribor &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; moving up, not negatively affected by the cost of funding. That, as we said already, is under control. <mark type="indiscernible" /> definitely a positive trend, quarter-on-quarter and year-on-year.</p>
          <p>So a positive evolution of revenues despite of the fact that as you see in term of credit income there is a big drop, third quarter versus fourth quarter, is negative in itself, but overall is also positive. So in spite of this we've been able to move up.</p>
          <p>In trading income, January and February shows a completely different trend versus what you see in this slide.</p>
          <p>Net interest, up 2.5% quarter-on-quarter. As we said, the Euribor rise starts to have effect on the account of the Group. Let's keep in mind that, contrary to other banks, we are basically unhedged. So when there is an increase of rates, there is a good effect on our accounts. This is also supported by good commercial activities coming from Central Eastern Europe, from Germany, other part of the Group, Italy included. And finally the funding cost, as I said, hedging up, but substantially under control, so a positive trend.</p>
          <p>Fees and commissions, just to give you an idea, the trend, as I said, is definitely up, particularly net commission from investment service, from &#x20AC;723 million to &#x20AC;844 million through that third quarter of each year is the fourth quarter, but the trend is definitely positive. Same when we talk about other net commission. This is positive not just for the number in itself because these are confirmation that in term of commercial activity things start moving in the same &#x2013; in the good direction.</p>
          <p>Expenses, we are doing a lot of effort to keep costs under control. Clearly there is a strong commitment to continue also this year, and we're starting to see some positive effects. Costs are down 4% quarter-on-quarter. As we said, we have some one-offs, third quarter versus fourth quarter. Nevertheless, all-in-all, also eliminated &#x2013; eliminating this one-off, we are down 0.7%. The challenge really in front of us &#x2013; challenge that we want to win, obviously just to maintain a good trend also in 2011. Composition is minus 3.9% in term of staff expenses, partially offset by cost in <mark type="indiscernible" /> other expenses, mostly coming from invoicing arriving at the end of the year for IT services and some investments we have to do. Of course, we have to sustain the marketing activity, once again, because the business has to pick up especially in Germany, Austria and Central Eastern Europe, so we had a notion to spend. Finally, for a good reason, some money, but together all trend is positive and costs are under control.</p>
          <p>One clarification about the staff because the staff is increasing, but this is mostly a technicality. Actually, we had to consolidate for the first time a number of small companies that have never been consolidated in the past. There was a change of approach from regulators in this respect. So the cost of this staff was already included obviously in the overall cost of the Group, but the internal number of people are not included, from this quarter it is included. So we have an increase of 1,200 people. Excluding this effect of consolidation, we would have seen once again the staff overall going down from 383 people, confirmation of the strong attention also in term of hiring and utilization of people.</p>
          <p>Starting from 2011, we have the effect of One4C. So already in Italy in January 2011 we have 1,500 people leaving the company due to agreement reached with the unions and I think October last year.</p>
          <p>Loan loss provision, here as you see the picture, let me say, is a mix, even though, again, I think that the trend is positive. But the pickup to &#x20AC;1,751 million fourth quarter versus third quarter coming mostly from a slight increase in Italy and a very prudent, let me say, approach in Central Eastern Europe where we had country-by-country right conservative prudent review of all the provisions that brought us to bring up a bit the level. All in all, the cost of risk goes to 126 basis points. Again, I think, if we look year-on-year, there is a positive trend that has to continue in 2011.</p>
          <p>Asset quality, we've seen 3.4% increase quarter-on-quarter driven mostly by Italy. Meanwhile in Germany, we have exactly the opposite situation, same good trend in Austria and Poland. Particularly 2.5% up is the level of gross non-performing loans or NPLs, 4.5% up the other gross impaired loans. Here again during the presentation and later on, we'll give more details.</p>
          <p>The coverage ratio is 44.4%, is slightly down compared to the previous quarter, but I think is quite stable and sound. Let's keep in mind that our policy is &#x2013; and we're not comparable too much with other banks, because our policy is to provision more on the doubtful loans rather than other banks. So at the end, if you look doubtful loans and yes it seems that we provision less on NPL, we provision more on doubtful loan. If you put all together, at the end the, level of provision is better because we provision more and higher level stock is the impaired loan deducted NPLs.</p>
          <p>Included in them also the &#x20AC;3.5 billion (sic) [&#x20AC;3.1 billion] of let's say generic reserves, we think that the level is very sound and that is enough in terms of coverage.</p>
          <p>Some information about the different asset quality situation region-by-region, as you see, they start with the good news. Germany is definitely going down; Austria is under control; Poland, stable; CEE, excluding Kazakhstan, is slightly up; Kazakhstan, this is a good news, starts to see some positive effects accounting from the restructuring. So the gross ratio starts to go down from 49% to 45.6% in the last quarter.</p>
          <p>Italy is still growing with a gross ratio that is moving from 13.8% to 15.1%. This is a point of attention, clearly first for us, it is a point of attention also from your side, is in any case also, let me say, I want to be a bit provocative, a very high potential looking forward, because as we will explain for Italy, we're going through a strong turnaround, includes revenues but mostly cost of income &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; cost of risk, and cost in general terms. So, we have definitely some issue, but at the same time, we probably <mark type="indiscernible" /> can become the interesting story of turnaround. So for us bringing Italy to a level of profitability "decent" will be a big important achievement.</p>
          <p>In terms of asset quality, the good trend in any case confirm, again, we have to see year-on-year and we have the net addition quarter-by-quarter decreasing. So overall, let's say the annualized cost of risk is going down, impaired loans addition as well is decreasing. So the trend is in the right direction. Even more confirmed by this slide, as you see the reverse ratio was 41% first half '09, keeps going up, it is now at 69% second half of '10. So that the new addition and reverse ratio are definitely improving.</p>
          <p>I will not talk too much, this slide, you already see the number is the non-operating items <mark type="indiscernible" />. So we'll move to the next one, just a few words about the balance sheet. I would say that total assets are substantially stable. That is minus 4% versus the third quarter, mostly due to hedging instruments that are growing sharply down. Tangible equity, stable; and the leverage, improving to 21.5.</p>
          <p>Customer loans as well are stable, even though if we exclude what we call Cassa Compensazione e Garanzia. Marina can explain better than me what exactly &#x2013; I mean, what exactly is working, but excluding Cassa Compensazione e Garanzia, in reality loans are going up &#x20AC;5.4 billion. So we start, again, to see some positive commercial trend here.</p>
          <p>Deposits are moving in the right directions, as you know very important in this period of time of liquidity. For us it is very important to have this large customer base in term of rising deposit, but also in term of having capability to sell our bonds. Any time, we go to our customer with a bond, we don't &#x2013; we experience a very positive response from all of them.</p>
          <p>Security issues are going down mostly due to the fact that, as you know, the CD/CP U.S. market declined quite significantly in the last part of the quarter. This is reflected in the slides, look down, bottom right on the interbank, it is going proportionately up to compensate the decline on the CD/CP market. Financial investments are up. We are investing the liquidity that we hope with the commercial activity picking up will be disinvested to make space or to loans that are more profitable.</p>
          <p>The funding structure is very solid. No hesitation in term of this data. There are banking &#x2013; there are typical customer-driven balance sheet with the banking book almost 80% of total assets. The funding base is stable. Again, it is very important to have a very solid, loyal customer base in a period like this one. There is definitely space with this liquidity to push on the lending side.</p>
          <p>Also, a few words about the funding plan. In these days liquidity, as you know, is all the time an issue. We had &#x2013; we have a funding plan for 2011 of &#x20AC;32 billion that has been already executed, almost 43% in the first two-and-half months. So we have already covered most of our needs. We decided to dissipate part of it.</p>
          <p>In term of mix, it is very well diversified as you can see. So for us funding is not a major problem. Clearly &#x20AC;32 billion is a challenge, but with this diversification, with our capability to access the market also from different geographical liquidity centers, we normally go to the market, to Italy and Germany, partially in Austria and Poland, we feel extremely comfortable in rising funding at very competitive rates.</p>
          <p>And the liquidity position, again very strong. Our internal liquidity ratio is above the limits, internal limits that are traditionally very conservative. We are today at 0.98 with an internal limit of 0.90. So our liquidity horizon is above 90 days and the counterbalancing capacity, which is more than &#x20AC;100 billion, is totally unutilized.</p>
          <p>So in term of liquidity, we are very prudent. There is an internal debate if we are too prudent or not. We prefer stay in this situation by now because we think that the volatility in the market &#x2013; with the volatility in the market, it is better to be conservative rather than opposite.</p>
          <p>And finally capital, Core Tier I is at 8.58%; Tier I, 9.46%. We have a slight decline on the Core Tier I of three basis points, coming mostly from increasing of risk weighted asset from operational risk. We see the reason why. Dividend distribution, in line with the consensus, has been &#x20AC;3 per &#x2013; $0.03 per share, so is in line with 2009.</p>
          <p>Most important I think is to see, here in the slides is about Basel III. So substantially if you remember the last &#x2013; previous quarter we gave some guidelines about the impact of Basel III on us. Here we have a much more detailed and clear explanation. The concept substantially is that if we apply today Basel III without phasing, we are already above the 7% minimum that is supposed to be reached in 2019. So the impact would be 1.31 basis point. So we are above 7% with no phasing, the impact would be 0.76% with phasing.</p>
          <p>So again, from 8.58% capital ratio, including all the impact in positive and negative of Basel III, conclusion is that, today we would be already aligned with &#x2013; we will be above minimum 7% supposed to be reached in 2019. That means that with the business plan that we have in mind, with our capability to generate profit in the next few years, with the capability to generate also dividend, we will be in a position to have a comfortable capital base.</p>
          <p>Let me close with some messages, let's say, that 2010 was definitely a difficult year, has been a difficult year, it has been an year of restructuring. Now we look with a much more optimism, 2011. As I said, the first two months of this year are showing good results, results in line definitely with our expectation.</p>
          <p>What is our strength, that has been declared in the past is becoming really a strength, one is the geographical diversification and business diversification. Again, as I said, we are now in countries that are really performing very well; Germany, one; CEE as well. Again last quarter of last year, first part of this year is confirming what I am saying.</p>
          <p>CEE potential is there. We have definitely an healthy balance sheet and a stronger liquidity position. Room to increase cost efficiency is there. It is one of the major challenge we have in front of us. And we think to have a solid capital ratio that give us flexibility to move strategically to improve the performances of the Group.</p>
          <p>So what are the challenges in front of us, and this is the last slide. I am not talking now about mission or about vision. Let's see what we have to do in 2011, starting 2011. Italy first of all, Italy is definitely a story of turnaround. So with the 40% revenue, let's say, generated in Italy and the profit that is definitely not in line with that, for me Italy is the focus for 2011.</p>
          <p>And we've already started to execute our internal plan, that is to focus mostly on cost of risk; reduction of cost of risk; working, yes, on the quality of the new underwriting and mostly on recovery and restructuring.</p>
          <p>Cost in itself, not just cost cutting, but creating a structure that keeps cost stable and under control is the second challenge. One4C is helping in this respect. It is not indicated here on the revenue side, but the more I am personally entering in the business in Italy, the more I see very good potential, also to improve on the revenue side, especially in SMEs and in <mark type="indiscernible" />. Anyway, Italy is the turnaround story of the Group. If we are able, and we'll be, because I am very confident in this respect to bring Italy back to a level of profitability in line with our expectation, the effect on the Group will be for sure positive.</p>
          <p>Germany is, as I said, there the priority is consolidation. In reality, Germany is a market that is performing very well. As you know, our presence is mostly corporate. The corporate in Germany is definitely performing even above the expectations. I don't know if you're familiar with Germany, but I've been in Germany also a couple of weeks ago. I am going quite frequently. The mood of meeting customer is very positive. I met two weeks ago, yes, two or three weeks ago 400 customers in a talk that we organized in the bank. And believe me they are really &#x2013; compared to what it was one year ago, it is a different world. They see the cost of their companies and this is a potential of the German system in a very positive way. And in Germany in term of business, in term of corporate business, we are very strong in my opinion.</p>
          <p>Market is performing really well. Here we are improving day-by-day on the synergies with the franchise of the Group. Especially, in Central Eastern Europe, we see an increasing number of transactions coming up.</p>
          <p>Austria is similar to Germany even though the scale is clearly different. And CEE is the area of growth for our Group. Again, I don't want to repeat the story about CEE, but also again, the first two months of this year in CEE are definitely showing results above our internal expectations.</p>
          <p>So this is the homework that we have in front of us. I am closing here the presentation. And now we are ready for your questions. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Domenico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. It's Domenico Vinci from Goldman Sachs. I have two questions, one on funding and one on asset quality. On the funding side, a clarification, you explained the interbank fund increase replaced the commercial paper. So is that to assume there was no sharpening of the maturity profile of your funding and also that you are not using in any major size ECB funding?</p>
          <p>And then, can you give us an idea what is the difference in the cost of the bonds that are maturing for you over the next two years and the cost of the new retail bonds to be issued? It seems from the presentation that it's going to be a major area of funding for you going forward.</p>
          <p>And then, on the asset quality, you gave quite a positive outlook or expectation from your side on the turnaround of Italy. At Group level, you had a reduction in cost of risk of 17% this year, so the provision dropped 17%. Do you expect this trend to be confirmed actually improve next year? And more in general, do you have a sense where &#x2013; when we can see impaired loans stop growing for the Group and particularly for Italy? I am referring mostly to their watch list rather than the NPL initial trends. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe before going to Marina with the funding issue and the numbers, let me say once again, the funding for us is a completely different story compared to other Italian banks. The cooperation inside the group between the four major treasury centers of Italy, Germany, Austria and Poland is constantly improving.</p>
          <p>Clearly, when we go to the market, with Italy, we pay the country spread of Italy; when we go with Germany, we pay the country spread for Germany. And this again has an overall positive impact on the cost of funding for the Group. So, it is something that was not maybe so effective until some months ago is becoming now a point of strength of the Group. Here, we endorsed are still AAA countries.</p>
          <p>Regarding then the trend in term of cost of risk, clearly the trend is confirming is going down. The pressure I am putting personally is, it has to be going down even faster. And we will see what our CRO will say, but is a battle that we have to win and I have no hesitation to say that it will be positive platform for us.</p>
          <p>Finally, for the question &#x2013; the last one was about? Yes, in fact at this as well, Karl will give you more details. If we talk about Italy and anyway, we start to see retail going down, so level of stabilization and improvement has been already reached and CIB, there is a strong deceleration, still a slight increase but this is much less some respect also here during 2011 the stabilization in them possibly decrease. Marina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, thank you for asking only two questions. We kindly ask you to ask only two questions each in this room to allow people to connect later on to ask their own question. About funding, you're right, the point we lost CD/CPs during the last quarter. This is a common trend across Europe, mainly due to the peripheral and the sovereign crises, but the impact has been limited on our structural liquidity ratio and on the KPI, we're using it to measure our liquidity and I would say that this is not impacting as you have seen in the slide presented the structural liquidity ratio of the Group which stays at the significant good level above 0.90%.</p>
          <p>You asked about the weight of &#x2013; due to the significant weight of <mark type="indiscernible" /> bonds and the implication in term of cost going forward, I don't see a significant material impact and the weight is not that remain a significant and relevant contributor of our funding plan for 2011. But the level of rates is not going up in a material way. So we'll not change the overall cost of the funding plan in 2011 versus the one realized in 2010, and to give you the sense that the Group Network Bonds will be anyway slightly below the level that we have put &#x2013; we have distributed during 2010. We were close to 40% in 2010, while out of the &#x20AC;24 billion, while in 2011, we will stay probably below the 30% in term of volumes. I guess that this was the question about liquidity on funding and I will pass over to Karl about <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. My normal position is between a rock and a hard place, my boss being the rock, you being the hard place. So I am used to the pressure on asset quality and provisions. And the first question, when do we expect to stabilize? I think it's reasonable to expect that it will be end of summer, beginning of third quarter. This is when I expected it to stabilize. But you have to look at the underlying picture to get a different picture but as in Germany, it's largely dominated by large corporates. And I think that we've already seen that happen in Italy where the portfolio is much more granular and much smaller.</p>
          <p>The credit lag effect takes time and a typical cycle as you know is seven years and three in a cyclical downturn. So we're into the third year of that. So the drag effect will be for another two or three quarters before bottoming out and then moving definitely in the sort of upward direction. But we do see in the migrations that we see within the performing portfolio, which defines what you asked earlier, the watch list. There is a definitive improvement. And it's been for the last few quarters. So we see the improvement very consistent.</p>
          <p>Your second question was about, what was your question actually, on liquidity, I don't know whether you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Andrea Scauri from Mediobanca. Two questions, one on capital and one on Pioneer. On capital, slide 28, you are giving a lot of guidelines that refer to growth except for Italy. I wonder what type of capital consumption do you expect this growth to have and when do you expect SEFII banks to be communicated capital requirements?</p>
          <p>The second is on Pioneer. And it's a question also for Mr. Mustier. And asset management in general is a business of high ROE with very little capital requirements. UniCredit is a bank that is positioned in high saving rate countries and in countries where there is a high perspective of growth of customer assets in CEE.</p>
          <p>Well, it's quite clear, the rationale behind economies of scale in this business. Are you not afraid that by disposing of Pioneer, you would be losing competencies in advisory and hence losing synergies, not only directly on asset management, but also for the other divisions of the Group? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding capital, as I said, we are today at a very, in our opinion, comfortable level. If we look further including risk-weighted asset growth, including profitability expected and including an appropriate dividend policy, still we are at this position opinion that the level will continue to be positive and comfortable. So that view that you see is not static, is also forward looking.</p>
          <p>SEFII, we should have &#x2013; we should receive if I'm not mistaken some information by June. This is the first threshold that regulators put in front of them. From what I know &#x2013; but can change any time. We will not have a list of banks classified SEFIIs, is at least is what is coming up to today from regulators. So, I don't think that they say they will not come with a list. UniCredit is inside, UniCredit is outside. They will come with the requirements. We will see which one. So here, we are just awaiting and seeing because the level of information is not now enough to judge a possible impact in positive or negative on capital activities of the banks so far.</p>
          <p>Pioneer, before leaving &#x2013; going to Jean Pierre, and by the way, we welcome in our team. He started officially &#x2013; this is the second week. So it's very fresh and he may also help in replying with a different new management coming from different experiences. Pioneer, as I &#x2013; first of all, we don't want to give &#x2013; we don't want to stay in this situation of uncertainty too long. We gave to us two, three weeks to take a final decision. Economy of scale, yes, but this was not again our main driver as it was not our main driver. I don't know of relief in terms of capital, et cetera, et cetera. I was to see it was possible or not to find a solution for Pioneer, where Pioneer will continue to serve in any case our customer base as it is today, but if possible better in term of service and efficiency.</p>
          <p>We will say if the present proposals are matching this ambition or not, if not, we will stay with Pioneer in the Group and rework in &#x2013; on developing and restructuring Pioneer by ourselves. And this would be taken as a decision in a very short period of time. Jean Pierre?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to comment about the synergies between the &#x2013; say, the activities in the asset management side, from a previous life experience, I could say that the synergies between the CIB side and the asset managers do not change, whether the asset manager is in or outside of the Group for the simple reason that we deal on the completely arm-length basis with the asset manager. So, I don't think that Pioneer evolution will impact the situation that we will do.</p>
          <p>But you raised the issue of the CEE side and clearly, and as far as the SEFII side is concerned, CEE is a very important area of development and of synergies with the rest of the Group. And in the market side, there has been a certain number of initiatives taken. On the financing side, we are looking as well to develop the business, which is not only the local business with local clients, but also the cross-selling with &#x2013; inbound clients from our various regions, which could be Germany, Italy, Asia or the U.S. into the CEE. So CEE will be as far as we are concerned a growth area, but the asset management side is looking to impact due to develop synergies that we want to develop it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning. Francesca Tondi from Morgan Stanley. I'll stick to the two questions, one on funding and one on capital. Going back to your slide 23 on funding structure, you just mentioned that perhaps the Network Bonds will be in proportion lower than last year, but the total funding requirement is higher. Can you give us a little bit more color on how you see the mix changing for 2011? And also, if you can give us a bit of color on how this looks, not just at group level, but Italy versus Germany. You just mentioned you have the arbitrage on the spread, but also in terms of the balance sheet structure of HVB, the need for more liquidity there with the Investment Bank, if you can actually comment on that if possible I think it will be useful.</p>
          <p>And related to that, your net interbank remains high, take the point of the switch from the commercial paper in Q4. Do we see that rebalancing? Is it something that we should be concerned about? Can you comment on that?</p>
          <p>And on capital, do you see pressurizing overall in Europe? I mean, we hear of a stress test coming, the SEFII definition, the additional buffers, how do you look at that in a context where, even on Basel III, the capital that you have, by all means is not bad at all, but it is on the bottom scale and of the European in a large cut league. Your earning generation needs to improve. So can you actually tell us a little bit more how you see the environment changing and how you're thinking or reacting to that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About funding plan, and I will take over and let's say, and I don't see only a couple of figures, so the most recent one to give you the flavor. We are already, say, well advanced in our funding plan for 2011, and we are above 40% of the percentage of achievement at the Group level and 48% in Italy. So the level of, say, the funding plan is already "launched" for 2011 and well advanced. And as in the past, we are trying to keep a balanced situation in Italy versus Germany and <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
          <p>Italy is calling for more funding. We are for sure <mark type="indiscernible" /> structures of the balance sheet in Italy, but at the same time we have the advantage that we can move liquidity, as pointed out by Federico, from Germany and since Germany is showing a better level of rate, so we are trying to leverage and to fully exploit this opportunity in order to be able to have &#x2013; and to keep under control the cost of funding at adequate level.</p>
          <p>In term of mix, I have already pointed out that the level of Network Bonds will not be in excess of 30%, while public sector and Covered Bonds will be almost 35% in 2011, while we were at the level below 30% in 2010. Based on these figures, you can detect that we are trying to push a lot towards the type of social funding which are showing better rates, lower rates and are mainly sourced in Germany and those were from refi and Covered Bonds can be easily distributed that there is good supply and that there is a good level of rates.</p>
          <p>So overall, I would say that the mix and the composition and the fact that the CD/CPs market write-up in the last month is something that is not affecting our ability to offset the market due to the diversification and due to the nature of our balance sheet. We have assets to be used and a good pool of assets for Covered Bonds which facilitate our &#x2013; and keep under &#x2013; allow to keep under control the cost of funding.</p>
          <p>Hopefully, I answered your question about funding. I think that we have in the appendix &#x2013; I don't know if I will be able to get there easily. In the appendix of the presentation, we have some slides showing not only the detail about the recent issuances we launched and the level of &#x2013; terms and condition we managed to get, but we have also some information about our retail bonds, natural bonds and the weight out of our key effects. So, there are a couple of slides, which might be useful to go through and to look at to have a better understanding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In term of capital, I do not see it recognized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would say that you put the right question, but at the same time, I don't want &#x2013; or we don't want to be managed by the pressure of the market. So &#x2013; and step by step. Now, what I said before, I'm confirming, which our feeling is that we think to have a positive and good capital position. SEFII, we'll see what will come; stress test as well, we'll see what will be the outcome. And personally, I go back to some statement of &#x2013; couple of months ago, I was saying that for me, stress tests are simply welcome, since that the previous stress test was not considered credible. So I hope this one will be, because, the end is good for everybody.</p>
          <p>So I am not feeling pressure from stress test. We know, what is our position. We'll see the results and important is that we have a plain &#x2013; we have a situation of same rules applied everywhere to everybody in the same way.</p>
          <p>Pressure, we'll see &#x2013; depend which kind of &#x2013; what do you mean for pressure. If pressure means the regulator is coming, telling you tomorrow you have to increase a capital, okay, this case, you have to increase the capital.</p>
          <p>If the pressure is -- there is an expectation to have the capital gradually going over the level you have today, we were to see and how to react to this pressure, the plan can be different. We may be confident in our capital generation, and so we can manage through our respected profitability, we can manage on our balance sheet. We can also have in the worst-case scenario plan B, with some asset for disposal.</p>
          <p>So again, I am not &#x2013; I don't want to take a decision without knowing what will be the situation tomorrow. I'm staying with the situation of today. The situation of today is that I strongly believe that our capital base is good enough to sustain the development of our business. If new events will come, we will manage them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And for sake of clarity, again that it was to underline that the slide we presented about capital is &#x2013; but for a way this &#x2013; we present &#x2013; we didn't include as we have done last time the impact of earning generation.</p>
          <p>So here is what will cost the Basel III effect while if we take, say, for the sake of argument also, the consensus earning without giving any guidance, you know that summing up the two years of consensus earning, 2011 and 2012, we will come at the level, which is well in excess above 100 basis points, it's 115 basis points to be precise, which means that that is in excess of the 0.76% we are showing here as impact of Basel III as of 1st January, 2013. So you were asking about the earning generation, the earning power, the earning judged by the analyst and so the consensus one is already covering the impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Alessandro Roccati from Macquarie. Two questions from me. The first one is for Mr. Mustier on the CIB division. What is your impression? I know you've been there for just a week. On the slide on the presentation and on the strategy, you mentioned that the franchise has been repositioned. I'm just wondering in terms of products whether there's going to be any repositioning?</p>
          <p>And the SocGen where you're coming from was very strong in equities and French banks are very strong in CIB. So what do you think is the future for the bank in this division? And then, also in terms of NII, it increased &#x20AC;160 millions in the division in the fourth quarter, and financing contribution was only &#x20AC;40 million, so understand the other &#x20AC;100 millions are coming from market. If you can tell us where this difference is coming from?</p>
          <p>The second question is very short for Mr. Nicastro, is actually on the margins. We see margins down in the fourth quarter, both in the mortgage and consumer credit for the new production, that's one of the slides presented. Just wondering whether there is any pressure in terms of repricing assets and what is your view in terms of asset repricing in case of an increasing interest rates. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just on the CIB side, I think it will be clearly a mistake to try to duplicate, you see UniCredit what other model can be used by other banks basically. So clearly not coming in <mark type="indiscernible" />. I think that within the past few weeks where I've been within the Group, I can see the strong and unbelievable client franchise that this group has in various European countries and we've seen and this is a quality of the local banks by our clients in various countries and the same time while global bank in terms of product delivery. And to be seen as a &#x2013; I mean a strong bank locally gives you an unbelievable potential in terms of development.</p>
          <p>So, I'd discuss with my colleagues and I think what we want to do is make sure that we exploit fully the potential of our clients. We have a relatively large capital allocation on the CIB side, which we use in terms of providing financing to our clients, and I think that we can work from that to create more synergies basically with the various product that we have. We have been developing in terms of the product side, product which today have high credibility in the European level we mentioned here. Our debt capital market product which I think has reached today European credibility level as far as the offering to the various issuers is concerned.</p>
          <p>We are working on other product development on the capital market side, on the financing side. And we are working as well, which I think is very important to create more synergies with the other parts of the group and mostly with the CEE side which is as well a differentiating factor for the bank. So what I am going to do with the team not only on the CIB side but with the teams of the other parts of the bank and is to look at how we can use this very strong client franchise of strength in the various product and to create more revenues which are probably going to be non-interest revenues but more fee revenues for the cross-selling in order to develop our activities while keeping a level of resources and capital in line with what we have today.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the non-interest income that you mentioned, there has been in the mix of revenues for the fourth quarter contribution of various segments which basically changed slightly the mix, it's mentioned in document and that's part of the explanation of the evolution that we have. It's coming mostly from one specific product or restructuring which improved our non-interest income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We experienced some slight decrease in the new asset repricing. This is &#x2013; I mean that is out of the fact that it took a little bit of time to move the slight increase in funding cost you need for the customers. For instance, if you take mortgage production from the moment in which you agree on the rate with the customer and the moment in which there is actually mortgage booking and mortgage funding introduced, there is a slight time lag that typically generates when there is slight interest rates movement that will have affect, but if you look at it &#x2013; at the slide, what you have is a reduction of 1% in the spread because what you have in the slide is an index that is 100 at the beginning and you have a decrease of 1% in the spread. So we are talking about a few basis points and no more than that.</p>
          <p>Then, there has been in Consumer Finance some slight changes in mix with higher weight of car loans that are a bit more &#x2013; have a lower tax spread than with the personal loans. So there is a product mix effect. And instead, we experienced some slight decreases in the spreads on mortgage lending in Austria. All of this to say that we don't see these as a structural trend been happening and I would say it on the other side that the actual <mark type="indiscernible" /> in 2011 is quite positive in terms of volumes and those in terms of the spread being captured.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Marcello Zanardo from Bernstein. And Mr. Ghizzoni rightly pointed out Italy as the key turnaround, so I would like to ask a question to him and to Mr. Guha. If I look at slide on page 16, clearly the dominant part of the gross impaired loans is Italy with &#x20AC;44 billion, which is roughly 10% up since June.</p>
          <p>Could you &#x2013; and this is the question, could you be a bit more specific on which kind of actions are you thinking of doing to improve the recovery process in Italy or any other actions which could accelerate write-backs or stop new flows, because clearly this is key &#x2013; this is the key turn &#x2013; one of the key turnaround for the story. So anything you could tell us today on this will be appreciated, at least by my side?</p>
          <p>And the second question on strategy. After a painful cleaning up exercise in Kazakhstan, which I think is almost done, and to pay full goodwill impairment, probably you're approaching the possibility to decide on what to do on the subsidiary, of course, if there is appetite. So the question here is should we expect additional &#x2013; I don't want to say clean-up, because Kazakhstan has a massive real estate bubble, so should we anticipate additional increased efforts in provisioning in other countries which you might consider selling or swapping? And if you sell Kazakhstan or other subsidiaries, where do you think that capital would be allocated in the rest of the Group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so about Italy, let's say that also taking profit from One4C, so from the merger of the three major banks. We have started to better design all of this area of recovery and restructuring division-by-division, segment-by-segment. There was a quite different situation in retail banking, the old retail banking and the old corporate banking.</p>
          <p>The old retail banking, let's say, the capability to recover and restructure was really quite well advanced for individuals and SMEs. On the corporate side, the situation was a bit different for many reasons, also because with the crisis coming, clearly we had to concentrate on big tickets rather than going all through the organization.</p>
          <p>So once we had the One4C we changed the threshold. The part of the portfolio of corporate, old corporate, up to &#x20AC;50 million revenues has moved to the retail division. What we have done here is, to apply more or less with some differences, the same system of recovery and restructure that we're applying to the old SMEs, and this has been done. So there is a structure fully dedicated and already with good experience coming from the old retail banking.</p>
          <p>We have completed just a few days ago, few weeks ago, the project &#x2013; so the implementation of this structure for the corporate, the new corporate division, and maybe Karl can give you more details. So he has been redesign the restructuring unit of the Group as a whole.</p>
          <p>Substantially just to give you some example, what is the total exposure below &#x20AC;75 million. Responsibility coming also to Italy has been given to the Italian Chief Risk Officer. By the way, also a new Chief Risk Officer in charge for the country as a whole has been implemented. It was not existing before. So we have one point of responsibility at the country level. And this guy, with his structure of restructuring, is in the position to take all the decision needed for what is below &#x20AC;75 million of exposure, that is what was our weak point because we were concentrating on large exposure, not too much on the other one. So as you know, restructuring and recovery, timing is essential.</p>
          <p>Having a strong link with a customer is essential, so to have responsibility home ground, close to business is in my opinion very important move. We're also accelerating some changes on the underwriting side.</p>
          <p>One of the problem that we have, let's say again with the corporate side, so there is a lot of <mark type="indiscernible" /> here as you see, is that we have still a very high number of customer with line of credit expired. And here as well we have to put in place a task force in order to have this line renewed. This is helping in term of avoiding additional, let's say, impaired loans even though more important is it has to add new business.</p>
          <p>And the more we go inside the business, the more we see potential for Italy. For example, I will continue with corporate, it's the same for retail. That the number of customers that are giving &#x2013; that's positive &#x2013; let's say, 80% of the net interest income in corporate comes from 10% of the customers. So this gives you a huge potential that we have also in term of revenues. 10% of the customer generating 80%, 85% of net interest income. So, again, all this activity have been put in place. We will have &#x2013; I will have customary as well monthly monitoring of the results, and I am confident again things will move in the right direction.</p>
          <p>Kazakhstan, yeah, the restructuring substantially is completed. We stay consistently on our line, meaning it's not country, let's say, core for us. So it depends on the possibility, capability to find a good proposal. If yes, yes. If not, restructuring anyway is finished, so should not be any more a problem, but we are open for discussion.</p>
          <p>And clearly provision in other countries are, honestly speaking, I don't think is needed because if we look for example some of the small countries, I know talking with you also privately for third year in line. In this country, in reality I think that the level of provision is very adequate.</p>
          <p>In Central Eastern Europe, we have three countries, let's say, still at risk model, the other one is &#x2013; one is Kazakhstan. Even though, again, Kazakhstan is started, with restructuring, completed now, country for the second year in a row is growing 6%, 7%. Ukraine as well delivered a loss is very high, and then is Romania. All of the other countries are &#x2013; Bulgaria maybe still with some point of attention, but all the other countries are showing positive trend. Some might &#x2013; would not find a space for cosmetic, let's say, decision actually. I am really &#x2013; I really &#x2013; I know, I know, as you know we see very well, I think for all this country now the level of provision is under weighed, not an extraordinary move.</p>
          <p>I don't &#x2013; I never go &#x2013; and I never disclose the list because there is no list. Any case it would be very negative for the people working up there and for the performance. So the list, sorry, is not available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Ronny Rehn from KBW, and one &#x2013; the first question I want to follow on the disposal point. You said one of the key problems in selling Kazakhstan is to find a buyer. It's probably also true for Ukraine, there are many sellers, a few buyers. I know one which wants to expand there which is SpareBank, active strategy to grow in those countries over the next couple of years. As it happens you just hire Mr. Profumo to the run the M&amp;A strategy, and so are you in discussions with SpareBank to sell Kazakhstan and Ukraine? That would be my first question.</p>
          <p>And secondly, on HVB with &#x20AC;1.7 billion net profit this year, compared to &#x20AC;1.3 billion for the whole Group, definitely a strong performer, what is your dividend policy going to look like in HVB? And could you even consider upstreaming more than 100% of the net profit given that the HVB is running on almost 17% Core Tier 1? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the first question, no, we are not in discussion with SpareBank. We have a very good relationship with SpareBank to say because also of the M&amp;A potential. For example, we exchange frequently view on back office activities, we exchange also ideas. We're also discussing about potential creation of new products in area where we have common prices.</p>
          <p>I know that they are interested to grow in the CIS countries. They know our position. I met also recently in Davos, the CEO. Now we see if with Alessandro this speed will &#x2013; or potential will grow or not. I'm sure that knowing Alessandro, I'm sure that he will not look only Kazakhstan and Ukraine, but also maybe other countries with higher potentials. It can be seen in positive and negative, his presence, vis-&#xE0;-vis Kazakhstan.</p>
          <p>HVB dividend policy. This year we have distributed 100% of the profit, correct. There is no discussion about the next dividend, 2011, so we will see what will be the situation.</p>
          <p>In HVB &#x2013; and we're committed to keep the big rate &#x2013; the level of capital also because of the investment banking activities booked in HVB. So that is not &#x2013; we don't have any discussion ongoing. This year there is 100% of the profit generated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. It's Santoro from Nomura. A question again on the NII, because I see your volumes increasing, I see also &#x2013; I've got your comment on cost of funding before and I see you are starting also to bank it probably from increasing rates. So I was just wondering whether you can comment on any contribution from hedging in Q4 and in 2010? I mean, especially to understand whether the growth of the NII might be constrained by any operations on this side?</p>
          <p>Second question is again on the NII, on the CIB, because I didn't get before the answer. So I was &#x2013; just to understand what is coming from the improvement in Q4 vis-&#xE0;-vis early Q3 which is a very, very strong? And then very quick, just a little bit of color on costs in 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On NII, I would say, to try to split in different components the contribution, we have almost, I would say, &#x20AC;40 million coming from the positive effect of movement of rates. 15 basis point quarter-on-quarter generate these positive contribution.</p>
          <p>Coming to your last point, I &#x2013; which is the contribution due to CIB, there is a significant chunk coming from the <mark type="indiscernible" />, which is a specific case, is a specific impact of new instruments, i.e., I would say that this is affecting or impacting, positive impacting the NII, but has to be treated as one-off.</p>
          <p>While there &#x2013; what we use internally to call the replicating portfolio, you used to call hedging, we have a limited contribution, as you know our hedging is limited. And to give you &#x2013; I think that we have already &#x2013; last time we have already disclosed the wait out of total assets of our hedging policy. It's almost 7% looking at the total assets. So out of &#x20AC;900 billion, we have only 6.7% hedged.</p>
          <p>If we look at only total side in saving deposits throughout of &#x20AC;250 billion, only 25%, which means that in a situation where the rates should go up, banks will share, and we will be exposed in a positive way to the upwards movement of the curve. And so we will benefit going forward for -without suffering for any hedging creating a ceiling. So &#x2013; and this is a positive element for our NII. Is that everything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Q1 actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, because as I mentioned to you, out of the &#x20AC;40 million, a portion is due, I will say, half is due to the mechanics of Euribor and a good portion is coming from the business. So the mark-down and mark-up, so our ability to manage the movement of rates on the deposit side and our ability to put in place the price reduction are contributing to the &#x20AC;40 million I mentioned to you, I will say, in the same portion. And also in the first quarter we see positive impact of rate movement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on cost maybe, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is &#x2013; cost in general for 2011, let's keep in mind, first of all that on the cost base we will have also the effect of levies encounters on banks, levies encounters like Germany, like Austria, Hungary, a small amount also U.K., what else? So to get in total, we have &#x2013; our estimation &#x20AC;170 million, &#x20AC;200 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;200 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;200 million? Not &#x20AC;170 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not &#x20AC;170 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;200 million, sorry. Marina's precise, &#x20AC;200 million of negative effect are coming from bank &#x2013; levies on banks. Another important guideline is that in 2011 we will start some investments, meaning we have to invest on IT. We have to invest on new product development and marketing. In IT alone the cash out will be in the range of &#x20AC;500 million. But clearly the effect on cost is amortizing. But just to give you the idea that if you want to move up on business we have to start also some investments.</p>
          <p>Having deducted, let's say, levies on banks and investments, cost will be substantially stable. If you want to take the worst scenario, definitely below the salary drift, that is estimated in the range of plus 1.5%, 2% maximum. So we want to stay definitely below that level. This is what I have been instructed to say by Marina. But clearly my ambition is to do better than Marina suggests. Anyway, it's a stable cost for 2011, excluding clearly what we cannot control. So maybe some banks and investments that have to be done to sustain the development of the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Really, we are creating room for additional IT investments, because we start to leverage all the synergies. In the last couple of years we created after the merger of Capitalia before as we bid IT platform that we put all together. So we are freeing up room for the new investment with a cash out of &#x20AC;500 million for next year. This is what we are forecasting in order to support our business. But on the other side we want to keep under control the amortization line, and we are also keeping under control what we call the work in progress, now what it is not yet in our balance sheet. So we see room for additional investment, thanks to the lending of the different integration that we implemented in the last three years of then and now are reality. Capitalia, HVB and One4C that as you remember was the mix of eight different legal entities to just one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. This is Giovanni Carriere from Autonomous. Thank you very much for giving us the slide with profitability by country. For me that's a key one. I could sense your excitement talking about story of restructuring of Italy. You stopped short of being more specific. You have said we'd like to return to more acceptable profitability. How do you think about that? I mean, is there any reason why Italy wouldn't have to return to the average return than the rest of the Group? I mean, personally I think, I don't see why you shouldn't make &#x20AC;1 billion to &#x20AC;2 billion pre-tax every year, without really being very, very aggressive.</p>
          <p>And number two, are you continuing to look at the synergies from One4C when you compare them to the cost base in Italy? The more I look at them the more they look like very low to me. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right. I mean, we don't see why it should not come to the level you have said. Clearly it will not come automatically, so what we really need is execution, and the things can be done, but we have to be committed on a daily basis, it's a boring exercise. And it's better to talk for us here about vision, and this is Kazakhstan, but when we talk about Italy, it's a daily boring exercise to bring back Italy to the level of profitability expected. Boring exercise on the cost side, also unexciting exercise really on the revenue side, because let's go back, for example, to the story of funding.</p>
          <p>With the level &#x2013; with the cost of funding we have and the liquidity we have and the potential liquidity we can have, we have an advantage now versus other banks in Italy. So if you combine our capability to work on the cost of risk and cost in general terms, cost is not just cost cutting.</p>
          <p>The cost cutting you can do, but we have to work out on the reorganization of the structure of the Group. It is very complex and it is very granular, so we have, I was looking a couple of days ago, we have 350 units in all with less than five people.</p>
          <p>In charge of them there is what we call a <mark type="indiscernible" />. So these are the things boring, that we have to fix. So cost of risk and cost this direction, on the business side again, we have a potential coming from some advantages, coming from the market funding, and we have to develop a more tailor-made service segment-by-segment.</p>
          <p>So is &#x2013; it can be done. I am sure it will be done &#x2013; it needs a strong daily commitment. So this is the story of Italy. Then we think to reach, say, return on equity higher than cost of capital for sure by 2014. Rate of return of equity is almost close to zero. So this is, I think, quite improvement looking forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am <mark type="indiscernible" />. Two questions. The first is on, if you think about your subsidiaries like HVB and the Italian operation in Central Eastern Europe, and the regional allocation of capital and funding, does Basel III or changes in regulation make you &#x2013; force you to change regional capital allocation and funding structures or is this something you would revisit anyway?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on the payout ratio, I mean 50% this year you said, and you use the Basel III slide consensuses expectation that's about assuming a 30% payout ratio, a third, is this something or is this how you think payout ratio will develop going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Capital maybe &#x2013; let's say we have Basel III is I would say not done on our internal policy to allocate capital based on the consumption of the business, so capital consumption coming from the business. So we are looking at the capital allocation within our Group, taking into account where the business needs more capital.</p>
          <p>So, HVB, as already pointed out by Federico before, is carrying out market business, investment banking business. They need capital and they will need more capital in the future for sure due to the fact that <mark type="indiscernible" /> and all the new regulation will call for higher level of capital. And we are already on target, so we have already allocated the total level of capital to the business based on the basis of their needs.</p>
          <p>So we are not &#x2013; the question is because with the M&amp;A sector I can understand that you might wonder, how we are going to deal with minority since Basel III is creating a negative impact not being able more to account for minorities in excess of a certain level of capital.</p>
          <p>For the time being, I'd say, it will take time, so we'll not &#x2013; Basel III we'll be keen on and there will be a phasing and then we'll delever <mark type="indiscernible" /> only in relation to a certain level of capital. So &#x2013; and we are confident that we will manage to optimize in this specific situation to make sure that we'll not be affected by the new Basel III regulation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your view is then also that the regulators will not look at an individual country level like for &#x2013; also on the funding side because HVB will not have enough deposits. And will the regulator apply Basel III regulation on the country basis, or you think it's only going to be on a consolidated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have already internal rules not only on capital but also on liquidity whereby we are not allowed in our liquidity regional center to have unbalanced situations where we are already well above the level. The structural liquidity ratio we mentioned before at the Group level applies to all our liquidity centers, and we are self-funded, being a commercial bank, we are self-funded in all the regional centers. So we are not faced challenging neither on &#x2013; either on capital or liquidity, being self-funded.</p>
          <p>And there was another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That about the payout.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's about the payout. Also we are not giving guidance about payout. So I will prevent Federico to be nasty and say, no unfortunately and I will do the bad cop. Unfortunately we are not going to give guidance about payout for sure. We have the ambition to keep capital at the high level so &#x2013; and we will use payout as a tool to make sure that capital will be met based on the regulators' requirement.</p>
          <p>So we need to switch to the people connected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13">
        <plist>
          <p>Our first question comes from the line of Matteo Ramenghi. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company's name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He is already satisfied.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> Go ahead with another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Are you thinking on maybe in an environment where we see that the CDS price also go down if the capital position is better the cost of funding also improves, so and the business bank has decreased. So I am just thinking when your profitability improves and your capital generation is better clearly, are you thinking also of may be securitizing some NPLs?</p>
          <p>We haven't seen any securitization of NPLs it needed to be for a very long time. Clearly the markets have not allowed that. So is there something you are thinking which might decrease the risk profile of the Group benefiting you on the funding as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If the market will move in the direction to which we are mentioning, yes. At this moment there is no possibility, I think. But the market open up, we can consider all sorts. But at this moment unfortunately theoretical <mark type="indiscernible" /> why to exclude this possibility a priori. So should the market come back we will have look for sure.</p>
          <p>Securitization, we are trying more in general together with a group of the major European banks. We are trying to work on the idea to start again <mark type="indiscernible" /> to launch securitization in the market.</p>
          <p>As UniCredit we are the leading of this &#x2013; we've the leading role of this working group. The problem that we are facing at this moment is unfortunately the fact that regulators want to see first the markets stats. So they are telling us, okay, you banks start to go for new securitization. So you launch the instruments, and we will maybe consider to help you in term of Basel III relief as soon as we will see that the market has been activated and is working in a way that doesn't put any threat in term of transparency, in term of customer services and this and that.</p>
          <p>So we're in a kind of standstill situation where the group of banks, I'm talking about the major European banks are ready to start. But <mark type="indiscernible" /> is not ready to start if you don't have &#x2013; since the beginning, assurance is that if the instrument is in the market. We have some Basel III positive effect. Anyway we are in discussion with the regulator, with EU commissioners, we'll see. So we're making effort in order to see if we could start again or not. It's not so easy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> possible to get the question otherwise we will move to <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Alberto Cordara [Bank of America]. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's working?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's working. Thank you. Paola Biraschi from Royal Bank of Scotland. I have questions on asset sensitivity to interest rates. You mentioned that you are positively engaged to an upward shift of the income. Can you please be more specific as to which part of the yield curve you are sensitive to, clearly it's the short end. Do we need to look at the one-month Euribor, the three months or the six months? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Usually we perform this analysis are based on the three-month Euribor, because it is the easiest way to do it. And based on, say &#x2013; and we used also to disclose this information in the past so I am giving to you the same number. Today, we are sensitive in a positive way up to &#x20AC;291 million, in the event of 100 basis points shift of the curve, which is part of the shift is theoretical one. So it's difficult to &#x2013; it's not to be taken full, because this does have a certain effect on our structural balance sheet, what I can add, which may be a relevant information for you is that our balance sheet, our equity duration is short. We have a duration in the range of 18 months. So which means that we are exposed or positively exposed more to the short-term end of the curve rather than the long term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeremy Sigee from Barclays Capital. I don't know, if you are willing to comment at this point, but could you talk about the extent to which you have work underway for your next business plan and what the main topics of study internally might be or what the main priorities you're setting your managers towards that next business plan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can simply say that our intension is to come with a medium-term business plan within this year. We are still to decide exactly when, but definitely within this year. Anticipating today, I think, it's not fair. We have also by the way, also Jean Pierre that he just joined us and he is working on CIB. The division, I have already done a lot in this respect. We're almost ready, but on the CIB side, we need to make the point. So we come, let's say during the year with full disclosure of the medium-term plan.</p>
          <p>There was one question this side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The lady there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If there is no chance to connect people from outside, I would say that, Simone you are close to that, so no chance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If no chance, we can do in a way that we can receive their question and we reply...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will be available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...individually later on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And that we conclude. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>