<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1226013" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1185</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Paul Polman, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James A. Lawrence, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James Allison, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4">Martin Deboo</participant>
      <participant id="5">James Lawrence</participant>
      <participant id="6">Paul Hoffman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Paul Polman</participant>
      <participant id="8">Julian Hardwick</participant>
      <participant id="9">Marco Gulpers</participant>
      <participant id="10">Xavier Croquez</participant>
      <participant id="11">Sara Welford</participant>
      <participant id="12">Alan Erskine</participant>
      <participant id="13">Jeffrey Stent</participant>
      <participant id="14">Harold Thompson</participant>
      <participant id="15">Celine Pannuti</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody and welcome to Unilever's first quarterly results call for 2009. I'm joined here by Jim Lawrence, our Chief Financial Officer and by James Allison our head of Investor Relations. Jim will briefly run us through the quarter one performance and after that I will give you a little bit of my own perspective on the markets, our priorities, as well as the progress we are making towards that. And then hopefully we'll have plenty of time left for questions after that.</p>
          <p>So, let me first hand over to Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Paul, and good morning everyone. Before I get started, I do draw your attention to the usual disclaimer relating to forward-looking statements and non-GAAP measures. After that let me start by summarizing the highlights for the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Organic growth of 4.8% was underpinned by continuing double-digit growth in our D&amp;E [Developing &amp; Emerging] markets and strong performance in our Americas region. In Western Europe, our market shares are still down, but we've seen some improvement since quarter four. Our savings programs are continuing to deliver strongly helping us to offset high commodity costs and adverse currency pressures.</p>
          <p>Underlying operating margin declined by 30 basis points, it would have been flat without the impact of dilution from disposals. We're benefiting from our strong balance sheet and prudent financial management. We issued two bonds in the quarter. One in the Unites States and another in the U.K. both issuances at very competitive rates, both issuances heavily oversubscribed, and both issuances performing well in the secondary market, and I should correct that it was three bonds two in the U.S. one in the U.K.</p>
          <p>And we continued to strengthen our portfolio with the announcement of the acquisition of Baltimor, the leading ketchup business in Russia, the acquisition of TIGI, the premium range of salon hair care brands, which was completed at the beginning of April. Overall, a solid performance in a tough environment, in line with our own expectations.</p>
          <p>Turnover in the first quarter was &#x20AC;9.5 billion that is 0.7% lower than last year, that includes a negative currency effect of 2% and disposals net of acquisitions further reduced turnover by 3.3%. Given the above, underlying sales growth was 4.8% in the quarter with price at 6.8% while volumes declined by 1.8% similar to the volume decline in quarter four of 2008.</p>
          <p>Turning to the regions, our strong organic growth continued in Asia, Africa, CEE with underlying sales up by 9.5% in the quarter. The price component remained high at 10.5% plus and volumes declined by a little under 1%. There was some further trade de-stocking in a number of the markets in this region. Growth continues to be broad based with particularly strong performances in Indonesia, South Africa, Australia, Russia, and Vietnam.</p>
          <p>A number of counties in Central Europe by contrast saw double-digit declines in volume as the markets softened considerably. That said, our own share performance in these markets continues to hold up well. Underlying operating margins improved in the quarter by 170 basis points, reflecting good recovery of cost increases, lower media rates and the phasing of our innovation program.</p>
          <p>The Americas grew by 7.2% in the quarter with pricing up by 8.3% and volume down by 1%. This represents an encouraging step-up versus the previous quarter. In the U.S. underlying sales grew by 3.8%, and our consumer business returned to positive volume growth. We continue our planned exit of unbranded business in the foodservice division and this suppressed the overall growth levels in the U.S. There has been some down trading in our categories with private label gaining some share, but not at our expense. Indeed our own market shares are up in the United States.</p>
          <p>Latin America grew by 11% with volume improving, but still staying slightly negative. In the quarter, we saw particularly encouraging progress in Brazil and Mexico. Underlying operating margin improved by 60 basis points in the quarter and that is despite a negative 80 basis point impact from the disposal dilution.</p>
          <p>Western Europe, underlying sales declined in Western Europe by 2.8%, volumes declined by 3.7%, and underlying price growth was plus 1%. Markets slowed significantly in the first quarter and our shares are still down compared with a year ago. That said our share performance improved on the levels of the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Sales performance in the U.K. was strong and it was volume driven, and sales in France improved to close to last year's level. Sales in Spain were down significantly reflecting the very challenging market conditions, but also the tough comparator of Q1 2008 in which volumes were boosted ahead of a system implementation at the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Germany remains difficult with lower market volumes, a tough retail environment and comparatively low promotional volumes. Customer service levels in the region improved throughout the quarter. The transparency and the visibility provided by our regional IT system is starting to improve the ways of working between our European supply chain company and our multi-country organizations in the region. Concerted actions to address weakness in volume will we believe progressively come through as the year unfolds.</p>
          <p>Operating margin in the quarter was down by 310 basis points reflecting the combined impact of continuing high commodity costs as we work through our forward covers, the adverse impact of exchange rates especially on our important U.K. business and the impact of lower volume on fixed cost recovers.</p>
          <p>Now, let's spend a few minutes on some of the innovations, which have driven growth in the first quarter, and we'll go category by category beginning with Savoury, Dressings and Spreads which grew by close to 3%. In Savoury, Rag&#xFA; pasta sauces have performed strongly in the U.S. by appealing to consumers who are eating at home with our Feed Your Kids Well campaign.</p>
          <p>In Savoury also, we continued to roll out Knorr Stock Pots</p>
          <p>across Europe. Hellmann's continues to perform very well, based on simple ingredients and healthy oils; Hellmann's Light with our citrus fibre technology continues to be rolled out globally.</p>
          <p>The Goodness of Margarine campaign is helping to reframe the health benefits of our margarine brands versus butter, this is working well. We've implemented the campaign in 16 markets, and we plan to roll it out to nine more over the course of the next 12 months.</p>
          <p>Ice-cream and Beverages grew by over 4%, ice-cream innovations in quarter include the launch of Popsicle Slow Melt water ices, this is with ISP [ice-structuring protein] technology and it lasts for over 30 minutes without dripping. We also introduced a new Fruit Magnum Temptation variant and a Klondike ice-cream with more chocolate.</p>
          <p>Lipton, our &#x20AC;3 billion plus beverage brand continues to perform well. Our Pyramid Teas are delivering exceptional growth in Russia and in Poland, and our premium range of Lipton Fruit Teas and Infusions has been rolled out across Europe.</p>
          <p>Home Care grew by 10.7%, Surf, our value brand, is performing strongly across all regions. In Asia we've launched Dirt is Good with Oxymax which provides tough stain removal in a single wash thus helping the consumer to save precious water. In household cleaning we launched Domestos 24 Hour in over ten European markets and our best ever Cif cream in a more contemporary and ergonomic pack.</p>
          <p>Our Personal Care categories grew by 4%. Dove Go Fresh and Axe Dark Temptation deodorant are continuing to perform well. More recently we've rolled out the successful Clear mix in Argentina, and we launched Axe hair in the United States. Our range of clinical protection deodorants in the United States is growing share and has helped to extend our leadership of the category. We have now launched Sure Maximum Protection in the U.K. to all of our benefit.</p>
          <p>Let's now look at the development of operating profit. Here is the waterfall chart which shows the moving parts of operating profit versus the same period last year. Lower volumes and lost profit contribution from disposed businesses reduced operating profit by around &#x20AC;150 million. Price increases boosted operating profit by over &#x20AC;600 million, but costs were higher and they were higher by around &#x20AC;900 million.</p>
          <p>Within the cost component commodities were 600 million higher year-on-year and that includes negative currency impact. We expect commodity costs to be up again in quarter two of this year versus last year. But then we expect them to be down in the second half and consequently broadly flat for the year as a whole, again including a negative impact from currencies as they now trade today.</p>
          <p>Savings in the quarter were close to &#x20AC;300 million. Advertising and promotions [A&amp;P] were down by around &#x20AC;80 million, which reflects lower media rates, the phasing of innovation and our ongoing efficiency programs. I should also note that media rate negotiations in one of our larger Asian markets led to a temporary suspension of media buying for a portion of the quarter and consequently a reduction in spending.</p>
          <p>Phasing plans call for higher levels of A&amp;P in the coming quarters, as we increase spending in support of innovation and brand building activities.</p>
          <p>So, with all this, it left operating profit before RDIs [Restructuring, disposals and one-off items] down by about &#x20AC;30 million at constant exchange rate. Absent the effect of the lost contribution from disposals, operating profit would actually be up 3% versus the first quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>There was an underlying decrease in operating margin of some 30 basis points in the quarter. Substantial commodity cost increases were only partly offset by a lower overheads ratio, and lower A&amp;P spending. We expect gross margin to continue to be down quarter two versus last year, but then to improve thereafter as commodity costs ease. A step-up in A&amp;P spending, together with a still subdued gross margin will mean that underlying operating margin in our second quarter will be lower than prior year before recovering in the second half.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share declined by 44% in the quarter, largely as a result of prior year disposals profits mainly related to Boursin sale. Before the combined impact of restructuring, disposals and impairments, earnings per share reduced by 12.5%, and this was largely driven by the negative impact of pensions on the interest line in 2009 and by the low prior year tax rate which in 2008 benefited from favorable settlement of previous tax audits.</p>
          <p>Net debt increased by &#x20AC;1.1 billion in the quarter to slightly over nine billion at quarter's end. The majority of this increase was due to the negative impact of exchange rates, particularly the strengthening of the U.S. dollar. Cash flow from operating activities was just over &#x20AC;100 million, largely reflecting a 1.1 billion seasonal outflow of working capital and cash pension contributions, which approached &#x20AC;300 million.</p>
          <p>Working capital is progressing in line with our plan with an improvement in cash conversion days in every quarter since the high of quarter two in 2008. We expect this progress to continue into the next quarter and we expect to see a sizable year-on-year working capital improvement at the end of June.</p>
          <p>Liquidity remains strong as evidenced by our ability to issue bonds at very competitive rates. In February we issued US$1.5 billion in two tranches and we followed that in March with a 350 million sterling bond. Both of these issuances were well received by the market and they were priced very competitively, an indication of the financial strength of our company. The net pension deficit increased by &#x20AC;200 million in the quarter to 3.6 billion, which reflects a reduction in asset values, while liabilities were largely unchanged.</p>
          <p>In these uncertain times our financial strategy and strong cash generation remain a source of competitive advantage. It supports our highly attractive dividend policy while providing ready financing for attractive bolt-on acquisitions. And in the quarter we announced the acquisition of the Wonderlight laundry brand in Sri Lanka and Napoca the iconic Romanian ice-cream brand.</p>
          <p>We completed the acquisition of TIGI in early April, and just last week we announced the acquisition of Baltimor, the leading ketchup business in Russia and this an excellent addition to our Dressing category portfolio with a strong positioning in the value segment in Russia.</p>
          <p>And with that I'll now hand back to Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you Jim. Let me just say a few words about the markets in general, our own performance, some of the initiatives we've been taking to strengthen the business and then the progress we're making before I open it up for some Q&amp;As.</p>
          <p>Now this time we have benefited of having most of our competitors results actually being published before our own, which gives us an opportunity to calibrate our performance better in this volatile environment, but I'll leave it up to you to actually do that. Now let me briefly share with you some of my thinking of what we are doing now to ensure that we come out of this recession stronger and in a better position to achieve a more consistent long term performance.</p>
          <p>First we continue to operate under the assumption that markets will be soft and prudently plan our business accordingly. Both Europe and the U.S. are forecasting negative GDP growth this year and at best flat next year. In the U.S. in the last quarter of 2008 consumer spending on food actually fell by an inflation adjusted 4%, which is the steepest drop we've seen in over 60 years. And we expect global markets to stay soft with growth of around one to 2% a year in value and probably flat in volume.</p>
          <p>The effects of falling house prices, excessive credit card debt, falling equity prices and job security fears are contributing to ongoing consumer habit changes. In fact, never has consumer habit behavior changed so rapidly. We're clearly seeing a premium placed by consumers on value. For example: coupon searches on the web are at record highs in the U.S.; substantial hits on our websites for value recipes; consumers more frequently shopping with smaller basket sizes; switches towards perceived value channels; consumers sticking closely to a shopping list with less impulse buying becoming more common, even in men; and value in many categories is becoming even more of a discriminator of choice.</p>
          <p>So, consumer behavior is changing and we do need to understand and adapt to take advantages of the opportunities that this brings. Yes, there are some categories where private label has benefited from the economic slowdown and probably more in food than in HPC [Home and Personal Care], but not everywhere and certainly not a consistent picture.</p>
          <p>For companies that are close to the consumer and shopper, it is not all bad news. I continue to believe that strong, well supported brands committed to innovation can win in this environment and we are seeing evidence of that in many places, even in North America and Europe. For example brands like Hellman's, Bertolli and Rag&#xFA; in the U.S. are clearly benefiting from increased sandwich and pasta consumption at home, as well as a good innovation pipeline. The same is true in Europe where our Home Care and Tea businesses are both performing well behind a steady stream of innovation.</p>
          <p>Let's briefly look at the regions. In the developing and emerging markets we are pleased with our progress, even though there was still some de-stocking and currency weakness in many countries which led to increased prices and slower market growth. Our businesses in countries like India, Brazil, China, Vietnam, Russia and Indonesia although slowing are holding up and growing faster than the developed world. The main softening as Jim has mentioned has been in Central Europe, some African countries and Central America where our footprint is still relatively weak.</p>
          <p>Now, there is no doubt that our overall D&amp;E foot print remains a competitive advantage over the long-term with still strong growth opportunities from building share, expanding markets and a continued population growth. Russia and China, which I visited in the last few weeks, will continue to be priority investment areas.</p>
          <p>In North America consumer volume is actually picking up from last quarter, boosted by the eating at home phenomenon and good innovation. At the same time our Foodsolutions business is seeing lower volumes, but frankly that's mainly from the divestiture of non-branded business and only partly as a consequence of consumers eating less outside of the home. The main challenge in Western Europe, where GDP as a whole is expected to decline in 2009, by 4% is our overall situation. Going forward we expect these markets to continue to be soft. We have some brighter spots like the U.K. and Belgium. And there are early signs that our shares, although still down year-on-year are actually improving as we step up our innovations.</p>
          <p>Now, let me briefly mention some of the actions we are taking to strengthen the business long-term. As mentioned before we are now focused on our growth agenda, but as you can see with still strong pricing as a component. That is therefore profitable growth without comprising operating margins or cash flow, not growth at any price. The primary focus for growth is our core business, but we will augment this with selected M&amp;A. Now, we see early indications that our sharpening strategy is yielding results.</p>
          <p>First, our &#x20AC;13 billion brands to which we gave priority are in aggregate growing ahead of the company. Second, our U.S. business has returned to positive volume and share growth over the quarter. And third, our share decline in Western Europe is showing signs of stabilization although not at the levels yet I'm happy with. And finally, the volume trend is picking up through the course of the quarter after a relatively weak start.</p>
          <p>Following the portfolio and organizational transformations of the last few years, we are now driving the cultural changes needed to succeed long-term, making the organization increasingly consumer and customer focused, faster and more disciplined with an action plan we call 'Nine for 2009' which has simple focus areas for the whole organization to follow, for example, making the innovation pipeline more robust.</p>
          <p>During the first quarter we moved to the one R&amp;D structure for Unilever, focusing our R&amp;D efforts in six global centers to better leverage our scale. The organizational model now allows us to consistently roll-out innovations multi-regionally. As we move from an opt-in to a justified opt-out approach in all markets. Quarter one has seen the rollout of our Pond's Face Care range in North America and the Middle East and South Africa. Signal White Now, our toothpaste, and the Dove hair minimizing deodorant have been rolled out across Latin America. Lipton Linea has been rolled out to Russia and China and premium variants of the Lipton Pyramid bag have been rolled out across Western Europe and CEE. As a result, we expect to consistently get more incremental turnover from our innovations.</p>
          <p>Now, support was comparable, with A&amp;P at 1.1 billion for the quarter, but down by 110 basis points versus the first quarter of last year. Yes, we do see media rates coming down rapidly, yes, we are benefiting from greater efficiencies and yes our competitors are spending less, some actually a lot less. Now, rest assured that in all of this we will not compromise on maintaining a competitive share of voice and strongly supporting our innovations. However, the reality is that more of our innovations come in the second quarter and later. It simply takes a little bit of time. You will see a pickup in A&amp;P as we go forward, behind strong initiatives such as Starbucks ice-cream in the U.S., or the Dove hair minimizing deodorant and the Pond's Face Care initiatives I talked about, that we've launched in the various countries.</p>
          <p>Not only are innovations getting bigger, we're getting actually faster in addressing those areas where our brands are challenged. We call them the 30 day action plans which are now in place for all key markets representing about 70% of the business. Indeed some actions have already been taken and we're starting to see the effects in the market place, in other areas not yet. We see good progress in South Africa, for example, where our laundry market share has reason strongly after several years of decline.</p>
          <p>We have fixed supply chain issues, improved formulations and filled the gap in the product range at the entry level with a low price variant of Surf. We've seen similar improvements in other parts of the world like the Indonesian Skin Cleansing business, our Ice-Cream business in the U.K. Germany and Australia et cetera, et cetera. However, it's not all plain sailing, our global Hair Care business will take longer to fix as our equities are not yet as strong as we want to, and the same is true for things like Knorr in Germany, or Skin Cleansing in India, where actions will take longer to show results.</p>
          <p>I'm also pleased to see the progress we're making in our go to market capabilities, where we have focused as a priority on improving customer service. Although we still have some way to go, we have already seen significant improvements across all of the regions resulting in better on shelf availability and improved relationships with our retailers.</p>
          <p>Following a successful implementation in Europe we now also have decided to roll out our regional supply chain structure to Asia. On cost reductions, we are accelerating our restructuring plans and aim to complete most of the remaining projects by the end of this year. As you could expect, most of the restructuring is actually concentrated in Europe and we've pulled forward activities in France, Italy and Germany. We are also looking at other parts of the organization especially the overheads to make the organization even more consumer and customer focused. Accelerating the plans this year will allow us to fully focus on building the business in 2010 with restructuring much reduced and hopefully a part of normal ongoing business.</p>
          <p>A big opportunity continues to be simplification, and with the implementation of the regional IT systems, we're now getting the transparency we need to take faster actions here as well. An example is in formula and SKU simplification. In laundry powder alone for example we aim to reduce the number of base formulas by well over 50%, will give us lower cost, but also other benefits in operational efficiencies, reliability, lower working capital and improved cross border sourcing opportunities.</p>
          <p>On cash flow, which is the other focus area, we are on target. Our cash flow &#x2013; our cash conversion cycle is actually improving in all regions and working capital objectives, as you know, account for one third of the variable pay target for all managers.</p>
          <p>Now, finally let me say just a few words about the organization and culture. As mentioned we will evolve the culture towards a faster, more consumer centric organization with clearer responsibilities and accountability. We are driving speed and discipline with our 30-day plans and ensuring that we are aligned around the common 9 for 2009 action plans. We have set six monthly variable pay targets, and simplified the number of individual objectives, aligning them better between the various business units. We're also continuing to make good progress in putting the right people in the right jobs. Roughly one third of the people filling the top 100 leadership roles will have changed or rotated by the middle of this year.</p>
          <p>In summary, we feel good about the progress we've made, but recognize that there is more to do, we will continue to pursue the priorities we set out at the beginning of the year. And they are to re-ignite volume growth whilst protecting underlying operating margin and cash flow. I do believe that volume growth can be achieved profitably and sustainably and that this is the surest route to long-term value creation. We are strengthening our brands and our innovation capabilities. We are improving our go to market execution. We are cutting costs that the consumer is not prepared to pay for. We are strengthening the organizational capabilities. And we will continue to set the bar higher in the areas that matter.</p>
          <p>With that, ladies and gentlemen we're happy to take your questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>First on the line should be Martin Deboo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Polman. [Operating Instructions] Okay, we have our first question. Our first question is from the line of Martin Deboo from Investec. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentlemen good morning, I'm interested in the margin movement in Europe, the negative 310 basis points, can you give us some more color and commentary around that? And could you particularly talk around how the weak sterling is affecting margin? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Martin, the operating margin before RDIs for Western Europe was down 310 basis points and there really are three parts to that. The first is the high commodity costs year-on-year, which is both in dollar terms they're still high year-on-year, and then with currency impacting even more. The second &#x2013; and that's true of course for all the regions.</p>
          <p>The second is that in particular the devaluation of sterling against the euro in the quarter meant that the costs in the U.K. were higher in sterling than they were a year ago putting pressure on margins. And finally, we had deleveraging of our supply chain with volume down quarter-on-quarter and that causes less fixed cost recovery. So those were the three factors behind it, Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Jim, just so I can understand it, presumably the U.K. is taking adverse currency translation on the commodities for what it's manufacturing in the U.K. But is the U.K. a net importer or exporter of goods for sale, if you follow me? Presumably there is a flow of product, complete product from Europe into the U.K., is that an issue as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We manufacture some things in the U.K. for the U.K. We manufacture some things in the U.K. for Europe. But the majority is a net import, but it's not significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thanks for that. That's very useful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Move on to our next question, the next question is from the line of Paul Hoffman from Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good morning, Paul Hoffman, Cheuvreux in Amsterdam. A question about emerging markets, you say there's still some favorable volume growth categories or trends there, but anyway it was minus a 1% volume pressure. What is exactly the impact from Central Eastern Europe [CEE]? And secondly, you also mentioned de-stocking there, what was that an impact, more or less? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you Paul. As I mentioned, I'm very pleased actually to see the progress we're making in the emerging markets. As you've noticed there is still a strong price component over 10% in the region, and only a small volume decline, which we basically attribute to the Eastern European countries. We have seen some softness in the Czech Republic or in Hungary, those parts of the world, surprisingly strong performance for us still in other parts like Russia etc. So, we read this as positive, but it's also true that we have seen trade adjustments in that part of the world, especially in the wholesale channel as some of the economic pressures are playing through there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, if you take Central Eastern Europe out is it then still positive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, if you take Central Eastern European out, we would be about flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Moving along to our next question. The next question is from the line of Julian Hardwick from RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, I just wondered if you could run us through the volume trends in each of your categories, and in particular highlight the categories where you've seen significant changes in your market shares across the quarter. And secondly, given the acceleration in the restructuring program, should we expect that you'll generate bigger cost savings in the second half of the year than the circa 300 million you achieved in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the second question first, because it's pretty straight forward. We &#x2013; at 300 million in the first quarter we're at a run rate which is faster than we had last year and we don't expect that run rate to go down. So we do expect the savings to continue through the year. The most important factor though as we go quarter-by-quarter will be commodity costs, where as I said in the second quarter they will still be up year-on-year versus Q2 last year, due to both the dollar based commodity costs and the coverage that we have as well as then the currency translation. Again assuming currencies stay where they are today.</p>
          <p>However, in the back half, we expect in Q3 and in Q4 progressively that the year-on-year difference will be positive in terms of commodity costs and as a consequence for commodity costs for the full year, assuming exchange rates stay where they are, they'll be flat. And so there'll be a net for full year of flat and we'll have the savings programs come through. And that's our expectation of margin development through the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now Julian, if I take the second part of the question on the categories and a little bit of a global picture on that very briefly. I think the first thing to note is that all of our categories actually grew in value and even on the toughest benchmarks like our Foodsolutions business were actually up in value. So, on the categories that did particularly well is Tea and Deodorants, not surprisingly with the strong initiatives that we've talked about. Those categories we grew both in value and in volume.</p>
          <p>But I'm also pleased to see that in other categories like Ice Cream, Savoury and the rest of Personal Care we actually grew in value and broadly maintained volume, little ups and downs in perhaps different countries, but we broadly maintained volume. The areas where we actually grew in value, but where volume was down were limited to Spreads, where we've seen the market behind butter prices coming down, and in our Laundry business in some of the places. But broadly a consistent and good performance across the categories with certainly a lot of upside still is there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Could I just ask on price evolution over the course of the year, how rapidly we should expect that to unwind?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the guidance which we'll give relative to rollover pricing is it's about 2 to 3% and in the first quarter obviously was substantially more. And it works its way down quarter-by-quarter as you look back to what we did last year. And in the first quarter we did not take up net prices, we simply had the rollover and in fact some places with promotional spending we took effective prices down. Although in some countries where the currencies weakened, we had to take prices up to accommodate the cost increases. But for the year as a whole expect rollover 2 to 3%, obviously working its way down quarter-by-quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on pricing it's also important to point out that our price component is not coming down as much as some of you might have expected over the first quarter. We were one of the, clearly one of the companies that has taken prices up earlier last year in our competitive set. And as we get our volume to grow again, and we're getting encouragement by that, I just want to point out that that is not price driven, we're looking for initiatives that sustainably build our categories and I hope that you can see that in the price component that we published now behind these first quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Let's move on to our next question, the next question is from the line of Marco Gulpers from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning gentlemen, two questions from me. What effect do you expect from the harmonizing trade terms and conditions for the company, but especially also in Western Europe? And the second question is on your internal 30-day 'fix-it' plan, how is this helping volume recovery that you've mentioned to expect for the second quarter? Just to give us some feeling on that, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's good Marco. Well, it's very simple, on the trade terms obviously we are already dealing for some time with first of all European retailers, retailers like Carrefour or increasingly the Tescos or the Aholds of this world. And there has been a fair amount of harmonization going on over the last few years. And so has our price and trade term harmonization with the move to the euro, which is not new. So, we are broadly in a good position across our brands in Europe, but we'll continue to monitor that. I don't think there is anything changing in today's environment at least what we see.</p>
          <p>The 30-day plan is actually more important. What we look at is &#x2013; we look at about 70% of our business at what we call the key sells, which might be Ice Cream in Germany, it might be Laundry in South Africa, it might be Hair Care in the U.S.; you understand what I'm saying? And in some of these key sells where we see our business being disadvantaged, we just want to put 30-day plans in place where the organization is aligned on the action steps. It doesn't always mean we immediately implement it, you understand. Sometimes it might require changes in our formulas or packaging and those take time, but we try to be aligned on the plans what we do, and get that in the marketplace as soon as possible.</p>
          <p>If you take the example of South African Fabric Cleaning we talked about. Our business has been under pressure there, frankly for the last two years. And we've now taken action quite rapidly by launching a value variant on Sun that is gaining share. We're improving the product quality across our portfolio. We've stepped up our customer service, and we've seen our shares respond fairly quickly as you would expect. In Indonesia, on our Skin Cleansing that I mentioned, we looked for example at stepping up our marketing support, we've done that. We've built in significantly higher loyalty schemes and we're seeing our business correct.</p>
          <p>Now in other areas, I mentioned that I wasn't happy totally was our Indian Skin business yet. There it simply takes longer to have the actions we're taking cutting through to a much more dispersed retail environment where the general trade takes longer to reflect changes than the modern trade does. So we knocked them off one-by-one and we keep looking at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But broadly we feel comfortable that with the stepped up innovations that we're doing and the faster rollout of those, as well as our 30-day plans that we're putting in place, that we are getting increasing benefits from that in our volumes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Maybe one follow-up question on &#x2013; which is more technical of nature. The D&amp;E growth in the first quarter; what was that overall for the Group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you see the reporting that we do. So, we have the total growth on &#x2013; if you take &#x2013; you can see that from the results. If you take the D&amp;E countries in total, we have about 10.4% underlying sales growth, which I read as very competitive based on the results I've seen from all the other companies published. Within that there is a small component of volume decline in line with quarter four, despite very high pricing still that is taking place.</p>
          <p>And the volume decline frankly as I mentioned before is isolated to some spots. I mentioned Central Europe and frankly Central America was the other one I should have mentioned. But the rest of the countries we're pretty happy about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Move on to our next question. The next question is from the line of Xavier Croquez from Exane. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Xavier</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions, the first one is on the billion-plus brands, the 13 you mentioned. Can you just remind me of the share of sales that they represent, and if they can provide us their organic sales growth and volume that would be great?</p>
          <p>The second point is that you mentioned at the end of your speech a couple of areas where you were expecting medium long term fixing. I noted three of them. Over the last &#x2013; so it was Hair Care, Skin Cleansing in India and Knorr in Germany. Beyond these three topics is the list much longer or after spending a little bit more than six months in the company, which are the main areas where you think it's going to take time to be where you want to be? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks Xavier. The &#x2013; first of all the 13 brands that have &#x20AC;1 billion or more in turnover, that's about 50% of our total turnover. So that's a big chunk of that. And obviously we're looking at growing increasingly our portfolios, but in order to do that we need to be sure that our leading brands are getting stronger as well, so hence that focus. And that group of brands in aggregate is growing ahead of the total company and as positive volume growth. So we are very encouraged by that.</p>
          <p>Within that we &#x2013; there's obviously different brands and different pictures, I don't want to go through that in detail because we really don't want to get to those levels, but I can share with you that brands like Surf, which have a good value proposition are growing very fast. Our Dirt is Good brand is growing, the Axe brand that Jim talked about. Our Hellman's dressing is absolutely on a roll behind very, very strong innovations, and the more eating at home trend. Our Lipton brand is doing very well. Our Lux brand is doing very well. So we're getting encouragement that that is more consistent and I'm seeing definitely accelerations there.</p>
          <p>In terms of the overall company, again if you run an average there are some things below the average and some things above the average by definition. But we would like to see better performance on our Savoury business in Germany and we're starting to see our Soup business responding positively, again behind value initiatives and new launches of soups, but we have more to do there.</p>
          <p>Our Hair Care business has been relatively soft, the market has definitely moved to the top and to the bottom, which is putting pressure on the middle. Some of our competitors are seeing that as well. The TIGI acquisition has been strategically right, and I feel very good about that, but we need to strengthen the other equities again there as well globally, and obviously actions are underway to do that. And then we've mentioned some individual pockets like Skin in India or others that we look at. But broadly I think I get encouragement to see more and more of our sells in better shape than months-by-months than when we started.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Moving on to our next question, the next question is from the line of Sara Welford from Bank of America-Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had a question on trade destocking. You've talked about trade destocking in Asia, Africa and Central Eastern Europe. Do you see this trade destocking continuing? Do you think that's broadly over? And are you able to strip out at all the impact of trade de-stocking? I know it's difficult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think you answered &#x2013; with your last sentence you answered that question. It's a little bit difficult to look at all of that. But we definitely knew that some is going on, as there is more of a pressure on credit in the system. And we've seen some of that in individual countries, but frankly not a consistent picture. And where we've seen share movements for the positive or the negative I continue to believe that it has more to do with us being close to the consumer and us having a strong or lack of, for that matter, innovation program. It's deliberately &#x2013; we want to stay away from these discussions of the destocking or not. Although, Eastern Europe has probably been the area where we have seen it and have measured some of that.</p>
          <p>I would have expected, if you want my private opinion, that the D&amp;E markets probably would have been flat were it not for the destocking, but we cannot really see it in these details. But you look at markets that some report Russia being weak, Russia is strong for us. Some say the Far East is showing signs of weakening. We actually have stronger performance than the previous quarter. America is picking up whilst others report America being weak. If I look at private label is growing in Europe, yeah that's true in some categories, but not in all of our categories. In fact some of our strongest growth comes from the U.K. as a whole, where private label is very strong.</p>
          <p>So, I haven't seen a pattern. And for that reason I didn't think it was a good idea to use too many excuses. The Easter has definitely shifted. The weather has definitely been lousy. The truckers have definitely been on strike in South Africa and in India in the last quarter. We definitely had sell in last year against strong price increases. Our IT implementation systems, the trade is definitely destocking, but at the end of the day all that stuff I don't care about. We will focus now on starting to grow our volumes again, we're getting encouraging signs that we're doing that, and I think most of the destiny is in our own hands, if you want my honest opinion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And as a follow-up to that, a more qualitative question, you've said that you &#x2013; obviously you want to concentrate on volumes, and that's going to be your primary focus, but equally you've also got at the moment the commodity costs that are still up year-on-year. So, how do you think about that volume price equation? Are you basically not going to compromise on the pricing as longer as you have the commodity costs going up, is that broadly the way you're thinking about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've always been consistent and we've always said this, we want to get our volumes to grow again and that's what we're focused on, but not at any price. We have put the whole organization on very simple targets which is underlying volume growth, operating margin and working capital. And as you can see in the first quarter, we are having a good discipline about that. Our prices are not coming down as much. In fact what you see is that despite our high price component versus our competitive set, we actually showed the slowest &#x2013; the lowest change in volume, and we tried to invest in brand building activities for the long term not short term pricing activity. So, it's not just volume at every cost, it's a balanced approach towards growing long term volume.</p>
          <p>We're confident that we can achieve that because we are putting in a tremendous effort to pull forward savings. We have the ongoing restructuring program that the company had started already a few years ago where we look at pulling it forward to 2009. We have tremendous efforts in the organization itself in all cost components to cut out the non-value added costs. And obviously we're working on those to see that we can reinvest in the business where appropriate. And that's why we're moderate on the margin predictions, we're saying whilst protecting our operating margins, and we'll prioritize as we do that the volume growth that hopefully comes with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Move onto our next question, the next question is from the line of Alan Erskine from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good mornings, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Alan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Three questions, one, just if you can give a little bit more clarity around the word protect. Should we interpret protect as meaning flat margins? I noticed in the statement you said that margins would have been flat in the first quarter bar disposals, and things do look to be improving as the year goes on. So maybe just a little bit more clarity on what protect means.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you say that you're going to see a decline in commodity prices in the second half. You say that the rollover pricing is around 2% for the year. But should we assume that you won't give any of this falling commodity prices to what you've said is a much more value conscious consumer? So, are you saying &#x2013; is 2% guidance or are you simply saying 2% is the rollover effect, which may or may not be what you actually report?</p>
          <p>And then my third question is on the emerging markets. Volumes stayed flattish. How much of that do you think is still the elasticity effect of the pricing? In other words as the pricing starts to fall away quite quickly, are you assuming that some volume will come back simply as a consequence of that, or do you think most of this slowed volume is around the market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Alan, very quickly, because on the margins itself when we say protect margins we mean that we don't plan margins to go down at least. But we're sitting here in the first quarter, we cannot predict for the year plus or minus ten basis points. So I'm not going into that direction, but nor do we look it at by quarter, we talk to total year. Next quarter we have a lot of investments, we will &#x2013; innovations, we will spend A&amp;P behind that. Costs will not have come down yet, so there might be a different margin movement. We manage this on the total year and we think broadly on the total year we can protect our margins. And I think in the English dictionary the word protect is pretty well described, what that means.</p>
          <p>In terms of the value conscious consumer it is true that we will always ensure that our brands will stay competitive, that I can tell you. But what the market needs to understand and what we're trying to communicate is it doesn't mean just price, value is too quickly translated into price.</p>
          <p>I just came back from a long-term trip to the &#x2013; from a two week trip to the Far East to see most of our countries, and for example, if you look at some initiatives, on Deodorants we're putting in mini roll-ons in Vietnam that are VND500 because that's just a unit price. It's a smaller package but people can afford it. Instead of buying the sprays we are now putting in roll-ons or sticks which are cheaper.</p>
          <p>In Knorr, instead of having the real meat, people cannot afford the meat anymore, so they buy our cubes that are pork flavored and we're launching some of those things. So, in Rama we've introduced a new butter &#x2013; margarine variant just made for cooking and spreads for everyday usage at a lower price point.</p>
          <p>So we are doing a lot of things to provide the consumer better value without really lowering the price. In fact those are growth initiatives and that's how I like to look at it. Jim talked about the Dirt is Good, our mainly Laundry brand where we have launched an initiative called Oxymax. Well that's just stain remover with a simple single wash, that's a better value proposition. So again, I want to reiterate once more that it's not just all mark &#x2013; not all pricing, the opposite.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I could just jump in, specifically Alan on the 2 to 3% which I quoted. That is a simple mathematical rollover effect from last year to this year. We'll see, in fact, what happens to the actual pricing, but that is the rollover effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then D&amp;E, we have to look at the currencies. Unfortunately these people are hit many times with different things in that part of the world and our focus goes to continuing to work on improving their lives. But the reality is that most of these currencies have shown swings of 20 to 30% and you've seen that as well. And that gets translated again into pricing. I'm actually surprised how well these markets are holding up. We continue to see growth in most of these markets albeit at slightly lower levels. These markets are growing, and we continue to see our significant presence in D&amp;E, which is now already over 50% of the total company, as a key competitive advantage. I do agree with you that if these prices ease in the future that we should see that translated into even more positive volume trends. I don't disagree with you there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Move onto our next question, the next question is from the line of Jeff Stent from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I think Mr. Polman's quoted in the press this morning as saying he thinks Unilever should be able to expand sales at a rate of one to two percentage points ahead of its market. I stand to be corrected; under the old guidance 3 to 5, I think the view on the momentum growth rate was about 4% or so. And I think you subsequently said that had been enriched by about 100 basis points through the disposal impacts you've been making. So my question is once we're through the cycle, what is your view of the momentum growth rate of Unilever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Jeff, as usual they are selective quoting in some of these articles and leaving words out. What I am very clear about, and I've never been different, is that long-term companies like this should grow one to 2% above the market. And that is very clear to me. We are investing over four billion in A&amp;P and we will continue to do that. We're investing over one billion in R&amp;D. We're investing in our people and the quality of our people and so if we cannot translate all that investment by growing ahead of the market that's a pretty rotten deal for our shareholders. So, I think that that is a fairly reasonable objective to get to.</p>
          <p>The challenge is to do that consistently and whilst doing that grow both top and bottom line. And that's what we're trying to do as a model. And that would move this company from what is a very good company to a great company. I think we can get there, but there's no sense speculating nor is there any sense chasing our own tails by putting out quarterly estimates and then revising them all the time as some of our competitive set are doing.</p>
          <p>So that's why we've set no guidance, we stick with that, we don't need that. We will look at delivering these numbers, we're focused on achieving that and long-term we will get to there. I have no doubt about that. Our brands are strong, our innovations are getting stronger, our organization is strong, we have all the elements to succeed and we will continue to focus on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I deduce from that then that you're not willing to give me an estimate of what you're momentum growth rate is once we're through the cycle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's no need for that right now. There's absolutely no need for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, move onto the next question. The next question is from the line of Harold Thompson from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning gentlemen. I've just got the two questions, please. The first one is on North America, where you've shown positive volume growth on your core consumer business. Is that region benefiting from maybe earlier price changes or marketing or product innovations? So is that what's to come elsewhere around the world? And you've also mentioned the U.K. there.</p>
          <p>The second question is on &#x2013; again on emerging market volumes, recently you showed a chart of positive volume growth in emerging markets for over 20 years. Do you believe volume growth in emerging markets this year will be positive overall? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in &#x2013; very briefly in the U.S. indeed we've taken some actions. The U.S. has more modern trade so you can get quicker actions in place in the market. So there's no doubt about that, and the U.S. has done that whilst improving operating margins at the same time. If you look at our U.S. retail business, the growth is actually positive. We've talked about the eating at home habits that have benefited our portfolio from the Rag&#xFA; brands to the Hellmann's brands, to the peanut butters. So, we see that benefit, but at the same time I have to complement the U.S.</p>
          <p>Our Skin Cleansing business is benefiting from our strong portfolio and initiatives in bars. We have launched the Vaseline For Men, which is doing extremely well. And we continue to have further gains in Deodorants, where we have quickly reacted to competitive launches in that area. So that organization is very focused, is very fast, and you can see when you do that in fast moving consumer goods that you get the benefits.</p>
          <p>For the D&amp;E markets, if you want my honest opinion, I do think that the heavy pricing that had to be done there is behind us. That's important to keep the profitability right. That market again has shown growth in overall value whilst improving operating margins. I think over the balance of the year, we should start seeing positive volumes coming through there as well. So, your assumptions there I would certainly support. We have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Shall we move onto our next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there's one more. We have time for one more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question is from the line of Celine Pannuti from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. My first question is on the value &#x2013; your views on value and how consumers have adapted. Could you give us a feel of the level of promotions and whether these could hinder your plans to improve volume through higher promotion because of higher promotion or negative mix? So, that's my first question.</p>
          <p>And my second, sorry I'm coming back on emerging market, but one of your competitors mentioned that they had increased prices a lot and they have got volume drop as &#x2013; and they have lost volume share as a consequence. One, did you benefit from that? And two, I find it hard to reconcile how well your margin has done in emerging market given the input cost and FX transaction cost there, so if you could just give light &#x2013; shed some light on this that could be helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well volume promotion mix in some parts of the world, not in all parts of the world, but in some parts of the world &#x2013; and we all live in Europe &#x2013; that promotional intensity in some markets has increased. We've seen that as well and you would expect that, but the main drivers of growth once more, in terms of value is providing consumers better propositions. Domestos 24 Hour protection is a better proposition than other products on the market, so it's growing very fast and it's not just driven by price, it's driven by value and by the way on the market in more than 10 markets in Europe.</p>
          <p>The Knorr Stock Pot, the new jelly bouillon that we've launched is actually a more expensive product, but preferred by the consumer because it simply is a better product, so it's better value. The Dove Hair Minimizing deodorant that we're rolling out across Europe is a tremendous consumer benefit for women that we're starting to see a take-up on, but that's not done at a lower price. So we continue to look at propositions where we strengthen the value, but not just the price.</p>
          <p>But I've talked about other things where we look at unit price or where we introduce a smaller or cheaper variant of a new product. Those are incremental initiatives for us, those are not price adjustments. But there are certain markets where we will stay competitive. If we see promotional intensity going up, like we saw in Southern Europe markets like Italy or Spain, we'll have to react to stay competitive with our brands.</p>
          <p>The interesting thing is here, as you say, is that if you look at some of our competitors they are having to work more the pricing component to get less of a volume pick up than we do. If that is the case, that gives me confidence that we're on the right track by strengthening the underlying fundamentals of this company. I'll have Jim answer the margins for a second.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the D&amp;E margins, if we take Asia, which is largely D&amp;E not entirely, it does include Korea, Japan and Australia, New Zealand. The margin in 2008 before RDIs was 12.1%, which is low compared to either &#x2013; sorry that was for the full year it was 11.9 &#x2013; 11.7, which is low compared to the Americas, which is 15.4 and Western Europe at 16.8. You should bear in mind though, that includes Russia and China, which we are investing in for growth and basically running more or less at a breakeven level as we take our good gross margins and put them into brand building and development of our capabilities in those markets. So it's not surprising that it's down.</p>
          <p>As we go from quarter four to quarter one, Asia margins have improved sequentially, and year-on-year Asia margins were up 170 basis points. And for the quarter, they're at 13.8 and that plays off Americas at 15.3 and Western Europe at 15. As I said earlier, we've had to take the cost increases from commodities, but we have successfully recovered that through substantial pricing. And we have had lower A&amp;P in the quarter, but that has largely to do with the innovation program and when we're scheduled to launch them, as well as the fact that media rates are substantially lower in the quarter. And in one of the markets we actually went off air as we were haggling with media sellers to make sure we got the right price and we were actually off air for a while. So that's how we saw the 170 basis points increase in Asia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I thank you for joining us this morning and your passion and engagement about the business. We have certainly over the next few days or weeks ample opportunity to engage more in the discussions once you have digested all the data in a little bit more detail. As we say it's only one quarter and that's we say an early bird doesn't make a summer. But we think they are solid results with encouraging early signs. I'm confident that increasingly the actions that we're taking are taking hold and we can certainly reconfirm the priority for our business, which is to re-ignite the volume growth whilst protecting the underlying operating margins and cash flow. Thank you once more and I certainly look forward to engaging with you in the near future. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>