<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1308153" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>515</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Paul Polman, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jean-Marc Hu&#xEB;t, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Celine Pannuti</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Warren Ackerman</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Sara Welford</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Martin Deboo</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jeff Stent</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jeremy Fialko</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Harold Thompson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well good morning everybody and thanks for joining us in this First Quarter Call for the Unilever Results. The &#x2013; as was mentioned before I'm actually joined by Jean-Marc Hu&#xEB;t, our new Chief Financial Officer, and James Allison our Head of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>Before I really dive into the results, let me just briefly mention that it is a pleasure to have Jean-Marc in the company. Jean-Marc has been here now about two months, but I have to say hit the ground running. He obviously comes in with tremendous track records from his experience and I am already convinced that he will also make an enormous difference to the company as we move forward on our strategy that we've all set out together.</p>
          <p>Before Jean-Marc actually takes us through the details in a minute and looks at the performance in the quarter in the different elements, let me share with you a little bit my own reflections and certainly will keep the talk small, short and allow for ample Q&amp;As at the end of it.</p>
          <p>Before we dive in, let me remind you again once more of the priorities that we have for 2010, and these are very simply to drive profitable volume growth ahead of our markets not different from what we successfully did in 2009, to increase again the underlying operating margin steadily and sustainably very important and then last but not least, again in line with what we did last year, to generate a strong cash flow and obviously to lower the average working capital that comes with that.</p>
          <p>Now the most important thing obviously is to be able to do all this whilst at the same the same time putting thing in place to ensure that long-term health of this wonderful company. Again these priorities, I think we have made solid progress and again a solid start this year as you've seen by the numbers we just published in an environment that continues to be challenging. We are certainly well on track to implement our strategy and well on track actually with the results we are getting but the environment as you read again yesterday and this morning in the papers especially here in Europe and some of the places is not that easy.</p>
          <p>So, before I give you my perspectives on the results let me just hand over to Jean-Marc for a second, who will take you through some of the details on the quarter one performance. Jean-Marc?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Paul and good morning to everybody. I am delight to be participating in this, my first results call with Unilever. I have met a number of you already and I look forward to meeting many more of you in the months to come.</p>
          <p>First let me draw your attention to the disclaimer relating to forward looking statements and non-GAAP measures. Now let me begin by looking at our sales performance. Underlying volume growth for the quarter accelerated to 7.6% with underlying price growth of minus 3.3% this resulted in underlying sales growth of 4.1%.</p>
          <p>With the euro weakening against a number of key currencies, the ForEx effect was positive at plus 2.3%, turnover at &#x20AC;10.1 billion, 6.7% up on the same quarter last year. Quarter one marks an important turning point in the evolution of our underlying sales growth, the first sequential improvement in our growth rate since Q3, 2008 when pricing peaked.</p>
          <p>Let me take a moment to look at the recent trends in pricing. I will then look at volume growth in a bit more detail and at the innovation that is underpinning our performance. In quarter price growth was flat for the Group overall. We see an improving trend in the Americas, despite high levels of price competition, specifically in Brazil.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, the overall position was stable with improvements in some markets but substantial price competition remaining in others. In Asia, Africa, CEE we've adjusted prices where necessary to respond to intense price competition in markets such as India, China, Indonesia and Turkey.</p>
          <p>In fact, in these markets, volume growth is more than compensating for the additional price investment, a testimony to the strength of our brands. Overall, we now expect underlying price growth to turn positive towards the end of 2010 rather than around the middle of the year as previously indicated.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to volume. Volume growth in quarter one was the highest we've seen in many years. Even though the prior year comparator was weak we are encouraged by the consistent upward trend in volume performance across both regions and categories.</p>
          <p>In the Americas, and Asia, Africa, CEE volume growth has been increasing since the start of 2009. In Western Europe the trend is similar but a lower level. Central to this strong growth momentum is innovation. We are bringing to market bigger and better innovations and rolling them out faster.</p>
          <p>The scale of this has struck me as I've started to visit our business. For example in Jakarta, recently I learned about the 67 new launches we will bring to the Indonesian market this year.</p>
          <p>Let me build on this theme with some more examples. In HPC we are continuing to drive powerful innovation through the Dove brand. In hair, for example, the Damage Expert range of shampoos and conditioners will build a position based on better hair therapy solutions. It is also a good example of innovative use of new packaging design techniques. We will push this range into more than 50 markets by the end of the year, much faster than we have done before</p>
          <p>We have continued to rollout Dove Men+Care throughout Western Europe and North America with encouraging early results. And in India we have re-launched our Wheel laundry brand. The improved formulation is delivering strong results despite aggressive price-based competition</p>
          <p>The chart just shows a few of our recent innovations. There are many more in Europe for example: we have launched Signal anti-age, the first tooth paste that fights the signs of aging, an important development in better oral care; Axe Twist in deo is across the world; the re-launch of Fair &amp; Lovely in India; Lux Shine in Japan and China, the list goes on.</p>
          <p>In ice cream Magnum Gold will be launched into 28 markets this year. This is a truly great tasting product. In Savoury we are supplementing our range of restaurant quality meals with the launch this month in April of the P.F. Chang range of frozen Asian dishes in the U.S. We have also introduced a two in one range of Knorr Mealmakers in several CEE markets. In dressings we are continuing to roll out Hellmann's Mayonnaise with Cage-Free Eggs throughout Europe and North America</p>
          <p>We have also launched some of our key brands into markets where they are not yet present. In the first quarter 2010, we introduced Cif, Lifebuoy and Vaseline for Men into a wide range of our developing and emerging markets and we have also been active in Western Europe. Domestos has been launched in Italy and even a brand as ubiquitous as Lipton is not yet in every market, in Q1 we launched in Spain and early signs are positive</p>
          <p>All this activity requires investment, as we step-up the pace of innovation and roll our brands to new markets, so we've responded with more and higher quality advertising. Our A&amp;P spend was up in the quarter by 220 basis points, despite lower media rates and our share of voice is up across our brand and category portfolio. We now expect full year A&amp;P to be comfortably ahead of where we were in 2009.</p>
          <p>Not only are we investing more, we are investing smarter as well. Our advertising quality continues to improve and we are actively embracing the moves into new media with our digital communication spend up 90% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>So, I have gone through our volume growth, the innovation that has underpinned it and our step-up in advertising and promotion. Now let's look at the performance across our regions in a bit more detail.</p>
          <p>Starting with Asia, Africa, CEE, in this region we recorded another strong quarter of volume growth despite intensifying competition. Volume was up by 11.7% with strong performances especially in markets such as Turkey, China and Indonesia where the competitive battles have been tough. An encouraging quarter in our CEE business saw a return to growth after a very difficult year in 2009 when markets were severely depressed.</p>
          <p>On the chart we show a couple of examples of recent innovations. In India we have launched Sehatmand variant under the Brooke Bond brand. This allows people at the bottom of the price pyramid to buy a branded tea for the first time and in homecare the Radiant laundry powder range with new optical whitening qualities has been re-launched in Thailand as well as South Africa.</p>
          <p>Gross margin was strongly ahead with benefits from savings, operational leverage, positive mix as well as lower commodity costs, this more than offsetting the price investment. Advertising and promotional spend saw another step-up, and underlying operating margin was up 30 basis points.</p>
          <p>Turning to the Americas. Volume growth reached 6.3% in the quarter. This was led by Latin America where growth was in double-digits driven by a strong performance in Brazil. North America also had a good quarter with both the U.S. and Canadian businesses growing volume ahead of their markets, this despite the continuing impact of the product recall on our Slim Fast business in December last year. This incident is now behind us and that brand is back in full distribution.</p>
          <p>Innovation activity in the Americas also included the launch of the Breyers Smooth &amp; Dreamy range in North America. The recent re-launches of the Surf and Skip in laundry are progressing well in Brazil, Argentina and other Latin American markets. Despite a substantial increase in A&amp;P, underlying operating margin was up 40 basis points in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to Western Europe. Volume growth here was at 4% in the first quarter well ahead of the market. This was led by the U.K. and Benelux but was broad-based with contributions from all major markets.</p>
          <p>Innovation also played a major role in Western Europe. In skin cleansing, we have launched the Dove Visible Care range of body wash. This makes use of patented Nutrium technology and follows a similar launch last year in North America. We also re-launched ProActiv in spreads and introduced the new TG Curlesque collection of hair products. Gross margins were higher with the benefits the European supply chain set up coming through strongly. A&amp;P spend was also higher, but with lower overheads from the One Unilever restructuring program, underlying operating margin was up by 130 basis points.</p>
          <p>Let me now move on to some key aspects of our first quarter financial performance. Gross margin was up 240 basis points and has now returned to the level prevailing prior to the commodity cost escalation in 2008. Progress was widespread across all regions and all major categories.</p>
          <p>Please note our gross margin performance stepped up during the course of last year 2009 so, as the year progresses the positive variance we have seen in gross margin performance will lessen.</p>
          <p>Turning to commodity costs, these continued to be a tailwind in the first quarter, albeit at a lower level than in Q4 last year. And again please note that with a number of key input costs starting to trend upwards we expect higher commodity cost headwinds not tailwinds in the second half than previously anticipated. However, we expect these to be offset by more favorable currency effects. So, our view of 2 to 3% inflation for the year as a whole remains unchanged.</p>
          <p>Savings delivery has continued to play an important role in driving our margin development. Savings in the quarter were &#x20AC;300 million with just over half of this coming from buying, around 30% from restructuring activity and the balance from local efficiency programs. We continue to expect savings of at least &#x20AC;1 billion in 2010.</p>
          <p>As we further sharpen our operations in response to the increasingly competitive environment we are finding new opportunities to take costs out the systems. Restructuring costs in the quarter were around 120 basis points. We now expect restructuring costs for the year as whole to be somewhat higher than the 50 to 100 basis points previously anticipated. We have guided towards the higher end of those 50 to 100 basis points. This is before any costs related to the acquisition of Sara Lee.</p>
          <p>Turning to underlying operating margin, this improved by 60 basis points. This reflects strong gross margin development as well as good progress in overheads which were lower by 40 basis points. This improvement came despite an increase of 220 basis points in advertising and promotional spend.</p>
          <p>We intend to now primarily focus on a single earnings per share measure, post-RDIs and fully diluted. Going forward we will adjust out only disposal profits and sizable one-offs. As you can see from the chart, the first quarter saw strong EPS growth albeit against a lower base from last year</p>
          <p>EPS of &#x20AC;0.34 represents an increase of 32%, with importantly 12% coming from operational performance. As we guided with Q4 results most of the non-operational factors that were a drag on earnings in 2009 have now turned positive, although pension costs and restructuring should remain positive through the year, the other elements obviously may fluctuate.</p>
          <p>Progress an improving trade working capital continues to be strong. The cash conversion cycle is now 18 days better than a year ago. In fact we had negative trade working capital across the group for the second quarter &#x2013; second straight quarter, excuse me. There has been strong progress across the business in better forecasting, improved transparency and greater rigor in tackling obsolete inventories and overdues. There is, however, still more to be done.</p>
          <p>Net cash flow from operating activities was at 0.6 billion in the quarter well ahead of last year.</p>
          <p>Net debt was &#x20AC;7.1 billion at the end of the quarter, up from &#x20AC;6.4 billion at the same period last year. This increase was mainly caused by dividend payments and the adverse impact of currency movements on our debt balance. This particularly related to the weakening of the euro against the U.S. dollar, in which much of our net debt denominated.</p>
          <p>The interest rate on net debt in the quarter was slightly up at 6.5% compared with 5.9% in the same period last year.</p>
          <p>The pension deficit, as defined under IAS 19, was broadly stable at around &#x20AC;2.7 billion. Cash expenditure on pensions in the first quarter was around &#x20AC;200 million. We still expect full year payments to be around 750 million, well below the 1.3 billion figure from 2009. The pension financing charge was close to zero, a reduction of around &#x20AC;50 million from Q1 2009.</p>
          <p>Finally, we've announced this morning that the second quarterly dividend of 2010 will be &#x20AC;0.208 to be paid in June. This is an increase of 6.7%.</p>
          <p>On that note, let me return you to Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jean-Marc and hearing Jean-Marc talk actually reminded me of there is no better way for a new CFO to get his feet on the ground and into the company by having immediately to announce the results, so Jean-Marc, congratulations.</p>
          <p>Let me just briefly comment on these results and give you my own perspective. I think that we certainly read this as the model is starting to work for us and to the credit of the people here in the company, the organization is definitely rising to the challenge. So I would call this a solid set of results that starts to hopefully show you increasingly the signs that our strategy is starting to work.</p>
          <p>Let me just give a few bullet points of perspective on these results if I may and the first one really is on the volume and innovation that Jean-Marc talked about. Volume growth of more than 7% is obviously strongly driven by the stepped-up base of innovation which probably is at the highest levels that company has seen for a long-time and that drives the performance across all of our countries or MCOs, as we call them, and most of our categories.</p>
          <p>Things like Dove for Men, the Men plus, the skin and deodorant initiatives that Jean-Marc talked about. In hair care the Sunsilk co-creations that we're launching in many places, the Dove Damage Therapy re-launch in hair, the Knorr Stockpot this is continuing to be expanded in other countries and fortunately strongly patent protected, and Magnum Gold on ice cream, another example of this, and the list just goes on.</p>
          <p>In fact we are in the process of upgrading over 30% of our portfolio and rolling out the mixes obviously that come with that, much faster into our core markets than ever before. At the same time we are also investing back in our products and product superiority, filling in the opportunities that we have in the price pyramids and extending some of our best known brands into new geographies like the Cif's, the Domestos, the Lifebuoy's, the Vaseline's and the Pond's.</p>
          <p>In fact, here once more we have more new brand launches than we could trace in the history of the company. Now all of this again is fueled by a step-up in the amount as well as in the quality of our advertising and yes, the rates are down but we are still up as you see in absolute to fuel this growth. And we are getting to the competitive levels that we aspire to.</p>
          <p>Now this is building our brand equities and that's obviously underlying the growth rates that you are seeing. This is how we've been able to register double-digit growth rates across Asia which by the way includes for us Japan and Australia and we have 4% volume growth in Europe which you know better than I, how difficult that is.</p>
          <p>At the same time we have the discipline to capture the benefits of volume growth in the form of fixed cost leverage and efficiencies getting much better at this. Adding to this is the contribution from our continued strong savings program and some commodity cost tailwinds and we are continuing to discover, as Jean-Marc mentioned in his restructuring comment, new opportunities to drive further savings into the company. But this adds up to substantial fuel for growth which in turn again drives our volume.</p>
          <p>All this represents what I have explained many times to you before, this virtuous circle of growth that we are trying to get to and increasingly getting closer to. The operating margin improvement in this model will primarily come from mix and margin accretive innovations.</p>
          <p>The second bullet point I quickly and briefly want to touch on is that we are actually winning where the markets are toughest. There is not a doubt that competitive intensity has increased and many of you have now commented on that but it's also clear that the some of our competitors have been referring to stepped up innovation with a very broad definition and in fact in some cases the definition undoubtedly must extend to the amount of pricing activity that we see by some selective competitors going on. But we actually welcome this increased base of competition.</p>
          <p>And we welcome it for two key reasons, let me just briefly explain. The first on is, while I have been saying before, very humbly, we as a company have made tremendous progress but we still have some more things to do. And with this increased level of competitive activity, it actually helps us to accelerate our transformation program to become a more sustainably competitive company to become faster and to become more externally focused.</p>
          <p>So we will use this as fuel for change in the same way as we have actually use the global financial and economic crisis last year as a catalyst to shift this company's performance. Also, as Jean-Marc has mentioned, where we actually have seen the most the aggressive activity, very often pricing related from one of our key competitors, the market development is actually being stimulated and as a result we have accelerated our growth. Let me just give you some examples.</p>
          <p>In China, by the way, a market that is far more developed than India, three to four times more developed in any of the categories we compete in, we actually have gain share in all categories bar one. Now we see the same picture in countries like Indonesia and Turkey.</p>
          <p>I recognize, reading the newspapers as well, that there is a disproportionate attention to India for some reason. Let me just first put some perspective around that. Unilever has a 52% stake in Hindustan Unilever, a business which accounts for about 5 to 6% of the Group turnover, important but not the only business we have.</p>
          <p>Now local low-cost competitors have actually been winning share in this market at our expense and others and recently more internationally branded players have rediscovered the opportunities for growth in India. We have had years of very, very strong growth in that organization but it is also fair to say that last year's results were disappointing to us as that growth had come to a halt.</p>
          <p>Now in India, like other places, we are 100% determined to stay competitive. I actually was there four weeks ago once more going through our plans with our whole organization. We've strengthened innovations, we've strengthened our support and obviously we've strengthened the white spaces in the pyramid that we have, as the tea example, for example, shows, and not surprisingly growth is returning.</p>
          <p>We've stabilized our volumes in laundry powders. We are investing in superior products in a number of other categories such as Vaseline for Men. We've launched Cif, Domestos and then the tea thing that I talked about. We've also re-launched our entire portfolio in skin cleansing with again brining attention back to the local jewels and we are seeing that business responding positively as well.</p>
          <p>And then finally I am pleased to say an important category is Hair and there we are growing again market share versus a international competitor. I recognize that there is much more to do in India and certainly it keeps us a little bit humble and we know that success doesn't come lightly but we are confident that we are doing the right thing there to bring this business back on track and the Indian organization should be complimented about that.</p>
          <p>In the meantime I continue to be encouraged by our performance in all of these fast growing competitive D&amp;E markets. Just to grow at these rates requires an awful lot more volume that has to be put through our system and somehow our organization is able to do that and increasingly at a faster speed.</p>
          <p>The third thing I want to briefly touch upon is related to a little bit of a longer term things that we keep working on and that's our culture and performance. It's easy to get short-term results, I believe, but what we really are after is to have a long-term steady and good performance for this company. So there are a few quarters that we're pleased about, but it really has to come down at the end to sustainable growth.</p>
          <p>We see the organization continuing to strengthen. Our strong cash conversion cycle, our tremendous discipline around our savings programs, the accelerated pace of innovation we talked about, are all examples of our organization getting faster and more agile.</p>
          <p>Jean-Marc himself is a great addition to the team and I certainly also look forward to welcoming Mike Polk as the President of the Categories who replaces Vindi. As you know, Vindi is retiring at the end of May and let me use this opportunity to say that I believe that Mike has very big shoes to fill.</p>
          <p>Vindi has obviously been instrumental in driving this acceleration that we are now talking about in stimulating this innovation program making it bigger, better and rolling it out faster across the world. He will leave a lasting legacy in this company and obviously we will benefit from that for many years to come. Fortunately will be able to keep him as a very good friend, but we'll miss him, obviously, as a colleague in the company.</p>
          <p>I also welcome to the UEX Dave Lewis and Keith Weed. Both of them are actually Unilever veterans in experience if not in age and they have each of them their own powerful track records.</p>
          <p>Now let me just give you some facts and figures about the strengthening of the organization we have done. If you just take the top 100 people, the senior people that lead this company, it is true that about 60 of them are in new positions over the last 12 to 15 months. 20 of those have been promoted from within and four outsiders have been brought in and specifically mention that to you as an indication of the outstanding bench strengths that we have in the company.</p>
          <p>And there is no doubt to me that the changes we are making will help us to continue to accelerate our journey towards implementing our strategy. At the same time we are also stepping up the training and leadership development programs. Increasingly, senior management is being benchmarked against the best-in-class and in-depth personnel development plans are being created which allow the company and the individual to succeed.</p>
          <p>We see our progress again increasingly being recognized also by the outside. In many, many places we're becoming again the employer of choice for many of the highly qualified people out there. Our new compensation system that we will be putting in front of the AGM in May is also designed to further sharpen this performance culture.</p>
          <p>There are a number of elements that will be covered there: a simpler, more stretching target aligned to the company's strategy, more differentiation in our compensation based on individual performance, more weight to the long-term performance and more skin in the game for each of us and all of us and finally, a higher potential reward for outstanding performance. I'm convinced that these changes will boost the overall performance of the company and we are starting to see that coming through</p>
          <p>Now the final point I want to end with is just a few words on the outlook. You might hear increasingly bullish noises from economic commentators about the green shoots, as they call it. In the U.K. I have deliberately used the word, "Green sprouts," from the beginning because I am personally not convinced they are shoots.</p>
          <p>We are starting, in many cases, with companies that have a tremendous low base a year ago, so easy to show some improvement and there certainly is some inventory replenishment that is starting to take place showing again a partial lift in the numbers but we continue to believe that the recovery will be long and drawn out and we plan our business accordingly. Just the recent events this week again in Europe point out the extreme volatility that we are living in and the level of ambiguity that we are dealing with</p>
          <p>We actually see the wealth increasingly diverging in two different worlds, not surprising to many of you. In the developed markets there is a tremendous amount of de-leveraging that needs to go on. The impact of the huge fiscal deficits not only here in the U.K., where we are currently, but in many other places: the effects on public spending, the increase in taxes, the continuously stubborn high and in many places increasing unemployment and low consumer confidence will have &#x2013; will have a prolonged effect on the growth or lack of growth there, I say, in the markets that we compete in.</p>
          <p>Now in D&amp;E we see a more robust growth, but it again is at a lower level than we have seen prior to 2007 with risk of overheating in some of these markets, actually, like China and India. For that reason, let me be again once more very clear and consistent. We do not &#x2013; we do not expect the environment to get better and we do expect competition to get tougher. As Jean-Marc has said, the tailwind from commodity cost will turn into a headwind and we will see an increasingly tough comparator as the year progresses.</p>
          <p>So please once more, don't run ahead of yourselves. Our guidance is clear. We will continue to focus on profitable volume growth &#x2013; profitable volume growth whilst delivering steady and sustainable year-on-year improvements in operating margin as well a strong cash flow.</p>
          <p>With that, ladies and gentlemen, we'll certainly look forward now to taking your questions. Thanks for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" /> And we have our first question, and this comes from Ms. Celine Pannuti [JPMorgan], please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have, well, two questions. The first one is on pricing. You have highlighted &#x2013; well I think the Indian issue is quite well-known but could you please give a bit of color on what's going on, you mentioned Brazil, I think you mentioned other parts of Asia and you also mentioned Western Europe, if you could give us some colors on that? My second...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can't hear anything now. We lost the connection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we apologize, we lost the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay we will take our next question from Mr...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we can do the pricing question, but we could not hear the second question if you don't mind repeating that then we can answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, state your answer, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, we have a problem here for a second.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you like to take the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to &#x2013; the first question we only got a part, and we were cut off so I would like to get the first question again, if you can get the connection, otherwise we have to move on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Our next question then comes from Mr. Warren Ackerman. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Paul, morning, Jean-Marc. It's Warren Ackerman here at Evolution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Warren, morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Three questions. First one, I just wonder whether you can drill down a bit more into Western Europe, obviously a pretty good quarter in terms of volume and margin, but what are you pleased about in Western Europe, what still needs to be done?</p>
          <p>And then the second one is really on the market share performance of the business in aggregate. I think in the Q4 stage you said that two-thirds of the business was growing market share up from one-third at the beginning of the year. I am just wondering where we are overall and whether you can maybe dig down into some of the categories where you have taken or lost market share? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Warren. The first thing is just let's start with Western Europe. I think we are overall pleased with the results. As you see here, it's quality growth, and it's done at the same time as we improved the bottom-line. And I think that's important to point out as we had mentioned, obviously, before, but you are seeing increasing proof points from that.</p>
          <p>Europe, in all fairness, will continue to be a overall tough market. We are certainly growing share in Europe. This is the 7th consecutive period, actually, that we are growing overall share in this market, but the market is low in growth. We will &#x2013; we don't expect really this market to show significant growth rates above the 1%, more or less, that we are seeing right now.</p>
          <p>Not surprisingly the progress that we are seeing in Europe is really driven by the stepped-up innovations again. In fact, dare I say that our European region was probably the lowest region in innovation, and that was a self-fulfilling prophecy as we were running this region with different objectives than we do now.</p>
          <p>We have taken the attitude, as I have mentioned before, that we roll out the same innovations that we have globally also in Europe. You see the Signal anti-age, we are actually growing share in oral care. You see our ice cream with Magnum Gold, we are actually growing share in ice cream. In our deo business we have rolled out the Natural Minerals very fast across Europe. We are growing share in deos.</p>
          <p>So increasingly we see that, as I mentioned, cheek in tongue (sic) [tongue in cheek] before, Europeans are human beings as well, that if we launch the right innovations across Europe we get results.</p>
          <p>We are also a little bit more daring in launching new products in markets which we haven't done for a long time. In fact we had more of a strategy of retracting than launching, and we have again launched household cleaner products in Italy. We've actually launched Lipton Tea in the UK recently and now in Spain, so the list goes on. So frankly, Doug Baillie and his team are getting robust growth across categories.</p>
          <p>The category that continues to be difficult in Europe is obviously SEC, or spreads, heavily correlated with butter and the butter prices, and we are growing share in that category but I have to say the overall volumes are not moving at the speed as I would like. And then the market of Savoury, we have a very good pipeline of initiatives there again with the two in one product, which is doing extremely well with our proprietary Knorr Stockpot product which is doing extremely well but those are markets that are very, very competitive.</p>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; so I think I have included the market share in that comment as well. If you look on the global market share level, Warren, we have about that same ratio of two-thirds building share versus what I mentioned before, one-third at the beginning of the year. There are some sales, as we call them, that are obviously stubborn, that take a little bit more time, but I think that that consistency is coming through now across most categories. There are one or two categories I don't really want to go into.</p>
          <p>Right now where I'd like to do better, as I said, Savoury and SEC. They are actually growing share but we'd like to grow a little bit faster there as well, that would be helpful. But I broadly I see the improvements across all categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just one for Jean-Marc. Jean-Marc, why is the restructuring spend going to be higher than the 50 to 100 bps, or beyond the top end of that range? Is there any specific projects that we should know about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let met just take a step back. If you look in 2009, we brought forward restructuring. It was the right thing to do and we are very much going to be doing that this year as well. And so again, our restructuring was 120 basis points in the first quarter, markedly down from where we were last year and we had given guidance of 50 to 100 and quite frankly towards the higher end of that range towards 100 basis points and so we'll be in a level similar to Q1 and where we see opportunities we will advance the restructuring to make sure that we can now reinvest in the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what do you think the Sara Lee deal will be on top of that? Is that another top 10, 20 bps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, they are accessing that. That might be the range but we have to wait first till we get approval in the third quarter before we can do that, Warren, but let me &#x2013; obviously we cannot talk all the restructuring programs before we announce them and deal with them, you understand the sensitivity of that. But we increasingly see the benefits of the discipline that we are driving into the system. And as we do that we also discover other opportunities and that's obviously where we go after.</p>
          <p>One of the projects that I can mention is we are just rolling out the Unilever Enterprise Services in a bigger scale under the leadership of Pascal Vis&#xE9;e, which really groups all of our bundles of services and moves that forward across the organization.</p>
          <p>We also have announced the regional supply chain company, Cordillera, for Latin America which basically then structures the company into three regional supply structures. So those are major projects to make the company more efficient and we are actually expecting more efficiencies out of that but it also is a slight acceleration in savings.</p>
          <p>Just to put it in perspective, by the way, if you have 10 basis points more on the restructuring it's 40 million on a company of 40 billion. So I don't think we should spend too much more time on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Warren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Sara Welford with Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have two questions. First of all in terms of pricing you've talked about how you think that it's going to be toward the end of the year when you'll see pricing turn more positive. Can you just talk a little bit more about how you see that change coming about and what has changed your mind?</p>
          <p>And secondly in terms of rolling out brands to new markets, how long do you think &#x2013; how much longer do you think you have of this? Is this something that is going to last through to the end of the year and perhaps into next year as well? How much scope do you see there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me just briefly address those. On the pricing, let me be clear again the good news is that pricing in the quarter is flat. We have not seen any price movement downwards or upwards. I would have liked to see a little bit more upwards, if I have to be honest, but we have not see any movement. In fact, in some categories we are moving up and some categories we are slightly down.</p>
          <p>The main driver for why we don't have any price movement in the category is really the increased competitive activity which is at extremely high levels and as I mentioned before some people have a loose translation of innovation and we have to be very clear that we keep our brands competitive. Where we do that, we actually see acceleration in our growth and the numbers would support that.</p>
          <p>We do expect that as we lap the price adjustments we've made in 2009, that progressively over the next quarters we will see an improvement in the price component and we very much believe that and some of that we have actually seen coming through already in the quarter, so it's only that positiveness as we lap last year's price adjustments, will occur at the latter half of the year and that is really what we are flagging you.</p>
          <p>The question on pricing is the same thing. I think the main pricing activity we see in these newly discovered countries by some, like Indonesia, like Turkey, like China to some extent, like India and we have to keep our brand competitive and it's mainly in the laundry, household cleaning area, some of that in hair care.</p>
          <p>And I was very interested in some of our competitive comments and I think some of the others have commented as well to see the same price activities in laundry in the U.S. or Eastern Europe or in Germany, markets that we don't participate, but I think some of our other competitors have referred to significant pricing activity as well by one of the key competitors in the market. And that we need to stay competitive.</p>
          <p>I personally think that that increased promotional intensity that comes with that will be at the levels that we see now and slowly improve. It will take a little bit of time to get out of that again. And obviously we will be looking at ourselves at driving our business by the innovations that we talked about.</p>
          <p>How long can we go on with these new brand introductions and innovations? Actually, quite a long time. We are becoming better and driving our innovations across multiple markets. It's now quite normal that we talk about 30, 40, 50 markets of extending these new innovations, but we also discover the tremendous strengths of our portfolio both in the emerging markets and the developed markets and the tremendous arsenal of good brands that we have that we can launch.</p>
          <p>We don't have &#x2013; we have Lipton probably only in about half of the world. So there is a tremendous opportunity to launch a brand like Lipton. Magnum Ice Cream is not even in the U.S. yet. So there is a tremendous opportunity to expand still our portfolio in many other parts of the world, and that is true for our hair care brands. Our Pond's brand, our face brand which is doing extremely well and gaining share in places like the Middle East or China against our main competitors, we have only &#x2013; we only have that brand from, if I may make a guess, in about 35 countries of the 140 countries that we operate in. So we have a &#x2013; certainly enough juice in the system to keep extending our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Our next question comes from Celine Pannuti from JPMorgan who re-joined.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. I hope I am not going to repeat some other questions, but I'll continue on the pricing point. You mentioned in the conference call that there was activity in Asia, while we know much about the Indian issue, but you also mentioned Brazil I think and Western Europe. Could you give a bit more flesh on exactly categories or what's going on there?</p>
          <p>And my second question will be in terms of market share. I understand that you are gaining share in two-thirds of your business. Could you try to give us some indication on how your market share overall is tracking versus the market in order to understand what is the good performance versus what is the easy comp and replenishment issue that you mentioned in your comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's a very important question. If you look at the pricing activity, I think it is more intense in these emerging markets where new competitors are entering often with low-priced products that they will report as volume growth, but obviously, we have to respond to by keeping our prices competitive. So that is actually the activity going on in India or the activity that we talk about in Turkey or Indonesia. To some extent we have seen price adjustments in China and the same happens. Actually in Europe in categories like laundry and dish, we have seen the promotional and pricing intensity increase over the last six months. It's not really a three-month phenomenon; it's a last six months phenomenon.</p>
          <p>The good thing is that about &#x2013; just take Europe itself, 60% of our top 30 sales were actually gaining, volume, overall Europe second consecutive quarter of volume growth. So I think we know how to deal with that, and at the end of the day, the long-term battles, I think, will be won with discipline and execution and strength of our innovations. So we will go through this and where we have it, we actually deal with this pretty well, to be honest.</p>
          <p>If you look at the market shares, our overall market &#x2013; it's probably better to express it that way. We look at Europe at best at 1% growth, more or less. Slightly different stories between food and HPC, but it's maximum 1% growth and the same in the U.S.</p>
          <p>These are really sluggish markets, at least for the categories where we are in. And then the emerging markets or the developing markets have a growth rate around 3%. So if you average that out we see the global picture at about a 2% growth rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah that's volume growth rate, and value, actually, in some of these markets might be more or less the same to be honest. There is not much difference, plus or minus 1 percentage point. So against that, you need to calibrate our results of 4.1%, and you can do it by region. So we broadly believe &#x2013; we broadly believe that we grow share across the regions on our core categories.</p>
          <p>There are some categories we don't grow share in yet, that the shares are stable. Oral care, we grow with the category but we are not growing share. But the category is growing nicely. We are only growing in Europe. So that would be one category. Dressings will be a category that we could do better. But they increasingly become smaller categories. We are growing share in tea. We are growing share in ice cream, if you look at the food side and then if you &#x2013; Savoury, we are more or less flat, I have to say.</p>
          <p>And then in the HPC side, we are growing share in the whole skin area on a global basis. We are growing share in deo consistently. We are growing share in our household cleaners and laundry and we are more or less stable in hair coming from a decline of many years behind the strong pace of initiatives now across our total hair portfolio. So that's more or less the picture that we are dealing with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to come back with the pricing question, do you think that if input costs are rising that would somehow dissuade some of your competitors to play with pricing further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it will because we have seen some of these launches in some of these countries that have frankly limited success based on that basis alone and these things average themselves out. I have been 30 years in this industry, so at the end of the day the models that we compete with, with our competitors, are models that have to pay out for our R&amp;D and for our organizational structures and these battles over time are won by branding and innovation and so I think we will &#x2013; and we see that in some markets already, we will get to those situations again. I have no doubt about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We know how to deal with this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Martin Deboo of Investec. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. It's a question on restructuring. I am less interested in specific guidance or specific projects, but I am interested in the sort of strategic dimension of this. I would imagine from what you are saying that you are seeing increased opportunities to find either cost savings or effectiveness benefits from restructuring. I am interested in general perspective on where you are seeing that and where you think that's going. Is this mainly supply chain or is it sort of white collar overhead or where are you seeing the opportunities and what's that telling you about your ability to improve the performance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just start by taking that question. I think that, again, one of the things that impresses me with Unilever, only having been here for two to three months, is this whole theme of continuous improvement. So if you look at the type of savings that we have achieved, wherever we are, we will not stop and we will continue.</p>
          <p>So if I look at Pier Luigi's organization in supply chain, where we are reorganizing ourselves on a regional basis and really trying to drive supply chain savings, they will be at around 1 billion plus for this year and so this is something that will continue. And if you have the mindset of continuous improvement we will continue to improve year upon year.</p>
          <p>I think the same thing goes from with respect to overheads. I will just go back to the virtuous circle of growth. You see that if you get the volume growth you will get the leverage from overheads as long as we keep our overheads in line. Now you will know that we made a lot of improvement last year in terms of our overheads. As volume growth goes through, we will get leverage from overheads. It's going to be an area of continued focus. And so again if you go through all the different aspects of our P&amp;L we will continuous to &#x2013; continuously improve those line items.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A quick follow-up, Jean-Marc, and in terms of region, do you see that mainly in Europe or in other regions as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I am impressed by some of the activities that have taken place in Western Europe, and I go back just to the margin improvements that have taken place there. I think there is scope for improvements actually throughout the three regions. Obviously each and every region has a different type of P&amp;L, a different type of dynamic, but I think it's across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See, what Jean-Marc is referring to, now that we are increasingly stabilizing the One Unilever in terms of our organizational structure and which also affects the way we operate, we also see increasingly more opportunities to leverage scale around this company. Just to remind you, this last year alone in white collar we actually went down by about 1,000 people. And one of the big opportunities we continue to have is to make this company more customer and consumer centric and change that balance between the number of people that are customer/consumer faced versus support. That is a big bucket that we are looking at.</p>
          <p>The Unilever Enterprise Services which is a global project that we are rolling out is a big enabler of that. And then having Pier Luigi at the board level now is for the first time really that we have a supply chain officer at the board level, and that is unlocking more and more opportunities as we dive into that. So these will continue to be our two buckets. And then the efficiencies and disciplines of capturing our volume growth will add to that and that's the juice, really, that we will be reinvesting in the business for continuous growth that drives this virtuous circle we talk about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. So our next question comes from Jeff Stent from Exane. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just a brief question, please. Could you just talk me through Latin American detergents and what you are seeing there in terms of the competitive dynamic? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Latin America, obviously, we're very strong in the south cone: Chile, Argentina, Brazil; very strong shares. We have actually &#x2013; if you look at it on a 12-month basis, we have grown the shares, but as some of the sell side analysts point out, don't only talk 12-months. If you look at the shorter period of time, we still see over a 12-week basis our shares improved.</p>
          <p>There has been a pricing activity, unnecessary in my opinion, in Chile by one of our competitors but also there we have responded. The unfortunate earthquake there on the one hand has given some disruption in supply for all of us but also has brought back some stability in the pricing situation as that happened. But broadly in that region we are holding our share, I would say, in laundry, and those are very high levels. Our growth in that region is &#x2013; continues to be double digit on that category, by the way, which I also think, again, points out that the main opportunity that we see in future growth is market development and which is very much the case in that part of the world as well and that will continue to be our main driver of growth as we move forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And our next question comes from Jeremy Fialko with Redburn Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning; it's Jeremy Fialko at Redburn here. A couple of questions. First of all, I just wanted you to clarify whether there has been any dichotomy between your volume and your value market shares or are they both growing at a similar rate?</p>
          <p>And then secondly one area that got virtually no mention in the press release at all was Africa. Could you just briefly run through that business and how that did in the quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, the first one is our delta between our volume and value share is more or less the same. So we look at that, we don't see significant differences. Obviously, that is a mix by country and category, but broadly that is the same. We have both of those in positive territory and obviously like to keep it that way.</p>
          <p>The Africa situation is obviously a broad question because there are many parts of Africa. South Africa is an economy that's actually being hit more than other places. We have softness in the Greeces or the Spains or the Portugals or Irelands of this world in Europe. We have softness in the Japans of this world, in Russia and then the other country I would single out is South Africa. We are growing share overall, but volumes in that part of the world are soft.</p>
          <p>In Central Africa we are doing very well, we have a very aggressive program of new brand introductions and innovations without going into that in detail, but we just launched another laundry brand in Nigeria and actually rapidly gaining market share. We have stepped-up our activities in other parts of that region, which frankly, had been a forgotten region by many, and we can not have these people pay the price for that so I think we have a responsibility there. And we are able, increasingly, to fulfill that responsibility to improve their lives, whilst also building shareholder value for our company and we are focused on that.</p>
          <p>And then the North of Africa, obviously, the Maghreb region and Mashreq region, our business is in line with the total company. I am just looking at it as I talk to you. So the Moroccos, the Tunisias, the Libyas, the Egypts, etcetera. So that's basically the story of the Africa.</p>
          <p>I do believe that there is potential on the African continent that we need to continue to focus on and go after like we do in other parts of the world, in line with our strategy of growing everywhere. We are not here for specific consumers, we are here to improve the lives of all consumers and I think more than ever, it should include the people in Africa as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. We will take one more question if that is okay</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and our next question comes from Harold Thompson from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. Just two follow up questions, one on raw materials and the additional cost savings they are generating. You mentioned raw materials would clearly rise by the time we reach H2 and we're going to annualize on a higher gross margin. Should we still expect though, you to make gross margin progress through the second half as these raw materials rise?</p>
          <p>And the second one is on A&amp;P, really crucial for the long-term investment, you're up 220 basis points, how much is more into the A side rather than just in the P? Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me just take gross margins. As you will have noted in my speech, we will have more difficult comparators as we get into the second half of the year given just the uplift in gross margins in the second half of last year. Secondly you also get the rise in commodity costs in the second half. So again, if you are comparing with last year, our gross margins will be adversely impacted by those two points.</p>
          <p>I think just overall, gross margins will improve for the overall year and that's an impotent point. In addition to that, we're focused on cost savings which will also have a positive impact as we go through the year.</p>
          <p>In terms of A&amp;P, I think that if you look at our spend, the increase of 220 basis points, around 60% or so is actually through the increase of A versus P.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you all. First of all, thank you for your support and thank you for the continued interest obviously in our company and the results and for some of you, thank you for getting up very early to be part of this conference call. Your support and friendship above all is always highly appreciated.</p>
          <p>You'll have an opportunity to go into a little bit more detail with James and Jean-Marc in the upcoming road show that the two of them will actively participate in and I certainly look forward to meeting you throughout the year at other occasions.</p>
          <p>We are pleased with these results and we should be. The environment is pretty tough but at the same time I again want to once more stress that we shouldn't run ahead of ourselves as straight-line projections don't make any sense here. We are in against tougher comparators. We are in against an economy that is certainly not out of the doldrums and we are seeing a competitive situation, which frankly, I like, because it makes us better but at the end of the day it's a competitive situation that we have to deal with. If these markets don't grow, there is increased tension in the system.</p>
          <p>All of that we are able to handle very well. You see that in these results. We will continue to focus on our strategy and making that come alive but don't &#x2013; as they say in Dutch, don't smoke too much pot, stay realistic, you know? Look at these numbers and look at our guidance that we give you and we stick to that guidance and we will deliver on that guidance.</p>
          <p>Thank you for once more for your attention and I look forward to seeing you soon. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>