<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1171058" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>515</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Patrick Cescau, Group Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James A. Lawrence, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">James Allison</participant>
      <participant id="3">Patrick Cescau</participant>
      <participant id="4">Polly Barclay</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6">Warren Ackerman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Xavier Croquez</participant>
      <participant id="8">James Lawrence</participant>
      <participant id="9">Martin Deboo</participant>
      <participant id="10">Marco Gulper</participant>
      <participant id="11">John Rothenberg</participant>
      <participant id="12">Paul Hofman</participant>
      <participant id="13">Julian Hardwick</participant>
      <participant id="14">Manvinder Singh Banga</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone, and welcome to Unilever's quarter two and half-year 2008 results presentation. I am joined this morning by Jim Lawrence, our CFO, also John Rothenberg on my left, and it's a pleasure to introduce today his successor, James Allison, our new head of investor relation, who is taking over from John.</p>
          <p>In the audience, we have Vindi Banga, our President, Foods, Home and Personal Care; we have Harish Manwani, President of Asia, Africa, Middle East, Turkey, Central and Eastern Europe; and certainly last but not least, Professor Genevi&#xE8;ve Berger, our newly-appointed Chief R&amp;D Officer.</p>
          <p>As usual, I draw your attention to the disclaimer relating to forward-looking statements and non-GAAP measures. This disclaimer is included here and will be posted in the text of this presentation on the Unilever website.</p>
          <p>In a moment, Jim will take you through the details of the result for Q2 and half-year. but first let me remind you of the priorities we set out at the beginning of the year. First and foremost, to maintain our competitiveness in the market place and deliver consistent top-line growth. Second, to drive for sustainable margin improvement, keeping us on track to deliver our long-term financial goals. And third, to gain market share where the opportunities arises and when the return on investment's attractive.</p>
          <p>Measured again these priorities, the performance in the first half has been good, with organic sales growth of 7%, and aggregate growth broadly in line with our market, and an underlying operating margin improvement of 40 basis points. And we have achieved this despite operating in a more challenging environment, and we have faced two particularly strong headwinds.</p>
          <p>First, the continuing escalating in commodity cost, mainly driven by mineral and edible oil prices. This has added 560 basis points of additional cost in Q2 versus the prior year, and is somewhat more than we had expected. And then, there has been a softening in consumer volume, especially in developed markets.</p>
          <p>There are number of reasons why our business has continued to perform well in this environment. First, we have stuck to a very clear and simple strategy based around directing resources to our most attractive opportunities including D&amp;E, Personal Care, and initiative which support Unilever's this mission of adding vitality to life.</p>
          <p>So in the first half for example, we've seen growth in D&amp;E countries ahead of the market with a good mix of price and volume. Growth was broad-based with good contributions from Latin American and CE. We have almost grown ahead our market in Personal Care with more than half the incremental A&amp;P spending going behind our Personal Care brands. In total, we supported our brands with some &#x20AC;100 million additional in-market advertising spend, maintaining our share voice.</p>
          <p>And in the last six months, we've made progress in reshaping the portfolio for long-term growth, firstly, with the previously-announced disposal of Lawry's and Boursin, both at attractive prices.   And then, in the last two weeks, we have announced the disposal of Bertolli and our North American laundry business, both in line with strategy and both representing good value for our shareholders. At the same time, we have demonstrated with Inmarko in Russia that we'll add bolt-on acquisition which support our strategic priorities.</p>
          <p>The second reason why our performance has been good in the first half is that we have benefited significantly from the transformation of the business, a process you may recall that we promised to accelerate when we presented to you this time last year. Unilever today is a much more agile and responsive business than ever, an agile is &#x2013; agility that has been very valuable in responding quickly to changing economic circumstances, and we see that reflected in a number of aspects of the first-half performance, and hence we have continued to drive productivity improvements, with saving in the quarter of 250 basis points, up from 200 basis point in quarter one, and firmly on track to deliver &#x20AC;1 billion in the year. And these have help us to mitigate some of the impact of input cost inflation and to remain price competitive.</p>
          <p>We have been able to move decisively in taking pricing action to recover input cost inflation. Our brands are strong, and we are often led the way. Moreover, our price increases are sticking. And we have also seen continued benefits from our capability building program, whether in marketing, where we have won 18 Lions at the prestigious Cannes Advertising Award, four of them, gold. Or in our "Win with Customer" program, or in the greater emphasis we are giving to science and technology. This is something that has always underpinned our innovation program, but this will now be further strengthened with the appointment of Genevi&#xE8;ve Berger as Chief R&amp;D Officer.</p>
          <p>The third reason why we've been able to remain competitive is that we have adjusted our go-to-market tactics to accommodate the external environment. Examples include: moving pack size down to maintain critical price points, at the same time, offering larger economy packs with lower price per usage; price tiering, providing products across a wide range of consumer income levels, straddling the price pyramid; driving new product forms that consumers prefer, but at the same time, contain less oil or packaging material. Hellmann's Light Mayonnaise and our range of Small &amp; Mighty concentrated detergent are excellent examples. And last, tailoring our activities to capture broader channel opportunities.</p>
          <p>That said, while the performance overall has been good, there's some areas where we have not progressed as much as we wanted. In Europe, volumes were down 3.9% in the second quarter, and this is partly explained by ice cream where volumes are sharply lower despite share gains. There is no doubt that markets are softer. Price increases required to cover input cost inflation have been implemented in all categories, and the price increases have been particularly acute in spreads, and this is where the volume reduction has been highest, excluding ice cream. Our cash flow performance is behind last year, and this is working capital related. Jim will come back to this later in his presentation.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we are focused on our priorities and we continue to progress our strategy and transformation program. Our business is leaner and more agile than before, better able to respond to markets which are more difficult to predict. We had a good first half and we are on track to meet our guidance for the year.</p>
          <p>With these opening remarks, I will now hand over to Jim to take you through the details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Patrick, and good morning everyone.</p>
          <p>Let me start by reviewing top-line performance. Underlying sales growth in quarter two was 6.8%, driven by price increase of 7.4%. Our reported underlying volume growth was down 50 basis points, but was marginally positive when adjusted for sales that were pulled forward in the U.S. prior to major systems implementation in July of last year.</p>
          <p>Pricing has continued to rise steadily, as we've taken steps to recover commodity cost increases. There's been some volume impact in some markets, specifically North America and Europe.</p>
          <p>Underlying sales growth in our D&amp;E countries picked up to 15% in quarter two, with more than 4% coming from volume. Growth has been broad-based across all categories. Every category grew in excess of 5% in the first half.</p>
          <p>Turnover in Q2 was &#x20AC;10.4 million, and that is 1.4% behind last year. There was an adverse currency effect of some 7.1%, as well as 0.6% increase from acquisitions, which was more than offset by a 1.3% reduction from disposal proceeds of the earlier year.</p>
          <p>The adverse currency effect reflects the continuing strengthening of the euro, our reporting currency, against a wide range of currencies including the U.S. dollar and sterling, each down 15% year on year. This left turnover for the half year at &#x20AC;19.9 billion, or 0.5% below the same period last year.</p>
          <p>I'll now review the regions, and I will begin with Europe. Underlying sales growth was 2.3% in both the quarter and the half year, and this is slightly behind the growth of all markets, but it's a tale of two parts. Central and Eastern Europe continued to grow strongly. Half-year organic growth was 10%, equally split between volume, 5%, and price, 5%. Our priority market, Russia, continues to perform strongly, and it recorded underlying sales growth of over 17%. In Western Europe, our growth was 1.4% in the quarter and 1.3% in the first half, the volume down 3.7% in the quarter and down 2.5% for the half year.</p>
          <p>It should be noted that volumes in the second quarter were affected by the poor start of the ice cream season, as well as the 50 basis points impact of sales which were pulled forward into Q1, which we called out at last quarter's conference call. And as Patrick has already mentioned, substantial price increases and the prevailing impact on consumer incomes have also led to lower volumes.</p>
          <p>In Foods, we've seen an acceleration in market growth driven by pricing. Here we had lost some share to private label in countries such as France and Spain, but not in others, such as the United Kingdom here.</p>
          <p>In Home Care and Personal Care markets, they are down, but our share has been maintained. We  continue to take pricing action where necessary, but not to the extent that we lose competitiveness in markets and categories which are strategically important. And we are beginning to see the benefits of the transformation program coming through in margin. Underlying operating margin in Europe, before the impact of restructuring and disposals, was 130 basis points higher in Q2 and 100 basis points higher for the half year. With our change programs making good progress and with the newly-appointed president Doug Baillie taking responsibility specifically for Western Europe, we are ready to step up our efforts to drive top-line growth.</p>
          <p>Now we'll turn to the Americas. Underlying sales growth was 4.9% in the quarter and 5.7% in the half year. This is against a prior-year comparator as I mentioned which was inflated by additional sales in June 2007 ahead of a system implementation in the United States. This impacts The Americas' sales performance by around 2% in the quarter and 1% for the half year. The impact on the U.S. performance specifically was over 3% in the quarter and around 1.5% for the half year. Adjusting for this effect, which will reverse in July, organic sales growth in the U.S. would have been around 4% for Q2 and for the half year, again driven by price.</p>
          <p>Our own growth has been slightly ahead of the market. Market volumes are weak but we have not seen any significant down-trading across our categories.</p>
          <p>Sales growth in Latin America was 13% in the quarter and 11% for the half year. Good performance in all the major countries including Brazil, and particularly strong volume growth in Mexico.</p>
          <p>In terms of profitability, there was an underlying reduction in operating margin of 60 basis points for the half year. Whilst the combination of pricing and savings have covered commodity cost increases in absolute terms, this was not sufficient to maintain margins.</p>
          <p>Now we move to our Asia Africa region. And here, underlying sales growth was 15.1% in Q2 and 14.7% for the first half. Volume growth remained strong at 5.7% for the half year, and 4.1% for the quarter. And the strong performance is broad based. We see India, China, Indonesia, Turkey each posting growth of around 20% for the first half. South Africa grew 15%, all price, as volumes were held back because of supply chain constraints in that country. Performance in Japan and Australia was soft. Underlying operating margin for the first half of the year in this region is up 80 basis points, reflecting the impact of scale with pricing and savings covering cost increases.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to our categories and a review of some of our innovations that we delivered in the first half. Savoury, dressings, and spreads grew by 8.7% in the first half of 2008, and that is up from 3.8% in the first half of 2007 and reflects substantial price increases across dressings and spreads. A combination of vitality-focused product launches and global health campaigns have driven growth.</p>
          <p>Examples here include our family spreads brands such as Rama and Blue Band. They grew strongly, supported by the "Goodness of Margarine" campaign where we educate consumers on the important role of essential oils in the diet. Hellmann's Light Mayonnaise continues to perform very well, utilizing new technology which provides great taste at lower oil content. In Europe, we've launched Hellmann's Mayonnaise with free-range eggs, and this part of "It's Time for Real Food" campaign with Hellmann's brand.</p>
          <p>In the United States, the new Mediterranean flavors for Bertolli Frozen offer consumers authentic, restaurant-quality Italian meals right at home, and they're proving to be a great success. And you should note that in selling our olive oil business, we have not sold the Bertolli brand, but rather licensed it for specific use by the buyer.</p>
          <p>Ice cream and beverages grew at over 5% in the first half of 2008, in spite of the lower ice cream sales that we mentioned here in Europe. In the same period last year, our ice cream sales in Europe were up 6%, by contrast. Looking first at beverages, we've seen strong broad-based, double-digit growth of the Lipton brand. New launches include the rollout of Clear Green Teas to further markets, Lipton Premium Pyramid Bags in Central and Eastern Europe, and the Lipton range bearing the Rainforest Alliance seal is now available in over 12 countries.</p>
          <p>Ice cream. In ice cream, we continue to gain market share in Europe supported by exciting new launches including Magnum Minis and Magnum Temptations. In Asia, we've launched the new Cornetto Disc variant, and this is driving considerable growth in that region. And we're expanding the repertoire of Ben &amp; Jerry's in Europe with FroYo. This is a new frozen yogurt range and it's under the banner of "More Love Less Handle."</p>
          <p>Homecare. Homecare had a strong first half, with growth of 8%, up over 2 percentage points versus the same period last year. Small &amp; Mighty super-concentrated liquid detergents have been rolled out across Europe, and that is under the Dirt is Good! brand, and we have grown share. The global "Every Child Has the Right" campaign was successfully launched. It's takes up the cause of diminished childhood in the modern world, and this campaign also supports the Dirt is Good! brand.</p>
          <p>In household cleaners, we introduced new Cif with effervescent technology, and Domestos Grot Buster, which destroys grot everywhere that it lurks. Our laundry business in the D&amp;E world has grown by 15% in the first half of 2008. Here, our brands straddle the price pyramid, catering consumers at specific different income levels. For example in India, our brands are Wheel, Rin, and Surf, and they all delivered double-digit growth. In Brazil, our brands at the higher price point, OMO, and at the entry price point, Surf, have grown at double-digit rates, more than compensating for flat sales of the mid-tier, Brilhante, delivering strong overall sales growth.</p>
          <p>Now to Personal Care. In Personal Care, our underlying sales growth of 5.7% in the first half of 2008 outpaced the competition. It did not match last year's 7.9% USG because of weaker market conditions in both North America and Europe. Deodorants grew strongly through technology-driven innovation. We have upside-down Rexona and upside-down Dove deodorant roll-ons; we have new Rexona for Men deodorants, which are unbeaten in dryness; and we have the new variant Axe Chocolate, which is shaping to be the most successful variant that Axe has launched. We have just launched our number one deodorant brand, Rexona, in China. More than 85% of Chinese women are already predisposed to adopt the deo habit, and we are confident that we'll turn this market into another Unilever deo stronghold. Dove Go Fresh continues to perform well globally.</p>
          <p>We have also launched in the U.S. and in the U.K. Vaseline for Men face and body care range, specifically formulated to fortify men's skin, to keep it looking and feeling healthy. Lifebuoy grew double-digit with a range of affordable shower gels, hand wash, and bars, providing users with a gold standard in germ kill without compromising on fragrance. In Asia, the Pond's brand has been transformed around the core essence of Pond's with a leading anti-aging and skin lightening technology. Supported at the point of sale in store, we have highly trained sales personnel. And Clear continues grow strongly in the key markets where we've launched.</p>
          <p>In summary, a strong innovation program focused on our key strengths, health and wellness, superior technology, and the ability to rapidly deploy across new markets.</p>
          <p>Now that covers the drivers of top-line performance. Let me now turn to other aspects of financial performance, starting with operating margin.</p>
          <p>The second quarter operating margin, at 13.2%, was 50 basis points lower than last year. Restructuring charges were higher this year, and with no significant impact from disposal profits, there was an underlying improvement in operating margin of some 50 basis points.</p>
          <p>Advertising spend increased in the quarter by about &#x20AC;35 million at constant exchange rates. I will remind you, it was up 100 million for the half as a whole. Promotional spending is lower. This is the result of two things. First, intense promotional activity is not sensible at a time when price increases are being implemented in the market, and second, we are driving promotional effectiveness, leveraging global programs and improving the return on our investment. With the added benefit of the higher sales, advertising as a percent sales was 22 basis points lower than last year. Promotional spending was down by 50 basis points, making it 70 basis points in total. Savings programs accelerated in the second quarter and contributed 250 basis points to the operating margin. These mostly offset a shortfall between price, mix, and cost.</p>
          <p>So far, we've been reviewing the component parts of operating margin in percentage terms. Now let's take a look at what's happening in absolute terms.</p>
          <p>Here are the drivers of underlying profit change in the quarter measured in constant exchange rate. The contribution from the better mix was fully offset by the impact of lower volumes. Price increases contributed around &#x20AC;750 million. Commodity cost increased by around 600 million, and I will give you some more detail on that in just a moment. And other cost increases such as energy and factories, salary inflation and so, they added a further 250 million.</p>
          <p>So you can see, price increases recovered about 90% of the cost increases in absolute terms, which would have left a shortfall about 100 million. However, savings programs accelerated in the quarter, delivering close to 300 million to make up all of the gap and more, and the advertising increase of 35 million was partly offset by the lower promotions, and this left underlying increase in operating profit of about &#x20AC;170 million, or about 11% in the second quarter of '08 versus the second quarter of '07.</p>
          <p>So now let me take you through the half-year performance. Operating margin development for the first half-year shows a similar pattern to the second quarter. First, we look at it in percentage terms. Underlying improvement of 40 basis points, savings matching the shortfall between cost, price, and mix.</p>
          <p>And we'll take a look at the drivers in absolute terms again. Volume growth and mix, up about 100 million. Price increases contributed 1.2 billion for the half. Commodity cost increased about a billion in the half. Other cost increases, another 400. Savings programs across the half delivered nearly &#x20AC;500 million, and the advertising increase of close to 100 million was only partly offset by the reduction in promotion, a small reduction there. This leaves an underlying increase in operating profit for the half year of some 300 million, or about 10% up versus 2007.</p>
          <p>Now as I mentioned commodity cost obviously stand out, so let's take a look at what's happening there in a bit more detail. There has been a further acceleration in input cost in our categories in the quarter. Commodity increases of close to 20% resulted in an impact of about 550 basis points in the quarter, and that, in taking the first half impact to 480. There are two main drivers for this year-on-year increase: the price of mineral oil which particularly affects plastics, petrochemicals, and transport. And then secondly, edible oils as we started in the second quarter to consume materials which had been purchased on higher price-forward covers. The size of the increase in the second quarter was a bit more than we expected.</p>
          <p>So let's take a look at the mineral oils first of all. Here [slide 10: Commodity Costs &#x2013; Mineral Oils] you can see the spot price for mineral oils in the market . Mineral oil has been at or around the 130 to $140 per barrel cost for most of the second quarter. That is some 40% higher than it was only three months earlier, and it is double the level that it was for the quarter last year. A number of other mineral oil related materials saw even sharp rises. Mineral oil therefore is going to impact our cost development for some time to come, notwithstanding the recent easing.</p>
          <p>Turning to edible oils, as you can see from the chart [slide 11: Commodity Costs &#x2013; Edible Oils], the spot prices for edible oils seem to have stabilized in recent months, albeit at a high absolute level. If current trends continue, this should provide some stability to our input cost going into 2009. In the second half of 2008, consumption prices will continue to rise for us as we work through our covers  towards this buy.</p>
          <p>Turning to the overall outlook: We now expect commodity cost increases of about 600 basis points for the second half which will result in an increase of around 550 basis points for the full year. The development of mineral oil price will of course influence where we end up for the year, as well as setting the level of price increases which we need for ourselves and for the rest of the industry for that matter.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to earnings per share. Earnings per share grew by 6% to &#x20AC;0.79 in the first half. The graph here [slide 13: H1 Drivers of EPS Growth] summarizes the various key drivers, the ins and outs, for that EPS growth. First, the operational drivers: Underlying sales growth, underlying margin improvement, together they contributed 10% to our EPS growth. There was a positive 8% contribution from RDIs, and that more than offset by the 6% negative impact of currency and a similar size impact from the much lower prior-year tax comparateur.</p>
          <p>We continue to have a strong balance sheet. We were recently reaffirmed by A1 &#x2013;  by credit agency Moody's, and A+ by S&amp;P. And we continue to return cash to shareholders. Through the end of June, we've paid out &#x20AC;1.2 billion in dividends, and we have repurchased &#x20AC;1.1 billion of shares, or in total some &#x20AC;2.3 billion returned to shareholders. Our net pension liability at the end of June reduced slightly, to 1 billion. This is because of reductions in asset values being offset by the beneficial effect of higher corporate bond yields which are used to discount liabilities.</p>
          <p>Our net debt stood at 10.2 billion at the end of June. Cash flow from operating activities in the half year was 900 million, which is down 800 million from 2007 as a result of higher working capital. Patrick alluded to this earlier in his presentation. Now, while some of this can be explained by input cost inflation and higher selling prices, stock builds to support the change program, calendar effects such as the close of our fiscal quarter ahead of the calendar month-end, nonetheless, working capital levels are higher than we would have liked. We know how to fix this, and you can expect to see improvements in the second half of 2008. We have a strong track record in terms of managing and reducing our working capital. Over the last 10 years, our working capital as a percent of sales has a continuously downward trend, from about 9% of sales to close to 2%, and it's my intention to see this downward trend continue in the back half of the year.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to a review of our progress in accelerating the transformation of Unilever. This program was announced one year ago, at this mid-year conference. We said that we were setting out to accelerate change in three ways: First, to innovate more effectively, simplifying and leveraging our global scale. Second, to shape the portfolio, including disposals of businesses which constituted more than &#x20AC;2 billion of turnover. And third, to accelerate margin improvement, reducing our cost base by some &#x20AC;1.5 billion by exit 2010, and that's against a 2006 base. So let's see how we're progressing against this program.</p>
          <p>Now I have already shown some of the innovations that we brought to market recently. Patrick described what's being done to further advanced innovation capability. Those of who will be joining us at our Investor Event in November will have the opportunity to see much more then. So for today, let me cover the other two parts of the program.</p>
          <p>First, shaping the portfolio. Over 75% of the disposal program as announced has now been completed. You've obviously seen the announcements as they've come out. We have disposed of businesses with a combined turnover of &#x20AC;1.5 billion. We did that at an average sales multiple of 1.8 times sales. There is likely to be some margin dilution from these disposals in 2009 due to residual uncovered overheads, but this will be of a short-term nature. And we have acquired the Inmarko ice cream business in Russia, and we will be acquiring a West African soap business as part of our portfolio realignment in the Ivory Coast. So we're buying as well as selling.</p>
          <p>Our restructuring programs are firmly on track. We have announced or completed 23 factory closures globally, and we have announced the streamlining of 28 more factories. &#x20AC;450 million of cost savings have already been delivered. We have 1.2 billion in restructuring charges which we've taken so far in program. We have fewer interfaces and touchpoints. We now have a one category organization which serves 29 multi-country organizations. We are satisfied with the progress we have made. We are happy that we started when we did, and we are determined to deliver what we promised and more.</p>
          <p>Now, before we return to Patrick, may I say just a few words about how we intend to utilize cash from disposals. By the end of this week, we will have bought back shares to the value of &#x20AC;1.5 billion. At the same time, we reiterate our commitment to our strong single-A credit rating. Our priorities for the use of cash are: First, capital expenditures and restructuring which enable us to grow the business and/or to improve our margins. Second, any value-adding bolt-on acquisitions. And third, returning capital to shareholders in the form of dividends and share buybacks.</p>
          <p>Yesterday, regulatory approval in the United States was given for McCormick's to acquire our Lawry's business, and we plan to close this transaction later today and do it in line with our expectations. In the last two weeks, we've announced the disposal of our Bertolli Olive Oil business as I mentioned and our North American laundry business. So additional cash will be generated upon the completion of these deals. We are unlikely to see most of this until quarter four. We'll be updating you on how we intend to use the additional cash from these disposals in due course.</p>
          <p>And so with that, I'll pass you back to Patrick for his closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me summarize. Our strategy is working, and working in a tougher economic environment. Our priorities are clear. First, to maintain our competitiveness in marketplace and deliver consistent top-line growth. Second, to improve sustainably operating margin, keeping us on track to deliver our longer-term financial growth. And third, to gain market share where the opportunity arises and where the return on investment is attractive.</p>
          <p>It is likely that today's challenging environment will test us for some time, but we believe we're well placed. We have strong brands, with nearly half of our top 25 brands posting double-digit growth, with a broad geographic footprint of products which meet the everyday needs of consumer and which straddle a wide variety of price point. And we are a more nimble, more agile, more focused company which is able to respond more quickly and act more decisively than ever before.</p>
          <p>We have experience of managing big businesses through very volatile periods. Since 1990, the average annual growth of our business in D&amp;E has been around 9%, with volume growth positive in every single year. And this has been through many difficult and turbulent times in different countries: Indonesia, Russia, Mexico, Brazil, Argentina, to name just a few. We are fully aware of the challenge and will be vigilant in our response.</p>
          <p>So all in all, a good first half, clear priorities going forward, and we re-confirm previous guidance for full-year 2008: Underlying sales growth in excess of our 3 to 5% target range with an underlying improvement in operating margin.</p>
          <p>And with that, ladies and gentlemen, I will conclude my remarks and open the floor and the wires to Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if I can just make one request. If you haven't already done so, if you could switch off your mobile phones or your BlackBerrys, because that does interfere with the reception, and we'd like you to do that.</p>
          <p>First of all, it is &#x2013;  let me say how we take questions from the floor. It is a little technical. You stick up your hand, and we'll give you a microphone. Please &#x2013; please, although it sounds silly, waiting till the microphone arrives before you start speaking, because again, it makes a difference in terms of reception for other people.</p>
          <p>Could you begin by telling us your name and who you represent, and then ask your question. If you're on a teleconference call and you wish to call for a question, please press *1 on your handset. If you then decide subsequently to cancel your call, please press *2, and if you wish to speak to the operator at any time, please press *0, and if you're asking a question on the teleconference line, please use your handset.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we are taking questions online, and if we have time, then we will raise one or two of those questions in the next few minutes.</p>
          <p>So with that, Patrick, if I could pass to you to take the first question from the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. It's Polly Barclay from Cazenove.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Polly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just given what we've seen in terms of negative volume in a developed market, can you talk us through whether these prices will stick? And what you'll do with pursuing perhaps less or more aggressive pricing structure going forward, and where that will leave you versus input cost pressures?</p>
          <p>And also, could you just tell us whether we'll see now several quarters of negative volume growth with ongoing pricing? Can you just walk us through all that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, just to correct that underlying the North America, or The Americas, were and North America, were positive in volume. We have a, as we indicated in the call, three to 4% impact of the change &#x2013;  <mark type="audio gap" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> &#x2013; lower ice cream sales. With some change in again  system which was <mark type="inaudible" /> of 50 basis points, and then the biggest impacts that we see in term of volume is a number of category where we have effectively increased price substantially and led price increase, dressing and spreads, and we talked about high double-digit price increases with gross margin reduced.</p>
          <p>Developing market we continue to see good volume growth. So what's for the future? We see less pressure on Food. We see some more pricing and pressure to come on Home and Personal Care, simply because of all the <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Now without making any comment on what's going to happen in term of volume and price going forward, there will be certainly a substantial contribution from price in our supply coming, but I would like to be very clear is that our number one priority is to maintain our competitiveness. Our number two priority is about sustainable margin improvement. That's our number two priority. So I'm absolutely clear and so is my management team that we not let our competitiveness and our overall share position deteriorate.</p>
          <p>I hope that clarify the perspective that we have as regard to pricing and volume. This answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, sir. Warren Ackerman of Dresdner. Can you actually tell us what's happening to the market growth in both Europe and the developing and emerging markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Recently &#x2013; Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the first one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just secondly, on the actual share position within Europe, it seems to be more of a Foods issue than HPC. Can you actually clarify the extent of the share loss? And then just finally, I have one for Patrick, there's obviously a lot of speculation that you will retire next year. I'm sure everybody here would be interested in you clarifying your intentions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I'm not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it all right if?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the market growth. In North America, we see growth around 3%, and we're growing ahead of this market. In Europe, we see growth also around 3%. We are not growing at 3%, so we're under share pressure in specific categories, and I'll come back to that. In developing market, we growth on average &#x2013; we see growth on average in our markets of 10 to 11%, and we are growing ahead of that, so gaining share.</p>
          <p>Overall, we see in term of balance, volume and mix, we see more pricing in all of the market where we're operating, we see some very soft market. Interestingly, market where we are gaining share, laundry and deo would be an example, and ice cream.</p>
          <p>As for as the share of concern in Europe, we indeed have lost share in a couple of categories, and of course interestingly, these are categories where we've increased price substantially, spreads and dressings, this is savoury, and we have been getting in tea, we have been getting in ice cream, as I mentioned. We've maintained our share in laundry, we've maintained our share in the rest of personal care. We have lost a bit of share in hair care. Altogether in Europe, we have lost a bit of share, definitely. Yeah?</p>
          <p>And the third question &#x2013; ah, the third question. Yeah. I was not forgetting this one. Look, good companies have good processes, bad companies bad processes. So it's very appropriate, it's very normal for Unilever to start a process of succession. And as far as I am concerned, we can achieve  a lot of what I wanted to achieved, it's not unreasonable to contemplate the future. And that's all.</p>
          <p>When I've gone, and the news of my death are greatly exaggerated. I can reassure one thing, that I'm not focused on the future, I'm focused on continuing to drive this business to deliver, and that's the only thing which is in my mind. Okay? <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Xavier Croquez, Exane BNP Paribas. I'd like to put myself in the shoes of a middle-ranking manager in Western Europe, and for the last two, three years, it hasn't been easy. The game of gaining share and growing is much more fun than cutting costs and getting one new lever on my back and all that mess. When is the end of the tunnel? When do these guys have fun again, and when will the agenda be growth again? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, of course Xavier, you won't be surprised that I disagree with everything that you said. First and foremost, our agenda is a growth agenda. This growth agenda in Europe, with minus-3% three years ago, we have plus-1.3% Western Europe. I promise you, if you are a manager, middle manager in Western Europe, you feel better with 1.3 than minus-three. And you feel so much better, because at the same time that you have got to 1.3, you've been going through a very extensive transformation program, and what you understand is that this transformation program is not the strategy. It's a transformation programming in support of the strategy. It's about simplification, it's about cutting bureaucracy.</p>
          <p>We're going to cut more than 50% of the regional headquarter people obviously in the region. It's about getting wider territory, that's our multi-country organization. That's about outsourcing everything which is not core. That's also about increasing innovation, and more importantly, that's about investing in our core capabilities.</p>
          <p>So your middle manager of course will feel the pain. With 12,000 people leaving, friends, colleague, you can't be ecstatic. But you understand that the agenda is a growth agenda. You see some of the benefit, and you see the investment in capability. And you see examples. Netherlands grew 6% in the quarter. Now that's a sort of number which people will look with enthusiasm, and why is it important? Because Netherlands has been trailblazing all of the activities. They were the first to complete One Unilever, they were the first to go to the MCOs, and that's why they are going to move.</p>
          <p>So it's not a bad job to be a middle manager. It's a little bit tough, but you do see a lot of <mark type="inaudible" /> And if you are interested in a job, Xavier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's <mark type="inaudible" /> our position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, &#x2013; can I move on my &#x2013; We have been training for the last three, four years, is just what you explained. Now, the Olympic games start when? is another way of putting the same question. Because you explain all the potential and I buy your answer, but I mean, when will the cost structure be fixed again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, try this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; so that before &#x2013; And a small one is clarification. The 9% organic sales growth since 1990, how much was volume in the emerging markets? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll turn the last part over to James. We do &#x2013; I know there was volume in every one of them. I can't say what the total was across the time.</p>
          <p>We announced a program for accelerating the transformation at this meeting a year ago, prior actual to my arrival, and we targeted 2010. And I gave you an update on the factories closed. And  so we are well along the way, and I would say that 2010, there's always going to be restructuring and retuning and refining, so it's not, we come to 2010 and it ends. But we're doing a very clear goal of 2010. I think the comments I've made earlier today give a good sense of how far along we are in that program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not selling the far ends, most of what I call the heavy lifting. Because the structure, and when you look at Europe in 2004, and Europe in 2010, you had three or four companies in every country, you have large regional headquarters, you had several go-to-market, you had each country, and in some cases, each company, had its support system.</p>
          <p>2010, you'll have a reason number of multi-country organization. Most of the transactional process will have been outsourced. Our supply chain has become a regional supply chain, in other words, it has become a global, and what we're focusing out in go-to-market. There is not going to be a lot more there. We track like hawks our competitive cost versus the best-in-class, and we're getting there. And we have plans that will bring us in term of indirect and structural costs close to the best. So we continue productivity, but there's not much space for us for anything in structural in country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question in the front row, before we get that, we have the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The long-term 9% that we post for developing and emerging markets. I can't tell you precisely what the volume number is, but what I can tell you is that there hasn't been a single year when the volume has been negative in our D&amp;E markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you give a call later on, once he has the number? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Patrick and Jim. Hi. It's Martin Deboo, Investec. This question I think just comes out what you just said, Patrick, and it's really about your margin model and how it's going to revolve in relation to probably conditions which two years ago, you would probably have seen as completely unprecedented in sort of structural cost inflation and inputs.</p>
          <p>Jim, your waterfall charts just speak very eloquently to that, in my view, and it looks to me like you're recovering more than commodity cost in pricing, which in my view is a very commendable performance.</p>
          <p>But you're dissipating almost the entirety of your restructuring and procurement savings in what is called other cost inflation. Now Jim, you hint that some of that is energy, which is beyond your control, but we know there's lot of overhead in there.</p>
          <p>So I guess my question, in the context of Cadbury yesterday increasing their commitment to cost optimization in light of what's already a very aggressive margin progression model, don't you feel you can do more to control your other cost by things like outsourcing, off-shoring, et cetera? I'd just value your comments on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're not generally talk about that what we are doing. I just want to be absolutely clear, because that's important, just in case anyone would believe that it's all pass-through cost prohibitive.</p>
          <p>I have been absolutely crystal clear as to the number one priorities, which is maintain our overall competitiveness. And that's about the strength of our brands and our ability to fund investment in our brand, that's about innovation, and that's about ensuring that we build our core capability. That's our number one objective.</p>
          <p>The number two is margin, so we don't have a different ranking, and this is why I will be absolutely clear, that we not let margin numbers 2006, '07, '08, or '10 distract from this agenda.</p>
          <p>Now second question, are we doing everything we can, on cost, outsourcing, off-shoring. Jim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin, first thing I'd say is, you are absolutely right, that when the original program was put together several years ago, when the accelerated transformation program was announced one year ago, the management team did not anticipate the sort of commodity costs increase that we have seen.</p>
          <p>Second, I think it is impressive the way we have reacted to those commodity cost increases and taken pricing. We saw some of the costs come in earlier in Foods, we took the prices earlier in Foods. The oil prices, as I said, went up 40% in the sequential quarter, and we are taking those prices in Home and Personal Care, and it's great that we have such strong brands, that the prices are sticking.</p>
          <p>And we are not surprised, by the way, that when you take that kind of price, you have a temporary volume impact, and we expect to see that gone over a quarter or two. But that's sort of all in plan. That's what we expect to do.</p>
          <p>Now as to cost reduction, the fortunate thing for Unilever is, some time ago, we said we are going to work on cost, and we're going to do it in terms of supply chain, we're going to do it in terms of overhead, we're going to do it in terms of purchasing. And what I would say is that we have had as our goal for some time getting to lowest cost by category, by country, versus the best in class, and we are going to continue to do that.</p>
          <p>We have a whole indirect cost structure program which we're working on and which is showing results. And you've seen it in the quarter indirect cost. We're going to continue that and push that. It would actually be untrue to say we're going to do it harder, because we're going at this as hard as we can, we're going to continue. So I said, I' just glad we started this some time ago, because lot of these things take some time to be an effect.  It's a good thing that we started &#x2013; started some time ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we may, at this point, I think we should go to the telephones, because people have been waiting very, very patiently there.</p>
          <p>Just to let me answer the volume question that you asked a little while ago. The answer is, the long-term volume growth rate in D&amp;E is 5% of the 9%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So 5% volume, 4% price, 9% in total since 1990.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the question from the wires?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The wires.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our first question comes from the line of Marco Gulper from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning all. I've got three questions, if I may. The first question is a bit more shorter term I sense a underlying change of tone on the use of future cash in your comments focusing more on capital expenditure and bolt-on acquisitions, versus dividends and share buybacks. Is that something that I am reading through this correct, or am I mistaken here?</p>
          <p>Second point is a bit more of the longer term. Internally your guidance is for 3.5 to 5.5% sales growth. Now with the disposals more than 75% completed, adding 0.4% to your internal growth rate, which is 3.5 to 5.5, should we be adding this, let's say, from '08 onwards, in our expectations for external communications to Unilever, i.e., the four to 6% growth rate?</p>
          <p>And the final question is, could you update us on the Knorr V performance year to date? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the last one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Knorr V. How's Knorr V.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, you want me &#x2013; I'll take the first one. Marco, there is no change in what we have been doing. We are explicit that obviously the first use of cash is for necessary capital investment to provide for the innovations that come out of the categories, to provide capacity as we grow, and to lower cost. And we've announced the accelerate the transformation program and the cost that that would take, so obviously that's the first call on cash.</p>
          <p>We only do acquisitions if they're value-creating for shareholders relative to the business as it would be otherwise, only if they fit within our strategy. And then we have said that while we intend to maintain a strong-A balance sheet, what cash is left over goes back to the shareholders. And there's question of, does it go back by dividends or share repurchases, but it goes back to the shareholders. So I don't think it's a change in what we have been doing or how we've said it, if it's made more clear, but what we've said today, then that's a good thing.</p>
          <p>As to the second question, on growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we've certainly not changed our guidance. Everything you say is absolutely correct, that a lot of the disposal is growth and I'm seeing in something like 40 basis points. We have reconfirmed our guidance for 2008 which is grow in excess of our 3 to 5% range, and we have been all through the guidance for the year subsequent to 2008 when we announce our result at the end of the year, but technically you are absolutely right. This is a benefit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'll just clarify, because Marco I think said 3.5 to 5.5. Our guidance is three to five.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In excess of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's in excess of-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-it's in excess of 5, but our long term guidance is 3% to 5%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think Marco is giving us some credit for the effect of the excellent work that we did on the disposals, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know, but he's taken 3.5 and another half, but &#x2013; just so there's no misunderstandings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As to  Knorr V, Marco, it's been very valuable for countries, and the key is access to competitiveness in the Knorr chain and the fresh dairy cabinet if you want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Meaning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Meaning that we have a very good performance in places like the Netherlands, and a lousy performance in places Spain or France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And overall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Average. Bit below my expectations, to be honest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But, Marco, there are a lot of other innovations you have not asked about doing extremely well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more call coming through now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Paul Hofman from Chevrot [F. Van Lanschot Bankiers].  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Good morning. This Paul from Van Lanschot in Amsterdam. Two questions, the first one about the visibility of your input costs. Yeah, what can you say about a hedging? I mean, it's not for the last couple of quarters you increased your guidance, what's not the chance that you have to do it again, in let's say the third quarter.</p>
          <p>And the second question is on the pricing in Asia Africa, it's now exceeding 10%. Do you still see room to lift that further without hurting volume growth? I mean, Asia Africa is predominately HPC, so also primarily driven by oil prices. What room is there to go further with your pricing? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning. As to the guidance on input cost, I'm sure not going to say that we will never change our guidance. We've been through unprecedented times, and we could have more unprecedented times, so I certainly am not going to say that.</p>
          <p>What I will say is that, at the half-year mark, we got pretty good sight on what the cost will be through the balance of the year. The big variable for us is mineral oil, because we do not hedge mineral oil. We have some long-term contracts for our inputs which are affected by mineral oil, but many of those contracts have price escalators based &#x2013; and, for that matter, price decelerators &#x2013;  based on the oil price.</p>
          <p>At the moment, we've given you our best guidance for the second half, which is 600 basis points, for the year therefore, 550, and we feel that's the best guidance we can give for the remainder of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As to the pricing in D&amp;E, or Asia, Africa, and volume. First of all, what consider good volume growth in excess of 4% in a quarter, and in fact, if I would go one level below in terms of granularity, most of our key market have shown growth well in excess of that. We have one or two countries, like South Africa, which is important to us, where -- and that's one goal, the growth came mostly from pricing. But by and large, we've produced number like more than 20% in China, in volume, with good growth in Indonesia -- volume growth, good growth in Turkey -- volume growth, good growth in India -- volume growth. So by and large, we've seeing that we are able to grow both, the volume and price.</p>
          <p>And one of the reason is in fact has to do as we mentioned, and we give two example, one in Brazil and one in India, we see good growth at the top-end of the market and at the bottom end of the market, less so in the middle, as you saw in Brazil. And as we can both drive the strategy of getting the price increase, and mostly &#x2013; benefiting for the most affluent part of the population, at the same time being very competitive at the low end of the market, and be able to drive volume.</p>
          <p>So at this stage, once we recognize there will be some reduction in overall volume growth, in fact, from a very good place, and that has to do with the strength of our brand and the strength of our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is also something interesting, is that in times of a tough economic condition, consumer are less experimental, and brands very often offer them much more safety and security in their choice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. One final one-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got questions coming in online and we will answer all of them during the course of the day, but I thought maybe we could take a couple of them. This one is from Alistair Anderson of Ivy, who asks the question, "Why are you see in savings in A&amp;P when volumes are under pressure?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we have had 100 million increase in advertising. And if you look at a percentage, it's basically more or less in line with our <mark type="inaudible" /> promotion. Because when you increase your prices 15, 20%, you have to take a very, very strong position and certainly not start bidding back and bonusing back your price increases, and promotional intensity has reduced.</p>
          <p>Now there are two ways or so to appreciate what we are doing. One is to look at our overall market share situation. And as I said what it is, growing in aggregate with our market, losing market share in Western Europe, but gaining in the U.S., and gaining in developing and emerging markets by and large. And our share of voice, share of market, we see them very good.</p>
          <p>So I have no intention to say if on advertising or in promotion. For other country, I see an opportunity. And even in Europe, we have increased by five points, percentage points our investments behind advertising and promotion Personal Care. We have a very clear strategy, we <mark type="inaudible" /> show you and after 13 quarters, I hope that I have some credibility in saying that, A&amp;P is not a balancing item, and there's no boom and bust devil that is suddenly now coming up out of the box. And last but not least, my number one objective, and I have not changed, is top-line competitiveness. Not top-line competitiveness, and maintaining the margin, and gaining market share. We have a clear strategy, and a clear <mark type="inaudible" /> So no savings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will tap the answer too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, from Andrea Bergamaschi of Intermonte. And she is saying, she's talking about volumes, or he, not really not sure if it's a he or she, what has been the role of destocking after the price increases that we have been taking? And what are the actions that we will be taking in order to deal with this quarterly volume weakness?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the time being, we've not seen destocking. One of the reason is we've been extremely careful, especially in D&amp;E, to ensure that was no -- there was no stocking in advance of price increase, and we monitor the situation, especially with our distributor, mostly its under our control,  very, very carefully. We've not seen a destocking. There may be some announced in some geographies. U.S., where the grocers here are regular part of destocking but at this stage, honestly destocking has not been factor in our number.</p>
          <p>As to volume, I have been very clear that we not let our volume competitiveness be eroded by price increase, and at this stage, we certainly not there in developing and emerging market. I think we are comfortable in North America. I think we need to be reassured that some of the increases, especially in places like dressing and spreads, are not affecting our competitiveness, and this is complicated because butter prices are going down.</p>
          <p>So we have an increase in prices against, let's say, a market which is producing. This being said, as far is dressing is concerned, we see a second improvement in volume versus the first quarter. So it's something we're going to monitor very, very closely. At this stage, we started out throwing money at the consumer, certainly not in order to buy her back. We want to leverage our brand, our innovation, our capabilities, building on our market place, to come back in term of volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I might just add to that, Patrick, the level of commodity cost increases in total around the world is unprecedented, and the need to raise prices around the world at the level we have is unprecedented, and in particular categories, there is extraordinary pricing.</p>
          <p>However, we have lots and lots of experience in the D&amp;E world in particular countries, when there was substantial input inflation at the same kind of levels that we're having in terms of input cost generally around the world.</p>
          <p>And so we have lots of experience with what you do in that kind of environment in terms of raising prices in order to hold your business model together, accepting that there's going to be a bit of volume fall after you do that, consumers get used to the new prices, come back, you've held your business model, and you move on. So while it's unprecedented on the global basis that we're seeing it, is not unprecedented for us in particular countries. We've got a lot of experience, we've done it before, we've done it successfully, and we're going to do it successfully now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think we've got time for two more questions from the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Julian Hardwick of ABN Amro. I've got three quick questions, mainly for Jim. Could you tell us &#x2013; just ballpark for us what the EPS dilution next year from the disposals is likely to be? Secondly, could you give us some sort of sense in the current market environment about what you'd regard as being the appropriate range for net debt for the group looking ahead? And thirdly, I noticed your finance costs in Q2 were down quite significantly, despite that the fact that debt went up, at a time when borrowing costs are generally going up, which is a tremendous achievement. I just wondered how you did it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the third one first. I'm afraid that the average debt was lower than the quarter-end debt I mentioned; so that's one aspect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm pleased that we have <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then second, I should say that the mix of debt, we were heavily dollar denominated in this quarter versus year ago. So that helped.</p>
          <p>And then third, we actually had a flattery comparator versus last year. There were some things which were in and out last year which made the comparator easier, so. It's not &#x2013; we have a great treasury group here, <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>As to the second one, about the appropriate debt level. In my view, we believe, having A-plus, A1, our balance sheet is very important. I think it has served us extraordinarily well over the past 12 months, since this meeting a year ago, and our intention is to have a debt level which is consistent with that. We're going to be having proceeds coming in from the sale of the various businesses. We have a plan which, I said before, 1.5 billion plus in terms of share repurchases. We'll have an interim dividend to do at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>I really would not care to speculate on the exact level of debt that we'll have, because it's a function of a lot of things going in and out. But what I can confirm is the A-plus, A1 target for the balance sheet and the commitment to return surplus cash to shareholders, but also in the context of sensible value-creating acquisitions, and all that goes into the mix.</p>
          <p>As to the first question of how much the dilution will be, I don't know the answer to that. I know there will be a little bit, and I'll just see if either John or James can answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not going to give any number, because it will depend on the exact timings, but just &#x2013; each of the big ones has a small short-term dilutive effect. In the case of North American Laundry in particularly, we will have a transition services agreement, which will take a few months to help the new owners, and depending exactly on how long they take that on for and how that will affect the exact numbers next year, but each of them has a small one, and then cumulatively, there will be an effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So on one of them, <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we'll declare when we know what the final timings are and what those transactions, so we can do that certainly in the third quarter, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Last question. Martin. I hope your question is going to be able to pass to one of the colleagues. To ask about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks. Martin <mark type="inaudible" /> from Execution.  It was my understanding that Unilever basically takes trade promotion until you back off of revenue? So when you talk about promotion declines, or talk about consumer promotion, and I would have thought you increase consumer promotion at a time when you increase prices, rather than decrease it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's good. Vindi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, at a time that we're trying to increase prices and actually succeeding, the most important thing is to first position that price to land it and make it stick, and that's not the moment to offer any form of alternative incentive to the trade, or indeed to the consumer. Once the price &#x2013; again stabilized, that opportunity comes back, as it will for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me sum up.</p>
          <p>We believe that our strategy is working and delivering in a tough environment. Our D&amp;S focus and our D&amp;E story continues to be strong and make very good contributions to the business. We certainly seen some weakening in volume in developed markets, more so in Europe than we have seen in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Our priority remains to be competitive, to maintain our overall market position, and that's our number one objective. And we've certainly make sure that we are not going to let our competitiveness deteriorate, and hence, we are watching very closely the volume line.</p>
          <p>As to A&amp;P, it's not a balancing factor. We're very focused in taking advantage of the downturn to strengthen our market position, especially in developing market, and not even close anything like the so-called boom and bust, which we have not had for the 13 years &#x2013; 13 quarters, and we certainly not have as long as I am Chief Executive, and beyond.</p>
          <p>So with that, thank you very much, and I hope we have help you to better understand the set of results. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This conference has been recorded. Details of the redial number and access code can be found on Unilever's website, and <mark type="inaudible" /> also be available on Unilever's website, www.unilever.com</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>