<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1285790" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>515</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Paul Polman, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James Allison, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Douglas Baillie</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Jeremy Fialko</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Christopher Wickham</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Nico Lambrechts</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Marco Gulpers</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Julian Hardwick</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Charles Pick</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Xavier Croquez</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Manvinder Banga</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Joseline Gaudino</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Warren Ackerman</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Simon Marshall-Lockyer</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">Pier Luigi Sigismondi</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Pierre Tegner</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody and obviously welcome here. Good to see so many familiar faces.  I hope the year has started well for you.  Obviously, we're here to share with you the full year results and the fourth quarter results.  And I really do appreciate you taking the time out and obviously showing your interest in Unilever and for being here in your busy schedules that you have.</p>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; I was just talking to him, so let me pay a particular welcome to Charlie Mills, where' s Charlie actually?  I saw Charlie, but I don't know.  Here is Charlie, my friend who actually today marks his 25th year of covering Unilever and he's still smiling &#x2013; that's 100.  It also gives away his age, I guess.  That's 100 quarterly results calls, that's quite an achievement Charlie and obviously congratulations to you and many others who have covered us for so long.</p>
          <p>I'm joined today by James Allison, the Head of Investor Relations, and in the audience I'm delighted to introduce to you Jean-Marc Huet -- if you can standup Jean-Marc for a second -- our new Chief Financial Officer and I certainly look forward to sharing the platform with Jean-Marc over the course of the coming years.  Jean-Marc is a great addition to the executive team and we're obviously welcome &#x2013; happy to have him here.</p>
          <p>Besides, we have other members of the UEX here, Vindi who is sitting next of Jean-Marc.  Vindi Banga, our President of the Categories is here; Doug Baillie, I see him sitting there, our President of Western Europe; Genevi&#xE8;ve Berger, our Head Chief R&amp;D Officer; Sandy Ogg, our Chief HR Officer; and Pier Luigi Sigismondi sitting here in the front row, our Chief Supply Chain Officer; and then I saw Steve Williams here as well, our General Counsel.  Not joining us today are Mike Polk, who is the President of the Americas, and Harish Manwani, President of Asia, Africa, and Central and Eastern Europe.  They are in their respective markets driving their business and I thought it was a good thing that they continue to do that.</p>
          <p>So let me say a few words about the highlights of the year before handing over to James, who will actually cover our business performance in more depth.  After James takes you through the details, I actually will review what is driving our performance, what we will do more of and what we will need to do better.  I am convinced that the environment is going to stay competitive and it's by no means clear that life will get any easier for our consumers and our customers in the coming year.  I believe we're ready and prepared for this, for this environment that will continue to be tough, but obviously time will tell.  I will conclude my comments by sharing our priorities for 2010 and then opening up the floor for questions.  So let's get going.</p>
          <p>Let me start by drawing your attention to the usual disclaimer, which is related to the forward-looking statements and the non-GAAP measures.  As we have discussed in prior quarterly reviews at the beginning of 2009, there were a number of areas where Unilever was insufficiently competitive.  With a few exceptions, volume market shares had been declining for too many quarters.  Brand equities were weakening in too many markets.</p>
          <p>Many of our products lacked the superior performance that we were looking for and many of our innovations were undersupported and deployed in a fragmented way.  Service levels were unsatisfactory in too many places.  At the same time, markets were soft and uncertain in the context of the global recession.  To build long-term shareholder value, we felt that the priorities for Unilever in 2009 should be to restore volume growth whilst protecting cash flow and operating margin.  We set out to do this whilst addressing the underlying weaknesses of the business.  I am pleased with the progress we have made recognizing, and I'll be the first one to do that, that still more needs to be done.</p>
          <p>Volume growth of 2.3% for the year as a whole is a significant recovery from the 2% decline we actually started with in the first quarter.  Volume market share has improved as the year has progressed and was strongly positive in the fourth quarter.  More importantly, the growth was widespread.  At the beginning of 2009, we were actually growing share in roughly a third of our turnover.  By quarter four, we were growing share in nearly two-thirds of our turnover.  This is clear and measurable progress.  Actually, 10 out of our 13 brands are gaining share and the others are maintaining share.</p>
          <p>Value share has equally improved, trending in the same direction as volume share, suggesting that we have retained our relative price position and competitiveness.</p>
          <p>Underlying operating margins, although we had started the year by going for flat, are actually up 20 basis points.  We've done this whilst at the same time increasing the support levels behind our brands by a whopping 80 basis points for the year as a whole.  You know as well as I do that building brand equity is a cornerstone of the long-term success of consumer goods companies.  And this is very important to me in the way I certainly think about running the business.</p>
          <p>I'm also delighted with our cash and cost discipline during the year.  Again, we started the year by saying protecting our cash flow, but we ended the year with cash from operating activities up by &#x20AC;1.4 billion, despite an incremental contribution to pension funds of &#x20AC;0.5 billion, more than exceeding the stretching internal targets we had set ourselves and reflecting the good discipline across the organization.</p>
          <p>This has been driven by a strong focus on working capital and you've seen the results of this progressively coming through the year.  We're also seeing the benefits from the accelerated restructuring and the fast reduction of all discretionary costs that do not add value to the consumer or the customer.  In fact, overall cost savings were &#x20AC;1.4 billion for the year.  Again, this is ahead of the stretching internal targets we had set for ourselves.</p>
          <p>So frankly, I'm pleased with the quality of the results and the progress we've made in a relatively short period of time.  We have definitely raised the bar on performance.  We must now do this consistently as we move forward.  Before I give you my perspective, let me just pass over now to James, who will cover our performance in a little bit more detail.  James, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So thanks Paul.  Good morning everyone.  I intend to focus on the key aspects of the results rather than repeating a lot what is already in the announcement text.  In the attachments to this presentation, you will find some additional details which we will not cover specifically in the presentation.</p>
          <p>Underlying sales growth for the year was 3.5%, with 2.3% from volume and plus 1.2% from price.  Turnover was 39.8 billion, that's 1.7% down on 2008, reflecting negative currency of minus 2.7% and disposals net of acquisitions of minus 2.4%.  Underlying sales growth in quarter four was 1.8% with volume up 5% and underlying price growth of minus 3.1%.</p>
          <p>During the year, we saw volume momentum building. At the same time, the lapping of prior year price increases and early price corrections to reflect lower commodity costs reduced the components of price growth as the year progressed.  Turnover in the fourth quarter was 9.7 billion -- that's down by 4.8% -- impacted by negative currency movement of 5.7% and disposals net of acquisitions of minus 0.8%.</p>
          <p>The size of the negative currency exposure in the final quarter reflects the strength of the euro against most currencies, but particularly against the U.S. dollar, pound sterling, and Indian rupee.  The devaluation of the Venezuelan bolivar on its own accounted for 60 basis points of the negative currency movement in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Let's look at volume in a bit more detail.  This chart tells its own story. with momentum building each quarter and ending the year at plus 5%, albeit against the weak prior year comparator.  This compares with estimated market growth of about 3% in the same period.  Within this, it's worth looking beneath the surface of the quarter four performance of Western Europe.  Here, volume growth was lower on a reported basis by 0.7%, but you'll remember that there were two fewer trading days in quarter four 2009.</p>
          <p>On a like-for-like basis, the volume growth in Western Europe was between one and 2% positive. That's faster than the market and is reflected in improved volume and value share performance.  So here too, a strong sense of momentum, albeit in market conditions that continue to be challenging.</p>
          <p>Volume growth in D&amp;E markets has improved sequentially, finishing the year very strongly with volume up by 9.5% in the fourth quarter -- helped by the timing of Ramadan, prior year trade destocking in Russia, and some easy comps in a few of our markets.  For the year as a whole, we are encouraged by volume growth of over 4%, close to the average of the last 20 years of 5% and so soon after the recession with share growth in most markets.  This reflects not only the robustness of the D&amp;E markets, but also the strength of Unilever's competitive positions across so many geographies.  We stepped up innovation in 2009 with bigger initiatives rolled out to more markets, more quickly, and better supported.</p>
          <p>This chart shows a number of the products which we introduced during the course of the year.  Examples of more recent launches include Dove Nutrium launched in the US in quarter three, Dove for Men, launched in six countries in Western Europe in quarter four, and Sunsilk Co-creations, launched in Brazil, Argentina, Turkey, and India, also in quarter four.  All have started well.  For example, Dove for Men+Care is already the number two male shower brand in Belgium.</p>
          <p>Advertising and promotional expenditure increased substantially in the second half of the year, as we supported innovation strongly and continued to build brand equities.  Media impressions for the year as a whole were up by over 15%, partly through incremental expenditure and partly through lower media rates.  We substantially increased our expenditure on digital support, leading the expansion into this media across a number of our brands.</p>
          <p>Let me now say a few words about pricing and costs.  This chart shows the development of commodity costs set against the trend in underlying price growth.  From this, it is clear that prices have been increased and subsequently reduced in line with the movement in commodity costs.  Pricing in quarter four was minus 3.1%, at the bottom end of our guidance, because of actions taken in specific categories and markets to protect our competitive positions.  So for example, in some areas we did not take price increases that we had planned and in others we took actions to ensure that our consumer propositions remained competitive.  This should be seen in the context of the very substantial price increases taken in 2008 ahead of our competitive set in the face of unprecedented commodity cost increases.  In fact, price levels in the fourth quarter of 2009 are still around 5% higher than in the same period two years ago.  We now feel that pricing levels are appropriate, given our strategy, but this remains subject to any competitive pricing moves.</p>
          <p>We expect to see commodity cost tailwinds, albeit at a lower level, in the first quarter of 2010 as we work our way through forward covers and inventories.  For the year as a whole and based on today's exchange rates, we expect to see commodity costs two to 3% higher than in 2009, and this will put upward pressure on prices during the course of 2010.  We expect to see underlying price growth turning positive around the middle of 2010.</p>
          <p>As Paul mentioned, cost savings in the year were 1.4 billion, a real step up.  This comprised around 700 million from buying savings, 500 million from restructuring, and 200 million from local efficiency programs.  We expect savings in 2010 of at least &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>Let me say a few words about the status of the restructuring program, which we initiated in 2007 and which you will remember we called One Unilever.  We anticipated restructuring spending of roughly &#x20AC;1 billion a year from 2007 through 2009, that's three billion in total.  In fact, we've charged 2.6 billion to the income statement over this period, despite increasing the scope of manufacturing rationalization.  And we targeted restructuring savings of 1.5 billion in 2010 versus the 2006 base.  As at the end of 2009, we have delivered cumulative restructuring savings of &#x20AC;1.2 billion, with at least a further 300 million to come during 2010.</p>
          <p>This chart also shows the progress we are making in manufacturing restructuring.  You can see that by the end of 2010, we will have closed or streamlined 88 sites, higher than the 50 to 60 previously planned.  The bulk of the costs associated with the 2010 closures and streamlinings have already been charged to the income statement.</p>
          <p>Restructuring charges will now reduce to nearer to our longer term guidance of 50 to 100 basis points from the 250 basis points of recent years, this for normal ongoing productivity improvement.  The planned completion of the Sara Lee personal products acquisition in 2010 will lead to further restructuring costs and this will come over and above the 50 to 100 basis points. And we'll provide further guidance on this after completion.</p>
          <p>For the year as a whole, gross margin was up by 100 basis points, regaining much of the ground lost in 2008.  The increase in the second half of the year reflects the benefits of our strongly improved volume performance, lower commodity costs and savings programs, offset by lower pricing.  Gross margins were strongly ahead in all regions in quarter four.</p>
          <p>Operating margin before RDIs was up by 20 basis points in the year, with gross margins strongly ahead.  Overheads were flat, despite dilution from disposals, and A&amp;P was up by 80 basis points with advertising spend in particular strongly ahead.</p>
          <p>Let's have a look at earnings per share and I'll start with quarter four.  Basic earnings per share before RDIs were &#x20AC;0.27, down 6% versus the same period in 2008.  This is despite a strong contribution from operational performance, which added plus 10%.  The negative currency impact, which I described earlier in relation to turnover, reduced EPS by 6% in the quarter.  Finance and pension costs reduced EPS by 7%.  Minorities impacted EPS by a further 3%, reflecting cumulative adjustments to prior year minority interests booked in the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>So as you can see, non operational factors reduced EPS growth substantially in the quarter.  For the full year, earnings per share were &#x20AC;1.21, down 33% versus 2008, which benefited from substantial disposal profits.  Earnings per share before RDIs were down 7%, with EPS from operating performance up 4%.  This was, however, more than offset by negative impacts from currency of minus 2% and finance and pension costs of minus 6%.  In the year, disposal dilution impacted EPS by 2% and minorities a further 1%.</p>
          <p>Based on exchange rates as at the end of quarter four, we expect currency impacts to be broadly neutral in 2010, with pension financing costs contributing positively to EPS growth in 2010.  The pension deficit reduced from 3.3 billion at the end of quarter three to around 2.6 billion at the end of quarter four.  With corporate AA discount rates broadly stable, this reduction reflects strong investment returns and the additional company contributions paid in the quarter.  With long-dated government bond yields rising, local pension deficits for funded plans will also have improved.</p>
          <p>Cash expenditure on pensions in 2009 was 1.3 billion. That's up 500 million on 2008.  We expect payments in 2010 to be closer to &#x20AC;750 million.  We expect the pension financing charge to be close to zero in 2010 after a debit of 164 million in 2009.  At the same time, we expect additional charges in operating profit of approximately 30 million as we return to normal levels after some one-off benefits in 2009.</p>
          <p>Net debt ended the year at 6.4 billion, down from eight billion at the start of 2009.  This reflects the strong cash generation in the year.  Cash proceeds from the disposal of most of our minority interest in JohnsonDiversey contributed &#x20AC;300 million in quarter four.  Interest on borrowings was up slightly at 4.9% from 4.5% in 2008, reflecting a longer maturity profile on our debt.</p>
          <p>The tax rate before RDIs in 2009 was 26.6%. In 2010, we expect the tax rate before RDIs to be close to our long-term guidance of around 26%.  As previously discussed and agreed with shareholders, we will now pay dividends quarterly.  We have announced today that the first quarterly dividend will be &#x20AC;0.195. That's one quarter of the total cash payments made in 2009.  This will be paid in March and the next quarterly dividend will be announced with our quarter one results on the 29th of April.</p>
          <p>With that, let me return you to Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks James.  Okay, so you've heard the good set of results from James.  So let me spend a little bit of time to reflect on what we've been doing, what's making the difference, and frankly what's left to be done.  I see 2009 as the first step towards a consistent, long-term, top and bottom line growth.  We recognized the severity of the economic crisis and actually we recognized it earlier than some of our competitive set and actually took the steps to protect both the financial and the business fundamentals.</p>
          <p>For example, we refocused the organization on volume growth, operating margin, and cash flow.  We simplified the remuneration scheme.  I think this helped us drive alignment and a sense of urgency.  We removed costs wherever we could and we accelerated restructuring where possible.  We reduced our head office head count by approximately 1000 managers. We froze salaries. We cut travel budgets, and all other elements of discretionary expenditure. We simplified our portfolios, our SKU lineup and rationalized packaging and material and ingredients to drive more efficient buying.  And we simplified or eliminated many of the internal non-value added processes.  We started to leverage scale more effectively than before, with all of our main supply contracts, for example, being re-negotiated, including those related to media buying and planning.</p>
          <p>Now, we used these savings to invest more strongly than ever before in our brands and in our products.  In so doing, we have been laying the foundations for sustainable profitable growth.  We also launched towards the end of the year a new and exciting vision for the company built on sustainable growth and leveraging increasingly our unique competitive advantages. An energizing vision to double the size of the business whilst actually reducing the environmental footprint.</p>
          <p>Before I go into a bit more depth on our strategic priorities, let me just say a few words about the economic environment.  And you've heard me say this before, but we expect the economic environment for our business in 2010 to continue to be tough.  With the reduction in stimulus packages by governments and an increase in taxes, consumer spending will continue to be under pressure.  Unemployment will continue to stay high and consumer confidence is likely to remain low.  And those are the key drivers of our business.</p>
          <p>We expect continued deflationary pressure in many markets as customers compete on value.  Competitors are equally increasing their activities in many of the markets, trying to frankly regain share on the back of more brand support hopefully and innovations.  So as I said earlier, we do not underestimate and we should not underestimate the size of the challenges we face.  But we believe that we have been building the competitive strength necessary to continue on the journey we started in 2009.</p>
          <p>D&amp;E markets, which account for about half of Unilever's turnover, have actually been more robust than many had feared.  As you've already seen in our volume growth, here has quickly and very quickly returned to pre-recession levels.  In fact, volume growth in the last quarter was over 9%.  We've spoken before about what makes the opportunities in the D&amp;E markets so exciting.  The demographic trends, an extra one billion consumers will be able to afford to buy our products in the next 10 years.  That's exciting. Levels of per capita consumption are actually much lower than the developed markets and offer enormous scope for more consumption.  The categories where we have the global strength have actually still low usage.  Just to give you a few examples.  The use of branded deodorant products is not yet a part in many of these places of the daily grooming routines and our ranges of household cleaning products will be perfectly complementary to the needs of millions of consumers that enter new home ownership.</p>
          <p>The hair conditioning and fabric conditioning markets are not yet well established in many of the D&amp;E markets, etcetera, etcetera.  And sometimes, it's easy to forget the size and the scale of the existing D&amp;E business that we can leverage.  In fact, it's well ahead of our competitive set.  If we take the Home Care and Personal Care categories for example, we reach 96% of the 1.9 billion consumers in Asia and South Africa.  That's 33% more than the next biggest competitor. Per capita consumption of Unilever products is also nearly double that of our next biggest competitor.  So, we're well placed in these markets.</p>
          <p>And it's good to see that our businesses are performing well in the areas, even in the areas where we're being attacked by our competitors with increased competitive activity.  Let's take Indonesia for example, where I recently visited them.  We've seen an increased activity from both international and local competitors.  Despite that, our value market shares are up by 270 basis points in the last 12 weeks alone.  A market like Turkey with increased competitive activity saw equally strong performance.</p>
          <p>Now, let me just briefly say a few words about the four strategic thrusts that underpin our business performance.  Now just to remind you, these are Winning with Brands and Innovation, Winning through Continuous Improvement, Winning in the Marketplace, and finally Winning with People.  Let's just take them each in turn.  First and most importantly, let me address Winning with Brands and Innovation.  Now, that's not new to us.  In fact, the most recent Best of Decades Award which was published by Ad Age in the US recognizes two of the Unilever brands.  Axe was named the third best new product of the decade.  In fact, it came just behind iPod and the WiFi and well ahead of other competitors. Not bad.  And if that is not enough, the Dove Evolution campaign was recognized in the top 10 non-TV ads of the decade.  That's outstanding recognition of the great work that is being done on two of Unilever's leading brands.</p>
          <p>Now during 2009, we have significantly stepped up the quantity and effectiveness of our brands and our brand support.  Our share of voice as a result of that has been improving.  And at the same time, we've been improving the quality of our communication as well as the quality of our products.  So it's not just about more advertising, it's about better advertising behind better quality products.</p>
          <p>Now, we will continue to improve our products when we move forward.  In fact, on product quality of 2010 alone, we plan to invest over an additional &#x20AC;100 million to improve our product quality.  Here are some examples of the advertising behind some of our recent launches and product improvements. Just have a look.</p>
          <p>[Company Advertisements]</p>
          <p>That's about as far as we go.  Now there are plenty of Klondike bars for you to try afterwards for the people that are here.  This brand actually had underlying sales growth in the US or in North America of over 15% in 2009.  So my recommendation to you really is get those bars as long as they last.</p>
          <p>Now, we've be working hard to improve the quality of our innovation funnel as well, as you can see from the chart here.  We expect to significantly increase the incremental turnover from key innovations in 2010.  The incremental turnover expected from projects launched in the next three to five years has also doubled.  And you've seen that we are focused on fewer bigger innovations, which we are rolling out to more markets more quickly.  Dove for Men+Care has launched simultaneously in six markets in quarter four of '09 and will be in 50 markets by the end of 2010.</p>
          <p>Axe Variants routinely travels to over 50 markets inside the space of 12 months.  This chart shows other examples of the quickening speed of our rollouts.  It's now truly becoming embedded and a good habit and a proven way to build sizable incremental turnover.  But we also recognize that not everything needs to be everywhere.  Axe Hair, for example, has generated over a &#x20AC;50 million incremental turnover in North America alone, 12 months since launch.  And this despite the simultaneous launch of a key competitive brand that is disappearing now from the shelves.</p>
          <p>These are high quality innovations from a pipeline which is increasingly becoming healthier.  With a stronger R&amp;D organization in place, open innovation accelerated and genesis projects underway, our flow of innovation is strengthening each year a bit more.  I believe certainly that is now our innovations are at par with the best of the rest.</p>
          <p>Now not all great brands are leveraged as much as they should be and there are still many opportunities to introduce our brands in more markets that we're not yet in, growing those markets and taking share from our competitors.</p>
          <p>Examples of this include the launch of our ice cream brands in Vietnam, Cif in India, Ben &amp; Jerry's in Norway and now Australia, Sunlight in Nigeria, Pond's in the Middle East getting to market leadership in year one and the list goes on.</p>
          <p>M&amp;A activity is equally helping us to take our brands further as well and to fill our wide space in category positions.  The acquisition of the Napoca brand in Romania gave us a foothold in ice cream from which we are able to launch a broader ice cream portfolio.  The addition of Baltimor ketchup in Russia allows us to fill out our dressing portfolio there.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, the acquisition of the Personal Care products brands of Sara Lee, brands like Sanex, Radox, Neutro, and Duschdas will allow us to meet the consumer needs across a wide range of price points in the skin cleansing and deodorants market.</p>
          <p>The second key thrust I briefly want to touch on is Winning in the Marketplace -- how well are serving our customers and consumers. And this runs from the basic requirements of delivering our products on time and in full right through to the business planning, where we work together for the benefits of our retailers and ours.</p>
          <p>As we have discussed before, in-store execution is critical to our long-term success.  Whilst we have great examples within our business, our performance frankly has been uneven in this area and we have prioritized this over 2009 for improvement.  In 2009, for the first time, we have mandated a single scorecard across all of our key operations to track performance on the key sales fundamentals. By establishing aligned KPIs, we have become clearer about our performance in critical metrics, such as onshelf availability and share of shelf; and not surprisingly, we're showing improvements there.  With sharper accountability and clearer metrics, we can now drive performance improvements.</p>
          <p>Where we were behind versus our competitors, we're catching up, and where we are ahead of our competitors, we're increasing our gaps.  We are striving to understand the needs of major customers better and the behavior of the shoppers so that we can grow their business and grow the business with them.  Now, I'm pleased with the way we have rolled out with discipline our joint business planning across the business to a wide range of customers.</p>
          <p>We're now using it to identify and to take opportunities to our mutual advantage.  Our actions are starting to be recognized as well, gaining preferred supplier status in a number of markets or indeed awards -- supplier of the year in some of our key markets from some of our key customers.</p>
          <p>You can see from the chart that we are improving service levels in almost all key markets.  Onshelf availability is improving as well, up to 89% in the second half.  The Customer Insight and Innovation Center concept, which some of your experienced in New Jersey at our Investor Seminar that held in November. is now being rolled out globally.  Last week, we opened the second center at here in the UK in Leatherhead at our MCO.  Later, we will do the same in several other countries around the world.</p>
          <p>Now, let's turn to the third area, which is Winning through Continuous Improvement -- equally important.  I will not go back over the numbers, which you already have heard, tempting though they may be because these numbers are good.  But let me remind you of the model.  Volume growth leads to operating leverage, which in turn lowers unit costs.  At the same time, we are removing with discipline costs which do not add value to the consumers or customers.  Taken together, this creates substantial fuel for growth and gives us scope to reinvest in the business whilst steadily improving the operating margins.</p>
          <p>Up until 2009, too many of our brands lacked the investment and the support to compete effectively.  In 2009, we took the first steps towards fixing this by materially increasing advertising as well as promotional expenditure, realigning prices in certain places become uncompetitive and investing substantially in product quality.  We were able to do this whilst still improving underlying operating margins. And this model certainly hasn't run out of steam yet.  It sounds simple, but it requires a growth mindset and the confidence to invest in our brands; and yes, it requires a lot of hard work.</p>
          <p>Overheads as a percentage of turnover have been held flat in the year despite the dilution impact from disposals we've had in 2008. The full year benefit of the head count reductions that we made in the second half of 2009 will provide further scope for savings, I believe, in 2010.  To further leverage scale, we have announced our move to global business services.  Our plan is to build on the excellent work started in the regions.  We will bring HR and finance transactions, IT services, information management services, office and facility services, all together under one roof in a first class organization.  In so doing, we will improve services and reduce costs at the same time.</p>
          <p>Now cash flow performance has been equally good.  By getting working capital into everyone's target, linked to pay, and by adopting best practices from around the globe, we've made good progress, I believe, in all elements of trade working capital, but especially inventories, despite the fact that our starting point for this company was already fairly competitive.</p>
          <p>You can see from the chart here that this has not been a flash in the pan, but a sustained improvement throughout the year.  Now, we will target lower average working capital in 2010 rather than quarter-by-quarter end positions, we will now go to average working capital.  This will put further emphasis on keeping working capital always low rather than simply achieving the period end reductions.  It's a much more transparent and honest way to get sustainable working capital improvement.</p>
          <p>Turning to the fourth thrust, I'm particularly pleased with the progress we're making on the organization and performance culture.  I've always said it will take several years, but here again, we're making good progress and we are calling this Winning with People.  During the year, we've reduced the number of managers from around 16,000 to nearer to 15,000.  The number of senior managers has been reduced in size by almost 50% from the levels of 2005.  Taking out layers of management has allowed us and the organization to become flatter, more agile, and more externally focused. We've seen management changes in over half of our top roles in the last 12 months alone, and almost all involving internal changes.  And we've better skill matched against the new roles that were required with each new appointment.</p>
          <p>Our management systems around targeting and alignment have been systematically sharper during the year and improved. Individual performance against measurable criteria is now more visible and individual performance assessments are becoming more robust, more differentiated, and as a result, also reflected in more differentiated pay.  And as we toughen the benchmarks, we will also increase the potential reward for exceptional performance.  At the same time, we will expect management to also increase further long-term share ownership.  Now you will hear more about this at the Annual General Meeting.</p>
          <p>In short, more stretching targets driving superior performance and only if achieved, more reward.  So as I draw towards close, there has been much that is good, but not everything in the garden is rosy yet.  You've heard me say that the progress we're making is helping to narrow the gap to best-in-class, keeping in mind that best-in-class companies never stand still either.  I expect the catching up to continue for the next couple of years. And whilst there are many things to be pleased about, there is still much more to do.  Although improving, we still have some countries and category positions that need to do better.</p>
          <p>Our competitive positions in India in Spain and in Eastern Europe have not yet improved to the extent that I would have expected.  Our sequential performances in Hair, SCC are improving, but still they need to build share consistently everywhere.  We've talked about product quality.  Yes, it is getting better, but we need to do more so that more of our products start showing the superiority.  Yes, brand equities are strengthening, but not yet everywhere.  And our internal surveys with our employees indicate that we're not yet as consumer and customer focused as our like and that we can be faster in the way we operate.  So there is still much more to do and much improvement still to be made.  But as the saying goes, Rome was not built in one day.  I do believe though that in 2009 we've made a good start.</p>
          <p>Now, I fully expect that the environment in 2010 will be just as tough as in 2009 and we're prepared for that.  We have the confidence that comes from a strong delivery in 2009.  We expect volume and value shares to further improve throughout the year behind a clear step up again in brand support and innovations.  We expect stronger delivery of savings like we've done in 2009 and we expect further shaping of the organization and culture.  But we are far from complacent.  We know that competition will be tougher and that consumers will be even more demanding; and rightfully so.</p>
          <p>Our priorities therefore for 2010 are to drive volume growth whilst providing a steady improvement in underlying operating margins and strong cash flow.  With that, I'll finish my talk and we'll open it up for questions.  Thanks for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the usual routine on housekeeping, if I may say so. If you are in the room and you want to ask a question then stick your hand up.  If you're selected, then please press the little button on your console and that will allow everybody to hear you.  Please tell us who you are, and if you don't mind, please restrict yourselves, at least to the outset, to no more than two questions.  If you're listening via the teleconference and hello Marco, then you want to poll for the question, then you can key star, one, and you'll get in the line for the question. Marco has already done that.  And if you want to retract that, then you press star two.  We're also taking questions via the web and if we got time, we'll take them as well.  So, without further ado, then let's have your hands up and take some questions from the audience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions on Europe, Paul and I guess Doug as well...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Doug is here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I find the comment generally on Europe, it's obvious that this is your most challenging region, the price volume elasticity, sorry, price volume elasticity equation is not as good as the other regions, and it looks if you are investing a lot in A&amp;P.  So just value any general commentary on how you're seeing Western Europe.  Specifically, could you comment on the spreads business in Western Europe. It looks to me as if pricing in particular has been difficult there and I'd value some specific commentary on how that part of the business has performed?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I will let Doug add to this.  Obviously, Western Europe is a tough environment on a macroeconomic level and then that's reflected in our results and our competitive results.  Despite that, I believe that Doug and his organization do an outstanding job.  We have actually seen our volumes progress throughout the year and we've seen actually our shares increase throughout the year in fairly tough conditions.</p>
          <p>In our Personal Care business, our Foods and Home Care business, I think we have many examples where we've built share and countries like the UK we've actually grown our business as well.  But you are right to say and it is fair to say as well, we've made a conscious decision that we should not manage Europe just for profit, but that we should actually grow Europe for long-term shareholder value creation. I've mentioned that to you last year that was our strategy.  And we're executing against that strategy and part of that reflects also an increased A&amp;P spend in Europe to support that.  And despite that, we're ending the year more or less in Europe with good progress and margins in line with the company average.  So I think Doug is delivering against that objective.  And with hopefully Sara Lee coming in in quarter three more or less of 2010, we expect to actually accelerate on that.</p>
          <p>On SCC very simply, there have been price investments. But again in 2008, prices were taken up about 18 to 20% in that category as a result of input cost inflation. And some of that, with the prices coming down in this year, we obviously have reflected in prices to stay competitive.  And that was again the right decision because we've built share on that business across Europe.  So I don't know, Doug, if you want to add to that anything specific.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think so. I think just that there's been just a dramatic step up in terms of our execution capability, our focus on the real basics in the organization.  We've made a number of changes in terms of the leadership of the team, I was just working out quickly, we've changed nine people out of the 15 people that directly report to me.  So we have really fired up team now that is getting the business really competitive.  We still have a long way to go.  We still have much to do.  A lot of the points that Paul covered today really apply to Western Europe in terms of the areas that we've got to step up.  But, I think there is a growing sense of confidence in the team, there is a growing sense of belief that we can win.  And the best result for me this year was to see the shares start to move and get back to competitive growth.  On SCC specifically, we worked very hard this year at filling the portfolio and covering price points.  Those of you who are with us in November about 18 months ago remember I spoke about getting tool boxes in place that cover price points and portfolio gaps.  And in SCC, that's been particularly good for us as we've gone out and covered right from the very bottom of the pyramid right up to the more premium sort of areas.  And having that coverage allows consumers to stay with the Unilever portfolio as they trade up and down.  So lots to do, but a bit of a step up certainly for us, but hopefully a lot more to come in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was on Monday and Tuesday with Doug and the management team, the European management team in Barcelona, they had their annual pow-wow of how are we going to beat the 2010 targets. And I'm sure they're going to do that.  But it's very good to see that the growth spirit is back and we have very strong initiatives that we're launching.  On the Laundry, we have the Small &amp; Mighty that we're introducing on both Persil and serve we talked about.  The Dove for Men is a very strong initiative being rolled out in Europe.  The Signal White Now and the mouthwash that comes with it are very strong initiatives.  Our deodorant business is growing again.  So Europe is just back in the game.  I'm European. Most of you are European and what I always remind ourselves is that Europeans are human beings as well and they will go for product improvements if they make sense.  So let's get rid of all the excuses, shake them off, and start growing.  Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Jeremy Fialko, Redburn Partners.  A couple of questions. First of all on A&amp;P, obviously there have been some big increases in the latter parts of 2009. Could you just talk about what you think that is going to happen there in 2010 and when you might start to see more kind of incremental increases in A&amp;P as a percentage of sales?  And secondly, you've changed an awful lot of managers over the course of the last year. Would you say you're pretty much done with getting the people you want in the top jobs and you're going to see much fewer, sort of much less turnover of the top managers in 2010?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Jeremy.  On the A&amp;P, we're up 80 basis points for the year and obviously a little bit more skewed towards the back half in the last quarter we're up about 250 basis points roughly from memory.  So these are big A&amp;P investments at a time when the rates have come down as well.  So there is a double effect.  You'll be pleased to hear that most of that investment, about 80% of that, is in the A and not in the P part, and that's good, because that's even better cholesterol to build our brands long-term.  So I'm happy about that.  And the reason it is skewed towards the back half obviously is that because we've had so many innovations that accelerated over the back half of the year as we were getting ready for them during the year.  There is no reason as we will continue to capture efficiencies over 2010 that we reinvest some of that into A&amp;P to further strengthen our brands and support our innovations.  We have increased our relative share of price the way we read it.  But we still have many places and many cells as we call them where we are not as competitive as we should be.  And as these innovations are being rolled out, we certainly will look at quality support behind that. And without giving you more details of that, I expect a significant increase in A&amp;P spend in 2010 as well.</p>
          <p>The second question that you had is on the management changes. The change is inevitable in this business obviously and we will continue to look for changes where they make sense.  As we aspire to double our business and become an organization of &#x20AC;80 billion or more, we also need to be sure that we have the capabilities and the people that are 80 billion or more.  We broadly have that in the organization, but we will continue to look at skill sets inside and outside that we need to have to get there.</p>
          <p>And I think a lot of people now have gotten new assignments over the last six to nine months, and those people obviously will be in those assignments for the next three to five years.  But there is no reason why we will not continue to look at other changes, if I may be frank.  I like to quote always Mario Andretti, one of my famous friends and race car drivers, who said if things around me change faster than I am, I know I am in trouble.  So I do know that competition also continuously looks at improving their organization and we should do the same thing, like we do with our brands and like we do with our innovations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. It's Chris Wickham from MainFirst.  Just two questions on the D&amp;E markets, where do you, I mean, I appreciate that across most of the cells and the categories, you're gaining share within category.  How do you feel that your categories are performing in terms of gaining share within the D&amp;E wallet and in terms of prioritization?  And the second point is you're talking about adding a billion customers in the next 10 years.  Just could you remind us perhaps how does that compare with the progress that was made in the past ten years in D&amp;E?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as you've seen in the D&amp;E in the last quarter alone, our growth is over 9%, so that's healthy growth.  Fortunately, we've been blessed that the D&amp;E markets have held up well, but we've outperformed those markets in terms of GDP growth.  And we've mentioned before that one of the key drivers for us in the emerging markets is actually market development, it's growing the pie.  So a lot of that growth is actually coming from market development.  The one billion incremental customers are coming from the two things: the growth in demographics in those countries and actually the consumers entering our choice set, if you want to.</p>
          <p>Our products are very well placed there and in most of the places where you see that strong consumer growth, we are actually market leaders.  You take a market like Vietnam, where in a lot of categories we have the leading brands, and even if -- or Indonesia  -- and even if competitive activity increases, which obviously is a good thing for the consumers there to accelerate the rate of innovation.  If we do our jobs, we see not only the markets accelerate further, but we also see our shares increase.  So we think that the bulk of the growth moving forward and the incremental one billion consumers, the main driver behind that will be market development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one more from the floor and then we'll go to the teleconference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I thought &#x2013; yeah, sorry forget, you have, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Nico Lambrechts from Bank of America-Merrill Lynch.  Paul, last year towards the back end of the year on November, I think you explicitly cautioned the market not to assume continuous increases in volume going from zero, three and then five. You did end up with the 5% volume growth.  What would you ascribe the main reason for the better than your expected volume growth?  Is it the lower price or is it stronger growth from emerging markets or is it the impact from innovations?  That's the first question.  And then the second question is you mentioned that half of the top management team are in new roles, almost all of those are internal.  Could you maybe just remind us how much of the new top management are external appointments versus internal changes?  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I appreciate the question.  The growth actually is, what I would still caution for us is life is not made out of three months.  I'm personally not a big proponent to have discussions with all of you on three months numbers and of one more trading day or one less trading day, or our systems changed last year or a little bit of a climate change and some country affecting our ice cream.  I think if you run the business like that and have an honest contract with all of you on quarterly numbers with all these little, little adjustments, I think you miss the big picture and obviously.  So what I think is our markets are growing two to 3%, we're indeed growing 5% now.  I don't think you should assume accelerations of that growth, I'd say the same thing as what I said before.  I think these are very healthy growth levels in competitive markets, ahead of the markets we're building share.  And the main driver of that obviously as you rightfully say it's not pricing because our volume and value shares, if you look at very carefully, our volume and value shares are both going up.  So our relative pricing stays the same.</p>
          <p>We've just been very early in the year compensating for price increases that were frankly out of whack in 2008. And it's mainly in these categories of SCC or Household Cleaners or Laundry that we have done that.  And what you see in the last quarter is the full year effect of that.  You guys all understand that when you analyze the numbers.  We had in the last quarter of 2008 a little over 9% price increase. The highest price increases of any of our competitors, despite what they said, you go back to the numbers, was 7%.  So we were early in adjusting that to stay competitive.  But our pricing strategy has not changed and don't be mistaken, our pricing strategy is just to stay competitive with the market.  And the fact that our volume and value shares both go up confirm that.  So the key driver of our innovation &#x2013; the key driver of volume growth is the acceleration of innovation.</p>
          <p>If you go to the second element, which is the top 100 people, in fact only 8% of the top 100 people come from the outside.  It happens to have a little bit of a higher exposure and I can only apologize for that, by the fact that I came in from the outside or Jean-Marc or Genevi&#xE8;ve in R&amp;D came in from the outside, or Pier Luigi.  So it looks like if you look at the top, there are three or four people coming in from the outside. But you have not seen and perhaps we haven't talked enough about that, about the many appointments once we made inside in the company by giving people other challenges and better skill matching of promoting people. And we've done plenty of that.</p>
          <p>So if you take the top 100 that really are the key change leaders, if you want to, or the people running this business, about 8% come from the outside.  And that's a very healthy mix of 8%.  Yeah, so eight out of the 100 is eight people.  So it's a very &#x2013; that's an easy calculation I can make, it's about as far as it goes.  But it's &#x2013; so it's a very healthy ratio by the way that I think we don't run in by ratios, but even if that goes to 10 or 15% it's still very healthy for running a company like this.  Because we also increasingly need to bring in this external benchmarking and be sure that we not only are internally strong, but also against the competitive side.  We take one more question here, because otherwise I shall stuck with you and then we go to the...Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Sara Welford from Citigroup.  Two questions. Firstly on the innovation pipeline, can you just talk about is there going to be any SKU at all that we should be aware of for 2010 like there was in 2009?  And secondly, going back to the D&amp;E markets, the perception at the moment is that perhaps competition is increasing there, but as you mentioned, this partly helps the markets evolve.  How do you see this moving forward sort of on a longer term basis?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those are good questions.  I'll start with the last one, if you don't mind, and then go the first one. I think it's quite normal that competition says look at where the consumers are growing and look at where the 100 million plus consumers are. And those are markets we should focus on as we want to expand.  That's frankly not a new phenomena.  And the fact that someone talks about it now you might ask yourself where have they been before.  So Unilever has had a strong presence historically in a lot of these markets and we've always said that our strong competitive positions in a lot of these D&amp;E markets is an advantage.  Now some people were worried about that at the beginning of 2009 with the economic crisis, but these countries have now achieved a certain level of maturity and stability.  So if we do our jobs well and continue to innovate our brands and stay close to consumers, we should welcome that competition. That is what the business we've chosen to be in.  It's good for the economies, it's good for consumers, but it's also good for us.  And over and over where you see this increased competitive activity, you actually see an acceleration of market growth.  So looking forward, I don't expect that to decrease, but I think that's very healthy.  And we certainly know how to operate in that environment.</p>
          <p>In terms of innovations, I will obviously not share with you some of the new innovations that will be coming in 2010 until we launch them.  But to give you a little bit of an idea and to build on the previous question, Dove Nutrium that I have here which is a wonderful product and certainly superior than anything else on the market, we've just introduced that in 30 markets in the last quarter alone, sorry, in three, but going into 30 markets.  But we've just introduced that, sorry, we've just introduced that going into 30 markets now as we talk.  So that's a big improvement.</p>
          <p>You look at Dove for Men, male cosmetics increasing tremendously, you just saw the advertising.  Dove for Men is a tremendous strong product. That will go into 50 markets as we talk.  So those are big improvements that we're putting in. The Axe Twist that you see here.  So again, tremendous product going into 50 markets as we talk.</p>
          <p>I just had a board meeting yesterday and we had them all taste Magnum Gold. And if there is one thing about ice cream it makes people happy.  So we had a happy board, which is good for me as well.  And so I decided from now on to give our board ice cream before they do my performance review.  But the Magnum Gold which is one of the leading ice cream products -- growing very fast, -- we're launching that now in about 30 countries, 27 countries to be exact.  So you see an acceleration -- and the list goes on, by the way.  So you see an acceleration of our innovations clearly coming through that will benefit us for years to come.  We will take one question offline then, I hope that answered it.  Yeah, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we should have actually two there on the telephone line, Marco Gulpers is first up. Marco, can you come through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning all.  I have two follow-up questions.  The first is indeed on an update on the underlying market growth and maybe you want to split that into regions to share with us what you're seeing on underlying market growth, and basically combine that with the current consensus in the market of about 3% volume growth in 2010, i.e., a further acceleration compared to 2009.  The second question is basically on the dividend, the &#x20AC;0.195. What does it actually mean for the full year '09 number?  Thanks again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marco, let me just take the first part of the question on the market growth and then the second part of the question, James will give you an answer on that.  And by the way, it's different for the PLC in the entry, so if you have the data on that, because that's the currency effect that we get that . On the market growth itself, we continue to see actually North America and Europe being sluggish in general.  Slightly more growth in, not much difference, but slightly more growth on food in Europe than on the HPC side, but the market growth, the way we read it in our portfolio of products.  So these mixes of us and our competitors might be slightly different and that's why you might get slightly different numbers.  But it's about one to 2%.  And in the emerging markets, we have seen a healthy growth of three to 4%.  So you average that out and you get to about a market growth a little bit above the 2% for us, if you read that. And the consensus as a result of that seeing our volumes accelerate over next year from 2.3% to 3%, I would be fairly comfortable with, Marco, if this is what you're saying.  So the next part is the dividend itself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Hi, Marco yes.  We've now moved to quarterly dividends. We've set the first quarterly dividend at &#x20AC;0.195, so now we will always set the dividend in euros and then it will translate into sterling and into US dollars based on the exchange rate that prevails two days before we announce what the dividend is. But we will always announce the dividend in euros.  So &#x20AC;0.195 is one quarter of the actual cash dividend that we paid out in 2009.  Our policy remains we seek to increase in a sustainable way the dividend year-on-year. All we've done so far is to announce what the first interim dividend is. And as we go through each of these quarterly announcements, we will then indicate what the dividend is going to be for the subsequent quarter.  So we're not giving guidance at this point, Marco, in terms of what the dividend is going to be for the year.  You just have to wait and see what comes as each quarter progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there was.  I'll take it.  Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Julian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Julian Hardwick at RBS.  Just following up on dividend, could you just help us understand what sort of parameters the board is looking at in terms of payout ratio?  If you look at it on an EPS pre-RDIs basis, you're up close to sort of 60% payout ratio. I mean is that a payout ratio that the board is comfortable with or should the expectation be that over time, you would look to reduce it and is EPS pre-RDI the basis that your &#x2013; the board setting the dividend on?  And sort of second question in terms of board parameters. Capital structure, I mean, could you just say something about the board's current thinking about what the appropriate capital structure for the group now is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  So, again let me start with the last one, because it ties in with the first one, it's probably better to start first.  And again we had that discussion yesterday in the board in all transparency.  We're of the opinion that our A+ rating is well served.  We're of the opinion that we want to keep that and I think the events of the last few years have brought to light why a solid capital structure is preferred.  We look at our normal capital investments, which I have said before will slightly increase as we grow again and build new factories, has been relatively low in this company and you should welcome that.  We more or less are happy with our dividend payout ratio and the percent is plus or minus, I'm not going to argue and then we do the one to &#x20AC;2 billion bolt-on acquisitions.  And it happens to be that in 2010, I need to pay for the Sara Lee acquisition.  So all of that taken together will put us in a capital structure and situation that maintains our A+ rating and we feel comfortable about that.  So that's how we look at 2010. And then obviously in function of how the business is doing, we will assess moving forward and that actually also then answers the dividend question.  Yeah, you want to add to that or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to acknowledge that the payout ratio is indeed high &#x2013; it's in the high 50s and that's higher than most of our competitive set.  So I guess in the longer term, you can imagine that as earnings per share starts to ramp it up, maybe the dividend increase isn't quite in line with the rate in which we are increasing EPS until such time as we are perhaps a little nearer to the rest of the pack.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we will continue to increasingly look at opportunities to give you the return versus giving you the money.  And we have to earn that right and that's what we are working on.  Yeah, I'm sorry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks good morning.  Charles Pick of FinnCap.  I had two questions please. You identified &#x20AC;1 billion of extra cost savings in the current year, of which 300 million comes from restructuring actions.  Is the bulk of the remainder coming from purchasing economies?  And second you referenced the A&amp;P. Is it possible to give some sort of pointer as to how much of that is now being directed at Western Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Contrary to what people think is when input costs go down, for example, because markets of raw materials go down, that for us is not a saving.  We don't book that as saving.  Savings in our system, which are 1.4 billion, so they're little bit higher than what you say, are truly doing things differently than we did before.  And that's the area that Pier Luigi is responsible for. And we still think that we have enough to go to set again the targets fairly ambitiously for 2010.  So those are real savings and efficiencies.  Obviously, our competitors worked that as well, so I don't know what the relative advantage is, but I think for the size of our business, coming out with &#x20AC;1.4 billion will probably close the gap in terms of efficiency versus our competitive set.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. The next opinion was in current year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For 2010, you're talking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I just wondered how that split, because you gave us 300 million from rationalization by the text.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we don't really split that, to be honest.  So I will not, we have our own internal targets for all of the components, but I think that's not too relevant anymore for the market where the differences come from.  I don't think we split that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but, most of it's going to come from buying savings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, obviously, but I don't think we're going to split up the savings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We're not. No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the second thing was your question on A&amp;P, question being if we would continue to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to know how much of that has been directed to Western Europe..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, how much to Western Europe. We have, if you look at Western Europe right now, our gross margins are up in Western Europe and our A&amp;P is up significantly if you look at 2009.  And these investments are starting to pay out.  So I think you will see further investments again in A&amp;P in Western Europe.  If you take the 80 basis points as a whole for the company, it's about the same basis points for Western Europe more or less.  I'm doing this from memory.  So don't put me on the 10 basis points itself.  But I see Doug nodding his head, so it's about the same...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's in proportion, it's not any longer...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  So Doug is saying the same.  So that is that part of it.  Yeah, go ahead.  Xavier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Xavier Croquez. Cheuvreux.  Two questions. The first one is on this chart with commodity prices and your pricing.  At the end of the day two years later, you say you are 5% higher than in Q4 '07. What does it mean in terms of price points and premium versus own label or your key competitors broadly speaking. And if anything would you sense that 2010, you will have to reduce that premium or you said you are happy where you are, but getting a clear picture on this would be fine?  The second question is having a brand review. What are the brands, where you still have lot of work to do? Specifically I would be happy to hear the update on Dirt is Good and Knorr and any other one you would like to comment on?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Xavier, when you said, work to do, what do you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're not happy with the brand equity, you still have to crack the knots and you don't know exactly how you will move forward in the next two, three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  When there was a lot of price inflation in 2008, branded products reflecting a price increase would have to be done and we were very early to do that and took more pricing than our competitive set once more.  It increases the absolute gap versus private label.  Private label is at 50 and you're at 100, you both put a 10% price increase, you're actually increasing the absolute gap by five.  Not surprisingly, we saw private label growing a little bit especially in the European and the US environment on top of the economic pressures that were taking place.  For the same token, as these prices have come down, with the easing of input costs, the relative price difference versus competition actually has come down.  And if, I was just looking at the Bernstein report on European private label, so I'm quoting an external source that you can take for what it is, but actually private label growth in Europe has slowed down.</p>
          <p>In our categories, it's actually down, it's not up. And in markets where private label is very strong like the UK, we're actually growing.  Now that's not just a combination of &#x2013; that's not just pricing and relative pricing, it's a combination of the products and the innovations with our relative pricing.  But obviously when we set prices in our categories, we look at a broad array of products, our competitive products, private label being one of them.  And I think we broadly are happy with our relative pricing position that we have, but that has to be monitored in our industry on a daily basis.</p>
          <p>On the brand equities, we are never happy with our brand equities, that sounds a little bit like a flat answer, but we have a lot of brands that we will, all of our brands for that matter, we will continue to look at strengthening our brand equities.  10 of our 13 &#x20AC;1 billion brands are actually growing share and the others are holding share.  So that's an indication &#x2013; a relative indication that our equities are getting stronger and we feel good about that and we monitor that, we call them confection scores, whatever you have.  So we have our testing techniques on that. But it is also true to say that in many of our categories, we can certainly continue to strengthen our brands and that is why we are fairly confident in sharing with you that we will continue to increase our A&amp;P levels over 2010 and obviously continue to accelerate our innovations.  I would not like to single out a specific brand or a specific category where we would say we need to accelerate more, because the message here is that all of our brands need to continue to work that.  Vindi is here, Vindi obviously responsible for all of our categories, I don't know if you want to add to that, Vindi, or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that's fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay.  Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Joseline Gaudino, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale I just want to come back to your price positioning and being competitive, which is the base of it.  I just want to understand what has been done because I know that commodity prices were up, down.  So I just want to know if some way you were forced to cut price because of competition, but not because your products were too expensive and not just because of commodity impact. And what needs still to be done to reposition your portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  You look at the last quarter, let me just take the last quarter, which obviously carries the full effect of the price adjustments made early in the year, but they're not really any more price adjustments in the quarter itself.  We had thought we would perhaps increase prices a little bit more in the quarter, which we haven't done.  But the two to three percent is in line with what we told you, we were at the 3%.  If you look at it, our gross margins are actually up over 300 basis points, our A&amp;P is up over 250 basis points, and our margins are up over 100 basis points.  So, we are building the economic model and staying very competitive on all of the measures that you should be concerned about.  So, we have, especially in the categories where we have seen tremendous inflation, we have been fast to roll that back. And as in 2010, inflation might be coming back in some of the categories, especially over the second half, we should see prices going up again in 2010, although at a lower level in my opinion, although at a lower level.  But they will &#x2013; we will, I think we will have the maximum effect in this quarter, if I'm right, on the pricing component.</p>
          <p>Now, we will always adjust prices if that is needed for competitive activity, and it happens in some markets, but I wouldn't make that a drama. Broadly, our competitors are operating under the same model as us, to drive by innovation.  But it is true that in some markets there is increased competitive activity that we're dealing with, but I would not make that a big part of what we're doing here. But you're seeing here really in the last quarter is no further price adjustments, yet significantly increased competitive activity. And yet we're able to not only hold to our business, but grow our business in that environment profitably.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My second question was related to A&amp;P. We've seen a step up quarter-to-quarter in '09.  What kind of split are we going to have like for next year?  And in terms of businesses, which businesses deserve more or in which &#x2013; what kind of effort you need to make in each businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  You will see the A&amp;P, we're not going to give it by quarter for next year, nor am I too worried about that.  Obviously, we look at it in our rolling 18 months forecast.  But I'm not so worried about the quarters, because it might be that we have a quarter that we have a lot of A&amp;P and that our operating margin is down in that quarter, but we run it on a year like I did this year.  I will do the same next year and I almost unashamedly will explain that to you, but we will invest behind our innovations and sometimes these innovations fall slightly differently.  Most of our brands have -- in fact, all of our brands have an increased innovation pipeline.  And I would expect the A&amp;P increase that we see in 2010 to be broadly across the board. It's not really skewed towards one or the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  It's Warren Ackerman at Evolution.  I had a question on the net debt. The net debt number looked very, very good, driven by extremely good cash flow for the year.  The question is what was the actual working capital change in the year?  And secondly, how much further upside is there on working capital, because when I look at you versus your payers on working capital to sales, it already looks top quartile?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I appreciate that, Warren, because it is absolutely outstanding work from this organization.  Our starting point was competitive and yet we have made a step change of about &#x20AC;1.4 billion, so in working capital.  And without going into the details of that and all the ratios that you know, it's actually brought across all of the elements of working capital and it's not just done by driving the end of the quarter position either.  So we've seen good improvement in inventory days that have come down, where I think we still have further possibility.  We have seen good improvements in both accounts receivables and accounts payables.  And but having said that, we don't think it's finished yet, and we will continue in our compensation plans to have working capital as a component of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean structurally, do you think this is a business that could be working capital negative as a percentage of sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some people would believe that. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon Marshall-Lockyer from Jefferies.  You still don't seem to be fully satisfied with the progress made in India with Hindustan Lever.  Can you give us maybe more detail of what you're doing with Hindustan Lever? Competitive trends are increasing quite sharply there, both from the domestic competition and from the international competition.  Can you tell us, maybe give us more detail of what's going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's obviously clear that India is all of a sudden on the map of everybody and since Vindi Banga got all the awards from the Indian Government, everybody is now looking to India.  In fact, Vindi got just recognized, I have to say, got the highest award from the Indian Government for the services to India and as a very respected Indian abroad. And so I want to congratulate Vindi.  I know he doesn't like that, that I do this publicly but it is a great honor that he just achieved.  And it is not surprising that India is increasingly on the map of many other countries which the Indian economy increasingly looking better as well. And in fact the population in India will overtake the population of China in the not too distant future.</p>
          <p>So we've always been in India, a long history in India. We entered there in the early 1900s and actually have established very strong share positions.  Now, for us what is more important, obviously we like to maintain these share positions or grow them, but the markets are growing as well and our overall Indian business is growing.  Again, there is no doubt about it.  But in some of the categories, notably skin and laundry we are still losing a little bit of share.  In 75% of the categories, we are gaining share.</p>
          <p>What has happened really in India, if you want to be -- give you the two minute spiel, is when the input costs went up so much, especially on the food side, etcetera, we had to take our prices up. And then frankly a lot of local competitors entered, local and regional. Just to take laundry and cleaning products, we saw over 500 regional or local competitors, personal cleansing and laundry alone, in India.  So, we got attacked from the bottom of the market.  As you have a longer supply chain, prices have to come down. When these commodity costs eased, it took us longer to get that implemented.</p>
          <p>We're also making some changes to the sales and go to market structure that probably weren't helpful to be doing at the same time.  The good thing is there was some certain level of modesty, we have learned from that.  We've taken corrective actions.  So our businesses are growing again.  You've seen the last results from Lever Hindustan, which were announced separately, so our business is growing again, 75% of them are growing share and obviously we're pleased about that.  But we continue to work our laundry business where you now have not only local competitors, but also branded competitors. And the same is true for our skin business, where we are growing again, but not yet growing share.  And obviously we are focused on that.  We have one of the, I would say, highest innovation and renovation rates of any country, in India. And I prioritize that again to get back to solid footing.  Do you want to add to that, or.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I could.  Just very briefly to underline what Paul has said.  I was there personally for a couple of days to look at the market situation, category positions, and I must say I've come back feeling very quietly confident of the extent of our innovation and renovation program.  It's very broad.  It's in all our categories.  And it's very deep across all the brands that we cover there.  So I think we should see a better performance and a competitive one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it will continue to be a competitive market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you expect to start growing market share in this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the indicator is not only market share. You have to be a little bit careful, because when we talk market share, if I may be honest and I give you my opinion, but take it, whether it's a Unilever's opinion, I'll not take that for granted .  Globally we look at gaining share. But in a country that is a developing country, if you have a 90% share, I'd rather have a 60% share of a market that is 10 times bigger than a 90% share of a small market.  So when we have these in transpositions in these emerging markets and very high shares, it might be that the market growth is faster and our share comes slightly down.  So let's not get totally hang up on the share story there.  You need to look at the overall business story in those cases. Now that's not an excuse at all. We need to grow India again and we need to grow it consistently, and we are focused on that.  But it will continue to be a market where I expect a competitive battle for some years to come to take place.  We will take one more question here and then we have one still to not short circuit the people calling in.  Yeah, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The first question is on Western European margin. Your margin now down 240 basis point in 2009 and you kind of mentioned about 80 basis point worth A&amp;P reinvestment taking it more or less.  So there was effectively negative operating leverage, higher input costs, some of those negatives will become positive next year.  So how do we look at past recovery on margin in Western Europe? Shall we be optimistic or do you think that you'll still have upfront reinvestment to be made there?  The second question is I would like to understand from Pier Luigi Sigismondi, he has been nine months in the job what he feels what his perspective on the business, and maybe all the good projects he want to talk about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we'll certainly give him the floor in a second.  If I, perhaps you said it or I misunderstood it, but our total margin in Europe at the end of the year is 14 &#x2013; I'm readiing it here, 14.4 versus the total company 14.8.  So it's not that we are in Europe running with too much of a margin gap.  The issue in Europe was it was managed for profit, not for growth.  So we are managing it for growth again.  And I'm pretty comfortable with the margins we have and we don't expect that to be significantly different from the company's average margin, plus or minus 20 or 30 basis points obviously, which is the margin of error we operate in.</p>
          <p>Now that's good performance for Europe, because 70% of the European business actually or slightly less than 70% is in food, which tends to operate with a little bit of a lower margin, if we like that or not.  So that's the reality of the mix that we have for now, with Sara Lee and over time and some other things that might change, but that's where we are now.  So frankly, if you want my honest opinion is where we came from from Europe was not sustainable for long-term value creation and it actually that was the case.  You might have been happy with these higher margins in Europe, but you certainly didn't get the shareholder return.  Now you get the growth at admittedly margins more in line with the company, but it is building shareholder value for the long-term.  So it's a good thing. <mark type="inaudible" /> We have Pier Luigi, you want to say a few words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think it is an energizing agenda.  We have really a supply chain that is really best-in-class and we're integrating ourselves with the business as well, consumers and customers being at the center of the strategies that we have.  And very much about driving value more than just cost reduction.  So everything is in place for us to keep delivering value as we integrate ourselves with the business and play more globally as well.  So very energized about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks Pier Luigi.  We'll take one question from the call-in, because we're short circuited  them a little bit. I apologize for that, and then we'll break up and we can continue after that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anybody out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, is there a question still, on the people listening in on the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are waiting a long time, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you're through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, well done. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, good morning.  Pierre Tegner from Oddo Securities.  I have two questions.  The first question is concerning market share gains and significant improvements from <mark type="inaudible" /> during the past quarters?  Are you estimating and are you feeling that you are <mark type="inaudible" />  confident with this fall in growth recovery and market share gains.  To think that you've gained some pricing power during the past few months and are you willing in the coming months to use this gain of pricing power to offset higher commodity cost base you would have to face in 2010?</p>
          <p>And the second question is concerning the calculation of operating margin leverage on your volume growth.  Could you help us in the calculation by disclosing the <mark type="inaudible" /> effect you had on margin improvements for the full year '09 or for the Q4 '09?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you got the last part, I didn't get the last part...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You got the last part, James.  Sorry, I couldn't hear the last one.  On the first part of market share, the market shares actually are broadly across the board.  And as I said, most of the categories, 14 out of our 16 categories that we're looking at are growing.  If you look at our brands, 10 out of this 13 brands that we're looking at were growing. Our MCOs, which are now the clusters running it, and we look at the combined shares of the clusters.  We have 16 out of 24 of those clusters growing.  As I said, if you look at the cells, two-thirds of the cells are growing share.  So the growth is broad based and it is a function of the A&amp;P and innovations once more.  So our equities are getting stronger, because our relative price position hasn't changed.  So you have to conclude that your equities are getting stronger.  Now, having been in this business for about 30 years now, you just don't get all your results within six or nine months.  We need to continue to invest in our brands the way we're doing for the next two to three years to really get to the levels that we aspire to.  This is not just a six months game that we're after and I continue to stress that.</p>
          <p>I do believe though that we are in a good position with our brands.  In 2008, when we moved prices up, up to 9% at the end of the year -- never seen that before in my 30 years -- we maintained volume. Don't forget that.  When people were saying Unilever and their brands don't have much pricing power, we were well ahead of the industry, earlier and more.  You might say too much, I agree.  But we were earlier and more and we ended up the year with more or less flat volume, 0.2%.  When I came in, it gave me confidence because it's said there are something on the underlying strengths of our brands.  And I've -- since I entered over the last 12 months only got more and more confirmation of that.</p>
          <p>So as we continue to strengthen our brands, as we put our money behind our innovations, as we strengthen our equities to do that, I also expect us to be able to price and stay competitive, but to be able to price behind commodity increases that we do expect again over the second half of the year. And as a result, end into positive pricing territory over the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>I will let James answer the second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Pierre you didn't come through all that clearly, but I think what you were getting at was what is the operational leverage benefit that we get from improved volume.  And just as a kind of rule of thumb, other things being equal, 1% on volume growth should give you something on the order of 30 basis points of operating margin.  Of course it's never quite as straightforward as that, because usually you're spending money, supporting the brand, improving your product quality, so it's very difficult to kind of be very precise about this.  But as a rule of thumb, that's what we use.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> and my question was what should have been the margin improvement <mark type="inaudible" /> and excluding effect for the full year '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't run the business on that basis.  It sounds like it's algebra.  And so, we're very happy with where our margin ended up.  In the year we're strongly ahead in quarter four, ahead of where we set ourselves the target at the beginning of the year Pierre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks Pierre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks to everybody.  I appreciate the time you spent with us this morning and engaged in the discussions.  For the ones that are here, I invite you to have a drink next door still.  We have our wonderful Lipton brands there.  We have our wonderful ice creams, try a little bit of a Klondike or the new Magnum. And for the first time for the men also, we'd be happy to share with you the Dove for Men, one of the leading products breakthrough, so that we only, that we not only satisfy the women with our Pond's and other products, but finally get these guys to smell and look a little bit better.  So thanks for your time this morning and hopefully see you soon again.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>