<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1279435" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-01-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>516</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Stephen J. Hemsley, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Scott Fidel</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Gail Boudreaux</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Christine Arnold</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Carl McDonald</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">G. Mike Mikan</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Kevin Fischbeck</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Matthew Borsch</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Rick Jelinek</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Justin Lake</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Charles Boorady</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">John Rex</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep">Dawn Owens</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Ana Gupte</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Doug Simpson</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Brian Wright</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, I will be your conference facilitator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the UnitedHealth Group fourth quarter and full year 2009 earnings conference call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question and answer period. <mark type="Operator instructions" /> For purposes of getting to as many participants as possible, we also ask those participants with questions to limit to one question per person. As a reminder this conference is being recorded. This call and its contents are the property of UnitedHealth Group. Any use, copying or distribution without written permission from UnitedHealth Group is strictly prohibited.</p>
          <p>Here is some important introductory information. This call will reference non-GAAP amounts. A reconciliation of non-GAAP to GAAP amounts is available on the financial reports and SEC filings at the company's investor page at www.unitedhealthgroup.com. This call contains forward-looking statements under the US federal securities laws. Such statements are subject to risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from historical experience or present expectation. A description of some of the risks and uncertainties can be found in the reports that we filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission from time to time including the cautionary statements included in our current and periodic filings. Information presented on this call is contained in the earnings release we issued this morning and in our form 8-K dated January 21, 2010, which may be accessed from the investor page of the company's website at www.unitedhealthgroup.com. I would now like to turn the conference over to the President and Chief Executive Officer of UnitedHealth Group, Mr. Stephen Hemsley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for joining us. Today we will focus our commentary on three key areas, 2009 financial performance and our early 2010 outlook, our progress against some key market-facing themes discussed with you over the last two years and lastly some thoughts about market needs and requirements going forward.</p>
          <p>The results from Massachusetts on Tuesday may have affected the legislative outlook and we're not going to comment on the outcome of health reform today. Whatever the result, we continue to believe that the heart of the issue is a need to thoughtfully stage comprehensive efforts around controlling costs and modernizing the health system in order to expand and sustain access to affordable health. We will do our best to make whatever changes which may be enacted successful to appropriately control costs, modernize and simplify the system and to improve access to affordable quality care in this country.</p>
          <p>As you read in our release this morning, the performance momentum that steadily progressed over 2009 continued in the fourth quarter. We reported solid fourth quarter results with earnings per share of $0.81 and operating cash flows of $1.3 billion. All key performance metrics for the quarter were in line or improved relative to our expectations.</p>
          <p>Full year 2009 results included just over $87 billion in revenues or 7% year over year growth. Earnings of $3.24 per share and cash flows from operations of 5.6 billion improved year over year by 10% and 16% respectively. Cash flows were 1.5 times net earnings.</p>
          <p>We managed through many unforeseen obstacles to achieve these results, including significantly higher unemployment trends, anemic short-term investment yields, the H1N1 outbreak, slower buy behaviors in the market for health services, COBRA benefit extensions and unexpected state [tax] actions on insurance premiums and more.**</p>
          <p>The performance drivers in the quarter were consistent with those throughout the year, disciplined commercial pricing supported by better product positioning market to market, steady and effective management of medical and operating costs, strong membership growth and market share gains across public and senior products and markets, and double digit percentage revenue growth in our services businesses. We see many of these performance drivers carrying forward into 2010.</p>
          <p>While we're pleased to have exceeded our financial commitments in 2009, we're equally encouraged by our advances throughout 2009 in key areas where we are demonstrating our ability to better serve people, which enhances our potential for growth in 2010 and beyond.</p>
          <p>In 2009, satisfaction levels improved meaningfully for every key constituency, consumers, physicians and care providers, employers and benefit sponsors, brokers and consultants. Our proactive engagement with regulators, medical societies and elected officials also had a meaningful and positive impact in 2009. Service and response metrics, processing and response accuracy all improved steadily each quarter.</p>
          <p>Integration efforts advanced. Some 93% of our total commercial, public and senior membership now resides on end-state operating platforms. That percentage should be 95% by the end of 2010. These are impactful advances and we'll continue to be unrelenting in our dedication to service and fundamental execution discipline.</p>
          <p>Our commitment to practical innovation over the past year or more resulted in the introduction of the Diabetes Health Plan, the consumer activation index, the personalized health score, the integrated eSync personalized care platform and our Connected Care tele-health program. We have advanced our clinically integrated premium networks across 20 clinical specialties in the vast majority of our markets. We are piloting new types of physician incentives to support improved care and developing medical home programs in more settings than any other payer, including the government.</p>
          <p>UnitedHealthcare is benefiting from its work to more effectively translate local market insights to national level initiatives and conversely national imperatives into more effective local market execution. The results include stronger local market relationships, more effective local market deployment of new products, better recognition and response to serving local market needs and variations, all while steadily advancing national scale, productivity and cost advantages.</p>
          <p>We're consciously nurturing a more mature externally oriented culture and expanding our social responsibility agenda. You can see these reflected in our own employee engagement levels, advancing 600 basis points over the past 24 months, which portend well for continuing improved performance.</p>
          <p>Our health services businesses continued to steadily diversify. We edged into the next set of market adjacencies, including revenue and claim cycle management, consumer health change consulting services, global employee assistance and prescription decision support in Europe, while strengthening our position in electronic health records software.</p>
          <p>Through these efforts individually and as a whole, we believe we are steadily elevating the value we bring to our customers and markets and meaningfully strengthening the reputation of our company and our relationships with the people we serve. These efforts will continue. Collectively they are our fundamentals. We are committed to consistent execution and continuous improvement in these fundamentals quarter by quarter as we've been emphasizing for nearly two years.</p>
          <p>Our financial position also continues to strengthen. We have reduced our debt to total capital ratio by more than eight percentage points over the past 18 months to 32%. We recently announced a $750 million debt tender offer for a portion of our notes. This debt repurchase is expected to further improve our financial flexibility while reducing our net debt service cost in 2010.</p>
          <p>Before we discuss our respective health benefits and health services businesses, as we begin this new decade, it's worth looking back briefly. When we entered 2000, UnitedHealth Group revenues were just over $19 billion. On a gross revenue basis, our business was about 60% commercial benefits, 35% public and senior benefits and 5% health services.</p>
          <p>Entering 2010 we see over $90 billion of revenues with roughly 40% of gross revenues in commercial benefits, 40% in public and senior benefits and 20% in health services. And over the next decade we see opportunities to naturally diversify further into healthcare IT services, healthcare financial services, the deeper integration with primary care, the pursuit of international market settings and more.</p>
          <p>The scope of our business model is unique and allows us to look at healthcare market opportunities very broadly. This includes our view of the coming healthcare modernization era where we will pursue an opportunistic path and help enable change.</p>
          <p>In 2009, combined revenues in our health services businesses grew to $21.8 billion, a 13% year over year increase. Earnings from operations of $1.6 billion increased 20% over last year. The prime contributor to this growth was Prescription Solutions where revenues reached nearly $14.5 billion, a 15% year over year gain and pre-tax earnings grew an impressive 90% to $689 million.</p>
          <p>Ingenix grew strongly even in a challenging economic environment. Ingenix increased revenues 17% in 2009 to $1.8 billion and earnings from operations to nearly $250 million and this is after investing significant amounts in start-up efforts around payment and revenue cycle management, comparative effectiveness research, international markets and electronic health records.</p>
          <p>OptumHealth revenues grew by 6% in 2009 and delivered the best overall external growth year in its history. The continued decline in the UnitedHealthcare commercial enrollment obscured that external market growth and continued to impact OptumHealth's margin. New business from public sector customers tends to have lower margins than commercial risk products. That business mix dynamic should reverse as the overall commercial risk market strengthens.</p>
          <p>As we look across our health benefits businesses, 2009 played out largely in line with our original expectations, albeit somewhat weaker in commercial enrollment levels as national unemployment trends were more severe than we had anticipated. More than half of our 2009 commercial membership decline was driven by attrition. For the fourth quarter our commercial enrollment was slightly ahead of our Investor Day outlook, posting an underlying growth of 40,000 members before employment related attrition. The full year commercial decline was offset by stronger than expected growth in the Medicare and Medicaid market and we are positioned to expand our services in the military in early 2011.</p>
          <p>In total, health benefit revenues increased 7% to more than $81 billion. We effectively managed both medical and operating cost trends. These cost containment capabilities are becoming more mature and consistent, particularly as our benefit businesses become more integrated and simpler, using more shared services and common clinical care management processes.</p>
          <p>Turning to our early outlook. Momentum from 2009 is carrying through in our earliest 2010 indicators. We expect first quarter commercial membership to be slightly stronger than our Investor Day outlook. We should be flat to slightly positive in first quarter fee-based business, even after attrition. On the risk-based side we should come in slightly favorable to our prior guidance of a decrease of about 500,000 members in the first quarter. Attrition continues to run at a high level and will be a concern all year in this economy.</p>
          <p>Across our Medicare portfolio, more than 8 million consumers choose the UnitedHealth Group Medicare product in 2009. The recent enrollment period demonstrated once again the value of privately managed Medicare products to America's seniors. Going into the enrollment period there was considerable uncertainty about the Medicare Advantage program caused by benefit reductions, premium increases, plan closures and the ongoing healthcare reform debate. In spite of that uncertainty demand for Medicare Advantage plans industry-wide remained solid. Our Medicare Advantage business is expected to grow nicely for 2010. We attribute that growth to a focus on affordability, managing our portfolio of benefit offerings with a steady long-term view and our ability to adapt our plan offerings to the challenging rate environment.</p>
          <p>Seniors continue to recognize the real value of our Medicare Advantage products and have voted their conviction by trusting their healthcare to our plans and our strong network of quality providers. We expect first quarter net growth to be above 100,000 seniors in Medicare Advantage with strong mix towards the network based products and 225,000 Part D standalone participants. That is a stronger start than we originally expected in this sector and the Health Net Northeast acquisition will add further to our totals.</p>
          <p>First quarter Medicaid membership should grow in the area of 100 to 125,000 people, in line with our 2010 plan. Our services businesses are all stronger as we move into 2010 than when we entered 2009. And we're on track to achieve 2010 revenue growth plans here as well.</p>
          <p>We expect consolidated 2010 revenues to grow above $90 billion. We have reconfirmed our 2010 earnings outlook at $2.90 to $3.10 per share. That outlook does not include any proposed federal healthcare reform elements that could potentially be phased in this year. We believe this earning range to be appropriate given the Medicare and Medicaid rate pressures, the loss of Part D performance-based pricing of Prescription Solutions, ongoing COBRA costs and lower commercial membership levels going into the year.</p>
          <p>These headwinds will be strongest in the beginning of the year before any mitigating efforts can get full traction. And this pattern does not appear to be fully reflected in the first quarter consensus earnings estimates.</p>
          <p>For 2011 and beyond we will factor in business and market changes driven by healthcare reform and modernization, whether incremental or comprehensive. We believe coverage will expand and increasing healthcare costs will continue to make our work to promote access to quality care even more important.</p>
          <p>No matter what form change ultimately takes, there will continue to be very strong market demand for affordable quality care, demand that will create the next generation of growth in our markets. That future includes new ideas and committed actions around payments and incentives for quality care, development of integrated accountable care capability, transparency around quality and performance and paperless end to end defect free service, further innovation around product designs to achieve lower price points, a much stronger commitment to drive outcome based payment arrangements and a clear need in the seniors market for continuous improvement in total cost and values, which will encompass both operating and medical cost performance gains.</p>
          <p>There will be companies who will and &#x2013; who can and will respond to these needs and we intend to be one of them. Doing so will require the focus on fundamental execution and intelligent adaptation we described at Investor Day last month. We see that more than 300 million Americans will continue to need to get care and that this care needs to be intelligently coordinated, financed and delivered and documented across the system. Our goal is to be involved in that process through both our services businesses and our benefit businesses. In total there is an exceptional opportunity to build an enterprise that successfully serves these important social needs.</p>
          <p>We're interested in your questions this morning with the understanding that the health reform situation is very fluid and sensitive. As usual we'll ask that you limit yourself to one question topic today in deference to time and I thank you for your interest in UnitedHealth Group and we'll turn this over to the operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question will come from the line of Scott Fidel with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Could you just provide an update on the pricing environment that you're seeing at this point in commercial for both the risk-based market and then the ASO market just in terms of level of price competition you saw for 2010 renewals relative to last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Gail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Good morning, Scott. Let me start with the risk-based market. That market continues to be competitive. But I think as we've talked about, we've seen some firming in that market over the last couple of quarters and would expect to continue to see that type of activity. We've had a very disciplined approach and I think our ability to keep our medical cost trend very consistent and predictable and our ability to manage our medical costs has helped us with that level of consistency. On the self-funded side, again that market over the last several years from a fee-based perspective remains very competitive and again I think the story there is the same. We've had a very consistent approach and have not done anything traditionally different. As we look to 2010, based on the fee-based membership that we reported and we think it's going to be slightly positive and up in the first quarter, that's a fairly significant improvement for us year over year from 2009 to 2010 so that's some very good momentum for us. But from a pricing perspective, pretty consistent for us year over year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Gail, how would you just characterize the Blues on the risk pricing side for 2010 relative to 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the Blues, I think the answer is pretty consistent to what I said on the risk side, that we are seeing some pockets of rate increases obviously as they take their base rates up, but it is different geography to geography, but overall there is some firming going on there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from Christine Arnold with Cowen and Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Your PDP and Medicare enrollment are all poised to be better than you thought they'd be at Investor Day. You just said your fee-based revenue is going to be up, your commercial enrollment's going to be better than anticipated. Can you help us understand what offsets those such that you're not increasing guidance or is this just conservatism?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I would point out that it is January and let me then reaffirm kind of what I would say those headwinds are. This is kind of an economic environment that is unparalleled in our lifetime. We have meaningful rate pressures in the Medicare and Medicaid environment. We have a real loss of lock-in pricing in the Prescription Solutions business. We had a number of unforeseen obstacles at this time when we entered 2009 and we have no sense of what will be coming down the road. So I think it is quite early for us to offer any indication other than that environment hasn't changed from about a month ago when we had our Investor Day and that environment is quite challenging and I think that that is what we need to be conscious of. We have a lot of work to do in 2010 to hit the guidance that we've offered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Carl McDonald with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Some of the smaller private plans that I've talked with over the last couple of weeks have suggested that in their commercial business they think utilization is rising. When you look at your business, excluding to the extent you can, the flu, COBRA expenses, do you think the underlying base utilization based on your recent claims data is unchanged, up or down, any noticeable trend there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know maybe we should answer that kind of an enterprise-wide level, so maybe Mike, maybe you could -- and then if the other businesses want to add some color.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We really haven't seen any real change in underlying utilization. I would tell you though, we continue to be very focused on our clinical management programs. We've been talking about them for several years now and we're really starting to see traction there. So our utilization continues if you just look at commercial as an example to be flat to down. And we're seeing other favorabilities in the Medicare and AmeriChoice Medicaid book as well. I don't know what the rest of the market is seeing, but our underlying utilization continues to be stable to down from -- especially on the in-patient side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Kevin Fischbeck with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks. Good morning. Q4 favorable development for the current year looked higher than normal compared to prior years. Does that favorably impact the quarter or did you reaccrue and I guess what came in better for the first nine months than you were thinking? And then does that have any impact on your cost trend outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me try to answer it this way. Let me give you some context on our view of reserve development. First, as we've said for some time, our reserving methodology and processes remain consistent with prior years. Second, we continue to be proud of our ability to predict cost and estimate actual usage and I think that's evidenced by our prior year development in 2009 or 2008 in prior years was 0.5% of prior year medical costs, which we think is well within a normal range of variation.</p>
          <p>With respect to current year true-ups, there are several factors that have impacted our initial estimate between the quarters in 2009. First of all, we had significant growth in the government business, as you know, about 300,000 additional Medicare Advantage lives, 565,000 additional Medicaid lives. We've continued to see advancements as I just talked about in our clinical programs that as the data trues up, that starts to prove out to be favorable. The operational advancements that we've talked about over the last several quarters at our investor conference, you know, we've seen some of the best performance we've seen in the history of UnitedHealth Group and as that  performance continues to improve, as the data catches up to that, we've seen favorability.</p>
          <p>And then frankly just the volatility with the abnormal flu season, has created a fair amount of volatility in our reserve set. That's just to name a few. But overall we feel we've got good data and insight into all these items and are very comfortable with our 2009 full year estimates.</p>
          <p>And with your last question with respect to trend, we wouldn't change our outlook on trend at 8% plus or minus 50 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Matthew Borsch with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Could you just talk a little bit about the AmeriChoice business and if you can give us any sense geographically how that's running and what markets you're finding challenging or you expect to be challenging, particularly challenging in 2010 versus where you're having better results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd be happy to. I would point out that they have actually had perhaps their strongest year and really well positioned. So Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, we're coming off a very strong year as Steve mentioned and one of the strategic positioning points that we started on a couple of years ago was to diversify our portfolio so that we were not over relying on any single customer or product line. So from a outlook standpoint we feel really good about our current positioning and the breadth of our states and while some states will continue to face challenges going forward, we're working closely with those states on rates for the coming years. To date we have about 40% of our 2010 calendar year rate locked in and so we've got a little ways to go to get clear visibility on some of those other markets, but generally we feel relatively comfortable across the board.</p>
          <p>Now there's a couple markets that we'll watch closely in terms of assuring that revenue is meeting the medical trend requirements and if they're not, we'll take a closer look at working with the state on benefit designs or other structural changes to assure that these programs are working for the long-term and for in particular 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Justin Lake with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My question is on the impact reserves from the Health Net acquisition. You outline in the earnings release a $250 million increase in medical cost reserves due to the acquisition and I'm curious as to the driver of that. It's my understanding was that Health Net was going to be responsible for the run-off claims cost in that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Justin, without getting too much into the weeds on the transaction, that's a balance sheet as we acquired the legal entities, we assumed the balance sheet obligations. It gets trued up through a purchase agreement adjustment that they ultimately take the claim cost as long as it's on their book. So it's balance sheet transaction which ultimately gets trued up and we feel comfortable with that process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so there was no impact to the quarter specifically from any kind of increase or decrease in Health Net's reserves as you brought that on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it would net to zero. We don't see any benefit or detriment to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Charles Boorady with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. I wonder if you could comment a little bit on capital deployment. You alluded at your Investor Day to the potential to increase the dividend and you've brought debt to cap down 600 bips in the year and have significant cash at the parent. So we're clearly out of the credit crisis. I'm wondering if you can characterize for us how you plan to deploy the cash this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we described at the investor conference that we were through the course of 2009 really valuing financial flexibility and that's kind of been our path. I think we have made some meaningful inroads on that. We have made acquisitions also through the course of a year and would like to make sure that we're maintaining our financial flexibility, not only to invest internally in our business, but also for acquisitions. So I don't think there really has been any kind of change in our thinking along those lines, including as we said there, really evaluating whether a change in our dividend policy is appropriate and we said we would take that up as kind of the reform situation clarified. That's still in the mix obviously, but we expect there will be some clarity on that early this year. So Mike, do you have anything further? Does that get to your question Charles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So the debt to cap at around 32%, I mean should we think about it as being closer to 40% by a certain period in time or what point are you more comfortable with a higher leverage ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would just say broadly kind of on a more middle of the road kind of environment, 35%, something like that as a kind of a middle of the road suggestion. That can vary meaningfully between 30 and 40%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Charles, it's Mike. We are comfortable that the business, given the, in its current state again pre-health reform, not trying to predict either way on the impacts of health reform, but in its current state as we've said before we think that the business, it's our diversity, the growth aspect, the risk profile can support a higher debt leverage than where we're at today. We talked about that over time. We put out annual guidance based on what we know of ending the year somewhere between 30 and 33% debt to total cap and we're comfortable with that and with our current expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of John Rex with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. A question back on the UHC book and I'm thinking particularly about yields on both the risk and non-risk business. I guess just first, it looks like the commercial risk yield continued to strengthen in the 4Q and I guess as I'm thinking about the 2010, should we expect the effective yield, so that is kind of net of kind of product mix shift and as such to continue to strengthen like we've seen throughout 2009, maybe not at that pace, but continue to come in above that level? And then specifically on the ASO book, one of your competitors last week talked about lower PMPMs in the ASO business for 2010 as employers eliminate some specialty products and wondering if you are seeing that impact on your ASO book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John. Let me start with the premium yield question first. We're pricing on our risk business to our forward view of medical cost trends and as we look at our premium yields and you commented, those are tracking in line with our expectations. And I think the best judge of that is looking at the stability of the medical loss ratio as we've discussed over the last couple of calls. Once you adjust for COBRA and H1N1, which obviously were not predicted when we set that, so I think our philosophy and our approach has remained very consistent around our pricing and I think ultimately our yields and bottom line our medical costs ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So would it make sense we should expect those yields to continue to rise in 2010 then, like the, kind of this trajectory we've been seeing in '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we're pricing to what we believe is the forward view of costs. So our, again, it's the stability of the medical cost ratio that we're really tracking to. And I would point you back to our medical cost ratio that we shared with you at Investor Day, it's 83.8% plus or minus 50 basis points and I think within that range it gives you a good sense of our expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And John, I would actually say that we've seen some really good market response to the kinds of services that you're referring to. Maybe Dawn could comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John, Dawn Owens, OptumHealth. When we look at the employer market, we've had our strongest year ever 2009/2010 selling season with not only pipeline activity up in that market across the board in all the services we offer, financial clinical care management, wellness, behavioral health. But we've translated that at a higher rate into closes actually with a 25% conversion rate on closure. That is both in partnership with UnitedHealthcare on an integrated basis, as well as an independent cross-carrier externally focused agenda. So we're actually seeing very strong demand for the services and a marketplace that is interested in productivity, health, wellness in ways that we can offer. So we feel very actually good about that market and have diversified well into it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So net-net all that on your ASO book, would you expect your PMPM revenue to not be worse than flat in 2010 over 2009 when you think about &#x2013; so you &#x2013; it sounds like you're saying you haven't seen attrition off those specialty products. So is that a fair assumption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our expectation is our revenue would be relatively flat. So our penetration rates have remained fairly stable. John, this is Gail Boudreaux.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And John keep in mind that we're talking about two different businesses. So OptumHealth's direct employer business also has different and additional revenue streams in that large employer marketplace which would account for this additional external growth that we talked about within OptumHealth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Optum had more external, its external growth here is, 2009 was probably as fast and its pipeline is probably its strongest level. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Ana Gupte with Sanford C. Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. While I understand you cannot comment on the outcome of reform, as you are doing your scenario planning internally, has that changed or would it change your view on the various portfolio of businesses that you have? So health benefits versus health services, domestic versus international? And may commercial relative to Medicaid and then consolidation for capabilities relative to horizontal consolidation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's a really &#x2013; it's an excellent question. But I'd step back a few years and put kind of reform to the side and say if you really look at the markets in terms of what the compelling needs of the markets are relative to benefits and relative to services, and how the market needs to be brought along to a more kind of what I'd say modern state and the demand for more services and a more seamless integration of services all thrown in with the kind of consumer trends that have actually been building over the last 10 years, that is what we have been responding to. That's how we have positioned our existing portfolio of businesses and there are common core elements of what reform is trying to get at. So if you just put that aside and took a look at the core fundamental market needs, that's what we're responding to. They align with reform because of the same issues and challenges.</p>
          <p>So the answer to that is we wouldn't change it at all. We think that the construct has been really built for that kind of response, which is why we feel we can position ourselves somewhat differently and we're going to continue that pattern. So we &#x2013; you have seen over the course of the last year steps into natural market adjacencies and I think you can expect to continue to see that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Doug Simpson with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks, good morning. Steve, could you just talk a little bit about given the challenging economy, healthcare costs continue to clip along at -- ahead of wage growth. And given the unemployment situation, what are you guys seeing from customers in terms of pressure to help deal with rising costs? Has there been a heightened awareness of it? And I guess along those lines, how do you guys think about in-patient pricing strategy and looking out a year or two, any read on potential direction of benefit structures more broadly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it is all about cost and there is, you know, business operators are looking at, they are committed to their benefits. They are looking at optimizing those benefits and staying with them and trying to get a better cost outcome. That's actually been partly why there has been a good response in terms of more of the care management programs, the dedicated kinds of programs like diabetic health plans, etcetera, because those are effective tools at getting at, in an appropriate way, a better cost outcome for their dollars.</p>
          <p>So that is really where they have really been working. They have been, to the extent they have a broad portfolio of different benefit types across their companies, they have been trying to rationalize those benefit types. They have been just trying to manage their programs and get at cost and to engage their employees because they also recognize that it is the consumption patterns that is driving a significant portion of their trend and they think that they can influence those consumption patterns in a very positive way and a positive way for the health of their people. That's really where it is &#x2013; those discussions are very, very consistently company to company. And that is why we have been really driving our clinical programs, as Mike talked about utilization management and so forth. These companies want to see demonstrated performance along those lines and that's where our themes have been. Gail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just adding to Steve's comments, I think there are three core themes that our largest customers and across our book are looking at. One is managing their total cost. I think it's been very important to them this year. The second is improving the health status of their members so getting more value for the dollars that they spend. And the third I'd say is getting consumers more actively engaged in their program. We have had some very good momentum in the marketplace because our programs directly address that. Things like our consumer activation index that we shared with you.</p>
          <p>On the provider side, we're very focused on making sure that we're paying for cost and quality so our premium designation network where we're trying to steer more of our members through plan design and incentives. The second area that I'd point to is we have a number of initiatives around patients that are in medical homes where as Steve said in his early comments, have more of those than anyone else in the country, including the government, and we are tracking the results of those very closely.</p>
          <p>The diabetic health plan would be the third I would point to. We introduced that a little less than a year ago and have seen wonderful uptake from our customers because it's a very focused program that drives results in a targeted population. So those are really the themes that employers are looking at and again it's around managing total cost but driving better quality and outcomes for their health for the population of their employees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, next.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question will come from the line of Brian Wright with Collins Stewart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Is there any potential impact on your bank from the deposit tax? The proposed deposit tax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't think so. Well, we don't think that those accounts are subject to that tax. But we'll &#x2013; you can sense a lack of surety here so what we'll do is we'll follow up and make sure that we get back to you with a more confident answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess that concludes our, the questions in line. In closing we'd like to just quickly sum up that we think UnitedHealth Group delivered a relatively strong financial performance in 2009 despite a difficult economy. In addition to meeting our financial commitments, the business has continued to steadily advance in service, innovation, scale, national scale and local responsiveness and to continue to diversify. We're entering 2010 we think as a operating enterprise much stronger than the beginning of 2009. We're respectful of the challenges that we're facing in 2010. And we think we're really positioned well for the next generation of growth over the next several years to come. So thank you very much for your attention this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude today's teleconference. You may all disconnect.</p>
          <p>**Editor's Note: Though it was not said in the call, [tax] has been inserted in the last sentence of page 1 as per UnitedHealth Group's request.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>