<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1202454" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-01-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>516</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Stephen J. Hemsley, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Scott Fidel</participant>
      <participant id="3">Stephen Hemsley</participant>
      <participant id="4">Gail Boudreaux</participant>
      <participant id="5">G. Mike Mikan</participant>
      <participant id="6">Rick Jelinek</participant>
      <participant id="7">Joshua Raskin</participant>
      <participant id="8">Gregory Nersessian</participant>
      <participant id="9">Dawn Owens</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Penshorn</participant>
      <participant id="11">Matthew Borsch</participant>
      <participant id="12">Justin Lake</participant>
      <participant id="13">Charles Boorady</participant>
      <participant id="14">Simon Stevens</participant>
      <participant id="15">Carl McDonald</participant>
      <participant id="16">Michael Baker</participant>
      <participant id="17">Mitchell Zamoff</participant>
      <participant id="18">Ana Gupte</participant>
      <participant id="19">John Rex</participant>
      <participant id="20">Peter Costa</participant>
      <participant id="21">Sheryl Skolnick</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  My name is Dennis, and I will be your conference facilitator today.  At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the UnitedHealth Group Fourth Quarter and Full Year 2008 Earnings Conference Call.   <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> This call and its contents are the property of UnitedHealth Group.  Any use, copying, or distribution without written permission from UnitedHealth Group is strictly prohibited.</p>
          <p>Here is some important introductory information.  This call will reference non-GAAP amounts.  A reconciliation of non-GAAP to GAAP amounts is available on the Financial Reports and SEC Filings section of the company's Investor page at www.unitedhealthgroup.com.</p>
          <p>This call contains forward-looking statements under US Federal Securities Laws.  Such statements are subject to risk and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from historical experience or present expectations.  A description of some of the risk and uncertainties can be found in the reports that we filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission from time to time, including the cautionary statements included in our current and periodic filings.  Information presented on this call is contained in the earnings release we issued this morning and in our Form 8-K dated January 22, 2009, which may be accessed from the Investors page of the company's website at www.unitedhealthgroup.com.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to the President and Chief Executive Officer of UnitedHealth Group, Stephen Hemsley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and thank you for joining us.  Today we are pleased to report UnitedHealth Group's fourth quarter and full year 2008 results.</p>
          <p>For the full year 2008, revenues increased $5.8 billion, or 8%, to $81.2 billion, and our fourth quarter revenues increased 9%, to $20.5 billion.  In the fourth quarter, we added nearly 100,000 people in our Benefits businesses. Our adjusted fourth quarter operating margin of 7.9% was in line with our expectations, with some out-performance on the consolidated medical care ratio of 80.8%, offset by a slightly elevated operating cost ratio of 15.4% as adjusted. Earnings were $0.78 per share for the quarter, and $2.95 per share for the full year, both adjusted for special items.</p>
          <p>I should mention upfront that these earnings numbers do not include $50 million, or almost $0.03 per share, in venture capital investment write-downs in the fourth quarter which was not in our outlook. The adjusted results exclude an accrued $350 million, or $0.18 per share, in operating cost to resolve class action litigations related to out-of-network medical services from early 1994 to date, as we announced just last week.  We believe it is clearly in the best interest of our company to resolve these matters and move forward.</p>
          <p>Adjusted cash flow from operations were $4.8 billion for the year, including a strong $1.6 billion for the fourth quarter, and I am pleased to report that full year adjusted cash flows were a healthy 1.3 times adjusted net income and in line with the range we provided last July.</p>
          <p>Stepping back, against the economic turbulence of the last year, these are encouraging results for our business overall.  In 2008, we have seen advances in many important initiatives, including our efforts to improve fundamental execution and instill a strong service culture, and we progressed in building deeper and richer market relationships with the people we serve and the physicians we work with in the healthcare community.</p>
          <p>On the Benefits side of our enterprise, UnitedHealthcare's business continues to strengthen internally against a challenging economic backdrop, and is in line with our previously stated expectations.  Ovations had a successful sales and marketing season during this fourth quarter enrollment period, and our AmeriChoice Medicaid business continues to grow in the markets we serve, and is successfully expanding into new programs and geographies. As you might expect, some of our services businesses are feeling some effect from the broader economic pressures.  However, the pressing interest in healthcare affordability, quality, information technology, should also open up new opportunities for these businesses.</p>
          <p>As we look to the year ahead, we continue to project earnings per share between $2.90 and $3.15 for full year 2009, and cash flow from operations are expected to be approximately $5 billion.  The ranges in our outlook remain wide, but the economic uncertainties of 2009 remain as well.</p>
          <p>Our financial position is strong.  We have been careful stewards of our resources, and our operating cost and capital control efforts that started early in 2008 will continue in their intensity.  And as we discussed at our Investor Conference in December, we are fully engaged participants in the health reform movement.  We bring deep experience, broad industry expertise, and diverse capabilities to this discussion.  We have been meeting with a variety of stakeholders and emphasizing the need to reform all aspects of health and healthcare if we're to achieve affordable, quality healthcare for all.</p>
          <p>We would like to begin the business review by giving you more detail for the quarter and full year for our Benefits businesses, which include UnitedHealthcare, Ovations, and AmeriChoice. Earnings from operations for these businesses were $1.3 billion for the fourth quarter, and $5.1 billion for the full year 2008, all fully in line with our expectations.  As expected, UnitedHealthcare risk-based enrollment decreased by 135,000 people in the fourth quarter, while our fee-based business again performed in a solid fashion, growing 10,000 people in a period where there is more limited growth opportunities and increasing attrition levels.  We continue to expect UnitedHealthcare 2009 enrollment to decrease by 1 million to 1.5 million people in total, depending upon the severity of the recession, with decreases in both risk- and fee-based benefit categories.  First quarter fee-based enrollment is expected to decrease in the area of 500,000 people.  While we are still gathering final January results, this should hold, supported by very strong growth from our expanded relationships with the State of Georgia.</p>
          <p>We continue to expect the first quarter 2009 organic decline in risk-based membership to be slightly better than 2008, but in the same general range, even as we work intently to strengthen our underwriting discipline in the Small Group market and fully priced for expected medical cost trend.  We are operating with stronger market relationships and greater agility at the local market.  The economy remains a challenge, and we have limited visibility today into January group terminations and employee participation levels.  That said, we do have local markets where we are seeing growth for the first time in two years or more, and we are excited by the interest employers are showing for our innovation around health personalization and the concept of building communities of health.</p>
          <p>Turning to medical costs, we are in a solid position.  Cost trends remain in line with our expectation.  Our emphasis on regional leadership and rebuilding local relationships is helping us to work more effectively with physicians, hospitals, and healthcare providers to keep costs under control for our customers.</p>
          <p>The UnitedHealthcare medical care ratio was 83.9% in the fourth quarter, slightly better than our most recent projection and 20 basis points better than the fourth quarter of 2007.  We have moved forward in &#x2013; as we move forward in 2009, we can confidently tell you that UnitedHealthcare's performance is strengthening on many dimensions.  We will continue to dedicate resources and strong leadership to local market, build better provider relationships market by market, and leverage the momentum in service improvement and fundamental execution established throughout 2008.  This better balance of local engagement and focus in each market, combined with our national scale, clinically integrated network, and technology capabilities, we hope will continue to lead to profitable growth over the long term.</p>
          <p>Moving to our Public and Senior Markets group, which includes Ovations and AmeriChoice, we added 220,000 people with medical benefits in the fourth quarter.  This was sharply above our expectations due to strong Medicaid growth and consistent performance in senior products.  We had total organic growth of 650,000 people in 2008, a growth rate of 12%.</p>
          <p>Our Ovations senior health benefits businesses are in the midst of a very successful selling season.  Ovations Medicare Advantage is on course to exceed the upper end of the range of 100,000 to 135,000 net new seniors for full year 2009.  We estimate we've gained more than 120,000 new members for January 1, net of terminations, and importantly, the mix of this growth by product type is clearly better than last year and in line with our 2009 plan.  We are seeing steady interest in HMO and PPO products and a lift in private-fee-for-service versions, driven by both significant corporate group sales and individual retail participation.  These results also include a net reduction of 7,000 people for January 1 in chronic care special needs plans. Medicare Supplement sales also continue to perform well, and finally, we are tracking to exceed our growth plan of 100,000 to 125,000 seniors in the standalone Part D drug benefit market this year.</p>
          <p>Very strong early performance in Ovations is driven by improvements in sales, marketing and distribution, product positioning, and local market engagement.  We are seeing improved balance and sizable gains year-over-year from all principal distribution channels, including external brokers, affiliated representatives, telesales, and internal sales professionals.  While there may be some upside to our Medicare Advantage growth forecast, we will wait to receive additional data, including confirmation of our estimates of terminations, and to watch performance in the remaining open enrollment period, before updating our outlook.</p>
          <p>The consolidation and integration of Ovations' in-market care management with the UnitedHealthcare's local care management resources and programs is beginning to translate into stronger medical cost management for these businesses.  We expect this to be an important element in Ovation's performance improvements in 2009 and for 2010.</p>
          <p>We've been very pleased with the strong advances AmeriChoice made throughout 2008, including their outstanding performance in the fourth quarter. Total Medicaid membership grew by 175,000 people this quarter, bringing total expansion for 2008 to more than 800,000 people.  We continue to expect growth of 325,000 to 400,000 people in 2009, which is a mid-teens membership growth rate.  This includes the last significant piece of the one-quarter million new people that we are in the process of adding as part of the expansion of services in Tennessee, and unemployment pressures could potentially increase these AmeriChoice numbers as the year progresses.</p>
          <p>There's been a lot of market speculation about SCHIP expansion.  This is now moving very quickly, and I believe no company is better positioned to serve an expanded SCHIP mandate. In AmeriChoice, we have a significant, dedicated, and capable business that leverages the best of the entire UnitedHealth Group enterprise, and we offer on-the-ground services in 22 states and serve more Medicaid program participants today than any market competitor.</p>
          <p>So summarizing across the Benefits businesses, we have a meaningfully improved start in 2009, supported by solid and diversified organic growth, and a higher quality business mix.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to our Services businesses, which include OptumHealth, Ingenix, and Prescription Solutions.  They all serve the healthcare marketplace broadly and are a consistent source of innovation and thought leadership inside and outside UnitedHealth Group.  Their capabilities are a large part of our overall diversification and make us a more adaptable organization for a changing healthcare marketplace.</p>
          <p>For the full year, on a combined basis, these businesses generated $19.4 billion in aggregate revenues, and $1.3 billion in total earnings from operations, with fourth quarter revenues of 4.9 billion, and total earnings from operation of 330 million.  This quarter, we saw the continued impact of UnitedHealthcare's unfavorable risk-based membership trend in OptumHealth.  We also saw reduced demand at Ingenix for CRO consulting services and coding and reference material.</p>
          <p>Operating margins for the year declined for both OptumHealth and Ingenix.  On the other hand, Prescription Solutions' margin strengthened, increasing 90 basis points year-over-year to 2.9%, driving 35% year-over-year growth in operating earnings in 2008, as Prescription Solutions continues to realize the benefits of larger scale and improved generic and mail order fulfillment performance.</p>
          <p>The economic climate is presenting our Services businesses with both opportunities and challenges.  Pressures on both government sponsors and employer groups are creating new opportunities for Ingenix Consulting and Prescription Solutions to apply their technology and their innovative approaches to help control cost and manage care more effectively.</p>
          <p>We're seeing increased interest at OptumHealth in freestanding care management and wellness  prevention services, as market interest in more intensive cost management and affordability once more returns.  While OptumHealth clearly continues to be impacted by membership losses at its largest customer, UnitedHealthcare, this impact will reverse as our Benefit businesses strengthen. Furthermore, OptumHealth is meaningfully expanding its external revenues in its behavioral healthcare solutions and specialty benefit businesses.</p>
          <p>A clear example of this is within the public sector marketplace.  Two years ago, we identified public sector services as an opportunity for growth and diversification.  OptumHealth had distinctive capabilities to offer, and we had local market relationships throughout our enterprise, but our market share was unimpressive. With a renewed focus, we have now sold new business representing more than 2 million people over the past year.  We are implementing behavioral health benefits for the last piece of the more than one-half million participants we serve in TennCare.  We were awarded the Empire behavioral health benefits in New York State, serving 1.1 million people.  We recently received a mandate to finalize terms of the State of New Mexico to provide behavioral health benefits to another 400,000 people effective July 1, 2009, and just last week, we were awarded the contract to provide services to 50,000 people in Pierce County, Washington.  These market successes improve OptumHealth's balance and business diversity while adding operating earnings at margins that are fair and appropriate to public sector business.</p>
          <p>Ingenix is a significant supplier to the healthcare industry and is being impacted by economic and industry trends.  Spending on discretionary products and services is under pressure across the healthcare industry, and challenges facing the pharmaceutical industry are affecting spending on new product development and creating challenges for the CRO industry. At the same time, there's increasing demand in the government sector, in international markets, and in the electronic and medical records business.  In total, Ingenix has experienced some weakness in demand which has been partially mitigated by its broad product and market diversification.  Many of its offerings are attractive in this environment because they provide strong and rapid financial payback for clients.  As I'm sure you are aware, the Federal stimulus package will have a strong health IT element, and Ingenix should participate in that significant market expansion.</p>
          <p>Prescription Solutions continues to see growth in the demand for mail order pharmacy fulfillment, and its operations continue to mature.  We're making significant progress in our work to in-source specialty pharma services for all of UnitedHealth Group. In 2008, organic membership growth outside the UnitedHealth businesses exceeded 400,000 people, and in 2009, we expect Prescription Solutions will further develop its position in the industry as a full-line, large scale national pharmacy benefits manager.</p>
          <p>Bringing these trends and developments across the various businesses together, our outlook for 2009 remains in line with our most recent projections.  We anticipate revenues of 85 to $86 billion this year.  We see evidence of strengthening sales momentum, but we need further information on retention and business mix before we can make any changes to this forecast.</p>
          <p>We remain comfortable with our commercial medical cost trend outlook for 2009 at 8%, plus or minus 50 basis points.  We continue to forecast the consolidated medical care ratio in the range of 82.7%, plus or minus 50 basis points.  The year-over-year increase in this consolidated care ratio is due to anticipated changes in product and business mix favoring government markets.</p>
          <p>Adjusted operating costs, at 15.4% of revenues, increased slightly from the third quarter.  This included $80 million, or 40 basis points, of seasonal expenses, including marketing and new business installation costs, as well as some miscellaneous expense items such as an increase in general legal cost. Since the first quarter of 2008, we have reduced our operating cost by an annual run rate of roughly $470 million.  We have reinvested about 60 million of that run-rate reduction to strengthen our presence and responsiveness in local markets.  We clearly have opportunities for further reductions in areas such as better sharing of our administrative services across our businesses.  Operating cost management is critical to healthcare affordability, and we will continue to be a focus for us in 2009.</p>
          <p>While we no longer provide quarterly EPS guidance, we expect the first quarter of 2009 to reflect the seasonal decline for businesses such as Part D and Ingenix, as well as the effects of lower projected investment income on a year-over-year basis.  One would logically expect our year-over-year increase in the first quarter medical care ratio driven by business mix, and it appears a number of the more conservative first quarter earnings estimate on The Street are giving a fact to these factors.</p>
          <p>On the balance sheet and investment portfolio remains strength for our enterprise.  We reported a full year net realized capital loss of only $6 million on a $21.6 billion cash and investment portfolio, which is a virtually unique accomplishment in 2008. Our full year net realized loss of $6 million includes a fourth quarter realized $14 million net capital loss on our operating investments, and a prudent $50 million write-down on our approximately $200 million corporate venture capital portfolio.  Importantly, our net realized loss position on investments improved by $235 million in the quarter, to a net unrealized loss of only $47 million at December 31.  To put that number in context, that means we had a net unrealized loss of about 0.2% on our portfolio at year-end.</p>
          <p>Our unrestricted cash position improved by $765 million from September 30, to a balance of $865 million at year-end, even as we reduced our outstanding commercial paper to $101 million, from 586 million.  Looking over the past six months, we've decreased our leverage ratio by 230 basis points, from 40.4% at June 30 to 38.1% at year-end.  This more conservative leverage occurred even as we dispersed $900 million in the third quarter to fund the shareholder litigation settlement.</p>
          <p>In total, these results demonstrate UnitedHealth Group's strong and consistent operating cash generation.  We expect to have the capacity to repay the $900 million in term debt due this quarter without accessing the credit market if need be.  Our strong liquidity, cash position, cash flow, and investment portfolio will support our businesses during these challenging times and give us financial flexibility and strength.</p>
          <p>To sum up our operating trends, UnitedHealth Group's continuing to improve fundamental execution, service responsiveness, and in-market relationship dynamics for our customers, members, and the healthcare community at large.  Our improvements are gaining traction in the marketplace.  We continue to focus on translating our evolving culture of service into trusting relationships that will help differentiate us and enrich our market position.  We have determined to accelerate these improvement trends in 2009.</p>
          <p>We continued to steward our resources wisely.  We are controlling cost and reducing non-essential spending, with a slower capital spending pace than last year overall.  We've always been a leader in innovation and we intend to pick up the pace, with a concentration on bringing simpler consumer and provider innovations profitably to market, innovations that are cost effective, that enhance the personalization of healthcare, and that are practical.  That means innovations that change healthcare for the better, cost less to develop, and can be introduced with less overall disruption.</p>
          <p>Let me give you some quick examples.  We pioneered a diabetes health plan for the commercial market.  The plan is tailored to the unique needs of diabetics, and importantly pre-diabetics, and links them to the best resources, the best science, so they can control their condition and live healthier lives while reducing employer cost.  The diabetes health plan is just one example of our new family of personalized condition-specific benefit offerings for the self-funded market.</p>
          <p>We are also helping employers with our proprietary Consumer Activation Index.  This Index measures consumer decision making across key decision points and helps employers specifically target opportunities to improve health, wellness, and cost in their employee base.  For example, we can identify an issue with preventative screening rates for females in a specific age cohort employed specifically at an employer's branch location, in say Fresno, California, and give that employer the tools to improve health for that group, or a group that we would call a "health community."  This was a very granular, personalized approach leveraging deep data and clinical resources.</p>
          <p>And one final example, our emergency room decision support service reaches out to frequent emergency room users and connects them to other resources such as primary care, urgent care, or NurseLine resources.  Participants in these programs use NurseLine three times more frequently, and over 40% now routinely choose the less intensive, less expensive setting for their care.  Each of these examples is cost effective, personalized, practical, and easily deployable.</p>
          <p>We also continue to attract and position exceptional new talent across our enterprise.  These leaders are helping us build greater depth in our management team, as well as bringing fresh perspectives along with new energy and new ideas to our businesses.  I can quickly think of more than a dozen high profile people added in just the past six months or so, but let me address today's developments.</p>
          <p>This morning, we are announcing that Larry Renfro, a very senior executive from Fidelity Investments, will join UnitedHealth Group as an Executive Vice President.  He will serve as Chief Executive of the Ovations business.  Larry is a very senior and accomplished executive with diverse experience.  He is clearly well grounded in individual product sales and distribution.  His experience involves senior health and financial services businesses and markets, and large-scale, highly regulated operations.  This is another important move in developing the broad and deep executive leadership needed to advance UnitedHealth Group to its full potential. Larry inherits an Ovations business with maturing distribution and operations and improving overall performance consistency, as well as some nice growth momentum as it enters 2009.</p>
          <p>Simon Stevens will assume new duties, leading our overall healthcare reform undertaking across our enterprise.  Simon will dedicate himself to the engagement, development, and coordination of our healthcare reform effort.  He will also assume the overall operational leadership of our international business interest, with a goal of making this one of our next significant platforms for growth and diversification.  Simon's background, as Tony Blair's Health Policy Director in the United Kingdom, as CEO of America's largest seniors' health business, and as an operating executive in the hospital sector, makes him ideally suited to these challenging tasks.  We greatly appreciate Simon's successful leadership of Ovations, and that he will now broaden his role and help guide our constructive participation in health reform while also leading our international growth.</p>
          <p>Let me add, our Chief Legal Officer, Tom Strickland, who has served UnitedHealth Group with distinction, has recently accepted a senior position in the Obama administration, in the Department of the Interior.  All of us appreciate Tom's thoughtful leadership on matters of governance and his energies in resolving a number of challenging UnitedHealth Group matters.  Tom helped us build stronger relationships with regulators and elected officials, and he substantially strengthened our legal team.  We wish Tom the best in his new endeavors.</p>
          <p>Finally, we are continuing to add new and diversified leadership to our Board of Directors, including the additions in 2008 of Bob Darretta, Michele Hooper, and Glenn Renwick.  We recently announced that Dr. Ken Shine will join the Board.  Dr. Shine, who currently serves as Executive Vice Chancellor for Health Affairs for the University of Texas system, brings to UnitedHealth Group 30 years experience as a leader in healthcare, including ten years as President of the Institute of Medicine for the National Academy of Sciences.  And you can expect the addition of another Independent Director in 2009.</p>
          <p>In closing, I'd like to remind you of a few key points regarding our enterprise and the reasons we are optimistic about our continuing success, even while we continue to be cautious concerning the challenges our economy is currently confronting.  We have spent significant efforts in 2008 refocusing back to fundamental execution, and we're starting to see the signs of improving visibility, reputation, and results.  We have a strong and diverse business model that reflects in responds to the national healthcare landscape.  We are actively engaged in the dynamics of healthcare reform.  We believe UnitedHealth Group can serve a broad-based reform agenda while actually growing our businesses as we further diversify to meet the evolving needs of that reform.  Our financial stewardship has positioned us exceptionally well.</p>
          <p>Change is inevitable.  Some changes will be disruptive for us and for our industry, but leading companies take advantage of disruptive change and challenging markets, and that is our intent.  There remains a huge opportunity to continue to advance care for people and create value for society through innovation, technology, and service.  When we execute on this agenda, our shareholders will prosper.</p>
          <p>I thank you, and at this time I'd like to open up for questions for our senior team, and turn it back to the moderator.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question will come from the line of Scott Fidel with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  First question.  Just if you can give us an update on how your medical cost trends are looking in the west, particularly in California? And just, on the hospital contracting, how that progressed for 2009?  Just at the Investor Day, you did spike that as an outlier, and just wondering how the actual contracting is progressing for '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gail, I'll ask you start it off, and then maybe Mike can add color?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Thanks, Steve.  In terms of our medical cost trends, let me just start with the California marketplace.  It remains a continuing challenging market for us.  Our overall trends are where we expected them to be, and we certainly continue to see some pressure on unit cost. I think Mike will spend a little bit of time on that. But we have seen and made some changes obviously in that marketplace, with our leadership changes and a pretty robust focus on our affordability agenda.  So we're seeing some traction in the market.  But again, we have a long-term view on competitiveness for the California market, and I'll ask Mike to comment directly on the medical cost ratio and our view on trend there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I want to clarify, Scott, we didn't spike out directly the West Coast per se, but unit cost in-patient, I think we've been talking about pressure on the West Coast as well as the East Coast.  But we anticipate that there is going to be continued pressure on unit cost in in-patient next year.  So I want to make sure we're clear on that.  And I think that's reflected in the guidance that we gave.</p>
          <p>We did see, as you will note in Steve's comment, favorable reserve true-ups.  There was, again, favorable true-ups on the West Coast.  I would indicate that that's from our actuarial models, I think reconciling or truing up to the operational and performance improvement that we've made.  So overall, the reserves have trued up favorably in the West Coast.</p>
          <p>But nothing has changed in terms specifically in hospital contracting. We still continue to see strong unit cost pressure on the West Coast.  And then I think we mentioned at the Investor Day or on the last call that our efforts, after coming into the year, around midyear, to manage bed days and implement our clinical models from legacy UnitedHealthcare have taken root in California and that's part of the improvement that we're seeing in the California marketplace today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And, then, if I could just ask a quick follow-up question on the fiscal stimulus package, and do you have any details yet on how the formula will be developed in terms of how Medicaid relief will be allocated across the states?</p>
          <p>And then just also interested in your views on the COBRA relief and whether you think this will actually play out to a benefit commercial enrollment, in terms of potentially establishing some type of downside floor in where commercial enrollment attrition would trend to, relative to the economy?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Scott, we will have Rick Jelinek respond to this one, and then we'll try to keep to our one question kind of protocol.  Rick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Federal match component of the stimulus, it's still a little early to predict exactly what's going to happen, but as you know, the ranges are in the 800 to $100 billion range that would end up at the state level to increase temporary matching.  And what it looks like right now is that there will be somewhere in the 5 to 8 percentage increase of a match that would hit each of the states for the period of time, and more matching dollars would be going to states with the higher unemployment rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rick, just to clarify the numbers, that was 80 to 100 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="inaudible" /> Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Joshua Raskin with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  Thanks. Good morning.  My question also relates to cost trends.  I just want to make sure I understand what was going on here. In the fourth quarter, it sound like you guys had cost trends were well within the range, and I think it sounded like not at the high end, which to me sounded incrementally lower than what we were thinking last quarter, and then combine that with 300 million or so of intra-year development in the second half, maybe suggesting slightly better than we thought, at least in the first nine months, probably the first half of the year as well.  So, I'm curious, still talking about 8% plus or minus 50 for 2009, and what's the expected acceleration in cost trend from here, if we're still sort of not seeing it at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Josh. That's a lot of questions in one.  If I -- I hope that we were clear, that -- we have provided guidance of 71/2% plus or minus 50 basis points coming into 2008.  That remained firm throughout the year.  We did see, Josh, as you may recall, significant pressure in unit cost on the in-patient side, and that drove us to -- as we were looking to the Investor Conference, our best estimate for the year took us to a range of  71/2 to 8%, and I would tell you, we were, at that point in time, viewing our trend to be closer to the higher end of the range for the year.</p>
          <p>Clearly, the development that has transpired as we closed out the fourth quarter, we did see improvement in that team, on -- If you go back to the Q1 guidance that I gave you by category, which clarified the year, versus our year-ago Investor Conference, we improved in physician, in-patient was in the zone of what I said, and out-patient was slightly higher than what we said.</p>
          <p>So as the year trued up, with the development from the West Coast that I previously mentioned, we would be on the lower end of that range of  71/2 to 8% for 2008.  For 2009, we continue to expect that our trends will be in the 8% plus or minus 50 basis points.  As you know, that includes &#x2013; or that doesn't include the favorable contract from the PBM change that we mentioned at the Investor Day conference, but for now, we're very comfortable with the range of 8% plus or minus 50 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess, Mike, maybe I asked it poorly.  Last quarter, it sounded like you were thinking more around 8% for '08, and now you're saying closer to 71/2, and yet we're still thinking 8% for 2009, so I'm curious why some of the progress or improvement this year does not translate to next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think the answer is, Josh, first of all, we were -- I want to make sure we're clear.  We put out the range of guidance for 2008 at  71/2 to 8% at the Investor Conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not sure I indicated, but if I didn't, that was, at that point in time, at the higher end of that range.  It is coming down. Obviously, as a result of the favorable true-ups that we had, the total doesn't include all commercial.  It's split between commercial and other businesses.  And if you look at by category, you can see that we are expecting continued pressure on the in-patient side as a result of unit cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that is what is driving the ultimate change, give or take, and we'll update you as the year goes along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I would say, Josh, that while we're pleased with the performance in the quarter and what it suggests, it is certainly not enough to change our view of what we see the overall trends to be, the pressure in the marketplace, and how we should be guiding our business and our pricing.  And so, I would just leave it at that, but that, while we are certainly pleased with the quarter, I don't think it establishes anything which would take us off our trends at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's helpful.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Greg Nersessian with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Good morning.  My question was just on the commercial risk business.  I was wondering if maybe, Gail, you could give us a sense for, on the commercial risk membership that you're losing, may be compare the MLR on the business that you're losing on January 1 versus the business that you're keeping.  I know it's probably early, but if you could just give us a little bit of directional take there?</p>
          <p>And then if I could just sneak in a second one, a clarification. Did you say that you actually won the New Mexico behavioral RFP, or that you've been asked to bid on it?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Gail, why don't you take the first one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Good morning.  Let me take the first part of the question, which I sense from your question is really a question about our risk pool.  Let me say, based on the business that we are keeping, we clearly have favorable medical cost ratios for the business that we're looping in. That has not changed.</p>
          <p>As we think about our risk pool in total, we really haven't observed any noticeable overall changes to the risk pool, and we track that, based in our <mark type="inaudible" /> book, on health status indicators, and those have remained very stable.  As we look ahead to 2009, obviously 2009 for January is not completely mature.  We've got early indicators.  Obviously are staying on the range that Steve said in his opening comments.</p>
          <p>But I do want comment on just, again, we stay pretty disciplined, very disciplined to pricing to our forward view of costs.  We made a number of changes in underwriting processes in 2008, and we are seeing, actually in a positive sense, on our risk pool, our first year benefit cost ratio as far as small group cases are coming in more favorably than they did a year ago.  So while those are early indicators, and again, given the timing of this conference call, it's positive relative to the risk of the health pool.</p>
          <p>So we will continue to watch as we look ahead to 2009, attrition -- in-case attrition, which we expect obviously to be higher in 2009, and also continue to be very disciplined on our process around benefit buy-downs.  And, I guess I will turn it over then to Rick or Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'll answer your second &#x2013; the second part of your question, but I'll have Dawn do it, because it was her success.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks, Steve.  We are pleased to say we were selected by the New Mexico Collaborative for Healthcare to administer the behavioral health benefits for their Medicaid participants.  We are finalizing the contracting process right now and expect to be implementing it this year.  So, yes, we were awarded the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, and thanks for the detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's John Penshorn. I caught an offline question for something that I just wanted to clarify which was about the venture capital loss.  The reported earnings per share of $0.78 does include $50 million on venture capital write-downs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was there a question somewhere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Matthew Borsch with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.  Maybe if I could just ask for a little bit more about something you touched on, where you said that you're seeing local market growth for the first time in awhile.  I'm curious if you can spike out any geographies where you're seeing that, and what factors you attribute that growth to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure that we'd like to get into the specific geographies, but I think Gail can speak to the trends we're seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Steve.  Yeah, I think in terms of the &#x2013; while we're not going to comment specifically on the states, what I'll say to you is that the growth is across a multitude of different regions, and going back again to our focus on balancing within our regions and a lot more sales discipline locally, we see the growth as the result of our stronger market relationships with our distribution partners in particular, and also more effective positioning of our products which we think offer very affordable solutions for consumers especially in the environment they're facing.</p>
          <p>Steve also touched on something else that's taking hold in the marketplace, which is our focus on personalization, and those products we're seeing good traction in as we look to help integrate the system and make it work more effectively for consumers.</p>
          <p>Finally, I just want to touch on the State of Georgia open enrollment, which I think is a great example of how our focus on local execution is paying dividends and translating into growth at the market level.  In this case, consumers had the option of health plan choices under their just-completed open enrollment, and based on our local deployment, our strong member service skills, they overwhelmingly chose UnitedHealthcare as their plan of choice. So I think that gives you a little bit of flavor about how we see the market turning for us and the improvement in both our service and our satisfaction and our ability to deploy our resources locally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and to Steve's point, it's across a number of markets. It's not necessarily intensely concentrated, even to a region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but you attribute it more to your own actions, as opposed to a change in the industry environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very much so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And a variety of factors, including the &#x2013; in some instances, network access; in some instances, much better product positioning. The factors that Gail talked on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Justin Lake with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.  Questions around pricing.  Given the timing issues of having perfect visibility on January 1 renewals at this point, especially in some of the smaller ends of the business, just wonder if you could tell us what percentage of your 01/01 renewals do you feel like you have good visibility on pricing on at this point?  And then can you also tell us if buy-downs have been in line with the 150 to 200 basis points you discussed on Investor Day?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start. This is Gail Boudreaux.  First, I think you commented, and I would agree, it is too early to declare on 2009 pricing yields because our data is still developing.  However, based on what we know in our data, we do believe that we're tracking to the expectations that we outlined at the Investors Conference.  Our fourth quarter results were in line with the expectations we laid out.  And we are -- I just want to again reiterate -- we are staying very disciplined to our pricing and underwriting to our forward view of costs, and are starting to see some traction, particularly when we talked about some of those processes, we mentioned them before, we're starting to see that, the reduction in our new business discounting, and also I think very tight management of the benefit buy-down process in terms of the premium credit we give.</p>
          <p>In terms of overall buy-downs, at this stage, our buy-downs are tracking pretty consistently to our expectations, but given what we're seeing in terms of the focus on affordability, we would expect, certainly in Small Group, for that to see some additional focus.  But again, those are tracking in line to what our expectations are at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Gail, given -- I know you weren't there last year, but is there any way you can compare or contrast how '09 is tracking from a pricing standpoint at this time, versus where you were kind of looking back to '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe Mike Mikan can respond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what might be better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Justin, it varies by product.  But what -- I think I'll echo what Gail said, and I think we're seeing it in the numbers, is we are tighter in our pricing this year than we were last year.  And so we're seeing that in our underwriting models in terms of what we target to get in loss ratio, for new business, and retained business, and that's just better on a year-over-year basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great.  I appreciate the detail.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Charles Boorady with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Good morning.  When you look at the prescription trends for the first three weeks of '09 for your Medicare population, which I understand you have fairly real-time, robust data on, does that data on prescribing patterns tell you anything about the health status of the PDP and Medicare Advantage populations that are using Prescription Solutions, and how the health status of those lives compare with your expectations? So in other words, is the average risk of your population kind of in line with what you expected, a little worse or a little bit, better based on the first three weeks of data?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Hi Charles, it's Simon Stevens.  So we've got two data points around the Part D -- element of Part D lives.  For the 120,000 new Part D <mark type="inaudible" /> low income members, we've now got their individual risk scores, and at least according to our actuaries, they don't of themselves suggest that there's an issue there.  We'll obviously be able to track their actual clearance quite closely.  Secondly, we've got, as you say, the first few weeks' worth of Part D utilization data, and that appears to be showing the same sort of pattern that we would expect based on what happened last January, so again, nothing there suggestive of an issue at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.  And Simon, any way to articulate, with three weeks of data, how good a predictor that is, or roughly how many weeks of data you might need to get 90% confidence that your expectations are going to be met in terms of the average risk of your population this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you look at, not just our individual Part D members, but you are also, I think, Charles, asking about the Part D predictor for the MAPD members.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at the MAPD population as a whole, what we can say in summary is that we've seen very strong new sales across the Medicare Advantage portfolio, double what they were in last year's annual enrollment period, and they're very well diversified geographically and across product, so we don't have a concentration of risk in a particular market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Charles, it's Mike.  I want to make sure we're getting your answer.  If we look at the PDM volume for the lives that we have, the actual prescription volume that we're seeing are in line with the expectations, and the mix is in line with our expectations.  So we're not seeing anything out of the normal out of the prescription data today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  And that data, how good a predictor is that data of overall health status of your members?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that data, Charles, is a reasonable surrogate for it, but I actually think that Simon's comment about the profiling of his population and the risk attributes of it is actually most instructive.  When they actually go in and evaluate the risk status of the membership they have, and conclude that that status is not unfavorable, and then, as you are suggesting, then it also reflects in some of the operating results, that you're not seeing any of that, recognizing that it's early, I think that reaffirms that conclusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Carl McDonald with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>--fixed costs versus variable administrative costs. I'm thinking in the context of rising unemployment. When you lose a risk member, how much of the admin costs are totally variable, things like commissions, that go away immediately, versus more fixed costs like systems that you can't get rid of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know if I can give you the -- a formula response to that.  Obviously we have a meaningful fixed cost infrastructure in our business, but the variable elements that you talk about are -- you've got your finger on them. Mike, do you want to....?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carl, there's a lot to that question, and obviously it varies by product, and I think between John, Brett, and I, we can spend time with you to get into more clarity on the question that you're asking.  But that would be &#x2013; it would be too much explanation to try to give it on a call like this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Michael Baker with Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>--might be, and whether or not you anticipate any upward pressure on cost as it relates to that development?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, we didn't get -- whatever was going on with your -- we didn't get the first part of your question, so could you repeat that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry about that.  With respect to the Ingenix settlement, can you give us a sense of timing, as well as any potential or degree of potential of potential cost pressure or push on that, as a result of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of timing of this, maybe I'll have Mitch Zamoff talk about the timing of actually the settlement itself?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  The settlement is complete with the New York Attorney General in that the documents are signed. The amount of time it's going to take for the new database to get up and running is an open question.  The Attorney General predicted that it might take six months, but he said that that was possibly an optimistic estimate.  And with respect to the settlement of the class action lawsuits, again that settlement has been signed and remains subject to court approval.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the actual funding of the damages in that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the funding components of that, the AG settlement, the funding components will be dictated by the Attorney General and we would fund our $50 million commitment on a schedule that he determines.  And with respect to the funding of the class action settlement, that would not take place until after the settlement is finally approved by the court.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But sometime expected in '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sometime mid to late '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how about in terms of any potential impact on cost trend as you recalibrate usual and customary through that process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  That's the second part of your question, and I think Mike can respond to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's a lot of things that go into out-of-network pricing, with shared savings programs and other things, but when you get to billed charges, outside of that, there's really two ways that we apply our reimbursement.  One is, obviously using the U&amp;C rates that we talked about.  We'll continue to use the database, as we have in the past.  And then second, several years ago, we moved to a reimbursement formula that was indexed to pay at a set percentage above Medicare, rather than U&amp;C.  So when you blend the two, either way, we don't believe that there's going to be a cost issue going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ana Gupte with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Good morning.  My question is about your recent growth in Medicare Advantage private fee-for-service. It's sort of a departure from your usual strategy of growing in-network products, and I was wondering how much of it is coming from group relative to individual?</p>
          <p>Secondly, how are you planning to manage cost on that population, which are largely unmanaged? And are you looking to actually convert these at some point to network products, as <mark type="inaudible" /> gets eliminated and further rate cuts may be coming down the pipe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that is generally yes to all of those, but Simon will answer in detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can elaborate on the yes, Ana. Yes.  Well, the first point to make is that we've grown across the board. This is not just private fee-for-service growth during the annual enrollment period. As I said, our new sales are about double what they were last year, and the majority of our new sales for January 1 were in our network-based HMO/PPO product designs, not in private fee-for-service in the individual markets.</p>
          <p>Of our private fee-for-service growth, as you asked, about half that was from employer groups, and the rationale for that, as I think we said at our Investor Day, is that given the strength of our provider networks, we are willing to see some growth in private fee-for-service this year, seeing the opportunity to then migrate membership to other plan designs where we're very strong in the run-up to 2011.  And of course, even with this growth, our private fee-for-service will still comprise less than 13% of our total Medicare Advantage membership, so we continue deliberately to be underweight here relative to our potential.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks, Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Rex with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  I was wondering if you could get into a little more detail specifically on commercial utilization trends again?  So obviously, just looking to see kind of what you're seeing versus what the vendor community is speaking to out there in terms of some decline.  So maybe getting in, breaking into the four buckets of cost, if you could just speak specifically to the utilization components in each of those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I don't want to get into each bucket with respect to utilization and directly impact to the economy.  What I can tell you is, broadly speaking, utilization continues to track to our expectations, what we've been talking about for several periods now, we're not seeing significant change.  Areas that typically get focused on are bed days utilization, and we continue to see that tracking down, and that has a lot to do with the clinical programs and a lot of the effort that we put at the local market taking root.  So we continue to see that.</p>
          <p>We have not seen any real change in utilization directly related to the economic downturn.  We recognize that hospitals and clinics have talked about reduced volumes and an increase in bad debt.  We think that is more related to uncompensated care, or those that -- without coverage.  For those members that have insurance coverage, at least with us, we're seeing utilization very typical of what we expected.</p>
          <p>I will note, and I think there were several reports that mentioned that in October and November, utilization seemed -- appeared to be slightly down.  We saw that as well.  We can surmise what that was related to.  Again, within the range of what we anticipated, but it did bounce back in December, as we expected, as a result of the deductible wear-off.  So utilization from our perspective, currently, we're not seeing any real impact from the economy.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, we see -- we believe that, as the downturn in the economy, the shock will impact health benefits offered by employer groups, buy-downs will increase, and we ultimately believe that, beginning in 2010, maybe a year earlier than historical pattern, you will see utilization directly related to the economic impact of 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So when you speak to declining -- modestly declining bed days still, can you put a number around that, a percentage, just so we can get the broad side of the barn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>1%.  Somewhere in that zone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then on pharma, and script trends in particular in the commercial book, is that flat or has that come down at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's -- I don't know, I don't have it specifically in front of me, but I would say pharma utilization is generally up every year.  But I don't see any significant change in what we --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.  I meant the pace of change.  So, you'd --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't seen any real change in pace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Peter Costa with FTN Midwest Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just want to say, nice work on Medicare and getting that back to growing again this year.  My real question comes on the commercial side and when you expect to see the improvements show up on the commercial side? Do you believe your balance sheet -- your out-performance from the industry on the balance sheet is going to help you win more accounts on the national account level going into next year?  Do you -- are you using that as a marketing tool at this point in time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Peter, we will use everything possible as a marketing device.  I can assure you of that.  There certainly is interest in making sure -- companies want to make sure that they're doing business with enterprises that have strong stability and so forth.  But there are so many other factors that lead to what is valued in those kinds of relationships. I don't know Gail, if you want to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I would say -- add Steve's comments, is that in the national accounts space, we touched a little bit on some of the areas that they're focused on.  They're focused on affordability and quality-based networks.  We're still seeing a lot of interest in health and wellness programs and activating their employees to make better decisions so that they can get better total outcomes. So I think as we look at the national account selling season in particular, it's -- I think significant improvements we've seen in our service model and are focus on building a culture of service, plus the affordability and value that we bring to that marketplace around personalization  that's going to be our value proposition in the market.  So I think it's a combination of all those things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Mike has an observation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, also, I just want to mention that one of the things we do, and I think Steve and Gail both said this, is continue to demonstrate strong financial stability, and in our largest license, UHIC, continues to be rated A+.  So we feel very good about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say that this also has positive things when we think about state business and relationships like AARP and so forth, that the general conduct of the business and the positioning of the business aligns favorably in terms of how we've been positioned through these difficult times.  So, a good question, and as I said, we will certainly use that and any other device we can to grow and advance our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we expect you to see more financial-type products coming towards the senior population, with Larry Renfro being added with his AARP Services background?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would offer that we have for years thought about senior marketplace as a marketplace unto itself, and I think there's, in many respects, a health product is a financial product itself.  I think the key in that is that that business is sold very much in an individual distribution kind of a pattern, like financial products are often sold.  So I think that would be kind of the first line of step-off I would take.  And then, clearly, there is a perspective about how health plays into an individual's overall security, and a sense of financial security.  So to that extent, it crosses over, but I would think it's very, very premature to suggest that there's a financial product agenda itself here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Sheryl Skolnick with CRT Capital Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  I appreciate the opportunity to ask a question.  I'm looking at the -- and most of the juicy ones have been answered, so I'll ask this one.  I'm looking at the $865 million in cash available at the parent at the moment, and that seems to me to be a little lighter than I would have thought at this time of year.  Are there -- is there the ability to dividend up additional cash to meet maturity needs or any other cash needs that you might have, if, for example, the timing of the court settlement or the schedule of payments for Cuomo or any other settlements or issues that might come up might happen sooner rather than later? And including the debt repayments that you have coming up, especially if, say, your Medicare premium payments timing is a little bit off.  So I'm a little bit concerned about there being that little cash at the parent, and if perhaps you can give me some comfort on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a good question, but I think we have a very appropriate response for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the question, Sheryl.  It's a good question.  I -- what I told you at the Investor Conference is, I think right before the Investor Day, we had about $1.5 billion of available cash.  That's a timing thing. There's inter-company settlements that occur.  We ended the year in a very strong cash position, given the fact that we paid down significant commercial paper and ended with roughly $850 million of available cash.  Today as we sit, we've got the same balance as we did back at the Investor Day, of about $1.5 billion.  So period-over-period, we continue to pay down commercial paper and we continue to have significant liquidity on our balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, that number today would be 1.5 billion, and I think that is -- our response.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's great.  Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I think that concludes the Q&amp;A segment.</p>
          <p>I'll just leave you with a brief summary, that our financial performance for the fourth quarter and for 2008 met expectations. We continue to improve in fundamental execution, and we see very early signs of that improving visibility on reputation and results. We have a strong and diverse business model that reflects and responds to the national healthcare landscape, and we're going to use that actively to engage in the dynamics of health reform. Our financial position remains exceptionally strong and we continue to be careful steward. And while we recognize that there's broad economic challenge, and that 2009's clearly represents that, at that same time, we feel a very positive momentum across our businesses and we're anxious to perform.</p>
          <p>So I thank you for your attention today.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude the UnitedHealth Group Fourth Quarter and the Full Year 2008 Earnings Conference Call.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>