<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1123515" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-01-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>516</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Stephen J. Hemsley, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Joshua Raskin</participant>
      <participant id="3">Stephen Hemsley</participant>
      <participant id="4">Dirk McMahon</participant>
      <participant id="5">David Wichmann</participant>
      <participant id="6">Kenneth Burdick</participant>
      <participant id="7">Michael Matteo</participant>
      <participant id="8">William Georges</participant>
      <participant id="9">G. Mike Mikan</participant>
      <participant id="10">Charles Boorady</participant>
      <participant id="11">Eric Rangen</participant>
      <participant id="12">Justin Lake</participant>
      <participant id="13">Christine Arnold</participant>
      <participant id="14">Gregory Nersessian</participant>
      <participant id="15">Matthew Borsch</participant>
      <participant id="16">Scott Fidel</participant>
      <participant id="17">Sheryl Skolnick</participant>
      <participant id="18">Carl McDonald</participant>
      <participant id="19">John Rex</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>My name is Dennis and I will be your conference facilitator today.  At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the UnitedHealth Group Fourth Quarter and Year-End 2007 Earnings Conference Call.  All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise.  After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question and answer period.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  For purposes of getting to as many participants as possible, we also ask those with questions to limit to one question per person.  As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>This call and its contents are the property of UnitedHealth Group.  Any use, copying, or distribution without written permission from UnitedHealth Group is strictly prohibited.</p>
          <p>Here are some important introductory information.  This call will reference non-GAAP amounts.  A reconciliation of non-GAAP to GAAP amounts is available on the financial reports and SEC filing section of the company's Investor Information page at www.unitedhealthgroup.com.</p>
          <p>This call contains forward-looking statements under U.S. federal securities laws.  Those statements are subject to risk and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially from historical experience and present expectations.  A description of some of the risk and uncertainties can be found in reports that we filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission from time to time, including the cautionary statements included in our annual reports on Form 10-K and quarterly reports on Form 10-Q as well as our current report on Form 8-K filed in connection with the company's January 22nd, 2008 earnings release.</p>
          <p>Information presented on this call is contained in the earnings release and Form 8-K dated January 22nd, 2008, which may be accessed from the Investor Information page of the company's website at www.unitedhealthgroup.com.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to the President and Chief Executive Officer of UnitedHealth Group, Stephen Hemsley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for joining us this morning.  In 2007 our primary goals were continued predictable growth in earnings, the strengthening of our operating fundamentals and further leveraging the value of our diversified market-facing business approaches, including our capacity to generate and apply capital to build shareholder value.  As we look at UnitedHealth Group's 2007 performance, we can report that we have begun to make strong advances in all of these areas and that we have a significantly more powerful sense of momentum than we had at this time last year.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter earnings of $0.92 per share brought full year 2007 earnings to an adjusted $3.50 per share, that represents an increase of 18% over full year 2006 results.  Earnings growth was driven by a more than $1 billion increase in adjusted operating earnings and complemented by a reduction of more than 40 million weighted average shares outstanding for the year.</p>
          <p>We saw improved profitability in public and senior programs, while Enterprise Services businesses continued to deliver exceptional growth and financial performance.  These strong performances were offset by year long softness in our commercial risk benefits business, which today represents roughly 40% of our operating earnings.  Our overall medical care ratio improved by 60 basis points year-over-year, and our operating profit margin expanded from 9.8% to 10.6% as adjusted.</p>
          <p>The value of our diversified business approach was evidenced again in 2007 as we pursued expansion in virtually every segment of the healthcare landscape.  Our earnings stream continues to diversify by business, product, service line, client type, and geography.  Our operating performance continues to strengthen across the full expanse of our businesses with a smooth transition into January for commercial, senior, and public sector clients.</p>
          <p>We continue to see clear improvement in our market relationships and in service as measured both by our metrics and more importantly by direct market feedback.  We are instilling a greater emphasis enterprise-wide on building relationship equity with all of our stakeholders and those efforts are beginning to get traction.</p>
          <p>Strong capital generation remains a distinctive characteristic of our organization.  We reported cash flows from operations approaching $6 billion in 2007 or 126% of net income.  We achieved these results amid reductions in risk-based memberships at UnitedHealthcare, at Ovations Medicare Advantage, which underscores both a remarkable cash production capacity our businesses have, and the critical focus we maintain on capital generation.</p>
          <p>I would note that there were some timing differences that impacted fourth quarter cash flows including certain state Medicaid receivables, some accelerated income tax items, and the timing of certain federal program payments.  We now expect cash flows to be roughly $7 billion in 2008.</p>
          <p>We increased our debt to total capital ratio in 2007 from 26% to 35% and expanded our share repurchase commitments while maintaining strong credit ratings.  We repurchased 125 million shares in 2007 for $6.6 billion including 40 million shares for $2.2 billion in the fourth quarter.  This fourth quarter activity gives us a strong start on our stated target; $7 billion in share repurchase by year-end 2008.  In addition we had 2.4 billion in cash on hand as well as further debt capacity as of December 31.</p>
          <p>Our capital will support our previously announced all-cash mergers, share repurchase goals and general corporate uses.  While 2007 was seen as a quiet year for us on the merger and acquisition front, we made a number of significant moves to strengthen our enterprise.  The most visible announced acquisitions were Sierra, Fiserv and in early 2008, Unisys.  We also executed a number of lower profile but strategically important acquisitions, including the Lewin Group in public policy consulting, Administration Resources Corporation, the market leader in VEBA administration, and Healthia, LighthouseMD and Red Oak in clinical data and physician revenue cycle management.</p>
          <p>Since we are discussing capital, I'll anticipate a question about our investment portfolio.  We have a total portfolio of cash and investments of about $22.3 billion.  Our exposure at the beginning of the fourth quarter to subprime loans was de minimis, and what little exposure we did have was further reduced in the quarter.  Our municipal bond portfolio is about $5.5 billion in size and represents about one fourth of our total cash and investments.  Those bonds were selected by highly regarded outside investment managers, specifically based on the strong underlying credit quality of the issuers, and independent of any credit insurance. Our investment philosophy remains one of conservatism rather than one of overreaching for yield and that approach has produced dependable results in times of bond market turbulence in the past.</p>
          <p>As we discussed at our recent Investor Day, we have completed the transition to our new business segment financial reporting this quarter.  We have posted historical quarterly detail for 2006 and 2007 for both income statement and the membership tables on our website and Mike Mikan can answer any questions you may have related to these changes through the course of the day.</p>
          <p>We will now turn to a brief discussion of our key fourth quarter, January trends in the areas of costs, growth and finance delivery.  The short version is that all three of these are tracking with our most recent outlook.</p>
          <p>Full year adjusted earnings from operations of 8.025 billion were near the upper end of our range we've provided at Investor Day.  The year-over-year earnings growth in Enterprise Service businesses continued to be powerful in the quarter, Health Care Services earnings showed an expected sequential decline, which reflected the decrease in earnings in the commercial benefits businesses due to normal seasonal usage pattern, as well as the increased investment in marketing to seniors.  In general, our businesses serving senior and public sector markets had another very solid quarter and showed strong year-over-year earnings improvement.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter medical cost trends were inline with expectation, with the full year medical care ratio of 80.6% inline with the low end of our Investor Day outlook.  Ovations and AmeriChoice again had strong gross profit results continuing the recent trends.  The commercial risks, medical care ratio for UnitedHealthcare was 83.7% in the quarter, bringing the full year ratio to 82.1%.  That fourth quarter care ratio includes certain negative non-recurring items, the largest of which is an accrual that reduced premium revenues in the quarter, due to one state's recently issued regulatory determinations on prior year underwriting performance.</p>
          <p>After consideration of these &#x2013; our fourth quarter medical care ratio was about what we expected for the quarter.  This includes a prudent and appropriate accrual for estimated medical cost in high deductible health policies, which incur seasonally higher claims cost in the fourth quarter each year.  All-in, our 2007 full year commercial medical cost trend came in comfortably within the 7 to 7.5% range we discussed at Investor Day.  We are pleased with that excellent and consistent medical cost trend performance.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter operating cost remained well controlled coming in at 14.4% in the quarter and bringing full year to 13.8% as adjusted.  This sequential quarterly increase in operating cost of about 80 million included expenses for fully staffing the annual January surge in benefit changes and enrollment service needs for membership businesses and marketing costs for our senior business, including significant advertising and market launch expenditures for the only Medicare Advantage products branded with the AARP name.</p>
          <p>Turning to January 2008 growth, we are still chewing up retention figures, so these remarks are very much based on preliminary estimates.  Our Enterprise Services businesses are on track for solid 2008 revenue growth.  Ingenix closed the year with the revenue backlog exceeding $1.7 billion, an increase of 46% over last year.  OptumHealth's integrated capabilities and new branding are resonating well with customers in both the employer and payer market.  Exante, which is being re-branded as Optum Financial Services has been building its electronic payment network at a rapid pace and moved total of $19 billion in funds electronically in 2007, an increase of 80%.</p>
          <p>Prescription Solutions is in final negotiations for the location of its third mail service facility and will start fitting out this space in early 2008, as we move aggressively to advance our growth agenda.  I would point out that this collection of Enterprise Services businesses made more operating profit in 2007 than the entirety of UnitedHealth Group did in 2000.  They are each well situated for growth in 2008 and for longer term performance.</p>
          <p>AmeriChoice grew by 245,000 people in 2007, a 17% advance, including 10,000 people in the fourth quarter.  We are pleased with the momentum AmeriChoice has generated this past year, which includes a new Medicaid program in Tennessee, SCHIP in Texas, and the January 1 launch of an innovative consumer-driven model serving the uninsured population in Indiana.  We anticipate continued growth during 2008 from this business.  Additionally, the State of Tennessee recently issued its RFP for the East and West regions and we are well positioned to pursue both.  Missouri and Connecticut are also markets we are evaluating for 2008 expansion.</p>
          <p>Our pending acquisition of Unison will further strengthen AmeriChoice in these states and expand our services in this high growth market segment to a total of more than 2 million people.  We expect this transaction will close before the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In Medicare Advantage, our advanced planning, broker training, national and local market advertising, and electronic enrollment processes drove a productive start to the selling season.  This is a much improved position from last year.  The broker channel has reengaged and the build-out of our internal distribution channels will continue throughout the year and into 2009.  Ovations is off to a strong start with preliminary January figures, putting us on-pace for growth of 125,000 to 175,000 people in Medicare Advantage offerings in 2008, as we said out at Investor Day.</p>
          <p>Compared with last year, new sales are meaningfully up and customer retention has improved sharply.  Our strong gross sales are estimated to net out at around 60 to 85,000 new members by the end of the open enrollment period which runs through March 31.  We continue to expect that one-half of our annual growth in this line will come after April 1 from aging activity and in particular, strong monthly growth trends in our expanded chronic care Special Needs Plan.  Those are all organic numbers and exclude any impact from the pending Sierra acquisition.  While we are limited in what we can say here, we are in very advanced and productive discussions with the Department of Justice and plan to close the Sierra transaction in the near future.</p>
          <p>As for Part D, as previously discussed, January saw the reassignment by the government of the number of our Part D low-income members.  We anticipate a reduction of about 650,000 people that will be at least partially offset by open market growth, the pending acquisition of Sierra's Part D business and the Part D component of the new Medicare Advantage enrollment activity I mentioned a moment ago.  In the Part D open market, our sales trends are quite satisfactory recognizing that of course we need to wait for trued up dis-enrollment data from CMS before we have any final numbers.</p>
          <p>As we discussed at our Commercial Day or our Investor Day, our commercial markets businesses, UnitedHealthcare and Uniprise remained soft.  The first quarter 2008 decline in people served through fee-based arrangements is trending closer to 150,000 than to 200,000 people, as we are performing better than expected in open enrollment results with large employers.  We believe this is an early reflection in our service gains which I will discuss in a minute.</p>
          <p>First quarter losses in risk-based commercial products appear closer to 400,000 people than 350,000.  The components of the 400,000 include more than 200,000 from PacifiCare, 75,000 on funding conversions that remain with our company, and the balance representing organic decline.  We are still truing up all of these numbers, but it appears that first quarter will still have the expected decline of about 2% in total.</p>
          <p>Our results in 2008 business will be strengthened by the acquisition of Pfizer that enclose to 2 million consumers served in fee-based arrangements and Sierra contributing additional risk-based consumers in commercial market businesses.  This would result in a net gain of 7% in the first quarter for the UnitedHealthcare and Uniprise commercial benefits market.</p>
          <p>Let me now address our pricing discipline and improving service performance, which are critical given their efforts &#x2013; the effects on organic growth layer in 2008 and into 2009.  We continue to match UnitedHealthcare pricing to medical cost trends and expect to maintain a stable full year medical care ratio at around 82%, plus or minus 50 basis points, with natural quarterly utilization fluctuations.</p>
          <p>Our fourth quarter 2007 revenue show a sequential improvement in the rate of increase in realized per member per month yields and we expect this trend will continue steadily in 2008.  We remain comfortable with and committed to our discipline in long-term philosophy of pricing to our medical costs trend.</p>
          <p>As you are aware, we started early last year on a concerted effort to rebuild and enhance our service, which had impacted UnitedHealthcare's growth with both fee-based and risk-based customers.  At Investor Day, Dave Wichmann discussed in detail the significant commitment to this area and the tangible results we've already achieved.</p>
          <p>In summary, we focused leadership and resources on the issue and our service levels have recovered strongly.  We have more to do with legacy PacifiCare, but we are otherwise back to market performance levels and we'll further improve our service metrics throughout the rest of this year.  We are pleased to report to you continuing advances in these areas.  Let's start with some basics.</p>
          <p>Intense focus has brought down our adjusted inventories by 80% over the past six months and turnaround time on issues improved by more than 40% from the third quarter to the fourth quarter of 2007.  We expect to perform to less than 48 hour inventory on issue resolution going forward and we anticipate that this increased fee, the resolution will be felt positively by clients and physicians alike.</p>
          <p>Call quality also continues to improve with first call accuracy in the fourth quarter up 40% year-over-year for consumers and 60% year-over-year for physicians.  Our emerging service approach integrates pharmaceutical, medical and administrative data enabling empowered experts to provide once and done resolution service that cost us key functional area.  The feedback on this approach has been powerfully positive and we are expanding aspects of it broadly to the marketplace.</p>
          <p>Our dollar accuracy on claims payment has advanced 80 basis points in the past year to over 99% in the fourth quarter.  We are seeing improved audit scores from consultants that will continue to improve in 2008 as fresher results begin to be covered by their reviews.</p>
          <p>With regard to access, an independent third-party survey found more U.S. physician offices accept UnitedHealthcare than any other insurance plan.  We added more than 40,000 physicians and other care providers to our network in 2007 and continue to advance consumer access with key hospitals, most recently the Advocate in Chicago.  I would point out that less than 50 basis points of our hospital spend was in out of network status at any time, even for one day in 2007 taken for a highly stable network.</p>
          <p>Our Premium designation program is critical to consumers who want to make informed decisions about the quality and cost of their care into our new generation of consumer products such as Edge.  In 2008, the Premium designation network encompasses 21 distinct medical specialties and is available to consumers in 38 states plus the District of Columbia.  This is an important component of our integrated strategy to support consumers in receiving the right care at the right time and place.  Sophisticated employers understand the value of and advocate for this kind of transparency for their employees and their families.</p>
          <p>And our customer satisfaction on post-call surveys continues to be in the 98 percentile range in the fourth quarter and nearly 98% in December using the strengthened service approaches described earlier.  Consumers surveyed immediately after their interaction with our agents are indicating strong improvements in overall satisfaction.</p>
          <p>It's also important to note that 2007 was another fertile year for innovation across UnitedHealth Group.  We introduced exciting new products such as Edge and Vital Measures.  We expanded the integration of comprehensive care efficacy protocols, launched the next generation of consumer products, advanced and began to scale the integration of financial services, expanded our real-time adjudication capabilities, introduced the personal pharmacy history.  Brought Premium designation programs to scale and became the first company to adopt NCCN standards for determining chemotherapy drug coverage as part of our commitment to best science. And as I mentioned, we launched an innovative service model that is delivering compelling results for our customers.</p>
          <p>We are gratified to have been named the most innovative company in our industry in the most recent Fortune survey.  These service and innovation examples all directly relate to the broader aspiration of performing as an integrated UnitedHealth Group system.  We look forward both to external market validation of these gains and continued advancement in innovation in 2008.</p>
          <p>I will close with a brief summary and some forward-looking comments.  This year and quarter, we have done what we told you we would do.  We refocused to improve fundamental execution and we will maintain that focus.  We continue to expand and enrich our network across all products and did so with significantly lower levels of disruption.  We have substantially addressed PacifiCare integration and broader service issues, and fully recognize that we must continue to strengthen that market quarter-by-quarter throughout 2008.</p>
          <p>We executed on our marketing and sales approach in the Medicare Advantage and Part D sales teams.  We strengthened our discipline and pricing to costs across the commercial benefit market even at the cost of membership growth and demonstrated it with improving yield in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Our 2007 adjusted earnings per share increased by 18%.  This is directly the result of our diversified, adaptable and market focused businesses.  We are positioned to deliver continued strong results in 2008 and key elements for 2008 include an accelerating Medicare Advantage business supported by an exclusive alliance with AARP for 2014, expanded product offering and expanded geographic footprint and great brand name recognition.  Second, marketplace recognition of our stronger service performance across the board, new product launches and an intense focus on profitable growth in our commercial markets, a continued commitment to pricing discipline, timely closure of the Sierra and Unison mergers and as always our ongoing commitment to effective capital management.</p>
          <p>We continue to project revenues to be around $83 billion.  The impact of the timing of the Sierra acquisition and of a potential resolution with the Justice Department will be more than offset by closure of Pfizer.  Unison represents potential upside to revenues.  We expect earnings of $3.95 to $4 per share in 2008 supported by cash flow of roughly $7 billion and we are targeting first quarter earnings in the range of 82 to $0.84 per share or 11 to 14% over the prior year as adjustment.</p>
          <p>As we pointed out in Investor Day, we are focused on the greater long-term opportunities to become a fully unique enterprise, the opportunity to build out UnitedHealth Group as an open and engaged health system, one that can adapt to ever changing market condition and shifting demand in the dynamic healthcare landscape.</p>
          <p>I want to thank our employees for their focus and support of our customers and our businesses during 2007.  We stand together dedicated, de-leveraging our ideas, unique capabilities and scale, our solid execution and our strong financial standing for the benefit of the entire healthcare community, our customers, our employees, and our investors.  We appreciate your interest today and we can now move to questions.</p>
          <p>I am joined in this room by many of our senior business colleagues and John Penshorn, Brett Manderfeld and Mike Mikan and others will continue to be available after this call to respond to any additional questions you may have.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  We also remind you that for purposes of getting to as many participants as possible, we ask those with questions to limit to one question per person.  We will pause for just a moment to compile the Q&amp;A roster.  Your first question will come from the line of Josh Raskin with Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks.  Good morning.  Question on the improvement in the service metrics, I think you guys have a lot of statistics that sort of back it up, in terms of the internal measurement, but I am curious, how do you measure the external constituents? I mean, are there broker surveys that you do or how do you get sort of comfort that the market's recognizing that or is just simply looking at your membership growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Josh, I would react on two levels; obviously, given our focus on this, we have been in very consistent contact with brokers, with consultants, with employers, and soliciting very direct feedback in terms of our performance in these areas.  And I cannot overstate the degree of connection we have been pursuing, and will continue to pursue with that and that is one channel of direct feedback.</p>
          <p>I would point to another, and that is our post-call, post-contact surveys with consumers directly and with physicians with respect to their satisfaction, and our follow-up in terms of any areas where they express concerns. And we monitor those surveys which are really available and done on every call at every contact so that we can really track trends in this area, and those have been trending so strongly favorable through the course of the year; that is, I think another very credible and fact-based response with respect to our service levels.  But I'd also &#x2013; do we have Dirk McMahon here?, and David Wichmann, and I think perhaps they can respond more effectively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so, what I'd also say is that Josh at the -- after the call is over, we have the folks take a survey, and if there is a negative result on that survey, what happens is &#x2013; and the negative result is defined as two standard deviations from the mean in terms of performance, an e-mail immediately goes to one of our supervisors, and a supervisor follows-up within 24 hours with that particular customer to make sure the issue is exactly resolved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we've also been very, very powerful on the very first call, first contact basis, and that really is a trend that we are seeing, and that's just the follow-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a call perspective in terms of how we have improved, we've moved from about a 4 plus percent error rate at the beginning of last year to a 2% error rate at the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what I am trying to bridge is these improvements in these metrics which is obvious; I mean, the level of service is obviously dramatically better, and I guess I'm trying to bridge that with the expectations around membership. I think Steve, you alluded to the commercial businesses, first quarter losses trending a little bit better than expected.  Is it fair to say, sort of the outlook for the full year, I think you had said last time that you would have growth in the sequential quarters, two, three and four Q, is there maybe an update as to what you expect full-year membership to look like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll let Ken Burdick and Mike Matteo respond to that but our view in terms of membership guidance is really unchanged.  We do expect to see positive growth particularly in the risk products in the third and fourth quarters, and I would say to your opening comments that the momentum is -- dynamics are clearly distinctively different than they were this time last year.  Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Josh. Let me just respond on the outlook for the remainder of the year. You are correct; we continue to have an expectation that is absolutely in line with the guidance from the Investor Day.  There has been some variation in January results by funding type.  But the outlook for the reminder of the year is for growth both in the fully Insured space as well as the fee-based business, and it's really attributable to several things.  # 1, the improvements that the marketplace is seeing in both service and in the network stability; #2, the impact of the new generation of the broader range of price point products that we discussed at some length at Investor Day; and then third, we are really starting to get traction from the focus on expanding and revitalizing our broker and consultant distribution channels. And maybe I'll let Mike Matteo speak to some of the success we've had with some of the open enrollment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Ken.  In terms of our large case market with the enterprise, we saw a better first quarter than anticipated and a lot of that is attributable to working in concert with our large employers in a partnership, really helping them to showcase what we can do from a service perspective, but a medical cost trend perspective, and our ability to attract and retain individual members when they have a choice between us and a competing plan. And so, our open enrollment results were actually better than expected this year for January in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll throw one point of clarification in and that is, as we said, we are down 50,000 more than we anticipated as we look at January.  We don't see recovering that 50,000, but the expectation that we have in terms of growth for the balance of the year and that mix is &#x2013; continues to be in line with our investor guidance.  Bill?  Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Bill Georges with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.  I am wondering if you could just help out with a little more detail around your commercial medical loss ratio, and I guess you mentioned during the prepared remarks, some sort of state funding requirement. I wasn't exactly clear on what that was, but could you if possible spike out the moving parts around the higher commercial MLR?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll ask Mike Mikan to respond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, I don't want to get into the specifics on the regulatory items, it's an ongoing negotiation, but I'll try to break out and give you a little more detail on our context into what Steve said earlier. We did book the fourth quarter to an 83.7% medical care ratio that was impacted by these special cause items that Steve had mentioned.  The regulatory item was something we were made aware of in the late second quarter, early third quarter.  At that time, we booked to our best estimate based on our interpretation of the statute and legal advice.  We worked with this individual state throughout the remainder of the year.  Based on new information, we have reconciled this best estimate with the state and that impacted our fourth quarter care ratio.  If you excluded those items, we would be in-line with the expectation that we gave at the end of the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And, if you could also just provide detail around the moving parts in your cost trend forecast for '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not &#x2013; I would stick with what we had at the Investor Day conference that I laid out for you and I think also Ken Burdick did as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So, no change in view of the components of cost trend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We would still be overall at 7.5% plus or minus 50 basis points for 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Great.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Charles Boorady with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  Thanks.  Good morning.  Just curious in light of the changing economic environment what assumptions you are making about the impact of the economy in '08 versus '07 in terms of the top-line from the potential for layoffs and pressure on state budgets in your state programs?  And then, on the medical expense line, one can argue for lower trends if you assume, that a weak consumer is going to consume less healthcare, but there is also some evidence that people accelerate consumption ahead of being laid off in healthcare and I'm not sure how you see those two offsetting each other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there are several dimensions to that one question.  So, we build assumptions for attrition into our outlook, and I'll have Dave Wichmann respond to that.  I'll also suggest that the cost pressures that are imposed on states often present opportunities, probably more often than not present opportunities for us in growth.  So, we often view those pressures as a positive in terms of a growth outlook.  And then, I will have Mike kind of respond to the impact -- the economic impact that might manifest itself on trends. So, Dave?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Charles.  As you would expect, we too are concerned about employment levels and the fact that they may drop off.  We believe that we accounted for a normal course attrition in our forecast.  However, depending upon the severity of the economic conditions, that of course could be more severe as well.</p>
          <p>To-date, we've seen some modest &#x2013; very modest declines in the financial services industry related to the sub-prime market in particular.  Beyond that, we have really focused on advancing service and seeing if there is opportunities for us and grow our enrollment within our existing clients.  And, I think as Mike Matteo pointed out earlier in his response, we have been very successful that in a large case marketplace and believe that success is reflective of that improved service performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rick, you want to talk about the state programs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the state side, we have good visibility into roughly half of our markets already in terms of the rate setting for 2008 and we feel good about that in this year.  In addition, as Steve mentioned, any budget shortfalls or budget pressures at the state level provide opportunity for the business to grow in general as more people are added onto the medicaid roles and the S strip  roles for the programs.  So, we feel very good about the prospects for this year looking forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Charles, let me speak about utilization more in the broad context and then I will try to narrow in on the impact of the economy, and broadly speaking we think our products align well to the individual's consumption behavior.  That is, getting the individual more involved in the healthcare decision making process and that in fact has had a benefit on bringing utilization to a more appropriate level.  We are also very intent on managing our costs.  We &#x2013; as you know, we've talked about significant healthcare affordability initiatives, driving bed days &#x2013; in-patient days down and we've seen that again this year with another 1% or so decline in bed day utilization.</p>
          <p>With respect to the economy, as you know, healthcare consumption generally lags the economy.  So, at a point in time when you are going into a recession, you generally are experiencing higher utilization that is already baked into our run rate.  But, we will continue to manage costs and utilization by aligning our products and all the things that we do around educating the consumer and managing utilization broadly speaking to make sure that our cost trends are in-line if not industry-leading and we feel very confident of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have the employers been proactive in asking you to do more to control medical expenses?  I saw your initiatives on oncology and also mimicking medicare and not paying for certain errors in the hospital, are there other such initiatives that could bring down the trend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike, do you want to speak broadly speaking from our customers' perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  I'd say overall from the large case perspective, customers are always interested in the affordability agenda.  But, this actually presents an opportunity where some customers who may have been I'd say more paternalistic are willing to look at more aggressive tactics that help them manage costs in terms of how they interact with the system particularly around consumer-driven health plans and really evaluating those and how they can be part of their portfolio to drive more aggressive cost trends.  So, this economic exposure does at times create some opportunity for us to leverage what we have in our best-in-class networks, our premium networks and our activation strategies for consumer-driven health plans.  So, that kind of opens up the conversation a little bit more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Justin Lake with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Good morning.  Couple of questions.  Just first in regards to your -obviously with the fourth quarter issues you had last year &#x2013; just wondering if there is anything that you could tell us as far as what you've done to improve your visibility on cost trends or utilization as you went into year-end and maybe compare that to last year and same thing on the pricing side.  You said as you went through the first quarter of '08, it was apparent that your yields didn't reach the levels that you were hoping for.  Is there anything you could tell us as far as giving us an update in regards to what you see your pricing yields doing and what you have done differently to see those trends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Ken, do you want to respond to the yield aspect of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Justin.  After seeing the fourth quarter results in '06, we began making adjustments in '07 to our pricing.  Some of that fell towards the end of '07, much of that is going to felt in '08 and we are very confident that our pricing and our yield is tracking with our medical cost projections.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Then, anything on the utilization side that you can tell us as far as what you saw at the &#x2013; maybe you guys focused on the hospitals at the end of the year?  Do you see anything differently than last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is an area that we've spent as you can imagine Justin a fair amount of time on this year trying to get better information &#x2013; real-time notification information from our hospitals, also understanding what is occurring in the out-patient setting.  And, then, as important to that is just looking at the pharmacy data as we closed out the year between the holidays and we saw a significant drop-off in the pharmacy consumption which really last year occurred from two-fold.  One was, the significant ramp-up that we saw within &#x2013; call it the high deductible benefits just the switch over from traditional products into that and then also consumers that wanted to get their prescriptions filled and an out-patient procedure done near the end of the year.  We just didn't anticipate that.  As you know, last year, we talked about that or at least the degree and this year we feel we are a lot closer to understanding that and we feel we've reserved appropriately as you can see as indicated in our expected loss ratio for the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  And, just one quick follow-up on the economic question that Charles had.  I saw that your accounts receivable is up about 200 million and your DSOs were up a day.  I'm just wondering if that's timing-related or maybe there are some issues, I'm just curious, around the individual segments with the economy being what it is.  I'm wondering if you are seeing people may be paying their bills a little bit later or not paying them at all as far as they are  individual &#x2013; maybe they are very small and a small group on the premiums?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know they were timing-related issues, and in particular Steve mentioned the state Medicaid payments, we had two states that we did not collect at the end of the year and we've collected in January already. So, they are just timing differences.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, nothing on the individual side to worry about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, nothing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, actually the receivables on the commercial businesses have performed exceptionally well. Most of the receivable growth is in the other businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Christine Arnold with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a question about your commercial MLR. The premium yield improved in the fourth quarter as you mentioned. You increased price such that you said much of the benefit will be felt, kind of in the first quarter and into 2008. Given that the MLR was higher than your expectations in this business in '07 and you've taken pricing action, what's the potential that the MLR could improve in 2008? I know you are guiding for kind of stableish plus or minus 50. But, it seems to me it should improve given the pricing action. Could you talk about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, we offered guidance that represented a corridor and obviously we are striving for stability there. I think there is potential for upside performance, but I think it would be very, very premature to provide any indications of it at this point in time. And so we are &#x2013; our guidance stays where it is, but we would be looking to outperform just as a natural instinct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then as a follow-up, we heard from the marketplace that you have changed some of the ASO terms entering 2008 in some cases in order to retain accounts where there were some service issues. Can you talk about the change in ASO terms and how at risk you are for medical trends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think, Mike Matteo is perhaps the best to respond to that and then maybe Dave Wichmann to put some color on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks. When we look at the large case marketplace and the performance guarantees, we had to increase some of our amounts at risk from a service perspective, but we are that confident that that will be a non-issue for us going into the year. We do not have a very different profile in terms of a ASO fee at risk from an affordability perspective or a cost perspective in terms of that -- what we have done on selected accounts is not something we think will substantially change our risk profile in 2008 or 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that because you don't think medical trends will hit that risk quarter or because you didn't put much of risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's a little bit of combination of both. While we have put some amounts at risk, we only will put at risk what we think we can hit and achieve. The other part of this is that in the large case market, we were able to achieve very good trends for our large customers, even below some of the trends in our fully insured books of business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christine, the only thing I'd add to that is that we throughout the year, and this kind of get back to Josh's question too -- we throughout the year seen a steady decline in the amount of payouts and performance guarantees out of our business particularly related to service. So, it's just another external validation point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Greg Nersessian with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, thank you. My question is just on the quarterly progression of earnings next year, and just specifically in light of three factors. I just wanted to hopefully get a better understanding for this. First is just the loss of the dual eligible PDP lives, how that might influence the earning seasonality in Ovations? The second was just on the M&amp;A marketing costs related to the AARP relationship in '08. Was there any one-time amount of spending this year, or do you expect the same amount of spending next year? And then the final piece is just on the high deductible plans in the commercial book. Has that kind of stabilized or do you expect the commercial MLR progression to get even more pronounced next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'll have Mike respond in terms of those elements, and then from a business point of view we will, we might have some color so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, with respect to the loss -- there is two things going on with the Part D. One is the change in the risk corridor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which will affect the quarters, especially the first three quarters negatively and then positively in the fourth quarter. That will be somewhat offset by favorable impact of not having the level of Part B dual eligibles in the first quarter. So, that should be favorable in the first quarter offsetting some of that negativity, and then I apologize, what were the last two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, high deductible plans, and I think that basically we have a very clear beat on that -- that the pattern to establish that would be --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Roughly the same as, -- we expect it to be roughly the same as this year and then with respect to marketing cost there is, I am sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Simon might respond to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, great. So, as far as the AARP brand launch is concerned, we have had a number of one-time launch costs which we incurred in the second half of last year, which we wouldn't be repeating at that same level next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you quantify the magnitude of that or a range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>While we obviously make adjustments, precisely what the shape of our marketing spend will be next year when we see the full-year impact of it this year, but we have talked about the 30 basis points of cost associated with that in the last part of 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but just in -- so just generally speaking, overall that the quarterly earnings progression for next year will be most impacted by the two part B components, Mike that you mentioned on the dual eligibles and the risk orders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Matthew Borsch with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes, hi, good morning. Just a quick one on pricing, could you characterize what you are seeing in the market versus maybe a year, two years ago, particularly in terms of the intensity of price competition on the commercial risk side of the business, and is there any variation between public companies and-not for-profits where may be one is more aggressive, one is less aggressive than what you saw a year or two ago? And just, if I could just add to that one other piece, which is can you give us any sense of where you think the commercial risk MCR will land in the first quarter just because there is obviously a lot of focus on that metric?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ken, maybe you should respond in terms of what you think the pricing environment is, and then Mike can talk to the first quarter care ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Matthew.  Let me speak first for the not -for-profits.  We are seeing the consistent pricing behavior that we've really observed over the last 18 to 24 months, no change, it continues to be competitive.  With respect to the individual market, that's where we think we have seen an increase in the number of competitors which is driving a higher level of price competition, and then in the upper range, it's really consistent with the patterns that have emerged over the last couple of years.  We don't see any fundamental change in the dynamics around either fee or risk-based pricing.  It continues to be a competitive but rational market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then relatively stable consistent with the last 24 months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The  ratio? Hey, Matt, when you adjust out -- you know, last year we reported a Q1 loss ratio in the UnitedHealth care business of 81.2%.  When you adjust out development, we believe that this year we will be in line with that adjusted loss ratio of around 80.5%  that's what we would expect in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Scott Fidel with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.  Just had a question just around if you could give us little more details on the MA open enrollment fees and then just relative to the net sales you are seeing maybe how that's tracking in network-based products with the AARP relationship compared to private fee and then also if you are seeing any higher disenrollments in terms of retention in MA, a couple of competitors have cited seeing some of that recently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon, I think this is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  So, the Secure Horizons folks are clearly seeing a sales turnaround from the acquisition last year, growth sales are up and the terminations are down.  As Steve said based on current enrollment trends, Secure Horizons believes that they should be on track for 60,000 or more net new Medicare Advantage members, sold by March 31st and effective by April 1st in line with our full year projection that we set out at investor day of 125 to 175,000.  As for product mix, we are seeing gross sales consistent with the strategy that we set out for you at investor day with deliberately strong acquisition in network-based products, AARP branded HMO products and  <mark type="inaudible" /> products scheduled with private fee-for-service sales, but focused particularly on our network based offerings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then in terms of disenrollments or retention levels, I think you said that those are tracking in line with expectations for '08 so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  I mean the termination rates are significantly down on what they were last year below cost.  We have a larger installed base of Medicare Advantage members than anyone else in the industry, nearly 1.4 million members, so even with a much reduced termination rate, simple math means that we still have a higher number of member exits during the selling season than others, which we obviously have to then net off against strong growth sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then if I could just ask a follow up just around the group Medicare piece and whether you have signed any sales to-date yet or what -- and then what the pipeline looks for the remainder of 2008 and then looking out to 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  So, I mean we are a leader in the employer group retiree marketplace.  We have got over 400,000 group Medicare members including those in Medicare Advantage.  We are going to actively participate in the 2008 opportunities group business recognizing of course, that for the large groups these are most likely to take effect for 1/1/09.  So, I guess in passing it is worth remembering that much of the group Medicare Advantage now showing up on the  <mark type="inaudible" /> Medicare roster actually reflects commercial lives of other plans converted to Medicare Advantages far back as last summer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Sheryl Skolnick with CRT Capital Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.  I am a bit &#x2013; I still confess I am very curious to understand what's happening with that one particular state, but I'll hope that we we'll get some more clarity perhaps in the 10-K on the disclosure.  And so, I don't want to waste my question by pressuring you on that point, but I guess where I do want to pressure you little bit for a more clarity or color if I could is you mentioned that that membership &#x2013; the commercial membership was going to be down about 50,000 more than anticipated and if I heard you -- or at the lower end of the range and if I heard you correctly, Steve you said that you probably don't make that up.  A) is that correct, and B) did I hear you correctly and B) can you break that down into -- are these old products or these markets in which you've not yet gotten traction on your service and innovative product initiatives or is it a lack of traction in the new more innovative products or where you put the effort into reconfiguring the broker channel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, Sheryl, you absolutely heard correctly.  We are 50,000 more, we are talking risk based.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, that's what I mean, the commercial risk based.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it in a group size, can you give me more detail on where the weakness appears to be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ken, do you want to respond to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sheryl, the &#x2013; you are correct that it's in the older product line.  As I mentioned at the Investor Day Conference, our Edge product for example is rolling out throughout the country, but we only had it in 21 markets as of January.  I will just speak to the momentum that we are gaining. I will cite one example of the Chicago market, because I know if I talk about things like network stability and improved service in broker engagement, it may not resonate.  I will just quickly describe that using Chicago in example, all of these things have come together, so that with the signing of Advocate we experienced growth in our small book for the first time in several years.  We sold seven new customers with brokers that we had not been writing business with, and we added 2500 additional members in one open enrollment opportunity and our large case proposal activity is up 25%. And that's really &#x2013; it's one illustration of the impact of these three or four different things that we talk about as fundamental initiatives that are building momentum in our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  But nevertheless it was not enough to offset what appears to be another attrition story, and I am trying to understand that. I mean we know about the American Medical Securities attrition and the PHS book attrition.  Are we now going to have to go through another period in which new products replace old, new services replace old, and we have more than expected attrition? I mean I think that &#x2013; I know the attrition itself is obvious, but it sounds like it's more than anticipated and that's what I am trying to get at.  Are we going into yet another cycle of disappointment because we are surprised by a lack of traction in the old product base for UnitedHealthcare?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Sheryl, I would not think that that theme resonates. And if you really take a look at the concentration, it is more California, I won't put it all in terms of PacifiCare, and I won't put it all in terms of repositioning of that book.  But I would say, if there is a concentration it is more in the California direction. And I actually think that our outlook with respect to going forward is, as I said, more positive than we have been probably in a couple of years.  And &#x2013; I know you are focused on risk, but we are also seeing fee-based product performance that was actually stronger in January than we anticipated and we are kind of positive with respect to that going forward as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And the tax rate was lower than anticipated in the quarter, was there any specific reasons for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is right.  Mike, do you want to comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we just &#x2013; when we did our end of year reconciliation with the income across the different tax jurisdictions, we had a favorable state income tax impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I am concerned because the cash flow was lower, the tax rate was lower, there were a couple of one-time items in the quarter, the revenue was lighter.  I know that's history, I know you want to look forward, but the quality of earnings there make me a little concerned. Why shouldn't I be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually think the quality of earnings is quite strong.  I think we were very appropriate with respect to how we established care ratio for the fourth quarter.  I think the earnings actually were at the upper end of our range.  If you take a look at our earnings in terms of where we positioned them from an operating point of view at 8.25 billion, we were five short of the absolute upper end of the range.  I think if you take a look at cash flow capacity that was approaching 6 billion and the cash is really more a function of timing, so we have basically strengthened the 2008, so actually I don't see a quality issue at all.  I actually see us addressing very appropriately any and all concerns and continuing to perform well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from the line of Carl McDonald with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  It looks like the Medicare Advantage had another very, very strong quarter in the fourth quarter.  I am still having a little trouble cross-walking between the loss ratio in '07 to the expectation that the loss ratio is going to be stable again in 2008.  So can you help us there in terms of, it looks like there was a lot of favorable development in the Medicare business in '07, your assumption is that doesn't continue in '08.  Is there less favorable development impacting the Medicare business than we think there is, or are there other factors that are helping 2008 and then offsetting the loss of that favorable development next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll let Mike start and then maybe Simon can add to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We talked about this after the first quarter.  We've got a broad diverse business across the insured different blocks and development as most of you all are aware, that we did have negative prior period development or prior year development for the UnitedHealthcare business.  We have a diverse block of business across Medicaid programs, the OptumHealth program, Stop Loss and others.  And so I don't want to just focus in on MA which is what seems to be where we are naturally going. You do need to look at it across a block of business that represents, and I know that's insurance talk, but that is in fact this part of the business, is roughly &#x2013; call it $55 plus billion in medical costs and over $8 billion of medical payable.  So we need to make sure we look at it in the context of the overall block of business in that insurance talk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then Carl, just to supplement that, in terms of the Medicare Advantage MCRs for 2008, you asked if there were other factors that might explain our outlook, and I would draw your attention to quite a few.  The first is obviously that the 2008 rates were reasonable.  The second was that our 2008 benefits were designed prudently.  Third was that our medical cost trends are expected to be broadly stable.  In addition, our clinical model is gaining traction.  The efficiency of the drug components of our services continues to improve in part through greater mail and generic usage.  There are some annualized effects from the change in member mix that we saw during 2007, and of course the risk-adjusted compensation that we now receive to meet the health needs of our members is a continuing resource flow, not a one-time payment.  So those are some of the variables that lead us to the outlook that we've given you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to quantify the impact on margins from favourable development to the Medicare Advantage business in '07?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We really haven't commented about that in any area of our business. Could we get to the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of John Rex with Bear Stearns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  I just wanted to go back to the commercial cost of accrual again here, just thinking about what we saw this 4Q versus 4Q '06, so if we adjusted the 4Q '06 for the negative development you talked about in the 1Q '07, it'd be roughly an 81.6, 81.7 loss ratio compared to the 83 call it plus a little bit this Q. And &#x2013; can you just help me understand like, how much of this is about a higher proportion of your membership being in high deductible plans this year versus last over the 10 million UHC risk book, how much is &#x2013; you've alluded a couple of times to more conservative accruals in the commercial book as you exited 4Q, and can you just kind of give us a feel for what was driving that higher adjusted comp?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, John...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because it's a pretty big shift.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty big shift. And it's getting into detail, and I don't want to get into reconciling non-GAAP items, so I'll try to answer it as best I can and if I don't I'll have John, Brett and I follow-up with you afterwards to make sure we're getting to the questions, like I said, as best we can.</p>
          <p>The &#x2013; if you go back to last year, the adjustments that &#x2013; the things that were impacting that loss ratio vis-&#xE0;-vis the loss ratio this year in the fourth quarter, are developments, the in and the out in both periods and that would be about, call it 150 basis points.  So you were close to what I would have estimated the adjusted loss ratio to be.</p>
          <p>We are impacted by those special cause items that we mentioned earlier.  As you know, even though we are seeing pricing increase, the impact on that has not &#x2013; on the loss ratio is not far enough along to see that result in the fourth quarter.  We do expect our pricing actions to be seen in 2008, but that did impact as well.  And then also the net item that you are probably trying to quantify is, the fourth quarter does have heavier day content.  You price for that across the year, but the fourth quarter 2008 is a higher utilization days than the previous year. And then the ramp up of the high deductible plans, as evidenced by the increase in CDHP plans in the legacy UnitedHealthcare product going from 11% to 15% in the fourth quarter.  So that does impact the individual quarter, not necessarily the full year.  As you know, you price for that for the full year, but if you've got months that had heavier utilization, that does in fact impact your loss ratio.  So taking all those things into context, we believe we are appropriately reserved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, maybe you could see it this way, is your view of utilization in the 4Q '07 &#x2013; is it that it was higher than even your revised view of 4Q '06?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  It's a &#x2013; all that was, was a reserving issue as we talked about in the first quarter, and....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, no...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I mean, just reading in it's just an 83 plus a little bit versus an 81.6, 81.7, I'm just trying to understand if there's something in the book of business that's shifting that I need to be thinking about more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think it's those reconciling items that I referred to.  I don't think there's anything else to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Before we conclude, if I could kind of recap in a nutshell. We performed at the high-end of 2007 guidance in operating and per share earnings for the quarter and the year. UnitedHealthcare commercial ratio for the quarter performed largely in-line with our previous statements and we reaffirm our commercial care ratio for '08 in an 82% plus or minus 50 basis point range. First quarter membership appears roughly to be in-line with our Investor Day discussions, higher premium yield are &#x2013; from pricing actions, are getting traction and are being realized, Medicare and Medicaid and supplemental products all appear to be in-line with our '08 membership projections. 2008 revenue estimates and annual operating earnings and per share outlook remain unchanged. First quarter per share earnings should be as much as 14% above the prior year quarter and we expect roughly 7 billion in operating cash flows for '08 and we'll continue our share buyback program.  All of these elements &#x2013; all of these represent a significantly stronger level of visibility and momentum compared to where we were this call last year and we will continue to focus on improving our performance as we go through 2008.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your attention today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude our conference for today.  You may all disconnect, and thank you for participating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>