<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1236823" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>518</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James R. Young, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John J. Koraleski, Executive Vice President, Marketing and Sales</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dennis J. Duffy, Executive Vice President &#x2013; Operations</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Robert M. Knight, Jr., Executive Vice President &#x2013; Finance and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Randy Cousins</participant>
      <participant id="6">Robert Knight, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jason Seidl</participant>
      <participant id="8">Thomas Wadewitz</participant>
      <participant id="9">Matthew Troy</participant>
      <participant id="10">Walter Spracklin</participant>
      <participant id="11">Ken Hoexter</participant>
      <participant id="12">Allison Landry</participant>
      <participant id="13">John Larkin</participant>
      <participant id="14">Edward Wolfe</participant>
      <participant id="15">Gary Chase</participant>
      <participant id="16">William Greene</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="corprep">James R. Young, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer, and President</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Greetings and welcome to the Union Pacific Second Quarter 2009 Earnings Conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded and the slides for today's presentation are user controlled.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to introduce your host, Mr. Jim Young, Chairman and CEO for Union Pacific. Thank you, Mr. Young. You may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Welcome to Union Pacific's second quarter earnings conference call. Joining me today in Omaha are Rob Knight, our CFO; Jack Koraleski, Executive Vice President, Marketing and Sales and Dennis Duffy, Executive Vice President, Operations.</p>
          <p>For the second quarter, we're reporting earnings of $0.92 per share, a 10% decline versus 2008, and included in that number is approximately $0.14 per share from a land sale in Colorado. Similar to the first quarter, the business environment over the last three months was extremely challenging, with volumes down nearly 22%. Although we typically see carloading increases from the first to the second quarter, that seasonal growth was notably absent this year, in particular quarterly coal volumes were at their lowest level in nine years.</p>
          <p>Our operating ratio was a second quarter best at 77.3%, a more than 2-point improvement from last year. Lower year-over-year fuel prices contributed to this performance, but we also worked diligently to size our resources with demand and align spending priorities with today's economic reality. While aggressively reducing cost in the organization, we're also pursuing new business opportunities in markets that can benefit from UP's outstanding service product.</p>
          <p>Our safety performance, operating metrics and customer satisfaction are all at best ever levels. We ended the second quarter in a strong cash position with a very solid balance sheet. Although the economy appears to have stabilized over the last month or so, it's important to maintain financial flexibility in such uncertain times.</p>
          <p>Now with that, let me turn it over to Jack to walk you through the business groups. Jack?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Jim, and good morning. I thought a good place to start this morning would be by taking a look at some of the market indicators that touch several of our business segments, from a 47-point drop in steel capacity utilization to a 10% reduction in electrical generation by coal. I think these give you a pretty good indication of the broad impact this recession is having on our business. So let's take a look at how these economic undercurrents played out in our second quarter volume. Volume fell 22% in the second quarter, as the weakness of the overall economy was reflected in declines across most of our business.</p>
          <p>Domestic intermodal was the only major market segment to post a gain. Lower fuel prices drove a significant decline in fuel surcharge revenue and along with a little negative mix, resulted in an 8% decline in average revenue per car, even as our core price improvement stayed within our five to 6% range, reflecting the value proposition that our improved service brings to the market. The end result was a net year-over-year price decline for many of our customers. With both volume and average revenue per car down, total freight revenue declined 28% to $3.1 billion for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Here's how it looked across each of our six businesses. A 14% decline in Ag products carloadings combined with an 8% decrease in average revenue per car, lowered revenue 21% for the quarter. Export demand for whole grains was well below last year as export shipments of feed and wheat both declined over 40%. Weak demand lowered domestic wheat shipments 30%, while domestic feed volumes were down 13% due to the continued decline in animal inventory.</p>
          <p>The decline in animal feeding is also a significant driver of the reduction in the U.S. soybean crush and that led to a 15% drop in meals and oil shipments. On the positive side, two of the ethanol plants that were shutdown by the VeraSun bankruptcy resumed production under new ownership and that contributed to a 4% growth in ethanol shipments for the quarter while DDGs grew 11%.</p>
          <p>Auto volumes fell 47%, which combined with a 12% decline in average revenue per car, resulted in a 54% reduction in revenue. Continued efforts by the manufactures to align vehicle inventories with slumping sales levels, along with the bankruptcy proceedings for Chrysler and GM, led to plant shutdowns and production cuts across the industry. As a result, our finished vehicle shipments declined 49% and our parts volumes were down 44%.</p>
          <p>In Chemicals, 24% decline in revenue was the result of a 22% decrease in carloadings and an average revenue per car reduction of 2%. Fertilizer volumes fell 43% with week overall demand and a sharp drop-off in the Canadian potash moves, both the export and the domestic moves. The economy took its toll with a 23% decline in liquid and dry chemical shipments, a 22% drop in soda ash and an 11% falloff in plastics, where strength in exports partially offset weak domestic demand. The slumping construction market's impact on asphalt shipments and low refinery utilization led to a 25% decline in petroleum volumes.</p>
          <p>With carloadings down 16% and average revenue per car up 7%, our energy revenues declined 22%. Southern Powder River Basin tonnage declined 14% due to lower demand and the contract losses that we talked about last quarter. Reduced demand as a function of the recession's impact on industrial production above normal inventory levels, some utility outages and to a limited degree lowering natural gas prices. In addition to soft demand, coal quality problems and production issues resulted in 366 fewer trains out of Colorado and Utah, a 35% reduction in tonnage.</p>
          <p>Our industrial products volume was down 34%, which combined with a 9% decrease in average revenue per car, resulted in a 39% decline in revenue. Our steel shipments declined 64% as production ran at only 45% of capacity during the quarter, half of what it was a year ago and scrap steel shipments fell 50%.</p>
          <p>Housing starts ran 45% last year, so our lumber carloadings were off 41%. With weak demand for residential and commercial construction products, cement and stone volumes also dropped almost 30%. Non-metallic mineral shipments declined 34%. The U.S. drilling rig counts are down by 50% from last year as natural gas prices remain low, reducing the demand for frac, sand, pipe and the other minerals used in the drilling process. Last but not least, our paper volumes were down 24% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to intermodal, with intermodal volume and average revenue per unit down 18% and 6% respectively, revenue declined 23%. West Coast imports drove the decline in international intermodal and the bright spot for the quarter was a 4% growth in our domestic segment where our capital investments, process improvements, and service performance are supporting a wide variety of new truck competitive services. During the quarter our IMC business grew 26% and our Streamline subsidiary saw volume grow 60%, with over 40% of that business coming from highway conversions.</p>
          <p>So what do we see for the second half? The economic outlook appears to have stabilized, as Jim said, but the economy is still somewhat fragile. That being said, here's some of the opportunities that should produce a stronger run rate for us. The fall crops are looking pretty good right now and the harvest should lead to an increase in grain shipments and soybean processing. The drought-impacted bean crop in Argentina looks like it could create some opportunity for U.S. meal exports, probably in the fourth quarter. Ethanol will also benefit from two additional former VeraSun plants that will resume production here in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>With record low auto inventories, resolution of bankruptcies and new models should provide traction in the second half. Sales rates are strengthening, with June coming in at 9.8 million vehicles, so that plus the government's new cash for Clunkers program, that's got some manufacturers actually adding to planned production schedules for the first time in 18 months.</p>
          <p>Chemicals that depend heavily on strengthening in downstream markets, liquid and dry and soda ash have both shown some modest improvement here recently, and we expect them to kind of maintain their current run rates. Fertilizer, which has been disappointing both in the fall last year and spring this year, could actually be an opportunity for us. For all of the reasons I mentioned earlier, our coal volumes will likely be off as much as 10% from 2008's record level. We expect to see some seasonal strengthening of that run rate during this high demand summer months, but it'll certainly be at lower levels than prior years. In fact if you look year-over-year, energy faces some of the toughest comps in the third quarter last year and a record fourth quarter as well.</p>
          <p>Fuel production has been strengthening lately, with at least three new- three mills starting backup and in early July, production rates topped 50% for the first time since late last year. We've also seen an increase in brown paper production with additional paper machines being brought back online. So strengthening in steel and paper are hopeful signs, which if they got to sustained, could also help drive some recovery in the industrial demand for electricity, which would give us an additional coal boost.</p>
          <p>We're starting to see some stimulus project activity but so far it's still hard for us to tell whether it's generating incremental projects or just shifting the source of funding. Intermodal, like Energy and Ag, should see some seasonal strengthening although international volumes will continue to run softer than last year. But we look for continued growth in our domestic segment with the added business from hub and the continued success in new services.</p>
          <p>Now we've seen some of these opportunities reflected already in the recent strengthening of our run rate. While we expect it to continue to strengthen, I think the chart fairly shows that a year-over-year challenge that we face and we're going to continue to pace below last year. Let me wrap up with a look at customer satisfaction, second quarter again averaged a score of 87, matching last quarter's best ever performance and up four points from last year.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn it over to Dennis for the service performance report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jack, and good morning. The priorities of the operating team are two-fold:  run a safe, sufficient volume-variable railroad and provide a high quality service product. Our second quarter results demonstrate we are performing well on both fronts. Let's start with service, these are four key service metrics. Train speed, at 27.4 miles per hour, was a quarterly best and up 20% versus last year, highlighting the progress we've made through our network management initiatives.</p>
          <p>Lower carload volume also helped create a fluid network, which we are leveraging into better asset productivity. Freight car utilization, at 8.6 days between loads, was another record quarterly rate. Despite fewer yard starts and reduced yard operations, terminal dwell time remained steady at 24.5 hours and matched last year's second quarter best level. Consistent with the high customer satisfaction scores that Jack just showed, our internal service delivery index reached a best ever quarterly &#x2013; quarter at 93%. While enhancing service and efficiency, we also improved employee, customer and public safety, reducing incident rates 16%, 13% and 12% respectively.</p>
          <p>Along with safety and service improvements, we continue to drive productivity gains across the board using organized, well-defined processes. Let me share a couple of examples. UP's re-crew rate improved a 3.8% in the second quarter, a record performance, reducing overall staffing requirements and crew-related costs. We reached another best ever in our fuel consumption rate, beating last year by 6% and setting all-time records for the second quarter in the month of June. In the first half of '09, we saved over 35 million gallons of diesel fuel by better utilizing our locomotive technology and increasing employee engagement with our Fuel Masters Program. These efforts enhancing productivity and performance also create capacity for the future when volume returns.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, however, we continue making the operation more volume variable. With second quarter gross ton-miles down 22%, we were fully volume variable with our train starts and resources. We reduced train starts 25%, our working TE&amp;Y, train, engine and yard workforce 22% and our road locomotives and active car fleet by 27 and 30% respectively.</p>
          <p>As volumes in April and May fell below our first quarter results, we increased furloughs and stored more assets. In June, we recalled a few employees and brought back some assets into service as we saw some increased volumes and entered the peak period for vacations and summer maintenance.</p>
          <p>We're managing volume variability, keeping in focus our dual challenge of improving both productivity and service. I talked with you last quarter about how we are using our unified plan to shift work from smaller, less efficient yards to more efficient network yards. We reduced shifts and over time adversely all yards on our network to size the operation for current volumes. To date, we have also closed or significantly reduced operations in 24 of UP's 114 principal yards. At the same time, we've achieved the dual goal of improving customer service, improving carload SDI, Service Delivery Index, by 10 points versus 2008. Also, industry spot and pull, which captures our first and last interface with the customer, reached an all-time best of 97% on time in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Our productivity and performance initiatives are supported by our capital investments. We invest for safety, service, growth and productivity improvement. As we told you in April, we reduced our '09 capital plan by $200 million to the current outlook of 2.6 billion. The pie chart shows the split between replacement spending and investment for productivity and growth. The engineering replacement spend was reduced by $88 million, on the basis of better productivity and material prices, yet protects our long-term goal of improving the infrastructure. Results are encouraging. Miles of mainline flow orders are down 20% year-over-year and we're beating our production plan running at 111% of goal through the second quarter.</p>
          <p>As we discussed before, the capital plan also includes $290 million for 125 new locomotives that conclude a three-year purchase agreement. Although demand does not warrant these, we are putting them to good use in distributed pair operations, saving fuel and storing less efficient locomotives. The majority of the growth spend is on the Joliet intermodal facility, plus select rifle shots where commercial opportunities such as wind energy and a few high leverage productivity projects, including signal upgrades along our Central Corridor.</p>
          <p>Looking forward through the second half &#x2013; to the second half for the operating team, it's committed to achieving further safety improvements, meeting the dual challenge of improving efficiency and service, progressing our summer capital programs with greater productivity, and being ready to leverage the upside potential when volume returns.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it over to Rob to talk about the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dennis, and good morning. Let's start the second quarter financial discussion with a look at our summary income statement. The 22% fall-off in carloadings and lower fuel surcharges drove a 28% year-over-year decline in operating revenue to $3.3 billion. Second quarter operating expenses totaled $2.6 billion, down 30% from a year ago. The company's ongoing initiatives to increase efficiency and operate a volume variable network played a major role in reducing quarterly costs. We also benefited in the second quarter from a 68% decline in fuel costs and a reduction in casualty expense.</p>
          <p>Another factor is that our 2008 expenses included over $20 million of higher costs associated with the Oregon mudslide and Midwest flooding. So we have a favorable expense comparison versus last year. Lower year-over-year operating revenue and expenses combined to produce $751 million in second quarter operating income, a 19% decrease. Second quarter freight revenue fell 28%, to $3.1 billion as a result of lower carloadings and reduced fuel surcharge revenue. Interestingly, this quarterly revenue amount is more than $100 million below first quarter levels, further highlighting the depth of the current economic recession.</p>
          <p>Average revenue per car declined 8% in the quarter as we continue to pass on the benefit of lower fuel prices to our customers in the form of reduced fuel surcharges. In fact, fuel surcharge revenue declined more than $500 million in the quarter. Our pricing efforts in the second quarter yielded results just north of 5%. For the full year, we are still comfortable with our outlook of 5 to 6% core pricing gain. The mix of business in the quarter was slightly negative as a result of significant declines in carloads of finished vehicles, lumbar and steel.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the quarterly expenses, as I walk through each category I'll highlight the impact of both volume and efficiency. Starting with compensation and benefit, this expense category declined a $125 million in the quarter, or 11% to $976 million. Second quarter workforce levels were 10% lower year-over-year as we continue to furlough employees and reduce overall employment through attrition and management actions.</p>
          <p>In fact, UP's average quarterly employment levels are the lowest since the Southern Pacific merger. Strong network fluidity and lower carload volumes enabled us to make these reductions and drove a 1% decline in average compensation per employee. Also contributing to the decrease was lower expense related to our incentive program. Offsetting a portion of this productivity was the 2008 Union wage increase of 4% and effective July 1st 2009, the Union wage increase becomes 4.5%. For the remainder of 2009, we will continue to manage workforce levels with demand.</p>
          <p>Second quarter purchased services and materials expense declined 21% to $391 million. On the purchased services side, lower volumes and increased operating efficiency contributed to both decreased contract service expense as well as reduced crew transportation and lodging. From a materials standpoint, we performed fewer locomotive repairs in the quarter, as a result of lower volumes and having a significant portion of our fleet in storage. This category also benefited from the favorable year-over-year comparison to last year's mudslides and flooding.</p>
          <p>Turning to fuel, this chart illustrates the impact of changing fuel prices. The solid blue line shows our actual monthly fuel price. The dashed black line is our monthly fuel price lagged by two months to illustrate our fuel surcharge programs. The areas shaded in red with a solid line just above the dash line represents periods where the lag in our surcharge had a negative earnings impact.</p>
          <p>Conversely the areas shaded in green shows the periods when fuel prices declined and earnings benefited from the surcharge lag. For the second quarter of 2009, the impact within the quarter was negligible, although we had a slightly positive lag to start the quarter, the lag turned negative as diesel fuel prices increased in May and June. Looking at fuel on a year-over-year basis however, the surcharge lag added about $0.20 per share to our second quarter 2009 earnings.</p>
          <p>As you can see from the chart, fuel prices spiked in the second quarter of 2008, where a significant earnings headwind was experienced in that quarter. As we look ahead, it's hard to say what might actually happen with fuel prices. It's a little like trying to predict the economy, but if you assume prices remain at current levels through the end of 2009, which is around $1.90 per gallon, you get some idea of how fuel might impact earnings. Assuming fuel prices don't fluctuate much, the earnings impact within the third and fourth quarters is minimal. The more meaningful perspective is how the year-over-year comparison is likely to shape up.</p>
          <p>For the third quarter of 2008, it was about a wash as prices receded in the back-half of the quarter. But in the fourth quarter of last year, we had a substantial tailwind to earnings from the surcharge lag.</p>
          <p>In addition to the lag impact of fuel, we consumed 84 million fewer gallons of diesel fuel in the second quarter. A portion of the lower consumption relates to the 22% reduction in second quarter gross ton miles, which saved as approximately $234 million. Improved consumption was also the result of our ongoing efforts to conserve fuel, which saved $65 million in the quarter. As Dennis mentioned, the operating team is having great success reducing fuel consumption with more to come.</p>
          <p>Second quarter equipment and other rents expense declined $31 million in the quarter, or 9%, to $307 million. Similar to what we've experienced over the last couple of quarters, lower volumes of industrial products and intermodal are driving down short-term car rents. Better asset utilization as fewer leased assets reduced quarterly expense as well.</p>
          <p>Other expense declined $46 million in the second quarter to $153 million. The primary driver of the decline was a semi-annual actuarial study completed in the quarter which reduced expenses by $38 million year-over-year. Our strong safety record and lower estimated settlement costs contributed to the lower expense. In addition expenses for employee travel, utilities and other miscellaneous expenses decreased in the quarter. Offsetting a portion of these reductions were higher property taxes and an increased provision for bad debt expense.</p>
          <p>Turning now to slide 30, we've summarized our expense performance in relationship to the quarterly volume decline. The casualty expense reduction and last year's weather-related expenses both helped our overall expense performance in the second quarter. But, with volumes remaining at historically low levels, we took actions throughout the quarter to align resources with demand.</p>
          <p>Reduced workforce levels, stored locomotives and freight cars, as well as ongoing efficiency gains combined to achieve a roughly 70% expense variability in our rate in the second quarter. Of course this analysis of variability normalizes for the year-over-year change in fuel prices. Our ability to operate a volume &#x2013; in a volume variable manner contributed significantly to achieving a record second quarter operating ratio of 77.3%, 2.3 points of improvement versus last year. Lower year-over-year fuel prices, pricing gains and the casualty reduction also played a role and helped offset the impact of lower carload volumes.</p>
          <p>Taking a look at the full income statement, second quarter other income totaled $135 million, driven by the $116 million pre-tax gain on the land sale to the Colorado Regional Transportation District. Excluding that one-time item, other income in the quarter was $19 million, equal to last year's amount. Quarterly interest expense increased $22 million or 17% to $150 million. Higher year-over-year debt levels drove the increase, although offset somewhat by lower effective interest rates in the second quarter of 2009. Second quarter income tax expense declined 8%, or $23 million, to 268 million as a result of lower quarterly earnings. The effective tax rate in the quarter was 36.4%, a point higher than a year-ago rate. We expect the full year effective tax rate to be around 37%.</p>
          <p>Net income in the second quarter declined 12% to $468 million, or reported earnings of $0.92 per share. If you exclude the RGD land deal that we talked about, adjusted second quarter net income would be $396 million, or earnings of $0.78 per share, a 24% quarterly decrease.</p>
          <p>Slide 33 shows our quarter end cash position and current debt levels. As we've discussed over the last several quarters, we are continuing to maintain a strong liquidity position as the recessionary economic environment lingers and business volumes remain low. Adjusted debt levels increased moderately to $14.8 billion, reflecting new debt issuances over the past year. As we think about the remainder of 2009, what happens with the economy will clearly be the driver of our earnings. Our current seven-day carloads are running about 150,000, a roughly 19% decrease versus last year. Although this is slightly better that what we experienced in the first half of 2009, as you heard from Jack, volume levels will remained challenged for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, at current fuel prices, we will likely lose the positive fuel tailwind we enjoyed in the first and second quarters. In total, lower fuel prices and the resulting surcharge lag added about $0.40 to earnings in the first half of 2009 versus last year. While low business volumes in fuel will pressure our second half results versus last year, the entire UP team has done a great job playing the hand that the economy has dealt us. We're not using the excuse of a slow economy to stop improving our overall profitability and we've produced solid results despite the challenges. Through our own ongoing commitment to pricing, strong operating efficiency, and focused efforts to right-size the organization, we will continue to increase UP's future earnings power.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it back to Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. Although we expect it will be some time before the economy recovers, our business levels, as we've said, appear to have bottomed out, with a few opportunities for improvement as we move into the back half of the year. This feeling is supported by the latest round of economic indicators, which seems to support the view that the economy has stabilized. With that in mind, we're managing the company under the assumption of a continued low-volume environment, advancing efficiency efforts while at the same time providing excellent service to our customers. We're fully prepared to handle more business when the demand returns. We're riding the network very well, which positions us to generate stronger volume leverage going forward.</p>
          <p>Talking more strategically for a moment, we're well aware of the activity in Washington regarding rail regulation. Because of the potentially negative consequence that this increased government regulation could bring to our industry, we're spending a great deal of time on Capitol Hill. We're talking to legislators and educating them about the benefits of rail. Everyone understands and agrees that rail needs to play a vital role in solving America's transportation infrastructure problem.</p>
          <p>We're optimistic that the leaders in DC also understand the importance of a financially healthy rail industry. Union Pacific and the entire industry is uniquely suited to help our nation's economy grow and compete in the 21st century. Our fuel-efficient environmentally friendly, and safe transportation products help customers compete globally, saves taxpayer dollars and as our business grows, creates good-paying US jobs. While our company is challenged by these unprecedented economic times, we remain confident in our long-term strategy, which is still firmly in place. We're focused on improving safety, increasing efficiency and delivering price-driven value for our customers, which will enable growing financial returns.</p>
          <p>Now with that, let's open it up to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now be conducting a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Our first question is from the line of Randy Cousins with BMO Capital Markets. Go ahead with your question sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jack, I wonder if you could comment on your Mexican business. How has it been doing, how is the trans-boarder stuff performing? Has it been hit harder than your domestic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, Randy, it probably has been a little bit hit harder. It's down about 30, 32% something like that in the quarter and of course, as you would expect a big portion, our largest piece of business typically would be the automotive franchise. So with the turmoil there for both Chrysler and General Motors, that kind of hit it pretty hard. On a brighter side, a lot of new business opportunities coming out of Mexico, the maquiladora industry is showing some signs of revival. We've kind of increased our sales force a tad there in Mexico and we're going after those new business opportunities. So, we're feeling good about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, do you see the Mexican business coming back fairly strong in the second half or do you see a Mexican business kind of lagging your domestic U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know I would &#x2013; I hadn't given that too much thought, but I'm thinking it's going to probably mirror what we'll see on the U.S. I think the automotive industry coming back will help us to some extent and I think actually we should see a little bit improved grain movement between the U.S. and Mexico. So I think it'll probably mirror what we'll see on the U.S. side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, Rob, just for you, I guess it's going to, comes back to Jack's as well. You mentioned bad debt. How big a number was it? And I believe you guys have some legacy auto contracts, does the bankruptcy or did the bankruptcies of a couple of the auto-related companies creating opportunity to maybe get at those contracts earlier than otherwise would have been the case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Randy, as I mentioned, we increased the bad debt reserve and it was relatively small, two or $3 million in the quarter, so not a material item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about the legacy business, is there a chance to get at auto legacy business a little sooner as a consequence of the insolvencies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Randy this is Jim. Keep in mind, Chrysler was already a new contract when we looked at it and General Motors has just a short time left. We're in discussions over it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then last question, in terms of cash balances, you guys are sitting with about $1.6 billion in cash. Do you have a sense of sort of what do you think is a suitable level and if the cash continues to build, do you put it back towards share buyback?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Randy obviously 1.7 billion is not the going run rate, we think, in normal times. We talked yesterday probably, maybe that 400 million kind of range may be better. We're being conservative now until we see the economy. We're in a good position. Our share purchase program is off the table right now. But when we start to see this thing turn around, we'll consider what's best for shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from the line of Jason Seidl of Dahlman Rose. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's talk about pricing a little bit. You mentioned just north of 5% and you're sticking with your guidance for the full-year. Can you talk about what you're signing contracts at right now currently? And also what percentage of your 2010 business is locked up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, we're &#x2013; I'm not going to talk about individual contracts, or next year, other than we're seeing real value we're providing in the market. We are getting price for our service. It &#x2013; you start looking at some of these corridors, we &#x2013; I won't get into the specific customer. But we &#x2013; his cycle times, when they looked at it, pretty big book of business, had improved 20, 25%. They assigned a very significant value of that to them internally, obviously inventory carrying costs, this case they owned equipment. We were able to get a very good price in that new contract that has been consistent with where we're going. And again, it's hard to look out to next year and where anything is going to be, but even you look at where we're at today in this very tough environment, I'm confident that five to 6% range we looked at starting the year will be there for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and again, what percent of next year's is already signed up? Forget percentage-wise in terms of the prices you've gotten, but what percentage is already booked?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, Randy &#x2013; we're not compared &#x2013; Jason, we're not going to get into that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you expand a little bit on some of your new intermodal offerings? Some of the contacts in the industry there that we talk to are sort of very excited about some of them and you've got a lot of people being able to sell this versus the truckload business because of your improved cycle time. Can you elaborate sort of what services were launched in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jack do you want to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Northern California down to Texas was the market that we had exited we brought back. We opened seven lanes of refrigerated boxes, including now an interline program with the Norfolk Southern that's gaining a lot of attention. The improved service on our Blue Streak network with the Norfolk Southern is also doing quite well. Service levels just all over the network are really doing well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason and we're not done here. Keep in mind if you go back three or four years ago, we walked away from many of these markets, when you recall we were struggling in terms of our business volumes. And so we've been consciously and slowly looking at new markets to reenter. You've got to prove yourself. This isn't a business that you open it up one day and it's full. You've got to prove your service offering. We've got a good track record that many customers are willing to one, reconsider UP or two, are looking to ship on a railroad for the first time. So we're pretty excited about it, that as you saw, our only book of business that grew in the second quarter was domestic intermodal and that directly relates to our strategic approach on the domestic market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And as you look towards service levels, how are they going to be impacted by the eventual turnaround in the economy? Without trying to put a timeframe on it, do you think you could maintain levels near where you have them at now with business coming back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, we're running 28 miles an hour right now and my goal is when we're running 190,000 cars, we're running 28 miles an hour.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sounds good. One last item and I'll turn it over to somebody else. Could you just refresh my memory when those ethanol plants you talked about actually came back online? Was it late in the quarter or early?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They were kind of mid-quarter and then the third one just came back up now, so it's up and running and the fourth one, I'm not completely sure when it's coming back, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the third one came back in July then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot guys. I appreciate the time as always.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from the line of Tom Wadewitz with JPMorgan Chase. Please go ahead with your question sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wanted to see if you could give some comments on the coal perspective. I think what we heard from CSX last week when they were talking about coal, that I think some of the utilities have contractual obligations with the coal producer and that would help their coal volumes a little bit in third quarter maybe look a little better than they did in the second quarter. I'm wondering if you &#x2013; if that would affect your customer base at all and help your coal volumes in third quarter and also just in terms of stockpiles, if you can give us a sense where you think they are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, I think the latest information we have says stockpiles are down a tad from their kind of record high levels in May, but still substantially higher than what they were a year ago, maybe to the tune of 16.7, 17% greater than where they were a year ago. I'm not as bullish on the idea that the customer commitments are going to drive business volume. What we're seeing right now is just that the burn rate from the summer season is much higher, so we're seeing customers put more train sets back in service again. We've seen our volumes kind of pick up here and we would expect that that will continue through the September, maybe even October. It kind of depends on the weather. But that's what we see right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that give you a little better year-over-year performance in coal looking forward, or is that just kind of a normal seasonality and the year-over-year looks similar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's normal seasonality, but it's going to be well below last year's pace. We set records in the third and fourth quarter last year and we're nowhere even close to that this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On a broader demand question, I think there's some degree of optimism about a turn in the industrial economy, the idea that they've been producing below the actual consumption level, taking inventories down and you would be at a pretty lean level on inventories for at least part of your customer base. But it seems like there's a lot of caution about the outlook for volumes. Are you seeing that with steel customers, automotive, with chemicals? Is that something that you would see and would lead you to be optimistic or are &#x2013; you really just don't have any sense that volumes will really get better in the near term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our optimism is one of it looks like things have stabilized. Jack had indicated there are a couple areas, steel is up, where they're going to reopen, I think, two or three plants, we had talked about. But we're a long ways to go to get back in that market where I'm going to feel good about it. So again, but you have to stabilize at some point before we can actually turn things around and we'll see. I think the stimulus money, I think most people were pretty up, maybe overly optimistic on its effect, on the timing.</p>
          <p>What we see with some of our local groups we work with, most of them aren't going to see real dollar spend until the latter part of the year. And if you think about the timing it takes to prove it to feds, get it to the state and get it out of bids, that's probably realistic. So I could say there's some optimism in the balance of the year, but we're going to be pretty cautious about it. I would tell you we are positioned to handle it. If this thing turns around, with the assets we have in place and the leverage, we will lever very nicely in the bottom line with just a little kick in volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and the last one, I'll pass along to someone else. When you look at the third quarter earnings, they &#x2013; seasonally, they're higher than second. That's kind of normal, but I'm wondering, given some of the comments you've got, do you think the expectation of a pretty big ramp in third quarter versus second, is that &#x2013; does that seem realistic in terms of what, I guess the $1.7, $1.8 that's out there versus the $0.78?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, there's a &#x2013; you can get a wide range on the numbers right now. You're going to see our carloadings, they are picking up some. I can get a pretty wide range in the numbers and really the bottom line there is going to be that &#x2013; the volume. Again, we will lever very nicely any volume impact. I'm just not going to be real optimistic right now and on &#x2013; you'll see it. I mean, watch the carload numbers that are produced every week and if you see those start to move, you're going to see we'll leverage very nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from the line of Matt Troy with CitiGroup. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I was wondering tactically and strategically, how you can resource or reresource the network? You went into this downturn a little bit over-resourced. Obviously done a great job in terms of right-sizing. Tactically, whether it's deploying locomotives or cars back online or getting furloughed employees back in, if you could just help us in terms of getting comfortable that there's a plan in place to accommodate whatever volume ramp we might see. How do you look at that versus past cycles? How are you confident that it's going to look better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Duff, why don't you take that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, that's a great opportunity for us. Every one of the resources that we have, whether it be locomotives, freight cars or our personnel on the operating craft side, have recall plans that we have for 30, 60, 90 days that we can do. And we think right now we've got at least 10% capacity &#x2013; 10 to 15% capacity &#x2013; in our existing network. But I can assure you that we spend a large amount of time looking at the cyclicality of our business and how can we respond to that immediately. So, there are very well defined plans, well rehearsed in terms of how we recall these resources back. We are not going to get caught short again and we're not going to overspend and making that protection too abundant, either.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think one of the things I think about here is you've got the fixed infrastructure, as Dennis said. The fixed infrastructure is probably a 200,000 carload per week number. In terms of what's built in there is the variable operating resources, as Duff said, is 10 to 15%. But there are other things. We introduced that alternative work program, where we keep employees at least current and training their benefits are paid. That was &#x2013; has worked very well for us as we've started to call them back. I will tell you, I'm very confident on the processes we've put in place and our ability to respond. I'm going to respond to the context I want to handle that volume and provide great service. I mean that is what we will lean to here when we think about recovery, but we're ready to handle it when it comes back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Second question, just relating to the safety and casualty adjustment in the second quarter of 38 million, was that a true-up and look-back for prior periods like we saw with CSX in the East in their second quarter? What &#x2013; I'm trying to get a sense of the economic impact allocated between the relevant period. Is that a true-up or is that a run rate savings going forward?  How should we think about the net year-over-year savings and impact going forward and contribution to the other expense line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rob?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean it's a look-back. I mean it's a look at over a number of years, looking back. We do get an ongoing benefit, Matt, in the neighborhood of the 2 or $3 million kind of number. But the adjustment in the actuarial study that we took in the second quarter was primarily a look back over the last several years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that 2 to $3 million you just mentioned, that was per quarter going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rough numbers, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Last question from me, then on Agricultural, obviously the export story there is impacting everyone in the industry. I'm just wondering in terms of looking for signs of a turn in Ag, are there one, two or three things that you can point to that should lead us out of this downturn, be it exports, be it on the fertilizer side? Just in terms of barometers, what do your Ag guys watch for in terms of a more meaningful turn away from what would be more macro-driven weakness in the industrial segments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we're looking at right now, Matt &#x2013; so here's what we monitor. The first thing is global crop situation. That plays a big role. Last year, we had record-setting performance because the rest of the crops around the world had not prepared all that well and the US dollar was weaker. So with the strength, some strength, back in the dollar, you know not to mercenary about this, but the good news was when we see the drought in Argentina, and we see their soybean crop substantially reduced, that says our soybean harvest and then beyond, going forward in the fourth quarter, you should see some opportunity from that hitting the US markets, just from an overall supply situation.</p>
          <p>Second thing we look at is animal counts. We've been surprised that the animal count across the US has not increased more. It's still below year-ago levels and at some point in time, we do expect that to pick up. When that does, that'll be another trigger point for us. The third is, the quality of the crops and right now the crop quality in the US looks excellent. There was an increase in corn acreage year-over-year and also an increase in soybean acreage. So that should help us as well.</p>
          <p>And then the last thing we look at in particular is wheat and in the UP-served territory, the wheat crop did pretty well and all we need now is for some demand to start drawing that into the market and we should see that turnaround. So, we're kind of hopeful we'll see a little bit of an improvement in the fourth quarter, although we still don't expect it to match last year's record-setting performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you very much for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from the line of Walter Spracklin of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead with your question sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the &#x2013; I just want to go to your intermodal and some of the price realization on that. We're hearing some more about increased price competition, price discounting and that some of the customers are looking at truck as a &#x2013; going back to truck from rail and sort of counter to what we've been hearing from you guys. I just wanted to hear your updates on how you're looking at the trucking competition, whether you think it's sustainable and how you're approaching it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've been consistent here that the intermodal market and trucks have been pretty tough for a half a year or more. Many cases, when you look at the pricing, it's not sustainable and the question that we have to decide is whether we're going to chase it and in several cases, we haven't. So it really does vary by corridor and the markets we're in. What we're focused on is kind of long-term plan, building those products that are in there, working with customers, helping them understand the long-term perspective of our market, but I will tell you, I'm not going to chase it. And our pricing is still on the positive side when you look at taking fuel off the table, but it is one that you have to decide kind of a tactical versus strategic discussion with the customer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good color. Just moving on, just still on the pricing, but more on sort of the regulatory side, can you give us an update on what you're hearing out of Washington? It's sort of gone radio silent there as they're working away on the bill and just any update on the talks that you've had, if they're going well and just your view on regulatory environment going into the next 6 to 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our industry, as you know, and all the CEOs are very active back on the Hill. Obviously there are, I think, other priorities on the current administration's agenda besides new regulations for us, but we're not going to let our guard down. We're continuing to be aggressive in terms of working with Chairman Rockefeller's staff in terms of understanding the long-term, one, values of our industry and the economic realities. I'll tell you a good example that I think is important. We're focused a lot on the potential new regulation side, but you have Chairman Rockefeller and Senator Lautenberg, who wrote a bill proposal to shift 10% of the business moving on highways to the railroads.</p>
          <p>Now they didn't, weren't specific about how that actually is accomplished. But I think it gives you a little insight in terms of where their thinking is on the value of rail in the United States. We are &#x2013; we've made it very clear on what I think where the points of a real conflict are and what's needed for this industry continue to invest. Again I can't predict. You may see something come out of the house this week on antitrust. But at the end of the day, this thing's going to be handled over on the Senate as a starting point and we'll see what happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you expected in the next six months, three months, out of the Senate or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a tough call. I'm going to &#x2013; listen. One thing, you can never assume anything when it comes to DC. Our view is we're gong to be very active. We're going to be very aggressive on the consequences here and we're going to be aggressive on telling the story in terms of the value of railroads.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is coming from the line of Ken Hoexter with Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon &#x2013; good morning. Rob I just want to revisit. You were kind of &#x2013; at the end of your presentation, you gave a bit of outlook for how things were trending. You talked a bit about fuel. I just wanted to understand, were you trying to suggest, then, that earnings deceleration would continue at a faster pace because of the $0.40 comp in fuel that you are not going to have that you had in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Ken, I was making &#x2013; trying to make clearer what the impact of fuel has meant on us year-to-date but, yes. Look at last year's third and fourth quarters, where there was a dramatic difference in terms of how fuel played out in the third and fourth quarter of last year versus the first and second quarter of last year. So when you look year-over-year, assuming the fuel stays about where it is, you kind of come up with a different equation in the back half then you did in the first half. Assuming fuel prices stay where they are, which nobody knows what's going to happen with fuel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then Jim I just want to revisit the &#x2013; looking at volumes down over 20% and the record low employment levels, I think Dennis kind of highlighted you're not nervous that you're overdoing it on the employee side. But however, if volumes stay at these levels, is there more that you can continue to pull out on the cost side, if you kind of stay at this static volume level, let's say for the next six months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we are not going to see the kind of drop you had, what we've seen in the last six months, but we're trying to gauge and we're being a little conservative here in terms of when this thing will come back. But if we continue to sit at this kind of a level, you'll see more cost come out. You're not going to match, though, what you saw before, but clearly, we've got kind of a tier three, four and five kind of look at what we would do in our spending if this thing remains flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just, have you been approached by any of the unions to say on that 4.5% wage increase job, jobs are more important than getting that wage increase? Is that something you've had discussions at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Ken I &#x2013; where we're spending our time with &#x2013; You know, I give town halls, all over the railroad. We get folks in the room there and we talk about what's going on. It's very clear in talking with our local Chairmen, the General Chairmen, the Presidents of our unions. I just had lunch in DC with one of our Presidents. They're all over jobs. They're focused on what do we need to do in terms of turning the economy around. I get that from whether you're the head of the union or the &#x2013; you just were hired three or four years ago. They understand the importance of safety. They understand service, what it means in terms of putting products in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>We have not had any discussions about that tradeoff at this point, that's out here. I &#x2013; that'll be part &#x2013; when you get into the next round of negotiations, all these things will be on the table here. But my goal is to make them understand what they can do to help us on service and safety and then also on the political world in terms of where DC may be dealing with some new regulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And did they &#x2013; do the Presidents seem responsive in getting involved at this point in those discussions, or do they want to wait to see what comes out? I just want to understand how, when you use that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ken, they're more involved than they ever have been. The consequence &#x2013; and I don't care whether you're talking about new regulations or you're talking about cap and trade. One of the things, again, that we are doing and I say this as the industry, is helping all of our folks understand the consequences of the legislation. And yeah, you can call it what you want to, but it's jobs and I've seen a willingness where they want to be at the table with us talking about what the consequences are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks for the time, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from the line of Chris Ceraso with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is Allison Landry in for Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Could you guys talk a little bit about the Colorado, Utah mine issues? What's going on there and when you're expecting things to get a little bit better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know the Colorado, Utah mines at the moment have been plagued with some really, really tough geology. Coal quality with some limestone deposits in the coal seam and just a variety of very tough issues for them to deal with. You couple that with weak demand, and it creates the scenario that we have today. We're running basically 8 trains a day or so out of Colorado, Utah. That's down from, what I would say our kind of record-setting levels of 12 or 13 trains a day. So it's just now it's pretty soft. They're working to solve those problems. I think they're working to get them resolved as quickly as possible, moving forward. If the demand were a lot stronger, they would probably work a little harder or may be spend a little more to get them resolved more quickly. But they're doing their best that they can with the economic scenario they have. There still is some, ample demand for Colorado and Utah coal and sooner or later they'll get it behind them and we'll be moving forward there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Is it still about 15% of your coal business or is &#x2013; has that declined?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's see, that might &#x2013; I would say that's, roughly, it's not too far different than that, because the whole coal business has declined as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay, and then in terms of natural gas, I know it's about 350, which is a little bit more than the competitive PRB price, but even still, have you guys seen any switching at utilities on the margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In our served territory, the natural gas capability to switch is not prevalent. Most of the utilities that we serve, they have peaking capacity in natural gas. But they, the majority of them, don't have the wholesale ability to switch over. However, given that you have the grid out there, that doesn't completely insulate us from low natural gas prices because other organizations and utilities that do &#x2013; can sell to the grid, so depending on the pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, John. And I think the switch, if it's &#x2013; has already happened. We have &#x2013; you look at the price of natural gas, we had some stories that you had natural gas at two bucks in some of the markets. So any meaningful shipped has already happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from John Larkin with Stifel Nicolaus. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the questions. I had a couple of questions on the domestic intermodal side, which looked very good for you. Congratulations, by the way, on winning that hub business. That's a huge win. How much of the hub business was included in the second quarter? I got the impression that that was spooling up during the quarter. What would the domestic intermodal would have been, say, without hub and what would it have been in terms of growth if hub had been running full bore with you the entire quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want to me to -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take it. Listen, if you look at that domestic market, it started &#x2013; hub started to come into play towards the end in June. Hub has actually been part of our business for a long time and their core business was growing from &#x2013; in terms of what they had already had on us. So it did have an impact in terms of the core. I don't want to get into the specific numbers. I think you have to keep in mind, though, in this market we have won some and we've lost some, if you look at the year-over-year comps that are out there. And again, I feel good about our domestic strategy that I think right now is just really starting to play. This is one that there's, I think, much more upside for us going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But fair to say that that growth rate with hub in the fold for the entirety of the second half should be a little bit higher in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You'll see &#x2013; that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then you talked about your Streamline product and how that has been growing very nicely for you. About 40%, if I heard it correctly, of that growth is coming from the highway. The other 60%, is that coming from the other Western railroad or is that coming from other IMCs or other folks that operate on your system?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What it is, John, is it's coming, a lot of it, from our own system, where the IMCs are moving from a ramp-to-ramp product to the door-to-door product that Streamline offers. So it's a value-add in terms of the product that we offer and also a margin enhancement for us, so, so that's a good business for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then, maybe just one last question, is it fair to say that as you've done such a great job of variablizing your cost structure, that you've been able to take the 25 or 30% of the least efficient locomotives, the least efficient freight cars, maybe those that are closest to needing major maintenance and laying those up, and then at the same time essentially furloughing your least experienced or least productive workers? Is it possible to be that good about eliminating the most inefficient assets and people?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Duff, you want to take it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think that's a pretty fair assessment, John. I mean we did put down our older, most inefficient locomotives. We did do the same thing with the freight cars as much as possible and obviously it's a seniority-based system, so the younger employees do get furloughed first. But as we've said, we try and keep them trained and ready to go because we don't want to suffer any productivity loss when we do do the recalls and the same way with our cars and our locomotives. So we're not totally neglecting them. We're making sure that they're work-ready and ready to come back under all three of those scenarios, the employees, locomotives and the freight cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there won't be a big lump of managed expense when you take them out of storage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Will not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, John. This is Jack Koraleski, one more time. I just want to clarify. Some of that 60% did come off the competition. Clearly hub is a good customer of Streamline as well. So I don't want to imply that none of it came from, but I just don't think that was a major drawing factor of the 60%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question will be coming from the line of Edward Wolfe of Wolfe Research. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, just a couple of clarifications. You talked about pricing, real pricing, up around 5% which is down from 6% you were talking about last quarter. Can you talk about, in the three months which segments that are relatively feeling a bit weaker and which ones are holding up a bit firmer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ed, I would be careful about interpreting the 5%, that it's weakening price. You also have a mix impact in there, when you think about, a good example is in the auto business where we've been able to renegotiate some legacy contracts, yet the book of business is off 50%, or you think about coal is another one that you've got a book of business that has still outstanding and some large legacy contracts that have been renegotiated and that business is all down. So it &#x2013; I would look at that more in the context of, again, we said five to six for the year. We had a little bit stronger first quarter, but I'm in the bottom end of the range for second quarter. I think the majority of that, again is mix. I mean, Jack you want to -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that is not what I would describe as same-store sales. It is in fact what you would say is the actual price realization for us. So to the extent the business didn't move, we weren't able to capture any price off of it. There really hasn't been any substantive change in our pricing environment between the first and second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Jim can you talk a little bit about the timing as you understand it for the regulatory bill? I think you said the antitrust could come in a week in the House, but the Senate regulatory bill, any sense that there's a chance that still happens before August recess, or at this point as this a if it's going to come, it's at the end of year at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, before the August recess. I would tell you one other thing with this bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't hear what you said Jim. You got low.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, nothing will happen before August. What is also important to understand about this bill, the members on the Hill that are involved with this discussion understand the significance of this thing and it is complicated. And we made it very clear that if you get it wrong, capital is going the other way. And they understand that, so I don't &#x2013; what I don't see a focus here to get something done quickly. If something happens, they want to get it right because they do understand the consequence so. Nothing will happen before August, I think. There's one side of me says nothing happens this year, but we can't take that assumption. We're going to be very active working our story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for that. Slide 17, where you talk about bringing back some of the resources and the April, May peaks for furloughs and locomotive stored, if I look at these numbers, you're bringing back 17% of your heads and 9.5% of your locos and 15% of your cars. If I look at '08, there really wasn't much on an absolute basis change volume between third and second quarter. What's your assumption here of peak and if it doesn't happen, is it easy to put the stuff back into the closet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh sure. There's not &#x2013; what you have to be careful of now, again, is you don't want to &#x2013; calling employees back &#x2013; I mean it's tough, obviously, furloughing people here. I mean it's real personal in terms of what it means to them and you have to be careful about calling them back then cutting them off again, so we want to make certain we see some trends here. But you &#x2013; if this thing turns back around and starts going south on us, we will put more assets back in storage and we'll unfortunately be forced to furlough employees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And why, I mean other than just &#x2013; historically there's a seasonal pick up. We didn't see it last year, obviously. Do you think there's going to be a seasonal pick up this year that you're doing that? Is that a safe assumption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well keep in mind though, Ed, you also have attrition here. You know we're going to lose this year. I just looked at the latest numbers in terms of our attrition rate and we're going to lose 3,000 employees this year. Now, that's down from where we were running, but we do have real attrition that we've got to keep up. And then again, the seven-day run rate, when you look at car loadings, has picked up. We're running about 151 or so right now. We were at 143. So it &#x2013; and my gut says you will see some seasonal, a little more attritional seasonal pick-up with a peak. But we watch it very closely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Jim and/or Dennis, Jim you said before that volumes are the key, because you can leverage them here. Where do you think you can start to leverage volumes in terms of margin, is it minus 15ish? Is it minus 10ish? Where is kind of directionally, you start to see some of that leverage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anytime you have, right now even the current train network we're running has capacity in terms of train size. So you think about again, coal would be different because coal has incremental train starts, although you're not adding any capacities there. So it's immediate when you look at the first 5, 10% of bump in business volume, you are not going to see much in terms of adding new train starts into our network. So it, I think, is pretty significant and pretty immediate when it starts to turn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just last question on cash, before you said you got $1.7 billion and 400 million's more of a normal level. Does that 1.7 keep going up? Is there some level, 2.2 billion, or is there some debt that you have in mind that you want to make sure you have covered for out a couple of years from now? Where do we think that that you stop growing the cash and start to deploy it in other ways?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we'll continue to grow cash as the business earns income here. I don't see us doing any incremental addition of debt in terms of what's out there. Again we're being cautious on &#x2013; I just don't have a visibility. You can see, forecast that say this is &#x2013; it's stable, but this is just a kind of a point before you turn down even more that's out here. We're being cautious and again I want to put our company in a good position that when it does turn around, we've got some great opportunity to return value to shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, at this point -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About $500 million of debt due next year. So that's all part of the equation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it sounds like if we're modeling for the end of the year, we're going to assume that you're going to continue to generate some free cash and that 1.7 goes up, not a substantial change to your dividend or start to repurchase stock at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It could Ed, but again it's a function of where the business is going here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks so much for the time. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from the line of Gary Chase of Barclays Capital. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Gary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just wanted to quickly clarify something, Jim, first and obviously I know you're not going to talk about the specifics, but somebody had asked you about GM and whether the bankruptcy allowed you to open that process. My understanding would be they could open it, but you couldn't and all I'm asking is should we expect that there's going to be some resolution on that business, or is it just as likely that you'll keep operating under the old contract until it renews?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well your assessment's right. They have the option, we didn't, of changing the contract. You know there's just &#x2013; there's a short time left. I'm not going to get into the details and we're in discussions right now. And quite honestly, with the service products and the value we're providing &#x2013; I mean, they adopted the old contract I guess is the point, but there's a pretty short time left on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's just, it's the way it was. There's nothing special that the bankruptcy creates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And you've talked a lot about the unified plan and the ability to better leverage volumes and there have been a lot of questions. When you were answering Ed a second ago, you mentioned attrition and we can see the headcounts. I guess, as we see the volumes start to pick up as it is depicted in one of your charts here, should we expect that head count could continue to go down on a net basis? Is it going to flat or are you going to need to take some heads back on period-to-period, on a net basis net of attrition, in order to handle that volume growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we've got some actions underway right now that we're reducing employment that doesn't show in these numbers here. Again, when you say when it turns back up how quickly will we respond, you're going to lever very nice, but we're going to have to make the decision is this is a sustainable trend. That will be the decision point in terms of calling employees back. So I don't &#x2013; I'm not quite certain where that head count number will go. I mean, quite honestly, I hope it starts to move up as we continue to grow aggressively over the next several years. Because if you look at, it'll be in the areas where you see the direct connection to volume, like our train and engine crews. That is where the biggest reduction has come in play and it's &#x2013; over the &#x2013; over a quarter period, it's directly related to volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just quickly, everybody's talking, you're no doubt aware of, of and no doubt aware of the auto production outlook as we move from the second to the third quarter. Presumably that's going to have a significant impact on your volumes and I assume --  network-wide, you talk about capacity network-wide, but it obviously matters what you've got in specific lanes. Presumably, you're fully prepared to handle whatever you're expecting from that production increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gary, the thing about these numbers, the first half of the year, production was at about 3.8 million units, if I recall, 3.5 million out there. I think the forecast of a 10-million year is about right. So if you think about that, we know inventories are at, I think, the lowest point they've ever been, about 64 days right now. They were running as high as 118. The 118 isn't realistic, but they're clearly very low. So you have the potential for the numbers to pick up quite nicely on the autos. We are very well positioned. We handle the &#x2013; we're the largest carrier of finished vehicles in the West. We're very well positioned to handle the pick-up. I'm looking forward to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, guys. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question is coming from the line of William Greene of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead with your question sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Just a couple of quick questions on the follow-up with autos, inbound and outbound, does that matter for you? Because I think if you as mostly a destination railroad, so is it really just about production, not about kind of what you would send into plants?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No it would be balanced for us, but we're interested in inbound, outbound, certainly the auto parts and then there's also how does it impact the steel manufacturers and everybody else that plays in. So it is &#x2013; we have such a large piece of that business that the whole piece of it matters a great deal to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you, do you have an estimate about what all automotive-related traffic is on UP?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How about on international intermodal, what did that move in the quarter on a volume basis year-over-year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Down in 28, 30% range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's it. Thanks, I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Bill. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions at this time. I would now like to turn the floor back over to Mr. Jim Young for closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I want to thank all of you for joining us this morning. And we look forward to talking with you again with our third quarter earnings. Again, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's teleconference. You may disconnect your lines at this time. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>