<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1279677" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-01-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>518</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James R. Young, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John J. Koraleski, Executive Vice President, Marketing and Sales</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dennis J. Duffy, Executive Vice President, Operations</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Robert M. Knight, Jr., Executive Vice President, Finance and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">John Larkin</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Robert Knight, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Walter Spracklin</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Matthew Troy</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Thomas Wadewitz</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Gary Chase</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Randy Cousins</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">William Greene</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Ken Hoexter</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Christopher Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Edward Wolfe</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Jon Langenfeld</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Donald Broughton</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Jeff Kauffman</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Cherilyn Radbourne</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Jason Seidl</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Greetings, and welcome to the Union Pacific Fourth Quarter 2009 Earnings. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. A brief question-and-answer session will follow the formal presentation. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded and the slides for today's presentation are user-controlled.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to introduce your host, Mr. Jim Young, Chairman and CEO for Union Pacific. Thank you, Mr. Young. You may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Welcome to Union Pacific's fourth quarter earnings conference call. Joining me in Omaha are Rob Knight, our CFO; Jack Koraleski, Executive Vice President of Marketing and Sales; and Dennis Duffy, Vice Chairman, Operations.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter, we're reporting earnings of $1.08 per share, that's off $0.23 from 2008's record quarter. As we experienced throughout 2009, our quarterly results reflected the global recession with total volume down 5% year-over-year. For the full year, volumes declined 16% producing our lowest business levels in over a decade. We finished 2009 in an upswing, however, as fourth quarter carloadings was the highest of the year, both in absolute terms and year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Of course, the 2008 comparison period was already seeing the impact of the recession. As you'll recall, volumes were in a virtual free fall at the end of 2008, but it does point to some stability in freight demand as we enter the new year. Over the last several years, we've been executing our long-term strategy designed to drive Union Pacific's performance across every area of the business. Efforts to strengthen our infrastructure, deploy new technology and engage our employees positioned us to act quickly when the economy faltered. We idled resources, modified our operating plan, and adjusted our cost structure to the new lower demand levels. Despite the lower volumes, we achieved a number of performance milestones that demonstrate the focus and commitment of our organization.</p>
          <p>UP's safety performance set new records in employee, customer and public safety. Our operating team achieved best in virtually all metrics as we increased network fluidity, improved asset turns and delivered a highly reliable service product to our customer. The scores on our customers' satisfaction surveys validated our internal data with customers giving us their highest marks ever. We kept commitments, expanded our service offerings, and provided our customers with cost efficiencies to the benefits of rail transportation.</p>
          <p>In addition, UP's increasing value proposition continues to support our long-term pricing objective. We also achieved the best full-year operating ratio in the history of our company at 76%. Solid efficiency gains, continued pricing strength, and lower year-over-year fuel prices helped us to overcome negative volumes and generate better margins. Importantly, this sets the stage for us to produce strong bottom line leverage as volume returns. In addition, we ended the year with our balance sheet in great shape, solid free cash flow after dividends and a strong year and cash position. Overall, we feel satisfied by what we accomplished in 2009 given the challenges. Our objective coming into this year was to manage through the recession the best way possible, emerging at the end as a better company. And we believe, we've attained that goal.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it over to Jack to walk you through the business teams. Jack?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim, and good morning. As we close the books on 2009, we ended the year with some positive momentum, which we're hoping carries forward here into 2010. Three of our six businesses groups; Ag products, automotive and intermodal posted gains during the fourth quarter as volume made its strongest showing of the year, but still ended the quarter down 5% against 2008. Our pricing came in at just under 5% for the quarter, but the decrease in RCAF fuel brought our net price realized to 3.5%.</p>
          <p>Much like in the third quarter, the timing of our legacy expirations didn't give us much of a fourth quarter boost, and our legacy intermodal contracts actually resulted in negative pricing in our intermodal business lines. We should see that situation improve over time, with our new Pacer arrangements in place. At the same time, volume growth in intermodal created negative mix for it. All of our other businesses had positive pricing, although the economy didn't help, especially in industrial products and Ag products where tariff-based pricing was more reflective of what's going on in the economy.</p>
          <p>Taken altogether, average revenue per car declined in all the groups and many of our customers realized the net year-over-year reduction in their freight bills as a result of lower fuel surcharges. Overall, average revenue per car was down about 9%. With volume and average revenue per car down from 2008, revenue declined 13% to $3.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Now let me take you through a look at each of our six businesses. We'll start with Ag. Our Ag products volume grew 3%, but a 10% decline in average revenue per car resulted in a 7% reduction in revenue. Soybean volume increased 68% over fourth quarter 2008's record levels, as damage to the South American soybean crop combined with a plentiful U.S. supply to create a strong export market. Demand was also strong for soybean meal, with specific Northwest export shipments more than doubling the previous best achieved back in 2003. With all the former VeraSun plants now operational and under new ownership, ethanol volumes grew 13% and DDGs also saw a continued growth, they were up 11%. Record unit train shipments supported the growth in whole grains and grain products throughout the quarter.</p>
          <p>Our automotive volumes grew 1%, but revenue declined 1% as the average revenue per car fell 2%. Although light vehicle sales declined from third quarter's Cash for Clunkers highs, they remained much stronger than the first half of the year. With inventory replenishment and production increases, our finished vehicle shipments increased 37% from the third quarter, posting their strongest levels of the year and coming in flat versus 2008.</p>
          <p>Parts volume grew 2% with its best showing in five quarters. And also during the quarter, we wrapped up negotiations on our last remaining major legacy contract in our automotive business and that new contract is set to take effect at the end of this month.</p>
          <p>Our chemicals volume was down 2%, which combined with a 5% decline in the average revenue per car, and resulted in a 7% revenue decrease. Docked economic conditions continue to impact key segments of our chemical business with soda ash volume down 13%; sulphur down, 14%; and a 6% drop in petroleum products.</p>
          <p>Fertilizer volume declined 7% with soft demand for fall purchases, driven in part by a relatively late harvest. The plastics business grew 9%, as strong exports offset a 1% decline in domestic shipments and our industrial chemicals were up 2%. Stronger demand for heating fuels and propylene shipments drove a 4% growth in LPG.</p>
          <p>In energy, high stockpiles and lower electrical demand led to a 15% drop in volume from 2008's record fourth quarter carloading. I think energy is a good example of how lower fuel surcharge revenues and negative mix masked our positive pricing in most of our business groups. Solid price gains driven by legacy renegotiations in prior periods were completely offset by fuel surcharge declines, and negative mix drove average revenue per car down 8%. That decline, combined with a shortfall in volume to lower revenue to 22%.</p>
          <p>Powder River Basin volume was down 16% as a result of softer demand and the SPRB contracts that we lost at the beginning of 2009, which accounted for about a third of that drop in volume. Loadings out of Colorado/Utah were down 20%, hindered by soft demand and to a lesser degree, continued coal quality problems. We had strong service performance and that was reflected in a number of best fourth quarter productivity measures for both the Powder River Basin and Colorado/ Utah.</p>
          <p>Industrial products volume fell 21%, which combined with a 9% drop in the average revenue per car to produce a 28% decline in revenue. Continuation of low steel mill production translated into a 32% decline in steel shipment. Our rock business was down 29% because of soft demand and high inventories, and the story is pretty much the same for cement, where our volume was down 37%.</p>
          <p>Lumber volume was down 23% as housing starts continued to track well below 2008 levels. Hazardous waste posted significant growth with our uranium tailings move in Utah and the Hudson River clean up combining to add over 10,000 new units of business in our fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Intermodal revenue was down 3% as lower fuel surcharges and the legacy price reductions more than offset the 5% improvement in volume. Our International volume declined 9% even as the segment showed some surprising seasonal strength with fourth-quarter volume up 3% from the third quarter. More than offsetting the softness in International was a 28% improvement in the domestic segment. The shift of hub business provided about half of that growth, but the strength of our value proposition in the domestic intermodal market drove the rest.</p>
          <p>Our streamline subsidiaries door-to-door product grew 42% in volume, with nearly 70% of that growth coming off the highway. And this actually marked the first quarter that our domestic revenues surpassed international in our intermodal business line.</p>
          <p>As Jim said, 2009 was a great year for customer satisfaction. Great service continues to underpin the strong value proposition for our customers. Overall, satisfaction came in at 88 for the fourth quarter, equaling the record set during the third quarter and our full year also came in at 88, which is up four points from 2008's record setting performance.</p>
          <p>So what about 2010? Let's start with our legacy contracts. The pie chart on the left shows you where we were a year ago as we headed into 2009. Legacy contracts with 2% of our revenue had been renegotiated towards the end of 2008, about 18% remained, with about 1% still to be renewed in 2009 and about 3% lined up for 2010. With the pull ahead of a piece of our Pacer contract and our last major automotive contract now renewed, the pie chart on the right shows that of that 18% remaining at the end of 2009, 4 percentage points has been renegotiated for 2010 and we expect at least another percentage point to be completed by year end. This will leave about 13% of our revenues still moving under legacy pricing as we move into 2011 and beyond. The bar on the bottom of the chart shows that about two thirds of that remainder falls within our energy business, just under 30% intermodal and the remaining 4% is spread among the other four businesses.</p>
          <p>So, we're continuing to make good progress. We're continuing to work hard to accelerate the renegotiations of legacy deals where that makes sense, and although the benefits of the new Pacer arrangement are phased in between now and the original expiration, our legacy contract renewals are still a solid contributor for our price plans as we remain absolutely committed to renewing those deals at market rates and helping us to reach our reinvestability objectives.</p>
          <p>Okay, from there 2010 becomes a little less clear. Global insight forecasts a slow recovery with key indicators climbing from the lows of 2009, but still remaining below the 2008 levels that were already depressed. Key to recovery will be improved consumer confidence reflected in increased spending. So, if the economy doesn't falter, we believe that all of our businesses have opportunities to grow in 2010, with the greatest potential, probably, in those that were hurt the most by the economic slowdown.</p>
          <p>In Ag products, ethanol and DDG should continue to grow as the renewable fuels and the California mandates kick in. You add to that some slight improvement in animal feeding and we could see some modest growth for the year in our Ag products business.</p>
          <p>Our automotive volume strengthened in the second half of 2009, and improved economic conditions and increased demand will likely drive further recovery in 2010. Expecting sales are going to be some place between 11 and 11.5 million for the year.</p>
          <p>As downstream demand improves, so should our chemical business, and we're hoping to see an improved fertilizer market, both here home and abroad. And we're not really counting much at this point on volume growth in coal, but the recent reports indicate that this severe cold weather, both here and around the world, may have put more of a dent in stockpiles than what we might be expecting. So if we see some improved industrial production and a more normal summer burn, there may even be a little opportunity out there for us in the coal business.</p>
          <p>A modest increase in housing and construction activity should translate into modest growth in lumber, rock, cement, and steel for our industrial products line. And when the construction season rolls around, we're going to be looking to see if stimulus spending provides more of a boost in 2010 than we saw in 2009.</p>
          <p>Hazardous waste was one of our few lines of business to post year-over-year volume gains in 2009, and we anticipate that's going to continue to grow again this year. And of course, that leaves us with intermodel, where a stronger economy should get our international business back into the black, and we're hopefully going to keep our momentum going on the domestic side of the business.</p>
          <p>Assuming fuel prices stay where they are, volume gains across the six businesses should combine with our pricing plan to drive revenue growth. While the economic improvement in 2010 would be welcome, our real opportunity lies in the strength of our value proposition, providing a solid foundation for our business development efforts and our price plan. Driving that value proposition is excellent service that results from the commitment of our employees, our strategic investments in facilities and equipments and the new and innovative solutions and offerings that we're providing to our customers. Our customer satisfaction score says we're headed in the right direction, and we're confident in 2010 we can do even better.</p>
          <p>With that, I'm going to turn it over to Dennis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jack, and good morning. The operating team put a solid finish on 2009, making improvements in all aspects of our operations. Let's start with safety, Union Pacific's top priority. So achieving record levels in all safety categories for the second straight year is a great accomplishment. For our employees, we achieved a 12% improvement in our incident rate as we continue deploying total safety culture, which emphasizes everyone's role in working safely together. Customers benefit from a safer railroad through enhanced reliability and lower cost. In 2009, the rate of equipment incidents was better by 10%. Our improved track infrastructure, training and process improvements all contributed.</p>
          <p>For the communities where we operate, our rate of grade crossing incidents improved by 11%, education, engineering work and improved technology all play a role in eliminating accidents. And that's really the goal, achieving a zero tolerance safety performance.</p>
          <p>From a service standpoint, '09 was also a record year across the board. We made strong velocity gains, finishing at a record 27.3 miles per hour, an increase of nearly two miles per hour from our previous best set in 2002.</p>
          <p>Freight car utilization, the cycle time between loaded moves was an all-time best at 8.6 days. Faster asset turns lets us move more freight with fewer cars, positioning us for strong volume leverage going forward. For example, the nearly two-day savings we've achieved from 2006 to 2009 equates to roughly a 34,000-car reduction in our active online inventory or 340 miles less of potential rail congestion.</p>
          <p>Terminal dwell time established an annual record at 24.8 hours, and more efficient operations drive a better service product establishing the new customer satisfaction records Jack discussed. These ratings are highly correlated with our internal service delivery index, which increased nearly eight points from 2008 and 23 points since 2006.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we faced the operating challenge of reducing costs while improving service. Moving into 2010, the added challenge will be performance sustainability, driving efficiency and service excellence regardless of the volume levels. Our formula for success is threefold. First, run a volume variable operation. For the full year, we were more than volume variable with our working resources, as train starts were down 20% with gross ton-miles off 17%.</p>
          <p>One way we achieved that productivity was by maintaining or increasing train length in every major category. Second, deliver service excellence. Looking at the middle chart, from 2006 when volumes were growing, SDI has continued to improve. Through our unified plan efforts, lean processes and customer inventory management systems, just to name a few, we've continued to make progress, no matter what the volume. We have seen a little reversion as a result of winter weather here lately, but that's already starting to snap back.</p>
          <p>And third, create upside leverage. While we took steps in 2009 to drive efficiencies and take out costs, we've also been positioning ourselves for the upside. I mentioned train size earlier. We believe there is still room to grow in most areas of our existing network offerings, particularly within our premium area, autos and intermodal.</p>
          <p>Another reason for this upside leverage is the significant progress we've made with our basic track infrastructure, reducing slow orders by 30% versus 2008, driving record velocity. Other significant capital projects includes the Boone High Bridge on our Iowa east-west mainline allows us to operate two trains across the bridge simultaneously at a maximum speed of 70 miles per hour, versus one train at 25 miles per hour.</p>
          <p>Completion of Centralized Traffic Control or CTC signaling all the way from Wyoming to Chicago, increased tunnel clearances on the Donner Pass in California, opening the route to double-stack intermodal containers. This saves us 75 miles and up to three hours for our customers, making UP's route the shortest and fastest from Oakland to Chicago. And we completed the Melrose connection, a strategic project in Chicago constructed as part of the Create Project, illustrating a public-private partnership that can really work for UP, the city of Chicago, and the shipping community.</p>
          <p>Turning to 2010. Coming off a very solid year, we will continue to differentiate ourselves as a world-class transportation provider. Our 2010 goals are to drive towards best-in-class safety, enhanced service and asset utilization and stronger financial returns. Above all, we will be ready for whatever demand comes our way, up or down. Cyclical demand changes, seasonal variations, and hopefully a strengthening of the economy, all require that we stay agile and resilient.</p>
          <p>So with that, let me turn it over to Rob for a look at the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dennis, and good morning. Let me start things off with a high-level earnings summary. Fourth quarter operating revenue declined 12% to $3.8 billion as a result of continued weakness in our business volumes and lower year-over-year fuel surcharge revenue. Operating expenses totaled $2.8 billion in the quarter, down 12%. Lower diesel fuel prices, along with Union Pacific's initiatives to operate in a volume variable manner, contributed to the year-over-year decline. The net result of lower revenue and expense was a 12% decline in operating income to $1 billion. Other income was down slightly at $23 million, and an effective tax rate for the quarter came in at 36.8%. Altogether, these results produced fourth quarter net income of $551 million and earnings per share of $1.08.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 23, this slide gives some perspective about how we view the year-over-year change in earnings. Starting at the left, we show reported 2008 earnings of $1.31 per share. Comparing the year-over-year change in fuel prices and the resulting lag impact, 2008 benefited versus 2009 by roughly $0.22. That brings 2008's comparable earnings, excluding the impact of fuel to $1.09 per share. With the two months lag in our fuel surcharge programs, fuel price fluctuations between months or quarters can impact earnings. And as you'll recall, the fourth quarter of 2008 benefited from the fuel surcharge lag as fuel prices declined rapidly in that quarter.</p>
          <p>Included in 2009 earnings are a couple of items that I'll give you more detail on later, but they essentially netted out to a zero impact in the quarterly results. The first item was casualty related. Although both 2008 and 2009 benefited from our reduced expenses associated with our strong safety performance, the 2009 change was larger year-over-year, adding $31 million or $0.04 per share to earnings.</p>
          <p>Also included in our 2009 results, was a previously announced one-time payment of $30 million to Pacer. So on a more comparable basis, we see our 2008 and 2009 results being pretty flat year-over-year, demonstrating that, despite the lower volumes, we generated a strong financial performance in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning now to pricing. As Jack just described for you, our pricing initiatives, legacy renewals and valued service contributed nearly 5% price growth in the quarter. Similar to the third quarter, however, the negative drag of RCAF fuel reduced that 5% by about 1.5 points, bringing our reported core price in around 3.5%.</p>
          <p>Full year 2009 core price came in a little over 4.5%, consistent with our view of being close to the 5% mark. Again, negative RCAF fuel reduced our reported price by roughly a point on a full-year basis. Interestingly, as you could see from the chart on the right, UP's full-year 2009 price initiatives, excluding the RCAF fuel impact was about 0.5 point higher than 2008's pricing.</p>
          <p>As you'll recall, we define core price as an all-in yield number that is applied to the entire portfolio. This differs from a same-store sales type of methodology, which only looks at that portion of the portfolio that matched year-over-year. On that basis, our 2009 pricing numbers would probably have been somewhere over 6%.</p>
          <p>Turning now to expenses. Compensation and benefits totaled a little more than $1 billion in the quarter, an 8% decline. Consistent with our actions throughout 2009, we worked aggressively to align workforce levels with demand. In fact, with the 10% fourth quarter decline to just over 42,000 employees, every area of the business is working with fewer employees today than it did 12 months ago. On top of these employment actions, we're working more efficiently overall and utilizing less overtime. The combination of greater efficiency and lower volumes enabled us to offset the 4.5% wage increase given to our agreement employees last July. In addition, quarterly costs related to post retirement benefits declined year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter fuel expense fell 26% to $541 million. Lower year-over-year diesel fuel prices, lighter volumes and improved efficiency, all contributed to the $191 million decline. On average, diesel fuel price in the quarter was $2.05 per gallon. This compares to $2.46 per gallon in the year-ago quarter and saved a little more than $100 million. In addition, a 10% decline in gross ton miles reduced quarterly diesel fuel expense $73 million. That savings, combined with greater fuel efficiency, decreased total fourth quarter fuel consumption 33 million gallons.</p>
          <p>Slide 27 shows purchased services and material expense, down $37 million or 8% to $421 million. On the purchased services side, this category continues to see the benefit of Union Pacific's efficiency efforts, as well as the impact of less volume. In the fourth quarter, with fewer train starts and greater crew productivity, we used less crew transportation and lodging. In addition, our joint facility costs and other contract services declined year-over-year. For material costs, ongoing reductions to locomotive and freight car repairs contributed to the lower quarterly expense. Similar to what we've experienced throughout 2009, reduced volumes and fleet storage contributed to this result.</p>
          <p>Depreciation expense increased $24 million in the fourth quarter, or 7%, to $377 million. The drivers are pretty evenly split between our ongoing capital programs and the locomotive leases we restructured in the second quarter. Although the restructuring added expenses to the depreciation line, it reduced equipment and other rents by $22 million.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter equipment and other rents was a total of $54 million lower in the quarter at $266 million. In addition to the lease restructuring, lower volumes, UP's increased asset utilization and reduced use of leased equipment contributed to the cost reductions in this category.</p>
          <p>Short-term car rents were also lower in the quarter, down $23 million, as a result of reduced business volumes and better freight car utilization. Other expense totaled $129 million in the fourth quarter, a 29% or $52 million year-over-year decline. This expense line had a number of moving parts. The biggest addition to the quarterly expense was the $30 million payment to Pacer in November. This was offset, however, by $31 million of year-over-year expense reductions related to our casualty costs.</p>
          <p>Consistent with the record safety metrics that Dennis just discussed, our semi-annual actuarial study resulted in a quarterly change that lowered our casualty expense. Beyond these items, there were several components of the other expense line that drove the year-over-year decline. The primary contributors were better experience with the provision for bad debt and higher equity income. In addition, we exhibited very good cost control across a wide variety of expenses.</p>
          <p>Taken together, our cost structure has changed greatly over the past 12 months as we acted aggressively in response to the recessionary freight environment. As shown by the chart on the left, while our business volumes declined 16% in 2009, we reduced operating expense 13%. In this chart, we've normalized 2009 operating expenses to reflect the year-over-year change in diesel fuel prices, which illustrates that we were roughly 80% expense variable in 2009.</p>
          <p>Of course, we still have significant fixed costs in our business, as well as the ongoing impact of inflation, but what we've accomplished in 2009 is to combine lower volumes with strong efficiency gains and cost management to drive permanent changes. In fact, we'd estimate that about two-thirds of the 2009 expense reduction was driven by lower volumes while one-third came from productivity and cost control. We were able to achieve these savings as a result of our strategy to drive organizational efficiency, strong operating productivity and greater profitability.</p>
          <p>In particular, we are well positioned for the future and the opportunity to move growing volume. Of course, ultimately, UP's progress on improving total returns and profitability will be measured by our operating ratio.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, we made a slight improvement against a prior all-time best producing a 73.3% operating ratio. Greater productivity, a smaller cost structure and ongoing pricing gains offset the volume and fuel price headwinds to drive this record performance.</p>
          <p>On a full year basis, we reported a 76% operating ratio. This was also a new all-time best for Union Pacific and 1.3 points of improvement versus last year's record. Importantly, this is Union Pacific's fifth consecutive year of annual improvements in our operating ratio.</p>
          <p>I'll wrap up the earnings discussion with a look at full year income statements shown on slide 33. Operating revenue declined 21% versus 2008 to $14.1 billion. A 16% reduction in carloadings, coupled with $1.7 billion reduction in fuel surcharge revenue, more than offset the benefits of stronger core price. Operating expense fell 23% in 2009 to $10.8 billion. Although lower volumes and efficiency gains contributed to this decline, the biggest factor was lower fuel prices.</p>
          <p>Our average diesel price of $1.75 per gallon was 44% below 2008 levels and the lowest annual price since 2004. Other income increased $103 million year-over-year as a result of our second quarter land sale. Excluding that one-time item, other income was $79 million, or slightly lower versus 2008. Interest expense increased 17% to $600 million. This reflects a higher average debt level in 2009, as well as slightly higher year-over-year interest rates.</p>
          <p>Income tax totaled $1.1 billion in 2009, a 17% reduction. Driven by the weak economy, UP's lower earnings contributed to the decline and offset a slightly higher effective tax rate for the year. Our 2009 tax rate was 36.5% compared to 36.1% in 2008. 2009 net income totaled $1.9 billion, a 19% reduction versus a record 2008. Full year earnings were $3.75 per share, which compares to 2008's best ever earnings of $4.54 per share.</p>
          <p>Despite 2009's recession impact on our earnings, Union Pacific finished the year in a very strong position financially. Free cash flow after dividends totaled $515 million, compared to $825 million in 2008. While we had some puts and takes to cash flows in 2009, it does emphasize our ability to produce positive results in a tough economy.</p>
          <p>Looking at the balance sheet, although we increased our all-in debt by about $440 million versus 2008, we reduced our adjusted debt-to-cap to 45.9%. Our 2009 capital investments totaled a little more than $2.5 billion, just under our budget of $2.6 billion. The funding in 2009 was roughly 2.4 billion of cash capital and 100 million of capital leases.</p>
          <p>For 2010, we are still finalizing the budget, but our current thinking is that our base capital investment would be around $2.3 billion. On top of that, we will spend an additional $200 million on positive train control, bringing total capital to about $2.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Year-over-year by not purchasing new locomotives in 2010, we are saving roughly $300 million. Beyond that, we remain committed to making long-term investments in our company that support operating efficiencies, growth and returns.</p>
          <p>We must balance that, however, against the current economic environment. An example of this type of an investment is our new Joliet Intermodal Terminal. This facility, which accounts for about $150 million of our 2010 budget, supports our plans to convert more business from highway to rail, driving both intermodal pricing and return.</p>
          <p>Looking further at the year ahead, we are not providing specific financial or price guidance. I would like to discuss, however, some of the factors to consider as we think about 2010. As Jack discussed, we do see the potential for volume growth in all areas of our business. With 2009's depressed business levels, that seems like a reasonable expectation. But the actual magnitude of any growth will depend on the macro economy.</p>
          <p>Another plus for the year is our pricing. We are confident in our ability to achieve real price gains that cover the cost of doing business, plus the additional benefits of legacy contract renewals, and excellent service offerings. Balancing out these potential pluses for 2010 are fuel prices and inflation. Our current spot price for diesel fuel is a little more than $2.50 per gallon. At that price, we are paying over $0.60 per gallon more than 2009's first quarter average price of $1.51 per gallon. And at these prices we lose the benefit of the fuel surcharge lag experienced in the first half of 2009. As you might remember, in both the first and second quarters of 2009 the lag added roughly $0.20 per share to earnings each quarter.</p>
          <p>We also see labor inflation trending higher in 2010 versus 2009, particularly for agreement, health and welfare expenses. Of course, against that headwind we will work to offset at least a portion through greater productivity. Beyond these items, we have to stay flexible and nimble as an organization to effectively and efficiently handle whatever comes our way. In 2009, we played the hand that we were dealt and produced strong results. In 2010, we will build on that momentum to generate greater profitability and stronger shareholder return.</p>
          <p>Let me turn it back over to Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. We'll wrap up here. With 2009 behind us, we're looking forward to a new year and new opportunities. As you heard from both Jack and Rob, the volume picture is still uncertain, although most economists are calling for some growth. Within that environment, we'll continue to pursue the strategy we adopted several years ago to increase UP's value proposition through our investments, service offerings, technology, equipment ownership and our employees.</p>
          <p>These efforts are bringing new business to our railroad as well as opening the door to new markets that can benefit from the suite of services UP has to offer. With our customer satisfaction ratings approaching 90, we've really raised the bar in the eyes of our customers. They expect more from us today and we're prepared to deliver.</p>
          <p>Now, we also know that 2010 will be another active year in Washington. As you know, Senator Rockefeller introduced his rail legislation last month. We provided input to his staff of the Senate Commerce Committee prior to introduction and a number of changes were made to the bill. We're continuing to have discussions with the Senate staff today, but as we continue to study this very complex piece of legislation, our concerns have increased. In fact, without additional changes, we cannot support the bill.</p>
          <p>In addition, the FRA just released their final rules for positive train control, which as Rob mentioned adds 200 million to our capital budget this year, and at least 1.4 billion in total over six years. And that's just the capital installation cost. It will cost us millions more annually to maintain this system.</p>
          <p>The PTC mandate is an example of well-intended legislation with negative unintended consequences. Union Pacific shareholders cannot be expected to bear the financial burden of PTC. It must be passed on to our customers to the extent the market will permit, especially those chemical customers who drive the vast majority of our installation requirement. Our position, whether the discussion is PTC or other regulations, is that we must be allowed to earn adequate returns and attract new capital.</p>
          <p>With PTC for example, if we cannot be fully compensated, we will cut discretionary capital and our ability to expand and grow with our customers will be reduced. Although there seems to be unanimous agreement in D.C. that more freight rail is needed for the good of our environment, our nation's transportation infrastructure and our economy, new regulations and draft legislation that are coming forth do not support that vision, and in many ways could impede it. So stay tuned.</p>
          <p>For our shareholders, we remain committed to achieving the target of a low-70s operating ratio by 2012 and should make further progress towards the goal this year. We believe strongly in our ability to generate solid bottom line leverage from improving volumes, and we are focused on achieving pricing gains that reflect our strengthening value proposition.</p>
          <p>These efforts are the underpinning of our long-term strategy to invest for the future, grow with our customers and reward our shareholders. This is consistent with the belief that freight rail transportation has never been more important than it is today, with benefits that are undisputed.</p>
          <p>With that, it's time to open it up for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now be conducting a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you. Our first question is from the line of John Larkin with Stifel Nicolaus. Please go ahead with your question sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was wondering if you could give us a little more clarity on how labor cost increases will be feathered in during 2010 and what you expect the contractual obligations there to be in terms of a percentage increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well there are no more contractual obligations, other than the potential of a COLA sometime in the middle of the year. I would look at it pretty even overall, and contract negotiations are under way today. We still have long ways to go, but I don't see any particular spike in any given quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Was there any impact associated with reduced bonus accruals that benefited the fourth quarter results at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rob, do you want to answer that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A little, not much, not a material amount, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then maybe a broader question regarding the opportunity to grow domestic intermodal, which has obviously been doing quite well. I think there is a perception amongst some at least that most of the opportunity for future growth lies in the East, which hasn't been quite as well penetrated as the West. What's your view on the percentage of long-haul western intermodal domestic opportunities that's been already converted and how would you see that conversion continuing here over the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jack, do you want to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I think there is still plenty of opportunity in the long-haul. I couldn't put my finger on an exact percentage point, but in terms of long-haul west opportunities, when you look at the Highway business, it's moving out there today, there is still plenty of opportunities to convert business. We've had &#x2013; our streamline subsidiary that does door-to-door is doing quite well, the growth prospects and the conversion from the highway business is quite strong. So I don't view it as just an Eastern opportunity, I think we still have plenty of room on the West to grow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, there is one other piece to keep to mind here. You may recall, we walked away from quite a few markets years ago and are now re-entering those markets and you've got to have the capability to provide that great service consistently. So we're in a very good position; when we put new products in the market today, we're seeing great success; when we open a new ramp, we're seeing great success. So I think there is, again, like Jack, I think there is a very good opportunity for us for growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other thing, John, I think the length of haul of the move that we are able to compete in with the greater efficiency, the service parameters we put in place, the cost effectiveness now double stacking, some of the things Dennis showed in terms of like the Donner Tunnel clearances and things. Really, it's going to allow us greater efficiency that &#x2013; I think we're going to probably be able to move down into the 500 mile range in terms of effective competitive standing in the marketplace that will help us actually have more business available to take a look at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. That was very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Walter Spracklin with RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Walter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the operating efficiency, just found it interesting you noted that two-thirds due to volume decline, one-third due to efficiencies. Is that a good way to look at now what the productivity initiatives that you can hold on to regardless of where the &#x2013; where volumes come back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's not a linear relationship as volume goes back. These are all kind of set variable, but I think, that's not an unreasonable way to look at it long-term. We may &#x2013; the first &#x2013; again, you think about the first jump in volume, we're going to lever significantly. I've got 1,600 locomotives sitting in storage that we're depreciating. So you think about some of these costs that we will &#x2013; we've got a long way to run here on volume before you see a substantial jump in costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question &#x2013; my second one here is on the rail bill. And Jim, you mentioned that after further review, you have a few concerns out of that, suggest that you can't support it. Can you give us some color on what you looked at that you really don't like in this bill that's causing you to take this stand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's a very complex bill and it covers a whole range of areas; the ability to earn adequate revenues, there is no language on antitrust when you look at it. And again, what we are trying to do here is to step back and look at how do we, maybe, bring some certainty to our industry? Where they have been talking about new regulations ever since we were partially deregulated 20 some years ago, that's out here, and my number one concern is the ability in this business to earn returns.</p>
          <p>There is no discussion on replacement cost in this bill. That's a huge issue for us as we go forward. But, we've worked with Chairman Rockefeller. I'm &#x2013; he is a believer in rail. When he is &#x2013; when I've met with him personally, he has, he really is a &#x2013; advocates more business movement in the freight railroads. So I hope common sense prevails here and that we are incented to grow this business and not go the other way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That is great color. Thanks very much guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Matt Troy with Citigroup. Please go ahead with your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Rob, I was just wondering if you could comment on the balance sheet, per your own comments, obviously at the end of the year in a very strong position, more cash than UNP has ever ended the year with. Historically, you ran with about half the level of cash and investments you have on the balance sheet today. I was wondering if that level is a good run rate to bogey in terms of what you need to run the business quarter-to-quarter? And, as we think about avenues for capital deployment relative to the cash you ended with, what are the hurdle rates or assumptions you use and priorities you have for redeploying that cash as the economy feels a little bit better in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, you're exactly right. We ended the year with $1.8 billion on the books. Of course, we've had payments that have brought that down to about closer to 1.5ish today. That is &#x2013; you're right, that is a higher level than sort of a historical level. But, our priorities remain the same and that is we look at capital investments, where the returns are there, we'll continue to fund our dividend of course, but we look forward to the day when we can get back in, if you will, to the game of consistent dividend and consistent share buyback. But what we're waiting on there is just more clarity in the markets, more clarity in the economic environment, and we'll see that in consistent business levels. And when we see that, we'll feel more comfortable in moving forward deploying that, perhaps in a four-month share buyback.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And is it fair to assume that levels, let's call it between 500 million to a billion, is a more reasonable level of cash balance for the balance sheet directionally, if things &#x2013; assuming things do stabilize?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean, we'd like to see it on the lower end of that number that you just gave, but we'll have to see how the economy plays out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, to me &#x2013; this is Jim. It's really a function of what you see happening here in the economy. Obviously, we've been conservative. It's the right decision. There is still uncertainty when you think about where the economy is going this year. We're in good &#x2013; we're in a great position. Eventually, we have to deploy that cash and &#x2013; but I want to wait until we see some strength here in terms of where the economy is going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. The last question I have relates, and perhaps I'll ask it of Jack. On the coal front, obviously coal is a significant energy source for U.S. power generations and no one believes it's going away anytime soon, but obviously 2010 looks to be a challenging year, at least early on. I'm just curious, are you seeing any of your customers come to you seeking to renegotiate on take-or-pay contract, break the floor, or just think about being a little bit more aggressive about negotiations given the intermediate-term weakness? And how should we think about the recovery into the years? Are we really just waiting for more extreme weather? What gets us to the other side of this little blip in coal? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, I don't &#x2013; I wouldn't be able to tell you that we've seen a significant change in behavior from customers. I think we've had a couple of customers that would be interested, particularly as the chart showed about two thirds of my remaining legacy business is in the energy business. And I think some of those customers are kind of testing the waters to see if an early renewal of those would be beneficial to them and us. So we're kind of working through those deals. But I don't really think the behavior, I don't think the view of this has changed a heck of a lot.</p>
          <p>I think basically, as we sit right now, we're looking at Powder River Basin, our served customer base, probably on average has 75 days, of stockpile sitting out there, they feel more comfortable being at about 60. But within that average, we have some fairly large customers who said they'll take every train we can get them. And we have some that are trying to figure out ways to kind of slow the flow.</p>
          <p>And so we're working with everybody to try to meet the objectives and still deliver the coal. I do think from what we've been able to see and you read all of the Genscapes and EIA and all these kinds of things in terms of potential impact that the cold weather is having. And I think it's the cold weather prospects here in the U.S., but also in Europe and in China that says, there actually may be a little more upside out here than what we were thinking when we first got into this year. So I'm the eternal optimist in the crowd here, but I'm not willing to throw in the towel.  I think if we see continued improvement in the economy, I think a more normal weather pattern, I think we should be okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from the line of Tom Wadewitz with J.P. Morgan Chase. Please go ahead with your question sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's see, I wanted to ask you a couple of questions on pricing and I guess in specific the impact of the legacy repricing. So you gave us the charts on slide 24 that were pretty helpful. If you looked at the numbers in 2009, I guess, 5.5 &#x2013; include &#x2013; excuse me, excluding RCAF fuel, can you tell us how much of that 5.5 was due to legacy contracts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, we've said, and it's been pretty consistent about two points is what you look at. And that roughly is how it's playing out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that ex-legacy it would have been about 3.5. But it looks like you've &#x2013; I'm sorry, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it looks like you've got potentially a bit bigger impact from legacy contracts in 2010. I guess you got the Pacer late in 2009, so full-year impact in 2010 you got the GM and you got some other things. I guess it appears that there is a little more legacy impact in 2010. Would we assume that that's maybe another percentage point, maybe you get 3% impact or how would we view that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom I think you stick &#x2013; you kind of stick around that two points. I mean, you have to also keep in mind we still have legacy contracts that have negative and have a negative impact on pricing when you look at it long-term. So I wouldn't go that far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What about &#x2013; and if you take out legacy, would you expect much of a change in the repricing on the other part of your book that's really not legacy contracts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you've got some areas. We know &#x2013; always when you think about 2010, where is the economy going? We do have some areas that are softer like we've said, the intermodal area, maybe Ag a little bit. But given the &#x2013; what's happened here with demand in the economy, I feel pretty good about what we've been able to accomplish on our core pricing. And I will tell you, we are committed here. We've got to get the returns up in this business if we're going to justify the capital we're putting into it and that means the pricing line has to be strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then one &#x2013; well, I guess one more question on &#x2013; I guess, this is probably for Rob. In terms of the other operating expense, you helped us out with some of the reasons &#x2013; some of the noise in that line. It sounded like Pacer and the casualty offset each other, but that 129 million in the quarter was still a very low number. And I'm just wondering, should we run rate and the other operating expenses at a low number around that in 2010 or is that kind of materially lower than what you would think is a reasonable run rate? Because it was &#x2013; even with the clarification it seems like that was a very good performance, I'm just trying to understand whether that's sustainable or not on that line item?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Tom, there was some puts and takes in there. I think from a modeling standpoint, you're probably better off looking at 2008 level as more of a run rate, which is a little higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That, so back, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Back up to like the 180 million level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Somewhere around there, yeah. That's a safe &#x2013; that's probably a safer run rate there for your modeling purposes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, nice quarter. Thank you for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Gary Chase with Barclays Capital. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Gary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to ask Jack, you mentioned that I think somewhere in the prepared remarks that tariffs were more reflective of what was going on in the overall economy. Can you give us a sense of what was changing in those tariff rates during 2009, if there is a way to generalize, and what you think the outlook is for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gary, I think if you just kind of look at what's happening in the overall economy, what's happening in the tariff rates, we saw the increases we were taking in our tariff business somewhat less than what we had seen in the say in the last two, three, four years, and that's indicative of market conditions, competition, a lot of the truck side of things.</p>
          <p>And while we are not chasing business and we're making right decisions in terms of reinvestability, there are some of those issues that when we have the business at a profitable level, it's reinvestable in going forward. We are working with customers to reflect market conditions. So it's just a kind of a way of saying instead of getting some of the four and 5% increases, we were getting in various places the one or 2% kind of increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And has &#x2013; is there any sign that that's starting to show some traction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's really market specific. In some places, we've been able to see some turn around in the economy, we watch very carefully the price increases that our customers are taking in their markets. And so in selected places, we've had opportunities to be a little more aggressive because we've started to see some improvement in business, and in other places, we are still just kind of working with our customers to understand the market dynamics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is there a way Jack to give us just a qualitative feel on how Pacer phases in, is it focused at front-loaded, back-loaded, is it relatively even?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gary, I can just tell you that what I said in my remarks which is basically it's phased in between now and the original expiration and not really give much detail beyond that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, guys. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is coming from Randy Cousins with BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Randy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just &#x2013; Jack for you, first question. CSX yesterday was kind of bearish, very bearish on the outlook for coal, and you seem to be taking somewhat of a contrarian point. Obviously gas substitutions are a bigger issue for them. How much of your coal ends up in the eastern half of the country where gas substitution is a big issue? Or do you just think at some level that maybe they're just being a little overly bearish?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I actually do believe that less of our served customers have the opportunity to do much of a gas shift. I think if you look at some of the statistics that I've seen, the plants in the Northeast and Southeast, which would be their served territory, have greater capability to make that shift than the customers in the Midwest and the Southwest where we play more heavily. So I think they probably do have somewhat of a difference from that perspective. And then our sourcing from Colorado/Utah and Powder River Basin, even when you look at national statistics, our overhang in terms of the number of days stockpiled doesn't appear to be quite as onerous as Appalachian coal and some of those kinds of sources.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Randy, I think, one thing to keep in mind here, the ability to ship pretty quickly has happened. I mean, that happened when gas was at $3.00 here a while back. So you've already had, wherever you have a capability shipped in our system, that's pretty much been done. Now, when new plants are built, you've got to look longer term there. But I would also argue, while Jack might sound a little bit more bullish, this is &#x2013; we averaged about 30 trains a day out of the Powder River Basin in the fourth quarter and you go back about two years ago, we were running 38. So we have a pretty substantial fall off here. That's why you look at this thing and you have to say how bad could it really get? We just need a little bit of economic activity, you've got gas prices, I see this morning are moving up. I think there is some potential there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And at current shipping rates, are we actually drawing down on the inventories?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The current shipping rates with the weather conditions being what they are right now, the inventories are drawing down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then to Dennis, his slide number 17, you've got freight car utilization for the year, previously you've given them from the quarter, I wonder if you can give us some indication to sort of how Q4 operating practices or network velocity performance was. But more particularly, the other thing I really want to get at is, once upon a time you guys used to move 200,000 carloads a week, then it was 180,000 carloads a week. I think at the low it was like 140.</p>
          <p>You got back up to 160. Let's assume we go back to 180,000 carloads a week. Can you maintain the same kind of network velocity, the same kind of cycle times statistics? And is the head count that we're looking at today, the same kind of head count that we would have with 180,000 carloads a week? How should we think about the sort of &#x2013; again in real hard terms the cost take out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Randy, for your first question first. On the quarterly numbers, everyone on the same suite of numbers that I showed you, velocity, freight car utilization was all improved significantly. And specifically on the freight car utilization, a year ago, 4Q was nine, we're 8.4 this year. So the terminal dwell, service delivery index, all of them were up, and at least 10, 15%, over &#x2013; Q-over-Q, 4Q versus 4Q. And if we got into the 180, we've always said that, as I talked to you about on the train length side, we've got at least 10 to 15%, on average, across the board, in every major category of train service that we offer. If we're running at 160 and we get to 176, 180, we see marginal, very low, marginal increases and possibly some train starts where there might be some recalls, possibly out of the AWOTTS boards but it would be minimal. We think we can handle that level in the foreseeable future with principally train link improvements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Randy, keep in mind, and you've heard us say this before. Our core infrastructure right now is set to handle about 190, 200,000 cars a week. But we do have a lot of leverage moving up here on volume and our capital. And honestly, I hope we get to the point where we're out hiring. That means we're growing that side of our business. But as Dennis said, at 180,000 cars right now, we are a better railroad today or tomorrow when we're at 180,000 cars than we were the last time we were at 180.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the last point to your question is, absolutely, you would expect the performance numbers to stay the same, if not improve continuously. And that's what the reason for that chart, when I showed you volumes versus SDI. They're on a continuous trend, and we expect that to continue, no matter what the volumes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent, outstanding. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Bill Greene with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just one quick follow-up on the coal issue. Did you actually say what the days outstanding are in terms of stockpiles in your region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, it's about 75 days on average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And where would you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And again, that 75 days, I've got guys that are probably at 100 days and I've got some that are at 50, and maybe even a little below that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And historically, 50ish is about normal for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have customers probably average in the 50 to 60 range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then Rob, do I remember correctly, you guys didn't really cut incentive comp all that much in '09, mainly because your metrics weren't purely financial related, but also service-related. So would that suggest we should have less of a headwind, at least on that metric, looking into 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, that's exactly right. I mean we &#x2013; it is down in '09 versus '08, but not significant. Again, we don't have some of the equity programs that required mark-to-market, like some comparisons I know you've looked at. So that's exactly right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will not have a headwind in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just quickly, as we think about train length, I know you ran that very long train. I know that was a bit of a test run as well, but how much ability would you say or how &#x2013; I don't know exactly how to measure this. But how much latent capacity is there, just by increasing train lengths, do you think, in the system?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to handle that one, Duff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there is not as much as you saw in that mega train, believe me. But overall, Bill, what we say is 10 to 15%. We can handle the next 10 to 15% on average across all of our major train categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that implying that there is only variable cost on the cars that you add to those trains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first inflation hit would be in fuel and equipment costs, yes, that's it. And the labor would be very minimal if any.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, don't read that 18,000-ton train as where we're heading. That was &#x2013; we were doing some testing on technology and train dynamics and fuel efficiency. But you're not going to see us running 18,000-ton trains consistently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from the line of Ken Hoexter, Merrill Lynch. Please proceed with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rob, just want to follow on on the employee question there, the cost per employee. Just look like, if we go back, if the contract kicked in midyear, last year, the last few quarters, looked like the cost per employee, average salary and benefit per employee, was down about 2%. I'm sorry, down 1%.</p>
          <p>In this quarter, it jumped up about 3%. So I'm just wondering what the cost per employee kick-ins were just as we look forward into 2010, where &#x2013; you talked about no headwinds, but wondering why that jumped up this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This quarter actually was more reflective of what we would have expected, given the 4.5% wage increase to the agreement workforce. I think that's a pretty &#x2013; that answers the fourth quarter question.</p>
          <p>The point I was making in my prepared remarks, Ken, in terms of 2010, is that is a category where we will see some cost pressure from the health and welfare component of the cost per employee on that line item. Overall, our inflation is within sort of historical levels, but that particular line item, we will have some cost pressures on the health and welfare line on labor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wonderful. And then, Jack, you mentioned earlier that the &#x2013; about the Powder River Basin coal contract that was lost early last year. Are we now grandfathered past that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep. We rolled January 1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, you mentioned that, when you talked about pricing, you mentioned some legacy pricing could actually push pricing down. Does that mean you're renewing some contracts at lower rates? Or what are you trying to suggest there? I think you were talking about the intermodal at that point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have existing legacy contracts that have pricing provisions that, in the third and fourth quarter, resulted in negative price. Some of those will persist into 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So inside the legacy contract, it had some reductions. It's not that you're repricing old legacy contracts at lower prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just wanted to clarify that. Thank you. And then, just to wrap up, Jim, I just wanted to clarify on the legislation. You mentioned three things as to why, all of a sudden, you cannot support the legislation now, after having some time to study.</p>
          <p>You mentioned that &#x2013; you also mentioned that there is the ability to earn adequate returns. It actually mentions that four separate times. That it's focused on there. And you said, it doesn't mention replacement costs. It actually mandates the STB to review &#x2013; six months after passage &#x2013; to review replacement costs.</p>
          <p>And then you said there is no language on antitrust, and so I'm wondering, since there is no language, why would that be a concern? Is it a concern because something might get stuck in before passage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right, Ken. And remember, the language includes a study.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you can study things a long time and get no place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So &#x2013; and then back &#x2013; that's an important differentiation. Thank you. And then on the overall legislation, it has to do with &#x2013; I guess just what has changed. Or is it just looking at it now and saying, hey, they are &#x2013; on a quick look, it looked like it was a big broad brush, but the more we get into it &#x2013; what was it that triggered that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These are very complicated. In many cases, it relies on judgment from the STB in terms of when you look at it. And as we had more time to look at specific language, we were more concerned.</p>
          <p>But, listen, our objective here, and we've said this to Chairman Rockefeller's staff, is we want to continue to work with them. And I said that earlier. The first time I met him, he said to me, we've got to figure out how we move more business on the freight railroads. So he understands the value. Energy efficiency, emissions, safety, competitiveness. The U.S., as you know, freight system is unique in the world.</p>
          <p>So I &#x2013; we still have a long ways to go here, but our commitment is to work with the staff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then similarly, on the PTC, is anything going on with FRA to maybe lower the cost pressure to the railroads? Maybe slimming down what is required?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What just came out certainly wasn't an objective here in lowering cost. But you're in a comment period. What came out of the final rules, I think we've got 50 or 60 days to provide comments. We clearly will take a hard look at it.</p>
          <p>But I'm concerned about that one. It is &#x2013; even their latest report raised the cost benefit ratio. I think the original report was about 10 or 11, to 15:1, and now it's 22:1. So even the FRA has, in their own analysis, has pointed out this thing is very tough, to where you're going to see there is little financial return in it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great job on the cost controls. Thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from the line of Chris Ceraso with Credit Suisse. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick follow-up. I know a couple of people have asked about the comp inflation, but just so we're clear, between the comp and the health and welfare, what do you think in percentage terms you see as an increase in 2010? Is it 4.5%? Is it...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Chris, this is Rob. For 2010 rough number is it may be 4.5 plus-ish in that range is probably not a bad number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Chris, but keep in mind, it's another reason why we have to stay absolutely focused on efficiency and productivity. And don't &#x2013; you've got to &#x2013; yes, there will be some inflation in here, but that just raises the bar in terms of our productivity focus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So then, your comment about achieving, quote, real price gains. Is the reference to real a reference to inflation? So can we kind of bracket your price gains to something around that 4.5% range or better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I know what the economist's definition of real is, and that's the way I think about it, in terms of we've got to do better than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, this is Rob. Just one clarification, though. Our overall inflation should be 3.5-ish.</p>
          <p>Just that one line item, we'll have a little bit additional cost pressure. But as Jim said, we're focused as always on productivity and right sizing and getting our cost structure down and cost management.</p>
          <p>But, overall, inflation is probably in that 3.5-ish range, which is historically a more normal level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that's the hurdle that you're thinking about vis-&#xE0;-vis price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just lastly, there has been a recent surge in export activity out of the West Coast. Can you just talk to &#x2013; for a minute about how that's impacting your business? What commodities are you seeing? What kind of activity is on your network there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The greatest strength that we're seeing is probably soybeans, meal and grain products right at the moment. That's been quite strong for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from the line of Edward Wolfe with Wolfe Research. Please proceed with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you, Ed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought I heard Jack say that the Pacer was negative to intermodal yields in fourth quarter, but you expect it to become positive for yields? Can you explain that? Or did I miss it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I said was I had legacy contracts that were negative in the fourth quarter. And that with our Pacer arrangements in place, some of that will improve going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So am I interpreting it right, that Pacer is the driver of that improving?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pacer is not my only legacy contract.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there are some others that are going to improve as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are some others that will have to run through the negotiations and let the contract play its course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you also give a little clarification. The slide that shows 3% of legacy business, is that 3% has already being negotiated for 2010, and there is 1% that's yet to be negotiated in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the 3%, Ed, was the prior year's slide. So the slide you want to focus on now is the one that's on the right side that says, as we stand here today, we've got &#x2013; with the Pacer and the automotive contract behind us, we've got four percentage points that are renewed for 2010. And we've got about another 1% to go over the course of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and the 4%, as I understand it, the Pacer is already in effect, and the auto goes into effect February 1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The 1% that's still left out, is that end of the year, or through the year, or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's through the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk a little bit about what you're seeing in Colorado Utah production and what your expectations are for '10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Colorado Utah production has improved from where we were a year ago. They've gotten a lot of the mining issues and some of the coal quality issues. Although they're still having some spot outages for one reason or another. It's not as severe as it was beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>A lot of it is going to depend on demand, and right now, as we said, the demand isn't looking real strong for 2010, although hopefully that's going to change, and we might see a little bit of upside opportunity.</p>
          <p>But I think that, for the most part &#x2013; I think one of the big Colorado coal customers is TVA. TVA just announced they were having some record burns right at the moment. So that would say that that would be good news for Colorado Utah coal, and we'll just have to kind of watch and see how the weather unfolds and how stockpile situations play out.</p>
          <p>But I think they've got a better handle on some of the coal quality issues and gas problems and geology issues that they were dealing with in the first part of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is it fair to say that, based on lower stockpiles there and better handles on some of those issues, if you had to guess, relative to PRB, probably better coal volume in Utah  Colorado this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, it's about a push.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ed, you got to think about summer burn and there's lot of variables that could come in play here. Hey, Ed one more, because I want to make certain &#x2013; we're getting short on time here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, no, I understand. Of the 31 million casualty expense in fourth quarter, Rob, is any of that that what you would consider ongoing, assuming safety &#x2013; the improvement you have doesn't slip at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to continue to aggressively go after improvements in our safety. So we hope where &#x2013; there is two studies a year, as you know, and we'll see the results when we do the second quarter study. But we're going to keep at improving our safety record.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot for the time. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question is from the line of Jon Langenfeld with Robert W. Baird. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just wanted to clarify a comment you made at the end of your prepared remarks. Were you basically implying that you thought that OR could be better in 2010 than 2009, given kind of the back drop you laid out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you say &#x2013; say that again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you imply that the OR could be better? You made the comment that we're going to -.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But again, keep in mind, I said I'm still confident when we look out to 2012, we're going to be in the low 70s. That means we have to make progress every year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fabulous, okay. And then there was also a comment made during the prepared remarks about other potential contracts out there that you may be able to pull forward? What are the variables you look at on some of the generic brands and some of these other contracts that allow you to pull them forward? And is that a material part of the remaining 14% or only a small part?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon, I don't want to get into details here on the &#x2013; a lot of factors come into play. Length of the contract, obviously. The partnership, in terms of how they think about doing business with UP long-term. All those come into play.</p>
          <p>If it makes sense for UP and our customer, we'll pull them ahead. And we've had some success. Others have chosen to let it ride right to the end. And so let's just leave it at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly, on the pricing side, how much of your pricing is locked in now for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jack?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon, I've got 30% of my business in tariffs, so those prices can change on a 20-day notice. I've got 70% that are tied up in single and multi-year contracts, and the majority of those are pretty much done for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that 30% is what would respond if freight pricing and general truckload pricing moves higher? A big portion of that might be able to respond quickly. The rest of that would respond with contract renewals?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the most part, I would say that's true.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from the line of Justin Yagerman with Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Rob Salmon on for Justin. Could you give us an update on your DPU initiatives? I believe in last conference calls, you guys have mentioned that roughly two-thirds of the ton-miles are using DPU. Where are we at the end of Q4, and what are your goals on &#x2013; with regard to that initiative looking out to 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Duff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Justin [sic], we ended the year around 65%, right around the two-thirds portion. And our goal is to take it up to about 70% plus in 2010.</p>
          <p>So we're working with OEMs. We think we can do that with the existing fleet, by just some better utilization. And we're also looking at some ways with the OEMs on some retrofits. So we expect to continuously improve our ratio of DPU.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And should we still be thinking about that as 4 to 6% fuel savings versus conventional power?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is, Rob, on those trains that are using them. 4 to 6% is a reasonable range on DPU.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, that's helpful. And one of the things on the expense lines that you guys have highlighted in prior calls and alluded to on this call is the operating leverage benefit that you guys would gain as you move more of the parked equipment that is currently depreciating on your P&amp;L into service. Could you give us a sense of the headwind that you guys were facing during Q4 as a result of this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not quite certain I understand your question. I mean, we have billions of dollars of assets sitting idle that we're depreciating. It's a pretty substantial number when you look at it. You notice our depreciation line was up 6 or 7%, although a part of that is shifting some leases. But it's a pretty substantial cost that's flown through the P&amp;L without generating a dollar revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was our overall sense, so I was just curious if you guys have quantified what that expense is that's been running through your P&amp;L without the offsetting revenue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The number is &#x2013; I can talk about locomotives, but think about the infrastructure investment that's in the ground. We've got a substantial amount of capacity that we're depreciating, that's not generating a dollar of revenue. So again, locomotives are obvious. Maybe not so obvious in a lot of cases is basic track and facility infrastructure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I appreciate the clarity, guys. Thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from the line of Donald Broughton with Avondale Partners. Please proceed with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Don.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You highlighted the casualty cost benefit of $0.04 a share, was that a reserve adjustment, or are you just highlighting the ongoing or outstanding reduction in the frequency and severity of it? And what that's saving you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don, this is Rob. That was a reserve adjustment as a result of the actuarial study, which was a result of the great work we made on our safety improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, perfect. I'm excited about the spending on the completion of the Joliet terminal, as I'm sure you guys are. Have you guys applied for or do you expect to be able to take advantage of any of the tiger grants to drive your &#x2013; to assist you in your drive to improve your domestic service offering? And if so, where geographically are you going to use those funds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dennis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Don, we haven't applied for any &#x2013; obviously for the Joliet facility, but we have applied for them across our system in conjunction with some of the states. Tower Pick Five down in Texas, some in Iowa, Chicago, some in the West Coast in California. Nevada, we also have some in Nevada out there.</p>
          <p>So we work with virtually most of the states in which we run through on some portion, either on the high-speed rail portion or the tiger portion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you expect to really actually be able to benefit from that program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're hopeful. We'll see when they come out with the allocations here. A small amount anyway. There is a combination of three Ps there, a public private partnership and our portion in the public's benefits are a compilation of the total cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Timing of spending on PTC. You highlighted 200 million this year. Is that going to be rather smooth across the next six years, or do you expect it to be more front-end weighted or back-end weighted?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think it will be a little more back-end weighted. But, again, over five, six years, 1.4 billion.</p>
          <p>You know what? We've got the 200 million for this year. Actually some of that is pull ahead of some signal upgrades and things that are going to be necessary to make this thing work. But it will pick up with a little more back-end load.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We've all talked about coal. It seems like everybody has asked at least one question about coal, and the potential for improvement in volume. Like you guys, I'm actually optimistic about future coal volumes. So help me turn this question on its head.</p>
          <p>What if anything do you guys see out there that could lead to markedly lower coal volumes in the short to intermediate term? Or is it more realistic to simply say, look this is a bottom. How we improve from here is an open debate, but there's not anything that can lead to markedly lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don, I think, in that world, you would have to see a pretty significant fall off in economic activity. I think, a lot of folks were pretty shocked when you saw the &#x2013; what the slow down in the economy did to power consumption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think that's a scenario there. Now, you can look at weather, but weather &#x2013; you had a relatively mild cooling season last year. You can get some pretty big swings on weather, but at least the last year or two, it has been pretty mild. We're off to &#x2013; and extreme the other way &#x2013; with one of the coldest winters in long time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, sure. Great. Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Jeff Kauffman with Sterne Agee. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Hi, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is getting long. So I'll keep it short, because most of my core questions have been answered.</p>
          <p>But, Dennis, can we think a little bit out of the box? Obviously the mega train is in the future. You mentioned that 10%, 15% excess capacity in the system, which to me is thinking within the box, the way you're used to running.</p>
          <p>What needs to happen and how much opportunity is there on the train length upside? What can you realistically run, the way your system is configured today, and what do you think you could run if you have the ability to make the changes to your system? What could you run safely in terms of train length, in terms of future opportunity for productivity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've established that we could run an 18,000 foot train safely. But -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not without media, YouTube, and all that, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yeah. Well, you said think outside the box, and we -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But you know the real issue is, it's not going to be the safety issues from an internal perspective. It's not going to be the operational characteristics. It's going to be the public affairs issues and dealing with those. And the structure by which we can operate trains efficiently into and out of these various terminal complexes.</p>
          <p>So we're making little niche type investments to facilitate longer trains. We've grown our train length every year now for the last ten years. We will continue to do that.</p>
          <p>We think we understand the theoretical upside, but we've got to make sure that we continue to bring the average train size up, because that's where the leverage is. It's not so much running the maximum train, it's getting the average train length up. There is more leverage in the average train than there is in the longest train.</p>
          <p>And that's the way we're going about it, and we want to design our network accordingly to take care of those average trains. And we'll deal with these idiosyncrasies as we see those opportunities. But there is still plenty of leverage in just doing that, getting every train longer than it is &#x2013; it was yesterday. And that's what we're all about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And one last thought on coal. I'm a big follower of Farmer's Almanac, and they were saying sunspot activity is down, expect the cooler weather for the next few years.</p>
          <p>Do we need a more normal summer to really resolve this coal issue in the service areas with the higher inventories? Or is this something that through exports and the burn that we're seeing this winter could potentially be in a pretty decent situation by the spring?</p>
          <p>I guess what I'm asking is, where there is the overhang, particularly in the eastern service or some of the Midwest regions, are we less likely to get that solved before summertime?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wow. I think we need a normal summer burn to help us get through this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay, very good. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Cherilyn Radbourne with Scotia Capital. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, and good morning. We are running long. So I'm just going to ask one.</p>
          <p>And that is, with regards to the STB Reauthorization Bill, can you just comment on the committee's level of openness to continue to work with you on the bill? Because my sense was that the original posturing was, they wanted to settle all of those issues before the bill was actually released. And their thinking was that, once it was released, there would not be material changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think that's ultimately how it came out. Again, it's a very complex bill. They are very open to discussion. We're continuing discussions today. They're talking with really both sides.</p>
          <p>And one of the things I've seen with the committee &#x2013; they want to get it right. Again, it &#x2013; the members that we talk to are scared to death that they get this wrong, because we've made it very clear. We don't &#x2013; we have very little room &#x2013; there is no room to move. And if they get it wrong, investment and good jobs go the wrong way. And that is the last thing you want in today's environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with the healthcare bill debate sort of dragging on, and the prospect of mid-term elections, what do you think the risk is that this gets deferred again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not quite sure I know how to call that one. I mean, obviously, what happened in Massachusetts says most people don't want more government oversight.</p>
          <p>And I look at our industry &#x2013; we're the only industry, when you look at it in terms of transportation infrastructure in this country, that we kept our word. As profits moved up and returns moved up substantial new capacity went in. And it's a pretty hard argument to debate, because those are the facts. So we'll see what happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much. That's all from me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Cherilyn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from the line of Scott Plower from Macquarie Bank Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning, all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple of quick questions. A couple for Jack. You mentioned that Ag and Industrial, a little bit more tariff based. What proportion of those businesses lines roughly are for tariff versus contractual?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that the industrial products business, Scott, is primarily tariff-based. And I would say the Ag product world, the Ag, my Ag products world is a little unique in that some of my contracts take their pricing from tariffs. So it's kind of a mixed bag in there. So tariffs do have more of an influence both on the contractual side as well as the tariffs side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then what proportion of your auto business is the legacy renewal this year? In other words, is it a third of the auto business that you currently have, I'm just trying to get a sense on revenues, just to get the common sizing of just the legacy renewal, relative to your auto business in total?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say, roughly it's in the 25, 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one quick question for Dennis. Is the velocity number that you showed us on, I forget the exact page, is that mix adjusted, in other words, obviously everything fell off in terms of volumes, but some of the intermodal fell off less than some of the slower moving bulk trains or manifest trains. Is that a mix adjusted number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's an absolute number. Whatever it is, it is Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So there was some benefit from mix then because you had relatively lesser falloff in the intermodal versus some of the other businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there will be a small amount of mix in there, you bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. Well, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our last question will be from the line of Jason Seidl with Dahlman Rose. Please go ahead with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, everyone. Listen, Jim I think you've mentioned that you guys might pull back some of the capital spend. Could you talk about some of the areas you might reduce capital spending if this bill goes on as is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you've to ask yourself the question of what's the viability of growth in the returns. If you look at our &#x2013; Rob gave you the number. We've got 2.5 billion kind of targeted; I still need the Board to approve where we're going there, which includes 200 million of positive train control. So leaves you 2.3. You look at the 2.3, you've got about 3 to $400 million of growth capital in there. And what we will do is, take a very hard look at the returns of where we thought we would be, we're not there yet. That's the thing I keep reminding members of Congress. While we've had a nice run in our profitability, in our returns, we still, in my mind are a long ways away from justifying kind of new capital. So we take a hard look at it, and our capacity, our facilities, new locomotive acquisitions, all that comes into play.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's good color. Last question on the coal &#x2013; on the stockpiles. Given the normal seasonal weather pattern, how long does it take to start drawing down the day supply among the utilities that you guys supply?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, I think we are actually in kind of a draw down now because of the extreme weather situations. So that's good. There is a lot of things that are going to enter into it. It's going to be &#x2013; some plants will take some sort of maintenance shutdowns here until the spring leading up to the summer burn. I guess we're probably in a situation where you have some discussion as to weather. Typically what would happen is if they had stockpiled a little bit to get there, this year they probably won't do that. So that will probably help to some extent, and then whatever is going to go on with industrial production, the steel utilization is at 65% versus last year at 45%. If that stays true, if U.S. Steel brings up their, I think it's long view is the one they are talking about bringing up, all of those things consume electricity. That industrial production will help us as well. So it's really a myriad of different things that will help us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Guys, I appreciate the time as always.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions at this time. I would like to turn the floor back over to Mr. Jim Young for closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I thank everyone, for joining us this morning. I look forward to talking to you again in three months. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's teleconference. You may disconnect your lines at this time. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>