<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1179886" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>773</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Andy Dolny, Vice President of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">D. Scott Davis, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Kurt Kuehn, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Garrett Chase</participant>
      <participant id="5">Kurt Kuehn</participant>
      <participant id="6">D. Scott Davis</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jon Langenfeld</participant>
      <participant id="8">Edward Wolfe</participant>
      <participant id="9">Robin Byde</participant>
      <participant id="10">Tom Wadewitz</participant>
      <participant id="11">William Greene</participant>
      <participant id="12">Ken Hoexter</participant>
      <participant id="13">Justin Yagerman</participant>
      <participant id="14">David Ross</participant>
      <participant id="15">David Campbell</participant>
      <participant id="16">John Mims</participant>
      <participant id="17">Andy Dolny</participant>
      <participant id="18">Christopher Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="19">Mark McVicar</participant>
      <participant id="20">Arthur Hatfield</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Steven, and I will be your conference facilitator today. At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the UPS Investor Relations Third Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. And after the speakers' remarks there will be a questions and answer period. Please note we will take one question and one follow-up from each participant. Thank you.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to turn the floor over to your host, Mr. Andy Dolny, Vice President of Investor Relations. Sir, the floor is all yours, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to our third quarter earnings call. I'm here this morning with Scott Davis, our CEO, and Kurt Kuehn, our CFO, to discuss the company's results and our future expectations. But before we begin I'll review the Safe Harbor language:</p>
          <p>Some of the comments we'll make today are forward-looking statements that address our expectations for the future performance or results of operations of the company. These anticipated results are subject to risks and uncertainties, which are described in detail in our 2007 10-K and 2008 10-Q reports. These reports are available on the UPS Investor Relations website or from the Securities and Exchange Commission. Today's call is being webcast and will also be available on our Investor Relations website.</p>
          <p>In their remarks today, Scott and Kurt will discuss comparisons between the third quarters of 2008 and 2007 excluding the effect of the restructuring charge that occurred last year. We believe that these results more accurately reflect UPS's true performance last year. The adjustment stems from a $46 million restructuring charge and related expenses for supply chain business in France, which equated to about $0.03 per diluted share. A reconciliation of these results is included with our earnings announcement this morning and appears on UPS's IR website in the Financial Information tab.</p>
          <p>Now, to begin our review, I'll turn the program over to Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy, and good morning, everyone. As everyone knows, the third quarter turned out to be one of the most challenging that the world's financial markets have seen in a long time. I'm pleased to say that UPS performed well despite the difficult environment.</p>
          <p>At the present time we have a continuation of the same story. Consensus GDP and IP growth keep getting lowered. Economic recovery gets pushed out farther into 2009, even possibly into 2010, and leading indicators continue to reflect slowing global economic activity. Expectations are that the next few quarters will be challenging. Industrial production was negative in the third quarter and is now expected to be negative for the year. As we've said many times in the past, industrial production is one of the best barometers for our U.S. Domestic Package business.</p>
          <p>Retail sales growth has also slowed and is expected to remain weak. Forecasters anticipate that consumer spending will be worse in the current slowdown than in the prior two downturns. I know this sounds somewhat somber, but despite these dying challenges, there is much within UPS to be pleased about. Our international export volume growth increased 7% per day (sic) [volume per day increased 7%] , significantly more than the market. The performance of our supply chain unit continued the momentum we've seen all year, with operating profit up over 30%. We managed our Domestic Package operations well, in response to lower than anticipated volumes, with service levels at all-time highs.</p>
          <p>Once again the company posted industry-leading operating profit and margins and generated substantially increased free cash flow. And finally, UPS's strong balance sheet ensured we had ready access to commercial paper at very favorable rates. All in all, UPSes around the world performed well in today's difficult business environment. And we're benefiting from our extensive global presence and expanded product portfolio. In fact, 40% of revenue this quarter came from the International and Supply Chain and Freight segments. This compares to only 25% in 2003.</p>
          <p>Let me switch gears now and touch on a topic I know all of you are interested in, our airlift contract with DHL. We are still negotiations with them on this contract and hope to conclude an agreement before the end of the year. That said, we have not stopped competing with them. We will continue to do so as we do with all competitors, and we made that clear from the start of the negotiations.</p>
          <p>Now I want to recognize some recent achievements. UPSers did a magnificent job responding to the destruction caused by recent hurricanes. In spite of the personal challenges they faced, our people had Small Package and Freight operations up and running within days of each storm. That was no small accomplishment.</p>
          <p>UPS has contributed over $1 million in monetary and in-kind disaster relief for Gulf Coast residents. In addition, we're actively involved in Haiti, supporting CARE International, deploying logistics experts to work with the World Food Programme there, and providing supplies to make clean water available for over 5 million people.</p>
          <p>Another group of UPSers deserving recognition is our logistics team responsible for the behind-the-scenes support of the Olympic Games of China. Several thousand UPSers literally delivered the Games, moving 19 million items, including everything from kayaks to canoes to the 2,000 drums you all saw in the Opening Ceremonies. I congratulate them for their dedication, organization, and flawless execution.</p>
          <p>Lastly, I want to remind you that UPS published our sixth annual Corporate Sustainability Report in the quarter. We were the first in our industry to produce such a report and then annually benchmark progress against long-term goals.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the program over to Kurt, I want to reiterate my firm belief that adverse times test the mettle of an organization and that good companies can emerge better and stronger for having had that test. I am confident that UPS's mettle is resilient, flexible, and adaptable. UPS is and will remain a financially sound and well-run business.</p>
          <p>Now, for details on the quarter and our thoughts on the future, I'll turn the call over to Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Scott, and good morning, everyone. Against the backdrop of economic slowing and financial turmoil, UPS performed well in the third quarter. Revenue was up a healthy 7.4%, and earnings per share came in at $0.96. We made good progress on our cost initiatives, but these were more than offset by economic deceleration and the high cost of fuel, which drove product mix changes. In fact, fuel expense was up 65% compared with a year ago, driven by higher prices. However, since average fuel prices declined rapidly throughout the quarter, the two-month lag in the fuel surcharge did provide a benefit of about $90 million for the U.S. domestic operations.</p>
          <p>Three months ago, we told you that we anticipated the U.S. small package market would contract about 2% in the second half of the year. However, economic conditions worsened more than expected, and our results reflect that. We saw volume declines across our entire domestic portfolio. July and August volume continued second quarter trends. But in September, we saw precipitous declines. Most notable were the Next Day products, where letter volume declined more than package volume, largely due to significant softness in the services sector.</p>
          <p>Revenue per piece increased 5.8%, led by Next Day Air at 11%. Gains were due to focused revenue management efforts in both the Air and Ground products and to the impact of higher fuel surcharges. These were offset somewhat by lower weights and less favorable mix characteristics. New lighter-weight competitive wins in our deferred product constrained revenue per piece improvement. We believe the pricing environment continues to be rational.</p>
          <p>Domestic operating margin was down 200 points, although we still generated an industry-leading margin of 14.2%. In the quarter we implemented a number of cost control initiatives. While absolute costs are up year-over-year due to higher fuel expense, wage and benefit expense moderated as a result of our success in adapting our network to lower volume levels. For example, operating hours were down 3.4%, same as package volume. Miles were also reduced about 3%. The benefit of the new labor contract, however, was mitigated somewhat by the reduction in volumes. We also made adjustments to our Air network. Block hours were reduced without degrading service. In fact, throughout the company service levels were at an all-time high.</p>
          <p>Even though cost control is particularly important today, we will not sacrifice investment for the future. As part of our constant effort to enhance the product portfolio, UPS improved Air package pickup service for more than a quarter of all U.S. businesses. The enhancements provide more flexibility to meet critical deadlines for customers who do not have a daily scheduled pickup.</p>
          <p>Now to our International business. This segment posted solid results despite global economic challenges, illustrating the competitive advantage of our integrated global operations. Average daily export volume increased 7%, well beyond market growth rates. This is due in part to our broad global offering and the technology tools we've developed to simplify international shipping, like Paperless Invoice and International Returns.</p>
          <p>All regions of the world experienced mid to high single-digit growth. U.S. import volume growth from all regions of the world did remain negative, however, but non-U.S. lanes were strong. Transporter volume within Europe, for example, was up 10%, and Asia to Europe increased over 15. Although revenue per piece increased more than 11%, operating results were negatively impacted by mix change, particularly in Europe, and by the decline in U.S. imports. Nevertheless, just as in our U.S. operations, this segment generates the industry's best operating margin. And remember, this 13.1% operating margin reflects the traditional slowing in Europe in the summer.</p>
          <p>Across the globe, we continue investing to support future growth opportunities. In the fourth quarter, UPS will open its new hub in Shanghai, which will link all of China to UPS's international network. And tomorrow we will break ground on new our Intra-Asia Air Hub in Shenzhen, China. This hub will reduce transit time for almost 200 city pairs in Asia, and it will play an important role in facilitating robust intra-Asia trading activity.</p>
          <p>Let's turn now to the Supply Chain and Freight segment, which continued to demonstrate the positive momentum we've seen in previous quarters this year. Revenue increased 9%, and profitability improved over 30%. Operating margin of 5.6% was in line with our target for the year. International and North American air freight drove significant profitability improvements. The expanded air freight service portfolio that we introduced early in the year continues to attract new customers.</p>
          <p>UPS Freight posted 7.85% LTL revenue improvement, but tonnage was flat and shipments declined, reflecting the tough economic conditions and a more competitive pricing environment. Productivity and service metrics continued to improve, and we are attracting and retaining customers with our WorldShip and Quantum View managed technologies. Earlier this month UPS Freight announced the third round of network enhancements this year. Time and transit improvements have been made to over 12,000 lanes in the past 18 months, offering faster service for two-thirds of all U.S. ZIP codes. These enhancements are part of a continual process to add value for customers by improving the velocity of our network.</p>
          <p>Before I talk about the fourth quarter, I do want to comment on our solid financial position. For the first nine months of this year, UPS generated approximately $7 billion in cash from operations. With that we invested 2.1 billion in capital expenditures, spent 3.3 billion to repurchase 48.5 million shares, paid dividends of 1.8 billion, and still ended the nine months with $1.8 billion in cash and investments. Through the end of the third quarter, free cash flow reached $4.6 billion, reflecting the strength of our business model. This does include approximately 1 billion in U.S. federal tax refunds related to the company's withdrawal from the Central States Pension Plan. As a point of comparison, a year ago free cash flow was 3.1 billion.</p>
          <p>UPS also continues to experience ample liquidity in the commercial paper market at very favorable rates. In these turbulent times, investors exhibit a flight to quality mentality, and our strong balance sheet is very attractive. In addition, we have bank credit lines well in excess of our outstanding commercial paper. We did see a $23 million reduction in this quarter's investment income due to an impairment on certain auction-rate securities, primarily Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.</p>
          <p>In the quarter we spent over $800 million to repurchase almost 13 million shares. This was a somewhat slower pace than in the first half of the year. As credit markets became chaotic, we thought it prudent to pull back a bit. We intend to continue repurchasing shares, but the pace will depend on market conditions, which we'll continue to monitor. We've also reduced our 2008 capital expenditure budget by $200 million to 2.8 billion. All in all, UPS's financial position remains very strong, and we intend to preserve our ability to maneuver and to take advantage of whatever opportunities we may identify.</p>
          <p>Now for the fourth quarter. With consumer confidence approaching new lows, we're concerned that Santa's sleigh may be a bit lighter than usual this year. We expect domestic volumes to be down about 4% for the quarter, reflecting the economic slowing. We intend to execute an effective and efficient peak operating plan, diligently matching the network to volume levels. Given current economic conditions, we believe it will be several more quarters before any turnaround will become evident.</p>
          <p>In the international arena, several European economies are on the brink of recession, and most of Asia's economies are expected to grow at a slower rate than in the past. With the strengthening dollar and U.S. trading partners experiencing weaker economies, U.S. export growth is also expected to slow. Nonetheless, we except export volume growth should increase by approximately 5%, with a mid-teen operating margin for the segment.</p>
          <p>In the global Small Package operations, yield growth will moderate due to a substantial decline in fuel surcharge revenues. However, we anticipate base pricing to remain firm. The Supply Chain and Freight segment should continue the growth trends we've seen all year. Operating margin in this segment is expected to be at or above 5% for the full year, constrained somewhat by the tough conditions in the LTL Freight business. And lastly, earnings per share for the year should be towards the lower end of the $3.50 to $3.70 range that we provided midyear.</p>
          <p>You know, it's no secret that 2009 will be challenging. We intend to pursue long-term growth opportunities and be opportunistic in extracting growth in today's tough environment. In addition, UPS will implement a wide range of cost initiatives in both the U.S. and abroad to match our business to volume levels. This will include network modifications, lower capital expenditures, and reductions in staffing levels.</p>
          <p>UPS has a long history of managing through all kinds of economic scenarios. We're confident in our business model and in our ability to adapt it to match market conditions, both good and bad. We will invest for the future while managing conservatively through the near term.</p>
          <p>Now, Scott and I will be happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, we have time for one question and one follow-up. Our first question will come from the line of Mr. Gary Chase of Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you take literally the, Kurt, what you'd said about the trends' progression through the quarter in terms of what happened in September on the volume side, it sounds like September was a pretty bad month &#x2013; like, probably down double-digit in Air, solidly double-digit in Air, and sort of mid-single-digits in Ground, if you take that statement literally. Is that the case? And then it feels like the fourth quarter guidance on the domestic volume side, while it's not good, it certainly looks good relative to what that September comment would suggest. So can you just give us a little color there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Gary, if you look at what we said on our last earnings call, May and June both were fairly sluggish, and we saw those two months down a couple percent. That trend basically continued through July and August. And then in September that rate of decline more than doubled, and so we did see slower trends especially starting the second and third week of September, and basically that pace has continued through October so far. And, I mean, the good news is we do see some stability in that, but the bad news is it does generate, then, our best guess, of volume growth of 4% for the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Clearly the fourth quarter will be heavily dependent on the Christmas holiday. And it's anybody's guess exactly how that comes out, although frankly we do think that people will be conservative this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I understand that there's a lag, but the fuel surcharge component is going to come down dramatically, as I think you mentioned in the prepared remarks. What kind of impact do you think that's going to have? Do you think you've seen more of the volume weakness already because the surcharges were so high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, certainly the surcharge had a dramatic effect on shipping behavior. We do know that it did cause additional pressure on our premium products and a significant amount of trade-down into the deferred and the Ground products. Right now at least, fuel has come down dramatically, and we'll see where it goes from here. But if the conditions continue, we're hopeful that really there'll be some benefit, both on the premium products picking up a little more, and also we'll get some benefit in the fourth quarter from the two-month lag.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gary, we've built our guidance for the oil to be the mid-80s, forward curve in the 80s. So there's going to be a little bit of upside there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, appreciate it, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jon Langenfeld of Robert W. Baird. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. When you look at the Domestic Express margin, and even if I back out the 90 million of fuel, looks like you've made some progress there in the year. How much of that's related to the Teamster contract going in on August 1? And how much of that's related to just your ongoing efforts to control costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Jon, the majority really is our cost initiatives. We have moved pretty quickly to adjust the network, to prune out discretionary spending, and just make sure we right-size and let our people know that at least at this point we don't anticipate much change to the better.</p>
          <p>The labor contract certainly has some favorable attributes, but the effect of that was muted because of the very low growth. We really aren't bringing as many new employees in, and you get a magnifying effect as you do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've always said that we should be able to ride through these downturns better than most. We said that half of our costs are directly variable. And you really saw that in the third quarter, where volume was down 3.4% and hours were down 3.4%. And block hours were down in that area. So we do a pretty good job managing to the downturns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the margin for the fourth quarter domestic &#x2013; I mean, you're &#x2013; just summing all your pieces together, it kind of seems like you're looking at a low double-digit operating margin on the Domestic side to get to your guidance range. Is that true, even inclusive of the fact that your fuel benefit &#x2013; assuming fuel stays where it's at today &#x2013; is probably double what it was in the third quarter here for Domestic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as Scott said, we do have an estimate of fuel in there that's a little above where prices are at today. So there's certainly some potential there. But frankly with negative 4% volumes, this is a challenging quarter. The holidays are always an exciting time for us. You really have to forecast and commit assets and resources far ahead of time. So there is more exposure certainly during December to volume changes than at most times of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mr. Ed Wolfe of Wolfe Research. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, Scott. Good morning, Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a little more flavor on the DHL contract. You said you're still hopeful of closing it. Do you have a little bit more insight? It seems like they've hemorrhaged a lot of business, and you've certainly won your fair share of that, recently. Do you think it's still a billion a year, or is that number going to be a lot smaller, should the line haul agreement occur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Ed, as I said earlier, the negotiations are continuing. And we hope to reach an agreement before the end of the year. But realistically, the scope and size of the deal may be changed based on the customers' reactions to their announced restructuring and downsizing in the U.S. On top of that, the weakening economy is certainly going to have an impact on them, as is does everybody. So I think it's fair to say that we're still negotiating, but that the scope and the size of that deal could change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Has there become a time period where if it's not done by this time, it's kind of too late, from that perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's something that we got to look at from our perspective and they got to look at from their perspective. I think both parties are negotiating in good faith at this point in time, but I think sooner is better than later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and last thing. On the share repurchase, now that the stock's sitting here with a 4 handle in front of it, it's quite accretive to go in there, and I understand the credit markets aren't great. But you're certainly not having a lot of trouble with access, it seems, to capital. How do we think about those two conflicting things as we go forward in the near term &#x2013; the stock down here, and the markets &#x2013; in terms of your guidance of 5 billion a year of share repurchase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you know, Ed, this really has been an unprecedented time for turbulence, in the debt markets especially. And we've been fortunate in that we've really had as much access to commercial paper as we need, and at very, very beneficial rates. So the liquidity is there.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, the long-term debt markets still show some very sizable spreads, and ultimately our share repurchases will manifest themselves in longer-term debt. On the other hand, as you say, UPS stock is on sale today at a great price, and certainly we intend to be buyers. The exact pace of it will depend on conditions, both in the debt markets and the equity markets, but we do intend to be in there buying stock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We love the stock, obviously, at this price. We'd like to actually get it up to a higher price, but I think that Kurt said it right. The long-term debt markets need to stabilize. There has not been a lot of corporate debt issuance over the last two, three months. And we need to see that stabilize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mr. Robin Byde of HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys. Just on trading in European package, can you provide some more color on current market conditions, perhaps by country? And are you still seeing volume growth at your Cologne and Tamworth UPS? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Robin. We have continued to see good growth in our intra-European shipments. As we mentioned, that products within &#x2013; moving across borders within Europe grew at 10%. So even with a somewhat stagnant European economy, the network we've built, it's allowed us to continue to gain share.</p>
          <p>Some of the individual domestic markets clearly are seeing some headwinds, and the UK most notably, and then certainly Germany, which is one of our largest markets, has slowed a little bit. But the export market within Europe, especially the eastern part of Europe, Poland and some of those, is continuing to show great results. And I might note also that at least in the third quarter we continued to see shipments from Asia to Europe move along very strong.</p>
          <p>So, one of the fun things about us having built this balanced network is it gives us a view into how some of these trade flows are moving and in some sense diversifies our international results to not be quite so dependent on any one area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. And just a quick follow-up. On the Shanghai hub opening in Q4, I mean could you or would you want to delay this if Asian markets get a lot worse?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, absolutely not. I mean, that hub is a positive move for us. It improves our Air network, allows us to improve our service, and manage our costs better. So we're full speed ahead with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and the developing economies are &#x2013; they're slowing down, but they are still growing at a nice pace. And again, China is supposed to grow at 9% next year. So it's not 11 or 12%, but still 9% is not bad.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, guys, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tom Wadewitz of JP Morgan. Please go ahead, Mr. Wadewitz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to see if you could give few comments on how we should think about 2009. I know that's probably tough to do in light of perhaps not even visibility to peak season in fourth quarter. But you mentioned some significant cost initiatives. If you bear those in mind and assume we do have a recession for a couple quarters, do you think margins are down substantially in '09 and earnings are down substantially? Or are there enough additional levers that you can push on in terms of costs and whatever else that you could have some kind of stability in margins and kind flattish earnings? Just perhaps some broad comments for how we might think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, I'll start it off. And just as you look at the economy and again just a preface, that we're not a leading indicator, so we kind of go on consensus estimates. I think generally people are looking for the economy in the U.S. to be negative probably in the third and fourth quarter of '08, and probably the first quarter of '09. Beyond that maybe stabilizing some, but there's certainly risk into 2009.</p>
          <p>When you get into a recession after a financial crisis, it's usually of a "U" shape than a "V" shape, so it may be a little bit longer. But I think generally our best barometers, again, are industrial production and retail sales. And industrial production will probably be negative throughout a good part of 2009. Retail sales will grow, but probably less than inflation. But saying all of that, I think we still feel pretty good about UPS's prospects for 2009. I think that the first quarter may be one of the tougher comps for us, but the rest of the year, I think we stack up pretty good versus 2008. So we're fairly optimistic. We'll get into more detail obviously in January, in our next call.</p>
          <p>Kurt may want to add to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we're working hard to right-size our network for '09. We do have the toughest comps in the first quarter. But the labor contract continues to take more effect as we move farther into that, and we're not gloomy on the U.S. We just think we got a couple more quarters that we've got to manage. And also we're continuing to see decent momentum in our supply chain and freight arena. So we've still got a little bit of a bumpy ride, we think, Tom, for a couple of quarters, but hopefully after that we'll be able to show some more positive results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I appreciate that. And then one follow-up &#x2013; or I don't know if it's really a follow-up &#x2013; but on the pension side, in this market obviously downward pressure on assets. And I think within the Central States plan there's speculation about some risks, that one of the big participants there eventually could have liquidity issues and that that fund could be in a lot worse shape. Can you tell us what &#x2013; is there any risk that you could get drawn back into that fund in the next couple years, that it could deteriorate sufficiently? Or what are the protections that you don't somehow get drawn back into the Central States?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Tom, that somebody made a statement like that, and that statement really was inaccurate. There is a three-year look back on this fund, but it's only in case that there's a mass withdrawal of the 2,500 employers in that fund, which is extraordinarily unlikely. In other words, for all 2,500 companies to pull out of it. Even if a large company goes bankrupt, they're not released of their contribution requirement until they liquidate. And that's only one company out of 2,500 companies. So we have about &#x2013; a little over two years left of that clawback look, and it's extraordinarily remote that we could ever get tied up in any problems they would have.</p>
          <p>And overall on the pension situation, it is something that I think we've all got to watch and manage. From the single employer plans, I think right now you're seeing that the investment results are down but the discount rates are up, which help offset it. In UPS's own plan, we were well overfunded going into this year. I think we're still, even today, 100% funded on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of William Greene of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, Mr. Greene.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. Can I ask you to talk a little bit about how the pricing discussions are going with customers? Obviously the economy, I would think, would lead them to sort of push back a bit on some of the list rate increases you've tried to put through. On the other hand, one of your big competitors is struggling so much here that maybe you've had more succeed in that regard. So how are those discussions going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Challenging but stable, I think, Bill. Clearly with the fuel surcharges at record heights, there was increased pressure on our customers and on us to find ways to take their costs down. And as I've stated in some earlier calls, the fuel surcharge really became a part of overall price negotiation. We've been working through that and trying to make sure we keep those two separate, but there has been pressure. If anything with fuel coming down, we anticipate a little firmer environment as we start to see the results of this $70 fuel kick in and the fuel surcharges get back down to more reasonable amounts.</p>
          <p>The market is competitive. Clearly DHL was a very aggressive pricer in the market, and they are a bit distracted right now. But costs are up, and that's why we did put in a solid rate increase for next year, a net 4.9 on the Air and a 5.9 on the Ground, and certainly we intend to negotiate and keep the majority of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then Kurt, with regard to the volume comments that you made, can you talk a little bit about where you're seeing the weakness? You mentioned the overnight envelope business, but maybe like in terms of B2C, has that slowed dramatically since the last time we spoke?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it has. It has seen the most sequential slowing. Having said that, it is still moderately positive. But it was &#x2013; we've seen double-digit growth in B2C for quite some time, and clearly that's down to low single digits now.</p>
          <p>On the B2B side, there's been some deterioration, not as dramatic, although it has continued to be negative. U.S. imports, as I mentioned, is another area that's gotten very, very weak, and U.S. exports have been pretty strong, although they did moderate to the mid-single digits this quarter, although we continue to see just great gains in our international business across the world. So right now at least, the major change in the economy, the largest change, seems to be on the consumer side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one quick question, Kurt. Last call you mentioned you were doing a strategic review of your network because of fuel prices. Have you stopped that with them coming down, or if so, what was the conclusion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thankfully oil 200 seems a little more distant at this point, Bill. But no, this is all part of our long-term strategy. We create scenarios, and we've developed some insights around how the world would begin to change if fuel prices get back up to where they were and even higher, and so it has us just evaluating opportunities, thinking about acquisitions, thinking about how our network would change. In light of the fact that we are so far away from that right now, it doesn't really make sense for me to get into any details. But this work will be ongoing, so we're ready if and when it bounces back up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ken Hoexter of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Good morning. Scott, in the past you've talked about the percent of expenses that are variable, semi-variable to kind of highlight how quickly you can react in a downturn. Can you kind of update us on where that stands? And what I want to dig into a little bit is on the employees side, you don't really give employee numbers, but just wondering, is a reduction of employees part of this process? And where do you stand today on your base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, clearly, I think the numbers haven't changed much, Ken. 50% of our costs are daily variable, and then we say probably 30 to 40% are semi-variable. And when it comes to employees, really we've reduced 3,000 employees this year -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Over the last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; over the last year. So again, it moves pretty closely with the package volume. And nothing has changed as far as our ability to manage the business on a daily basis and react to what we're seeing in volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And right now we're certainly a big focus on the semi-variable things, some of the network issues, management overhead, some of those indirect costs. Meanwhile the operations people clearly are highly attuned to make sure that that direct labor is matched to volume also, and as Scott said, we've had pretty good results on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Generally the semi-variable takes, as I said before, a couple weeks to a few months to get implemented. Every quarter goes by you'll see more of those kick in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what is the total employee base now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have over 400,000 employees, around 300,000 in the U.S., where most of the changes have been made.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then sort of just a follow-up on capacity utilization. Was there &#x2013; you talked about 7% international growth, export growth. Did that kind of rapidly decline toward the end of the quarter as well? You kind of highlighted the domestic before. Just wondering what your international looks like. And can you talk, in that frame of reference, what your capacity utilization of the aircraft is looking like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, the international did not see the dramatic decline in September that the domestic did. We did see it trending down moderately over the course of the quarter, but nowhere near as volatile. I mean, part of that's why we're still guiding to showing 5% growth in an environment where most of our competitors are flat or down. So we feel pretty good that the value proposition is still there. We are seeing some slowing. We're seeing trade flows move, but at least so far we've been able to stay on top of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the capacity utilization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have any specific numbers to share with you. I will say one thing, though, that we're working very hard at, and I think it's part of how we've been able to manage. This deep integration of our freight portfolio, with Express Freight, with Small Package, is allowing us really to build a load plan for every major country-to-country lane and be able to take advantage of our fixed capacity for our freight when we have excess. So this whole freight alignment is a great benefit for customers, because they can easily choose from deferred forwarding activities all the way up to Express Freight. And it's also very good for us operationally as we learn to operate simultaneously as both an airline and a forwarder. So those things are kicking in right now and helping to improve utilization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And frankly, the reduction in U.S. imports, increase in exports, help balance out some of those loads too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Scott, Kurt, thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Justin Yagerman of Wachovia Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. How you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Justin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Justin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. You mentioned the fuel 200 strategy, and I was just kind of curious, when we were talking on the second quarter call and before that, when you guys had announced in June or July that things were going to be worse than expected, you said that shippers' behavior had changed dramatically as fuel escalated towards peak. And I was just curious to what extent you've seen shippers' behavior change back when it comes to consolidating loads or potentially moving down in terms of the margin product that they're using with you. And I wanted to get a sense of, are you seeing those changes in shippers' behavior? Or is the weak economy still pushing people towards the lower-margin product, towards consolidating freight? Has there been any shift that's notable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's a lot of moving parts to that question Justin. I guess the behavior we saw most notably was really just the trade-down behavior.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we went back and have looked at a couple of different economic slowdowns, and most of the trade-down behavior is typical in a economic slowdown. We think there has been some exaggeration of trade-down, especially into Ground, because of the high fuel prices. On the more strategic changes, the redesign of your supply chain, I think we said in Q2 there was a lot of discussion and interest in it, but we've not seen a lot of big changes by companies. Our guess is it may make a difference on the increment. If you're going to add another factory somewhere in the world, maybe you think about adding one closer to home.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Latin America, maybe Central and Eastern Europe, makes more sense than Asia. But not a big shift. And clearly with the volatility right now, it's awful hard to peg. So it is an interesting time, and one with our Solutions people staying real busy to help customers try to navigate a good long-term course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And some of that &#x2013; that near sourcing issue that Kurt's talking about &#x2013; some was driven by energy, but a lot of it was driven by inflation, perhaps in China, or maybe changing labor laws, just a variety of things that were driving manufacturers to evaluate those decisions. Certainly energy is one of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. FedEx announced domestic Mexican service in the quarter, and I think Southeastern Freight Line just went down there on the LTL side, and a bunch of other truckload and LTL carriers do some business in Mexico. Can you guys talk about how you're positioned there and if you have seen any increased interest from customers in terms of cross-border Mexican moves or setting up manufacturing and distribution in Mexico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Justin. We've clearly been in Mexico for quite some time with a domestic offering, and so we're pretty well-positioned. And we're seeing some uptick. Probably more notable is the focus we've had really for the last four to five years on the whole North American trading bloc, with a big focus on our trans-border products and our Trade Direct, which allows Mexican manufacturers to move stuff across the border en masse and then distribute it into our Small Package networks. So those trans-border products moving between the U.S., Canada, and Mexico continue to be very robust. Trade flows move back and forth. Clearly with the Canadian dollar changing so dramatically, we may see some changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But those continue to be more and more important. And that North American trading bloc remains very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful, guys. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Justin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of David Ross of Stifel, Nicolaus. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentleman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you first bought UPS Freight, there was a lot of talk of bundling the Small Package offering with the LTL service. Could you just give us an update on where that is and if that's helping to mitigate some of the lower volumes you've seen, either on the Ground package side or the LTL side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it is. And we've kind of got a tale of two parts on this LTL industry right now. Clearly, the environment is tough, growth is negative, and pricing has gotten a little more intense. So we have become a little less aggressive than perhaps our initial plans were, so as not to be chasing volume in a tough environment.</p>
          <p>On the flip side, as we've brought our technology, our operating methods, and our visibility services to customers, there's been a tremendous adoption of them. And being able to manage and process LTL shipments through our WorldShip shipping platform, to be able to track them and get predictive information from our visibility systems, is a huge value proposition. So there is macro issues that are very tough, but at the same time we are steadily embedding our technology and our processes into that segment. And over the long term we feel very optimistic. It's just a tough market right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we're extremely well-positioned when we come out of this downdraft we're in today. Because we've made a big investment. The LTL market will recover. I'm not sure who all the players will be when we get out of there, but we're going to be in a very good competitive position when we come out of this economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. If I can just maybe pile on a little bit. One of the things that's happening, and you're seeing it in the LTL, is we have taken our WorldShip platform, which for many years has been a small package domestic application, and at this point now we have upward of 600,000 installed users across the globe. So it's an international application, and in the last couple years we've gone beyond package to include fully automated processing for LTL and deeply integrating air freight. So we've really created, we think, a pretty unique technology platform that's global and multi-modal, and we see a lot of excitement about that, and we're going to continue to press that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That sounds good. Also just one other question. Given the current environment and kind of near-term negative outlook, the 32 aircraft you have on order right now, is that still pretty much in the plan, it's going to go through, or you're going to rethink how many aircraft you might need given the current volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, at this point we've not made any announcements on changing that. Clearly with Boeing being distracted a little bit and production down, we'll have to see how their delivery schedules come. But that's a fairly modest amount spread over five years. And over time we will be retiring our DC-8s also, as the aging aircraft directives move forward. So it's a natural replacement cycle. Timing may move a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And again, the economy is troublesome today. We're all looking, and there's a lot of fear out there, but there are positives out there. I think the lower energy prices is going to help consumer confidence as we move forward. I think the credit situation is beginning to improve. I think whenever the central banks can collaborate together, it's a powerful tool. We haven't had time yet to see the benefits of those lower interest rates. The fiscal stimulus is out there. So I know we're all wrapped up in what we're seeing today. We will get through this weak economy and get back to a normal economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of David Campbell of Thompson, Davis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much, and good morning, everybody. I just wanted to ask you whether you had any fuel benefit in the international operations, like the $90 million number you cited in domestic results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there was a modest amount. It's a fraction of what we saw in the domestic. But it was not significant in the international.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that because it's a smaller component of expenses, or just there was less of a lag, or what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a wider array of different fuel surcharge schedules that aren't as responsive to that. So we did have a tailwind, maybe a penny or so, from the international side, but it was not a large amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And second question is, you have a very big range in earnings in the fourth quarter, basically $0.82 to $1.02. What would it take to earn at the upper end of that range? Obviously some maybe lower fuel prices and better volume. Is there some things you just can't see, so therefore you're &#x2013; but $1.02 is still a possibility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that the fourth quarter is always the most difficult for us to forecast, because so much if it is tied to the Christmas season. And I think that that not knowing -you see forecasts out there that say retail sales are going to grow this Christmas season. Then you see forecasts that say it's going to be the worst since 1991. And so there's a lot of different thoughts out there. So I think we need to be cautious as far as the outlook for the fourth quarter. And again, so much of it's driven by Christmas season &#x2013; two or three weeks before Christmas &#x2013; that it's difficult to forecast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and David, we did say that it's likely we'll be at the lower half of the range, although clearly, as Scott said, there's opportunity and uncertainty in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question in queue comes from the line of John Mims of BB&amp;T Capital Markets. Please go ahead, Mr. Mims.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk about the European Ground network and what you've done or what you can do to rationalize some costs there, if volumes continue to decline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so far they haven't declined. They're continuing to grow, but we are being prudent on that. And it's just good network planning. Within country, it's important because there's very much more economic sensitivity within our domestic products, whereas the trans-border we've still got this secular growth story of the European economy.</p>
          <p>But we're looking at how we adjust routes. We have Air and Ground collaborating and coordinating. Some of the skills we've learned after trying to do this for 100 years in the U.S. serve us pretty well as we've done this in Europe. So there's still some good catalysts, Eastern Europe, Central Europe continue to be showing good solid growth, and the European economy continues to adapt. So we're very focused at it. As in the U.S., the Air networks are less flexible than the Ground networks, so that's where we have to be the most diligent. But in general we have similar structures that we do in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's a good point. Because I think the European Ground network's very similar to the U.S. Ground network, where we have a high degree of variable costs we can manage through a downturn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's helpful, thank you. And just as a follow-up, some housekeeping, do you have a average share cost for the repurchases in Q3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we spent about 800 million in the third quarter and bought about 13 million shares, so it's a little above $60.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About $63.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>63.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and you said &#x2013; I mean, the guidance, I mean, obviously it's affected by market conditions and whatnot, but the annual repurchase spend guidance was how much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our original target was to purchase $10 billion over the next couple years, and in the first half of the year, we've been clicking right at that steady rate. We did pull back a bit, although we still spent $800 million. And we're still committed to our repurchase program. And on the other hand, we don't want to be having to go out to the debt market right now where there's 4 and 500 basis point spreads. So we are leveraging commercial paper, and we'll continue to buy, and the speed will depend on how the credit markets look.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thanks for the time, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Chris Ceraso of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. To follow up on the question about the fuel benefit in some of the different businesses, do you have a number for the Supply Chain and Freight?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not as significant there. There's a lot of flow-through fuel surcharges on the Supply Chain arena. So it's not as notable there. Clearly, we've got to stay on top of it to make sure our surcharges match the rapidly changing environment, but I don't have a number on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The lag is not nearly as important it is on the Package side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The LTL's much more rapid, and certainly that's real time for a lot of the air freight.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then you've gone through a few of the different trade lanes and how things were Asia to Europe. You said it was still strong &#x2013; intra-Europe is still strong. Can you just comment on intra-Asia? And then Asia to U.S., I know you said U.S. imports were weak but if you could quantify those two lanes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, intra-Asia continued to be strong, certainly above our average growth, upper single digits. U.S. overall was &#x2013; as far as exports &#x2013; was mid-single digits. So the intra-Asia, we think, is going to continue to have legs. That's why we're investing and will break ground tomorrow on our intra-Asia hub to help speed up that network and reduce its costs. So countries are trading with each other in Asia even as the U.S. takes a break.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Asia to U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Asia to U.S. was down. All of the import markets were down mid-single digits, I guess, is probably the best -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Every region to the U.S., as mentioned, were negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mark McVicar of Dresdner Kleinwort. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, just a quick question. Some parts of the international freight market, not specific to yours, are reporting issues and concerns around the availability of letters of credit that obviously sit behind a lot of the international trade flows. Have you seen any of that or are you hearing any of that from your cross-border customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not as a huge issue. Clearly, I've read some anecdotes about that. We do have some products that can help customers with very short-term transactions if they're using our supply chain services. But in general that hasn't been a big issue yet. It's probably a bigger factor on some of the ocean shipments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it feels like it's more related to sort of heavy shipments at sea rather than the air-based products, but I just wondered whether you'd seen anything? Okay, that's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from the line of Mr. Art Hatfield of Morgan, Keegan. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Art.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Art.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one question. One thing that I've struggled with &#x2013; and believed me, I struggle with a lot of things -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So do we.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; and I can appreciate these days &#x2013; is we hear a lot of comments that people think we start to see the beginning of a recovery kind of midpoint of next year, second half of next year. Can you kind of put your finger on what you think needs to happen or what you think will be the catalyst to get consumers spending again, one? And two, if this thing drags on into 2010 or even farther than that, at what point are you kind of really restricted on working down the costs? Do the variable aspect of your business that you talk about get reduced as the length of time of slowdown increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think as far as the economy, I think there's &#x2013; I mentioned earlier, there are a couple positives. One is that energy prices have dropped dramatically. Two is I think we're beginning to thaw the credit issue out. I think the central bank collaboration's been a big move. We to get credit flowing again to get these economies recovering.</p>
          <p>Now, the negative of that is the employment side of it is still &#x2013; probably going to get worse before it gets better. And that's going to hurt consumer confidence. Perhaps as we get credit re-established the mortgage rates will drop a little bit, and that'll help the housing problem. We need to get to the bottom of that. So I think that there are a couple bright lights. I think the energy and the credit is looking better. We need to get those healed up before we recover. So we are optimistic that maybe the latter part of next year we'll see some recovery.</p>
          <p>We'll continue to obviously manage our company very carefully. As Kurt said in his comment, we're going to manage conservatively but still invest for the future. I guess that the bottom line of this whole thing is the more pain there is out there &#x2013; and we don't want more pain &#x2013; but if there's more pain, we're going to be a survivor. We'll come out of this thing in great competitive position. So and we'll keep that in mind. We'll invest so that when we come out of this economy, whether it's six months, 12 months, 24 months, we're going to be positioned to gain market share and grow this business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just three key point before we shut down the call. First, UPS turned in a good performance in the quarter, despite the weakening global economic environment. Second, UPS continues to have a very strong balance sheet. And third, we expect earnings per share for the year toward the lower end of 3.50 to 3.70 range we provided midyear. Thanks for joining us today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, today's conference call will be available for replay from today at 10:30 a.m. Eastern time and until October 30 midnight of that day. You may access that conference by dialing 1-800-475-6701 and entering the access code 962127. That dialing number once again is 1-800-475-6701, and the access code is 962127.</p>
          <p>I would like to thank you for your participation on behalf of today's panel, and I'd like to thank you for using AT&amp;T. Have a great day. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>