<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1507507" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>773</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Treasurer &amp; VP-Investor Relations">Andy Dolny</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">D. Scott Davis</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior VP">Kurt P. Kuehn</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Sales, Marketing &amp; Strategy Officer">Alan Gershenhorn</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Thomas R. Wadewitz</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Chris Wetherbee</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="President-United States International &amp; SVP">Daniel J. Brutto</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner &amp; Smith, Inc.">Ken Scott Hoexter</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="William Blair &amp; Co. LLC">Nate Brochmann</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="President-US Operations">Myron A. Gray</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">David P. Abney</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Sterne, Agee &amp; Leach, Inc.">Jeff A. Kauffman</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Bill J. Greene</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Chris J. Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">J. David Scott Vernon</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James &amp; Associates">Art W. Hatfield</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Peter Nesvold</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Wolfe Trahan &amp; Co.">Ed M. Wolfe</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Justin B. Yagerman</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="BB&amp;T Capital Markets">Kevin W. Sterling</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Brandon Robert Oglenski</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst" affiliation="Dahlman Rose &amp; Co. LLC">Helane R. Becker</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst" affiliation="Thompson, Davis &amp; Co.">David Pearce Campbell</participant>
      <participant id="24" type="analyst" affiliation="Robert W. Baird &amp; Co. Equity Capital Markets">Benjamin John Hartford</participant>
      <participant id="25" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">John L. Barnes</participant>
      <participant id="26" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">David G. Ross</participant>
      <participant id="27" type="analyst" affiliation="Morningstar Research">Keith Schoonmaker</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good morning. My name is Steven and I will be your conference facilitator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the UPS Investor Relations third quarter 2012 earnings conference call.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />
          </p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to turn the floor over to your host, Mr. Andy Dolny, UPS Treasurer and Investor Relations Officer, sir, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, today I'm joined by Scott Davis our CEO and Kurt Kuehn our CFO, to discuss the company's results for the quarter and future expectations.</p>
          <p>In addition, in an effort to increase access to UPS leadership, we have asked David Abney, our COO; Dan Brutto, International President; Alan Gershenhorn, Chief Sales and Marketing Officer; and Myron Gray, President of U.S. Operations, to participate today and in future calls.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, I want to review the Safe Harbor language. Some of the comments we'll make today are forward-looking statements that address our expectations for the future performance or results of operations of the company. These anticipated results are subject to risks and uncertainties which are described in detail in our 2011 Form 10-K and 2012 10-Q reports. These reports are available on the UPS Investor Relations website and from the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>In August we announced a restructuring of the New England Teamsters and Trucking Industry pension fund, as a result, in our third quarter earnings UPS recorded a non-cash charge of $896 million. On an after-tax basis the impact was $559 million or $0.58 per share. Excluding the effect of this transaction, diluted earnings per share for the third quarter were $1.06.</p>
          <p>In our remarks today, we will refer to UPS third quarter 2012 results excluding the impact of this charge. Additionally, all 2012 full year references and comparisons to 2011 will refer to adjusted results. We believe this is a more accurate picture of the company's performance.</p>
          <p>Reconciliations to comparable GAAP measures and free cash flow, which is a non-GAAP financial measure, are explained in the schedules that accompany the earnings news release. These schedules, along with a webcast of today's call are available on the UPS Investor Relations website.</p>
          <p>A couple reminders, any guidance that we provide does not include any operating results, synergies or post-closing integration expense related to TNT. Also, our outlook does not include any potential pension mark to market entry. If interest rates stay as low as they are, UPS will likely record a sizeable mark to market charge in the fourth quarter. Keep in mind, this will not affect cash flow or require funding. While this charge would impact our GAAP earnings it will be excluded in adjusted results.</p>
          <p>Finally, each of you will be allowed to ask one question and then get back into queue for follow-up. Thanks for your cooperation.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn it over to Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy. Good morning.</p>
          <p>Our third quarter result reflect the ability of UPS'ers to meet the needs of our customers while making the necessary adjustment in an environment of shifting market conditions. The U.S. domestic business benefited from e-commerce. International results have rebounded as exports from Asia grew slightly. Europe was steady, however, U.S. exports remained weak. The Supply Chain &amp; Freight segment continued to deliver strong operating margins.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a quick look at the global economy. In Europe more countries are slipping into recession as they impose austerity measures. Though the economy there has contracted, the small package market has not. In Asia, although projections have come down, economic growth there leads the world, although, as I said last quarter, exports continue to lag GDP growth.</p>
          <p>Here in the U.S., some of the recent economic indicators provide optimism, general economists have lowered their expectations for the remainder of the year. The lack of clear direction on future tax and spending policy has and will continue to slow business investment. This will clearly impact the B-to-B small package market.</p>
          <p>Regardless of outcome in November, the U.S. is on the edge of a fiscal cliff and there is concern whether politician consist reach an agreement that solves these issues. The lack of political will to fix our debt problem adds to the uncertainty in our economy, just what we don't need. That's why we are supporting Fix the Debt, the organization founded by former U.S. Senator, Alan Simpson and Clinton Chief of Staff, Erskine Bowles. Our goal is to have a bipartisan debt reduction plan drafted when Congress returns in January and we believe it is realistic to have it passed in early 2013. If solutions are in place to both reduce our deficit and eliminate the threat of a fiscal cliff, the U.S. will be in a much better position for sustained economic growth.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, UPS began formal negotiations with the Teamsters, more than 10 months early. We believe an early start will lead to an early conclusion and this is beneficial for all stakeholders. In addition, UPS successfully completed largest non-military logistics event ever when the 2012 London Olympic and Paralympic Games closed. I personally want to thank the thousands of UPS'ers who worked to ensure the success of these games, great job.</p>
          <p>The logistics support of the London Olympics is a prime example of our transformation and the trust the international community has placed in UPS. We've invested over the decades to build unique capabilities, creating the world's leading logistics provider.</p>
          <p>Further demonstrating the UPS strategy of investing to grow is our planned acquisition of TNT Express. We recently received a statement of objection from the European Commission. This is not uncommon. We are evaluating this confidential document and will respond in due course. UPS still expects to close this transaction early next year. We have committed to complete this acquisition and enhance our position in the logistics industry. We are further strengthening the UPS brand and positioning the company for worldwide growth well into the future.</p>
          <p>Speaking of brand, earlier this month Interbrand announced their 2012 list of 100 Best Global Brands and UPS once again ranked number one in our industry.</p>
          <p>Finally, UPS'ers around the world are gearing up for the holiday rush and I'm confident that no matter what Mother Nature throws our way, UPS will deliver.</p>
          <p>Now Kurt will review our results for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Scott, and good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>Given the economic climate, UPS executed well during the quarter with earnings per share of $1.06. This is down slightly compared to last year, primarily due to a lower tax rate in 2011. Total UPS daily volume grew 2.9%. Revenue was down slightly due to one less operating day, while operating profit and margin were flat with last year.</p>
          <p>During last quarter's call, we discussed our concern for global economic expansion, particularly here in the U.S., and we've taken the necessary steps with network changes and other adjustments. Over the next few minutes I'll share with you what we've accomplished over the past three months.</p>
          <p>Starting with U.S. domestic, the segment generated operating margin of 13%, operating profits were down slightly compared to last year as the quarter was negatively impacted by $60 million in fuel surcharge lag, as well as the one less operating day that I just mentioned.</p>
          <p>While business to business declined a bit, average daily volume growth was slightly higher than anticipated across all products, advanced entirely by B2C. Ground rose 3% fuelled by both light weight and traditional residential products.</p>
          <p>Not only are e-commerce shippers leveraging our extensive Ground solutions, but they also continue to look to UPS premium products to enhance their competitive edge. As a result, next day air volume increased almost 6% and our deferred air products jumped more than 9%.</p>
          <p>Total revenue per piece declined by about 1%. Base rate improvement was more than offset by significantly lower fuel surcharges, as well as changes in both product and customer mix. The rapid growth in lightweight B2C shipments continued to push average weight per package lower. Ground revenue per piece was up slightly while next day air and deferred were down 4.6% and 5.1% respectively. Next day saver growth continues to outpace AM products as shippers realize its value for residential deliveries.</p>
          <p>Once again, UPS technology innovations contributed to better cost control and efficiency gains in the network. In fact, paid hours, miles driven and aircraft block hours all increased less than volume. While U.S. domestic results were solid, UPS remains constructively dissatisfied. As B2C expands we are continuing to adapt both our business model and revenue strategies. UPS technology will ensure that our integrated network remains flexible, providing the ability to react quickly to evolving dynamics in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>Now let's review our International results. This segment rebounded after a few tough quarters in a row. In fact, we had a record third quarter operating profit of $449 million. Clearly the results of our initiatives are bearing fruit. Network adjustments combined with in country cost management resulted in operating profit growth of 7.7%. Operating margin expanded 170 basis points to 15.3%. Benefits derived from currency exceeded the headwind generated by higher fuel costs. We also incurred 20 million in acquisition related expenses which were offset by other one-time items including a pension adjustment.</p>
          <p>UPS average daily export volume was up 1.2% with slight increases in Asia and Europe while U.S. exports continued to disappoint. Non-U.S. domestic average daily volume declined 2.7% due to the slowing global economy and UPS's revenue management initiative in Europe. Fluctuations in currency and the lower fuel surcharge drove the revenue decline of 3.7%. When adjusted for these, third quarter revenue was up slightly.</p>
          <p>Looking at revenue per piece on currency neutral basis, non-U.S. domestic improved 3% and export was relatively flat reflecting the continuing shift in trade patterns and customer migration to less premium products.</p>
          <p>Now for Supply Chain &amp; Freight. This segment once again generated an operating margin in excess of 8%. Although revenue fell $75 million, operating profit was down just $15 million. Declines in our forwarding unit were partially offset by improved UPS Freight results. UPS Freight revenue improved 3.6% due to growth in LTL tonnage and revenue per hundred weight. UPS technology innovations like pickup notification have proven popular with our customers. Yield gains and productivity improvements contributed to another quarter of operating margin expansion.</p>
          <p>Poor industry conditions due to overcapacity in the Asia air freight market pushed revenue and margin lower in the forwarding unit. Meanwhile in distribution, demand for UPS healthcare solutions was a strong contributor to revenue growth, although investment in healthcare technology infrastructure and facilities did weigh on margins. Recently UPS opened three new state of the art facilities in China and Australia adding more than 350,000 square feet of healthcare compliant capacity in Asia.</p>
          <p>Looking now at cash and our balance sheet, UPS generated $3.6 billion in free cash flow after capital expenditures of $1.6 billion. The company also paid $1.6 billion in dividends.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, UPS took advantage of market opportunities to acquire more than 7 million shares. Year to date the company repurchased 18.5 million shares for approximately $1.4 billion. Our target for full year purchases remains unchanged at $1.5 billion. Total outstanding shares for the fourth quarter are expected to be about 5 million shares lower than in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>The financial quality of UPS was obvious during our recent bond offering which was oversubscribed seven-fold. The $1.75 billion in 5, 10 and 30 year notes is being used to replace debt maturing in January. We made the decision to go to the market a few months early given the historically low rates. We achieved an average yield of 2.45% on debt with average maturity of 13 years. As a result of this issuance, and in anticipation of closing the TNT acquisition next year, UPS ended the quarter with more than $9 billion in cash and marketable securities.</p>
          <p>And now to guidance. The UPS business model performed well during the quarter and the macro environment was, for the most part, consistent with our assumptions. Given our performance and greater confidence in fourth quarter execution, we have enhanced our full year earnings guidance to range of $4.55 to $4.65 per share an increase of 5% to 7% over last year. We are basically reaffirming guidance around our previous midpoint, but narrowing the range to reflect higher degree of earnings certainty.</p>
          <p>If you remember, 4Q 2011 was a record quarter for UPS. That being said, in fourth quarter of this year we expect all three segments to increase operating profits and to generate margins similar to or slightly above last year.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. Domestic segment for the quarter we anticipate operating margin will once again exceed 15% and average daily volume growth should be about 3% driven by B2C in both lightweight and saver.</p>
          <p>For International, we expect mid-single digit operating profit growth in Q4 with slight improvement in average daily volume growth trends. This guidance includes a similar amount of acquisition related expenses to what we saw in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In Supply Chain &amp; Freight, though we expect the challenging air freight environment to continue, for the fourth quarter operating profit should increase moderately on relatively flat revenue.</p>
          <p>Certainly consumer behavior during the upcoming holidays will affect UPS earnings fall within the $4.55 to $4.65 range. As we demonstrated during the 2011 peak season UPS is ready and more than able to handle whatever comes our way.</p>
          <p>But before I turn it over to Alan Gershenhorn for an update on peak season, I do want to encourage all of you consumers out there to indulge during the upcoming holidays, purchase lots of gifts and of course, have them shipped UPS. Alan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kurt.</p>
          <p>As everyone knows the holidays are a busy time around UPS. Every peak season millions of customers count on more than 400,000 UPS'ers to successfully manage the sharp and sudden increase in deliveries. This surge will take our daily average of about 15 million packages up to 28 million on this year's peak day, the most ever in our 105 year history. It is truly awe inspiring and in my 32 peak seasons I've always been impressed with how our people get the job done. This year will be no exception.</p>
          <p>The dramatic rise of e-commerce continues to alter consumer behavior and shipping patterns. Historically, peak season volume ramped up from Thanksgiving to Christmas. This year we are planning for two peak periods one that resolves around Black Friday and Cyber Monday, the other compressed into the two weeks before Christmas.</p>
          <p>Speaking to our global customer base about their expectations for this holiday season, they tell us they are cautious, however, they also remain optimistic. Economic uncertainty around the world has them uneasy about how their consumers will respond this year.</p>
          <p>On another note, the retail inventory to sales ratio is still historically low, so their supply chains could strain to keep up if demand is more than predicted. And although consumer confidence has increased recently there is still concern relative to political and fiscal uncertainty.</p>
          <p>According to a recent survey, 70% of Americans say the current state of the economy is impacting their spending plans and as a result forecast for holiday retail sales call for lower growth. The National Retail Federation is projecting a 4.1% rise in holiday sales, which is below last year's 5.6%, but still above the 10-year average.</p>
          <p>More importantly for UPS, e-commerce sales are expected to jump 12% over last year, so demand for our lightweight and deferred air products is expected to be high. As the season develops UPS will be ready, in fact, we already started the hiring process for temporary employees. This peak they will help deliver more than half billion packages around the globe and to support both shippers and consumers during the holidays, UPS offers many unique solutions.</p>
          <p>For example, UPS My Choice, which was launched at this time last year, is unmatched in the industry, almost 2 million households have signed up and are enjoying the benefits. Advantages like providing delivery alerts by e-mail or SMS the day before your package is delivered, eliminating those, "Sorry we missed you" notices left on your door or the ability to reschedule or reroute deliveries are one of the most popular features authorizing UPS to deliver without a signature.</p>
          <p>So if you haven't signed up for UPS My Choice yet, I strongly encourage you to join the almost 2 million who have and enjoy an exceptional package delivery experience this holiday season courtesy of UPS.</p>
          <p>Thanks and now we'll be happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our first question will come from the line of Mr. Thomas Wadewitz of JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning and you know congratulations on the good results, especially in international, looks like strong performance. Wanted to ask you about the domestic side and a couple things going on with mix. Can you give us a sense of how much B2C was up and how much B2B was down? And also in terms of that topic, how would you look at margins going forward if you continue to see that trend of B2C growth and slower or modestly declining B2B? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Tom, thanks and good morning. Yeah, B2C has continued to show slight declines, so it didn't get significantly worse from Q2 to Q3, but clearly with some of the challenges in the industrial sector and some of those areas we're just not seeing a lot of strength there. So B2C was absolutely the primary driver of the volume growth and as we said, this is one of the big market changes that we're adapting our business model to. So the B2C is a little more challenging, but as you have seen, both the operational technology side and the consumer side we're focusing enhancements to address that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, our long-term targets on domestic are 14% to 15% margins. 2014 to 2016, we're not backing off of those margins as we move forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give the actual number of what B2B or B2C were, Kurt, or you don't care to be that specific?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>B2C was upper single digits and B2B was slightly negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Chris Wetherbee of Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. Maybe a question just on the international side you mentioned the Asia outbound picking up a little bit. Just want to get a sense of whether that was specifically around product launches, maybe the sustainability of that and how we should think about that relative to capacity, so we get a sense if you got to the right point of capacity relative to the band right now and how do you think about the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. It certainly was great to see Asia get into positive numbers again and I think it is a little bit of both of the issues that you mentioned. I will have Dan Brutto talk about that a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I guess what I would say as far as the network cutbacks, certainly we've done that, but I would also say that we've also added in aircraft, we just added our fifth gateway in China. It started the middle of September in Zhengzhou, primarily for the high-tech sector and that kind of coincides with what is going on in China, this whole Go West strategy. So you've got a lot of manufacturers now in China that are moving off the East Coast to the West. Last year we opened up another gateway in Chengdu essentially for the high tech, so we are moving our equipment where the customers are and certainly it was good to see finally a small uptick in Asia this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think this slow global trade is cyclical and it will come back. I think one of the things we talk a lot about is this fiscal cliff in the U.S. If we resolved that, get the U.S. economy consumer going again will help demand, U.S. from Asia. We see it coming back some next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will from Ken Hoexter of Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Good morning. Can you just talk a little bit, Kurt, maybe about what gives you that confidence in the fourth quarter? If I look at the target range, it seems like you are almost raising the fourth quarter by a nickel, are you expecting a break after the election? Do you already see that kicking in?</p>
          <p>Then on the confidential letter, was there anything substantial in TNT or should that keep moving forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're not expecting a significant rebound in the economy, so this outlook is for kind of steady as she goes economic conditions, we've not seen a real change in momentum sequentially month to month and going into October. You know we're looking for about 3% volume growth in aggregate for the fourth quarter, slightly less than the current momentum. I think based just on the progress and the execution across all of the business units, we've adapted to the challenging condition, certainly you've seen it with International and Domestic continues to operate well, albeit in a changing environment. We feel more a little more confident at least with narrowing the range and clearly being able to deliver a decent fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ken, there are also several positives out there, I think, for the holiday season. You know, housing is starting to improve, we have lower fuel costs, lower interest rates, stock market has been strong. That usually correlates to good consumer behavior. That helps.</p>
          <p>There are negatives, I don't want to be repetitive on the fiscal cliff, sometime about the end of November, after the election, the fiscal cliff will be front and center and that will cause some uncertainty, so there are some risks.</p>
          <p>On the question on TNT, the Statement of Objection is absolutely a normal step in phase II merger review. It was expected, it happens in almost all phase II reviews. So it's &#x2013; it is basically the EC laying out their position, but does not prejudge the final outcome. We have got a lot of work to do on it, we've been working closely with the Commission over the last several months, we'll continue the open dialogue. We'll respond in the next couple of weeks. The document is confidential and we can't share the details of it at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Nate Brochmann of William Blair &amp; Company, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Wanted to talk a little bit, you know, obviously you guys have been kind of doing this and showing great results on the margin side in terms of "adjusting" the network to kind of compensate for the new shipping patterns. Can you talk a little bit more in detail of exactly what you're doing and then longer term in terms of the strategy to take advantage of that and also how, with such a big network, how do you remain flexible as obviously we have seen that things change so quickly. How do you make sure that you are always in the right competitive position to take advantage of the changes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of pieces to that, Nate. For starters, the big focus we have with the changing mix of B2C is really enriching our technology both for customers and operations, so that we can keep the margins. Myron, maybe you can talk at a high level on some of the things we've been doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kurt. We are in a constant transformation of our business model here in the U.S. to adapt to the changing mode of the market, particularly the B2C. Our use of operational technology has real-time optimization that we'll use moving forward. As you've seen in the past, we've talked specifically about telematics, but moving forward we'll utilize new delivery route optimization that will give us real-time optimization of the routes that will allows us to reduce the miles driven and direct labor hours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess one other real component if you talk to global network is our fleet composition and our ability to &#x2013; we have a very harmonized young fleet, so maybe Dave Abney, you can talk a little bit about how the airlines are reacting to these trade flows.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly can, Kurt. One thing I want to point out about the third quarter, block hours were down 5% on an export volume that increased 1%. And that is certainly due to leveraging Worldport, to the strategic composition of our fleet where we continue to add 767s, bigger containers and our superior technology. In fact, if you go back 19 &#x2013; excuse me, 2008 through 2011, you see that we've actually increased our packages per block hour by 15% and that just shows that we are leveraging this network.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the International side, we have reduced our Asia network, cut it down 10% year over year, but as Dan said, as we do have trade lanes that demand it, we certainly will put up block hours as necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think historically we have shown the ability to perform in good times and bad times better than most of the industry because we have such a flexible work force, we can flex it based on the volume on a daily basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Jeff Kauffman of Sterne, Agee. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, congratulations, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Normally the old rule of thumb used to be that you could get read on the economy based on what was happening in average weight per piece. Obviously for reasons B2C, B2B, the lower weight per piece might not necessarily be as accurate an indicator as it used to be, but what is your take on that and kind of if I look at your average weight per package, how do I segregate what's kind of a structural shift versus maybe cyclical weakness?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a great question, Jeff, and stuff we've been looking at ourselves and trying to isolate. I think if you go back to the more traditional view of weight, which was kind of the indicator of how many widgets are in a box, you could see that packages would get lighter during lean times and heavier. There is slight weight drop if you look at same store sales on the B2B for similar industries. So there is certainly &#x2013; things continue to get a little smaller and the economy isn't robust.</p>
          <p>The vast majority of the weight declines, and we are continuing to see substantial ones, is really the B2B and B2C mix because we have all of that mix in the same network and it does create some very big changes in average weight and also it's the biggest single driver by far of the revenue per piece comps that can be challenging. So our trick is to continue to find creative ways to manage through that and we're doing pretty well so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, for the last 20 years B2C has become sort of 1% more of the pie each year. In the last year, year and a half, that pace picked up to maybe 2% a year more of the pie. So that evolution is speeding up as we speak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good, very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Bill Greene of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. You know I was wondering if you can just clarify something that's in the press release. You talk about International benefiting from improving sort of exports, I think you said out of Asia, product launches, etcetera, but then supply chain got hurt by overcapacity in Asia. So I'm not sure why you would have differing trends in that regard and maybe you could talk about what has happened so far in October then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. Dan Brutto clearly can fill you in a little more on the product launches, but also the balance of forwarding and our international package business. Dan, why don't you take that on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I guess what is happening now primarily in the air freight market out of Asia is there is overcapacity in the market. Whenever there is overcapacity, even though our kilos are up, certainly the rates are down and that is pretty much consistent across the whole forwarding industry. On the positive side, though, we did see an uptick in <mark type="ph" /> hactel and pactel (32:08) in the month of September. Year to date, they're still both down on the export side <mark type="ph" /> hactel (32:15) being much more down than <mark type="ph" /> pactel (32:18), which is the Hong Kong index versus the Shanghai index, so certainly we're seeing that. Why the small package is up? Because of use of our network and certainly some product launches that came out of Asia as well as some easier comps last year in the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Chris Ceraso of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, actually I wanted to follow up on that subject, as well. Is there market share gains that you can talk about in tech that maybe helped you disproportionate to your competitors and then maybe if you can say that the strength you saw in September has carried into October?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're continuing to execute, clearly we have a very long history of continued share gains in the international sector. The product launches in September clearly was a boost that made September the better growth month. We're not trying to overplay this, plus we've seen sometimes there is a broader ecosystem around product launches where peripheral suppliers and some of that launch. So we like to think we're gaining share, clearly the profitability was great this quarter, but it is too soon to say that either we or the industry is out of the woods as far as long-term Asia exports.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've said all year we expected the third quarter to have easier comps and you'd start seeing better comparisons and you saw that. There is really no surprise. I would not say that global exports out of Asia are growing at fast pace. We've got a ways to go there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of David Vernon of Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. So Kurt, with $9 billion in cash on the balance sheet right now, that is obviously well in excess of the TNT acquisition price, can we assume that is going to be 100% cash or will you actually be levering up a little bit to close that deal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, we'll be &#x2013; we did do the debt issuance a few weeks ago and we were just thrilled to see the demand for that, as I said, was more than 7 times over-subscribed. That $1.75 billion really was an early draw to replace debt that comes due in early January, so basically a couple billion of that cash and marketable securities is just a prefunding for that debt. So you take that out and we're in pretty good shape.</p>
          <p>We'll use a little commercial paper, as we said. We have some commercial paper outstanding but we wanted to be in good position to address the cash needs to close that. So our intentions remain the same as we had said before, we don't anticipate a need to do any long-term issuance to fund the TNT acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The $5 billion in cash number, is that still a good number to think about or do you think it will be a little higher than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's still a good number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Art Hatfield of Raymond James. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, just real quick follow-up on your comments on Europe. You talked about in the press release that while Europe has slowed, your small package growth remains positive. Can you &#x2013; you've talked in the past about how the market is shifting toward small package, can you talk about that and where you see yourself in the competitive environment and if any of that positive growth is market share gains within Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly, we're long-term observers of Europe and have operated there for a long time, facilitating the trans-border movements. I'll let Dan talk a little bit about the competitive climate there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would say that Europe is a very competitive environment. We're slightly up, which is good, but just slightly above positive on the export for Europe and certainly we've reported negative on the domestic primarily negative on the domestic from the Southern periphery countries that are going through austerity programs right now that they are going through difficulties. So I would say the European market, we're very bullish on Europe although it is a very competitive marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Peter Nesvold of Jefferies &amp; Company. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to ask a question on the deferred yield on the domestic side of the business. So they started to step down in the fourth quarter of last year, presumably on Amazon Prime. That starts to anniversary in now, so I'm curious, optically should we expect deferred to continue to be down, the yield in that business to be down year over year? And if I can add a compound to that question, when you think about the increasing mix towards B2C lower weight, lower lane density, how do you add this business on without it being dilutive to overall corporate average returns for the business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll talk about return issue and maybe Alan can talk about market trends and customer mix change. Clearly we spend a lot of time focusing on adjusting our domestic network, as Myron talked about, to extract and maintain by far the industry's highest returns on capital and by far the highest aggregate margins. This growth in lightweight deferred packages whether they're B2C residential or the premium residential packages, does create some different operational challenges, but the returns on capital are very high, they tend not to consume as much in the way of assets and with our increased focus on the productivity at the last mile that we've been doing, clearly we're continuing to generate good returns.</p>
          <p>As far as the yield from changing mix, we've talked about that a little bit, but Alan can give a little more color.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, I wouldn't characterize the lightweight product as any specific customer. We have a broad base of customers that are using the lightweight SurePost product, but it is a relatively new product and we are going to be lapping some very significant growth in that product, so I think that you should see some yields firm up into 2013 in that regard.</p>
          <p>And by the way, on the previous question on weight in general I think one of the things we've been able to accomplish with the SurePost product, is we are now capturing a disproportionate share of the market That wasn't necessarily a market that we played in even with our Ground residential and we're able to go after lightweight, less time-sensitive economic type products in the marketplace that we weren't necessarily competitive for in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, we are, as Kurt said, focused on return on invested capital. Our long term targets have a minimum of 25% ROIC 2014 on, that's based on this mix of products. So we're focused on return on invested capital, we will keep great ROIC going despite the mix we're looking at here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Ed Wolfe of Wolf Trahan, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you comment a little bit, I mean, this was the first quarter where domestic packages operating income was down for 10 quarters or so and yet the volume has been so strong. Can you talk a little bit about how much of this has to do with mix with the B2C growing faster and how much of this has to do with maybe trying to take a little more volume and give up pricing and then what impact you saw if any on fuel? It's hard to tell. The expense is down year over year, but obviously, so is the fuel surcharge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Ed. I'll be glad to unfold that for you a little bit. The two most notable issues that were headwinds in the third quarter and frankly we guided at least some of those last quarter, the first was the fuel surcharge lag, which I think we did estimate was about $60 million. In addition, there was one less good working day this quarter which, as a ballpark, we usually say that is about $50 million plus or minus per working day. If you factor those two in, we did also say in Q2 we had a $60 million tailwind for fuel. If you average out those two quarters, you can see the business trends remain fairly stable and we would show solid increases in profit. So we feel that things are working pretty well, we knew third quarter was going to be a challenge, that is part of why we had to talk a little more about that last quarter. The mix &#x2013; changing mix is challenge that we're continuing to work through, but we feel pretty good so far. So in general, we think the business is steady in the U.S., the operational enhancement are helping to offset the challenges that we're facing with lighter weight packages and we expect that to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we expect, obviously, domestic operating profit improvement in the fourth quarter and a margin of 15% or over. So we feel like we are moving in the right direction there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Justin Yagerman of Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Just on the U.S. domestic small package side, you know, I guess from what I've heard at least, it sounded like the work-around on some of the large customer impact sounds more operational in terms of how you guys are thinking about this and taking cost out of the network to try to offset some of that negative mix impact. I mean, when you think about that business, how actively are you pushing back or managing volumes with those customers to make sure that mix is appropriate? Or does it really just take a reinvigoration, to your point, Scott, with fiscal cliff worries on the small to medium size customers to start coming back and adding growth to that mix in order to see more I guess healthy yield profile coming on that business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, no, clearly we've talked a lot about the cost and the technology enhancements, but equally important is the revenue management and extracting the value from all of this new capability. So Alan, maybe you can talk a little bit about how we're enhancing on the revenue side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so you know it is certainly noteworthy that on a year on year basis that the product and the customer mix continues to negatively impact the yield, again, I think a lot of those base rate improvements are being masked by the continued growth in lightweight products, but clearly the portfolio we have out there, whether it is for B2B customers or B2C customers allows them to certainly optimize their transportation and, you know, pick the service that they need to provide the service they need at the cost point they are looking for.</p>
          <p>The other thing I would just add, is that the core pricing certainly remains firm around 2.5% base price increase, a little bit stronger on the air side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Justin, your point on small and medium size enterprise is a focal point for UPS. I know Myron's and Alan's teams are looking for different ways to go to that market, I think. They have not been spending, they have not been stocking inventory, they have not been hiring because of all the uncertainty out there and they will get it going once the government makes some decisions. We are bringing a lot more solutions to this group, solutions that originally were focused to the larger companies, larger businesses. Now we're bringing those solutions to small and medium size companies, which will help us grow the middle market going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Kevin Sterling of BB&amp;T Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Kevin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Kurt, I wanted to let you know that my wife is taking your advice and is indulging in some online holiday shopping these days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, just got to make sure she signs up for My Choice, Kevin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Kind of talking about this question of shifting international patterns, have you guys seen any major shifts in international shipping patterns, say from the air to the ocean or is it mainly to deferred products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly we see, we've seen shifts geographically quite a bit with some of the intercontinental move slowing, which we've talked about a couple quarters. I'll let Dan maybe add a little color on the forwarding unit and express.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say to answer that, we've seen nontraditional ocean customers and what I mean is some air freight and some express taking at least a look at sending some of their lower margin products via ocean. And we've made it easy for those customers certainly with our broad portfolio and also with our preferred less than container load ocean product that lets a customer from the high-tech or the medical field at least test out ocean in a way that is quick and certainly allows them to move along this product portfolio in an efficient manner, but nothing to a major extent yet in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Back to geography that Kurt talked about, clearly European demand is down. That's impacting Asia exports and U.S. exports pretty dramatically as we move forward. Hopefully we'll get European imports going again in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you for your time congratulations on a nice quarter in a difficult environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Brandon Oglenski of Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You highlighted that you have already opened discussions with the Teamsters here, can you just talk about some of the objectives that you are looking to accomplish with this new contract round, especially in the face of the shifting mix, domestically to more B2C traffic, more of the lightweight lower yielding packages?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will let David Abney talk about that, he probably won't be able to tell you an awful lot because we are keeping the negotiations at the table.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the negotiations did start in September and we do believe that an early start is good for the employees, customers and shareholders. In the past two negotiations we have been able to reach early conclusions. We've got a positive relationship with the Teamsters. We both recognize that UPS success translates into jobs. You know, many of the issues that come up have been discussed over the last couple of years through the Competition Committee.</p>
          <p>As far as the particular issues, we just believe negotiations are best left at the bargaining table, so we won't review that today, but we're satisfied with the pace of discussions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Helene Becker of Dahlman Rose. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, operator. Hi, gentlemen. Most of my questions have been asked and answered, but just one point of clarification. Did you say how many people you would need to hire for the peak shipping season and how that compares to prior years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we'll be releasing more details about the peak season and the holidays in a couple weeks or so. As Alan said, we do expect over half-a-billion packages between Thanksgiving and Christmas, so we'll be very busy and there will be plenty of temporary hires that start with the company, like myself, during the holidays. But we'll give you more details in a couple of weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you driving during the holidays?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I need to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I did that too, when I was in school. Thanks very much, I appreciate it. That's it, everything else was really asked and answered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Have a good one, Helane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of David Campbell of Thompson Davis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, everybody. I'm just a little surprised that you're relatively optimistic about the fourth quarter forwarding unit given the fact that you're a little unsure about September's volume growth continuing in the Asia-Pacific region. What changed from &#x2013; what changes from the third quarter to the fourth quarter that allows you to be optimistic that earnings will be up in that division year to year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, that's a good question. I wouldn't interpret our guidance to be optimism specifically around the international forwarding. More important than that segment, as far as contributing to profit improvement, is our UPS Freight and our distribution business. We expect forwarding to have another challenging quarter, clearly the buy rates are low, but the revenues are also being pushed down quite a bit. So it is more an expression of optimism of the continued momentum in our Freight and in our distribution business which is benefiting from the healthcare growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, I thought that. That explains it, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh-huh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Ben Hartford of Baird. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Dan, I guess to that point, can you talk a little bit about gross profit per unit both on the air freight side and on the ocean freight side here in the third quarter relative to the second quarter and then maybe what the expectations are as we go into the fourth and then wrapping in &#x2013; discussing the competitiveness of the forwarding environment in the light of available capacity, but continued weakness in volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we did see some margin compression quarter over quarter, clearly we didn't quite hit the overall segment margin we hoped. We had hoped to get to 9% this quarter and ended up coming in still at a healthy 8.3%, the biggest driver of that was the margins on the forwarding.</p>
          <p>We don't disclose the exact margins of our ocean and air forwarding, clearly the ocean has been actually doing a little better than the air forwarding since that is an industry-wide trend and as Dan mentioned with our less container load and expedited ocean, we are finding what we think is profitable niche. We think the fourth quarter will again be a challenging one for all of the forwarders, frankly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That is helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of John Barnes of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Nice quarter. Quick question on the subject of B2B and B2C and that ratio. Is there any seasonality in the fluctuation in those ratios of traffic or are you starting to see B2B &#x2013; B2C, I'm sorry, being a more consistent level of your business? I know Scott said it was growing at 2% of the pie or whatever, is that quarter to quarter very consistent or are you seeing some seasonality in it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as far as the evolution B2B to B2C it's pretty steady, but clearly in the fourth quarter holiday season, B2C is a bigger piece of the mix as it always is during the Christmas season.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I'm sorry, the other three quarters, 1Q through 3Q, is it still very consistent among those three quarters taking out 4Q?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's pretty consistent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Nice quarter, guys, thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of David Ross of Stifel Nicolaus. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="26" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="26" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There is an article that came out highlighting Walmart's experimentation with same-day delivery a couple weeks ago and that they are using UPS to deliver to their customers' homes. Can you comment a little bit on that project and whether or not you are doing same-day delivery with others and whether you think same-day delivery is actually a viable method that people are going to be using and if you are going to be able to charge enough to account for the delivery density problems with same-day delivery?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Good question. I'll let Alan talk about some of those areas of innovation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, clearly there is a heck of a lot going on in the B2C market, you know certainly SurePost postal injection is one of those areas where UPS is doing with UPS My Choice is another and certainly a lot of noise out there with same day type delivery options. I think it's really too early to tell, you know, precisely how that will shape up. That's really an incubating part of the market at this time. I think more importantly is what the retailers are looking at out there and what UPS is helping them do in terms of what is being called like omni-channel out there. We're out there helping both e-tailers and e-tailers with brick and mortar leverage all the assets they have, and what you are seeing now is retailers that want to fulfill directly from their store to consumer or fulfill from their dot-com directly to their stores and create the ecosystem out there where customers have the maximum access and the maximum number of options out there. I think another area is if you can fulfill from a store and provide a customer late pickup then you can get next day delivery or near same day delivery with a late pickup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Keith Schoonmaker of MorningStar. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="27" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. I noticed you open a few more healthcare distribution facilities, and wondering if you can give some color on what portion of forwarding and logistics is in the healthcare distribution area? Also, in the current laboratory of economic uncertainty, what sort of performance you are seeing from your healthcare logistics relative to the cyclicality and uncertainty of the broader market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we did see healthcare grow approximately 20% from revenue perspective, especially in locations where we do a part of the distribution also. We don't share exact numbers, but I think the great thing about healthcare is it is an industry that really makes full utilization of the integrated network and the broad portfolio of UPS. Dan even mentioned in some cases healthcare customers are using ocean, clearly our air freight forwarding and temperature controlled configuration and our express services all come together. So it is an industry where we can really stretch our wings and take advantage of the entire portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the revenue shows up in domestic package, international package, obviously freight forwarding, distribution, so across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have now 5 million square feet of healthcare facilities around the world in 36 facilities and just this last few months we've opened three in Asia for around 400,000 square feet. So it's a growing part of our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="27" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will be a follow-up from the line of Mr. Tom Wadewitz of JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. Scott, I figured you might be disappointed if you get at least a second question on TNT, so I'll try to give you one more on that. I think there has been a lot of noise about what the EC is going to do and the idea that they are being really granular in how they are defining markets, that that might be a challenge. Is there any kind of high level comment you can give us in terms of the SO? Did this end up being a bit &#x2013; more challenging, more stringent than you would have expected? Would you say at the end of the day it is pretty reasonable what you have in there? Can you just kind of shade it in terms of being a little better or a little worse than you would have expected on the SO?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is a complex transaction and whenever you get into phase II, you spend a lot of time with Commission. Our team has spent a lot of time with Commission. I think it has been good, open dialogue and we are exchanging information. We have a ways to go. Certainly, we just got the SO Friday night, so we're obviously going through that right now and over the next couple of weeks we will spend a lot of time responding to that. I know Dan Brutto has spent a lot of the last couple months in Europe on the project. Any comments, Dan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. I think what I could say is we both have, they have a case team, we have a team that is working constructively. As Scott said, it's very complex, it's all the 27 member states of the EU that they are tasked with taking a hard look at. It is just part of the process. The SO is part of the process. We'll go through that. We'll have our response back, but the good news is the teams have open dialogue and certainly we're going to turn in the documents that is required by the Commission within the timeframe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we're confident we'll get clearance and we will get it early in 2013, and we're committed to the transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Due to time constraints our last question will be a follow-up from the line of Mr. Bill Greene of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my question. You know I just wanted to ask, we used to talk about B2C being around a third of the business. I'm curious where it is, you mentioned it sort of accelerated as a percent of the pie. Where does it ultimately top out at? I would sort of think at some point you'd rather say, let's just start raising prices on this stuff more aggressively because we don't want too much of it given the mix effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, certainly it's our goal to optimize the value, create the premium services either by speed or by My Choice and at the same time for those lightweight low value products, to keep prices down. Right now B2C is running about 40% and clearly given the holidays it will be significantly over 50%. We hope that the core B2B economy also picks up and so the balance remains healthy. Although we'll take whatever the market gives us and find a way to be profitable and generate good returns for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Bill, we adjust. 80 to 90 years ago B2C was 100% of our business, so we will adjust based on how the market changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. Thanks for the follow-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I would now like to turn the floor back over to Mr. Andy Dolny.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm going to turn to Scott for closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy. Unfortunately global trade continues to be slower than any of us would like at this point in time, but I think UPS has made the necessary adjustments. You started to see it in the third quarter results. We did a nice turnaround international going the right direction. In the fourth quarter we actually expect to hit on all cylinders. Each segment anticipates operating profit improvement with margin equal to or better than last year. This is not only a testament to the UPS business model but also the capability and dedication of the UPS team.</p>
          <p>Thanks so much for joining us today and we'll see you next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>