<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1296094" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>521</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Judy Murphy, Executive Vice President, Corporate Investor and Public Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Richard K. Davis, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Andrew Cecere, Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Matthew O'Connor</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">John McDonald</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">P.W. Parker</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jon Arfstrom</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Paul Miller</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Heather Wolf</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Ian Foley</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Nancy Bush</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">P. W. Parker</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Christoph Kotowski</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">P. W.  Parker</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Matthew Burnell</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Christopher Mutascio</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Meredith Whitney</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Betsy Graseck</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Carole Berger</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to U.S. Bancorp's First Quarter 2010 Earnings Conference Call. Following a review of the results by Richard Davis, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer, and Andy Cecere, U.S. Bancorp's Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer, there will be a formal question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> This call will be recorded and available for replay beginning today at approximately noon Eastern Time through Tuesday, April 27 at 12:00 midnight Eastern Time. I will now turn the conference call over to Judy Murphy, Director of Investor Relations for U.S. Bancorp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ashley, and good morning to everyone who has joined our call today. Richard Davis, Andy Cecere and Bill Parker are with me today to review U.S. Bancorp's first quarter 2010 results and to answer your questions. Richard and Andy will be referencing a slide presentation during their prepared remarks. A copy of the slide presentation as well as our earnings release and supplemental analyst schedules are available on our website at usbank.com.</p>
          <p>I would like to remind you that any forward-looking statements made during today's call are subject to risk and uncertainty. Factors that could materially change our current forward-looking assumptions are described on page 2 of today's presentation, in our press release and in our Form 10-K and subsequent reports on file with the SEC. I will now turn the call over to Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Judy. Good morning, everyone and thank you for joining us today. I'd like to begin on page 3 of the presentation and note some of the highlights of our first quarter 2010 results. U.S. Bank reported a net income of $669 million for the first quarter of 2010 or $0.34 per diluted common share. Earnings were $0.10 or 42% higher than the same quarter of last year and $0.04 higher than the fourth quarter of 2009. Total net revenue of $4.3 billion in the first quarter was 11.3% higher than the same quarter of 2009. With an industry-leading efficiency ratio of 49% in the first quarter, we achieved positive operating leverage on a linked quarter basis. We experienced strong year-over-year average deposit growth of 13.7% while average loans grew by 3.9%. Growth in both categories benefited from recent acquisitions.</p>
          <p>As expected, net charge-offs to non-performing assets, excluding covered assets, increased this quarter but at a more moderate rate with both categories rising by approximately 2%. Importantly, the provision for loan losses declined on both a year-over-year and a linked quarter basis as the increase in net charge-offs was more than offset by a decline in reserves built. We maintained our strong capital position with a tier 1 capital ratio and tier 1 common ratio increasing to 9.9% and 7.1% respectively at March 31.</p>
          <p>On slide 4, we show our performance metrics over the past 5 quarters. Return on average assets in the current quarter was 0.96% and return on average common equity was 10.5%, above the returns posted in each of the past four quarters. The first quarter results included two significant items which were net security losses of $34 million and provision expense in excess of net charge-offs of $175 million. Excluding these significant items, which Andy will discuss in a few minutes, return on average assets and return on average common equity would have been approximately 1.19% and 13.1% respectively.</p>
          <p>The five-quarter trends of our net interest margin and efficiency ratio are shown in the graph at the right-hand of slide four. Our net interest margin of 3.90% improved over the prior quarter by seven basis points, primarily due to the lower funding costs. Our first quarter efficiency ratio of 49% was essentially flat to the prior quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide five, our capital positions remain strong. As previously noted, our tier 1 capital and tier 1 common equity ratios rose to 9.9% and 7.1% respectively at March 31. Additionally, our tangible common equity to tangible assets ratio rose 3.8% from March 31, 2009 to 5.6% at March 31, 2010.</p>
          <p>Our company continues to generate significant capital each quarter due to our diverse mix of businesses, a number of which are less capital intensive than our traditional balance sheet businesses, in addition to our superior efficiency ratio and ongoing profitability. Given our ability to generate significant capital even under adverse economic circumstances, we believe we have the capacity to return more of our capital to shareholders through an increase in our dividend rates. However as I have indicated in the past, we must continue to defer a dividend action until we see clear evidence that the economy has recovered and is sustainable and we receive clear regulatory capital guidelines and approval.</p>
          <p>I'm aware of how important the dividend is to our shareholders and I can assure you that we will continue to work closely with our regulators to help facilitate their decision-making process.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide six, average total loans outstanding increased by $7.2 billion year-over-year. As noted on the slide, excluding acquisitions, total average loans declined 2.9% year-over-year. On a linked quarter basis, total average loans increased by 0.6%, driven again, by acquisitions. The lack of growth in average total loans outstanding, excluding acquisitions, was largely due to the lower usage of revolving lines of credit by our commercial and corporate customers. Utilization of outstanding commitments by these borrowers declined from an average of about 30% in the fourth quarter of 2009 to approximately 28% in the first quarter of 2010. Despite this reduction in the balance of average loans outstanding, we are continuing to see the benefits of flight to quality as we gain new customers and believe that our balances are declining less than those of our peers.</p>
          <p>We continue to originate and renew lines and loans for our customers who want and need credit. In fact, during the first quarter of 2010, US Bank originated nearly $9 billion of residential mortgages. We originated over $4 billion of consumer loans including installment loans, student loans, lines of credit and home equity lines and loans. We originated new prime based credit card accounts with lines totaling $2 billion and we issued $6.6 billion of new commitments and renewed $14.6 billion of commitments to small businesses, commercial and commercial real estate customers. Overall, excluding mortgage production, new originations plus new and renewed commitments, were over $27 billion, somewhat lower than the previous quarter's total, again indicating that the demand for new loans remains subdued.</p>
          <p>We continue to be open for business and eager to meet the credit needs of our current and new creditworthy customers. Total average deposits increased by $22 billion over the same quarter of last year and $1.6 billion on a linked quarter basis. Excluding acquisitions, the growth rate was 4.5% on a year-over-year basis. On a linked quarter basis excluding acquisitions, average deposits declined by 1.7% primarily due to lower average DDA balances in wholesale banking and in corporate trust.</p>
          <p>Importantly however, savings deposits which include interest checking, regular savings and money market savings were higher than the fourth quarter by 3.4% reflecting a number of our recent growth initiatives including our new START program, START -- Savings Today and Rewards Tomorrow and our consumer and small-business product packages.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide seven, the company reported total net revenue in the first quarter of $4.3 billion. The growth in core revenue was driven by earning asset growth and expanding net interest margins, our fee-based businesses, growth initiatives and acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Moving on to credit as we turn to slide eight, as we predicted for you last quarter, the rate of increase in net charge-offs moderated on a linked quarter basis. First quarter net charge-offs of $1.135 billion were 2% higher than the fourth quarter of 2009. This percentage increase was lower than the 7% increase recorded between the third and fourth quarters of last year. Nonperforming assets, excluding covered assets, increased by $91 million or 2%. This percentage increase was also lower than the fourth quarter's linked core 5%.</p>
          <p>Notably excluding covered loans, early and late stage delinquencies in all major loan categories improved during the first quarter. The first quarter's nominal increases in net charge-offs and nonperforming assets in addition to the favorable change in early and late stage delinquencies indicates that we are nearing the inflection point in credit quality. Accordingly, we expect the level of both net charge-offs and nonperforming assets to be relatively stable in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide nine, you can see that, as expected given the moderating but still upward trend in both net charge-offs and nonperforming assets, we increased the allowance for credit losses this quarter by recording a $175 million incremental provision for loan losses. This represented approximately 15% of the current quarter's total net charge-offs of approximately $1.1 billion. This compares with an incremental provision equal to 25% of net charge-offs in the fourth quarter of 2009 and to 67% of net charge-offs in the first quarter of 2009. This incremental provision raised the company's allowance for credit losses to period end loans at March 31, excluding covered assets, to 3.2%, up from 3.04% at December 31. The ratio of allowance to nonperforming loans excluding covered assets ended the quarter at 136%.</p>
          <p>With the expectation that the level of net charge-offs to nonperforming assets will remain relatively stable during the second quarter, the amount of reserve built as a percentage of net charge-offs is also expected to decline. The following eight slides provide credit related information about each of our major loan portfolios and I will highlight just a few items on each.</p>
          <p>Slide 10 provides more detail on the commercial loan portfolio, which has declined from an average of over $49 billion in the first quarter of 2009 to approximately $41 billion in the first quarter of 2010, primarily due to the lower line utilization and soft demand for new loans. The net charge-off ratio on the portfolio increased to 2.41% in the first quarter, but the early and late stage delinquencies as well as the nonperforming loans to total loans ratio improved on a linked quarter basis. Overall, asset quality measures are improving for the commercial loan portfolio.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 provides additional information on the commercial leasing portfolio. Delinquencies and the level of non-performing loans have stabilized in this portfolio primarily due to the improvement in BEFG, our Business Equipment Finance Group, where losses peaked in the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 12 and the company's commercial real estate portfolio, average total commercial real estate loans have increased over the past year primarily due to the growth in CRE mortgages, where a lack of permanent financing previously available in the CMBS market has allowed us to extend financing. Net charge-offs on the CRE mortgage portfolio remain low at 73 basis points of average loans outstanding and key credit metrics reflect stable trends. The net charge-off ratio on our commercial real estate construction portfolio, however, remains elevated. Delinquencies on that portfolio have, however, improved significantly year-over-year and property values are stabilizing.</p>
          <p>Turning to the residential mortgage portfolio detail on slide 13, the net charge-off ratio edged lower than the first quarter to 2.23% of average loans outstanding. Importantly, early and late stage delinquencies for the residential mortgage portfolio improved significantly. This improvement was seen in both the traditional branch originated portfolio and in our consumer finance group portfolio where loans with higher LTVs and lower FICO scores reside.</p>
          <p>Our company has been actively working with mortgage customers to renegotiate loan terms since late 2007. Beginning with our own modification programs and now including both the FDIC's modification program and HAMP. Since 2007, including loan service for others, we have modified over 33,500 residential mortgage loans totaling approximately $5.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 14 summarizes the performance of our home equity portfolio. The majority of this portfolio, 87%, was originated through our retail branch network. This traditional portfolio has performed well during the cycle as demonstrated by the current quarter's net charge-off rate of just 1.25%. The remaining 13% of the portfolio is primarily broker originated and is managed by the consumer finance group. Both segments contributed to the improvements in delinquencies and net charge-offs this quarter.</p>
          <p>Credit card loans are detailed on slide 15. Average loans outstanding grew by over 20% year-over-year, but declined slightly from the fourth quarter of 2009. The net charge-off ratio during the past three quarters has been impacted by portfolio purchases made in September of last year, and we have adjusted for the transactions on the chart on the right side of the slide.</p>
          <p>Similar to the other major loan categories, early and late stage delinquencies improved, while net charge-offs increased over the prior quarter, reflecting loan growth trends over the past number of quarters. Going forward, losses on the credit card portfolio are expected to stabilize but remain elevated as long as unemployment remains high.</p>
          <p>Given the high quality of our portfolio, however, we expect to continue to perform significantly better than the industry average.</p>
          <p>Slide 16 provides additional detail on the retail leasing portfolio. Net charge-offs and delinquencies have significantly improved since the first quarter of 2009 as better used car prices have significantly reduced end-of-term valuation and credit losses.</p>
          <p>Finally, slide 17 summarizes the credit information on the other retail loan portfolios, a breakdown by product of which is provided in the pie chart on the right. Early and late stage delinquencies improved in the first quarter, while net charge-offs remained stable. Similar to retail leasing, the auto loan portfolio loss rate improved as used car prices rebounded from their lows.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Richard. I will take just a few minutes to provide you with more details about the results. I turn your attention to slide 18, which gives a full view of our first quarter 2010 results compared to those reported for the fourth and first quarters of 2009.</p>
          <p>Earnings per diluted common share were $0.34 for the first quarter of 2010, $0.04 higher than the prior quarter and $0.10 higher than the first quarter of 2009. The key drivers of the company's first quarter results are detailed on slide 19. The $140 million or 26.5% increase in net interest income -- in net income year-over-year was the result of an 11.3% increase in net revenue driven by a 14.7% increase in net interest income and a 7.3% increase in non-interest income. This favorable change in total revenue was partially offset by a 14.2% increase in non-interest expense.</p>
          <p>Provision for credit losses in the first quarter was slightly lower than prior year's quarter as the $347 million increase in net charge-offs was more than offset by a decrease of $355 million in incremental provisions, as the need for additional reserves declined.</p>
          <p>Net income was $67 million or 11.1% higher on a linked quarter basis. Seasonally lower net revenue was offset by lower operating expenses and again a favorable variance in the provision for credit losses. A summary of the significant items that impact the comparison of our first quarter results to prior periods are detailed on slide 20. The two significant items in the first quarter of 2010 were the net security losses of $34 million, primarily representing impairment on our SIV exposure, and provision in excess of net charge-offs of $175 million.</p>
          <p>Note that the first quarter of 2009 included a $92 million gain on a corporate real estate transaction, which impacts the year-over-year comparisons of the other income line.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 21, net interest income increased year-over-year by $308 million or 14.7% primarily due to a $13.5 billion increase in average earning assets, $13.3 billion of which was acquisition related. Net interest margin was 31 basis points higher than the first quarter of 2009 primarily due to our ability to replace wholesale funding with low-cost deposits and achieve overall lower funding costs. On a linked quarter basis, net interest income was higher by $43 million, primarily due to a $3.4 billion increase in earning assets, which was acquisition related, and a seven basis-point increase in net interest margin. The net interest margin improved due to the change in mix between wholesale funding and low-cost deposits and overall lower funding costs. Assuming the current rate environment and yield curve, we expect the net interest margin to decrease modestly to the mid-380s in the second quarter of 2010 due to the impact of recent legislation on our credit card portfolio yield.</p>
          <p>Slide 22 provides additional detail on our growth in average earning assets this quarter. Year-over-year, average total loans grew by 3.9%. Excluding acquisitions, average loans declined by 2.9%. Average investment securities increased by 3.9 billion or 9.2%. Linked quarter average total loans grew by approximately  $1.3 billion again due to acquisitions, while average investment securities rose by $2.1 billion or 4.7%.</p>
          <p>Slide 23 breaks down the growth in average total loans by category. Looking at the chart, on the left, you can see that the decrease in total average loans excluding acquisitions was essentially due to the 15.8% drop in average commercial loans, as retail, residential mortgage and commercial real estate were all higher on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>The majority of loans related to the FBOP and Downey/PFF acquisitions were reported as covered loans and the $10 billion year-over-year increase was due to the acquisition of the banking operations of FBOP Corporation.</p>
          <p>On a linked quarter basis, the decline in average loans, excluding acquisitions, was again driven by the decrease in commercial loans, partially offset by increases in commercial mortgages, residential mortgages and other retail lending.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 24, you can see the very favorable growth in low-cost deposits over the past five quarters. Average total deposits grew by $22 billion or 13.7% year-over-year, partially due to acquisitions. Importantly, low-cost core deposits, non-interest-bearing, interest checking, money-saving -- money market and savings, excluding acquisitions, grew by 23.5%. This growth reduced the need for wholesale CD and foreign branch type funding, contributing to the net interest margin expansion.</p>
          <p>On a linked quarter basis, average deposits excluding acquisitions declined slightly, principally due to lower non-interest-bearing account balances in the corporate trust and wholesale banking divisions.</p>
          <p>Slide 25 presents in more detail the changes in non-interest income on a year-over-year and linked quarter basis. Non-interest income in the first quarter of 2010 was higher by $130 million or 7.3% for the first quarter of 2009. Excluding the $72 million favorable change in significant items, non-interest income was higher by 3.1%. This positive variance was driven by a 7.5% growth of payment related revenue, 24.8% growth in commercial product revenue, illustrating the success of recent investments and growth initiatives and higher other revenues due to lower end-of-term lease residual valuation losses. These favorable variances were partially offset by a decline in mortgage banking revenue which was $33 million lower than the first quarter of 2009 principally due to a 33% reduction in production volume, partially offset by higher servicing revenue and a favorable change in the MSR valuation and related hedge.</p>
          <p>On a linked quarter basis, non-interest income was lower by $98 million reflecting the fact that the first quarter of the year is the weakest revenue quarter for our company. Excluding the $124 million favorable change in significant items, non-interest income was lower than the prior quarter by 10.2% and was driven by seasonally lower payment revenue and deposit service charges, which declined by 4% and 13% respectively, an $18 million reduction in mortgage banking revenue primarily due to a 19% reduction in production volume, partially offset by favorable variances in servicing revenue and the MSR valuation and related hedge, lower commercial products revenue in trust and investment management fees which declined by 13% and 5% respectively and finally a decline in other revenue due to the fourth quarter 2009 contract termination gain and an unfavorable change in end-of-term valuation losses. Acquisitions had a minimal impact on the variance and fee revenue on a year-over-year or linked quarter basis.</p>
          <p>Finally on slide 26, we are provided highlights on non-interest expense which was higher year-over-year by $265 million or 14%. The majority of the increase can be attributed to acquisitions which accounted for $121 million of the increase, higher costs related to investments and tax advantaged projects, which accounted for $42 million of the increase, FDIC insurance expense in the first quarter of 2009 -- we used the last of our four credits -- and other loan expense primarily to costs associated with other real estate owned.</p>
          <p>On a linked quarter basis, non-interest expense was lower by $92 million or 4.1%, the net result of lower costs related to investments and tax advantaged projects, which accounted for $58 million of the decrease, a decrease in marketing and business development expense, which declined by $45 million and seasonally lower legal and professional services expense, partially offset by higher compensation and benefits related to incentive accruals and the seasonally higher payroll taxes, and finally acquisitions which increased by $53 million.</p>
          <p>Finally the tax rate on a taxable equivalent basis was approximately 24% in the first quarter of 2010. As you turn to slide 28, I will turn the call back to Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andy. Our company's first quarter results once again demonstrated the strength of our franchise and the advantages of our diversified business mix. We posted strong year-over-year revenue growth, maintained our industry-leading efficiency, we achieved linked quarter operating leverage and we saw a reduction in credit costs for the second consecutive quarter.</p>
          <p>We continued to lend, gather core deposits and expand our banking franchise. We remain profitable, generating significant capital and strengthening our already solid capital and liquidity position. We are well positioned to capitalize on the economic recovery as we continue to enjoy the benefits of the flight to quality and we continue to invest in organic initiatives, M&amp;A and joint ventures and those investments, including hiring the best employees and developing and empowering our leaders.</p>
          <p>We will continue to opportunistically acquire and we benefit from core businesses that are scalable and can leverage as the economy recovers. We are more than just a traditional bank, dependent on loans, deposits and a favorable interest environment to grow. We also bring so much more to the table with our breadth and scope of our franchise and product offerings, including global payment capabilities for our wholesale and retail customers, corporate trust services and more. It is this diversification of products and services in addition to our prudent risk management that has allowed us to continue to grow profitably during the past very challenging two years.</p>
          <p>The financial services industry continues to face an uncertain economy, regulatory and legislative environments. The world has changed and there is much more to come. We're actively participating in the dialogue to ensure that the financial services industry and US Bancorp play a vital role in the economic reform and the recovery. Our company is confident and focused on the future. We know that the momentum we have created has positioned US Bancorp well to grow and prosper for the benefit of our customers, our employees, our communities, and importantly our shareholders.</p>
          <p>That concludes our formal remarks. Andy, Bill Parker and I will now be happy to answer questions from our audience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And our first question comes from the line of Matthew O'Connor with Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you just talk a little bit about the revenue outlook and ability to capitalize on banks pulling out or cutting back on a number of product areas, we're seeing card, home equity, CRE, a number of the big banks are pulling back there and you guys generally have been gaining share, I guess we're always looking for more, and wondering how much we'll see in the near term here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Matt. This is Richard. I think we're actually continuing to see robust forecasts in that area, we are benefiting from flight to quality and at the same time, we've taken the measures to improve our corporate bank capability to be fully capable of not outsourcing any activities from anything from syndications to high bond business, high-quality bond businesses, to eventually municipal bonds and things like that. So I think our timing is perfect to step in to places where some of the companies have either backed down or actually exited. As a result, we are also getting more non-lending business that comes with it because as you come into a deal, where a client says, I need you to now be part of my syndication and if you are willing to be the last in, they're more often than not willing to let you have other business along with that. So we're enjoying the benefits of the payments and the trust along with this classic balance sheet banking and I think our timing is actually quite good. And to answer your question specifically, it's actually building momentum. So I think we'll continue to see our books strengthen with new customers as well as the ones we have, continuing to deal with this downturn pretty successfully.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the lending side specifically, obviously there's two factors going on here, there's the market share gains and just the weak demand, but when do you think we'll actually start to see some net loan growth for you guys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I don't think it's for a little while longer. I'm going to be a little less robust in my forecasting for the current economic situation, but the last we looked, housing prices are at record lows and they're staying there, and unemployment is at record highs, and it's staying there. And our customers are a reflection of that world and until we see either or both of those starting to move in positive directions, which eventually they both will, we're going to be likely to see our customers continue to withhold using the lines of credit they've already been extended and certainly new customers are not jumping in for large capital expenditures or big hiring activities.</p>
          <p>At the very early part of the cycle, we're starting to see more M&amp;A, more IPOs, more interest at the early stream of companies starting to get healthier, but those are not the systemically core activities that cause long-term organic growth and we're not seeing that kind of activity yet in the actions of our customers.   So I'm going to say a couple of quarters until you see a real strengthen up of core earnings based on loan growth, and not just from line usage, but from people coming back into the game.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of John McDonald with Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, good morning. I wonder if you could comment a little bit on credit.  Other banks are showing declines in their charge-off and NPAs and are starting to draw down reserves, obviously every bank is different. Just wondering what's your sense of why you are a little different there, maybe a function of how bad things got for other banks or a loan mix. Comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thanks, John. I'll go first, I'll have Bill follow up. I got to tell you, I'm actually quite surprised by the number of banks that have chosen to go from adding to reserves to not even meeting them but going to a recovery of reserves. So I can't speak to their modeling, but I am surprised. I think we're all in the same environment and for me until you get to a place where you're really assured that things are getting better, I think it's prudent to continue to have strong reserves for loan losses that have yet to happen.</p>
          <p>So in our case, and I'll speak just to us, we feel that while we're getting very close to that flattening point, where loan losses, charge-offs, NPAs are flat, which then portends that we can bring down reserve builds and eventually maybe bring them to equal. I don't see a time when reserve recovery is part of our future. I said before this management team is doing its best to make its estimates on where the loans will end up, where the losses will be and where we want to have the cushion to go into the next cycle. I want this to be a fortressed balance sheet and the way we see it is, we're continuing to appropriately do the math and the predictions say we need to continue to strengthen our reserves for the future.</p>
          <p>Now if there is an amazing recovery with both a speed and a slope that I don't expect, then perhaps we'll get to that point where one day we'll be able to recapture some reserves, but we're not intending to do that. We think we're putting in our best dollar hoping that it's the right amount and giving us at least a prudent position to start the next cycle with a very strong balance sheet. So speaking less for them and more for us, but I must say I'm surprised that that many people went that quickly to equal and then recovery, it's a surprise to me. And Bill, you might speak to our details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, John, it's Bill. Just, one thing, you mentioned the fact that our loss rates are significantly lower than most of our peers. And I think that's part of it, I mean we have gone up less, it looks now we're stabilizing, so we'll start, hopefully to be coming down soon, but we're not coming off of those very high peaks that some of our peers are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a question on regulatory reform. Richard, what are the biggest issues for you guys in your business model, and where do you have the strongest views?  And then also Andy mentioned the impact to the margin for the card legislation, if you could just remind us of the totality of the impact of card legislation already, as best you guys can tell?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll go first. I am actually very concerned about the impending reforms that are about -- I think they're imminent in the next probably few weeks. And I concern myself for a couple of reasons, one is we're building these solutions at a time when everyone is very stressed and concerned and these will be decades kind of decisions. So we better be careful and make sure that we get it right. I'm all for consumer protections being strengthened, I'm all for line down authority and the systemic importance of companies that we cannot have the taxpayers bail out anybody again. I'm all for all of that.</p>
          <p>If I had one thing to put at the very top of the list, it is to protect pre-emption. And let me just say very clearly, this is not a help the banks protect themselves, that has nothing to do with it. Pre-emption is a situation that allows banks to provide products to our customers and they don't have to worry about whether they work in different states and different ways. It is a chance to say that if there is something a state doesn't like, the current rules allow for them to challenge that and protect their state customers, or their state citizens. But right now to change the pre-emption to allow the states to have a providing, overriding view of whether or not things are safe for their customers will create an amazing amount of confusion for both us and for them and I hesitate to say, John, it will reduce the number of products that are available. So we are substantially aligned, most of us are, with virtually all the things that you're seeing in reg reform.</p>
          <p>But there are some nuances, not the least of which is the concern for loss of national uniform standards of pre-emption and the concern that we don't have a circumstance where the pre-funding of losses or the slush fund or whatever you want to call it, is burdened by some of those, many of us who actually will, never intend to use it and perhaps are being taxed in the form of a levy, that isn't really fair.</p>
          <p>So we will limit our issues on those couple of points, because I think otherwise why wouldn't we want the stronger protections, why wouldn't we want the non banks to finally have the same oversight we've all enjoyed and why wouldn't we want to be assured that our industry is stronger going into this next time, where the taxpayer will feel a sense of confidence and the shareholders will feel a better sense of confirmation in the stability of our industry. And so I welcome the majority of them, but I do worry about pre-emption and I do think that a backpaying tax of any sort is unfair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy, you want to talk about the real dollar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And John, from a dollars perspective, the Card Act legislation will cost us about $100 million in 2010. Started in the middle of the first quarter, and then will continue through the remainder of the year. The overdraft legislation in addition to some of the changes that we made will cost us 2 to $300 million in 2010 impacting us most specifically in the second through fourth quarters and that's principally in fee income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the card legislation is a mix, Andy, of the NIM and fee, both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is a mix John, but it's more heavily weighted towards the margin component.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And John let me remind as well, the audience, in the beginning of this month, we started our migration towards the new overdraft and NSF fees. We actually made some changes in the first quarter. We made more on April 1 where we started to limit the number and dollar amount of overdraft. And then at the end of June or July 1 and August 15, with the new Fed rules, we'll be prepared to move into the final stage. So you will see some disruption in run rate or linked quarter impact in quarter 2 versus quarter 1. We saw a little in quarter 1 versus quarter 4 and then when we get to the run rate in the second half, we will have a better sense of how those customer behaviors will play out.</p>
          <p>I'll repeat what I said 90 days ago and that is we have I think the luxury and I think the prudence to not force customers into a decision. We're going to watch and check their behavior, we are doing a fairly good job of surveying their interest now and we will create an outcome that allows them to pick how they want to deal with their banking relationships and we'll be very smart to watch what the other actions in the community of banks do and then respond to the best and most favored treatment. We are lucky enough that we have that luxury of time and I believe, waiting to see what the right answer will be. But you will see negative biases kind of linked quarter for the next couple as it relates to overdraft and NSF fees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is PAM-C, either of those pieces of legislation or regulation affecting your payments businesses in either a positive or negative way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a great question. We're actually, that's part of our study of customers and merchants to find out how they feel about if customers are going to be, let's say they don't opt in, and there is a significant higher level of denial at point-of-sale how do the merchants want to step in. Will they step in for their best customers or will they suffer a certain level of breakage that they haven't experienced before. I think at any case, it's got a slight negative bias, because less things will be transacted until people figure out how they want to operate their checking accounts, but I don't think it's a very significant one and we haven't placed any dollar financial detriment to it at all in the future and as we learn more, we will telegraph that. We don't see that as a problem yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Jon Arfstrom with RBC Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. A couple of questions for Bill. In the release, you talked a little bit about how the modification for residential and card customers, you expect that growth trend to continue. Can you talk a little bit about which part of the business is driving it and if you're seeing any light at the end of the tunnel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you talking about residential modifications?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So I mean that's both in our finance company and our home mortgage company that originates more of the Freddie/Fannie products. And we did about $1 billion total HAMP in the first quarter, about 250 of that was on balance sheet, mostly in our finance company. We expect that number to be about the same in the second quarter but there is already some evidence that we are working through the pipeline and that number should start to decline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the other question, the provision was up in the wholesale business a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk a little bit about what drove that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there was a little bit of lumpiness in some of our more leveraged portfolios, but other aspects of the overall portfolio, the middle market corporate book that we're actually showing improving quality trends, but we did have a couple of larger charge-offs in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No real trend, just the...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Paul Miller with FBR Capital Markets. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you much. Can you talk about the loan pricing out there, I mean some banks are out there saying utilization rates are increasing and you said they are relatively flat. But have you seen overheating in pricing, cap rates dropping?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll tell you what, we still do see the demand coming down. So I'm surprised to hear somebody saying that, otherwise. So I'll tell you what we are seeing is, there is, the market has become more balanced. The nice thing, first and foremost, Paul, is banks are getting paid for risk premiums again.  People expect us to charge for that, customers want a traditional bank. The alternatives are lesser than they used to be. So the margins are stronger than they were and I think they'll firm. There will be moments in time when depending on who is in the market, if you're in a community market or if you're in a large market, depending on who it might be, a more aggressive player, you can see unrealistic pricing again like we saw a few years ago.</p>
          <p>So for all intents and purposes, we're seeing a nice kind of a firming up of reasonable and rational pricing and most of the banks that we compete with seem to be taking that at that same measured approach that I would expect and Andy, you might mention that on the margin side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So Paul, we continue to see that loans that are renewing and new bookings are at a bit of a better margin than what is running off. So that phenomenon has been occurring for the last 4 or 5 quarters. I don't think it's going to continue to be at the same levels, but firming up of loan pricing I think is one of the factors in our improvement in our net interest margin in addition to our lower cost funding. The other thing I would highlight is that we are seeing utilization down a bit, it was 30% on average for the fourth quarter, it was 28% on average for the first quarter of this year and you compare that to a year ago, it was 37%. So it continues to fall, albeit at a slower level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is there some regions doing better than others in their loan pricing and utilization, or are they pretty much across your footprint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think there is a significant geographic difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Heather Wolf with UBS. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Heather.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Just a couple more follow-ups on the modifications, first, can you talk a little bit about this sort of inflows and outflows to that 1.6 billion that you're showing on slide 13 and can you also talk about redefault rates and where you see those going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me talk about redefault rates first. I mean there is a couple of different ways to measure it. There is some industry data which looks at 12 months out and so 2 payment delinquencies 12 months out, that's, we're at 30% and industry statistics are at about 40%. And then we also look at those that ultimately go to foreclosure and for that our rate's about 20% for the overall residential mortgage portfolio. So those are a couple of statistics on the restructured loans. So, and again what I talked about on residential mortgages is that the on-balance sheet, we did about 250 million of HAMP in the first quarter, we expect a similar amount in the second quarter. But there are signs that that dollar amount's already declining. So it may have already peaked.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And were there any outflows or do you follow the 'once a TDR, always a TDR' accounting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Once it's a TDR it's always a TDR.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And one last question, of this $1.6 billion, is any of this covered by your loss sharing, would, are any of the potential redefaults covered by loss sharing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not in these statistics here. No. That would be the Downey portfolio, which is under the covered assets section.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So this is just modifications on your book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, old-fashioned stuff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay, thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Heather.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Ken Usdin with Bank of America. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys, it's actually Ian Foley for Ken. How's it going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Quick question, wanted to dive into the fee items a little bit and kind of just talk to outside of some of the seasonality, what kind of areas came in stronger or weaker than you would have expected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Andy. So a particular area of strength was our payments group. We saw our payments in total go up 7.5% versus a year ago. Categories like merchant processing versus a year ago is up over 13%. We saw same-store sales increase 3.3%. So I think that's a reflection of us continuing to gain share and the strength across all those categories. Commercial products year-over-year was up, that's again a function of us building the businesses that we've been talking about in the wholesale and corporate banking group and those are areas of strength. Seasonally the first quarter versus the fourth quarter is lower, really across almost every category, probably 75 to $100 million. So we would expect the decline in the first quarter that we saw. In addition, mortgage production is down a bit. Last year, we had a production level of about $13 billion in the first quarter, this year it was just about 9 billion. So that's another key factor in the year-over-year results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Chris Whalen with IRA. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Nice quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, how much of your growth is coming from taking share as opposed to the economy recovery, I mean I'm not so much looking for a statistic as just your gut?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My gut is 50-50. We have worked really hard when basically no one was really paying attention in the last two years recrafting this whole company's ability to work with customers at a deeper level, build a full-on first-class corporate bank across the nation, not across the footprint, reconstruct our wealth management, Chris, all the things that I'll be able to talk about in a couple of years and describe to you all why we came out so much stronger. But at this early stage, for all of them, they are demonstrating high performance and we're still really lucky. I mean this company has benefited from the relative outcome of a negative environment we couldn't have changed on our own anyway.</p>
          <p>So we're taking advantage of it. We've got a lot higher quality people that we brought into these new business lines, we've changed the culture to deal more with relationships than individual transactions. And I'll tell you, those are the things that are probably 50% of our strength right now and what I like about that the most is when I go to bed at night I'm going to know that it's the reason we're going to be so much stronger in the future. It's not a one-quarter event, it's a momentum toward an entirely new kind of a run rate. And then the last piece that I said in my prepared comments, but I want to put it in my own words again, this is a big deal to be a company that doesn't rely just on the balance sheet. I think in the near term, at least, call it in the next few years, lending overall will be slightly depressed, deposit gathering will be probably slightly more positive and margins overall will probably firm up, but they will move around as well with rates moving up and down. I love the fact that we've got this other diversified earnings stream in the trust and the payments businesses that, they're not countercyclical, but there definitely not aligned exactly with the behaviors of balance sheets and I think that's going to portend, as the recovery hits, kind of an extra cylinder that gives this company a stronger future going out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up on that, in terms of interest rates, if we're at the peak or we hope we're at the peak in terms of credit loss, what do you see in terms of the evolution of NIM going forward and particularly, a lot of institutions, as I think we're all aware, are wide open right now trying to maximize net interest margin. How would you guys look at the interest rate risk environment just in terms of repricing your liabilities and the attitude of customers in terms of yield, because they've all been starved to death by the Fed, and as soon as the funds are able to offer them another quarter of a point, how do you think that's going to affect your stability in terms of both core and more volatile liabilities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, this is Andy, we have been positioning our balance sheet, we never really positioned it significantly assuming rates will go a certain way. We're always fairly neutral but we have moved to being asset sensitive. And we continue to position that way. So what that means is, for example on the securities portfolio, our purchases are more floaters than fixed, give up a little bit of yield in the short-term, but I think we've positioned ourselves appropriately for the long-term</p>
          <p>and that's the way we're thinking about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's something to add to that. This is Richard. As you recall, too, a few years ago, we were starved on interest margins and protecting it so viscerally that our deposit rates were at the very low, probably the low decile. And in this last couple of years we've gotten ourselves now above the median and competing not just, we're not losing on price, we're now competing on quality and we've got price as a non-issue. That's a pretty big deal and this company is constructed, the way we run it now, to be able to move lock step with rate changes and not need to withhold those benefits when they come along. We're going to get the benefit on the lending side, we'll give it on the deposit side. We've come to learn that you don't build a bank without getting new customers, you start most often with a deposit and then you have the fighting chance to work with them for a relationship. And that's another one of those underlying benefits that we've built over the last couple of years that I think will show themselves in the next couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Well, thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Nancy Bush with NAB Research, LLC. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Nancy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Nancy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Quick question on commercial real estate and your outlook on credit quality there and I'm talking about non-residential development, CRE, because there have been many predictions of disaster, this is a lagging indicator, et cetera, et cetera. Could you just talk about that, we haven't really had a disaster in non-residential CRE and can you just talk about why not, why the predictions have been so wrong?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll go ahead, this is Bill. If you go back to the early 90s cycle, that was one where there was really massive overbuilding and this cycle, it's really more of a demand issue. And I do think in general underwriting was better than it was in the early 90s cycle. In our particular portfolio, we have seen stress on some of the construction portfolio as it came online, some of the certain office retail, and some of the really soft Southwest markets. But the permanent, the mortgage portfolio, it's diversified. Our biggest asset class is affordable housing, that's been less impacted by some of this downturn. I think there is enough &#x2013; we've already seen values starting to stabilize and we have recourse on our facilities. So I don't view this as being that Armageddon scenario that some have predicted, and I think we will just, it's going to be soft for probably 18 months, but I think it's fairly stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, a question for you. There has been a great deal of speculation about USB's possible entry into the southeast, and is that a geographic region that, where you absolutely have to be, could you do that through an FDIC assisted deal which didn't give you huge presence in the region and then build upon that? Could you just talk about your appetite for sort of doing a non-contiguous acquisition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you. The question was asked perfectly. A very low appetite for a non-transformational deal out of market, or the opposite of that is I would only go out of market for a transformational deal. We really aren't finding our customers uninterested in banking with us because we're not in the 26 states that we don't currently have a retail presence. We're, as you know, Nancy, we have made a commitment to get stronger and deeper in the 24 states we are. The FDIC transactions are like, built perfectly for that and we will look forward to having more opportunities.</p>
          <p>If we were to go out of state, contiguous ore jumping states, it would have to be a substantial transaction, one that, number one, everybody would say, wow, that makes so much sense, number 2, it would be a price point that would have to make sense and good for our shareholders. And we both know it would have to be a capital raise activity that we would only do if it was so reasonable and so useful to the company's future that it made sense. So it would have to hit all those hurdles and if it isn't going to be transformational, we don't see a need to do out of market in order to be successful in the next decade. We just, it would be an opportunity missed if we didn't pursue it, but I don't know that that's ever going to come across, so we're more than happy to be focused on organic growth and old-fashioned quarter-by-quarter business that I think we're starting to demonstrate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Chris Kotowski with Oppenheimer. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to go back to the slide on page 10 about the utilization rate and how it keeps going down. I would have thought, or one would have hypothesized that normally that line utilization should be tied to retail sales, inventory, receivables and so on, or it's inventories and receivables, and those should, in theory, be going up with an economic rebound, and can you explain the disconnect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. This is Bill. I mean what we've seen, really starting late last quarter is corporate America and middle market companies are, they downsized very effectively in reducing their costs, primarily through job layoffs, but they are generating a lot of cash. So the fact that there was inventory buildup occurring here in the first quarter, they have not needed traditional bank sources of funding. So the companies that we deal with, they are very flush and they're waiting for clear signs of that economic recovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Chris, Bill's the smart guy, I'm the layman guy. I'll tell you what, you think about it, these businesses in America have figured out an entirely new level of productivity and efficiency and I think we all surprised ourselves. This bank is one of those. I mean we took a 5% expense reduction last February across the board to protect jobs, but to protect our future. And we did that because the world is different and we all surprised ourselves. Our customers are saying I did this for a couple of quarters and I'll be darned, I can actually be more efficient, I can get along a little further than I thought.</p>
          <p>So they're very hesitant to turn back on the spigot to start spending money unless they're absolutely sure they see it. And in many recoveries past, I believe that businesses went first and followed by customers and consumers who followed them because the products were there and all of a sudden the world got better. I think it's reversed this time, they're waiting for the consumers to move, to consume their products, after which point it's undeniably clear that they're ready and waiting and that inventories are too low, and then and only then they'll pop.</p>
          <p>So I'm believing that we're in a new paradigm where the recovery will be in parts a bit different than it has in the past and probably slower based on the prudence of businesses that have learned to be very efficient. And eventually they'll just say, look, I've got to spend money, but boy, our utilization rate is the best proxy for that because they've got the loans, they've got probably a preferred rate, they're our best customers, and they're still paying it down until which time they don't need it.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we'll be the first to see it because that's cash balances, as they're rich with cash, we're holding it. And so we'll be able to see them move from cash balances down first, second is the actual use of our credit. So there are actually two steps to occur and we haven't seen the cash balances starting to fall either, so I think that's why I answered the question earlier that it's a few quarters out until we see it show up on a bank's balance sheet as a loan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I guess my second sort of big picture question is that I have seen the interest rate disclosure in your 10-K, but I guess I still think, when I look at a company like yours, with so much in core deposits on the right-hand side and so much in what should theoretically be variable rate loans on the left-hand side, one would think that you'd really be fairly dramatically asset sensitive. And yours is a company that used to have a 425 to 450 basis point margin. And is there something structurally different in the world now that in a higher rate environment generally would prevent you from getting back to that kind of level a few years down the line, in say an environment where rates are 2, 3, 400 basis points higher over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, this is Andy. We try to manage the balance sheet, so we're not dramatically anything and we try to keep it fairly neutral. We are asset sensitive a little bit as we've talked about. There are a lot of mechanisms that you can use to manage the balance sheet rate sensitivity, and I'm very comfortable with the disclosure we have in terms of our positioning should rates rise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Matt Burnell with Wells Fargo. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks for taking my questions. Just an administrative question on the net interest margin. The increase in the net interest margin, and forgive me if you've already covered this, was up about 7 basis points over the quarter, that seemed to be largely due to the consolidation of assets on the balance sheet and that's one of the reasons why you're targeting a somewhat lower net interest margin in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, that didn't really have a large impact, the principal reason for the improvement was a little bit on the wholesale, on the funding costs, a little bit of the mix of funding, more of a move toward core deposits, and a little bit on the loan repricing that we talked about. Those are the key factors. The principal reason that we're expecting a little bit of a decline in net interest margin really rates to the Card Act and some of the legislative changes around that and that's the reason for the low to mid 380s.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And can you give us the amount of the reps and warranties expense in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Reps and warranties expense? Give us more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of mortgages that have been put back to you by the GSEs or other parties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I see, thank you, Matt. That's insignificant for us. We have had a very good origination process, we're very good at dotting the I's, crossing the T's, and that has just not been a significant issue for us. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then one last question, I guess related to Nancy's question on acquisitions, but of a somewhat different take, given the landscape has really, for, in consumer finance, rather than traditional mortgage lending, I've got to think the events of the past couple of years have made that market much more wide open for competitors such as US Bank. Is there any appetite in your, for you to purchase perhaps a more consumer-oriented finance franchise rather than a bank at this point given the somewhat lower competitive pressures in that business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the answer's no.  I owe you more than that.  A couple of reasons, Matt, we have a wholly owned finance company in the bank that we started in 1993. Actually I was part of that deal, Star Bank, and we have a very broad network of correspondents and brokers that we've worked with now for almost 20 years. We could turn that volume up a second if we wanted to, and as you know our credit in that portfolio is less quality than the banks and it was much better, I would say, than, more like near prime kind of business. So we don't have any interest in finding another avenue. I certainly wouldn't do a branch network. We actually had one years ago and closed it down because it's not conducive for those kinds of customers. Your branch is really your best place for deposit gathering.</p>
          <p>So I think if we wanted to turn on the spigot for consumer finance, you wouldn't believe how much we could do. So what little we're doing is a reflection of our fact that we only want to do it through the very finest people. We need to do a lot of it originated through our own customers and be very prudent about who we deal with outside. And what you'll see, we'll probably grow over time but we're not going to take advantage.</p>
          <p>And I do think, by the way, you're onto something, and that is that as the world starts to evaluate these consumers and small businesses that have failed, who is going to be the first to say, I'll look the other way and bring them back to a credit, and it isn't going to be us.  So some are going to do that, they're going to say, I'll waive the bankruptcy, I won't make you go years. Remember, our parents used to tell us, watch your credit history, it's your whole reputation. And sad to say, one of the first things we'll see is people jumping back in and allowing sales clients to get back in, and to me that's a mistake. But we will be very careful and you won't see that move much more than increments over quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Moshe Orenbuch with Credit Suisse .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Moshe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm showing that he has withdrawn his question. And our next question comes from the line of Chris Mutascio with Stifel Nicolaus. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Andy, most of my questions have been asked and answered, but I've done a remarkably poor job in forecasting your other fee income line item, it bounces around a lot. And I know in the release, you talked about three things, one was the payments related gain in the fourth quarter, I think you talked about the lower equity investment income and the impact of retail lease residual valuation losses that have -- between fourth quarter and first quarter. Can you go over those swings with me on those three individual line items?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure Chris. So in the fourth quarter of 2009, we had a payments related gain, about $30 million, that was a, more of a one-time event, not repeated in the first quarter. The equity gains, we have an equity investment portfolio PEMB, that was down a little bit quarter-over-quarter, under 10 or $15 million. And finally in the lease residual category, we continue to see improvement, the improvement in the fourth quarter was more dramatic in terms of auto prices and so we had a little bit more positive fourth quarter than the first quarter and that was the other factor. If you take those things out, it was fairly stable, but those are three sort of unique events that impact other revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the 135 or so in terms of $135 million in the quarter for the other kind of fee income line item, is that at a -- I know it's lumpy, but is that kind of a decent run rate to look forward going in subsequent quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was nothing unusual. Let me say it this way, there was nothing unusual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Meredith Whitney with Meredith Whitney Advisor Group. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to take the opportunity, a lot of good questions have been asked, but to get more of a landscape type feel, because you see so much of the consumer and the consumer activities and small business activities. There have been some mixed messages so far from the companies that have reported in terms of where spending has come from, and from retail sales numbers it looks like all but Wal-Mart spending's coming from everywhere. If you take out gas, can you bifurcate the consumer because it seems as if the lower end still has less access to credit and shouldn't be spending that much. Is it all driven by the high end, or could you just add some color to that? And I then have a follow-up, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'll start and then have Andy pick it up. We do have a great view of the world as, at least the consumer retail world. Our merchant acquiring portfolio is like a third airlines, a third hoteliers and a third retail. And then our credit card business is pretty robust. So what we're seeing is a lot more activity in the debit card, not credit, it makes sense, right, they're using money they have and you've all seen how consumers have gotten more prudent. And we've seen on a year-over-year basis in our merchant acquiring, Meredith, a 13% increase quarter one last year to quarter one this year. That's a nice spread between travel and retail activities but those are primarily the first large signs of quarter &#x2013; year-over-year, quarter-to-quarter growth we've seen and it's primarily found and demonstrated in the debit side. So we're also seeing consistency in people not using their credit cards.</p>
          <p>Andy, you might want to pick up on, corporate cards are also very strong. The government, I'm happy to report, is spending their budget and the money is being spent as we predicted. But the credit activities are still going to be slow and I think you'll see the NSF/OD reflect some of that lesser buying as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. That's right. Because we had our corporate card activity increase principally due to government spend, same-store sales again 3% up year-over-year, that compares to 3% down in the fourth quarter. So we are seeing some improvement there and I would say that that improvement, Meredith, was rather broad-based, it was both domestic and international, in our merchant acquiring portfolio in Europe and across most categories. So not a significant upward tick, but across the board everything was a little bit more positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But theoretically those that have less in their, in their savings accounts or checking accounts can spend less, so there should be a natural divide towards the higher-end in spending. I guess I'm trying to drill down in terms of where spending is really coming from if you take out gasoline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I am taking out gasoline every time I answer. I'll tell you, we get paid a great deal more on the actual transaction than the size of it. So everyone still goes to the grocery store, they still go to the gas station, they still swipe their card and that's one of the benefits of a merchant acquiring portfolio, is we get paid as much for the transaction as we do the size. So I'm probably less clear on the impacts of smaller ticket size in debits than I would be in credit because it's the outstandings that it creates. But I mean you're right, the people have less money, they're being more careful. But I'll tell you, they're actually spending it more often, so they're going to the ATM machine, to keep it simple for me, they'll go there and pull out $20 five times in a week and they'll pull out 100 on Monday. Because they're just not sure what it will look like by the time payroll comes around. So we're seeing activities actually starting to pick up, we're not necessarily seeing average balances and on the credit side, we're obviously seeing them slow down and be careful spending money they don't have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So when I do checks in terms of different regions, you feel real populist rage among small-business owners and consumers, vitriol against Wall Street. How &#x2013; as community banks are closing and whatnot, how are you addressing those needs, is that where you're picking up market share, is there -- what does the small business lending environment look like as they fund themselves from <mark type="inaudible" /> and credit cards going forward, and then I'm done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right on, no those are good. So small businesses used to fund themselves in great part, sole proprietors with their home equity, which is an ATM. And they typically would use their credit card. So I'll tell you what, we are getting a flight to quality of some customers, small businesses that are looking for a place that they feel safer at, but we're not seeing a great deal of growth in small-business qualified customers. I mean if they are, it's a perfect reflection of this economy and either those who are looking for a loan who need it the most are probably the least qualified, and we're certainly not making that loan. We wanted to help them out, we're giving them a lot of guidance, but we're not making that loan. And I'll tell you if they don't have the access to the credit cards and they don't have the home equity, that is what you're hearing from Main Street and that is we need loans, we want loans.</p>
          <p>I'll tell you what, we want to make them, but it would be imprudent for us to make them at a time in the cycle where they're least qualified.  And so the best we can do is give them guidance on how to become more attractive as a future lending candidate, but we typically will say no unless they're qualified and we're not changing our underwriting. So we are seeing a relative flight to quality but an absolute shrinkage in qualified people who are looking for a loan that they can actually pay back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so in another words you see a growing percentage of sort of a de-bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Factor. Okay, all right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Betsy Graseck of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks. Two questions. One is on the Administration's proposal recently for HAMP to have another way of restructuring loans to include principal forgiveness if the borrower qualifies. And could you just give us a sense as to how you're thinking about that program and how that could potentially impact your portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Bill, why don't you do that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so are you talking about the 2MP one or the one first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both, well, so they're different, but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, they are,  yeah...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, well my question was specifically on the first, but what's the overlap to the 2MP would be helpful, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so on the 2MP for our portfolio, I mean we have very few purchased money seconds and I think that is more what that portfolio, or what that program was designed for, where the first and second are done together and really act like one mortgage. So for us was almost 90% of our portfolio coming out of the branches where it's just traditional home equity, we don't feel that that program is really appropriate or designed for our type of portfolio.</p>
          <p>On the other program, I mean there is the home affordable foreclosure alternative, that's the one that's to encourage short sales or to make sure short sales don't get in the way of a transaction that's beneficial to the homeowner. That's something we're already working on, we've already been doing short sales and we continue to do that. The other one is the enhanced, what I'll call the enhanced HAMP, that's the one that they say that might get in place by August, or September, but they have temporary relief for if you lose a job, et cetera, et cetera. That thing is, there is a lot of details to be worked out on that. So it's not clear to us exactly how all that would work at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So ... go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To summarize, the 2MP, or what is the HAMP for seconds, we're not opting in.  We're not because our portfolio doesn't really lend itself to that. But I also just want to say when you opt into a program and the rules keep changing you regret having opted in because you just can't predict and we're in the business of giving you guys a fairly good predictable company. So I'm telling you what, this company will do everything that's right for all the people that deserve it. But in some cases, we're going to do because it's right, not because we're mandated and the rules change.</p>
          <p>And I'm very strong on that because we don't deserve to be told how to run the company, when we're trying to do what's right and sometimes the rules are actually prohibitive of letting us work around some other constructs for customers that have unique circumstances.  And I do think that, to Bill's point, the enhanced HAMP that's coming along, we are in HAMP, and we will provide support for everything we're asked to do. But we're going to continue to be vocal on making sure that the rules aren't creating outcomes that make it harder for consumers to get what they want. And/or that they don't create incentives for healthy consumers to find themselves in harm's way to play into the game of the new rules. That's a really unintended consequence we've got to watch for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Now that is very clear.  Thank you.  And then the second question I had is just on the dividend and the dividend outlook. Could you just give us some updated views there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure can. This is sadly an update of new information that's a repeat of what I said before. We believe a couple of key paradigms, and one is that we are able to increase our dividend based on our forecast of our earnings and based on the stress tests upon which we know there are a number of variations and versions that we are using. We can substantially increase our dividends and be fine with the earnings. But we understand the government's need, number one, to be absolutely positive this recovery is sustained and on its way. And therefore we understand that they don't want to be giving anybody permission to do that in case things would turn around. And I think we need to follow that logic.</p>
          <p>And secondly I understand that they're still waiting, I think at the level that you and I both know, both at the domestic and global levels, to decide what the final definition of capital will be and then what the final number will be, in fact, which final ratio will be.  So we are soon to find out what the ratio will be used, whether it will be core or the new definitions that they are now -- out for comment, whether it will be domestic or global.</p>
          <p>And I understand that's going to be a little longer than I'd like to wait, but I understand we're in queue, with that knowledge and that has to be understood as well.  So I'm waiting for permission. I'm waiting for guidelines. If it was my own information that I had in hand and I could do it by myself I would raise the dividend now.  But I, it would be imprudent to do so and I'm not going to challenge the regulators. We're working well with them and we understand that they are giving us all the information along the way and we are not going to either sit back and wait around without making it known that we're out here and we were eager to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from line of Carole Berger with Soleil Securities.  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Carole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Carole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there.  How are you? And just to clarify on your last statement, you sort of made it sounds like the regulators at this point don't want you, or are telling you not to raise the dividend. Is that what you meant to say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, I did. I think people didn't realize probably that in all the years we've all been together, and I've known you for many of those, we always needed to get permission to raise the dividend. It's just that everyone was making money all the time, the dividends were always probably 40 or 50% of total earnings and nobody ever needed that fee to work.</p>
          <p>When the world turned down and companies started to lose money and some were not able to cover their dividends, it became clear that the rules that we weren't all talking about were present again and that is the Federal Reserve has the right to decide and approve on any dividend action at any time. And that's who we're dealing with, and so the Fed has been very clear in telling us that whether you are ready in your own mind, we need to be sure that this economy is ready for if you and anyone else that we might permit, and we're not ready to give you that answer. And so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And have they given you the indication of what metrics they're looking at to decide that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, and that's my point earlier to Betsy's question, I think they would agree that there are a number of uncertainties in terms of which ratio we will use, whether it will be a national or a global construct, how long we'll have to get there and now, as you know, with a thing called Basel 3, or whatever you want to call it, now there's even a question of what will be the definition of core capital before we even decide what the number is.</p>
          <p>So all the moving parts are obvious to all of us and so it's not, I'm not surprised that we can't get an answer because I understand the prudence of making sure that we don't do something we, as an industry that we will regret. On my hand, though, I have to be a vocal advocate for my company and make sure that we're not collateral damage in the waiting game. And so we're good partners with our regulators, we're making it very clear we're anxious, we want to move on, we give them our numbers, we show them our stress tests, and we continue to argue the merits of, let us move forward, and at this point they're saying not yet, and we are waiting for better guidelines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My other question was both on deposit pricing and loan pricing, do you think that the consolidation that we have seen is going to make a difference going forward in the fact that we probably have more rational pricers in the marketplace and if you wanted to, could you comment on taking WaMu out of the game and replacing it with JP in your marketplace?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Carole, this is Andy and I'm not talking specifically, but your statement is absolutely correct. I think if you look at the last eight quarters or so, deposit pricing has become much more rational. At the same time we've moved up sort of from the lower quartile to the median in our peer group and I think the combination of lower rates and the fact that deposit pricing has become more rational allowed us to do that with very little impact to margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will say, Carole, well you know the world is uneven, and so the community banking markets where we have 1,000 of our 3,000 branches are later in the cycle and I will say, it wouldn't surprise you, that some of the banks that are starting to stress, kind of their last ditch effort is to be very aggressive on deposit pricing or to be very unrealistic in loans. And so until, I say until things are cleared up, that's probably a year or two from now, when the majority of FDIC transactions have been recognized and reckoned with, I think we'll see in different markets unreasonable pricing.</p>
          <p>But at the big markets and the banks you're talking about, we're seeing a much more solid rational performance in pricing, and it gives us all a better sense of dealing with that community of banks that are all working together to not coalesce or to price together but to working where we get paid for the risk and we do the right job of giving people the discriminate value for relationships and more business gets better pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just for my own edification, when you said you've moved up the rankings in terms of deposit pricing, have you moved up or has everybody else moved down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's definitely both. We've definitely -- we have made a very discriminate move in the last eight quarters to pay up on deposits and many have come down and I think partly because of the earlier conversation, there's a tighter range. We can be in the top half and not need to be overpriced or taking kinds of risks that we might have had to a couple of years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, Carole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions in queue at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just close. I want to thank you all for your interest in our company and your support. I wanted to characterize us as not very sexy and that's present company excluded of course, but this is a company that is simple and straightforward and I think predictable and I hope that has value to all of you and therefore to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>There is so much volatility and so much noise, we're very proud of what we have been able to accomplish in the last couple of years and let it be said while each quarter will continue to be predictable and hopefully repeatable and simple, I do think that from the earliest questions this morning if we are building a company that I know we are, you'll see the real benefits in years forward when you'll appreciate the kind of investments we made at a time when so many others were working on other things. And I'm excited about, I think today was a very good demonstration of our core simple bank but I think it portends that we have got a really good future based on some things that are starting to emerge and I'm looking forward to sharing them with you in future years.</p>
          <p>So, Judy, do you want to close?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks everyone for listening and as always if you have questions, please feel free to call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this does conclude today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>