<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1240585" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>521</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Judith T. Murphy, Executive Vice President, Corporate Investor and Public Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Richard K. Davis, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Andrew Cecere, Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Matthew O'Connor</participant>
      <participant id="5">P.W. Parker</participant>
      <participant id="6">Edward Najarian</participant>
      <participant id="7">Betsy Graseck</participant>
      <participant id="8">David Rochester</participant>
      <participant id="9">John McDonald</participant>
      <participant id="10">Nancy Bush</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mike Mayo</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to U.S. Bancorp's Second Quarter 2009 Earnings Conference Call.  Following a review of the results by Richard Davis, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer, and Andy Cecere, U.S. Bancorp's Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer, there will be a formal question and answer session.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  This call will be recorded and available for replay beginning today at approximately noon Eastern Time through Wednesday July 29, at 12:00 midnight Eastern Time.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the conference over to Judy Murphy, Director of Investor Relations for U.S. Bancorp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Michael and good morning to everyone listening to the call today.  Richard Davis, Andy Cecere and Bill Parker are here with me to review U.S. Bancorp's second quarter 2009 results and to answer your questions.  If you have not received a copy of our earnings release and supplemental analyst schedules, they are available on our website at usbank.com.</p>
          <p>I would like to remind you that any forward-looking statements made during today's call are subject to risk and uncertainty.  Factors that could materially change our current forward-looking assumptions are detailed in our press release and in our Form 10-K and subsequent reports on file with the SEC.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Judy and good morning everyone and thank you for joining us.  Andy and I will begin the call today with a short review of U.S. Bancorp's second quarter.  After we've completed our formal remarks, we'll open up the line for questions from the audience.  Since our last earnings call, a number of significant events have occurred that have impacted our investors and our customers, as well as our company as a whole.  I'd like to take a moment to summarize those events before Andy and I review the details of our second quarter financial results.  On May 8, the results of the Supervisory Capital Assessment Program or stress test were released.  As we announced, U.S. Bancorp passed the stress test.  I'm also very proud to say that we ranked the best among our peers in the categories of resources to absorb losses to risk-weighted assets and total loan loss rates.</p>
          <p>On May 11, we announced a $2.5 billion common stock offering and a $1 billion non-guaranteed debt issuance.  The capital raised was not prompted by the results of the stress test, but rather by our company's desire to redeem the $6.6 billion of preferred stock issued to the U.S. Treasury under the Capital Purchase Program, and then move forward from a position of strategic flexibility and independence.  The issuance of the non-guaranteed debt was also required to qualify to repay the TARP funds.  We were very pleased with the outcome of this issuance as it was completed at the best pricing of any other peer bank debt issuance up to that date and was a testament to the credit quality of our institution.  Both the common stock offering, which raised $2.7 billion of capital and the debt issuance were successfully completed in one day.</p>
          <p>On June 17, we announced that we'd redeem the $6.6 billion of TARP fund; and finally on July 15 announced that we'd completed our participation in the program by repurchasing the warrant issued in the conjunction with the TARP funds for $139 million.  Our successful exit from the TARP program validates the strength of U.S. Bancorp.  We are grateful for the support of the tax payers and the regulators during our participation in the program and we are now looking forward to capitalizing on our position as one of the largest independent banks in the country.  While we were managing through these corporate events, the rest of the company continued to run business as usual and produce strong core operating earnings in what can only be described as a very stressed economic environment.</p>
          <p>U.S. Bancorp recorded net income of $471 million for the second quarter of 2009.  Diluted earnings per common share were $0.12.  Once again, we achieved record total net revenue this quarter and it was driven by growth in both net interest income and fee revenue, the latter of which was led by mortgage banking activity.</p>
          <p>Although core operating earnings were strong, significantly higher credit costs, including the cost of building the allowance for credit losses to reflect existing economic conditions and higher FDIC insurance costs resulted in earnings that were lower than the second quarter of 2008 and the previous quarter.  Significant items impacting the company's second quarter earnings per share included an FDIC special assessment of $123 million, accelerated amortization of the discount or deemed dividend of $154 million associated with the TARP preferred stock redemption, net securities losses of $19 million and $466 million of provision expense in excess of net charge-offs.</p>
          <p>In total, significant items reduced diluted earnings per common share in the second quarter by approximately $0.34.  Our performance metrics were impacted by these significant items with return on average assets in the current quarter of 0.71% and return on average common equity of 4.2%.  Excluding the significant items I just noted, return on average assets and return on average common equity would have been 1.41% and 15.9%, respectively.</p>
          <p>As I stated, our company continued to perform well this quarter on an operating basis.  And I'd like to review a few of those financial highlights that impacted these results.  First, we recorded strong overall growth in total average loans year-over-year.  Total average loans outstanding increased by $20.8 billion or 12.8% with growth in all major categories.  Excluding the impact of recent acquisitions, total average loans on a core basis grew by over 5% year-over-year.  On a linked quarter basis, total average loans decreased by 1%.  This linked quarter decrease in average loans outstanding was principally due to the reduction in commitment utilization.  Specifically, the average rate of commitment utilization by our corporate and commercial borrowers declined from an average of slightly over 37% in the first quarter of 2009 to slightly under 35% in the second quarter.  The decline also reflected an overall softening of demand for new loans by our customers both commercial and consumer as they maintained a cautious outlook on the economy and their own growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>We are however continuing to originate and renew new lines and loans for our current and for our new customers.  In fact, during the second quarter of 2009 U.S Bank originated over $16 billion of residential mortgages, another record quarter for U.S. Bank Home Mortgage.  We originated over $4 billion of consumer loans including installment loans, student loans, lines of credit and home equity lines and loans.  We originated new prime based credit card accounts with lines totaling $2.5 billion and we've issued almost $9 billion of new commitments and renewed over $16 billion of commitments to small businesses, commercial and commercial real estate customers.</p>
          <p>Overall new originations plus new and renewed commitments were over 12% higher than in the previous quarter.  As I stated at the time we announced the redemption of our TARP preferred stock, we continue to look forward to supporting the government's efforts to maintain the flow of credit in these stressful economic times.  We will continue to be responsive to the borrowing needs of our current and new credit-worthy customers and more importantly we have the capacity to do so.</p>
          <p>Another highlight of the second quarter results was our outstanding growth in total average deposits.  Total average deposits increased by $27.4 billion or 20.2% over the same quarter of last year, and $2.7 billion or 1.7% unannualized on a linked quarter basis.  Without acquisitions the year-over-year growth was a very strong 11.2%.  We continue to be one of the highest rated financial institutions in the country with our lead bank U.S Bank National Association rated AA1 by Moody's, double AA minus by S&amp;P, AA minus by Fitch and AA high by DBRS.  These ratings have given us a significant advantage as our customers make the decision as to where they should bank and where they should place their trust.  The excellent growth in the average deposits further illustrates that our company is benefiting from the uncertainty in the financial market and the flight to quality that consumers and businesses that are looking for a safe, stable and sound financial institution.</p>
          <p>As I previously mentioned, the company reported record total revenue in the second quarter.  A major contributor to this success was mortgage banking, which also produced record setting revenue with increases year-over-year and linked quarter of $227 million and $75 million, respectively.  The growth in mortgage banking revenue reflected higher origination fees, servicing revenue and a favorable change in the fair value of mortgage servicing rights, net of economic hedging activity, the latter of which had a positive impact on revenue this quarter.</p>
          <p>Record mortgage production of $16.3 billion was significantly higher than the both of same quarter of 2008 and to the prior quarter.  Finally, I'd like to draw your attention to non-interest expense which was impacted by the special FDIC assessment and overall increase in the rate of insurance coverage, partially offset by benefits from implementation of the company's cost containment plan in late January.  Year-over-year, including the impact of acquisitions and the incremental cost of FDIC insurance, total non-interest expense increased by less than 1%.  The $258 million increase in expense on a linked quarter basis was the result of the increase in FDIC expense as well as seasonally adjusted higher operating expense and the national marketing campaign, partially offset by the company's cost savings efforts.</p>
          <p>Our efficiency ratio as reported for the second quarter of 2009 was 51.0%.  Excluding the FDIC special assessment, the efficiency ratio was 48.0%.  We continue to be one of the most efficient financial institutions in the industry and I am pleased to report that we achieved positive core operating leverage this quarter on a year-over-year basis.  Now moving on to credit, as I pointed out earlier an increase in credit costs including the cost of building the allowance for credit losses drove the year-over-year reduction in the company's net income.</p>
          <p>Net charge-offs of $929 million were 17.9% higher than the first quarter of 2009, a lower percentage increase than we experienced in the previous quarters.  The increase in net charge-offs once again reflected the continued stress in residential homes and mortgage related industries, and the impact of the worsening economy on both our retail and commercial customers.  Also, and as expected, non-performing assets increased this quarter, the rate of increase at 17.8%, less however lower than in the past number of quarters.</p>
          <p>At June 30, the total non-performing assets were $4.16 billion, compared with $3.410 million at March 31.  Included in total non-performing assets were $682 million of loans and other real estate covered by a loss share agreement with the FDIC in conjunction with our two California acquisitions.  There is a minimal amount of potential loss in these loans given the terms of the agreement with the FDIC.  Excluding these covered assets the majority of increase in non-performing loans was in the core bank portfolio, was related to residential mortgage and residential construction related industries, as well as other commercial real estate lending.</p>
          <p>Restructured loans that continued to accrue interest rose by 10.8% as the company continues to work with customers to re-negotiate loan terms, enabling them to keep their homes.  Since 2008 including loans service for others we've modified over 15,800 residential mortgage loans totaling approximately $3.5 billion.  These efforts are consistent with the government's objective to restore the housing market and our aim to retain the value of these relationships for our shareholders.  As expected given the upward trends in both net charge-offs and non-performing assets, in addition to the continued weakness in the economy, we increased the allowance for loan loss this quarter by recording an incremental provision for loan losses in excess of net charge-offs of $466 million. This represents approximately 50% of the current quarter's total net charge-offs of $929 million.  With this addition, the company's allowance for credit losses to period end loans, excluding covered assets, was 2.66% compared with 2.37% at March 31 and the ratio of allowance to non-performing loans excluding covered assets was 152%.  As we look ahead 90 days, we anticipate continued growth in both net charge-offs and non-performing assets.  However, we expect the rate of growth to trend lower.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we expect to continue to increase the allowance for loan losses until credit quality has stabilized and we have consistent evidence that net charge-off levels are leveling-off or declining.  We will continue to assess the adequacy of our allowance for loan losses and provide for credit losses at a level that reflects changes in the credit risk of the portfolio and the current economic condition.</p>
          <p>Finally and importantly, our capital positions remain strong.  Our Tier 1 and total capital ratios were 9.4% and 13.0%, respectively at June 30, both very comfortably above the well-capitalized levels as defined by the regulators.  Additionally, our Tier 1 common equity ratio increased to 6.7% from 5.4% at March 31, and our tangible common equity to tangible assets rose from 3.8% at March 31 to 5.1% on June 30.  All these ratios benefited from the recent $2.7 billion capital issuance and positive earnings.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn the call over to Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Richard.  Overall, the company's second quarter results reflected the quality of our core franchise and its earnings power, and I'd like to provide you with a few more details.</p>
          <p>I'll begin with a quick summary of the significant items that impact the comparison of our second quarter results to prior periods.  First, non-interest income included $19 million of securities losses.  Included in this total were $88 million of impairment charges on securities, including perpetual preferred securities, our SIV exposure, and a few agency and non-agency mortgage backed securities.  These impairment charges were partially offset by gains on securities sold during the quarter of $69 million.</p>
          <p>Second, other non-interest expense in the second quarter included a pre-tax $123 million charge for an FDIC special assessment that will be paid in the third quarter.  Third, diluted earnings per share was reduced by the impact of $154 million deemed dividend associated with the repayment of the TARP funds. And finally, we recorded an incremental provision for credit losses in excess of net charge-offs of $466 million in the second quarter.  These significant items in the second quarter reduced diluted earnings per common share by approximately $0.34.</p>
          <p>For comparison purposes, during the second quarter of 2008, the company recorded $63 million in securities losses.  Additionally, results in the second quarter of 2008 included an incremental provision for credit losses of $200 million.  The net impact of the second quarter 2008 significant items reduced diluted earnings per share by approximately $0.11.  Finally, non-interest income in the first quarter of 2009 included $198 million of security losses, a $92 million gain on a corporate real estate transaction.  The prior quarter also included an incremental provision expense of $530 million.  Together, these significant items reduced first quarter 2009 diluted earnings per common share by approximately $0.28.  As Richard mentioned at the beginning of the call, we repurchased the warrant issued as part of the TARP program for $139 million on July 15.  This payment will not have an impact on earnings in the third quarter as the payment represents a direct reduction to equity.  The payment will result in a nominal reduction in our Tier 1 and total capital ratios of approximately 6 basis points.</p>
          <p>Now, a few comments about operating earnings.  Net interest income in the second quarter was 10.3% higher than the second quarter of 2008, primarily due to a strong 10.5% increase in average earning assets.  As projected, net interest margin for the quarter was 3.60%, one basis point higher than the previous quarter or in other words relatively stable.  Our outlook for the net interest margin hasn't changed.  Going forward, assuming the current rate environment and yield curve we continue to expect net interest margin to remain relatively stable.</p>
          <p>Total non-interest income in the current quarter was higher year-over-year, primarily due to strong mortgage banking revenue, as well as favorable variances in net securities losses, commercial product revenue, ATM processing revenue and treasury management fees.  The growth in both commercial product revenue and treasury management fees reflected the company's ongoing revenue initiatives.  Payment related revenue, trust and investment management fees, as well as deposit service charges and investment product fees and commissions declined year-over-year, adversely impacted by the slowing economy and unfavorable equity market conditions.  These revenue categories particularly payments in trust and investment management, however, are positioned to rebound as the economy strengthens and the equity markets stabilize.</p>
          <p>Within non-interest income, other income was lower year-over-year primarily due to an unfavorable variance in equity investment income, which was partially offset by lower end-of-term lease residual losses.  Strong mortgage banking revenue and seasonally higher payments related revenue, trust and investment management fees, deposit service charges, treasury management fees, all contributed to the growth of non-interest income excluding significant items of $180 million on a linked quarter basis.  Additionally the other income category benefited from the lower end-of-term losses on auto leases.  As we indicated in our last call in January, the end-of-term losses on retail auto leases peaked in the third quarter of 2008 at $84 million as the number of cars coming off lease began to decline.  End-of-term losses in the second quarter of 2009 were down to $14 million.</p>
          <p>Finally, excluding the increase in FDIC insurance costs and acquisitions, non-interest expense was essentially flat year-over-year, again demonstrating the company's ability to control expense at a level appropriate for the current operating environment.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call back to Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Andy.  The past few months have been anything but ordinary for our company.  We've been operating in one of the most challenging economic environments in our country's history.  We completed and passed the regulatory stress test.  We raised $2.7 billion of new common equity.  We redeemed $6.6 billion of preferred stock and subsequently completed the repurchase of the related warrant.  Working against this extraordinary event-filled backdrop, our company posted record net revenue, maintained a controlled expense environment, continued to lend and gather deposits, and preserve the strength of our credit ratings and capital base.  As we move forward, we will continue to build our franchise, enhance our products and services, and engage and develop our employees.  In other words, we will capitalize on our now unique position of strength and independence to further differentiate U.S. Bank from its competitors.</p>
          <p>In fact, in early July we launched a nationwide ad campaign to reinforce that message to our current and future customers, as well as all of our financial partners.  We felt this was the opportune time to further build brand awareness for our company and its distinctive position as one of the nation's largest independent financial institutions.  Our focus on revenue generation continues with an emphasis on building deeper relationships with our customers.</p>
          <p>For example, 39 weeks into our relationship review initiative, we've held over 6,700 meetings with clients and have identified almost 9,000 opportunities to increase share of wallet, which translates into potential incremental annual revenue of almost $400 million.  On the revenue side, approximately 10% of our households have now signed up for relationship deepening package of products that provide our customers with the superior value and create more value for our shareholders.  While focusing on these and other new revenue producing initiatives, we remain poised to capture the many opportunities that will present themselves as the financial markets and the worldwide economy recovers.  We expect to continue to be among the best performers in the industry, as our diversified mix of businesses, long standing prudent approach to risks, dedicated employees and the strength of our balance sheet enable us to manage and even prosper in this period of unsurpassed economic stress.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, our second quarter results reaffirm that our fundamental businesses remain strong, although credit costs remain and will remain elevated in the near term.  We are open for business and managing this company for the long term.  As we continue to prudently lend to credit-worthy borrowers, judiciously invest in and grow our franchise, support our communities, serve our customers and importantly create value for our shareholders by sustaining our earnings power, high-quality balance sheet and capital strength.</p>
          <p>That concludes our formal remarks. Andy, Bill Parker and I will now be happy to answer any questions from the audience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Your first question comes from Matthew O'Connor with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The past few quarters, I think you've been a little more explicit in your charge-off guidance and I think this time you're just saying, we'll remain elevated.  Any comments you want to give in terms of what elevated might mean, up another 15-20% flattish?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, I'd be happy to.  As I told you in the quarters before this we were always projecting that we would see pretty much flat results from the prior quarters and then last time when we met 90 days ago we said we'd start to see that coming down.  In other words, the trajectory of the increase would come down.  I would expect that the trajectory you saw coming down in this quarter from prior quarters will continue in that same direction in the future quarter.  In other words, we're starting to see this continued reduction in increase becoming now a more consistent outcome.  So, if you like what you saw between quarters one and two, I think you'll start to see the same kind of a trajectory followed in quarters two to three.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So, charge-off growth to slow, that apply to NPAs as well or a little tougher there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It would do both.  So their both moving in not exact locked step, but they are both moving in directionally the same way. It's a fairly positive outcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I mean just in general, like if we think big picture here, you've managed the risk well on the market disruption the first part of the cycle, consumer credit the second part.  There are some folks out there, including myself, that are pretty concerned on the C&amp;I and the commercial real estate.  I guess two questions: just one, what's your outlook for those loan buckets in general; and then two, has there been a meaningful difference in underwriting at USB versus others the last several years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, I want Bill to answer the specifics, but I'll tell you, I think we're continuing to enjoy the benefits of the many years of not stretching to make loans to C&amp;I and commercial real estate customers.  I think you would agree as it will be told, we were the last large bank into the recession in terms of credit distress and I predict that we'll be the first out, because that longevity of long standing prudence is going to pays us dividends. And so you'll see that we are stressing like everyone else but I think you'll continue to see that our peaks and our values will be muted compared to others.  And Bill, why don't you bring some color around that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, on the C&amp;I portfolios, the mid market and corporate portfolios, the only areas that have been problematic there are the newspapers, media and gaming type industries, where you see higher leverage points.  But we have &#x2013; we did not have &#x2013; do not have a large leverage portfolio.  So, our core middle market and corporate is actually holding up pretty well, they've taken the correct actions to weather the storm.  Small business of course sees some stress in this environment but overall C&amp;I is holding up pretty well.  On commercial real estate, we talked about residential construction for a long time now, almost two years into the &#x2013; what began in California and our outstandings there now 2.7 billion, that's down from over four billion before. So, that is an area that's going to continue to be stressed and we're continuing to work through it.  I think I mentioned last time, it's moved into the Pacific Northwest, where we also have dwindled our exposure.  But the loss is very rare and not as bad as we've seen in California.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then just lastly Richard, if we look at commercial loan demand...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It seems like it's fallen off a cliff, both for you guys, but just the industry in general.  And I guess from a broader point of view is this a positive, because customers are paying down debt or is it a negative because it implies further cuts in output and staff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; let's see, can it be both? Because it feels like both.  I think it's a positive in terms of Bank's balance sheet not taking on customers that will &#x2013; in other words fall into further stress with the kind of duration of this downturn.  In our case, the reason I highlight the majority of our decrease in linked quarter outstandings was the derivative of our open-to-buy commitments was to show that the demand is still there for the right customers, and as you know we're up 12.8% in linked quarter originations.</p>
          <p>But those who have the money have the availability to use their money, have really restructured the way they run their businesses and they're simply not drawing on those open-to-buy loans and lines.  So, I believe that the demand overall for the strongest customers is reflective of what you'd expect at a year and year and half into recession, where they've really permanently reset their capital expenditures, some of their growth objectives and they're not using as much of the bank's balance sheet or their own frankly to grow.  So, I think that's a normal outcome at this point in the cycle.  I think it's good for banks if we continue to be prudent as an industry and not reach to get loan growth by reducing our underwriting, certainly we won't do that at this company.  And as I told you before, because of our strong operating earnings we will compete on price for the AAA customers in order to either keep our own or to go get someone else's and in fact our margin stability in part reflects that we probably could have a little margin increase, but we want to give it back in the form of high quality customer attraction.</p>
          <p>So, I think it's probably both, Matt in terms of the economy.  It's not very good news for the banks. I think those who stay pure to their underwriting, you'll see that demand is the biggest reflection of why loan growth isn't prominent across the industry and I think that's probably a good sign that we're not reaching trying to do something we shouldn't do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ed Najarian with Isi Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Ed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple questions.  First quickly, can you quantify the net gain in the valuation of mortgage servicing rates net of any hedges?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me give you the hedge number, the hedge gain year-over-year, so in the second quarter of 2009 it was a positive $45 million, Ed.  In the first quarter of 2009, it was a positive $2 million and in the second quarter of 2008 it was a negative $25 million.  So, on a year-over-year basis the improvement in the hedge was $70 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but this quarter the number that impacted revenue positively was $45 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct, and then with regard to the remainder of the mortgage improvements, I would say two-thirds of it was rate related and one-third of it was volume related.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.  And then secondarily any comments on early stage delinquencies? t looks like we're seeing a little bit less stability on early stage consumer delinquencies from you guys than maybe we've see at some other banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we did see some improvement, I mean our hard portfolio was down 30 plus.  I'll say 30 plus, was down 43 basis points in the last 90 days.  So, that's good for our outlook on the third quarter.  Autos, our auto portfolios both our leasing and loan portfolio showed a little bit of decline, one to five basis points decline in the 30 to &#x2013; 30 plus so at least that was stable.  Last year, it was still trending up.  And then finally on our small ticket leasing portfolio, their delinquencies came down about 50 basis points so that was positive as well.  So, we have seen a little bit of &#x2013; a little bit of more normal seasonal up-tick or improvement in delinquency patterns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But in terms of mortgage and home equity, I guess it's a bigger portfolio...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a little more mixed; on the late stage on both mortgage and home equity.  We did see improvement, but we did also saw an up-tick in some of the early stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You still feel &#x2013; you're still looking at those numbers and feeling confident that both NPAs and charge-offs can increase at a slower pace, it sounds like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And this is Richard.  If there is anything we've gotten good at it, it's modeling forecasting and testing and stress testing again our own forecast.  And if there is anything that I am comfortable with, it's our ability to predict 30 days for sure and now 90 days with a certain high level of certainty.  There's always a lumpiness where you can have a deal, a large customer come out of nowhere with the surprises.  We're going to leave that on the table as a possibility.  But in terms of the mechanics of the consumer, the home equity to mortgage, those are very much annuities.  You can get a pretty good line of sight now at 90 days.</p>
          <p>Commercial, commercial real estate a little lumpier, but when you know your portfolio like we know ours, we have a high level of confidence in our ability to predict that.  So, when we &#x2013; and I said this to you guys two years ago, we'll always tell you the bad news clearly and honestly and transparently, and when the news starts to get good, I'll hope to see responses that you'll believe us then too.  We're not seeing all green shoots and we're not seeing the end of the road here, but we're starting to see in our portfolio a new repetitive improvement in overall performance of our credit and we're starting to see that as first a decrease in the increase of negativity and over the course of time I think we'll be one of the first to see the top of the hill and get up the other side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.  And then Richard you paid back the TARP, you've strengthened your capital ratios.  Can you give us a sense of your M&amp;A appetite at this point in the cycle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  It's no different, first of all, because of those other activities, those are just nice variables to have behind us. The M&amp;A activity, interest remains the same, Ed. We are, first and foremost interested in payment businesses and corporate trust businesses that will add quickly to the scale and value of those businesses that right now have been impaired by the recession, but will come back with game busters when things get better.</p>
          <p>In terms of acquisitions, we will always be available to the FDIC, a list of opportunities that come along weekly, but we're also going to keep our powder dry for an opportunity that may be of a more significant nature like the down EPS after something like that.  So, I'm not going to do a lot of Bank of Idahos, a lot of the small 5 and 10 branch deals unless they are amazingly opportune. But otherwise we'll stay on the side lines.  We'll watch for a larger FDIC opportunity and in the old fashioned sense of acquisition that continues to be a very slow, quiet process given the new results of the SCAP and everything else.  So, we're probably in the near term going to remain on the sidelines and watch and see sort of good things come along and be able to be opportunistic when and if it happens.  But nothing transformational and nothing outside of the balance that we've been talking for the last couple years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Betsy Graseck with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of other questions on the early stage delinquencies.  You indicated that those have been improving in a couple of different asset classes.  And I guess, I'm wondering where you fall out with regard to the debate on why they are coming down? Some folks are kind of suggesting it's still seasonality, others saying it's just slowdown in unemployment rate, growth rate or the jobless claims.  And then another angle is it's management doing about a bit of job managing or having an impact on managing these early stage delinquencies.  When you look at your portfolio, what are the drivers there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'd have to say after seeing fourth quarter and first quarter going through very rapid deterioration in the number of portfolios, part of it is that we've completely upped our protocols in the collection areas and that does make a difference.  But also, I think it's more of a return just to some normal seasonal patterns, which were not here before while the economy was deteriorating rapidly.  So, we expect that as the unemployment continues to rise, card losses will over time go up again, but third quarter is normally a decent quarter for card losses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Betsy, for your benefit, we have an unemployment expectation of slightly over 10% by year end, with a continued increase in 2010.  So, we're not sitting here thinking, I don't think outside of the bounds of what others are expecting.  And as you all know, a few basis points in increase in unemployment it's like the Richter scale, it's not linear, so it's a big deal.  And we appreciate how to stress that to our portfolios.  But for the most part, our unsecured portfolios are prime only and our collateral portfolios are well written to low home to value.  So, whether it's a impairment in the beginning or an absolute loss, I think we're going to fair quite well.</p>
          <p>On the housing side, we're also expecting an additional 5 to 10% drop in housing values, which at the end of this process would be a peak to trough of around 40% fall and our expectations are so far aligned with that.  The mix of business we have across are primarily 24 states would reflect that that's not going to be above the average for the national, but probably near or at about that same level.  So, I think we're in the range of expectations that some of the economists would predict as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then on deposits and deposit growth, did a great job with core deposits this quarter.  I'm sure that this is in part the reflection of the efforts you've had with your brand strategies.  But could you speak to where you think the jumbo CDs are relative to last quarter, I mean obviously they're down a lot, but is that kind of an exiting of low risk strategy or did you price to get those folks out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Betsy, this is Andy.  Our pricing strategy on the retail side is to focus on core checking and savings accounts and that's where we are certainly more &#x2013; a bit more aggressive, not at the top of the peer group, but in the middle of the peer group.  So, that's been our focus in growing core accounts and we've been very successful with regard to that.  On the wholesale side we have had some volatility up and down, that's more a function of liquidity on the wholesale customers, but I would say overall both in terms of wholesale and retail we've had strong deposit growth and I think it's a function of the flight to quality and the reputation of our company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Betsy this is Richard, because I know you've followed us for a long time, one of the advantages that this downturn created for U.S. Bank was our chance to get back into the competitive game for pricing on core deposits and as you know we were probably at the bottom decile two years ago.  We're now very competitive, but just because we were competitive for core, I want you to know we still don't attract hot money, we just don't &#x2013; we don't like it, we don't &#x2013; we don't know what to do with it. It's not consistent and repeatable.  And so you just won't see us using our margin to go out and attract on the rate, on any basis where customers don't bring the rest of the relationship.  So, we stay true to that, but we've been fortune enough to be able to keep this strong margin at the same time redefine ourselves as a competitive deposit pricer from core deposits. And that's helped as well as the flight to quality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Super. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from David Rochester with FBR Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning guys.  It sounds like your economic expectations may be a little bit weaker than they were in the last call, at lease in terms of what's you're looking for from the unemployment rate perspective.  But you're still looking for a deceleration in the growth in NPAs and charge-offs. Would you say that that's largely predicated on what you're seeing on the early stage delinquency side, because you are seeing that the dip there you're thinking that the rate of growth should slow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's partly that. I'll let Bill answer that technically. It's partly that. We don't spend &#x2013; it's not all modeling. I mean a lot of it has to do with we know our customers, we know them very well.  And as I &#x2013; charge-offs, let's go back. NPAs are usually a proxy for future charge-offs, right?  And there are a lot of regulatory review and has a lot to do with capital allocation and those were all what we all know them to be.  But we really want to know at the end of the day, which of those NPAs would be a proxy for a charge-off and which unsecured loans from an early consumer will actually go to charge-off.</p>
          <p>And that has a lot to do with delinquencies and first and late stage. But it has a lot to do with just knowing the quality of your portfolio.  And we've got a real good sense, a very high sensitivity to who we have lent our money to, and how we have done it.  And I'd say that it's a blend between the statistics, David and what we know about our company.  And it'd be very easy for me to take a very safe road and tell you that it's going to be another many, many quarters of the same 25, 30% increase in both NPAs and charge-offs.  We just don't see that.  So, we're going to say what we see and we could be surprised like anyone else. But our facts set which has served us very well, I don't think we've been wrong on any of our 90 days projections in a full cycle are based on a lot of data a lot more than just unemployment, housing and delinquencies, but Bill that's kind of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the other thing I'd mention is that we're essentially prime based lenders and the early part of this economic downturn was really more market disruption, capital market disruption, unique events.  Now, we're entering a phase that looks more like just kind of a normal recession, not that it's not severe, but that has less of a dramatic impact than some of those things that occurred earlier on in this downturn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for that, I appreciate that.  One, last one, have you noticed any change at all, potentially improvements in the re-default rates that you're seeing in your restructure portfolio and have you seen any meaningful contributions or more notable, I should say, contributions growth in this bucket in the C&amp;I or CRE products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll do the residential mortgages one first because I'm guessing that's what you're asking about. Our re-default rates there, we do modifications, of course, for all our mortgage portfolios, first mortgage portfolios. And we have a measure of 60-day default rates and right now that's at about 22% and we also measure it based on who re-entered or who enters foreclosure, and that's at about 12%.  We take steps to improve that all the time, we increased significantly the number of mods that we do where the payment actually decreases.  We've doubled the percentage there up to about two out of three of them now where the payment decreases.  So, that should make the future performance even better.  And additionally we're entering into the HAMP program this quarter.  That's the administration's new program.  So, that should help too.  On the commercial or commercial real estate side we don't have a lot of TDRs there.  Generally, we'll try to work with the borrowers, try to go NPA, if it's a real estate deal we'll just charge it down to rate value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John McDonald with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.  I was wondering if you had an outlook on net interest income growth that seems that with the margin flat and loan demand being real tepid it's going to be hard to grow net interest income at least in the near-term, do you have some views there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I would say John is that we do expect relatively stable margin.  On the earning asset front I am going to separate wholesale from retail a little bit.  The retail side we would expect sort of flattish to some moderate growth which is what you saw in this quarter.  On the wholesale side a lot depends upon the utilization that we talked about.  We're booking new loans, we're gaining new customers.  The offset is what the utilization will do and I would expect that to be sort of flat to down.  So, those two things may offset and the bottom line from all that is maybe flattish net interest income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, how about on the securities portfolio, Andy? I guess you assume that will be pretty flattish?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would not expect major changes there but you see &#x2013; what you've seen in the last few quarters what you should expect in the next few quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You guys are pretty specific about the credit outlook.  How about our reserve build for the last couple of quarters, you were kind of building at 50 to 100% charge-offs and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dipped a little bit below that this quarter.  What kind of outlook would you have there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well 50 is in our history, so and we've had 50, 60, 70, 75 and 100 I just like round numbers that are divisible by something.  50 is on the low end of that six quarter range but it's still in it, I think we're supposed to be right at 50 today.  So, we're trying to telegraph that we're at the low end of the six quarter trailing circumstances.  And I guess what I think John is if we start to see a continuation of the kind of trends we saw this quarter and that continues to bear out as I said in my comments, it needs to be sustained and convincing.  Then we'll start to move that 50% down to 40 or 30 or 25 or eventually we'll get down to very close to where we're only I think reserve build for the growth that we expect in the portfolio, which would be very nominal. But I am going to be careful, I want us to have all the reserves built possible so that when the recovery is among us we don't have to take any of the earnings away from that recovery in order to continue to backfill out of reserves.  And we started this cycle as one of the strongest balance sheets.  I promised you every quarter we're going to end it.  So, you'll see us be generous on provisions, but we will also telegraph our views of the future by the way we start to move that down when it finally starts to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if the credit outlook plays out as you expect with the growth rate moderating in both NPAs and charge-offs, we should see that reserve build magnitude start to at least stay at the 50 and maybe go down from 50?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it has a positive bias to getting smaller, and we didn't talk about, it has a lot to do with, if you like where you are at the moment in time...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you like a coverage and we do like our coverage ratios. I must say we are adequately reserved; that's the appropriate way to define it. But I like the way we were &#x2013; we are satisfactorily adequate and so I think we're at a place we like and so if that's the only variable and that starts to become loan forecasting, loan loss forecasting and NPAs and those become favorably biased and I think so too will the reserve build.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, particularly if the loan book is not growing, all that much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, although we want it to grow, I mean I am hoping those commitments just the recoveries. Best thing about open to buy commitments, notice we're 35%. That's &#x2013; that will get better and our high quality customers decide to start drawing on their lines right away that &#x2013; that's the easiest, that's loan growth you are going to get because I know what the quality of our portfolio, we'll take that all day long.  So, I think you will see a growing balance sheet as well, but I think you will see that at the prime level that we've had in past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then last thing is with TARP repaid there is still some uncertainty I guess about maybe new regulatory regimes, but what kind of capital ratios will you guys manage to and which metrics can we look for you to manage too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all we have two principle targets that we've talked about John.  Number one is the Tier 1 capital level. As you know historically we've been targeting an 8.5%.  We raised capital actually to get above nine given the current environment I would expect us to continue to be above nine.  And then about two-thirds of that or just over two-thirds being Tier 1 common.  So the ratios that you see now would be consistent with what we would manage to in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You like that two-thirds of total Tier 1 being common is that a good approx, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do, at least two-thirds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>At least.  Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Nancy Bush with NAB Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Nancy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question for the future assuming there is going to be one.  Could you sort of clarify what the regulatory input is that you're getting on reserves when we come to the end of this credit cycle?  In other words, are you going to be able to draw down reserves as we did in past cycles or are the regulators going to expect reserve levels to stay high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nancy, Richard.  We've had no guidance on that.  I'm happy to report because we've had no reason to have conversation in any of the last two years on any quarter with our selection of both reserve builds and our adequate coverage.  So, we don't have the dialog even to reflect back on what kind of guidance they're giving.  But I will tell you from my perspective and what I know and what I'm affected by, I think that we all agree that the capital ratios will be higher in a pro-cyclical world than they were going into it.</p>
          <p>And I think we're all going to be required to keep both capital , I'm sorry, and loan loss reserves at a higher level.  I also think that in the future when I talk to you about loan growth being 10% forecasted growth that we're going to have to apply a 110% loan loss reserve built all things being equal so that we're starting to build for our future book.  I have no conversations though to record with anybody here on any guidance whatsoever.  I just think the prevailing wind is that on pro-cyclical basis all of us at banks will have higher capital requirements, higher loan loss requirements and we will be paying insurance premiums for many years forward, all of which were at lower levels or non-existent going into this cycle.  So, that's all I know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, your view is that the emphasis on the regulatory basis will swing from this anti-cyclical to a pro-cyclical emphasis going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's the pro-cyclical that's kind of a funny definition, but I do think that &#x2013; I think what you meant is that there will be if I can say vis-&#xE0;-vis the old SunTrust argument that they had too much.  I think there will still be a tight balance where we can have the appropriate level, but I don't think anyone is going to argue that more is worse than less.  But it's going to be important that we don't build reserves to use for future earnings, because that's just bad business and it doesn't give you, or our shareholders, a clear line of sight on real earnings.  So, I think there'll be a lot more guidance coming out as it becomes clear the recovery's ending and the banks will no longer look on linked quarter, they will just say, are you at the right place? And we will probably get that definition, I'm going to guess, in a couple of quarters, but we haven't seen it yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And just on the capital front.  Richard can you just give your philosophy about rebuilding the dividend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Wow it took six people to get to the dividend.  The philosophy hasn't changed here first of all.  And so I can give you everything about the math, but we said for a long time that will give a high percentage of our earnings back to the shareholders in form of dividend and stock buybacks.  As much as we all forgot stock buyback, it's still a reasonable approach to use.  I think it will come back one day as one of the options.  So, if U.S. Bank gave a majority of its earnings to the shareholders in those two methods, and I believe that both methods will be used in the future by our company, then the dividend will be something a percentage of a large amount of our earnings will go to the dividend but it will be a line of sight that I have to have and the Board has to have as we look into next year as we begin to evaluate our first dividend increase.</p>
          <p>And once we get into the latter part of this year, we'll have a good idea of 2010. It's my commitment for all of the reasons you would expect to give the dividend and increase at a level that's both sustainable; one that we can grow from, one that is predicted on the basis of future earnings and that's meaningful.  But I will hold back some for potential stock buybacks to benefit the shareholders in that way and we'll keep a little for ourselves to continue to invest in the future.  But, Nancy, you've known us for a longtime, our percentage of high value to shareholders through those two forms has not changed and it's just a matter of now getting my head around what those numbers will be and giving a high percentage of it back to the shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mike Mayo with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you're pursing some national advertising and I just, my first thought is that you must be doing a big deal out of market.  So, that's &#x2013; maybe I'm too skeptical there.  I mean you are gaining some share within your market, so why national advertising and how much might that cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, so the national advertising is intended to be a certainly all end market too, but we're a 24 state franchise and the other 26 we don't usually get a lot of visibility for.  This follows perfectly on our new found growth of the corporate bank, moving it from a regional corporate bank to a high quality national corporate bank.  As you know we have offices now in both New York and Charlotte and we've enhanced our team by more than 100 senior lenders and capital market people in these markets.  And so number one Mike you know the story from a couple of years ago, but our newest results on Fortune 500 companies is 467 of them do business with us.  But only a mere 132 do corporate banking with us. The others do corporate trust and/or corporate payment, all very good but we are a national bank and we should have the national corporate capability.  And so we are talking to the litany of high quality customers both private and public that are starting to know us by our quality, knowing our brand a bit.  If they don't know us, it's at least a neutral equity and now we want to build positive equity.  So, the campaign is slightly more than $10 million.  It will run the majority of quarter three and a little into quarter four. It will be TV and it will be print, and it will be equally in-market and out of market identifying primarily the attraction of C-Suite leaders outside of market and small businesses and consumers end markets.  So, it's got a nice kind of bifurcated view and it's all about strength, stability and being an honest partner with people who need a good partner in times like this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you touched on this before in terms of larger out of market acquisitions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Seems like you're a little more open to that and is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I didn't mean to say that so I'm glad you clarified.  Out of market acquisitions are going to be &#x2013; first and foremost, cost to this company on two bases.  One is we've got so much momentum going in our organic initiatives, many of which you also haven't seen yet, that the cost of us doing a deal in or out of market, that's substantial, will put again stress against that momentum and I'm willing to take it if its right, but I'm not looking for it.  Out of market additionally has a cultural risk.  At least when you're doing an in-market deal you have the ability to introduce your culture and confirm that it remains. And we have a culture now that I really like and I don't want it to get diluted.  To do an out of market would cause us to put a lot of people out of the current market to get into those new markets and create a culture.</p>
          <p>I wouldn't be unwilling to do it, but it would have to be a remarkably great deal to pursue and at this point in time we don't see anything like that.  So, I didn't mean to indicate out of market is of higher interest than in market.  There just aren't a lot of opportunities and I just want to let you all know if a great deal comes along, we'll look at anything, but we won't do anything outside of our very prudent approach we've used in the past.  But if in a couple of years, nothing big has come along and we haven't done a big deal, I hope you're not disappointed, because I like who we are.  We're very relevant and we're very good at what we do and acquisitions is not a course this company has to take unless the opportunity presents itself at which point we'll evaluate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, last question.  In terms of delinquencies as a good predictor for loan problems and maybe I am haunted, I think it was 2001 Labor Day or the day after that when you had your investor conference and that's before you were CEO, you had a different Chief Credit Officer.  But it was six weeks or so after that conference when you had the big credit quality surprise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just through your experience of a couple of decades of doing this how good of a predictor are delinquencies on future NPAs.  Are there times when it hasn't worked so well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mixed a couple of things there, but first of all in dog years 2001 you are right is five generations ago.  So, I'm going to tell you that this company and this team is much more able to forecast and we simply would not make that mistake; I guarantee you that.  In terms of predictability, I think delinquencies have always been the best predictor of most likely loss affects from consumers and from the small business portfolio because it's the annuity aspect of it, you just doesn't change that fast. It's not at all a good predictor of course in NPAs as a predictor of loss in the commercial and commercial real estate.  So, I would say it hasn't changed seven years later, it's still the best predictor, but this company has changed.  We know how to do that better, we do have a different team here, our focus and Bill mentioned it earlier has been to bring on as much competence on the defense of knowing what's going on in our credit and quality as it was an offense before.  I just think that this is a good time for you to have trust in our ability to predict and that last bygone of 2001 is just that.  And Bill do you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I just, second that I think the delinquencies are, delinquencies plus bankruptcy trends are a very good indicator at least for the next 90, 120 days on mostly consumer and the small business and again on the wholesale side it's not necessarily good predictor at all. You have to look at other factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if there is one factor that makes you feel better on the wholesale side or maybe it's just the offset to the two because aren't we in the &#x2013; it's kind of getting going on the commercial real estate side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there is still plenty of stress on our residential construction portfolio. Like I said, our stress there has moved into our portfolio in the Pacific Northwest, that's about a $700 million portfolio.  So, we &#x2013; yeah, we still see stress.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think, Mike, two things.  One would be the mix of our business that's unsecured versus secured and that which is secured was underwritten at a fairly conservative level that we can even sell to spend for the majority of this downturn and predicted downturn.  So, risk to loss continues to be less than perhaps likelihood of NPA in both the mix of our portfolio and the quality of those that were underwritten.  But, we will definitely see the continued stress.  We're not immune to it at all, which is why we're not saying losses or NPAs will go down in the quarter, we just continue to think they'll go up by less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Mike &#x2013; Michael, thank you very much.  Judy, the official close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>The official close.  Thank you for listening to our review of second quarter results.  If you do have any questions, please feel free to give me a call at 612-303-0783.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you ladies and gentlemen.  This will conclude today's conference call.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>