<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1511980" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2481</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Luciano Pires Siani</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America">Felipe Hirai</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Banco JPMorgan SA">Rodolfo de Angele</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Officer of Base Metals and IT">Gerd Peter Poppinga</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Officer of Ferrous and Strategy">Jos&#xE9; Carlos Martins</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Corretora de Valores SA">Rodrigo Barros</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Alexander Hacking</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Carlos F. De Alba</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="TIAA-CREF">Chelsea Konsko</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Brasil) SA CTVM">Marina Melemendjian</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Jonathan L. Brandt</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to Vale's Conference Call to discuss the Third Quarter 2012 Results. If you do not have a copy of the relevant press release, it is available at the company's website at www.vale.com at the Investors link. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>As a reminder, this conference is being recorded. To access the replay, please dial 5511-4688-6312, access code 6213907 hash key. The file will also be available at the company's website at www.vale.com at the Investor section. This conference call and the slide presentation are being transmitted via Internet as well. You can access the webcast by logging onto the company's website, at www.vale.com, Investor section, or at the www.prnewswire.com.br.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Actual performance could differ materially from that anticipated in any forward-looking comments as a result of macro economic conditions, market risks and other factors.</p>
          <p>With us today are Mr. Luciano Siani, Executive Officer of Finance and Investor Relations, CFO; Mr. Jos&#xE9; Carlos Martins, Executive Officer of Ferrous and Strategy; Mr. Galib Chaim, Executive Officer of Capital Projects Execution' and Mr. Peter Poppinga Executive Director of Base Metals and Information Technology. First, Mr. Luciano Siani will proceed with the presentation, and after that, we will open for questions-and-answers.</p>
          <p>It's now my pleasure to turn the call over to Mr. Luciano Siani. Please sir, you may now begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First of all, Mr. Murilo Ferreira apologizes just for not being here. He had an emergency; he could not attend. Thank you all for attending. We have the presentation that was put on our website. It has three parts. I am not going to follow it on a slide-by-slide basis I'm just going to remark some of the information which is in there. It starts with an overview of the approach that we're having to strategy and to how &#x2013; and capital discipline. Then we will go into the details of the performance of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In the end of the presentation you see also a few figures on China, which is our main market, which displayed additional data points and information for yourselves to make up your own opinions about how this important market will develop go forward. But certainly we will have the opportunity to talk more about this during the Q&amp;A and the news session here.</p>
          <p>Well, the very first thing that I would like to start as to re-emphasize that we will prioritize only investments in world-class assets going forward, which can provide the best return to shareholders. This is very important at a moment where we face the challenge of matching our cash flows to our investment program. So in that respect, we're not pursuing diversification per se anymore. Diversification will be a consequence of us having world-class assets in different commodities, but it's not a goal pre se.</p>
          <p>Having this goal while also operating and developing many world-class assets means that we are going to reassess very carefully all of our assets which do not fit that characteristic. And we would like to reemphasize our commitment to returning cash to shareholders and maintaining our investment grade and a prudent leverage in our balance sheet. So for us going forward, the most significant challenge is to how to solve the three dilemmas: adapting cash flows, the dividend policy, investments and balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Another important outcome of this strategy also is that we will reduce R&amp;D expenditures. The need to reduce the investment program means that we now have model of options that &#x2013; what we need for the coming years. So that it doesn't make sense to keep generating additional work options so there is an immediate consequence, which is reduction of R&amp;D expenditures.</p>
          <p>You should also bear in mind that CapEx will peak in 2012. It's not going to be as high as what we announced in 2011 when we made that plan. So making our effort to have a lower number, you can see by the accumulated figures for the first nine months of 2012. And certainly in 2013, our goal is still to have even a lower number still significant because we do have important growth options, but still a lower number than the trend for 2012.</p>
          <p>Another important message is that in our core business, which is where the most important world-class assets are located, which is iron ore, we do believe that we are at a turning point; reason being because now we have all the conditions to resume growth in our iron ore business. We are having a very good performance in environmental permitting this year. We have had already 72 licenses granted by the authorities against a little over 20 last year. That means that we're being able to open new pits. We're going to be able to develop our world-class projects and over time we will not only increase volume, but also recover the quality that has always characterized Vale iron ore.</p>
          <p>So in that respect, S11D is our priority and also the &#x2013; it characterize projects in the Southern/Southeastern System, which are described in the press release, which have two-fold objective of not only replacing and marginally expanding capacity at the Southern/Southeastern System, but also recovering quality. So these are &#x2013; together with the Plus 40 and Serra Leste are the cornerstones of our growth in iron ore going forward.</p>
          <p>So you should start to seek growth in the production rates in the second semester of 2013 and more explicitly in 2014. And then going forward with S11D coming on-stream in 2016 and on you should see important growth.</p>
          <p>So iron ore remains our key priority. Obviously, we need to also to finish the projects which are ongoing: Salobo, Long Harbour and so on. So this puts pressure in our CapEx over the shorter-term as well. And outside of iron ore, we do have also world-class assets to keep investing on, which I would highlight the Moatize coal mine.</p>
          <p>Important to notice as well that in the shorter-term the fact that we have been granted the license to open the N5 South mine in Caraj&#xE1;s is a short-term catalyst for recovery of quality and production, especially in the Caraj&#xE1;s region. You saw that in our production report released a few days ago that there was a drop in the Northern System production of 4%, when you compare it to the first nine months of 2011, which is pretty much related to the environmental permit process. But as I mentioned, we've been working together with the authorities. We have improved our internal processes. We've been granted more licenses. So it's just a matter of time to get back the flexibility that we didn't have at the &#x2013; in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>When you look outside of iron ore, our approach of iron ore is very vigorous, as I've mentioned, specifically in base metals, which has been a source of concern for a few investors. We believe that we have a few good news to tell you; the one being the successful ramp up of Salobo. We're already running at 40% of production capacity. So you're already starting to see some copper production in the production reports under the Others account. Gold production increasing, Salobo I and II is capable of producing over 300,000 ounces of gold, so it's very, very attractive at the current gold prices. So you should see normal ramp-ups and Salobo adding results to today's metals.</p>
          <p>Also New Caledonia where &#x2013; have resumed operations with all the circuits, so we intend to keep you posted once we have more clear signs that we're being able to resume ramp up in Vale New Caledonia as well, but you should bear in mind that we already have resumed production in the plants.</p>
          <p>We are committed to generating value across the nickel business. It is the core business. We have announced recently the shutdown of two mines for care and maintenance. The two mines are mines which are not adding value at current prices, much on the contrary, they were losing money. This is a different approach as well.</p>
          <p>In the past, as we privileged volumes over value, we didn't do this sort of detail analysis to try to understand what specific assets are contributing to value for shareholders, but now we're committed to not to operate those assets, which are not value adding.</p>
          <p>Important to notice that even if we shutdown some mines in Canada, it doesn't mean that nickel production will diminish because expected growth in Indonesia, which is going quite well. So we will feed these processing plants in Canada with material mines from Indonesia; that's the strategy going forward. So you will see quite an improvement in the nickel business, without loss in production.</p>
          <p>And finally, we will divest and no value-adding assets of this business.</p>
          <p>Well, now going &#x2013; another key message that I would like to leave with you is that as an important lever to adjust the size of the capital expenditure program going forward is partnerships. So Vale now is very keen and we're actively looking forward to partners for our most important projects, so we would rather develop an opportunity in partnership if we have cash constraints, so with lower exposure, cash exposure to the opportunity, rather than not doing it. So our first preferred option is to try to find partners to develop some of the opportunities and this is something that I would like to leave with you because you might have news in the coming months. On Vale Day we will present more details on those partnerships.</p>
          <p>So when you go to the actual results on the third quarter, I'm going to start first by talking about giving additional highlights on production, then talking about prices, then going down the income statement. I'm going to talk a little bit about costs, expenditures and talk about the net income, as well the tax impact on the net income. Then I'm going to briefly talk about our balance sheet and then we'll move on to Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>In terms of production, I already mentioned that we had a fall in production in iron ore in the third quarter 2012, compared to 2011. However, one thing that I would like to point out is because we now we have an extended enterprise strategy, and we have our own fleet of vessels, and we have &#x2013; we do have iron ore inventories, even positioned throughout our inventories across the supply chain, which means that if you lose production in one quarter that doesn't mean you're going to lose sales. So we have now buffers of flexibility to cope with those variations, which means that we're confident of recovering the production loss and with no impact in sales, as you saw.</p>
          <p>In terms of the pellet plants, we also have halted production at three pellet plants. These are plants which were less competitive than the new ones. So, again, the value equation comes in. Obviously, we are reacting to the market conditions, whereby the quality that is embedded in the project such as pellets is not being rewarded as it should, we are changing. So we do have the option of changing it from producing pellets to producing sinter and pellet feed so we're opting to the alternative that brings more value to shareholders.</p>
          <p>Just for our guidance as well, when you look at the realized prices &#x2013; when you compare the realized prices of pellets with the realized prices of iron ore, you see a very large premium when you look at the numbers. However, the iron ore prices are much influenced by the spot market and the &#x2013; whereas the pellet prices, our pellets are mostly sold through contracts, so they still reflect the lagged pricing formula, which carries the higher prices from the previous quarters. So that's one reason because, again, behind us this large difference, so where on the margin &#x2013; marginally speaking, we're closely following the pellet premium and the cost of transformation to assess all the time the advantages and the disadvantage of selling pellets in the market.</p>
          <p>In terms of coal, we have had the &#x2013; we resume production at Carborough Downs after the shutdown, which is good news. Our mines in Australia are finally running at very good rates, all of them, so we should see improvements in production in Australia.</p>
          <p>In Mozambique, as you saw, the production this quarter was smaller than the quarter before. The reason, not being any problems with the ramp-up of the mine, but rather some bottlenecks in the logistics. And we're not stocking coal because coal is not a product that you should stock with an inventory because it degrades its quality. So we're slowing down production within the mine, but we expect to de-bottleneck the railway to the Beira corridor and resume ramping up. There's not any &#x2013; ramp-up in the mine and the processing plant in Mozambique is going very well.</p>
          <p>In terms of nickel, the production if you look at the nine months has been affected by the safety shutdown on the second quarter in February, when we had &#x2013; we lost a few lives, unfortunately, and we decided to do that shutdown and also reassess all our plants. But this year &#x2013; I'm sorry, this quarter the decrease in production in Ontario relates more to the plant maintenance shutdown than to any further problems, so we should see again February production &#x2013; Ontario production resuming.</p>
          <p>In copper, I already mentioned the successful ramp-up of Salobo and to point out as well that now we had the first concentrate being produced at our Lubambe mine at the JV in Zambia, which is also marginally a credit on the medium-term.</p>
          <p>And also in fertilizers, we had record production of phosphate rock, mainly from our Bay&#xF3;var mine in Peru, which is doing very well.</p>
          <p>Talking about prices, as you saw, the fall in iron ore yield at 62% prices has not reflected fully into the fall of value realized prices. There's a number of reasons for that. I am certain that we will explore this in the Q&amp;A session, but in a nutshell there were market factors for sure, but there were also the effect of successful commercial strategies that we have implemented in order to deal with the &#x2013; an environment where clients they &#x2013; we have more spot sales and clients they value also the lead times of delivery for our products.</p>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; another highlight in terms of prices is, I would say the, the fertilizer prices they moved on a different direction than other resource prices, which shows up the nature &#x2013; the countercyclical nature of this business. And we have adapted our product mix in order to make the most of these opportunities in specific products as well.</p>
          <p>So when you see how this has translated in a loss of revenue, these overall falling prices, mitigate by successful commercial strategy, has yielded falling revenues of about $1.2 billion in the quarter, which translated directly into the bottom line and into EBITDA. Reason being because the expense accounts were pretty much stable during the quarter, so we're talking about operational costs, we're talking about SG&amp;A and R&amp;D expenses.</p>
          <p>When you look at cost of good sold there are numbers of analyses in the press release which show small items going up and down, but I would say the outlook is pretty much of stability, which is &#x2013; I believe it's good news in this inflationary environment. And then we should start &#x2013; we hope to over the next few months to see if we can reverse this trajectory, not only stabilize costs but also make them to go down. There are number of initiatives to do that.</p>
          <p>However, I can point out to you that for other accounts I believe &#x2013; we believe that the &#x2013; we can bet more confidently in a downward trend path. The first one being R&amp;D expenditures. If you compare R&amp;D expenditures of the third quarter against the second quarter they are stable, but if you compare to the third quarter of 2011 there's a significant decrease.</p>
          <p>The third and fourth quarters are traditionally within Vale, quarters where you spend more in R&amp;D and in sustaining investments, and in capital projects. So that stability is already a first sign of we're containing that. There are a number of initiatives in place. I could mention for instance the closure of several exploration offices around the world, which we assess those. And we should seek reduction of R&amp;D expenditures like numerical, absolute term reduction of R&amp;D expenditures going forward.</p>
          <p>The same would apply to SG&amp;A, which is stable in this quarter but we are also confident that they will resume a downward trajectory quite soon.</p>
          <p>So that leads us to an EBITDA of $3.7 billion in the quarter, which is impacted by a provision for a tax dispute, the so-called CFEM, the royalties within Brazil. We made that provision I believe a month ago maybe; it was communicated to the market, I think it was in August and that reflects are assessment of the likelihood of our payments going forward.</p>
          <p>Also, we are also provisioning announced for the state mining taxes, which had developments recently, so we're talking about the State of Par&#xE1; and the State of Minas Gerais. The State of Par&#xE1; issued a degree with the reduction of the state taxes. The State of Minas Gerais approved yesterday &#x2013; the legislative chamber approved yesterday of the possibility that the state government also may make some adjustments.</p>
          <p>So these are developments that certainly are in connection with the comprehensive conversation that we are entertaining with the government of Par&#xE1; and Minas Gerais, with the goal of cleaning up all the tax issues, both past, present and going forward of all our operations within those two states. So it's a comprehensive effort. It's being done in partnership with the authorities, with mutual understanding from side-by-side, and it's being successful. We are waiting for the formal proceedings and documents that will confirm our understandings. And once they happen we can even make a specific conference about those issues. But I believe that the recent developments show that these issues are being well addressed.</p>
          <p>In the State of Par&#xE1; for instance the amount of the state tax has been reduced by two-thirds. So going forward, the provisions and/or payments should be only a third of what has been provisioned for this quarter, for the State of Par&#xE1;, which is the highest figure of the $145 million, it responds to around $100 million. So when you &#x2013; once you take that all into account, so adjusted EBITDA was $3.7 billion. If you compare adjusted EBITDA this quarter with the previous quarter, as I said, the difference is $1.2 billion, which is basically the loss in revenue. And net income you could see how the various other accounts lead to a net income of $1.7 billion approximately.</p>
          <p>Now taking about the balance sheet I would &#x2013; we would like to call your attention to Page 18 on the presentation and that's the only page I will highlight, which for those who don't have the presentation I will describe it. It shows how we generated cash in the first nine months of 2012 and how we used that cash.</p>
          <p>And the main message here is that we have, yes, adapted out investment program to our cash inflows. So you can see that the net debt increase in the period was only $1 billion. So the operational cash flows plus the divestitures that we had, net divestitures because we had some small acquisitions as well, was pretty much enough to, not only to pay for the investment program, but also to return capital to shareholders.</p>
          <p>So that's the type of matching that we are targeting going forward. So in the past we have talked about a moderate use of the balance sheet and that's what we call moderate, you see $1 billion net debt increase in the past nine months, so that's something that we're very keen, as I've mentioned, to keep our investment grade and to keep our rating as it is. So we're going manage very prudently that equation going forward.</p>
          <p>Well, having said that, we will open microphone for questions and answers and me and my colleagues we're here to address those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now being the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Mr. Felipe Hirai from Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, good afternoon, everyone, I have two questions. The first one is related to the potential divestment of the assets that you mentioned that you could sell if they are not adding any value. I'd just like to understand when would you make these decisions, so if there is any kind of a deadline for these assets to become profitable or not?</p>
          <p>And my second question is related actually to the potential impairment of assets that we still haven't seen any significant impairments on some of your like non-performing assets. So could we see that happening through the end of this year? And if could you give us some idea of which assets we should think of these impairments? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the first question of sale of assets, I would say that we have a clear idea of what assets we want to divest or look for partners. Now we are in a question of these are transactions that, as you know, they require time to be developed and they have the normal course of business. So &#x2013; but in terms of a decision, we already made those.</p>
          <p>One exception that you might be having in mind is New Caledonia, which, as I mentioned, we are resuming ramp-up successfully so we're still not in a position to make any decision about that asset. We need to wait for the next developments and we're probably going to make that decision by the end of first quarter or beginning of second quarter of 2013, with respect to New Caledonia.</p>
          <p>On the other fronts I think the decisions have been made, but we're not &#x2013; we're still, I would say, exploring the market to see what's the possibly to realize value on this sale as well. We're not going fire sale any assets; we know what their value are. So it's a question of I believe we have many possibilities but we will manage those very carefully.</p>
          <p>In terms of impairments, as we pointed out in the press release, we will do an impairment in the On&#xE7;a Puma asset this quarter. It will not wait for the closure of the fourth quarter and the two year financial statement, so we will announce it in interim basis. We already have a revised business case for On&#xE7;a Puma and we are waiting to just to confirm our expectations on the values to be received from the insurance providers, in order to have the final numbers. And as soon as we have them, we will announce the impairment numbers.</p>
          <p>But it's very likely that the revised asset value will be below $1 billion, so anything above that will need to be written off. The other impairments, we are having a comprehensive assessment of the assets, which perhaps are less likely to return the full book value, but in that respect we will probably have an assessment of all those assets and the impairments, if any, made at the moment of the insurance of the full year financial statements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Rodolfo De Angele from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you. I just wanted to get back on the pricing discussion and ask, looking forward, there were, as you mentioned on the call, there were a few issues that caused the company to post a better realized price than I think your investors were expecting; some of them were related to commercial strategy of Vale.</p>
          <p>We discussed on the previous calls, specifically, freight and others such as the level of impurities. Should we expect those to continue in place? Should we work with improved realize prices the next quarters? My second question is on projects so I just wanted to hear from management an update on Simandou and On&#xE7;a Puma, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I will start by the projects, I will address Simandou then we'll lead to my colleague Peter Poppinga to talk about On&#xE7;a Puma, and then we're going to go back to Mr. Martins for the realized price. So on Simandou, it is an important growth option for the company. As you know, our priority right now is S11D so the resources of the company will be concentrated in S11D, rather than Simandou. However, we are waiting for the regulatory landscape in Guinea to become clearer, and that includes the logistic solution. It may change, according to the government it may change from what has been agreed like two years ago, so that change if that happens &#x2013; it's likely to happen, it will entail additional studies, engineering studies in order to see the value of the new revised project.</p>
          <p>The stake that the government of Guinea wants to have in the project is also undefined, and the royalty. So there's enough uncertainty I would say in the regulatory environment in Guinea that prevents us to making any advancement at this stage and these are pre-conditions for us to make any more firm decision on the asset. Our expectation is that the time required for these solutions to be reached plus the time required for us to develop the studies for the project will pretty much match the ongoing strategy of the company.</p>
          <p>So we will concentrate first on S11D on the current iron ore assets that we have in Brazil, and then only if all these assets are resolved, so Simandou will be a growth option for the upcoming future.</p>
          <p>With regards to On&#xE7;a Puma, I would like to ask my colleague Mr. Peter Poppinga to address the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Rodolfo, thank you for your question. The answer is pretty straightforward. The furnace problem at On&#xE7;a Puma turned out to be more serious than we have anticipated and we have had significant refractory damage due to some design flaws related to the refractory quality and this led to some refractory hydration in certain layers. And so the furnace must be rebuilt and we are anticipating that production will occur only towards middle of next year. That's the reality of On&#xE7;a Puma. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Martins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rodolfo, actually we have a much better performance in this quarter than last quarter. The reasons are mainly freight performance, which was almost $2 better than last quarter in terms of cost. So then we have a much better FOB price after deducting the lower freight.</p>
          <p>Also, the <mark type="ph" /> silica penalty (33:54) that we saw appearing since we start selling in the spot basis is reduced also &#x2013; is almost disappeared. And we have in our sales, mainly of Caraj&#xE1;s ore on a spot basis, we get even a better premium than Platts index show. So the $2.30 that normally you deduct &#x2013; you add as a GIU in case of our sales on a spot basis of Caraj&#xE1;s ore, we were able to get better premium from it.</p>
          <p>So at the end, we got a price realization that was most in line with Platts, after deducting freight, deducting humidity &#x2013; moisture, and also after adding the GIU. Part of this performance was really caused by market, better market conditions and also because we learned, okay. We have to recognize that Vale was a newcomer in the spot market, so we are used to sell 100% of our sales on a contractual basis. After benchmark system, we continue to sell on a quarterly price basis, but kind of <mark type="ph" /> an initiative (35:29) pricing. And now we are entering more decisively on sales on a spot.</p>
          <p>So we are learning month after month how to operate better on this market. I made this comment before: time to market is becoming very important issue that on a fixed price system, you don't have this, okay. But now that pricing is mainly based on the market and daily pricing, so the time for sales is very important. So we are managing better times to sale. We are managing better the quality that we offer in the market.</p>
          <p>So even the volume of our ships we needed to better manage the quantity that we sell when we sell on spot basis because sometimes customers want to buy a lower volume than a big ship can deliver. So all of these things we are considering in our marketing strategy. But every quarter, every month is a different story, so you're needed to adapt very fast and that's what we are doing.</p>
          <p>So as time goes by, we really believe that we always can command a premium on our ore considering our average quality, which is better than our competitors. So those are the main issues that I would like to comment. And also I believe that our performance may improve in going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Rodrigo Barros from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and congratulations on the good results in that's clearly a challenging environment. I have two questions, first one, Martins, if you could do for pellet the same that you did for iron ore, explain how much you're selling cost of the contracts in the VIM? How much in monthly contracts? And how much in the spots because that's the number that we've been getting consistently wrong in our case, with being too conservative?</p>
          <p>And my second question to Luciano, if I may, is regarding the corporate events. We saw Vale sell its stake in the Oman pellets plant in this quarter. We also saw Vale increasing its stake in VNC, so if you could comment on those three events it will be great? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as the pellet pricing system, we sell &#x2013; our average is that we sell 20% on this former quarter with lagged pricing system, okay. And this'll help pellets much more than helps iron ore because a bigger part of our customers in pellet continues to buy under this system. So I don't have a specific figure for that, but in case of pellets we have a more than our average of 20% in this &#x2013; that we have in this system. So pellet prices were favored by this situation, okay. As far as the price continues to go down on average, that will help. But when the price moves the other way around that will be a &#x2013; will have a negative influence on our price.</p>
          <p>Our rule of thumb that we always sell our pellets at least with our pelletizing costs because we could sell the pellets feed, so then we always considering what will be the best option to sell pellets or to sell pellet seed. So we always continue to manage this difference. Besides the pelletizing premium, we also have the quality premium because the pellet has on average more iron ore content than you have in the regular iron ore. So those factors create a much better premium for pellets, but they are only effect &#x2013; mainly effect of this quarter because of this lagged system. So going forward we cannot expect premium for pellets to be much bigger than $40 and much lower than $35, so that could be the best guess considering a stable pricing situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martins, maybe you could address as well the &#x2013; our sale of a stake in the Oman pellet, please. That's another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So when we start building our pelletizing plant in Oman, we have made agreements with the local government to let them buy 30% of the pellets plant, but this has not an impact on the business in itself because the pelletizing plant it works as a service provider. So &#x2013; and we only buy the tolling of producing pellets there. And it's very important to have a local government with us because we depend a lot on the infrastructure that is provided by the government to our operation: electricity, gas.</p>
          <p>So we believe it's a very good partnership for us and also but not being any burden on our profitability; something that is fair based on the return on capital of the pelletizing plant. So we believe that this operation is very good for the company and very good for our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding New Caledonia, contrary to what you might be expecting, so you might be thinking, well, Vale increased its participation so it put money into the operation, which is not the case. I mean, Vale New Caledonia, actually, we are recognizing from that situation the fact, too, which is that our partners, SNN, a joint venture between Sumitomo and Mitsui has stopped funding the project as of 2010 after the accident with the columns. So Vale already put the money under what should have been put by this partner. So what we're doing here now is recognizing. So they're being diluted in order to &#x2013; and our participation is increasing, recognizing that reality. But going forward, the good news is that they will resume funding the project. They are now confident that the project may succeed. They will be &#x2013; resume funding the project at this new participation rates. And so that's the status going forward. So that does not involve any outflow of cash disbursement from Vale, much to the contrary, we should expect now the partner resume bringing funding into the project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Alex Hacking from Citibank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my questions. The first question is regards to copper. Can you give us some guidance on how much copper sales we should expect next year from Salobo and also from Zambia. And the second question relates to the possible partnerships, obviously, this has been discussed with Rio Colorado. But is there something that you're also considering in Mozambique with the coal? And does it make sense there to have some kind of partnership with Rio Tinto on the logistics platform? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So to talk about copper I will hand over to Mr. Peter Poppinga.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Alex, thanks for the question. So copper, as you know, we are starting up Lubambe and we just did it in October. This is a 45,000 tons capacity. It's a JV actually between Vale and ARM, and there's some government participation in there as well. It's going very well. But of course the ramp-up will be &#x2013; we expect no big hiccups during the ramp-up; it will be a normal ramp-up. I would be hesitant to say to you how much are we going to produce next year as would be a looking-forward statement. But I would expect that we passed easily the 50% capacity.</p>
          <p>On Salobo, if you take &#x2013; we have produced this year already 5,000 tons contained nickel. If you take the last weeks of production and annualize that so you see the <mark type="ph" /> quickness (45:18), you see the pace. We are reaching 40% and surpassing probably 50% of the capacity in terms of pace, in terms of <mark type="ph" /> quickness (45:23) this year.</p>
          <p>So what we expect for next year is Salobo could be close to capacity, which actually is very similar what happened with our Sossego ramp-up; we have learned some lessons there. The flow sheets are very similar and so we don't expect a major surprise in Salobo.</p>
          <p>Regarding Canada, as you know, Canadian copper comes as a consequence from our mines in Sudbury, which are gaining momentum again and going back to old levels of productivity we had before the strike. We still have some work to do. And so for next year, copper production for sure will be higher in the Sudbury basin as well. Don't know if you have answer to your question, but that's what we have to say for the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as regard to partnership, as a general statement I would say that, yes, we are looking actively forward partnerships with &#x2013; in many of our projects. We understand that this is a necessary condition for Rio Colorado. So it is almost &#x2013; it is a necessary condition, we need a partner in order to go forward in Rio Colorado. In Mozambique, it's an idea that we are entertaining as well, the only caveat that I would put is that we already have partners in Mozambique; the government is a partner in the railway corridor. There's a few private investors, so all conversation need to involve the government as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Carlos De Alba from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. Thank you for taking my question. The first one is on what is the rationale to keep the logistic service business? 1We have seen the performance has been sub par, but I want to know if there is anything that is related between this business and your mining operations in Brazil that may prevent you from potentially divesting these assets beyond the railroads?</p>
          <p>And the second question is if you can, Martins, explain a little bit or help me reconcile the fact that as you sell now more in the spot market you may need to use smaller ships, with the fact that Vale is getting more value max that are &#x2013; obviously, are larger in size? So how does the company think about reconciling these two trends? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on logistics, I will give you the same answer. I would say that as we are reassessing all of our assets, as specifically the new regulatory environment in Brazil has changed, and has incentivized the entity of a logistics operator, so there has been a separation between the entity of the concession holder and the operator, and as you pointed out the value brought by the business, maybe it's not in line with the best expectations of shareholders. This is also a business that we are evaluating &#x2013; constantly evaluating to see what are the best solutions and to see how we &#x2013; so how we go forward. As of, for the second question on iron ore, I'll hand over to Mr. Martins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Carlos, this is very interesting question and I have a great pleasure to answer it. First of all, for sure that to minimize the freight costs you really need big vessels, okay. So bigger the vessel, the lower will be the freight cost, and most efficient will be the energy consumption. So not only cost, but also environmental impact. As you probably know, there will be probably a new taxation on harbor emission ships, so that would add additional advantages of using big ships with lower energy consumption.</p>
          <p>But the other side is that many in the scrap market in China is small customers. They prefer to buy lower quantities and our competitors are closer and they sell normally 80,000 tons. So that make them more palatable for those customers. So what we are doing is we are as you know we are building a distribution center in Malaysia that will enter in operation by end of next year, beginning of 2014. So the big ships would make the big part of the journey, optimizing the freight cost, and later you can distribute with the small vessels. So you'll be in middle of Asia and you distribute very easily, using the right size of vessels for each situation.</p>
          <p>On top of it we have our floating transportation in Philippines, Subic Bay, where we can move the ore from the big vessels to smaller vessels or even to storage in the floating station also. And we are building a second floating station and if it was needed then we can build another one. But we believe that with the two floating stations, with our distribution center we already have in Oman, and a distribution center we're going to have in Malaysia, we can solve this problem.</p>
          <p>Vale marked vessels is now being accepted in many other ports, so we are now beside this Oman, Taranto and Rotterdam, we are also berthing our big vessels in Japan, in Oita, and also in Philippines in the JFE sintering plant that they have there. And new ports will accept in the coming months the Vale mark.</p>
          <p>So we are &#x2013; it's for sure that we have some setbacks on it. For sure, we have some additional costs on it, but on average we are improving day-after-day our operations with big vessels, improving the solutions we have. So we really believe that after Malaysia we'll be in a very good position and for sure we also hope to deliver through big vessels in China for big customers, okay. It's more customers that buy on a spot, they prefer smaller vessels. But the big customers that buy on contractual basis prefer big vessels. So as time goes by we see a lot of improvements that we can add to our price realization by improving our big ship operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me; our next question comes from Chelsea Konsko from TIAA-CREF.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I was just wondering if you could please discuss what is driving greater demand for sinter feed versus pellets in the market? And when do you expect this to be reversed and are free to start operating in your pelletizing plants that you closed down again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jos&#xE9; Martins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, pellet seed is always, sorry, pellets are always more volatile than sinter feed because customers use pellets mainly when they need the high productivity in the blast furnace. In a scenario that many of our customers are operating with the low &#x2013; at low rates, they use of pellets is not so convenient for them. So the answer to your question will depend on the market behavior, and as long as they need more productivity, they will come back to pellets, but I cannot say for sure when that will happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Ms. Marina Melemendjian from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, good afternoon, everyone, thanks for taking my question. My question is related to iron ores volumes. Year to-date, Vale has a good shipping amount of 220 million tons of fines in pellets. You have been guiding the volume of 310 million tons for the year, which would imply strong volume increase in the last quarter. I just would like to know if you believe that this guidance is likely to be achieved and, if yes, when could we see production picking up? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We keep our targets, okay, as Mr. Luciano Siani explained before, with this extended enterprise. Besides the quantity that we can produce in the last quarter, we also have some iron ore available. And then we can invoice a little bit more if the market conditions allow us. And if you don't have any &#x2013; I don't foresee an impact in our production, so we keep our target and we expect to reach it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Jonathan Brandt from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, good afternoon. Thank you for taking my question. The first question relates to the CapEx pressure and operating cost pressure. We've seen a lot of headlines from, not only Vale, but some of the other majors and some of the minor companies as well, talking about cutting CapEx. Have you seen or do you expect to see CapEx disinflation coming up? Or are things like trucks and tires still experiencing a lot of CapEx pressure? And I guess related to that on the operating cost side, if you could explain a little bit more about what plans you have in place to cut operating costs? Or should we think of it more as tied to the BRL and the potential weakness there?</p>
          <p>And, secondly, if you could touch upon the debt levels; they've been increasing a little bit over the past few quarters. Is there a maximum level that you would take those to? Is there a maximum level that the rating agencies would allow you take those too? And I guess, lastly, would you consider &#x2013; if you need to raise more debt would you consider doing another convertible? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay let me start by CapEx. It's a different situation in the equipment market than the services market. In the equipment market we are seeing some softness and possibly the easing of cost inflation, maybe even some disinflation. However, on the service side, especially in Brazil, we haven't seen it that clearly, so the market for construction sales in Brazil continues to be very, very tight.</p>
          <p>In terms of operating costs beyond the BRL depreciation, we're targeting our structural initiatives and beyond the usual more granular cost-cutting programs, I would say there are some structural initiatives in place. The first one is the reassessment of our low value-adding assets, so it's the same thing that we mentioned on the nickel mines, the Birchtree and the Frood mines. So that kind of assessment is being conducted through all our mines and process plants.</p>
          <p>So, yes, we believe there's room for optimization of the flow sheets, flows of materials to take the most and maybe halt non-performing assets and get the most value of the operations.</p>
          <p>The second one would be the &#x2013; on the procurement side, Vale traditionally has paid a lot of attention to the big ticket items, which are the ones which are usually procured globally. Now we're turning our attention to the small items. That's our goal more &#x2013; as I mentioned &#x2013; small items. They &#x2013; together they amount to a sizable spending. About 50% of our total OpEx spending comes from smaller items. So now we're addressing this internally and trying to change our approach to that as well.</p>
          <p>In terms of debt levels, I mentioned in the presentation that the net debt has increased slightly over the next &#x2013; over the last nine months, so just $1 billion. It is true that gross debt has increased more, but we had made a war chest in terms of cash going forward. So that was a deliberate strategy as well to operate with higher levels of cash in order to have more flexibility.</p>
          <p>The rating agencies, they don't have a target level of debt. They penalize I would say a company with a high CapEx profile. In what way? If you take the usual net debt over EBITDA, gross debt over EBITDA or interest payment coverage, the usual ratios that rating agencies use to assign a rating to an issuer, the implied rating that Vale would have would be A-plus or A, the last time I saw it. But it's above the current assigned ratio that Vale has. The reason being &#x2013; because the rating agencies assign a penalty for the CapEx program. They believe that &#x2013; they want to see that you have room to manage the CapEx program because they see it as a cash-out so that's not available for repaying that.</p>
          <p>So our belief is that as we show our capital discipline and we show that we can effectively manage with CapEx going forward that this penalty will be over time be disregarded and we will be rated more in accordance to our fundamental ratios. So in that respect, the debt levels nowadays are not the most concern for our rating agencies, but rather the current debt levels, which are low, if you look at the ratios, but in conjunction with the flexibility to manage the CapEx program.</p>
          <p>And if we do have the funding program for next year, we are going to look at all alternatives and we have debt coming due next year, which will need to be refinanced, so as usual we'll be tapping different sources of funds in order to &#x2013; for our funding program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o from Itau BBA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, everybody. My question is on nickel, if you could comment a little bit on the production expected for VNC and also Puma in 2013? And also on the pre-operating expenses, how do you expect that line to behave in 2013.</p>
          <p>And my second question is related to the CFEM provision. If you could provide an update on the discussions between Vale and the government related to the difference in the calculations from past royalties? If this increase in provisions is showing that the company is closer to a resolution in the short-term with the government? And if this value on the provision is likely to be maintained at this level or it could be increased at any point in time? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on nickel I'm going to pass it on to Mr. Peter Poppinga.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's, Marcos, thanks for the question. In terms of nickel you mentioned specifically On&#xE7;a Puma and VNC. So as I told you On&#xE7;a Puma is rebuilding the furnace and the future design floor. This furnace was built in 2008 and for safety reasons, we must rebuild the furnace. So if we start up mid of next year, roughly, we expect a normal ramp up for profile and this would be not very different from normal ramp ups in furnaces like that. Now that the furnace would have the problem solved.</p>
          <p>In terms of New Caledonia, we have as I said and as Luciano mentioned here, we successfully the production. So all the affected columns are repaired; the design has been changed. We started up some weeks ago filling the pipeline still and now in November the acid plants start up again and finally nickel will be produced.</p>
          <p>In Q1 2013, we are going to assess to decide if this is a viable operation in terms of capacity and how the ramp-up goes. But for sure, if you produce with two autoclaves, say, three autoclaves, which we produce with two autoclaves like we are forecasting to do, we should have a nickel production next year, which should be close to half of the capacity, and then the rest would come in 2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of pre-operational expenses, yes, you highlighted that if you can see in our balance sheet that that has been driving results. It's around $300 million every quarter, I guess, I don't have the number in top of my head. But we will not tolerate this situation as an ongoing situation, so we're committed to reducing that level of &#x2013; and that pertains mostly to the two operations mentioned On&#xE7;a Puma and Vale New Caledonia. So the reason why we're going to have an assessment in the first half of next year for New Caledonia is to really to &#x2013; not to perpetuate that situation going forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of the CFEM, so the provision was made when we &#x2013; in our talks with the authorities we recognized that that amount of R$1.2 billion, the provision in dollars, $540 million was really a part of our discussion that became very clear that the likelihood that we wouldn't lose this dispute is really high. Talks and conversations continue. I don't know if we should expect a big bang in terms of a comprehensive agreement that it will be finalized. I would say that the talks continue. A mutual understanding of the thesis and goals continue, but we are quite confident that the amount that has been provisioned is the expected disbursement outcome, but yet the discussions have not been finalized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. This concludes today's question-and-answer session. Mr. Luciano Siani at this time you may proceed with your closing statement sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I believe &#x2013; we believe that the message that we've been voicing recently of capital discipline, value to shareholders and cost consciousness has been very vocal and we made a point in repeating that over and over, but that has to be underscored with our results. And we believe that we have started to show a few instances, and few actions, and also preliminary results in the numbers, and in our decisions and actions that are quite well aligned with the strategy and the direction that we've been telling investors.</p>
          <p>So our belief is that going forward, we will be able to generate a continuous stream of additional improvement in the numbers, and additional decisions that are aligned to that &#x2013; to our directions and, let's say, deliver on our promises to be succinct.</p>
          <p>So I hope our investors and shareholders, they give us with this preliminary result they give us that confidence vote and we're sure that Vale will deliver on amongst newly established direction and approach.</p>
          <p>Thank you all for attending and our Investor Relations team is available for further questions after this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That does conclude Vale's Third Quarter 2012 Results Conference Call for today. Thank you very much for your participation. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>