<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1324549" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2481</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Guilherme Perboyre Cavalcanti, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Roger Agnelli, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Felipe Hirai</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Tito Botelho Martins</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Eduardo de Salles Bartolomeo</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Jos&#xE9; Carlos Martins</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Ivan Fadel</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Rodrigo Barros</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Leonardo Correa</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Rodolfo de Angele</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Tony Rizzuto</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Tito Martins</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Rene Kleyweg</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="corprep">Jose Carlos Martins</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by, and welcome to Vale's Conference Call to discuss Second Quarter 2010 Results. If you do not have a copy of the relevant press release, it is available at the company's website at www.vale.com at Investors link.</p>
          <p>At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session, and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>As a reminder, this conference is being recorded. To access the replay, please dial 5511-4688-6312; access code, 47095. The file will also be available at the company's website, at www.vale.com at Investors section.</p>
          <p>This conference call and the slide presentation are being transmitted via Internet as well. You can access the webcast by logging onto the company's website, at www.vale.com, Investors section, or at www.prnewswire.com.br.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Actual performance could differ materially from that anticipated in any forward-looking comments as a result of macroeconomic conditions, market risks and other factors.</p>
          <p>With us today are Mr. Roger Agnelli, President and Chief Executive Officer; Mr. Guilherme Cavalcanti, Chief Financial Officer; Mr. Jos&#xE9; Carlos Martins, Executive Officer of Marketing, Sales and Strategy; Mr. Tito Martins, Executive Officer of Basic Materials Operations; and Mr. Eduardo Bartolomeo, Executive Officer of Integrated Operations.</p>
          <p>First, Mr. Cavalcanti will proceed to the presentation, and after that, we will open for questions and answers. It is now my pleasure to turn the call over to Mr. Cavalcanti. Sir, you may now begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning to you all and thank you very much for attending this conference. We will have a brief presentation about results and perspectives, and then we'll go to our Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>We believe that we delivered an outstanding performance in the second quarter 2010, reaching operating revenues of almost $10 billion, EBIT margin of almost 48%, an EBITDA of $5.6 billion, and net earnings of $3.7 billion &#x2013; all significant increases from the previous quarters and also very significant increase compared to the same period of last year.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, we presented savings in two quarters in a row, savings up $500 million. Adjusted EBITDA almost doubled being driven by strong demand for minerals reflected on the price variation and we presented a decrease on the revenue ratio from 2.4 to 1.8 gross debt to EBITDA and to 1.3 times net debt to EBITDA. Our powerful cash generation also allowed us to increase our investment in 88% from 5.2 billion to almost $10 billion on the first half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Now talking about short-term outlook. It appears that financial markets were predicting risks that did not happen. This trend was reflected on the commodity prices that now appears to be covering as we can see on page 12.</p>
          <p>In core countries of Europe recovery also remains strong and on page 14 following the history of U.S. industrial production, we can see a quarter of moderate growth after strong recoveries.</p>
          <p>On page 15, we see China continuing to grow at high rates, although lower than previous quarters, we believe it is a more sustainable pace.</p>
          <p>On page 16, we can see global carbon steel output returning to the peak reached before the crisis. Despite short-term volatility, demand for iron ore remains strong. The quarterly pricing system is being consolidated with all our clients. Nickel inventories have been dropping while prices are hovering around $20,000. Therefore, we believe that markets already priced to the end of the strike.</p>
          <p> Vale stainless steel output could weaken due to seasonal factors, we believe the demand for nickel to non-stainless steel applications will remain strong. Our constraints to asset utilization and sales growth are being removed. For example, the end of strike in Sudbury and our gradual recovery of Ponta da Madeira shipping iron ore capacity.</p>
          <p>Now talking about growth opportunities, this year we delivered three projects already. Additional 20 million tons of iron ore, CSA steel mill, Bay&#xF3;var, a phosphate rock mine. And we have four projects to be delivered till the end of this year, Oman pelletizing plant, On&#xE7;a Puma Nickel mine, Tres Valles copper mine, and Estreito hydroelectric power generation. Those projects amounted $7.7 billion in investments that now will start to generate value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And there are many more to come from an exciting pipeline, and moreover many growth options to feed this pipeline in the future, as we can see on page 23 and 24. On July 25, we have a summary of Bay&#xF3;var phosphate project that came on stream, on time and on budget.</p>
          <p>And as you know, we announced it yesterday, our public auction to acquire 100% of Paranapanema copper smelter which can reach an investment of 1.1 million &#x2013; $1.1 billion, representing a belief in the Brazilian internal market and also a strategic feed to our copper mines.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn now to the Q&amp;A session please. Sorry, I'll turn now to our President and CEO Mr. Roger Agnelli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I wasn't supposed to speak, but I think it's good to say something about the results.</p>
          <p>First of all, good morning, everybody. It's our pleasure to be with you today. And I'm very happy to see that Vale make-up all countries recovery in Brazil that clinched a hot seat, because of the few things being &#x2013; this first presentation is showing a very good results in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>What I would like to say is that everything is going well. The trend is very good in terms of revenues, in terms of costs, in terms of perspective. We are very happy that we are in a very nice and very good year for Vale.</p>
          <p>We had several projects that we are finalizing right now. We &#x2013; as you know, we have been investing heavily in the last three, four years. And we have almost 15, $16 billion in capital allocated to those investments without any revenue. And now we are going to see some return on those investments.</p>
          <p>And I think the most important thing is that the major part of the projects are greenfield projects and we have already prepared those projects to brownfield expansion and we are going straight in almost everything.</p>
          <p>In Biovar we are going to inaugurate that in the 5 August <mark type="inaudible" />, and we are going to announce that we are going straight for the expansion. We are going to finalize Mozambique and again we are going straight for the expansion. We finalized already the CSA maybe in the end of the year we are going to decide if we are going to expand the project again or not.</p>
          <p>Other projects that we are finalizing next year also we are going straight to the expansion, example, Salobo. So, of course, the greenfield project in the very beginning is &#x2013; the return is lower, but when we add additional capacity, we are going to speed up we are going to increase the return on those investments.</p>
          <p>So I think we have several options of growth &#x2013; organic growth. As you saw in the presentation, we have several other projects that we are right now finalizing the strategic planning, but our intention is to go ahead with those projects. We are confident that there are, there is markets for all the new capacity that we are adding to our systems in different areas. We are not concerned about that because all those projects, they are very, very competitive, all of them.</p>
          <p>Big result &#x2013; big reserves, we know that we can really be in the first or the second quartile of cost in all those projects. After the expansion we will be in the first quartile. So we are very, very confident that we are going to bring a lot of returns to our shareholders. What we are focused today, or at least I'm really focused today is innovation. Innovation is something very important for the company.</p>
          <p>As you know any project we run for at least 20 years and there will be changing everybody in the global society is concerned about the environment, is concerned about social development. You know that we are right now investing heavily in Africa. Africa is a place that we really need to pay attention about social development, we have to pay attention in sustainability, they need that, they deserve that and that's what we are creating some opportunities for the local people. It's really important for a mining company like us to be really very sensitive to this kind of issue.</p>
          <p>And we understand that Africa, everybody feels is a risky continent, but we understand very well the needs that they have &#x2013; how we have to carry the investments there in Africa. So we don't see any problem there. We are very happy in Mozambique. We are very happy in Zambia and Kenya, everywhere that we are developing our projects, we are happy.</p>
          <p>Of course, we need to learn. They need to learn is a matter of get together and see and show that we are a company that we are going to respect the sustainability in our project. Of course, the issue is to create the mining of the future and we are working in all projects considering that in 10 years, nobody will accept the same ratio of water consumption that we have today. Nobody will accept the CO2 emission that we have today.</p>
          <p>Everybody will ask for clean energy &#x2013; much better than we have today. So in every single new project, we are delivering those projects and we are considering those projects as a much more clean, much more sustainable projects. So this is a challenge for the natural resource of the industry, mainly, after the issue that United States are facing in Gulf of Mexico that is polluting everything.</p>
          <p>So we have to really be careful with the projects. We needed to bring today the mentality that we are going to face in 10 years. So it's really very important to be innovative, to be concerned about environment, see how we can help the local governments to develop their communities there, social standards in every single country that we are operating in.</p>
          <p>I'm very confident that Vale is ahead of the other companies &#x2013; of the other mining companies in terms of sustainability. I'm very confident and I'm very proud for the work that we are developing today in Vale.</p>
          <p>As I said, the trend is good. We are prepared to take advantage of this very good moment in the global economy. Of course, there are some concerns about the near future. But again, we are here to look forward the next 20 years, not for the next quarter or the next year.</p>
          <p>We are confident that the markets will be very strong, would be good for everybody, and it will be good for our operations in order to sell wherever we are going to produce.</p>
          <p>Again, we are in a very strong position. I should say that we are in the best moment in our history. We are in the best moment of our history. We adjusted the company last year heavily in terms, of cost, we trained our people with wealth of our assets a lot in terms of maintenance. We've faced some issues, day-by-day issues. Like every year, we face them. And we've overcome all the difficulties that we have.</p>
          <p>That's what I would like to say to you. I'm very confident that the trend is positive. The trend is really positive. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Mr. Felipe Hirai from Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, everyone. Guilherme, good luck on your new role at Vale. So I have two questions here related to iron ore. So my first one is regarding prices, so if you could just give us some explanation of what happened to the realized prices? According to the formula, we were expecting prices closer or above $100 a ton. The average price came at $92. Maybe if you could talk on what happened with prices in May and June. And I'm also on that topic, if you could talk a little bit on what you expect to see prices in the third quarter? Again, according to the formula, we would expect to see prices going up by $30 in the third quarter. So that's my first question. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Felipe. Martins speaking. As far as the price system, it is rolling off very well. In the first quarter there was no problem to apply the new price system because, as you know, spot market at that time was going below the formula price, and in this quarter it's opposite, but the system is going well, very well also. It should return in this first month then we've all the investors nominated for the next month. And we don't believe we're going to have any kind of problems. So customers are fulfilling their obligation as far as the price system and also as far as the quantity.</p>
          <p>So the system in itself is doing very well. The difference you'd see on the price realizations in the second quarter are going against your forecast based on the market situation probably would be that looking the average of the market and you make your assessment. We have three points that put our price a little bit down. The first was the carryover because as you all know we face some problems in delivering our volumes in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>So there we have the rain and other issues that we already talked about the market last time. So we have a carryover volume that we had to deliver with the former price. This is the contract obligation that's where we work.</p>
          <p>And we're now &#x2013; we'll never change and we have to agree with our customers if it is on a contract. So we have to face the situation, and we deliver near 10 million plus in the third &#x2013; in the second quarter based on the price of the first quarter, so that is one of the problem. Another issue you have to consider is that the sales of our sales in the Mexican market.</p>
          <p>And for the Mexican market we take out the logistic that we don't use, so for the sales in domestic price the prices are little bit because it's not FOB based on the port on the ship, so then there is a more discount based on this, because we don't spend money with logistic, so we don't charge the customers.</p>
          <p>And the third point is that probably <mark type="inaudible" /> 66% lower our sales, and it's not true because the 66 is only in Caraj&#xE1;s, so in Southeastern System we have something around 65 and Southern System is around 64 so you should take all over those effects that the reason we have this difference in price.</p>
          <p>Going forward we know the index on marginal price will increase in this quarter and that's going on also. But I also needed to make this point that some carryover we have from the second quarter to the third quarter. So we expect in this quarter to finish all the carryover because the operation is performing better now, and we don't have the impact of the rain.</p>
          <p>So third quarter also is the best quarter in our track record, if you look at other quarters in the past you see that the third is always the best. So we believe that we can finish the carryover. So as price is concerned things are moving very well and we are very optimistic about this new system. And the market is following up the same system and so I think it was a case of <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>And again it's a good demonstration of the Vale as the leading in this market. So I do not see any kind of problems that are going forward. But living with this big &#x2013; quarter based on the &#x2013; is pretty much lower than the average we are using for contracts. Customers are committed and they are behaving like we expected. So that's the point I hope you I was able to explain your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Martins. And my second question is related to the production and the logistic issue that you had in the first and second quarter. So can you just explain to us what is going on now at Ponta da Madeira. And other, of course how &#x2013; when do you think that you're going to be able to resume like your full production if that is &#x2013; if those issues have been solve, and it caused to &#x2013; what do you think about production and shipment for the next two quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First &#x2013; we would love to talk about it, and I think we made a big change in our structure and I hope now that we have mine is very, very important with the same direction,. I think we are going to have a much more smooth operation, because those areas will be much more together and I think that will bring a lot of improvement in the performance, as far as the integration between mine and railway and port. And so Eduardo will talk about at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Felipe, first of all, we should try to separate what is from behind &#x2013; we had normal ramp up of the soft line in Ponta da Madeira started in November with <mark type="inaudible" /> and its really catching up the normal, the yard, the reclaimers, the packers and now it's all finished I think.</p>
          <p>If you look at June for instance will be the best year and the best month of this year. And we are looking very positive, you can say as Martin has already mentioned, during the first semester added to the normal problems that we faced in day-to-day operations in quality of equipment.</p>
          <p>Of course that hurt a little bit more on Ponta da Madeira. So the technicians worked very well and so that is solved, so we have the rainy season that in the case of the north goes a little further than to June. So &#x2013; but anyhow, if you look at the second semester the ramping up of the cost line is ready and going and it's doing well.</p>
          <p>The rainy season, of course, is over as Martins already mentioned. So we're looking &#x2013; and the normal problems that we have with day-to-day operations we've been tackling them and solving them and we are very, very close and at &#x2013; near to our budgets even some &#x2013; I'm very optimistic about the second semester.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Philip, this is Roger. Of course, it's very important to mention that we are preparing all the systems, all the systems in the company for the coming production. So you know that we are expanding production in the north system, in the south system, and we needed to prepare reports for this new capacity requirement. So Eduardo mention about the north, the Ponta da Madeira. I consider that nothing. It's not a problem, it's something that you have to face in a ramp-up pace. And as you know 2007, 2008, 2009 equipment, all the equipment that were produced in this time, some of them face some quality issues. So everybody is facing this kind of things, so they ramp up in instead of take like 3 months, took like 3.5, 4 months, so this is natural.</p>
          <p>You are going to see in the third quarter that the <mark type="inaudible" />, was stopped for us 2, 3 weeks, just to prepare report to receive the new car bumper the new ship loader, sorry, the new ship loader. So what we are doing is the work that is necessary to do to prepare the system to increase capacity in near term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And to consumer all the iron ore that is produced in the mines that's the most important thing, so we're going to move it through the ships.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Felipe, as far as the price issue is concerned, I would like to add another point that I forget &#x2013; forgot to say. When you make your calculations and you use our deliveries which is in wet basis and the pricing system is in the dry basis, so this brings something like 5 or $6 difference, okay. Because you calculate that our volume in wet basis and we price on a dry basis. So this is another point that you have to consider when you assess the average price that we are realizing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first and second quarter, the ore was really wet, and it was raining a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. [Operator Instruction] Our next question comes from Mr. Ivan Fadel from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Good morning, Roger, Guilherme, Martins, Tito, Bartolomeo. Well, my first question is regarding the project, the CapEx, when I compared the CapEx budget in the first and second quarter releases, I notice some changes in Caraj&#xE1;s 130 project also in Vargem Grande Itabiritos, Bay&#xF3;var, Moatize and Tres Valles. Could you go over them briefly to explain why the CapEx increased in most of them? And why in &#x2013; particularly in Caraj&#xE1;s 130, you have now a lower budget specifically for 2010?</p>
          <p>And my second question would be related to Vale's growth prospects and M&amp;A. So Vale's generate a very strong cash flows in the next few quarters and perhaps years on very high iron ore price is expected. And every once in a while I noticed that there are concerns from market participants, from investors that Vale might undergo large acquisitions in the future, perhaps taking lower returns. How do you see this going forward? Is it something that Vale is planning for larger acquisitions, given that you get a very strong cash flow ahead or you'll keep your discipline and perhaps focus on organic growth? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ivan. Beginning with the second question, first of all remember that Vale is the only mining company in the world who can double the capacity only with organic investments. So our focus is really organic growth, so there's a lot to do in this sense. And again, big acquisitions has also today, not only for Vale but also for the mining industry as a whole, restricted from the financing capacity of the banking system today. So that's not our focus today. And -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can go over the projects. When you look at the <mark type="inaudible" /> sorry, Caraj&#xE1;s 130 that you asked, it's because of moving target that we've started to update because due to environmental licenses that we face problems to take them for presentation, et cetera. When you look at specific, each one of the projects like Moatize; Moatize added some logistics on it, so we had to readjust the budgets to take that into account.</p>
          <p>And we're going to move to track access. We're going to have to make a solution on the data port. So that's basically adjustments, normal adjustments on the budgets. <mark type="inaudible" /> on a Phase II and Phase III studies, those things as Roger already mentioned are being challenged and discussed, anyhow it's been the best number we have now. But there are normal adjustments that we have over the projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ivan, this is Roger, how long have you been working with this list or covering Vale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, say it again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How long have you been working covering Vale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For 8 years, 8 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>8 years. Okay. So you know very well that in the last 10 years, we are following strictly this strategy plan that we announced there, back in 2001. As soon as I took over as CEO here, everything that we made in terms of M&amp;A was opportunistic approach. And, of course, there are some assets that we would like to hold, we would like to acquire, but they are not at our &#x2013; our disposition. So if someone decides to sell, we are prepared to buy.</p>
          <p>This fits to our strategy if we strength our position in the market, if we bring a lot of synergies for our company. I don't believe that much in synergies. In fact the issue is quality. If the asset is very good, we are going to &#x2013; after that. That's the reality. In terms of leverage, if we are going to spend the money, we have our commitment to grow the company. We speed up the implementation of some projects or we can delay some projects, so we can adjust our CapEx as we wanted to adjust or it is not in terms to adjust. Last year we postponed some projects because we said, well, let's analyze a little bit more of how it is going to be the community environment in the world and as soon as we saw that was good. Okay, let's start there some investments and that's what we are doing.</p>
          <p>Regarding to Paranapanema, these assets we were discussing, looking around there for more, we haven't been there for more than three years, right now, and there is an opportunity. And we feel that we are growing strongly in quarter as we mentioned many, many times is something that we believe that is going to be very good if the market is good, we are bullish about quarter and we are growing.</p>
          <p>We are growing &#x2013; going to double or triple our concentrate production. So it's time to have <mark type="inaudible" /> here or any other place in the world, why not? It's just to manage risk. And another point to that is really very important. We believe that Brazil is an economy that will perform very well in the next &#x2013; in the following &#x2013; in the coming years. So we would like to increase our exposure to the Brazil markets, why not? So part of our planning is good. So you can say whatever you want to say, but Vale has been disciplined and I hate that, I hate that. But sometimes you have to have some debt, just to optimize the return on assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Roger, that was very clear and I fully agree with you and I think that continuous reinforcement of that is very important for investors to understand. That is why we basically have Vale as our top pick, and I believe fully that Vale has enough organic growth to boost its growth pattern throughout this high cycle and I think that it was very clear, so I hope it does to basically mitigate this risk that every once in a while I see some investors raising concern. So I was really looking for this reinforcement, which I think was something to expect anyway. So thank you very much for your clear and very straight to the point answer. Thank you, Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ivan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Rodrigo Barros from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Congratulations on the very good results, in particular when we consider the non-recurring effect of the delayed shipments. I have two questions. The first one on the Vale news. We note that although iron ore prices came down from almost $190 per ton to $120 per ton, at the same time the well use increased from 4.5 to $6 per ton. Now, I would like to know if you have any explanation why anyone is increasing despite the falling iron ore prices? This is the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we needed to understand that the yield price formula was built exactly to get this, because the former price system was based only in the iron ore content. So if you have iron ore either at 58 or 66, the prices percent of iron ore would be the same, so that was fair for Vale so &#x2013; because that situation would allow us to correct the price from &#x2013; to correct iron ore from others without getting the value and use for it. So, exactly what's going on is, the price was down, and you have a more low quality ore available, more you need the high quality ore. So, in order the customer to get advantage of the low quality ore, they have attributable to buy more good quality ore and they have to pay for it. So, I think it's &#x2013; and that's the beauty of the new system for Vale, because now we really have value for our quality and the market is recognizing it and that's the most beautiful because the market is recognizing and paying it.</p>
          <p>So if the Australians have freight differential, we have the quality differential. So, I think both can be happy. Okay. Australians can be happy with the freight differential and we are happy with the quality differential. And customer he will be also happy because they can take advantage of proximity and can take advantage of quality. And they can mix their burning according to their best calculations.</p>
          <p>So I think the market is proving our presence in long-term debt that we always told you about it and people are paying. So if people pay, that's the reality. So, I don't think we need to explain too much why, because as long the market is paying it because the market is recognizing it.</p>
          <p>So, and it's &#x2013; if the market become stronger, probably, the VRU will be lower, because when the market is very stronger, what the market need is iron ore units more than quality, because if they &#x2013; if don't have iron ore units you cannot produce the steel. So in our very, very strong market, the VRU will decrease and now we can market the VRU will increase, so that's the way the market is recognizing it and it makes sense when you look at logically inside the system, inside the blast furnace more than how the people use the ore and a lot of those things. So, we are very happy with the new system and you believe that expendables while they will be stronger and everybody recognize the advantage of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you for your answer. My second question regards the reacting to iron ore assets that valued, but it's recently and we all know that these are extremely high quality assets which would definitely commend a very good value in use for Vale. I wonder if you could share with us what are your plans for developing that assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Corumb&#xE1; asset is best &#x2013; the best lump ore in the world. Okay. It's a big &#x2013; this mine is big producer of lumps and have a very, very high quality similar to Caraj&#xE1;s, but lump so that is an additional value which is when you have your <mark type="inaudible" />, you don't need to <mark type="inaudible" />. You're also &#x2013; there is an additional advantage beside the quality and the sizing is also is better. This resources had a big challenge with this logistic. The mine is 2,000 kilometers from the sea, whatever the side you look, it takes 2,000 kilometer to get the sea, so we have &#x2013; we're developing a fleet of barges for bringing it to the port, so down to the sea. And it's not all of the issue because that place is not suitable for big vessels. So, we needed to make the shipment, so there is a lot of logistic. I think it's not a mining issue to develop those cost, but logistically speaking the challenge is very big.</p>
          <p>We are moving to produce 6 million stock there. We make some investment and we are developing as I told you the barter system for it. But we believe that we can reach 15 million tons by 2012 to 2013. But that we always depend on the price of the ore in the market, because logistically wise it's very expenses to do it.</p>
          <p>And that was the reason that this mine was never fully developed. But as the price of iron ore probably stay above the 100 barrels per ton on a long-term, we believe that we can get full potential for this mining by 2012 to 2013 in the raising of15 million tons per year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is our second coal reserve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Leonardo Correa from Barclays Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Thank you very much for the call. My first question is regarding the iron ore, coal re-pricing mechanism. The question is for Martins please. We have recently hearing of high resistance levels of the industry on the coal re-pricing mechanism. And this is basically given the timing disclosures that may generate. So, just to hear from Martins if Vale is contemplating to change the system to a monthly pricing system going forward. Just to get your views on that? And the second question is regarding also for Martins regarding the outlook on iron ore demand for Europe given that the restocking is now close to complete, what type of demand levels are you seeing for Europe during your coming quarters? Those are both of the questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as the price system in concerned, we should come from price that was established for a period of one year to assist and that the price is established for quarters. So, it was a big improvement from one system to the other. I think the answer for your question you'll be giving by the market, okay. Because as long as volatility stay too high and probably there will be need for some adjustment. But I believe that after this over-shooting in this year, in this two quarters and you've seen now that the iron ore price is stabilizing in <mark type="inaudible" /> in the spot market in China. I believe that this volatility will be reduced going forward and maybe we don't need it to change it. But the answer will be given by the market. So, as we've told before, we need assistant that can cope with volatility. So &#x2013; and I believe the quarter re-price can cope with that and will help to reduce volatility. And if you reduce volatility and you have also a kind of vent that we keep the prices stable if the variation is under the same level.</p>
          <p>Long-term, I believe that we can have a more stable price. And then maybe a &#x2013; the prices established quarterly, but probably the price could be kept for near or two, if the volatility is not so big.</p>
          <p>So, I think, volatility and customers will have an answer on that. For the time being customers are committing their self with the new price system was a big change for them. They come from one year price system to acquire, so they have their relationship with their customers.</p>
          <p>So this is a big challenge, is really big challenge and we needed to realize that how customers will behave under this system, had a lots of this to stay or not. One thing is for sure, if you look at oil prices, oil prices are commodity much better than iron ore, much important than iron ore worldwide. And the prices are established daily. And the market is real  with that.</p>
          <p>I don't think that all the stocks about iron ore price moving every quarter is not good or is bad. I think is all a question to be used to that, and as time go by, people you adapt to it. And I think also volatility can be much lower under a system that can self adjust quarterly. So I believe the quarterly system will stay.</p>
          <p>You asked the second question about Europe &#x2013; the European market recovered faster than any other. It was a big recovery, very fast, also put a lot of pressure on us because of the deliveries. Because all the customers started putting more orders, almost in just in time, they're asking for more ore and so and so.</p>
          <p>And I think that was the history during the first half. Now the market <mark type="inaudible" /> a little bit. And it's normal because we have vacations in Europe, but every year was the same. So I think it's a natural movement. One thing that to look is that performance in Europe is uneven &#x2013; the countries have a different behavior, being Germany, practically come back to the same level of pre-crisis as far as the steel production, and iron ore consumption is concerned. But some countries are lagging. And Europe as a whole even after this recover on a average is 15% below pre-crisis level. So I believe that there is a space from some growth ahead, because the 15% decrease is too much for Europe. So I think in the fourth quarter, we're going to see some recover in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Rodolfo de Angele from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. My first question is about the Chinese iron ore industry. I wanted clarifications comment on what's going on there specifically, if you have a view on what's marginal cost of production and if there is any structural changes going on such as consolidation, anything on those lines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The performance of Chinese iron ore production was very good in the last three months. I think they're operating near their full capacity. And that was one of the reasons that brought some stability for the spot market also, because after the winter they come and produce almost full capacity. And this brought a lot of their ore to the market and brought some stability for the iron ore price, which is not bad &#x2013; which is not bad. But looking forward they don't have too much space to growth. And when you look at their structure, the largest mine in China can produce 10 million tons per year. So the majority of their mine is below 2 million tons per year. So their cost structure is very high.</p>
          <p>Another issue that 30% of their production is underground, and you can imagine how expensive it can be to bring iron ore from &#x2013; the separations very big. So then their cost structure is very, very different. For some mines it can be as low as $50 open pit and big mines. But for some mines it can be near, 140 to $150 and those mines when their spot price will go like it did, the tenants they get out. On average, their cost is around 80 to $90 per ton. So &#x2013; and that's the reason I believe in long-term price for iron ore will be not below this level, because that was the cost structure. As long as China continues to grow their economy and their steel industry they will need iron ore and their cost structure for their local mines can be a floor for the iron ore price. So I don't &#x2013; also quality is another point is important.</p>
          <p>Today, if you look at 66 iron ore from Caraj&#xE1;s and 58% iron ore from India, you'll have almost $30 difference between both. So it's a huge difference for quality &#x2013; for iron ore quality. So long-term, I believe that this price we will not go below $100. We had that problem in 2008. But in 2008 we had a slowdown all over the world, Europe almost disappeared and everybody dumped Chinese markets with iron ore. And their market that time was not so good also. So was so many factors that put together and then the prices went down as low as $60. But I don't believe that will happen again. And I believe that the iron price will be sustainable in the range of the 90, $100 per ton long-term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Tony Rizzuto from Dahlman Rose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I wanted to confirm something I thought I heard and then also ask a question about pricing for iron ore. And I think I heard earlier that Martins when you were mentioning about the carryover tonnage in the second quarter, I think I heard a figure of 10 million tons. If you could confirm that for me and if you could give us an idea -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, 10 million tons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you. And did I hear you say that, that would be behind you or little bit further in 3Q as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have some carryover for this quarter and lower than that for sure. And I think that we can finish all carryover by end of this quarter. when I enter the fourth quarter without any carryover.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you for that and then the second question is when I think about the realization, obviously there have been a lot discussion about that so far. But would it be unreasonable when we think about the pricing mechanism now and as this &#x2013; the carryover tonnage dissipates somewhat, you're operating at better levels, the port issues, et cetera, are we likely to see see a pricing increase that could be closer to 40 or 50% sequentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a problem, we cannot hear your questions because there is some interruption. There was interruption in your line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me repeat it and I apologize, I don't know what's going on. If we think about the pricing mechanism and with your operational issues behind you at the port, a little bit dissipation in terms of the carryover further behind you, is it unreasonable to think about a sequential price increase for iron ore that could be 40 to 50% in the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. But continuously interrupted, so I cannot understand your full question. I know you talked about carryover, about the price realization. But I was not able to get what your question was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Let me maybe take -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, but it's interrupting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe one final shot. Can you hear me now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I'm just trying to get a better handle on the third quarter price realization for iron ore. With these issues moving behind you, is it likely that we could see an increase of maybe on the order of magnitude of 40 to 50% in the third quarter on your realizations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the situation in the third quarter will be positively affected by &#x2013; because the price went up, we have &#x2013; if you look at the average of spot went up, so that information you have. And also you have some improvements in the points that you raised about the carryover. But I ask you to be very, very cautious about it, because I told you before that you are making calculation on a wet basis, and the price system is on dry basis. So then you have 5, $6 difference on that.</p>
          <p>Another point is the sales that we have in domestic market the Vale sells much more than our competitors in domestic market, Brazilian domestic market is a big market for iron ore. So in overall order sales are running. A price that is lower then FOB base price because we have the logic that cannot be considered.</p>
          <p>So the price will go up because of the average that increased in the spot in China and also because it can overall it will be lower, but you have the other factors that will be present anyway. So, and you might &#x2013; you have to be very careful when you're making our assessment. And as you know we cannot make any kind of forecast about what or where the price will be. The system is there, you know about the price. The points I told you what the points that could influence this average price, but it will be up to you to draw what number we'll be. Sorry for that, but I cannot elaborate more about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o from Ita&#xFA; Corretora.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everyone. Congratulations for your results. My first question is regarding iron ore volumes in the third quarter. I understand that shipping operations would be running at much more normalized levels in the quarter, but I would like to understand if from a market perspective, did Vale &#x2013; is Vale suffering or facing a little bit of shorter &#x2013; short-term demand on the wake of cool down in the Chinese property market during this period and also the seasonally slowdown in Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eduardo told before that production is running very well, so we're going to have sure a better performance in this quarter for many reasons. And as far as market, we are delivering every product we are able to produce and ship. So I told before that July all the &#x2013; that the sales were completely normal. No problems, no problems to deliver. For the August we have the orders and ships already nominated. And for the time being we do not see any problems arising for this slowdown in the appropriate sector in China. And I think good proxy for analyzing it is the iron ore spot price, that's moving up in China in the last two or three weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. My second question is regarding the nickel business. When do you expect volumes to return to more normalized levels on this business, and &#x2013; given the end of the strike recently in Sudbury?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Tito speaking. Thank you for the question by the way, I was almost sleeping here. We are already bringing back all the employees, so of course we need some time to train them again, so we should be back on full capacity by September. It's good to remind you that we were already operating with the 50% capacity, so that's why we believe the returns going to be fast. If we were not operating, probably it will take much more time, probably three months to come back to the full operation.</p>
          <p>To point to &#x2013; to address that we are still on strike in Newfoundland and Labrador, but it's not interfering with the operations because even they are &#x2013; we are operating 100%. We managed to bring in, to work with the staffs and replacement workers so. Canadian operations should be in full capacity by the end of September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Rene Kleyweg from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen, and couple of questions. One on Simandou; could you give us an indication of &#x2013; when or what hurdles need to be met for the next payment to be made to BSMG; and what potential capital commitments would be made prior to that next installment?</p>
          <p>And secondly, Roger mentioned the challenges facing the industry in terms of water consumption et cetera; There earlier been a mentioned possibility of a dry beneficiation process system for &#x2013; Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Previously mentioned the possibility of a dry beneficiation process system and for the 30 million ton expansion at Caraj&#xE1;s, is that still under review? I see you got the &#x2013; listed the &#x2013; recently you implemented or so, but I was just wondering if you could update us on the potential dry process there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin speaking; as far as Simandou, we are committing our now near $200 million for the project for developing the project for the mining and for the logistic, and the next payment; will only be done after some benchmarks are achieved as we get the full license to bring it on through Liberia, so and also after we have this feasibility study on place. So then the <mark type="inaudible" /> we are committing now is this $200 million for a feasibility study, basic engineering and also the project for the railway that we needed to revamp, the railway for anyhow that we needed to revamp it.</p>
          <p>So that's &#x2013; for in the next one year and a half we are not going to have a probably any other payment as far as Simandou is concerned. As far as the dry processing, we are now processing almost 50% of the ore in Caraj&#xE1;s by dry processing.</p>
          <p>The new 20 million ton project is dry processing system and even in the former system we are processing almost 40% in a dry way. So the 30 million tons project close to 30 will be dry processing and also the big Caraj&#xE1;s project will be dry processing.</p>
          <p>Our target from now on is to move the Caraj&#xE1;s, a 100% dry processing which will be very much environmentally-friendly. And not only we are working on this dry processing but we are working also in truck-less operation. So we intended to reduce a lot the use of trucks in the mining. And we believe that we can get 70% to carbon emission reduction by doing that. So we have a lot of initiatives in Caraj&#xE1;s with the new technologies, with the new process system to make it much more environmentally-friendly operation. And only to give additional figure about it when we move the iron ore through big ships 400,000 tonnes ships via Asia, we reduced 35% carbon emission.</p>
          <p>So one of our main target is to produce iron ore in a much more environmentally-friendly way. So we have a lot of initiatives on the way that not only bring more environmental concern, but also can reduce cost. So we can get those lower costs and lower environmental effect in the, it can effect less environmental by doing that. So it's a very good combination.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's question-and-answer session. Mr. Cavalcanti at this time you may proceed with your closing statement sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much to everybody for attending this call and see you next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That just concludes our Vale's second quarter 2010 results conference call for today. Thank you very much for your participation and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>