<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1423672" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2481</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Murilo Pinto de Oliveira Ferreira</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Carlos De Alba</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Officer of Marketing, Sales and Strategy, Vale SA">Jose Carlos Martins</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Felipe Hirai</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Officer of Integrated Operations">Eduardo de Salles Bartolomeo</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Equity Research">Alex Hacking</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Officer of Exploration, Energy and Projects">Eduardo Jorge Ledsham</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Chase">Rodolfo de Angele</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Rene M. Kleyweg</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Guilherme Perboyre Cavalcanti</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Dahlman Rose &amp; Co. LLC">Tony B. Rizzuto</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Officer of Human Resources and Corporate Services">Vania Somavilla</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Jonathan L. Brandt</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Citi">Andrew Mohan</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital">Leonardo Correa</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank">Rodrigo Barros</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by and welcome to Vale's Conference Call to discuss third quarter 2011 results. If you do not have a copy of the relevant press release, it is available at the company's website at www.vale.com at the Investors' link.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded. The slide will also be available at the company's website at www.vale.com at the Investors' section. The audio replay of this conference call will be available as of October 27 at the same number 5511-4688-6312, access code 1046681.</p>
          <p>This conference call is being transmitted via Internet as well. You can access the webcast by logging on the company's website www.vale.com, Investors section, or at www.prnewswire.com.br. Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Actual performance could differ materially from the anticipated in any forward-looking comments as a result of macro-economic conditions, market risks and other factors.</p>
          <p>With us today are Mr. Murilo Ferreira, Chief Executive Officer; Mr. Guilherme Cavalcanti, Chief Financial Officer; Mr. Eduardo Bartolomeo, Executive Officer of Integrated Operations; Mr. Eduardo Jorge Ledsham, Executive Officer of Exploration, Energy and Projects; Mr. Jos&#xE9; Carlos Martins, Executive Officer of Marketing, Sales and Strategy; Mrs. Vania Somavilla, Executive Officer of Human Resources and Corporate Services.</p>
          <p>It's now my pleasure to turn the call over to Mr. Murilo. Sir, you may now begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good morning. Thank you very much for having the opportunity to share some views with you. We'll do some comments and then later on, going to the question and answers.</p>
          <p>We are extremely excited to see Vale's iron ore production reaching a new level record of 87 million tons. We know that this is well above sales. As you know, we've decided to have the size of the team of Vale, the executive directors, we have decided as a team to increase the inventory in the system in Brazil and outside.</p>
          <p>Some think that it's critical for us to deliver to our customers based in the best performance and we strongly believe it was mandatory for us in order to have the same reputation that it used to have in terms of our quality. And sometimes, as you were so involved in delivering material to the market, that the quality, it was not so good. Then I think that was a chance managed by us in order to increase our inventories.</p>
          <p>Regarding the copper, I think that you are very happy as well with the volume that we reached, it's a record. And we believe that we must go ahead with some improvements, not having the problems that we saw mainly in Canada in the second quarter of the year.</p>
          <p>Just to some further items. We have &#x2013; we started our ramp-up in Moatize. It is a gorgeous project. I think that we can see a bright future in Moatize. We are so excited that the board has decided to call an expansion to 22 million tons from 11 million tons, which is excellent news to our investors. For sure, we need this to improve the corridor, the Nacala Corridor in order to provide a logistics system, not just the railroad, but the port facilities as well. Then is &#x2013; in a strategic point of view, Moatize, it's very important to our future.</p>
          <p>And I would like to say some few words regarding the Salobo copper project that we'd delay until the second quarter of the year. We had some problems. It was mandatory to replace some contractors, but now you are finalizing and we are extremely happy to see the results of the project. Karebbe in Indonesia, we have started our operations. In the first quarter of 2011, I had the benefit, the merit to go to there and to share the view with the Indonesian authorities. It was a great moment for us.</p>
          <p>I think that broadly speaking, later on I think that Vania will have a chance to discuss about what we are doing in order to be more efficient in the implementation of new projects regarding the environmental permits. I think that we are knowing &#x2013; we are working with a new guidance in terms of best practice. And we needed to do some movements in order to be more efficient.</p>
          <p>Now we have executives committed to the environment and this process of permits that we give an update in weekly basis for us. I think that through these measures, we'll be able to convey the level of efficiency that is required in this very important area.</p>
          <p>I must remember that we built many projects, the expansion of MRN [Mineracao Rio do Norte S.A.], the Paragonimus Project, three expansions in [indiscernible] (7:10), the Sossego, Salabo I and II. And then we needed to [indiscernible] (7:20) it in the iron ore business, the segment merit that we got in terms of the environment permits.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, we can begin the question-and-answer session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Mr. Carlos De Alba from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. Thank you very much. I wanted to understand a bit better what is the expectations regarding the previous start &#x2013; the pre-operation and the start-up cost of Onca Puma and VNC given that they have been significant over the last two quarters. And my second question would be if you can comment a little bit on how much &#x2013; have you or do you expect to sell in this poor market, in the iron ore market in Asia? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carlos, here is Martins speaking. I will address your second question. We are not used to sell normally in this quarter basis. We normally sell under contract. What's going on is, we are negotiating with the customers to use a more liquid price for the contracts, okay? I cannot say for sure how much be we will be doing in that way. But a good guess is to look at our volumes to China.</p>
          <p>And probably the majority of our Chinese customers will prefer a pricing that will be closer to the market situation. That trend is not clear in Europe. You have a different position from our customers in Europe. And in Japan, it seems that they want to keep the same system because it gave them, gives them more predictability. So that's the situation today. And we are under a lot of negotiations. So, it's not easy for us to give you a more precise information about that. So, look into volumes to China, could be a good <mark type="ph" /> approx (09:57) of this situation. But I cannot say for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the CNF sales are also increasing, are now around 30% of your volume. Is this a trend that you expect to continue? Thank you, Martins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Definitely, yes. I think our CNF will grow, because as you know, we are far away from China so customers are willing to have a more liquid price. So, the closer we are to China, the more market price you have. So, our CNF sales tend to increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hi, Carlos. Regarding your first question, you know that we produce the first metal in March this year where the commission is of the line one. So, we are in the final phase of the ramp-up. So, going forward you probably see more normal levels of costs since the main part of the accumulated expenses that are thrown on a ramp-up phase, on the pre-operational phase, it's already done. Okay? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Felipe Hirai from Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, good afternoon, everyone. I have two questions relating to the iron ore market. Could you just tell us if you were to &#x2013; if you didn't have the inventory build up in the quarter of let's say, $7, $8 million tons, if you were going to be able to sell that to the market, either if there was demand for that material, and if you could have the logistics, I mean in the ships to send them to China? And my second question is, how you're seeing the credit conditions in China if declines are having any kind of problems with letter of credits or anything like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Eduardo Bartolomeo speaking. Yes. I think so. What we've said earlier is that all the system will operate very well from the mine to the shipping site. So, if we hit records on the railway, on the ground transportation, because we don't want to only do on railways, but we do also in trucks, so we transport more or less 83 million tons, we transport 83 million tons. You have to remember there is some market numbers out of the 87 million tons, not to forget that.</p>
          <p>And we replenish our inventories on the mine, on the port and on the sea to obtain the ramp-up of a month. So I think, yes, we could sell it, but as we've already mentioned, we just filled the &#x2013; the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (12:43) whatever, the channels of distribution in our system. So, the answer is yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, as far as credit is concerned, for sure there is a kind of credit crunch in China now because customers are having problems to get finance based on the inventories. They only get credit based on invoice. So, this is creating a lot of pressure in this site. But for the time being, for our big customers on their contract there, we don't have any kind of problem as far as credit is concerned, but we see that one of the reasons the spot price is going down is because of that, because the traders are also suffering this situation. So, they came up raising money based on the inventories they keep.</p>
          <p>So, instead of buying and keeping in the stock to get better price, they are on the other way selling it in order to get money and pay back their former credit lines. So, that's the situation that is developing in China. I think it's a big part of the decrease in iron ore prices caused by this. But we also have <mark type="indiscernible" /> (14:08) signals that some &#x2013; loosening and the monetary policy is coming because many sectors are suffering and Chinese authorities already they made some speech talking about some &#x2013; specifically loosening of their monetary policy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our next question comes from Mr. Alex Hacking from Citigroup &#x2013; Citibank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks for taking my question and congratulations on the record iron ore production. I have two questions. First, the 40 million ton expansion at Caraj&#xE1;s, is Vale still expecting to deliver this project next year? And if not, then when should we expect to see this project? And then second question would be regarding iron ore prices. Do you think it's sustainable long-term to have two different pricing systems, one for Europe and Japan and then different for China, or does this create some frictions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Alex. Eduardo Ledsham speaking. Regarding your first question, right, the project <mark type="indiscernible" /> (15:28) it's on time, on budget. So, the expectation is to start the production in the third quarter of next year, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, here is Martins speaking. As far as the second question, I would say that I think the last word on this would be given by <mark type="ph" /> customers (15:52). So, they needed to know if they want some predictability or some stability in price. We are prepared to work in a quarterly basis, like we did. But the answer will be given by them. We are going to accept what the market and our customers decide. I think this question couldn't be better put if the question is put to our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Rodolfo De Angele from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I want to ask two questions. First, on this migration towards a more export without the lag, is there a date for clients who are deciding on moving to that spot today that do obviously have the benefit of the lower pricing on the spot versus the quarter right now? So, how is that happening? Is there any is Vale doing any agreements on the volume side to compensate for the $20 or $30 a ton that these clients may be getting? So, is there any condition <mark type="indiscernible" /> (17:15) that have been discussed with the client?</p>
          <p>And my second question is, despite &#x2013; we discussed and you mentioned the frequency of some traders buying iron ore, we still see the freight in &#x2013; we still see the freight rates quite strong into China? Is that a consequence of seeing volumes being diverted from Europe? Can you comment on that? That's all, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As far as your last question, some volumes are being diverted to China for sure, but not big volumes. We are talking about two or three additional ships per month. I think what's going on in the freight market is something very particular to the market. Probably more ore is going to China. I think in the last 15 days, we saw a 15% increase in volumes to China against last fortnight. So, this is not only &#x2013; you have many other suppliers send more volumes to China these days. So, this is the second part of the issue. One was, as I told you before, the credit situation in China. And the second is much more ore is going to China, not only these two, three additional vessels from Brazil, but also from other destinations.</p>
          <p>As far as the price system, what we are proposing to our customers is, if they want to go for a more, I would say liquid price according to the market situation today, they need at least to keep their volumes, okay. So, this is not a discount. We have some conditions for it. And also they have the opportunity to reduce their volumes if they want, but then they have to buy on a spot basis. And they can lose their contracts, okay?</p>
          <p>If the customers want to work completely on a spot basis, they can take this decision. But no contractual obligations any more from both parts. So it's not a free ride, okay. It's something that both parties have to think and to look what is better long term. We're trying to avoid the opportunistic situations. When we implemented the quarterly price, we lag behind the export for two quarters. And now, the spot is going below the quarterly price. And if the customers want to move, there is a price for it. So, we are not giving up this situation and for nothing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Rene Kleyweg from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen and congratulations on the production-based numbers. Just a &#x2013; would you be able to provide a little bit more color on the cost pressures and how much of the cost increase for the quarter comes from the seasonal effects of the high production rates? Whether there's any impact on higher freight rates on your cost structure? I know most of your freights is tied up in long-term contracts. But whether there's any impact from that? And how much of the increase do you think is structural changes just from cost pressures in the industry as a whole? And the second question is, if you could just provide a little bit more color regarding Onca Puma in terms of the production schedule for the next couple of years at Onca Puma in terms of production volumes? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Rene. It's Guilherme. As I mentioned before, our cost of goods sold included 9% and two-thirds of this increase was regarding volume as you mentioned. The difference that was not regarding to volume was mainly gas and energy, which is adjusted by inflation and materials. Therefore, we don't expect that this is seasonally. This is in fact a structural change in terms of parts going forward. It's worth mentioning that the high demands, the high investments in the mining sectors that is causing this material price increase. Okay. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (22:23).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may add. I would like to comment that cost pressures are simply the flip side of strong demand for minerals and metals. In response to this strong demand, mining companies are operating at full capacity. This is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (22:43), an all-time high investment here in mining, so there is a strong pressure on all resource, labor, raw materials, equipment, spare parts and engineering service.</p>
          <p>In place of this, one should expect a higher cost. The key issue is marginal revenues are above marginal cost and so far, we managed to have marginal revenues much higher than marginal cost and as you can see, our margins had been kept at very high level. Our cash flow has been increasing. This is the key issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as far as &#x2013; Martins speaking &#x2013; as far as freight is concerned, our revenues is FOB. So, when we sell CNF, we deduct freight cost from revenues. So, we don't have any influence to operate on our cost of goods sold so the freight is deducted from revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eduardo Ledsham speaking. Regarding your question about On&#xE7;a Puma. So, the start-up was in March this year and the full capacity of the first line, it will be achieved at the end of 2012. The second line, the start-up would be at the June of &#x2013; the middle of next year and the full capacity will be achieved at the end of 2013. The full capacity of both lines is 56,000 tons per year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our next question comes from Mr. Tony Rizzuto from Dahlman Rose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Hi, folks. Two questions. One on Serra Sul, could you please give us an update on the timing of the project in light of the recent reports about the deposits sitting near or on top of an archaeological site? And second, if you could comment as to domestic iron ore production in China given the sharp fall in pricing? Are you seeing signs that there will be production curtailments of iron ore in China? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Vania speaking. About the Serra Sul project, we are very confident that we are going to have the necessary permits by the beginning of the next year. We are just analyzing the last environmental studies that was &#x2013; some new requirements from the environmental agents, and we are going to send this to them by the end of this month and we are confident that everything is okay now. And we expect to have the license by the beginning of new year. We don't expect to have any problems. We're seeing some of the studies regarding this case that were considered in the nearby of the project. And we don't think that this is going to be a real problem for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the cash cost in China, what we have learned &#x2013; that at least 120 million tons, they are working with some loss. We are not able to convey so many details, but what we have learned, that at the level of yesterday a $128, they have this number that it probably will be out of the market in the next coming weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Jon Brandt from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Good afternoon. Thank you so much for taking my call. I just wanted to try and understand a little bit about the shifts of sales volumes to China. It seems like what you're saying is that on the margin, you're sending more to China, but you're not expecting to have the same proportion as you did in 2009 during the last slowdown. If you could just confirm that? And also I'm curious about the demand coming from Europe and Brazil, if you're seeing cancelled orders or delayed contracts or anything like that, that'd be much appreciated. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I mentioned, there is not too many volumes going from Europe, from Brazil to China. In our case it's only two or three ships only. The increasing volumes we are sending to China is due to better production performance in that we are having now. So Europe market is really a lot of concerns, more than production cut in this point in time. So, we see a lot of concerns with our customers.</p>
          <p>Everybody is talking about cutting, reducing production, but for the time being we don't have too many. In Brazilian market, there is a kind of similar situation because some of our customers are producing their own ore. So, they are developing their mine, so they are preparing to use their own mine. And the Brazilian market is not doing so strong now. So, this combination, as I told you is putting us in a situation that we have to send two or three additional vessels to &#x2013; per month to China. And the remaining is based on the increasing production that we are having. So that's the situation nowadays.</p>
          <p>I don't believe that the European market has space to go down so much as it did in the last crisis. Only to give you a figure, we are used to send to Europe normally, before the 2008 crisis, around 7 million tons per month. And during the 2008 crisis, we went down to 0.5 million tons in a month. So the market almost disappeared. So, the quantity that we had to send to China at that time, it was much, much bigger than today. And I don't believe that Europe has to &#x2013; I don't believe the steel production in Europe has too much space to go down. Even in the best months after crisis, Europe is working around 15% below former crisis. So, you don't have it too many inventories in the system so I think today the situation is completely different. So I don't believe we needed to divert too much volume from Europe or from Brazil to China. That's the situation as we see it today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Mr. Sunil Dapshadar (30:36) from Sentinel Investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I guess you spoke about &#x2013; you had a record production volume of 87 million tons this quarter of iron ore. Does that say that you're trying to flood the Chinese market or create inventory out there that may also push the prices down? Or you think that the demand from China is &#x2013; for iron ore will remain strong, the steel production is going to be robust given where they are? The concerns of China are steel production may just grow modestly in 2012. So, can you just give some kind of color on this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think we need to put it in a different perspective. Chinese market for, I don't know, is 1 billion ton per year and our deliveries to China normally is around 120 million, 130 million tons. So, we are talking about 12% and 13% in market share only. So I don't believe 1% or 2% more could create such a mass in the market.</p>
          <p>So, if you are looking for the reasons that the spot market in China is going down, I think you have to look at other reasons, mainly the credit situation and also some production increase in Australia. Australia is much closer to China than Brazil. It takes 45 days for our ship from Brazil to reach China. So some of the additional ships that we send to China didn't arrive yet there but from Australia it's 10 days. So when you have a production increase in Australia immediately, you feel it in China.</p>
          <p>So, I think we have to look at other reasons for this spot price. I don't believe with the 12% and 13% ore that we send to China. I think the best products of ore which is the correct ore we normally say. So we are not really working this mass market, which is a local ore and Australian ore. We are working on a different turf and we don't believe that we are causing &#x2013; Vale ore is a reason for this situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our next question comes from Mr. Andy Mohan from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen. Good morning. Just a couple of questions please. Can you just tell us where you are on your copper strategy? Are you still &#x2013; do you still see a million tons of copper over the next four or five years?</p>
          <p>Do you think organically you have enough to get there? Secondly, on your steel projects can you give us an update please on where those projects are? And if we just look at systems and the experience they have, do you see these projects are earning their cost of capital back or is this I guess, the question is, are these solely politically driven or do you still see any business logic behind the steel projects? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Andy. Murilo speaking. Regarding copper, our idea is to announce our strategic plan in our budget on November 28. Then I think that we are just finalizing everything to announce to the investors. Regarding the fuel, we are in a very advanced stage with our project in Sierra. It's going very well. I think that with a huge motivation of Posco and Dongkuk. I think that you are trying to push them in order to be here in Brazil.</p>
          <p>It's critical for us to sell much more iron ore in Brazil. We had in the past, 7% of the markets. Today, it's 50% going to 29% 2014. And what &#x2013; we needed to sell much more iron ore in Brazil as we used to be. And the most important is that in the beginning, we will have 50% of the project, but later on we'll be reduced to 20%. For sure, Posco and Dongkuk, they have a leading position and they are very interested to supply the Brazilian market and around. Thank you very much for your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our next question comes from Mr. Leonardo Correa from Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Thank you. My first question is regarding this new project. I understand the discussions with the Guinean government are now underway. So, can you please provide just an update on how those are progressing? I mean we saw the deal that we're looking for structured with the government and the government took a free carry. So, just to try to understand what Vale strategy will be there and if you are at this stage contemplating buying out the minorities at this project, like 49% minority stake that this project holds. That's my first question.</p>
          <p>The second question for you Martins. Just given the volatility and spot prices as you mentioned these prices tend to under and overshoot. We saw three big corrections since 2008. In this type of market, would it make more sense to Vale to start getting into derivative contracts to try to lock in future iron ore prices? I mean would Vale be willing to change its strategy into derivative markets to contemplate for this higher volatility? Those are my two questions please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Murilo speaking. Good morning. I think that right after the approval of the new mining law in September 9, 2011 in Guinea, we have decided internally to work in order to understand, to have a full assessment of the costs and risks involved in the project. I think that it's very early because as I said, it was on September 9, and we will have a conclusion of the economics of the projects under the new conditions in order to disclose to the market. By the way, you are not sure that the law will stay as is, because they have 60 days to be enforced. Eventually considering some comments by the market, they can change again. But regardless of this, what we intended to do is to go to the public, to go to the investor as soon as possible. But first of all, we needed to conclude our homework regarding the new mining law.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martins speaking. As far as the second question, we believe that the market is becoming more liquid. No doubt about it. So, we move from one year price system to three-month price system and many customers are looking for something even in a more, I would say, at-site basis. But it's difficult for it to make us abandon long-term contract because if you have to &#x2013; a black furnace is something that you cannot stop easily. So, you cannot rely in export price &#x2013; in export supply for it, so people need long-term contract. How to accommodate long-term contract with spot price or more liquid prices is the big question, okay.</p>
          <p>Europeans and Japanese producers and even some big Chinese producers, they don't like to see this market too liquid. So, they prefer to have a market that you don't have such a financial liquidity that non-suppliers and non-consumers could participate on it. They prefer to have a market where suppliers and consumers work together. So &#x2013; but as time is going by, we see that the importance of those markets is decreasing because Chinese market is growing. You have other markets growing.</p>
          <p>So, I think the trend for a more liquid price is unavoidable. How long you'll last to get there is the question? Even if you look on the supply side, perhaps some suppliers that are looking for something more liquid and you'll look some suppliers that are not so eager to move in this direction. But we needed to look reality and you'll see all the commodities, all the materials that are trading in the world and you see that as time goes by, it becomes more and more liquid.</p>
          <p>The timeframe for that is difficult to say. I think it will depend on customer's behavior. I think the answer for this question is more on the customer side than on the supply side. We are prepared to work in both environments. We know how to work in one way or another and we are prepared to work in both environments, but it takes two to tango, okay? It's not something that we want to do alone. I think we need a customer support space with us.</p>
          <p>I think the process is moving. I think every situation like that there is a lot of discussions and a lot of I would say things to learn in this process. It's a learning process and I think the market is moving and all of the participants are moving, but long-term I believe more liquidity will come to the iron ore pricing system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. <mark type="ph" /> Renato Antunes from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:36).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good afternoon, everyone. Thanks for taking my question. The first question to Martins. You talked a lot about traders destocking due to China credit conditions and I just wanted to hear your views on how is your assessment on inventory levels at the steel mills? I mean have you seen Chinese steel mills destocking over the past weeks? And do you have actually patience for potential restocking ahead of the winter and rainy season and consequently lower supply? So that's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is related to the base metals performance during the quarter. We're seeing a very significant volumes increase and I just wanted to get a better sense on how should we expect both nickel and copper volumes to behave over the following periods? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as &#x2013; Murilo speaking. As far as iron ore, the information we have, there is not too many inventories in the mills. I think the big part of the inventories are now in the port side and a bigger part of this belongs to traders, okay. So, not only because of the credit situation, but also because of traders are looking price going down so they try to get rid of their inventories also. So both situations, credit and decreasing pricing is creating an overshooting situation because everybody that has inventory is willing to get rid of it. So, that's the situation.</p>
          <p>As far as supply, now we are entering the winter in China and the local mining production will be down because of the winter and also you'll be down because of the price. Also we are entering in the raining season, so by end of this year, beginning of the next, we're entering the raining season in Brazil, the cyclone season in Australia, so normally, from fourth quarter &#x2013; from third quarter on, production is starting to decrease in Brazil, in Australia and also in China. So, that will bring some, I would say, a reduction in supply in this period. And we hope that we'll be together with some loosening of the monetary policy in China.</p>
          <p>So, I see a good prospect going forward. I think we are facing a V-shaped situation, a very deep decrease in price, but we also see the price coming back very fast. I wonder if you go back to the same level as it was, but I clearly see that the price has to go up, otherwise too many supply will be taking out of the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Regarding the base metals questions, I would like you to turn to Page 29 on our presentation. It's worth mentioning that different from 2008 when the base &#x2013; when the nickel prices went down together with the higher inventories, this time we saw a decrease in nickel prices, but the inventories are very low, so the lower inventories keep us optimistic about going forward, the nickel prices, also because we see that the substitution that we see from nickel pig iron to the nickel material in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o, from Ita&#xFA; BBA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Good afternoon, everybody. My first question is regarding our views, if you could share with us your views on China &#x2013; Chinese and Indian steel production in 2012? And the second question on iron ore prices, like on a stress scenario, what could go wrong for us to see iron ore prices actually declining and not bottoming as Martins is saying, as you have been saying for a couple of times in this call. What could be the risks for prices to go down to let's say $100 per ton? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's look at my crystal ball here. But we do not see big changes in the process of urbanization in China and India. So, steel production continues to grow in India for sure. In China, it will depend of this &#x2013; the loosening of the monetary policy, but I do not see Chinese steel production growing less than 5% next year against this year. So, when you compare the situation in the western world, you have a structural problem, okay. Population is not growing. Urbanization is completed.</p>
          <p>When you look at Asia you will see the opposite. They have a lot of urbanization to happen and they need a lot of infrastructure to build. So, it's a completely different situation and we do not see this changing. If you go to China, you go to India, you go to Indonesia, you go to those Asian countries, you see everyday people moving from the countryside to the cities, people moving from agricultural areas to industrial areas and you'll see people that were leaving to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (47:40) economy and moving to a market economy.</p>
          <p>So, you do not see changes. It's a structural movement and there is a lot of space for growth. So, we are pretty confident that this process will continue and will keep steel production going up and also you'll keep iron ore needs increasing. So, that's our view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our next question comes from Mr. Rodrigo Barros from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, thank you for taking my questions. Actually two quick questions. First, we have next year 36 million tons of additional crude capacity in China for next year and 33 million tons for 2013. I would like to see if those numbers are <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:34) what Martins has? And my second strategy on this potential, this shape of recovery, one thing that I'm thinking here is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:45) collapse, if it would make sense for some traders to restore iron ore on the water, just pay the time charter and buy iron ore at 100 weights  it actually comes to 130, 140 and salvageable much later. Do you think that could be a factor in this shape your recovery? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you please repeat your first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The first one is on the additional crude that you supply in China. We net 36 million tons of new blast furnace capacity in 2012 and 33 million tons in 2013. So my question is, is that in line with values on estimates, if you could give us some color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, about the second question, what I see is to keep the iron ore floating is a question of freight costs, okay. So because you have, everyday you keep the iron ore in a ship, it costs you money. So, I don't believe that will happen. I think the inventories in the Chinese ports has to <mark type="inaudible" /> (50:07) before the traders come back to the market. And they needed to see some change in the price direction.</p>
          <p>Nowadays, they're only buying on opportunistic way. So, they are trying to get the best deal that they are sure that they cannot lose money tomorrow. So, the market is completely, I would say, dead in China for traders in this moment. But I really believe that this change will move forward. Until the end of the year, we are going to have some movement. Because as I told you before, many ore will be taken out of the market. It is not immediate because you have a lot of ore arriving from different places and also you have some inventories in the local mines, so those inventories have to be depleted.</p>
          <p>So if you take maybe one or two months to get this done, and then the price will start to increase again. As far as steel production in China, they are always investing and they are always talking about reducing the small blast furnace. They continue to have a lot of small blast furnace to eliminate so big part of the additional capacity is in order to eliminate this small blast furnace. Long-term we see steel production in China growing in the range of 5% and 7% so we do not see their growth below that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Rodrigo. Regarding your second question, in general terms we think that one of the roles of financial markets is to overshoot the ton issue price, typical in the case for mining equities and commodity price. We have seen markets pricing a big section into our shares and also as Guilherme mentioned, in the case of base metals, we are seeing a substantial decrease in nickel price followed by a substantial decrease in stocks. It seems that it's out of sync with the reality of this market. This thing happens to the iron ore market. What we are producing, we are selling.</p>
          <p>So, it seems that there was also among the shooting in iron ore price as was very well discovered by Martins, the fundamentals remain intact. There was no change in the main fundamentals. The supply side, we had seen some season increase in Brazilian, Austrailian and production. Now an increase in Indian exports to the end of the monsoon season, but it would be followed by another seasonal effect, this time on the negative side because there will be the cyclone season in Australia, the rainy season in Brazil, winter in China.</p>
          <p>So, there will be a decrease in iron ore production and supply. So, it's fair to assume that there'll be a recovery in iron ore price. For how much? Nobody knows. It's a $1 billion question. But it seems that there will be &#x2013; it's very likely that there will be a recovery in iron ore price from the current levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's question-and-answer session. Mr. Murilo, at this time you may proceed with your closing statement, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for your time. Again, we are very happy to see a new record in terms of production. We are very excited and working very hard in terms of our projects in order to deliver on time, on budget and I hope to see you soon in the end of November in New York. Thank you very much. Have a nice day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>This does conclude our conference call third quarter 2011 results. Thank you very much for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>