<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1281748" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2481</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Fabio Barbosa, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jos&#xE9; Carlos Martins, Executive Director of Ferrous Minerals</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Felipe Hirai</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Eduardo de Salles Bartolomeo</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Carlos de Alba</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Victoria Santaella</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Ivan Fadel</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Leonardo Correa</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by and welcome to Vale's conference call to discuss 2009 results. If you do not have a copy of the relevant press release, it is available at the company's website at www.vale.com at the Investors link.</p>
          <p>At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions to participate will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>As a reminder, this conference is being recorded. To access the replay, please dial 5511-4688-6312 access code 45838. Again, 45838. The file will also be available at the company's website at www.vale.com at the investor section.</p>
          <p>This conference call and the slide presentation are being transmitted via Internet as well. You can access the webcast by logging onto the company's website, www.vale.com, investor section or at www.prnewswire.com.br.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Actual performance could differ materially from that anticipated in any forward-looking comments as a result of macroeconomic conditions, market risks and other factors.</p>
          <p>With us today are Mr. Fabio Barbosa, Chief Financial Officer; Mr. Jos&#xE9; Carlos Martins, Executive Officer for Ferrous Minerals; and Mr. Eduardo Bartolomeo, Executive Officer for Logistics, Project Management and Sustainability. First, Mr. Barbosa will proceed to the presentation and after that we will open for question and answers.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to turn the call over to Mr. Barbosa. Please, sir, you may now begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you very much for attending this conference call in which we are going to discuss our 2009 results and the perspectives for 2010.</p>
          <p>Of course, as well we should have in mind that 2009 was a special year in the sense that we observed something that we hadn't observed for let's say several decades. It was a very unique situation that caused a unique approach and I would say a unique set of results considering the previous trends that we observed in our sector and in our company.</p>
          <p>So it was a very challenging year, but we believe that considering the environment that we faced and the nature of our exposure to this global recession that Vale out of the major producers, minerals and metals producers, was the most exposed in a global fashion. We believe that we performed in a very reasonable way.</p>
          <p>In 2009 our EBITDA fell to $9.2 billion roughly and our net earnings as well showed a reduction from 13 to $5.3 billion. Despite what the number shows, it's important to stress that we implemented a lot of measures to cope with the recession that prevailed in 2009 and one of the few episodes of global recession in the last 100 years.</p>
          <p>And so we had to adopt ferrous structure metals in order to reach a linear structure and to be more efficient in the long term. Some results are there, but I would say that a lot of results you'll see over time as we move back to full capitalization as we expect this year.</p>
          <p>So we restructured our corporate activities and was a sharp reduction in the cost of the center and about 10% in 2009 compared to 2008, we stayed there about $40 million. The restructuring of the nickel business, it's something that we managed to achieve this year with across the board cost reduction of three to 5%.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we improved processes in our shared centers with the implementation of our global presence in this function. We have fostered innovation. In the last quarter we asked our employees to present their ideas and the result was about 7,000 ideas to improve operations in our company.</p>
          <p>So it's a lot of material to work with and we hope to deliver some results associated with that. And also we are working hard as we're a bulk producer, bulk product producer, we are trying to optimize our logistics efficiency and we have very nice results to show, as the MKBF shows there, which increased an average of 22.5% in the last five years ended in 2009.</p>
          <p>So it's a lot of structural matter that are being adopted with the aim of getting to a much better, much more efficient cost structure in the long term. Of course we observed our results in the fourth quarter and one cannot deny that it had some issues related to cost. Some of them were related to the depreciation of the inflection rate, as you may appreciate. And others or one-offs and others related to the recovery of our production to more normal levels.</p>
          <p>On the one-off items I would mention the tax contingency that we caught in the fourth quarter, that represented a savings for our company in the long-term of about $100 million, but we had to invest $110 million in dealing with this contingency as we are geared to a special amnesty program here. So we also promoted write-offs related to assets like Valesul, $85 million, but again, thermal plant, $70 million and corporate Valepar, a project in Canada that we also associated a $35 million charge to this project.</p>
          <p>And finally, we had labor agreement in the end of 2009 that represented a one-off payment of $35 million to our employees on the top of the 7% nominal increase that we observed in both November and December and also the <mark type="inaudible" />. So it is a set of elements that helps to explain the increase in cost that we observed in the fourth quarter, some of a one-off nature, some related to the exchange rate depreciation, but of course we have to work hard on that.</p>
          <p>We are not happy with the result, although we made a lot of progress. Part of the costs are associated with, as I said, the resumption of normal levels of production and we believe that we'll be able to deliver better actual results as we move on during the year of 2010.</p>
          <p>Turning to the sales, I would like to highlight the remarkable achievement of increasing our iron ore sales to China to 140 million tons, a record in our books and an example of our ability to go through a very different scenario that we faced in beginning in 2009. If you recall, we were fully exposed to a market that had reversed completely from the usual way of operating.</p>
          <p>Instead of the FOB market, we faced with a market that was mostly operating on a net basis and we are fully, almost fully exposed to freight rates and a very volatile environment. And we managed to, through a very dramatic and objective marketing policy, we managed to reach a new record in sales to this very important country in our sector.</p>
          <p>Well as we announced, we continue to believe that is a very positive perspective for the sector. I mean in metals and we, particularly in Vale, believe we have the best pipeline of projects in the industry. So in this connection we are investing $12.7 billion this year compared to 10 billion last year and 11 billion 2007.</p>
          <p>So it's a $12.9 billion. And in 2009, we also invested $12.7 billion if you put together the acquisition. So in total, we are taking about in four years' time, something around $50 billion in investments, showing our commitment and our positive view about the long-term performance of the industry.</p>
          <p>So it's a very important commitment that we have and it should continue. We have seven new projects coming on stream in 2010. Iron ore, we have the Caraj&#xE1;s, the additional 10, but this is the only project that you see in the ground before 2012, right, Martin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have the pellet sizing plant of Oman that will use our pellet feed. And in nickel, On&#xE7;a Puma, the first line will start in middle of the year. Tres Valles project in Chile with 15,000 tons of copper. Bay&#xF3;var, 3.9 million tons of phosphate rock that will start passing the middle of the year. And the power plants of Estreito and steel plant of CSA, in which we have a share of 26.87%, we have invested more money last year. So it's, again, a demonstration of our confidence in the performance of this sector.</p>
          <p>As for Goro, I'd like to inform you that we had a successful first half in the ramp up. Our first campaign of HPAL produced 18 metric tons of nickel in MHP. It's a good start.</p>
          <p>The autoclave was &#x2013; diesel impact was, there was no issue. It was a very smooth campaign. And now we are cooling the equipment in order to allow for the start of a new campaign, a three-week campaign, in the process of ramp up. This is a long process, but so far is going extremely well we noted.</p>
          <p>Coming to our perspective about the markets, we perceive the global demand, we put that into the title, gaining momentum. The global manufacturing output is in a clear recovery path, of course, with the impressive lead of the emerging market economies, but also with some contribution of the developed world by people in the U.S and Australia. Japan and Europe at a slower pace. So we see clearly a recovery on the ground and this is very good news for us, as the global industrial production is the main driver of demand for our materials.</p>
          <p>The global PMI reached the highest level since June '06, as we put there, and the ratio of new orders to inventory is also showing a positive indication about the future. So we are enhancing our perspectives of future sales on a worldwide basis.</p>
          <p>The global carbon steel output is recovering steadily, although with some discrepancies between what used to be in 2008 and what we have now. It's slightly below the peak level in July '07, July '08, but it's very close. We are talking about 1.2 billion tons of steel being produced in the world.</p>
          <p>So it's a very different position from the one that we had in January '09, when we were running at a 900 million ton production rate annually. And this is a global recovery, with more speed in some countries like China and less speed in others, but the fact is that the demand for raw materials increased sharply, particularly in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>And at the same time what we see is potential lower contribution of our important supply to the feed bond, which is India. And we show there that there's a steady decline in their share in the India and Chinese imports of iron ore and this is showing what we have been flagging for some time now that India most likely will have to address their own demand internally in the long term, considering their population and the demand potential for steel products in their country.</p>
          <p>So what we see today is a global iron ore market that is clearly showing an excess of demand and a clear supply constraint. We had operational issues in the fourth quarter that we were a little bit short of what we planned to sell in the market, to the market and we were not able to show, to address those operational issues.</p>
          <p>But clearly what is preventing us from selling today are our own issues because the market is there, is very strongly demanding more material than we are able to ship. And this is clearly shown by the spot prices that you can see in Chart 16. So it's a very strong market, it was choked in our view, it's choked supply constraint.</p>
          <p>The global stainless steel production declined in 2009, again for the third year in a row. The last time it happened a similar trend was in the three-year period ended in 1993. So in our view there is limited room for further decline.</p>
          <p>Actually as we see the recovery in the developed world, although at a slower pace, we should see some additional momentum to the demand of this material that combined with the demand from emerging market economies should provide for a stronger market for nickel in the medium to long term.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we are producing, we are resuming production at February and we are operating the mines of Coleman, Garson and Creighton. The Clarabelle mill is already back to operation, Copper Cliff smelter is operating. The first shipment of feed to Clydach happened this month. So we are positive about the perspectives of resuming standard normal levels of operations in our Canadian operations sooner rather than later.</p>
          <p>Finally, a word on our newest investment and just after the 9th we announced the conclusion of the negotiations with Mosaic and with that Vale is now &#x2013; is going to be when the deal is fully closed is going to be the owner of Fosfertil shares and also Bunge upstream fertilizer assets. So this is a major investment considering what we have in our pipeline and what we are paying for the assets, but the rationale for us allocating money to this business is virtually the same, that we have to invest in other minerals and metals as the drivers are very similar.</p>
          <p>And in our case and our perception is that the rapid cut on income growth of emerging market economies will have a very important effect on the demand for proteins and crop nutrients. So we believe that there should be, as we observed in the minerals and metals in general, a structural shift in demand for this materials and, again, in our perception there is a limited supply of those.</p>
          <p>There is also the impact of the increasing share of bio fuels as a source of energy considering the concerns about climate change. So this should force a further demand for this material. Emerging Asia and Brazil, as we put there, are the main sources of demand for fertilizer.</p>
          <p>So the strategic position that we are taking in Brazil is it's very important because together with our logistics this should allow us to grab more synergies and to be more efficient and combined also with our other projects that we have in India, Americas and other continents we should be able to become one of the top players in this segment.</p>
          <p>Brazil is a very solid platform for growth in this business, as we put there. Today it has a share in the total consumption of phosphates and potash at nine and 15%, respectively. This should grow in 10 years to 13.5 to 18%, respectively, again. So it is a very promising market by itself and we have a very good position when we combine this whole set of projects that we are developing or we're about to implement, particularly after this transaction.</p>
          <p>As you can see in Page 23, we have the Regina project in Canada. All the concessions in Canada there combined should allow us to reach a production of 5.2 million tons. We have Taquari-Vassouras, of potash, Taquari-Vassouras isn't under production right now, but we have there, we have Carnalita with a potential production of 1.2 million tons of potash.</p>
          <p>Neuqu&#xE9;n, an old project that we have in our pipeline, one million tons of potash as well. Rio Colorado, the project that we bought from Neuqu&#xE9;n together with the Regina project, 4.35 million tons of potential production when fully implemented. And in phosphate we have Bayovar in two stages that should allow us to reach about six million tons of phosphate rock, plus Evate project in Mozambique that if fully feasible we may be able to produce up to two million tons of phosphate rock as well. It's a very, very broad-based pipeline of projects that should allow us to compete in a very efficient way in this market.</p>
          <p>So the acquisition of Bunge assets and Fosfertil, it's very much in line with the strategy. So the combined assets have proven and probable reserves of 1.5 billion metric tons of phosphoric rock and phosphates and the production capacity of five million tons of phosphate rock and with the project Salitre that we are able to produce about two million tons per year when fully implemented.</p>
          <p>And was not fully developed because the differences of point of view between shareholders in phosphate deal. So now as we control the company we should be able to implement this project smoothly.</p>
          <p>And the end of the day we are acquiring a market share of 36% of Brazilian consumption of phosphate nutrient. So it's a very interesting transaction and that should allow us to position Vale as one of the top players in the fertilizer business worldwide.</p>
          <p>So we are investing in potash and phosphates, leveraging on our strong mining competencies. So we are actually in the mining business in our view and we operate in the upstream and we have no interest to go to the nitrogen set of product, our focus will be on phosphate rock and potash as we put there in Chart 25.</p>
          <p>So Vale has a very strong track record in operation of fertilizers with the Taquari-Vassouras, it's something that we operate for &#x2013; operation that we have for 18 years now. It's a very successful operation.</p>
          <p>And also then by other projects that we are implementing in Peru is one of the most cost efficient projects we have in the industry. So we are not newcomers to this business and we understand mining business. So we believe that we are increasing Vale's exposure to this very good momentum, as sponsored by the growth of the emerging market economy.</p>
          <p>And finally, our view about the future where we're going to be in indeed seven to eight years time, the idea is that we'll have in the production of phosphates have phosphoric acid at 2.3 million tons per year and a total production of potash of 10.7 million tons per year. That should allow us to be one of the top players in this segment by that time.</p>
          <p>Now those are my initial comments. We would like to have your views and comments in the Q&amp;A session. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Mr. Felipe Hirai from Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, everyone. I have two questions, the first one is if you could give us an update on the iron ore price negotiations and your strategy in the market going forward? One of your competitors suggested yesterday that the starting point of the negotiation should be the spot price at a 90% premature benchmark. And also given the spot premium I would like to know how do you expect actually to see your sales in the benchmark and the spot market in 2010? And my second question, Fabio, would be on your cost side, could you help us understand what happened to your costs in the fourth quarter because they were way above what we were expecting. Is there anything on these costs that was non-recurrent that we should expect because you come down in the first quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will ask Martins to answer the first question and then I'll come back to your last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Felipe and good morning and good afternoon, everybody. Last year was a year of big challenge for iron ore business. The very nature of the crisis affected particularly the Western world, put Vale and our business in a very difficult position because our main customers stopped buying. So we immediately feel the very fact that we couldn't keep producing and shipping it's because customers didn't send the vessels. And the market that was buying, which was China, it stopped buying because the customers decided to look to buy differently instead of fulfilling their contractual obligations. So the very nature of our business, which was supported by long-term contracts, FOB sales and benchmark pricing, was jeopardized. So we had to respond very quickly to that and recently we started shipping ore without the customers outside the contract to sell in China on a spot basis. So we already starting working in such a spot basis scenario.</p>
          <p>So I think we are looking at long-term contracts differently now. We are completely free to work on CNF, CFR basis, not only FOB, but CFR basis. If customers don't send their vessels, we send ours. And so this means that we are prepared to work whatever the market decides is better, benchmark system or a spot basis. We have no &#x2013; we said that before we have no documents. So we are prepared to sell benchmark or a spot basis, whatever will be needed. Nowadays it's clear that spot now is twice the price of benchmarks. We are fulfilling our contractual obligations for a while, but we will expect that our customers understand that this big difference cannot be capped. Our benchmark is able to accommodate the spot market situation. We are not talking about a small market. Nowadays spot means almost 50% of the total sea-borne market and in China it's probably near 70% of the total Chinese iron ore market. So spot price is a reality, is a price that has to be looked at a market price today.</p>
          <p>So the situation is such that our customers will have to accept a different price system that takes into consideration what's going wrong in this huge spot market today. Or if it's not possible to reach an agreement based on a fixed price for near that takes into consideration these changes in the spot, the outcome probably will be that spot will be the price that we will be referred as far as I don't know a market is concerned. So that's the scenario that we see today. And Vale is now much better prepared to work in every &#x2013; in many different scenarios that could arise from this situation. So we made our homework. We have now a big fleet of vessels, we can sell CNF, we can sell spot, we can even sell freight if it was bid. So we have a very, very comfortable situation as far as price system, as far as the way the customers buy from now on. We hope that customers will be needing to understand what's going on. It's a completely different situation from the past where you have a very stable market and practically no spot market there. So as time it went by, spot market was growing and I think today spot market, spot price is the market price, that's our view so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as for your second question, Felipe, I believe that you mean the cost of goods sold, right? And so we &#x2013; what we had, first the appreciation of the real. And this was a very important impact. It explains some $186 million of the total increase of $400 million in this item. We have, of course, what we mentioned, the labor agreement that represented a one-off cost of $35 million, but it has a permanent increase of 7% in reais from November onwards for this item. We hired 1,000 new employees this last quarter. We have with this agreement an increase in the provision for profit sharing as we moved the salary base.</p>
          <p>We have some important works in maintenance in order to resume operations and this is an important part of the strategy across the accounts, but you see there in materials, spare parts, maintenance cost, outsourced services, you see a lot of work done to put back in operation the operations that were previously idle. So part of those are &#x2013; the current part of the expenses are permanent. We also have the acquisition of the improving energy costs. That represented some 15% of the total increasing COGS in the fourth quarter of '09.</p>
          <p>We have, though we had also to increase the acquisition of products from third parties. So we bought pellets from our Hispanobras operation, which is not consolidated under U.S. GAAP, so we put it back in operation as a result of a stronger market and this represented part of the costs. And we doubled, no we tripled, the acquisition of pellet, from 220 to 740,000 tons. And iron ore from third parties, in order to cope with our clients and the very strong demand and a very strong market that we have, we doubled our acquisition from 600,000 to 1.2 million tons of iron ore in the same quarter. So nickel, the same, nickel as we have part of our operations stopped.</p>
          <p>We also increased the acquisition of products by almost 50 million. We have some expenses related to balance sheet that, once we concluded the transaction, they will no longer be there, but we bought aluminum from third parties of $22 million in the fourth quarter of '09. Another element that I would like to ask, to invite Eduardo Bartolomeo to comment on that. Eduardo, are you on line? Eduardo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would be the moorage costs and the operation at the ports, we had a lot of &#x2013; or some operational issues that I'd like to invite Eduardo to comment, but at the end of the day, the moorage cost increased by $18 million in the fourth quarter associated, of course, with the very strong market and again we're seeing the resumption of operations, particularly in logistics, and the strength of the market. Eduardo, could you comment on that, on the cut down issue that you had in the port?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. Good afternoon, everybody. I think, first of all, as Martins said, we had a very, very strong and very difficult year. We started with one facing the year and we ended in another side. Just to have an idea, we increased 40% of our production. So it's a shift from stop and go very, very, very fast. So it's a &#x2013; we did an amazing job to get back on track and, of course, there are some back falls on that.</p>
          <p>So what Fabio is mentioning, about specifically the moorage, is something specific about Tubar&#xE3;o port around the issue that we had to change our ship loaders in the third and into the fourth quarter. When you look quarter-to-quarter basis, we lost 2.5 million tons in Tubar&#xE3;o due to the shift &#x2013; to the change of the ship loaders. So that view is non-recurrence, but it's a excellent view because we have now finished the project, so we gave Tubar&#xE3;o port a new &#x2013; it's already the most efficient port we have to operate even in the world, but it's actually a brand new port with five dumpers, the two ship loaders.</p>
          <p>So it's operating really well in the logistics side and it's ramping up this year as the fifth line of Luco coming on track, one of the levers of the project this year on the higher north side of the mine, it is going to operate very well. So we've got very good expectation about the port. But we could have offset that on the Ponta da Madeira port, they are a main port now. It's in the San Luis port and we had, as Fabio mentioned before, the issues on dumpers, big costs.</p>
          <p>We had implementation of the fourth dumper on November. That should increase a little bit of our capacity, but due to the wrapping up of the &#x2013; or maintenance problems, very, very specific problems that we had there, we weren't able to offset the losses we made in Tubar&#xE3;o that were planned, because we had already planned the project. So basically are those issues. When you look forward, I think we are getting in better shape.</p>
          <p>Of course, historically, we have the rainy season, we had a very strong rainy occurrence in Tubar&#xE3;o on the November. This month in Caraj&#xE1;s was the biggest rainfall we ever had there. But anyhow, we operated very well in the mine side, we stick to our budgets, we were able to stick to our budget on the shipping side. But of course, historically, different periods of dry season and the rainy season, but I think we're in very good shape for 2010. Fabio, that's all I have to comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Eduardo and thank you, Felipe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Fabio. Thanks, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our next question comes from Mr. Carlos de Alba from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, everyone. Thank you for taking the question. The first one is, is there, you are trying to restart the production in Sudbury to increasing volumes. Can we share a reference of how much volume you expect to be able to achieve with this strategy that you have put in place? That would be my first question. And my second question is, if Martins could comment on the expectations of the Chinese steel production this year and how much that market may be imported, of iron ore from the global producers? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Carlos, thank you for your questions. And as for Sudbury, we want to resume normal operation as soon as possible, and we are working for that and that's our idea. Of course, there are issues that we are working, but we have a very good start on the smelter and the mines. So the idea is to progressively reach normal production levels and, as I said, sooner rather than later. Martins, do you want to comment on the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. As far as China is concerned, last year their imports grew 40%, to 627 million tons of iron ore. 12 months finishing this January already moved to 640 million tons import. Every information we have from China, the indication is that steel production will continue to grow, not in the same pace as last year, but there will be a small growth this year. So I think that iron ore market, iron ore imports from China, will be at least 650 million tons this year, probably growing a little bit above that level.</p>
          <p>We have a situation to see, because the spot pricing in China grew a lot to now, today is around $130 per ton. So what will be impact of these prices on domestic production, so this information is not clear for us because, besides the high cost of local miners, you have some environmental constraints. And also the very fact that, after importing so much ore this year, many steel mills in China that were used to use the local ore are now more resilient to buy local ore again and they are keeping there one based on imported ore. But we don't see big changes from last year and if some change it happen, it will be for the upside we think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our next question comes from Ms. Victoria Santaella from Santander Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, gentlemen. I'm sorry to insist a little bit, but I would like to understand if the supply demand situation in iron ore is so strong right now and so tight, what is going to be your marketing strategy? Are you going to give more preference or push towards spot prices or continue more on the line of referral prices, as we have seen in the past, contract prices? And I guess this comes from the situation where we are seeing other competitors moving or trying to maximize prices, average prices and average revenues? That's my first question. And the second one is, if you can comment a little bit in terms of, how is the evolution of your transportation fleet, how are your cost, if there's anything to be mentioned there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please, could you address and, Eduardo, if you could help us as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as far as the price system, Vale always keeps its policy of selling on benchmark basis, but we believe that you cannot keep such a huge difference between spot and benchmark. So our view is, if our customers want to keep a benchmark, they have to accept something first closer to the level of spot today. And secondly, some choices that keep some kind of flexibility on the pricing system, because we cannot live with a difference like that. This difference raises a lot of arbitrage in the system, everybody is trying to buy on a benchmark basis to sell on a spot basis.</p>
          <p>So it's really a mess to manage our situation with such a big difference between the spot and the benchmark. Another issue is that today, spot is a bigger market than benchmark. More iron ore is being sold today on spot base than in benchmark basis, so we stick with the benchmark system. But, on the other hand, we needed to have some kind of flexibility to accommodate this situation created by this huge and very dynamic spot market.</p>
          <p>Only to give you an idea, since the crisis started up to June last year, the spot price was below benchmark and attract a lot of customers to buy in this market. Since June, the price moved to the same level to the benchmark and it stayed there for three months at least. And from October on last year, it starts moving, spot above benchmark. So this change was a very dynamic change, indicate us that we needed to have &#x2013; if you want to keep the benchmark, we needed to define our system that could have some kind of flexibility to cope with these variations. It's impossible to keep a business as usual with this so huge difference between spot and benchmark. That's our strategy. I think I'm clear about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Eduardo, would you like to comment on the fleet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Last year, I think there was a big window that was open to us about evolving the strategy to fulfill the needs of that in our business about the fleet. I think we went on and fixed very comfortable level of freights for 2010. We acquired 17 load ships, added to our three load ships we had already in our fleet. We are building around 20 and we have long-term contracts for the future also. So I think we're in a very comfortable position. There is no evolution on the cost because we fixed all the cost for 2010 and forward. Of course, 2011 is going to come owned the long term contracts for the big vessels, but for 2010, it was already fixed during 2009 on a &#x2013; as I said, in our window that was very good in a sense to guarantee a reposition cost for the ships. And I think that's basically the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to add something to what Eduardo said, our shipping strategy has two basic points. First, is to ship anything we produce, even if we don't have the customers, we are going to ship it. Second, is to keep a freight differential between Australia, Brazil to Asia as low as possible. So based on these two objectives, our fleet will have the size which it'll have it to be to reach this target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Martins, thank you, Eduardo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, gentlemen. Excuse me, our next question comes from Mr. Ivan Fadel from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thank you, everyone for the explanation so far. I would just like some details about the subjects that were already discussed. Number one, I understood from Martins and Fabio that the spot market for iron ore is even larger than the contract prices in China. My question would be then, what were the reasons behind Vale selling less in the CNF basis in the fourth quarter, 6.8 million compared to the third quarter? I understand it could be shipping issues or maybe more volumes were diverted to traditional markets, but I would just like to know the reasons behind this, or if we could see that number improving going forwards?</p>
          <p>And also my next question would be, if you could quantify, as of today, how much Vale could sell &#x2013;  if you use the whole capacity that you have for shipping, how much Vale could sell on a CNF basis in terms of volumes, in a given year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martins, could you address that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; I'm sorry to say that the size of our fleet is confidential information, okay? We don't release this kind of information. But what I can tell you is, during this crisis, we have to stop producing, because we didn't have a ship for our vessels &#x2013; for our ore. Customers didn't send the vessels and so we have to stop operations, because you cannot keep producing if you have no space. The best place to storage, I don't know or any mining product is in the mine, is in the pit. So to take from the pit and to put somewhere is not a good solution. So we understood by that, that we have to move from FOB to CNF according to the market situation. If the customers send their vessels, we sell FOB. If they don't send, we sell CNF.</p>
          <p>So we needed to have the flexibility to work CNF and FOB according to the market situation. And as I told you before, we have three legs in this iron ore market, which is long-term contracts, FOB and benchmark prices and these three things works together. So if customers didn't fulfill their obligation and they are LTC, it's clear that they are not sending their vessels and also, they are looking for a different price in the market. So the situation we're having today is not we are going to move from FOB to CNF, no. The situation we have today is, we're going to sell every ton that we produce and we will do it FOB or CNF according to the market, according to our customers. So that's the big difference.</p>
          <p>We had to stop production last year because there we cannot ship. Now we are in a condition to ship even if you have problems with the customers. So I wouldn't put our strategy as moving from FOB or to CNF. It's not our policy to make money in freight. Our policy is to make money in iron ore. So the ship is needed as a way to give us this flexibility. What are we looking for is full flexibility in price and shipping FOB or CNF and also long-term contract or completely spot, as need.</p>
          <p>As we told you before, we don't have documents. And I think as the crisis was &#x2013; teach us that we have it to be more flexible in our policy and that we needed to have all of these windows open to use it according to the market moment. For instance, nowadays, every customers are sending their vessels, because they want to get the ore at the benchmark price. So it's a completely different situation.</p>
          <p>So and Vale in all is better prepared. If you needed to ship more CNF because the customers are not buying, we are in condition to do it. But to make it possible and what makes this possible is the spot market in China. Nowadays, you have near 600 million tons of ore being sold every year in the spot market in China. So this is a opportunity for everybody that wants to ship its ore. So, our main target is not to have to constrain our production because we don't have a ship. So that's the main base of our products from now on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Leonardo Correa from Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. My first question is regarding the annual volumes outlook and the challenges you are encountering as you shift to full capacity. We've seen in the fourth quarter that you have some maintenance stoppages at Caraj&#xE1;s and also at Porta da Madera terminal, which Eduardo has just commented on. Can you please comment if on these issues have been concluded or should we expect some impact &#x2013; negative impact going forward during the upcoming quarters? That's the first question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eduardo and Martins, could you comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eduardo, I think you can comment and then I will comment later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the side of the logistics, as I said before, we had &#x2013; we have separated in two levels. First of all, its very ways they are perfectly capable for shipping, whatever plan we have next year, either on MRS that's not fully operated by us nor Vitorominos and Caraj&#xE1;s. So we have even the fleet for the upgrades, that's no big issue.</p>
          <p>Around the ports, as we mentioned before, we have good news around Tubar&#xE3;o, that we finished the overhaul of Tubar&#xE3;o. It's an incredible project that enhanced capacity also, it's in &#x2013; so we are able to see the increase of production that is going to be happening, as Martins said in the beginning, around the margin, and he can comment a little bit later.</p>
          <p>We have issues around the Porta da Madera. The dumper, as I said, the fourth dumper was implemented on November, it is ramping up. It's operating very well so far, this month is going very fine. And I think we are overcoming the problems, naturally as we do the right thing, that is to do the right manners at the right time and I don't believe that will be a big issue on the quarters to come. Anyway, anyhow, so far we are facing a tough time for mining. This is the rainy season for everybody, for the railway, for the ports and for the mines, but it's not an issue to not start to fill our guideline to produce, from the point of view of logistics. If Martins can add something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In the mining side, our capacity is around 25 million tons per month, okay? And during the rainy season, this volume's down to 22, 23 and in the dry season, it goes up to 27, 28. But on average, it's around 25 million tons. Mining, railway, port, they all love this system. It's designed for such a level and with some, I would say, some spare capacity in the logistics side.</p>
          <p>So we believe that we can reach this level. We do humping up from the level we reached during the crisis was a big catastrophe for two reasons. First, we cut capacity a lot during the crisis, at least 40% in the mining side and 80% in the pelletizing plant. So that was the size of capacity cut during the crisis. So and because we are prepared to face a long period, the crisis will be less more, the yule type, WW VV, all of this, it seems that the crisis was a V-type. So we start to recover that and we have a lot of trouble to get back to the same level. And we have some space yet to conclude that &#x2013; to improve in order to get our full capacity. So &#x2013; but you can look at the average of 25 million tons per month as our average capacity for this year.</p>
          <p>And we expect operators to reach this level as soon as this rainy season finished, we expect to work in this level of production from now on. Market is very strong and the demand is very strong.</p>
          <p>Europe is recovering faster than we expect also. Japan is now in the same pre-crisis level, and then China is well above the pre-crisis level. So the situation for the market is even better than it was before the crisis.</p>
          <p>So the very difficultly for us to cope with this production recover, one side, and other, to implement the new projects that we have been developing during this period. So I think again situation moving to the production site. And we need you to work to improve our operations and to smooth the link between mining, railway and port. But we are much better prepared, as Eduardo stated, that we completely revamped Tubar&#xE3;o port. It is quite a brand-new port with five car dumpers, two big ship loaders, same situation also at Porta da Madera. So we are much better prepared now to ramp up our production and to reach a stable level according to our mining capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, our last question comes from Mr. Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o from Ita&#xFA; Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon everybody. My first question is on the iron ore market. If Martins could answer, what were the main reasons that pushed the spot prices up from $100 per ton in November to $130 per ton currently? And also if you could mention some signs of the market tightness? We have been hearing that, if you could confirm, we have been hearing that some clients are willing to pay a provisional price in order to guarantee the volumes right now in the beginning of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as the strong market mainly in China, I think many factors are working on it. First is, in China, you have today a very strong winter. And so this creates some problems for local ore production and also for logistics to move iron ore from ports to the mills. So this is an internal factor. Besides that, you have two additional factors. One is that low-quality productions continues to grow. And third is, many still use that never used imported ore, after this crisis, they had access to this ore. And now their preference is for imported ore. I think the space for local ore is becoming...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Narrowing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is narrowing and you can see, when you compare spot price for imported ore against the spot price for local ore, you already can see a difference. The customers are paying more for imported ore than local ore. So this means that there is a structural change in the blast furnace burning in China new. So more and more, the imported ore, it will take share from the local ore.</p>
          <p>As far as provisional price, yes, we are discussing with many customers a provisional price for interesting pellets that we have a very low price established last year to cope with the very low demand and now the situation is completely different, so we are now defining provisional price with pellet customers. And also in case of China, 75% of our contracts in China are based on calendar year. So it means that 75% of our sales in China is now based on the new price. And we already negotiated with these customers a provisional price for this year. So &#x2013; and I think this huge difference from spot and &#x2013; to the benchmark creates a good condition for establishing a provisional price when the calendar &#x2013; when the contract is based on calendar year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's question-and-answer-session. Mr. Barbosa, at this time, you may proceed with your closing statement, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would like to first thank my colleagues, Martins and Bartolomeo, for participating at this conference call and also to say that we are at your disposal for further questions that you may have about our results and perspective. Thank you very much for attending this conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude our Vale's 2009 Results Conference Call for today. Thank you very much for your participation and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>