<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1167529" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>527</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James Bombassei, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Sumner M. Redstone, Executive Chairman of the Board and Founder</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Philippe P. Dauman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Thomas E. Dooley, Senior Executive Vice President, Chief Administrative Officer and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Mark Wienkes</participant>
      <participant id="6">Phillipe Dauman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Thomas Dooley</participant>
      <participant id="8">James Bombassei</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jason Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="10">Benjamin Swinburne</participant>
      <participant id="11">Philippe Dauman</participant>
      <participant id="12">Richard Greenfield</participant>
      <participant id="13">Jessica Reif-Cohen</participant>
      <participant id="14">Douglas Mitchelson</participant>
      <participant id="15">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="16">Jason Helfstein</participant>
      <participant id="17">Michael Morris</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day everyone and welcome to the Viacom second quarter 2008 earnings release teleconference. Today's call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time I'd like to turn the call over to the Senior President of Investor Relations, Mr. James Bombassei. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon everyone. Thank you for taking the time to join us for our second quarter earnings call. Joining me for today's discussion are Sumner Redstone, our Chairman, Philippe Dauman, our President and CEO, Tom Dooley, our Chief Administrative Officer and CFO, and Jimmy Barge, our Controller and Head of Tax and Treasury.</p>
          <p>Please note that in addition to our press release, we have slides containing supplemental information available on our web site. Before we begin, let me refer you to page number one in the web presentation and remind you that certain statements made on this call are forward-looking statements that involve risks and uncertainties. These risks and uncertainties are discussed in more detail in our filings with the S.E.C.</p>
          <p>Reconciliations for non-GAAP financial information discussed on this call can be found in our earnings release or on our web site. And now I'd like to turn the call over to Sumner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon everyone, I thank you for joining us today.</p>
          <p>The past few months, as you know, have been challenging times for many companies. And the media industry is not immune to the negative impact of the current economy. I understand the frustration of shareholders, indeed to a greater degree than many, who have recently seen business prospects, share prices fall and they're falling victim to the broader economic turbulence.</p>
          <p>However, I have also witnessed more than a few economic cycles, so I also know there is opportunity even in difficult times.  Companies that have strong and enduring attributes, such as vibrant brands, a global reach, and a visionary and seasoned management -- companies like Viacom, they will be ultimately the winners.</p>
          <p>There are a multitude of reasons for optimism about Viacom as we look out over the horizon, both near and long term. And many of these Philippe will discuss on the call today. But my optimism is fueled by a highly competitive landscape and the unprecedented pace of technological innovation, both of which will result in escalating growth opportunities for companies with the right assets and the right capabilities. I'm sure it will come as no surprise to anyone that I believe that companies that possess the very best content, they will ultimately emerge as the winners. And of course, there is no better example of their kingly capability than Viacom.</p>
          <p>That's why Paramount is the number one student in market share this year. That's why we have powerful global media networks that are top performers in countries around the world. And that's why MTV Games has a run away hit franchise in Rock Band. And most important, Philippe, Tom, and the rest of the leadership team remain intensely focused on implementing the right plans that will make the most of those successes and many others, and unlock the full portfolio of our portfolio.  They are capitalizing on seismic shifts in the media today to cultivate new and attractive sources of revenue for tomorrow.</p>
          <p>That's how we will continue to deliver greater value to all of you, our shareholders. And now, Philippe, it's yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sumner, and good afternoon everyone. I'm very pleased you could join us today. Over the course of the second quarter, like many companies, Viacom was faced with an increasingly challenging economic environment which resulted in a slow down in advertising overall. Nevertheless, as you see from our second quarter results, the diversity of our revenue streams provides us with greater stability than others.</p>
          <p>In addition to consistently solid affiliate and ancillary revenue growth, increasingly solid performance of our motion picture business continues to help us mitigate challenges on the advertising front.  Furthermore, we moved forward with several initiatives to improve efficiencies and protect our operating margins. As a result, we delivered solid double digit growth in operating income and diluted earnings per share in the second quarter as compared with the prior year's adjusted results. With the short term outlook for the economy difficult to predict, we are continuing to improve our organization and business processes across the company. These enduring changes will enable us to continue to succeed in the near term and as the economy recovers, we will be better positioned to capitalize on the opportunities that will emerge in the marketplace.  Importantly, we remain on track to deliver double-digit EPS growth for the full-year 2008.</p>
          <p>Today, we will cover the following areas:  A quick review of our second quarter results, a few highlights from our Media Networks business, including an update on our successful upfront. Paramount has had a terrific first half of the year and I'll touch on our upcoming plans.  Finally, Tom will take you through our numbers and discuss the drivers behind those results.  Then we will be happy to take your questions.</p>
          <p>Let's begin with our financial results.  Our reported results in 2007 included some one time items so unless specifically noted otherwise, Tom and I will refer to growth rates on an adjusted basis.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated revenues were up 21% in the second quarter to $3.9 billion.  Revenues in our Media Network segment were up 11% for the quarter.  On a worldwide basis, advertising revenues were up 2%.  We saw a significant slowdown in our domestic advertising revenues this past quarter which nonetheless did grow 1%.  Despite a strong upfront which I'll address in a moment, the volume in the scatter market did soften during the second quarter and this softness is continuing so far this quarter.</p>
          <p>On a more positive note affiliate fees grew 12% for the quarter driven by both rate and subscriber increases across our core channels.  Worldwide ancillary revenues rose an impressive 62% with Rock Band continuing to be the biggest driver of our growth.  Next year we expect Rock Band to begin to generate increasingly meaningful bottom line results as well.</p>
          <p>Our Film Entertainment segment delivered strong top line growth with revenues up 35% for the quarter to $1.8 billion.  The growth was driven by an impressive 84% jump in theatrical revenue.  Better than expected top line growth resulted in a $64 million improvement in Paramount's operating income year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Viacom's overall reported operating income increased 13% to $792 million for the second quarter, primarily driven by upsides at Paramount.  Diluted EPS were $0.64, a 19% increase over the adjusted results in Q2 of '07.</p>
          <p>So for the first half of 2008, we delivered solid double-digit growth at both the top and bottom lines.  Revenues were up 18%, and reported operating income increased 19%.  While the economy overall and the soft advertising market do present challenges, we have and will continue to demonstrate our ability to manage our businesses well and deliver on our financial commitments.</p>
          <p>We have taken steps to reduce costs and streamline certain operations and there is more work to be done in this regard.  We remain committed to investing in our brands, our programming, our gains, and our development of multiple growing revenue streams for the long term health of the business.</p>
          <p>We remain on target to generate strong free cash flow and will continue to return value to our shareholders by repurchasing shares under our stock buyback program.</p>
          <p>Now let's talk about our Media Networks segment.  In the near term, the growth in our domestic advertising business has slowed significantly.  However, our affiliate and ancillary businesses are performing well.  In fact they're generating double-digit growth with a solid outlook ahead.  The primary question we've received in recent weeks is what happened in the ad market?  About midway through the second quarter, the scatter volume for several of our networks dropped off.  Advertisers in a few categories such as retail, automotive and certain consumer goods, pulled back their on-air spending as they adjusted their own operating plans and product launches.  Low ratings at a few of our networks also contributed to the softness.</p>
          <p>At the same time, audiences continued to drift away from broadcast channels, generally migrating to cable networks that skew to an older demographic, and the advertising dollars that were still in place follow those eyeballs.  That did benefit some of our networks such as TV Land and particularly Nick at Nite, but the trend did not benefit some of our other networks that cater to a younger demographic.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we do see potential opportunity to counter this trend as we enter the back to school season and prepare for major tent pole events on our networks such as the season premier of The Hills and the Video Music Awards in September.</p>
          <p>Also we are targeting new advertiser categories to replace those whose circumstances dramatically changed in the last few months.  The successful advertising upfront we just completed, which will be part of the mix beginning in the fourth quarter this year confirms the value of the connections we forge with our audiences.  We entered the upfront discussions armed with several key assets.  Most of our networks have delivered solid ratings growth year-over-year and our overall ratings year-to-date were up 5% in their respective core demographics.  We're also continuing to invest in original and acquired programming and we are leading the marketplace and accelerating our efforts in the development of customized and integrated marketing opportunities.  All of these factors helped us to secure double digit growth in volume and high single digit price increases in the adult upfront.</p>
          <p>Part of this year's kids upfront, Nickelodeon already had completed a significant portion of its business through multiyear marketing deals.  Nick was able to add to this base, growing revenue through share gains, and increasing business from key categories, including video games and movie studios, as well as wireless, a new category for them.</p>
          <p>With a steady infusion of new programming, including breakout hits, iCarly and the Mighty B, Nickelodeon is widening its lead over the other two children's networks and holds a number one spot in virtually every kids' demo.  Kids 2 to 11, 2 to 5, 6 to 11 and 'tweens.  This past quarter Nick grew it's 'tween delivery by 5%, expanding its lead over the second place network to 16%.</p>
          <p>The digital landscape continues to evolve and we are capturing more opportunities than ever before.  We are driving more traffic to our 340 plus online properties.  We are capitalizing on the explosive growth of social networking by integrating more social behavior across our major sites and virtual world.</p>
          <p>We are making great progress in rolling out Flux to connect our networks with Flux's external member sites.  When it comes to online casual games, our portfolio is already number one in the U.S. and number two in the world.  Growth in the global games market is projected to outpace every other media segment and online casual games will grow the fastest.  Over the next several years, we intend to ride that wave leveraging existing properties and creating original, demo-focused game offerings.</p>
          <p>The story on our affiliate sales and ancillary businesses illustrates the advantage of having multiple revenue streams.  Our affiliate sales teams have delivered double digit revenue growth for the past nine quarters and we believe this growth will continue.  Our networks are must haves.  Think Nickelodeon, BT, Comedy Central, MTV, and so many more and moreover, our networks are a great bargain.</p>
          <p>While we deliver well over 20% of the audience to ad-supported cable, our share of affiliate feeds is less than half that.  In fact, we have several networks that are significantly undervalued relative to their audience delivery.  One of our top priorities is to increase rates while providing greater value to our distributors and narrow that gap.</p>
          <p>As competition between cable carriers, satellite and Telcos increases, they will continue to seek programming and services that will distinguish their offerings.  Simply having technology as it becomes ubiquitous across distributors will not be enough.  Compelling programming and increasingly unique customer experiences will be the differentiating factors that drive subscriber growth for our partners. Our expertise in monetizing the content on new and emerging distribution platforms will also fuel our long term growth.</p>
          <p>Let me give you a few examples.  Our cable networks content constitutes over 35% of all free VOD orders but we occupy just 10% of our partner's shelf space.  In our increasingly I want it now culture, VOD will continue to grow, and we will build on our success with packages that add value for our partners and add revenues for us.</p>
          <p>Analysts predict that the mobile advertising market in the U.S. will grow at very high double digit growth rates over the next several years and Viacom is already the largest provider of video content on mobile.  We're also building on our number one position on online casual gaming in the U.S. by moving rapidly into mobile games.  Nickelodeon's Addicting Games has launched a series of mini games called quickies exclusively on the Verizon wireless network. And the new iPhone app store features the new South Park Imagination Land game and will feature games based on hit Paramount movies like Days of Thunder, Saturday Night Fever, School of Rock, and Top Gun.</p>
          <p>Ancillary sales is another revenue stream that continues to be a valuable asset for us as we exploit our most successful programming and characters through an array of opportunities.  Importantly, we also have the opportunity to build brands from scratch.  For example the Rock Band franchise is brand building at its finest, and it's a story we can and will replicate.  We start with an incredible product that appeals to multiple demographics.  We tap into our legacy of music curation to build a whole new platform for experiencing music.  And then we leverage all of our properties to build this brand.</p>
          <p>Since the launch, we've shipped 4.8 million units propelling MTV games to a top five video game publisher in North America.  We're in our second wave of our European launch and with the release of Rock Band for the Nintendo Wii, the game can now be played on all major video game systems.  Adding to the success is a secondary revenue stream from song downloads.  Eighteen million paid downloads to date at an accelerating rate now with a million downloads every nine days and our library of music continues to grow.  Rock Band two will be launched this fall exclusively on Xbox 360 with numerous new features, including a huge and eclectic song list and online modes to build an even larger community around the brand.  We will launch on other game systems later in the year.</p>
          <p>This brand is still in its infancy.  Over the next several years you will see us broaden its sphere of influence by moving to other genres and capitalizing on new marketing opportunities.  Looking at consumer products more broadly our international markets offer fertile ground for cultivating these businesses.  We are aggressively pursuing opportunities to expand into new areas and capitalizing on channel launches to create demand for our products as we build our brands in new locations around the world.</p>
          <p>Just last week we launched Nick Arabia, the first global kids' media brand to create a free to air Arabic service across the region, and Nickelodeon's 50th global channel.  Nick Poland and Nick Africa also launched earlier this month and Nick Jr. was introduced in six countries across Latin America.  Each of these launches included an integrated plan for developing a robust consumer products business.   in addition of selling merchandise, we're exploring new ventures such as audiences have with our brands, and provide new revenue streams for us.  This past spring, Nickelodeon celebrated a successful launch of Nick Universe in the Mall of America.  Last month Nick opened the largest Nick branded them park brand outside the U.S. at a movie park near Dusseldorf, Germany.  And next month, the first Nickelodeon brand cruise will set sail in the Caribbean.</p>
          <p>Finally, we're continuing to evaluate the processes of our cable networks.  We have made great strides in improving the efficiency of our organization, but we know there is more that can be done.  Our focus is on areas that do not impact the continued development of great content and experience, and grow our brands in relationships with our consumers.  These actions will provide immediate benefit, and over the longer term, greater efficiencies will translate into faster growth.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move to the Film Entertainment segment.  Paramount has enjoyed terrific theatrical success so far this year.  For the second year in a row, it generated more than $1 billion in box office both domestically and internationally in record time.  The studio also holds the number one spot in domestic market share.  Iron Man with $315 million in domestic box office marks the beginning of another great franchise.  Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull, also with about $315 in domestic box office and worldwide box office of about $750 million, has introduced a whole new generation to this adventure series.  In fact, the tremendous anticipation for the film generated during the quarter a nice boost in sales of our Indiana Jones library titles domestically and internationally.  And DreamWorks Animation's Kung Fu Panda is the top animated film with about $210 million of domestic and over $500 million of worldwide box office.  Over the past year and a half, I have spoken numerous times about how the economics of the motion picture industry need to be evaluated on a multiyear timeframe as a movie progresses through various windows.  Paramount released a number of strong films in 2007, and this year's shaping up to the second consecutive year of strong box office success for Paramount.  We are still early in the cycle of the studio's financial come back.  The profits from the breakout films will continue to cascade through the P&amp;L for some time.</p>
          <p>Paramount's pay-per-view and on demand business is driven by a growing portfolio of diversified distribution partners ranging from satellite to cable to the Internet domestically and around the globe.  While the share of total revenue today is relatively small, we are expecting significant annual double digit growth in these revenues in the coming years.  As we demonstrate in the second quarter, we intend to build on our bottom line growth by taking specific steps to remove certain costs from the studio.  For example, we consolidated the marketing, distribution and physical production departments of Paramount Vantage with those of Paramount Pictures.  This move will result in an annual savings of several million dollars in marketing spends and overhead expense.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we have several strong titles slated for release during the remainder of the year starting with next month's release of DreamWorks Tropic Thunder with an all star cast including several surprise cameos.  Other major films include The Curious Case of Benjamin Button, and DreamWorks Animation's Madagascar, Escape to Africa.</p>
          <p>Overall, I am optimistic about our future growth plans throughout Viacom.  Tom and I just completed our long range planning meetings with each of our divisions.  With new thinking and innovative approaches, the growth opportunities that exist across our organization in affiliate partnerships, consumer products, licensing, online and mobile platforms, games, movies, recreation, are increasingly important fast growing international businesses, and yes, advertising, are very exciting.  These opportunities will allow us to grow our core businesses and accelerate our plan to diversity our revenues.</p>
          <p>While we are in a period of transition, there has never been a better time to be in the content business.  Consumers today have a voracious appetite for content, and we have the capabilities to satiate that hunger across every platform and every geography.  As the leading pure play content company in the world with multiple strong brands, Viacom has the vision, the opportunity, the people and the assets to achieve our objectives and to continue to grow value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn it over to my partner, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Philippe and good afternoon everyone.  I hope you've all had an opportunity to review our release and web presentation summarizing our results.  Our 10-Q will be filed shortly with the SEC and should be available later this evening.  This afternoon I'm going to take you through our second quarter results in more detail, and I'll update you on the key factors impacting our outlook for the balance of the year.  My remarks will focus on our results from continuing operations as compared to last year's adjusted results as discussed in our earnings press release.</p>
          <p>As you will recall, last year's second quarter results included 11 million in restructuring charges at MTV Networks, the gain on the sale of our interest in MTV Russia as well as a write-off of our investment in Amp'd Mobile.  We believe that adjusted results are a better indicator of our core performance.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to our performance in the quarter:  Despite a challenging environment, Viacom's revenues, operating income, and earnings per share, all grew double digits.  I'm going to focus most of my remarks on the segment results, and I will start with the Media Networks group.  The Media Networks group continues to generate strong top line growth with revenues up 11% to $2.1 billion in the second quarter.  If you would like to follow along using the web deck, page nine provides a breakdown of Media Networks' revenue growth. Worldwide advertising revenues rose 2% in the second quarter to $1.2 billion.  Domestic advertising revenues increased 1%, reflecting recent softness in the overall ad market.</p>
          <p>As Philippe mentioned, softness in the second half of the quarter put pressure on ad sales growth.  It is important to note that we achieved a domestic ad sales base of slightly more than $1 billion.  Each percentage point of growth equals approximately $10 million.  So it only takes a drop in the expected scatter volume of 20 or $30 million to notch down the growth rate.   We continue to work closely with our key advertisers and their agencies to navigate this difficult economic environment.</p>
          <p>International Advertising grew 10% over 2007.  Foreign exchange contributed 10 percentage points to growth in the quarter.  Also, the first quarter of 2007 included ad revenues of our India operations which we now deconsolidate after having entered into a joint venture with TV18 in India.  This deconsolidation had a 3% adverse impact on International Advertising comps.  The organic growth was 4%, driven primarily by ratings performance as well as ad market growth in Europe and Latin America, offset by some softness in the Asian markets.</p>
          <p>Worldwide affiliate revenues grew 12% to $656 million, with foreign exchange benefits contributing 1% of the worldwide growth.  Domestic affiliate revenues increased 11%.  About 60% of the growth in domestic revenues came from rate increases, while 40% of the growth came from increased subscribers at both our core and our digital channels.</p>
          <p>International affiliate revenues increased 19% on a reported basis, with eight percentage points of that growth driven by foreign exchange benefits and the deconsolidation of India having a negative 2% impact.  Organic growth of 13% was driven by both subscriber and rate increases principally in Europe.</p>
          <p>Worldwide ancillary revenues grew 62% in the quarter to $307 million.  Domestic ancillary revenues were up 46%, reflecting the continued success of Rock Band including the rollout on the Nintendo Wii platform in June.  International ancillary revenues increased 94% in the quarter with 5% of the gain being attributable to foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>The rollout in late May of Rock Band in the U.K, France and Germany was a key driver, with higher licensing revenues also contributing.  This past Friday, we launched Rock Band in Italy, Sweden Switzerland, Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg and tomorrow we will launch in Spain.  Media Networks' operating income for the quarter was up 3% to 765 million from last year's adjusted results.  The operating margin declined from 39% in 2007, to 36% in 2008.  Two thirds of the decline was due to lower effective margins on Rock Band revenues and approximately one third of the decline was related to increased programming investment.</p>
          <p>Now turning to films and entertainment.  Second quarter revenues were up 35% to $1.8 billion and operating income was $86 million, which is a $64 million improvement from last year.</p>
          <p>Page 11 of the web presentation provides a breakdown of films and entertainment revenues. Theatrical revenues increased 84% to $805 million, versus 2007.  Growth in theatrical revenues was driven by the worldwide success of Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull, Iron Man and Kung Fu Panda, as compared the Shrek the Third in the second quarter of last year.  This quarter's releases were illustrative of Paramount's strategy of developing their slate around key franchises.  We look forward to the release of sequels to Transformers next year and Iron Man in 2010.</p>
          <p>Home entertainment revenues increased 67 million or 12%, versus the first quarter of 2007.  Home entertainment revenues reflect increased revenues from third party distribution agreements, including our new CBS distribution agreement, which requires gross revenue treatment.  It also reflects increased revenues from our catalog title, driven by the reissue of the first three Indiana Jones titles.  Partially offsetting this were lower revenues from this year's home entertainment releases which included Cloverfield and The Spiderwick Chronicles. TV license fees grew 4% to $300 million reflecting hire pay-per-view and video on demand revenues.  The $64 million improvement in Filmed Entertainment operating income reflects profit contributions from Iron Man and the Indiana Jones trilogy DVD release.  In addition, 2007 second quarter included a significant amount of prerelease spending associated with the July 3, 2007 release of Transformers with no comparable major release in the early third quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow and share buy backs are also critical to the conversation.  Page five of the web deck provides a presentation of the components of free cash flow.  There was a cash use of 182 million in the second quarter.  The principal drivers were working capital and cash taxes.  The working capital use of 469 million in the quarter was largely due to the acceleration of this year's film production to the first half of the year, so that the bulk of our 2009 releases would be completed by the June 30 expiration of the SAG contract.</p>
          <p>Cash taxes increased 197 million in the quarter, principally due to 2008 tax payments being spread more evenly over the year than 2007 tax payments, which were weighted more to the second half of the year.  For the full year, we continue to believe that free cash flow will be comparable to last year, excluding the one time capital expenditure of 75 to $100 million related to relocating several of our cable channels into new office space.</p>
          <p>The acceleration of this year's film production and the launch of Rock Band in Europe on the Wii in the first half of the year will result in the timing of our free cash flow to be weighted to the third and fourth quarters of 2008.  In terms of leverage, at the end of the quarter, we had $9.2 billion of debt and capital leases outstanding.  And our leverage ratio was 2.9 times.  We continue to return capital to our shareholders throughout &#x2013; through our share repurchase program in the second quarter.  During the quarter we repurchased 12 million shares for an aggregate purchase price of $446 million and had 623 million shares outstanding at the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to our guidance, for the three year period from 2008 through 2010, we continue to expect to deliver low double digit annual growth and diluted net earnings per share from continuing operations.  This outlook is based on adjusted earnings and reflects growth from 2007 adjusted, diluted net earnings per share from continuing operations of $2.36.</p>
          <p>Now I want to cover a couple of trends impacting our performance for the balance of the year that have not already been addressed.  The timing of our programming investment, as well as the continued rollout of Rock Band internationally, will put pressure on Media Network margins in the third quarter versus last year.  This will weight the second half growth in Media Networks' operating income and margins to the fourth quarter of the year.</p>
          <p>In filmed entertainment, last year's third quarter benefited from the worldwide release of Transformers and the fact that a significant amount of the P&amp;A was spent in the second quarter of 2007, thereby generating significant profit in the third quarter.  We will have no comparable circumstance in 2008's third quarter, so the studio will face difficult bottom line comparisons on a year-to-year basis.  We do however see healthy growth in profits at the studio in the fourth quarter.  Wrapping up, in a challenging environment, we generated strong top and bottom line results.  For the first six months of 2008, we have grown revenues 18%, operating income 12%, and diluted earnings per share 23%.  We are committed to investing for the long term growth, and continue to make strategic investments in our brand and key franchises.</p>
          <p>At the same time, in the third quarter of last year, we saw the slowing economic environment, and put in place a number of cost saving initiatives.  This is enabling us to operate with greater efficiency in order to protect our core margins.</p>
          <p>The company's fundamentals remain strong and we are optimistic about both our current and long term outlook.  We remain focused on growing organically by continuing to develop our brands and franchises.</p>
          <p>Thank you for listening and now we'll turn the call over to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  And we'll go first to Mark Wienkes of Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.  I was wondering, could you walk us through the affiliate fee step ups towards parity across the networks for the next couple of years, just where are the big buckets of opportunity on that side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, the &#x2013; I mean, several &#x2013; on the overall package of our networks, we are as I mentioned in my remarks, significantly undervalued.  But probably the ones that really stand out are Comedy Central, which is coming off of a number of very long term affiliate agreements that were forged a decade or so ago when Comedy Central had not reached the status it has today nor the viewership it has today, and Nickelodeon, which is a dominant force in kids' television and we think there is opportunity for growth there.  But across our portfolio of networks there is opportunity that should drive growth as we provide value over many years to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  And no specifics in terms of the approximate size of the opportunity over like '09, '10, '11?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we've indicated we expect to continue to see double-digit growth in our affiliate revenues for the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, okay, and then just one quick follow up.  Any sort of anecdotes you could provide with respect to the commentary about the erosion of viewers from broadcast toward cable skewing towards the older networks, just from an advertiser category perspective that you guys didn't see in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, there are a number of advertisers who reach for the older demo.  Most of our networks, other than TV Land and Nick at Nite principally target younger demos that just aren't served by broadcast, so as those dollars fall off, they are principally going to older skewing cable networks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The pharmaceuticals are driving it, the financial services companies are driving it and those are the guys that are spending big money and coming into cable aggressively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We'll take our next question from Michael Nathanson with Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, I have, for Philippe or Tom either one. Folks are struggling definitely with the domestic ad growth number this quarter and I wondered, I think it would be helpful if could you give some more color on the growth rates by demographic.  If you can actually burrow down and look at what was kids growth or maybe teen growth this quarter, so if you could help us on maybe demographic growth rates at Viacom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I indicated, obviously we did &#x2013; we did quite well in the &#x2013; in the older demo networks.  We had a lot of the softness really related to the &#x2013; I'd say the &#x2013; not so much the kids, the young kids, but that in-between demographic group.  Again, it was very &#x2013; it is very category specific.  I mentioned a few of the categories that were primarily impacted, probably automotive which I've mentioned before which probably was across the media industry, certain specific categories in consumer goods.  So it was really a lot of it had to do with specific issues going on with specific advertisers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>May I say this, has kids been holding back the growth rate the past couple &#x2013; couple quarters or teens?  Is there maybe a mix issue with not getting the older demographics which is funny?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we look forward and looking at the strategy of Viacom, obviously we are very strong in the younger demographics, we think that's a important demographic for advertisers, we are planning to introduce new categories of advertisers to this demographic as being very important to their marketing plans.  But also, we are looking to enter more significantly into the demographics where we have a lower presence.  For that reason, we've introduced original programming on TV Land, for example, which has been very successful thus far.</p>
          <p>And that will allow us to target more older-skewing advertising dollars as we go forward with that.  And we have some great growing brands like Spike, which is a male oriented brand which covers several demos, young men but also older-skewing demographics during certain program blocks.</p>
          <p>So, we're &#x2013; we are working to target demos where we are not as dominant as we are in kids.  So over the long term strategically that should also assist our growth, looking forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But over the long term you have different product cycles where different products targeting different demographic groups become stronger and weaker.  I mean, for many, many many years everyone was saying, there's no point in targeting an older, a 50 plus audience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now 50 plus has become very strong basically driven by pharmaceutical industries and the financial services industries which are specifically targeting the baby boomer demo. As Philippe said we're diversifying to take advantage of that stream and at the same time we look at new ways to monetize against our existing things.  From time to time you have quarters where the amount of product targeting a specific demo does get weak, but over time that tends to work itself out year in year out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Jason Bazinet with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just have one question on Media Networks' operating income margins.  I think you mentioned that about two thirds of the margin compression year-over-year stemmed from Rock Band, if I got that right.  When do you think that can begin to be a contributor to margins, or at least less of a drag?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be less of a drag as we roll forward here.  It's sort of mid to low single digit in this year, and it builds or maybe doubles year after year after year.  So I think that's some of the rough guidance as to how you might want to look at Rock Band's margins as it grows    and that's strictly a function as we get the penetration of the units and shift from selling a very low margin unit into the focus more on the download business which has a relatively higher margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And did I get that right that you said two thirds of the compression was driven by Rock Band?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two thirds of the compression was due to Rock Band.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We'll go next to Benjamin Swinburne with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good afternoon.  Couple of questions.  First Philippe, you talked about the upfront results and the success there which was true for a lot of cable networks.  We're in that time of year right now where those should start turning into firm orders while at the same time, it sounds like everyone's looking at their budgets increasingly critically.  I'm wondering if you have any confidence at this point or be willing to talk about how much of the commitments you saw on the MTV side, you think will turn into firm orders, because it would suggest that the add trends you saw in the second quarter and probably into the third quarter get better as we head into the next broadcast season?  Maybe you &#x2013; maybe you think that's an overly optimistic view.  I would love your thoughts there.</p>
          <p>And then for Tom just to go back I think you mentioned this last quarter, the timing of the cash flows this year, should we assume that buy backs will be larger in the second half than the first half which is what we saw last year, but given the timing of the production spend, would be true again this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the upfront, we &#x2013; we are having a good upfront, in both the adult and kids category, as I mentioned.  What we don't know about is where the economy is going to be headed, as we -- as we go into the next season and how that will impact the scatter market.  But every indication we have, assisted, I might add, by the multiplatform delivery that we're able to discuss with our clients, and by the continually enhanced integrated marketing opportunities we provide to them.  So the business we're writing looks good, very solid, good categories, what the impact of the scatter market on overall ad sales will be a function of the overall economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the buy backs, we're pretty much a consistent buyer month after month after month.  We don't sort of weight it to the lower cash flow or the higher cash flow, we maintain a consistent position month after month throughout the year.  So it's not something that goes up or down relative to cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Rich Greenfield with Pali Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, couple questions.  One just trying to drill down, given what happened from the time you gave an updated comment at one of the conferences in terms of domestic ad spend, what should we be looking at for third quarter right now?  A similar level to Q2 in terms of that weakness, or should it actually be a lower number and then a bounce back from Q4 as you begin to benefit from the upfront so any type clarity would be great there.</p>
          <p>And then just specifically on Nickelodeon, there's some stuff out today related to the FTC's decision or commentary on marketing to kids.  It sounds a little less threatening than it has been in the past in terms of amends that have been made by advertisers.  Just wondering how much that's hurt you in Nickelodeon in the last couple of years and to the extent it doesn't get worse, how much of an opportunity is that over the next 12 to 18 months?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Rich.  As far as the ad spending, going forward, it is very early in the third quarter.  So we're just not going to make any predictions.  I mentioned in my remarks, that the softness in the scatter market continues.  I mentioned, we're taking different steps to address it, introduce new advertisers to replace the ones who dropped off over the last couple months.  And we do have some nice tent pole events coming up.  Again, given the state of the economy it's just very hard to predict.  But we are aggressively out there, trying to make the best of the ad dollars that are available for us.</p>
          <p>As far as the FTC report, we've been at the forefront in this effort.  We're working, we have been working for some time with our food advertisers.  We promote healthy choices.  We've done a lot of, for many years, we've been leaders in &#x2013; in public service programming on Nickelodeon.  We have a "let's just play" program where we actually have no advertising on &#x2013; and no programming for several hours on a given day, urging kids to go out and play.  We &#x2013; we are &#x2013; we are not licensing starting in January '09 our characters to non-healthful products.  We don't take soda advertising, we haven't as a matter of policy, taken soda advertising on Nickelodeon, which is one of the categories that has been addressed in the report.  So, this is an opportunity as the &#x2013; as you suggest, as the marketers review their own product line, for us to work with them as they promote healthful choices.  Whether it's at the supermarket, or in &#x2013; in the quick service restaurants or otherwise.  So we are working with them on new marketing campaigns to promote healthful choices for kids.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you just comment on taking political advertising for the first time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we &#x2013; there has been a lot of attention to this presidential race, particularly in the demos we serve, a lot of interest in this campaign.  And we thought with the appropriate standards, we still review the advertising that's submitted to us, that there &#x2013; that we should take on the advertising, and so far we have run some advertising that's some on the Republican side, some on the Democratic side.  It's not a huge opportunity for us, since most political ad buying is on local media.  But it is &#x2013; it is an opportunity which we're taking advantage of.  And particularly for a demographic that's very interested in this year's presidential election.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We'll go next to Jessica Reif-Cohen with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  I have a couple of questions.  First you mentioned a few times that you are cutting costs and I was wondering if you could say what your target is in total and by division and will there be any restructuring charges?  And second, what percent of advertising &#x2013; of international advertising comes from the U.K?  And then finally can you give us an update on that new pay TV service?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Jessica.  As far as the cost cutting, we've been &#x2013; as both Tom and I indicated, we've been ahead of the curve there in just tightening our organization.  It's been a continual process really since we've gotten here.  We specifically identified a number of the efficiencies we drove through our international organization.  We've applied some of the same methods domestically.  We've been very careful in new hires.  But the overall mandate, by the way, has been that I don't want to see any cost cutting that will impact what we put on the various screens we serve or affect our brands.  We do not anticipate taking any restructuring charges this year that are related to any of this.  We are doing this as an ordinary course of business and part of making us more efficient.  And I believe this period will make us much stronger as we emerge.  Most recently we laid out specifically what we did at Paramount Vantage.  But it has really just become an ordinary course of business to just drive more efficiency in the system.</p>
          <p>As far as international advertising, U.K. is our most important territory.  And we have good vitality.  Several of our networks, ad sales are also in the area we have to watch closely in international markets.  But U.K, Germany, those are &#x2013; those are big advertising markets for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It can go up and down, Jessica, but it's approximately a third.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as the pay service, we are continuing as time &#x2013; as time passes, obviously we are getting into more detailed stages of our discussions with potential distributors.  But we're having very productive meetings, and furthering those discussions.  We have nothing to announce at this time, and when we conclude deals, we will be making announcements as we make them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Move to our next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We will go next to Doug Mitchelson with Deutsche Banc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon gentlemen.  One more question on advertising.  I'm trying to square the soft scatter volume in 2Q and 3Q with your commentary regarding the strong upfront.  And so I guess I would focus the question, since you're not going to give us a list by advertiser, when you look at the upfront and how strong it was by advertiser or category, and you look at the scatter weakness are the guys who are soft in scatter now coming back big in the upfront, which would of course make us worry that that upfront might be at risk of sticking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say when you look at our upfront, we have some of the traditional categories that we've been doing business with, whether it's the motion picture studios, the QSRs, wireless, all the ones that we've been &#x2013; we've been engaged with for a long time, continue to be the core of our upfront sales.  Again, I think we've benefited through our integrated marketing plans and a lot of the advertisers want to make sure that they're working with us on a programmatic basis across many of our shows and events during the season.  And that's probably been a driver.  But, we don't break it down as you suggest by advertiser.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the guys who are soft in scatter were also either soft in upfront or not a driving factor in your upfront I guess is what I'm trying to ask?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of the advertisers who were the softest or in some cases disappeared from scatter are companies that have, in some cases, significant overall difficulties that have been publicized who are reviewing their total spend in all categories including advertising.  So they have not been necessarily big players in the upfront marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We'll go next to Imran Khan with J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you for taking my questions.  Two questions, first going back to this advertisement category, could you give us some maybe qualitative or quantitative color?  What percentage of your domestic advertising revenues coming from the categories that you are seeing weakness like automotive?  And second question is hypothetically if DreamWorks and Paramount were to separate, how much in SG&amp;A savings would you expect?  Do you think you would go back to pre DreamWorks deal level?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Going back to what level?  I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pre DreamWorks deal levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the advertising question, we just don't break down the categories in that way.  As far as in the hypothetical situation, where DreamWorks concludes its deal as reported with Reliance of India, clearly there would be on a going forward basis in that situation some savings, in our &#x2013; in our overhead, as well as our marketing distribution, development spend.  And clearly, we would focus on the strategy we've articulated before, of putting out a &#x2013; over the course of many years, a group of releases that have focused on our brands and our franchises.  So the &#x2013; the savings would be significant.  Anything you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just don't think we can comment on the magnitude of the savings or the timing of those savings.  It's still a deal that is highly speculative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Jason Helfstein with Oppenheimer and Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, just one question.  Given your success with Rock Band is the company contemplating any other game related acquisitions either developer or publisher?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we Rock Band is a great franchise and we have a great group working Harmonics, which is the company we acquired which developed Rock Band.  There's a lot for us to do in growing out that franchise.  We could look at other game opportunities that are &#x2013; that have that kind of linkage to some of our brands.  But that's not a major focus for us.  Certainly, we're not looking to make any major acquisitions in the gaming area.  The other big area in gaming for us is casual games, where we have a very strong presence.  We are growing that organically.  There could be really, really small acquisitions in that space that we might look at but very small in terms of the value of the acquisitions would be -- just complement our activities there.  But we are totally focused right now on growing this great franchise and there are just so many new applications and brands that we can lay on the Rock Band franchise, that that's where the opportunity is for us at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our final questioner from Michael Morris with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  In your prepared comments on media nets, you referenced lower ratings in some of the networks and that you were trying to counter that with new seasons or new programs.  Can you talk about which networks maybe you're seeing the weakness at and then also, where you are in terms of programming spend?  If it's something that is still increasing at double digit rate as you try to counter the lower ratings in terms or where a steady state in terms of  programming spend increases should be year over year?</p>
          <p>And then on the film side, do you &#x2013; I understand the challenge with Transformers next quarter and the timing of P&amp;A, but when you talked about what influence this quarter you didn't mention I don't think Indiana Jones or Kung Fu Panda, you referenced the Indiana Jones DVD trilogy and Iron Man.  I was wondering if or when you expect benefit from those two titles, and also when you expect to see or if you expect to see impact from Transformers on television?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  As far as the regs issues, I mean, again, we're talking about temporary softness. in some cases it relates to when we launch a new season of a show.  For example, if you look at MTV, we have the new season of The Hills is debuting next month.  That's a huge series for us.  We didn't have it last month.  So we have these seasonal dislocations in a channel like MTV.    But of course MTV in addition to The Hills has the big tent poles, the music awards on September 7, so that will correct itself.</p>
          <p>And then we've had some weakness in BT, as an example, and that had to do with the transition that we've been effectuating in having BT less reliant on acquired programming and rolling in original programming,.  And as I said previously, this is a multi-year program that we are in the midst of, so again we're working to that end.  As far as the programming spend, we are going pretty steady state.  And as I've said in other calls, we are looking at the mix of programming.  We are looking to put on more original programming, as some of the older, acquired programming rolls off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But as historically as been noted, our second and third quarter, we usually ramp up the spending and the fourth quarter is when a lot of the revenue associated with that programming investment comes back in and smoothes out the margins for the year.  That's something you should keep in mind as you look forward here.  On the Iron Man in India should be hitting at the end, Iron Man hits at the end of the third quarter and Indy hits in the fourth quarter in terms of DVD.  Kung Fu Panda would hit in the fourth quarter.  Transformers on TV, that will be over a long window.  The revenue impact to that, we're not going to break that out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to understand then, you're waiting for the DVD releases for Kung Fu Panda and Indy, for the financial impact?  No impact during the box office window?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, say the last part again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've already had, we did include in the theatrical window, the theatrical release of both Indiana Jones, Kung Fu Panda, really drove through the second quarter, principally.  We didn't have that Transformers comparable, from last year, both on the cost side, which is in the second quarter, last year, it was P&amp;A for the very early July release of Transformers, the P&amp;A spending took place in second quarter, so that the revenues were not encumbered by the P&amp;A spending in last year's third quarter.  That's the difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The industry accounting doesn't match the expense to the revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to thank everyone for joining us for our second quarter earnings call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>That's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude today's call.  You may disconnect your lines at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>