<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1222593" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>527</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James Bombassei, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Sumner Redstone, Executive Chairman and Founder</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Philippe P. Dauman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Thomas E. Dooley, Senior Executive Vice President, Chief Administrative Officer and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Doug Mitchelson</participant>
      <participant id="6">Philippe Dauman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Mark Wienkes</participant>
      <participant id="8">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="9">Thomas Dooley</participant>
      <participant id="10">Michael Nathanson</participant>
      <participant id="11">Doug Creutz</participant>
      <participant id="12">Michael Morris</participant>
      <participant id="13">Anthony DiClemente</participant>
      <participant id="14">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jason Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="16">James Bombassei</participant>
      <participant id="17">Benjamin Swinburne</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day everyone, and welcome to the Viacom first quarter 2009 earnings release teleconference. Today's call is being recorded. At this time, I'd like to turn the call over to the Senior Vice President of Investor Relations, Mr. Jim Bombassei. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for taking the time to join us for our first quarter earnings call. Joining me for today's discussion are: Sumner Redstone, our Chairman; Philippe Dauman, our President and CEO; Tom Dooley, our Chief Administrative Officer and CFO; and Jimmy Barge, our Controller and head of Tax and Treasury.</p>
          <p>Please note that in addition to our press release, we have slides containing supplemental information available on our website. Before we begin, let me refer you to page number two in the web presentation and remind you that certain statements made on this call are forward-looking statements that involve risks and uncertainties. These risks and uncertainties are discussed in more detail in our filings with the SEC. Reconciliations for non-GAAP financial information discussed on this call can be found in our earnings release or on our website.</p>
          <p>And now I'll turn the call over to Sumner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jim. Good morning, everyone. Thank you for being with us today. The downturn that we have all witnessed over the past several months has really been historic in its severity, unprecedented in its global impact. Viacom's first quarter results certainly reflect that difficult reality. But they also point to a fundamental strength that I believe will take on more significance as the economy begins its recovery.</p>
          <p>While financial calamity always draws a crowd, a well planned strategy executed with understated resolve seldom gets headlines. However, as the recovery takes hold, it is these companies, solid, well run, strategically focused companies like Viacom that should and will command attention.</p>
          <p>Under Philippe's capable and insightful leadership with the contributions of Tom Dooley and the entire management team, Viacom has kept a tight leash on costs and financial leverage while it continues to fuel the company's creative engines, notwithstanding economic winds, notwithstanding short-term market turbulence. It is this vision that will keep Viacom creatively nimble, this determination that will keep Viacom operationally focused, this fortitude that will keep Viacom financially strong. And it is this commitment that will enable Viacom to deliver long-term results for its shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to National Amusements for a moment. As you know, we recently announced an agreement in principle with National Amusements lenders that extends the maturity date on NAI's outstanding debt to December 31, 2010. Additionally and very important, we have initiated a process that sells certain assets &#x2013; theater assets of National Amusements in the U.K. and the U.S. I can report that substantial preliminary interest is coming in. We are very encouraged by both the number of interested bidders and particularly the prices that are being discussed. Due to the fluid nature of this process, I naturally will decline further comment for now.</p>
          <p>So with that, I will return to the main event and turn this call over to my great friend and the greatest CEO of all, Philippe Dauman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Sumner. And good morning, everyone. I'm pleased you could join us today.</p>
          <p>Throughout the first quarter the economic environment continued to present challenges for our industry and for Viacom. The advertising and overall retail markets remain soft and visibility continues to be limited. Once again, however, the diversity of our revenue streams and our financial and operational discipline helped to temper the impact.</p>
          <p>We are focusing on what we do best: creating compelling content that resonates with audiences who now more than ever are seeking out sources of entertainment that they know and value. You can see this in box office receipts and in the growing consumption of content on television and other platforms. We are also working with our marketing and distribution partners on innovative solutions that provide even greater value to their consumers.</p>
          <p>We have and will continue to manage our business for the long term. While these recessionary conditions persist, we have seen signs in the last several weeks that the economy may be stabilizing. We are by no means out of the woods yet, but I am confident in our ability to manage through the times ahead.</p>
          <p>Over the past two years we have taken the right steps, increased operational efficiency, strengthened our balance sheet, accelerated creative development, grown our international business and exercised great discipline in our acquisition strategy and capital allocation. As a result, we are very well positioned, and as the environment begins to improve, we will have the invigorated brands and financial strength to pursue new growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>This morning I will run through our first quarter results and then get into some details about our segment performance. Tom will provide a more detailed review of the numbers and trends. Then we will open it up to your questions.</p>
          <p>There were no adjusted items in the first quarter of 2009, but there was an impairment charge in the first quarter of 2008, so my comments will reference the 2008 adjusted results. Consolidated revenues declined 7% to $2.91 billion in the first quarter. Media Networks revenues were down 8% in the quarter. As I mentioned during last quarter's call, we continue to see further deterioration of the advertising market as we entered the year, which resulted in a 9% decline in domestic ad revenues for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Worldwide affiliate fees grew 13% in the first quarter, reflecting both rate and subscriber increases, as well as 3% attributable to nonrecurring domestic revenues. Ancillary revenues declined 37% for the quarter, primarily as a result of lower sales of Rock Band. Keep in mind, however, that we were lapping the very strong sales of Rock Band in last year's first quarter, which followed the highly successful launch of the game in late 2007.</p>
          <p>The Filmed Entertainment segment saw revenues fall 5% on a worldwide basis, which included a seven percentage point negative impact from foreign currency exchange. As I'll discuss in a moment strong theatrical performance was not enough to offset ongoing weakness in the home entertainment market, as well as lower TV revenues and nonrecurring items from the first quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Cost containment remains a key focus for us, and we are on target to achieve the $200 million in savings we originally projected in connection with the cost savings initiatives we announced last December, and we will achieve additional efficiencies in the ordinary course. The company's net earnings were $177 million for the quarter, down 37% from the adjusted results in 2008. Diluted earnings per share for the quarter were $0.29, a 34% decline over adjusted diluted EPS of $0.44 in the first quarter of 2008. Our balance sheet remains strong fueled by substantial free cash flow. This financial strength positions us extremely well to operate effectively in this uncertain environment and to meet our future funding needs.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to our Media Networks segment. The deep and broad connections we forge with our audiences, coupled with our scale, continue to make us a marketing and distribution partner of choice. We provide an effective bridge directly to a narrowly targeted group on a particular channel or a broad swath of consumers across multiple branded channels and platforms.</p>
          <p>We once again delivered strong double digit growth in affiliate revenues, which reflects the benefit of the renewal agreements we reached early in the quarter. We continue to expand the reach of our networks and have increased distribution of our HD and digital networks, and there's growing interest in several of our international channels here in the U.S. For example, MTV India is already available in the U.S., and we are working with distributors to bring in more international channels to target multicultural markets in the U.S.</p>
          <p>We're also exploring a variety of new products, technologies and platforms with our distribution partners, including VOD dynamic ad insertion, authentication and fast-forward disabled VOD for certain prime time shows.</p>
          <p>Turning to our advertising results. The ongoing recessionary conditions had a significant impact in the first quarter. Marketers have been very cautious and discriminating, holding back much of their budget as they try to gain greater visibility in their own businesses. Nevertheless, there are real pockets of promise. Wireless, quick service restaurants and even discount retailers have showed continued strength. The results show a growing number of companies out there, even those in weakened market sectors, that are seizing the opportunity to grab market share, build equity in their brands and solidify their customer base.</p>
          <p>Importantly, we are not seeing any further deterioration. While it's too soon to make a call, over the past several weeks, we have seen the advertising market stabilize. Our upfront commitments to Q2 &#x2013; for Q2 are firm. Scatter volume has been soft to date, but pricing has remained stable.</p>
          <p>Moving on to ratings in our cable networks. We remain focused on improving weakness at certain networks and building on our upward momentum in others. This is the top priority for our Media Networks team. We made solid progress in this regard during the first quarter, building on new hits, new programming and new partnerships.</p>
          <p>Let me provide a few highlights. Nickelodeon continued to deliver a consistently strong performance with a first quarter peppered with huge hits. Nickelodeon's Kids' Choice Awards delivered its largest audience ever in all key demos and total viewers, and it was the number one cable telecast among kids two to 11 in the first quarter. Nick's newest series, The Penguins of Madagascar, premiered right after the Kids' Choice Awards to an enormous audience, and they continue to tune in. Penguins has jumped to the number three show for kids two to 11, and the buzz is continuing to build. In his latest prime time special, SpongeBob vs. The Big One, featuring Johnny Depp, our king of the sea in kids' TV, pulled in nearly six million viewers and drove record traffic to the SpongeBob website.</p>
          <p>When it comes to reaching young people on television, marketers know that MTV remains the place to be. Year-over-year ratings at MTV continue to be challenged, but we saw sequential improvement in the first quarter. As it has done so successfully in the past, MTV is reinventing itself &#x2013; this time to speak and connect with the Millennial Generation. Building upward momentum will take a little time, but we are already seeing the new programming we've introduced under this new brand framework gain traction. In particular, the Sunday night guys' block of programming is delivering consistently strong audiences with triple digit gains across the key male demos.</p>
          <p>As to VH1, VH1 is back. While the ratings were down slightly over the first quarter of 2008, which was the channel's most watched quarter in its history, sequential ratings growth improved by 6%, riding a wave of strong programming. We'll continue to add more programming, building on some of our most successful shows.</p>
          <p>BET ratings are now up, benefiting from new programming as well as several proven hits. Last week the network announced a new uplifting brand strategy that will capitalize on its stature as the leading media and entertainment brand for African Americans and consumers of Black culture. In addition, BET announced the launch of a new channel, Centric, that is aimed at the population of sophisticated, more affluent African-American adults, and will debut in the fourth quarter of 2009 in nearly 45 million homes.</p>
          <p>Comedy Central's first quarter ratings ebbed following its record-setting fourth quarter. We've already seen the tide begin to turn in the second quarter, and we are looking forward to maximizing a number of new partnerships such as our multiplatform deals with Jeff Dunham and with Levity Entertainment for a series of standup specials.</p>
          <p>The soft retail environment continued to weigh on sales of our consumer products, including Rock Band 2. Nevertheless we continue to build our song download business with more than 600 songs now available on disk and download and consumer purchase downloads of well over 40 million songs to date. We're developing new ways to build the value of this franchise, and as you all know, we're looking forward to the worldwide launch of The Beatles: Rock Band on 9/9/09. We expect to deliver improving results on Rock Band as the year progresses.</p>
          <p>Let's move now to the Filmed Entertainment segment. Paramount's first quarter results included a couple of notable items that had a significant impact on the top and bottom lines, namely the impact of foreign currency exchange and the overlap of a payment recognized in Q1 of 2008 in connection with an HD DVD exclusivity arrangement. Tom will provide some additional detail on that.</p>
          <p>As I already mentioned, consumers went to the movie theater in increasing numbers during the early part of the year, proving once again that compelling content for a great value is a winning combination. Paramount enjoyed a solid first quarter at the box office with strong carryover revenues from films released late in the fourth quarter. We also finished the quarter with a big opening of DreamWorks Animation's Monsters vs. Aliens, which to date is the number one movie of the year in domestic box office.</p>
          <p>The weak economy continued to dampen the home entertainment market, and Paramount was not immune to the impact. Consumers are particularly selective when it comes to acquiring catalog titles. In this regard, our focus on franchise pictures should serve us very well. Looking ahead, we have a strong slate for the rest of the year. Next week, the first of our major tent-pole films will open across the country. J.J. Abrams' truly remarkable reinvention of Star Trek premiered earlier this month in Australia and has already garnered rave reviews.</p>
          <p>Near the end of the quarter we will premiere Michael Bay's Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen. This is another highly anticipated film and the second installment of our successful Transformers franchise. And the second half of the year will bring, among others, Stephen Sommers' G.I. JOE: The Rise of the Cobra (sic) [G.I. JOE: The Rise of Cobra] and Martin Scorsese's Shutter Island.</p>
          <p>Our emphasis on long-term strategic leadership and operational discipline has created a strong and stable path for Viacom in this challenging environment, and we are confident it will further distinguish this company as we move into a brighter future where our world class brands and creative content can truly shine. If we continue to see stabilization of the economy as the year progresses, our strong foundation gives us the capability to excel in our operating performance, our generation of free cash flow and our ability to deliver long-term growth for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now I will turn it over to my friend and partner Tom, who will provide more details on our financial results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Philippe, and good morning, everyone. I hope you've had a chance to review our earnings release and the web presentation summarizing our first quarter results. Our 10-Q will be filed shortly and should be available later today. This morning, I'm going to take you through our results in a more detailed way, and I'll update you on the key factors impacting the remainder of the year. Also, I'll spend some time discussing our balance sheet and cash position.</p>
          <p>First, I'd like to turn to the consolidated results. From a total company perspective, revenues declined 7%. Foreign currency headwinds had a large impact on international growth rates in the quarter. A stronger U.S. dollar adversely impacted total company revenue growth by four percentage points. If you look at the breakdown of our international revenues in the quarter, approximately 30% were Euro-based and approximately 15% were U.K. pound sterling based. Total company expenses in the quarter declined 87 million. Approximately 50 million of which relates to cost savings associated with our fourth quarter restructuring charge. Of the 50 million, about half relates to compensation, while the other half relates to programming.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn to our segment results, and I'll start with the Media Networks group. Media Networks revenues declined 8% to 1.9 billion in the first quarter. The strengthening dollar adversely impacted worldwide growth rate by two percentage points. So on an organic basis, worldwide Media Networks revenue declined 6%. Domestic revenues decline 6%, and international revenues declined 16%. Foreign exchange had a 13 percentage point negative impact on international revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Page nine of our web deck provides a breakdown of Media Networks' revenue growth. As Philippe mentioned, domestic advertising revenues declined 9%. International advertising declined 24% in the quarter. Foreign exchange negatively impacted the international growth rate by 16 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Turning to affiliate revenues. Domestic revenues increased 17% while international revenues declined 6%. Foreign exchange losses impacted the international affiliate growth in revenue by 15 percentage points in the quarter. In terms of the drivers, approximately 70% of the growth in domestic affiliate revenues was from rate increases, and 30% of the growth was from increased subscribers.</p>
          <p>International growth was impacted by increases in subscribers, new channel launches, as well as rate increases. Worldwide affiliate revenue growth in the quarter included a three percentage point benefit from certain domestic revenues that are not expected to continue in the future. Moving to ancillary revenues. Domestic revenues declined 41% while international revenues declined 21%. Foreign exchange losses had a six percentage point impact on international revenues in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The domestic decline was largely due to lower sales of Rock Band as we comped against last year's Rock Band 1 results, and as we began shifting the sales mix from bundles to software. The decline in international was primarily due to lower consumer products revenue.</p>
          <p>Media Networks operating income of 629 million in the quarter was 9% lower than last year. The operating margin declined 70 basis points to 34% in the first quarter. If you exclude Rock Band, the core margins were 36% in the quarter. The decline in the core margin was principally due to the impact of lower advertising in consumer products revenue.</p>
          <p>Programming expense increased 3% in the quarter on a reported basis. The savings from the fourth quarter restructuring charge benefited programming expense by five percentage points. The growth in organic programming expense principally reflects our continued investment in original programming.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Filmed Entertainment. First quarter revenues declined 5% to $1.1 billion. Currency swings were a more significant factor for the studio in this quarter than in the past. Accordingly, the strengthening U.S. dollar decreased the worldwide Filmed Entertainment revenue growth rate by seven percentage points. Page 11 of the web presentation a breakdown of Filmed Entertainment revenues.</p>
          <p>Worldwide theatrical revenues grew 15% in the quarter to 283 million versus last year. Currency losses had a 10 percentage point impact on the growth rate. The increase in theatrical revenues was driven by the release of DreamWorks Animation's Monsters vs. Aliens, for which there was no comparable animation release in the prior year's quarter.</p>
          <p>Worldwide home entertainment revenues declined $47 million, or 9% versus the first quarter of 2008. Foreign exchange decreased the growth rate by seven percentage points. The decline in home entertainment revenues reflects fewer titles released in the current quarter as well as the prior year's recognition of 29 million of revenues related to the conclusion of our HD DVD agreement. TV license fees declined 9% to $308 million, reflecting lower network and syndication revenues.</p>
          <p>Filmed Entertainment generated an operating loss of $123 million in the first quarter as compared to an operating loss of $63 million last year. The $60 million decline in Filmed Entertainment operating income reflects the impact of P&amp;A spending for the March 27 release of Monsters vs. Aliens, the absence of income associated with our HD DVD exclusivity arrangement and fewer home entertainment titles released as compared to last year.</p>
          <p>During the quarter certain of Paramount's 2008 releases were made available to our Epix pay TV joint venture. Accordingly we recognized 57 million of revenue and 21 million of operating income at Filmed Entertainment related to the releases. We also recorded on $11 million of equity losses. So the net impact to Viacom was an increase in earnings per share of $0.01.</p>
          <p>Moving beyond the segment results. We incurred 33 million in total company equity losses from investments. The losses in the current quarter were related to our investments in Rhapsody America and minority investments overseas as well as the loss related to Epix that I just described. Other items reflect the loss of $19 million primarily due to foreign exchange losses as a result of the strengthening U.S. dollar. The reported tax rate in the first quarter was 36%.</p>
          <p>I'm now going to turn to our cash flow, our debt covenants and our upcoming funding requirements. Free cash flow for the quarter was $136 million. Page five of the web deck presentation provides the components of free cash flow. The decline in operating income was more than offset by lower capital expenditures, cash taxes and working capital uses. Recall that last year's capital expenditures included one-time expenditures related to the relocation of some of our cable channels.</p>
          <p>In terms of leverage, at the end of the quarter we had $7.4 billion of debt and capital leases outstanding and approximately 260 million of cash and cash equivalents. Our leverage ratio was 2.7 times. This compares to eight billion of debt and capital leases outstanding at the end of the last year. We ended the quarter with only $100 million drawn on our $3.25 billion bank revolver.</p>
          <p>During the quarter we used our cash balances to reduce amounts outstanding under our revolver. Accordingly, cash equivalents declined by $533 million to 259 million by quarter end. The bank revolver expires at the end of 2010, and the only financial covenant is for interest coverage, which for the most recent four consecutive fiscal quarters is required to be at least three times the coverage calculation at the end of the first quarter was approximately seven times.</p>
          <p>Of the 7.4 billion in total debt, approximately 800 million or 11% is floating rate, and 89% is fixed rate. The fixed rate debt has an average cost of 6.4%. The quarter end cost of short term variable rate borrowings under our bank line was under 1%. During the first quarter we repurchased $52 million of our floating rate notes, which mature in June, leaving 698 million outstanding. Given our unused capacity under our revolver, it is our intention to pay down the notes from our existing bank line.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to talk about some of the factors impacting the remainder of 2009. We expect to realize approximately 200 million in cost savings this year related to the restructuring charge we took in the fourth quarter last year. In terms of the timing, we expect the savings to be spread relatively evenly throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Media Networks programming expense growth will be weighted towards the first half of the year as we increase the level of original programming on certain of our networks. For the full year, programming expense should grow mid single digits on an organic basis. In terms of capital expenditures, in 2009 we will benefit since last year we incurred approximately 100 million in one-time expenditures to relocate certain of our cable channels into new office space.</p>
          <p>In summary, the global economic environment remains challenging, and a number of the difficulties that companies face are beyond their control. Many are being forced to sacrifice long-term investment in growth in order to address short-term issues. During these uncertain times, our strong brands and franchises, our operating discipline and our solid balance sheet have enabled us to continue to make investments for the long term.</p>
          <p>We remain focused on those areas that we can control, seeking ways to manage our cost structure, strengthen our balance sheet and maximize our cash flow. When the economy does turn the corner, we believe that this discipline and focus will enable us to take advantage of the opportunities that emerge.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to thank you for listening now, and we'll turn the call over to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And we'll go first to Doug Mitchelson with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and, Philippe, you seem to be optimistic or at least a little bit more optimistic about the ad environment. I wonder if you could do two things: one, talk about the kids upfront and what's happened so far and what you're seeing. And then on the upfront for the entertainment channels, what are advertisers telling you about budget volume and price, in particular for maybe MTV, as you approach the upcoming upfront? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Doug. Yes, I talked about &#x2013; started talking about it several weeks ago when we started to see the advertising environment stabilizing. I think you see out there, and recent statistics are bearing it out, the market's bearing it out, that our customers are starting to feel more confident about a recovery emerging later in the year and going into next year.</p>
          <p>Our kids upfront started several weeks ago, and we have been making strong &#x2013; getting strong commitments as we go forward. They will continue to unfold for the next several months. We've seen advertisers increase their spend in several important cases. The entertainment brands upfront is really just starting to get underway, so there's not that much visibility going forward.</p>
          <p>And as I said in my remarks, you do have some companies out there that are clearly challenged, some who would like to spend money on advertising, but they don't have the wherewithal to do it. But in many of those cases their competitors are pouncing and taking advantage of the opportunity to gain market share, and we're certainly focused on that. We're happy to sell the wonderful weapons that are our great networks including MTV to competitors fighting it out in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>So we're feeling considerably better than we felt two or three months ago as we enter this important upfront season.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I know you have lesser exposure to, I think, autos and financials, some of the other more cyclical categories, but are they telling you that they'll be back in the upfront at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's interesting. As you know, Doug, it's not a big category for us. And obviously in general that category has declined, including the small amount we have for ourselves, but we are seeing in automotive, for example, we are seeing some of the foreign manufacturers and lately one of the domestic companies coming in pretty strongly.</p>
          <p>So again, I think that where you have companies that have had to step back for a while, if they are going to have ongoing businesses, they have to spend. Advertising does work. That is proven. So, we &#x2013; we're seeing good stable pricing in the market. It's really an issue of the volume, which had been soft, starting to come back in as players prepare for a recovery and are trying to take advantage of what's left of the recession to gain market share so that they can really enjoy the fruits of the recovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Mark Wienkes with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. On the Media Networks margins only sliding like 70 bps year over year. I know some of that was the lower Rock Band revenue, but you also mentioned, I think, Philippe, early on the ability to achieve additional efficiencies on top of that 200 million run rate. I guess could you provide, well, is a less than a 100 basis point reduction a good run for the year? And then a little more context around the key levers of OpEx that you're modulating it at Media Networks this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously the revenue line is going to depend on how the advertising market plays out as the year goes on. Our affiliate revenues are pretty solid, so on the core part of our business, as Tom and I mentioned earlier, we are trying to contain costs to the extent they don't impact &#x2013; this is really important &#x2013; don't impact the building of our brands and our strategic direction.</p>
          <p>There continue to be opportunities in areas such as procurement, including on shows that we put on air, production costs relating to those shows. We are finding every way to coordinate among our networks to take full advantage of that. And the international marketplace, we continue to find ways to be more efficient and coordinating, if not globally, in various regions in which we operate. And at the studio as we go forward with our strategy of focusing on our brands and franchises, we are finding several opportunities to gain greater efficiency with our now very well established long-term strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just a follow up. So no change in the outlook for double digit organic growth in affiliate fees at the cable networks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're feeling very good about it. As you saw in the first quarter, it was probably &#x2013; there was a moderate increase in the allocation between fee rate increases and the subscriber, it was about 70-30 in the first quarter. So a lot of it now is rate increases, and there's a lot of visibility on that given the long-term nature of our affiliate agreements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next from Spencer Wang with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. Question probably for Tom just to clarify some of your comments on the programming expense growth. I think you said programming cost growth was 3% in the quarter, but it benefited from the restructuring charge in the fourth quarter of '08. Can you just explain how that benefited the programming cost growth -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as we said, we had 50 million of savings related to the fourth quarter. Half of those savings, or 25 million approximately, benefited the programming expense line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Were those personnel related, or was the pull forward of programming cost recognition from one -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you recall when we made that write-off what we did there was we wrote off or abandoned certain programming, and we also made a change in the amortization associated with some of the other programming where we went from 24-month amortization on certain of the reality-based programming to 12-month amortization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So those are the two factors that went into the net of 25 in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just a follow up, Tom, on &#x2013; when you said mid single digit programming cost growth on an organic basis, is that net of that benefit or is that on a reported basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's net of that benefit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's net of that benefit, Spencer, as well as it excludes the charge from last year, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then if you could just real quick maybe, Philippe, give us an update on Epix affiliation deals heading into the October first launch? That would be great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. We continue to be very much on track. We gained a lot of momentum at the cable convention. I don't know if you attended there, but we certainly &#x2013; you couldn't escape Epix. We are having productive discussions, many of which are at very advanced stages, with just about every distributor out there. So we feel we're going to have a very robust launch in October, and the programming wheel looks great. We have a lot of great hit movies, both recent movies since Paramount had two of the top three movies last year, continues to have a great slate going forward. And we have &#x2013; we're having a lot of fun in putting together packages from the three partners' libraries and greenlighting original series, looking for events. So it's going to be a great launch for us in October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Michael Nathanson with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I have two. One, going back to the Epix question, Philippe and Tom. Let's say worst case, you can't get the network launched on the terms that you like and the size that you like for the Epix. What happens to your serial financials if you can't get the network launched, and what else can you contemplate doing with some of the titles and the output if worst case this can't get done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Michael, there is no worst case here. I mean we have &#x2013; we're quite engaged in the discussions. We have &#x2013; you'll see the affiliate agreements being announced as we get closer to launch, so we are in good shape. And furthermore in addition to covering the movie costs on the Paramount side, we are creating a great new asset for Viacom and as well as our partners. So we're very excited by it. I think it's going to be an innovative value-building new brand for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then to both of you guys, on programming expense growth. We had thought when the year started you guys were pretty committed to growing high single digits program expense growth, and you've mentioned a couple factors this year mitigating why it's going to be lower. Do you thing longer term you guys can control program expense in the mid single digit range, or is this you're a bit anomalistic in how you're going to grow programming expense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think it's that &#x2013; it's anomalistic. It's &#x2013; part of it, as I mentioned, among the cost savings that we are achieving and continue to achieve are programming efficiencies. So we are able to get a lot more bang for the buck. So if you looked at how in the rosier general economic environment of a couple years ago, the amount of money that would be spent for the same programming, it would be considerably higher.</p>
          <p>So I think that we've taken this opportunity to get more efficient to put in some permanent efficiencies and how we view programming and how we order programming series, how we work with the third party production houses. And we're able to significantly increase our level of original programming without having a correspondingly significant increase in the related expense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Doug Creutz with Cowen and Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yeah, thanks. I wonder if you could talk about &#x2013; a little about Paramount. You clearly have a stew of franchises now that appear to be working the distribution deals with Marvel and DreamWorks. When do you think we can expect to see some margin expansion at Paramount? What's it going to take to get there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have made a number of structural changes that affect the cost line. We have also been able to now have a very clear strategic focus on our film development, the types of films we make. That should result in, all things being equal, in good margin increases. Of course we're impacted by the economy to the extent it's impacting DVD revenues, which is an important source of revenue. And as always in the movie business, it depends on how the movies play ultimately.</p>
          <p>We think we have increased the probability of success with the movie strategy that we have, and we certainly have structured the operation so as to minimize the downside to the maximum extent possible by having leaner organization, by being very judicious in capital allocation of the film business and by looking for new revenue opportunities.</p>
          <p>To the extent you have revenue streams such as Blu-ray DVDs growing, they are growing off a smaller base. They're each quarter now in the industry as a whole, it's close to 100% gains as the economy picks up, and you have more players out there in the marketplace. That should be a good factor, and that the margins are better generally for that business, and we have the sort of pictures that lend themselves to that platform.</p>
          <p>So, we are coming off a low base from a margin standpoint, and we expect to see structural growth. Such are the vagaries of the film business as we go forward in the next few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Michael Morris with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. Just if we could go back to that question on the films. It's obviously a very difficult business to predict given the top line variability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. There was a technical problem there. Could you start your question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no problem. I was just saying, just going back to the question on the films, it's very difficult for us to forecast, particularly given the top line variability, but can you talk a little bit about the cost reductions? I know that you reduced your slate this year. Is there a permanent reduction in overhead that we can be factored in?</p>
          <p>And also when you look at the cost of the slate this year, there are &#x2013; you have the three big tent-pole films, including the Transformers sequel. Can you give us maybe just a little more color? 2008's a tough year to compare to because there's so many distribution agreements, but just maybe you could help us out a little bit on how to look at the cost structure for the balance of the year.</p>
          <p>And then also just real quickly, on &#x2013; over at ancillary on Media Networks, the decline I assume is largely due to Rock Band, but what have you seen in your other consumer products over the last quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You're welcome, Michael. As far as the overhead at the studio, we had several factors that we achieved last year, which are benefiting us this year and going forward. One, we resolved the relationship with the principals of DreamWorks. That resulted in a significant structural overhead savings going forward. We integrated the Paramount Vantage organization. We &#x2013; in addition to those two factors, we were able to achieve a lot of other efficiencies.</p>
          <p>So we have a more efficient overhead structure at the studio, which will benefit us going forward. As far as production spending, since our strategic release plans involve in any given year are not having more than 20 pictures, and in fact there will be some years when we have fewer including those that we are distributing for DreamWorks Animation and Marvel, our production &#x2013; our net production spend is actually declining compared to prior year. Again, we're getting some benefit from the resolution of the DreamWorks principal situation.</p>
          <p>As far as your question on ancillary revenues at Media Networks, you're quite right; obviously it's impacted by Rock Band, but also in a difficult worldwide recessionary environment, consumer product sales in general have declined. So you look at various consumer products, whether they're licensed properties or DVDs, that &#x2013; there is some impact there. As the economy recovers, some of that should be alleviated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, as in the past, you will probably see the Filmed Entertainment margins really show the viability during the year in the fourth quarter when a lot of the major titles that were released through the year enter the home video window.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Do you know approximately the size of the overhead rationalization that you talked about from the change from 2008 to 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>50 to $80 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Anthony DiClemente with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just a couple of quick ones. Sorry if you answered these already. The first one is in terms of the stabilization in advertising, I mean should we be expecting another deceleration in the 2Q of that domestic advertising being down 9%? I mean should it be getting better or stabilizing from there, or if you can just guide us a little bit more on the model?</p>
          <p>And then on the affiliate fee side, that's 17% growth in domestic affiliate fees? If my model's right, I think that's off a very stiff comp in the prior year, plus 19%. So what's going on there? Tom, if you can just give us some more details on the affiliate fee increases. I know there's some one-time stuff in the quarter, but is that anomalistic, I guess, and what should we think longer term about the affiliate fee increases that you guys could sustain in the next couple years? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anthony, as far as advertising, again, we're one month into the quarter. As I mentioned, we have seen the environment stabilize. We are seeing people enter into the market. We are seeing more robustness as we head in the next few months in the upfront season. As far as prognosticating what that will mean on the pace of ad sales for the full quarter into the year, we just don't want to be in a position to make that projection. But we have seen over the last several weeks signs that are encouraging. Tom, you want to pick up on the affiliate fees?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the affiliate fee, we really aren't going to describe in too great detail. We do want to point out to people that three percentage points of the growth that were occurred in this quarter, that we do not effect that to be recurring in the future. They were unique to the quarter and wouldn't be comparable on a going forward basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So, but that 3%, that's to the worldwide, so what does that equate to on the impact to the domestic, 17%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Four percentage points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Anthony.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Imran Khan with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, thank you for taking my questions. Two questions. First on DVD market, you talked about slate being down. Can you give us some sense how is the revenue part released DVD doing? And secondly in the international market, it seems like international revenue, if I adjust for FX, was down like around 20%. Could you give us some color, what kind of trends you are seeing in the international market, is it getting worsening? That will be very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the first question on the DVD market because we really didn't hear the exact wording you used.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so the DVD seems like the slates are down, which is definitely impacting the home entertainment revenue, so I was trying to get a sense like how is revenue part released DVD doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the slates are down on a year to year basis in terms of the number of releases, and we are seeing some slight decline. It's not as severe as it was in the fourth quarter in terms of the comparables, in terms of the units that are being shipped, but it still is lower for the conversion rate that we spoke about in the fourth quarter, it's still lower than we had experienced in previous years.</p>
          <p>As far as international goes, U.K. is one of our biggest markets, and that's where we saw a relatively significant decline, as is Germany, also is one of our bigger markets. Foreign exchange was a big part of it, but half of the declines that occurred in those marketplace were pure organic declines due to the similar economic circumstances that you have going on in this country. They're great markets for us. Our networks are doing wonderfully there, and as the economies recover there, we expect to really continue to have a robust marketplace there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Imran.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Jason Bazinet with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just have two quick questions. Some of your peers have talked about sort of making the content available for free online and mobilely if you sort of keep your pay TV subscription intact. It seems like this &#x2013; the potential issue is a pretty big issue for Viacom given your demo so I was just wondering if you could elaborate a bit on sort of how you're planning on navigating the waters over the next three to five years? And then second, given your confidence on Epix, can you just walk through for us sort of the accounting treatment of how that will impact revenue and EPS, not numbers but just conceptually how it will flow through the income statement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Jason, I'll let Tom go through the flow through on Epix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But as far as our content strategy, we have learned a lot and what our consumers are looking for and how to navigate the on air, online and mobile distribution venues, and we will continue to learn as we will forward. Our relationships with our major distributors are very important to us so we have great partnerships there. We are working in conjunction with them.</p>
          <p>We have different strategies on release timing depending on what the nature of the programming is, so we are looking at how we do the windows on putting programming that appears on air and then online, and on mobile. We're able to use our very strong online presence to create more engaged consumers of our brands and programming and drive viewership on shows like The Hills, our Nickelodeon shows.</p>
          <p>And by the way, our branded online properties command some of the most robust CPMs out there because of the vibrancy of our brands. But what we need to do is to satisfy our consumers and make sure that we don't cannibalize any of our core brands to &#x2013; over the long term. And this is in the interest of consumers, the interest of the programmers, such as ourselves, and the distributors. So there's a lot of experimentation going on. There's been a lot of talk about working with the TV Anywhere concept, authentication. We are part of all the tests that are taking place in looking at new ways to get product to consumers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the accounting treatment for Epix, as I mentioned in the remarks, in the quarter we recognized $57 million of revenue. That's in accordance when the &#x2013; our revenue recognition policies, what we recognize upon availability for a window. Associated with those &#x2013; that $57 million of revenue if you looked at the margins on the films that were released or provided, there's about a $21 million operating income margin associated with the 57 million that was also recognized in the quarter.</p>
          <p>However, because this is a joint venture that we are in, we eliminate approximately half of that operating income associated with our equity interest in this venture and our funding commitments to the venture. All the funding associated with the venture is fully funded so these films are fully paid for on a cash flow basis. The net impact of the 21 of operating income less the 11 million of equity losses and tax affecting that amount is about $6 million, which brings us to about a $0.01 benefit to Viacom in the quarter on an earnings per share basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll take our final question from Ben Swinburne with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And thanks for squeezing me in. A couple of questions. On the balance sheet, maybe you could talk a little bit about your plans on the debt side? Are you comfortable, basically using the bank, the revolver, to have the revolver drawn sort of into next year? Are you looking for a certain rate in the market to sort of term out some longer-term debt as the credit markets continue to get better? So I'm just curious, Tom, on your thoughts on that front.</p>
          <p>And then, Philippe, on the kids upfront, which we've heard anecdotally is going fairly well, and fully acknowledging Nickelodeon's strong position there, any impact or thoughts on Disney XD, which is a relatively new player in that marketplace and how that might impact things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the kids upfront, yes, it is going quite well. Right now we have Nickelodeon continuing to pump out new hit programming. It's an extremely vibrant brand. We have a significant ratings lead in our core demo two to 11 over Disney now. I think in the first quarter it was in the order of 32% or so. We have over 100% lead over Cartoon.</p>
          <p>So we will continue to build the Nickelodeon brand, build new programming, and we expect to continue to see this prosper. And also Nickelodeon as I've mentioned in prior calls has a lot of room to grow internationally and a lot of room to grow in generating new long term forms of ancillary revenues, including in the recreational area and other licensing opportunities we have not yet availed ourselves of.</p>
          <p>Tom, you want to address the balance sheet question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. As far as the balance sheet goes, we feel that we're in really good shape there. As I mentioned, we only have $100 million drawn under our $3.25 billion facility with the banks. I also mentioned that the interest rate is just under 1% in terms of borrowing, so that is quite an attractive option.</p>
          <p>However, as you point out, the capital markets are opening up, getting more accessible. We could do an issue today. We're encouraged by the pricing. It's probably 200 to 300 basis points more efficient than it was a quarter or two ago. So the market keeps moving in our direction, and we'll analyze that and figure that out.</p>
          <p>As an overall goal for the company, though, we are moving to delever the company. The company generates very significant cash flows. Many of those cash flows are sort of netted out and come to us in the fourth quarter. We see that similar pattern emerging this year and will assess that our needs to reenter the capital markets, if we need to at all, at the end of this year. But right now we feel really good about our options and our ability to very cost effectively refinance the issue that's due this year and address any of the issues that will be coming down the road in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That makes sense. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to thank you everyone for joining us for our first quarter earnings call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, that does conclude today's call. We do appreciate your participation. You may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>