<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1126899" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-02-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>527</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James Bombassei, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Sumner M. Redstone, Executive Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Philippe P. Dauman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Thomas E. Dooley, Chief Financial Officer, Senior Executive Vice President and Chief Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Anthony DiClemente</participant>
      <participant id="6">Philippe Dauman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Thomas Dooley</participant>
      <participant id="8">Benjamin Swinburne</participant>
      <participant id="9">Michael Nathanson</participant>
      <participant id="10">Doug Creutz</participant>
      <participant id="11">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="12">Jason Bazinet</participant>
      <participant id="13">Rich Greenfield</participant>
      <participant id="14">James Bombassei</participant>
      <participant id="15">Imran Khan</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everyone, and welcome to the Viacom fourth-quarter 2007 earnings release teleconference. Today's call is being recorded. At this time I would like to turn the call over to the Senior Vice President of Investor Relations, Mr. Jim Bombassei. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Thank you for taking the time to join us for our fourth-quarter and full year earnings call. Joining me for today's discussion are Sumner Redstone, our Chairman; Philippe Dauman, our President and CEO; Tom Dooley, Chief Administrative Officer and CFO; and Jimmy Barge, who just joined us last month as our Controller, and Head of Tax and Treasury.</p>
          <p>Please note that in addition to our press release, we have slides containing supplemental information available on our website.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, let me remind you that statements made on this call relating to matters which are not historical facts are forward-looking statements. These forward looking-statements reflect our current expectations but involve risks and uncertainties that may cause our actual results, performance, or achievements to be different from that expressed or implied by these statements. Risks and uncertainties are discussed in our filings with the SEC. Reconciliations for non-GAAP financial information discussed on this call can be found in our earnings release or on the Viacom website.</p>
          <p>And now I'd like to turn the call over to Sumner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. I thank you for joining us today. Viacom's performance in 2007 was impressive, and impressive in multiple ways. Not only did we generate solid financial returns but our structural and operational progress moved us well down the path to maximize the value of our world-class assets. There is no doubt that we are building a solid new foundation for this company that has the potential to deliver expanded opportunities and even greater shareholder value.</p>
          <p>With a very clear vision of what needed to be accomplished, Philippe has made remarkable strides in his first full year as Viacom CEO. He is executing our strategy flawlessly, and he's delivering results that our shareholders expect. He and Tom and the entire Viacom management team have sharpened our focus in every key area, from program development and content distribution to brand extensions and new entertainment platforms. The result has been greater efficiencies and a renewed urgency and effectiveness in everything we do.</p>
          <p>You all know I am a big fan of content, and with good reason. As I have always said, it is content &#x2013; exciting stories, exciting experiences &#x2013; that makes the media world go round. And that is why I'm particularly pleased with the creative resurgence I see throughout this company. There's a great passion in our ranks, a renewed commitment to explore new areas and to develop innovative experiences. The strong connections that our on users have with our unparalleled media brands are becoming more and more valuable than ever to marketing partners who seek out highly engaged consumers. And our Filmed Entertainment, as you know, our operations are once again bringing crowd pleasing, critically acclaimed motion picture entertainment to the big screen even while they find innovative ways to make those movies available on as many platforms as possible.</p>
          <p>The bottom line is that I have tremendous confidence in our entire management team and their ability to continue to invest judiciously in our future and to rapidly expand our presence in core areas, and finally to grow our profitability and our shareholder returns over extended time.</p>
          <p>And with that let me turn this over to our esteemed CEO, Philippe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much, Sumner, for your gracious remarks as always, and good afternoon, everyone. I'm very pleased you could join us today to discuss our 2007 full-year and fourth-quarter results. Let me also welcome Jimmy Barge to our call. Tom and I were very pleased to have Jimmy join Viacom last month, and with Tom's leadership as our CFO we have built an outstanding team of finance executives with deep bench strength. I also want to wish our good friend Jacques Tortoroli all the best in his new role of CFO of MTV Networks.</p>
          <p>Now to the business at hand. 2007 was a year of positive change for Viacom, building a platform for sustainable long-term growth. We made substantial strides across our divisions in a number of critical areas. Along the way, we delivered on our earnings per share guidance driving long-term value for our shareholders. The work continues. And my confidence in our future success is higher today than ever. There has been a palpable change in the way we execute. We're faster, we're more entrepreneurial, we're taking appropriate risks, yet we're maintaining discipline. I view 2007 as a pivotal year. We now have a broader and stronger foundation on which to grow.</p>
          <p>Today I will quickly review both our full-year and fourth-quarter results and then go over some of the highlights for our businesses. Tom will take you through our numbers in more detail, then we will be happy to take your questions. Let's begin with our financial results. Some of the full-year and quarterly results in 2007 and 2006 that we will discuss this afternoon include adjustments. Detail on those adjustments can be found in our press release.</p>
          <p>Consolidated revenues for the full year grew 18% to $13.4 billion, and in the fourth quarter revenues were up 19% to $4.25 billion. Revenues in the Media Networks segment increased 12% for the year and 18% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Worldwide advertising rose 8% for the year and 9% in the fourth quarter. The scatter market was strong in the fourth quarter as supply tightened. We saw double-digit growth in pricing over the upfront. Worldwide affiliate fees rose 14% for the year and 11% for the fourth quarter. This growth was driven principally by rate increases across our core channels. Worldwide ancillary revenues grew 27% for the full year, and an impressive 72% in the quarter, reflecting sales of "Rock Band" and royalties on other video games including the "Guitar Hero" series.</p>
          <p>Filmed Entertainment delivered significant top-line growth with revenues up 28% for the year to $5.48 billion, driven primarily by theatrical revenues. In the fourth quarter, revenues grew 19% with the distribution of "Bee Movie" driving the growth in theatrical revenues. We made substantial progress over the past year in setting a new direction creatively for Paramount, which we are confident will yield positive results in the months and years to come.</p>
          <p>Adjusted operating income for the total company grew 6% to $3.01 billion for the full year and 15% to $985 million in the fourth quarter. This reflects higher total adjusted expense, which were up 22% for the full year and 20% in the fourth quarter. This growth was driven principally by higher distribution and programming costs.</p>
          <p>Net earnings from continuing operations increased 4% to $1.63 billion for the full year and 14% in the fourth quarter. Adjusted diluted EPS from continuing operations were $2.36, a 14% increase year-over-year. In the fourth quarter, adjusted diluted EPS from continuing operations were $0.84, up 29% over the comparable results in 2006.</p>
          <p>Now let me move to our Media Networks segment. Our business is based on incredibly strong brands, many of which are known the world over. We are redoubling our efforts to build those brands further, extending their reach geographically and into new lines of business while improving our returns. As we deepen our audience's connection with our brands, we can derive even greater value from our marketing partners. Our goal is to use our brands to become a great, global company. We have significant room to grow in this area and expect a higher rate of growth in our international markets compared with the U.S. and continued expansion of our margins there.</p>
          <p>The restructuring we completed has significantly enhanced our efficiency, and it's given us a stronger platform on which to build our business. We are very focused on reinforcing our MTV brand, expanding the reach of our Nickelodeon brand &#x2013; for example, launching Nick Arabia later this year &#x2013; as well as our comedy brands. Just today BET launched its network in the UK, delivering on our promise to expand the BET network's brand internationally. The UK version of channel will feature some of BET's top-rated programs, including "106 &amp; Park" and "College Hill," as well as topical news programming such as "Life and Death in Darfur."</p>
          <p>As we expand to new markets we have numerous ancillary opportunities to generate revenues without significant investment, through consumer products as well as recreation, such as branded theme parks and hotels. I've frequently talked about the investment we've been making in the area of original programming. Creative leadership is at the heart of everything we do. It drives our brands and ultimately our revenues. You saw what creative leadership can do this past year. With breakout hits like "A Shot at Love with Tila Tequila" &#x2013; who will by the way be hosting "Spring Break" on MTV &#x2013; and returning series such as "The Hills" and "Real World," MTV's ratings turned the corner in the fourth quarter. 2007 was MTV's 16th consecutive year at number one in the 12 to 24 demo. Building on this momentum, MTV has several new shows launching in March.</p>
          <p>VH1 enjoyed the highest-rated year in its history in 2007 and closed out the year with four of its original series ranked among the top 10 highest-rated basic cable shows for 2007. VH1 continues to score impressive numbers with shows such as "Celebrity Rehab," "I Love New York" reunion, and "Rock of Love" Season 2.</p>
          <p>Nickelodeon ended the year as the number one basic cable network for kids 2 to 11 in total day for the 13th consecutive year. It maintained a double-digit lead over its nearest competitor in total viewers. Innovative hits such as "Back at the Barnyard" and "iCarly," a new hit, continue to attract new audiences. "The Fairly Oddparents Movie: Fairly Odd Baby," which just aired on Presidents Day, was the number one telecast on cable this year among kids' demos and with the exception of the Super Bowl, the number one rated program in its demos on all of television, broadcast or cable, year-to-date.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile, let's not forget the most audience-absorbent show on TV, "SpongeBob," the perennial number one rated show on television among kids 2 to 11. On December 31, Noggin and The N split to become individual 24-hour networks. Early results are very positive, and we have a promising lineup of new programs to add to each network. Nick will close out this quarter with its annual "Kids' Choice Awards" on March 29. We will capitalized on the multi-platform opportunities that this event programming presents, from mobile voting, exclusive broadband video content on TurboNick, and Kids' Choice Awards themed environments in our virtual world.</p>
          <p>Though continuous experienced ratings challenges, BET is making progress on its ambitious multi-year programming strategies. The network launched 10 original series last year and brought back three returning hit series. "Sunday Best" built a solid following, and returning series "Keyshia Cole: The Way It Is" delivered 34% higher ratings than the first season. This quarter BET presented the inaugural celebration of the "BET Honors," celebrating the achievements of several African-American luminaries, and brought back the highly successful "Celebration of Gospel." Coming up next is "College Hill 5," "Rip the Runway," and the new original series "Iron Ring."</p>
          <p>2007 was the highest-rated year in Comedy Central's history in its core demographic of adults 18 to 49. The 11th season of "South Park" was the most watched season among total viewers since 1998. "The Daily Show" and "The Colbert Report" are back and have quickly regained their audiences. In fact January was Comedy Central's highest rated month ever in both primetime and total day in its core demo.</p>
          <p>TV Land delivered double-digit ratings growth in its core of adults 25 to 54 in the fourth quarter, which is continuing in the first quarter to date.</p>
          <p>Our progress in audience delivery in the fourth quarter helped us achieve solid growth in our advertising revenues. We were on target with our stated expectations, delivering more than 7% growth in domestic ad revenues. Like others, we benefited from the strike-related flow of ad dollars from broadcasted cable, particularly to TV Land and Nick at Nite. The double-digit scatter premiums we saw in the fourth quarter are continuing the first quarter of 2008. At this point, we expect our first quarter domestic ad sales growth to be comparable to what we experienced in the fourth quarter of 2007. With more original programming on the way, we feel good about our position for the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>To date, the slowdown in the economy has not impacted our ad sales. Moreover, most of our traditional lead advertiser categories, including movie studios, quick-service restaurants, beverages, and games, historically have been recession-resistant industries.</p>
          <p>The adoption of the C3 currency across all our channels is proceeding as we expected. We've made great strides in our commercial pod-busting initiatives, experiencing early success with viewer retention devices such as pod takeovers, quizzes, polls, and banners. We've also stepped up our use of integrated marketing solutions in which we commingle our brands or characters with those of our marketing partners, and co-created advertising. We're tapping into to our own creative resources to develop new advertising content to help our marketing partners better connect with our audiences. Recent examples include Pepsi and Target. We created mini-movies and mini-series for each of these premier advertisers, both of which over-index our average audience retentions.</p>
          <p>These innovative approaches that develop comprehensive solutions for our marketing partners have led to notable growth in the digital ad spend per advertiser, as well as more convergent deals. Convergent deals continue to account for about 40% of our digital ad sales. Late last year we formed the Digital Fusion Group, which develops customized digital marketing solutions for advertisers. They leverage online media segments such as social networking, gaming, and virtual worlds, and content created by MTV networks to create new digital ad products.</p>
          <p>Let me give you just one example. We recently created an immersive Web 2.0 experience for T-Mobile based on a 13-episode series called "Connected." Viral and social marketing tactics were used to generate buzz, and almost every one of our digital properties played a role. MTV.com integrated video on its site, Victed Games built a custom T-Mobile game, and "Connected" received prominent placement in the virtual worlds of Newport Harbor and the Hills. Most importantly, T-Mobile, our client, was very pleased with the results.</p>
          <p>Our digital presence continues to grow in many different ways. Over the past year we successfully forged multiple partnerships with leaders in the digital world, significantly increased our own portfolio of branded websites to more than 300 sites, and greatly expanded the distribution reach of our content across platform. Also in 2007 we added 205 new digital advertisers. Firmly established as a leader in the development of virtual worlds, to date we have attracted more than 20 top tier sponsors to participate in meaningful ways in our branded virtual worlds. We're also beginning to expand our subscription-based revenues through MyNoggin.com, Shockwave games and the sale of virtual items on Neopets.</p>
          <p>BET recently launched a vertical advertising network targeting African-American consumers across more than 30 premium content sites, and Nickelodeon launched a new ParentsConnect ad network bringing greater scale yet highly targeted audiences to our marketing partners.</p>
          <p>In the past several months we have forged a number of partnerships with select online video sites to deliver short- and long-form content from all our cable networks. Key partners include Microsoft, Comcast, Fancast, AOL, Bebo, Dailymotion, Veoh, GoFish, and MeeVee. The multiyear Microsoft agreement is particularly noteworthy because of the breadth of our strategic partnership and because it highlights Viacom's position as a preferred content partner for technology leaders. The deal which we announced December 19th encompasses advertising, content distribution, event promotions, and games over the next several years. Speaking of games, I'm sure you'll all agree that the pre-holiday launch of "Rock Band" was an unqualified success: two million units sold so far and more than 5 million songs sold to date. We plan to launch the game in Europe later this year, and we expect to be talking about this franchise for many years to come.</p>
          <p>And we're continuing to expand the games arena. MTV Games has signed an exclusive deal with Jerry Bruckheimer to develop a series of original video games. He will build a game incubation studio with us where gaming artists can develop new concepts and properties for distribution across multiple platforms. One of those platforms is sure to be mobile, where we are the number one provider of video content and growing strong. MTV Mobile saw the number of video streams nearly double in 2007 versus the previous year. While we continue to bring these deep branded experiences to every platform, we're also identifying new ways to expand the branded experience to our consumers, with our Nickelodeon brands leading the way.</p>
          <p>Let me give you just a few examples. Nickelodeon and Royal Caribbean announced the first Nickelodeon branded cruise, which will set sail in August and is selling very well. In our Nick on the Go partnership with Hertz, vacationing families can rent a fully portable preloaded media player packed with the kids' favorite Nick shows. Finally, Nickelodeon's first standalone theme park, Nickelodeon Universe, is slated to open in Mall of America on March 15.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to our Filmed Entertainment segment. Paramount Motion Picture Group had substantial box office success in 2007, regaining the number one market share position. "Norbit," "Disturbia," "Blades of Glory," "Shrek the Third" and of course "Transformers" were all major hits with audiences here and abroad. We also continue to deliver critically acclaimed films. "No Country for Old Men" won four Oscars, including Best Picture. Paramount Vantage's "There Will Be Blood" received two Oscars, and DreamWorks' "Sweeney Todd" took home one. In total we garnered 26 Oscar nominations this year for our films. We are very pleased with our multiyear distribution agreement with DreamWorks Animation, which adds significant value to our film business. Coming up in 2008 we're looking forward to "Kung Fu Panda" and "Madagascar 2."</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we plan to put more emphasis on our Nickelodeon, MTV, and BET movie labels and introduce our Comedy Central label over the next few years, taking advantage of the significant audience relationships and marketing muscle we have established through those brands. I'm very pleased with the progress we've made on the creative front, and our pipeline of projects is once again robust. With that in place, we are now laser focused on improving the bottom-line performance of our Filmed Entertainment segment.</p>
          <p>In the Home Entertainment arena, we continue to generate double-digit growth driven by new releases, such as "Transformers" and "Shrek the Third." Paramount is also moving aggressively in digital. In association with MTV New Media, "Jackass 2.5" was the first-ever studio-backed movie to debut on the Internet. Paramount is also the first studio to license its properties to the virtual world Habbo. And earlier this month we formed a new Mobile Entertainment Unit.</p>
          <p>Our 2008 slate is off to a great start with a record opening in January from J.J. Abrams' "Cloverfield," and solid performance from "The Spiderwick Chronicles," a Nickelodeon movie. We're looking forward to our second-quarter releases, "Shine a Light," which spotlights The Rolling Stones, followed by "Iron Man"; "Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull," directed by the incomparable Steven Spielberg; and Mike Myers' "The Love Guru."</p>
          <p>To wrap up, we feel very good about the progress we achieved over the past year. We have improved the structure of our organizations. We optimized our financial systems and processes. We reignited our creative machine to further build our brands. And we expanded and increased the profitability of our international businesses. We grew our digital businesses in dramatic fashion and forged strategic partnerships with Microsoft, Yahoo!, and other industry leaders. And we are expanding into new business ventures rooted in our powerful brands. This organization, I promise you, is energized, and we're taking our company to the next level.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn it over to my good friend and partner, Tom Dooley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Philippe, and good afternoon, everybody. I hope you've had all a chance to review our earnings release and the web presentation summarizing our fourth-quarter results. Our 10-K will be filed shortly with the SEC and should be available later this evening. This afternoon I'm going to take you through our fourth-quarter results in more detail, and I'll update you on the key factors impacting our outlook for 2008.</p>
          <p>Our remarks will focus on our adjusted results from continuing operations as discussed in our earnings press release. We believe that adjusted results, which exclude significant nonrecurring charges including gains on asset sales, are a better indicator of our core performance.</p>
          <p>At the beginning of the year we laid out a number of strategic and financial goals, and our executives did a great job on executing on these objectives. One of our key priorities was to allocate capital more effectively across the company. We reduced overhead and sold approximately $550 million worth of non-core and underperforming assets. That capital was redeployed into original programming and digital initiatives, as well as information system upgrades for things like our ad inventory management system.</p>
          <p>While there is more work to do in this area, we have already started to see the returns from this investment in both our rating and our financial results. We view the allocation of capital and the returns we generate on that capital as a critical factor in how we deliver value for our shareholders. In that regard we have begun to tie improvements in return on invested capital to senior management compensation goals.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our performance in the fourth quarter, Philippe reviewed the overall company revenue and EPS results, so I'm going to focus most of my remarks on the segment results. As I go through this, you may want to refer to the web presentation, which summarizes both the fourth-quarter and full-year results.</p>
          <p>Turning to the Media Networks group, the group generated 2.4 billion in revenue in the fourth quarter. That's an impressive 18% growth over last year's fourth quarter. Let's take a look at where that growth came from. If you'd like to follow along using the WebDex, page 9 provides a breakdown of the Media Networks' revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Worldwide advertising revenues rose 9% in the fourth quarter to $1.39 billion, with foreign exchange contributing 1% of that growth. So organic growth in worldwide advertising was 8%. That's up from the 5% in the third quarter. Domestic advertising revenues increased 7% led by strong growth at MTV, Nick at Nite, VH1, and TV Land. International advertising revenues grew 20%, and the organic international advertising revenue growth was 11%. The 9% difference between reported and organic growth was largely due to foreign exchange benefits. The strong organic growth was driven primarily by ratings performance and ad market strength in the UK, Germany, and the Benelux markets.</p>
          <p>Worldwide affiliate revenues were up 11% to $598 million, with foreign exchange benefits contributing 1% of the growth. Domestic affiliate revenues increased 10%. About 40% of the growth in domestic revenues came from increased subscribers, and 60% of the growth came from rate increases. International affiliate revenues increased 16% on a reported basis, with 8% of that growth driven by foreign exchange benefits. Worldwide ancillary revenues were up 72% in the fourth quarter to $460 million. Domestic ancillary revenues were up 113%, reflecting the successful launch of "Rock Band," royalties on "Guitar Hero," as well as strong home video sales related to the release of TNT's original movie "The Dale Earnhardt Story." Strong growth in domestic ancillary revenues is a great example of MTVN's Music Group using a deep understanding of its audiences to create exciting new products unique to their respective fan bases. These are great examples of brand extension that over time will allow us to drive improvements on return on invested capital.</p>
          <p>International ancillary revenues declined 5% in the quarter. This decrease was entirely due to the exiting of an international production business at the end of the fourth quarter 2006. Media Network's adjusted operating income for the quarter was up 14% from last year to $923 million. We continue to invest in program content and new initiatives like broadband to further engage our core audiences and drive long-term growth. The manufacturing and distribution costs related to the launch of "Rock Band" were the reason for the decline in the segment's operating margins in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to Filmed Entertainment, fourth-quarter revenues were up 19% to $1.8 billion, and operating income improved by 34 million to 118 million. Theatrical revenues increased 30% to 273 million, driven by an increase the number of films released, as well as the worldwide performance of DreamWorks Animation's "Bee Movie."</p>
          <p>Home Entertainment revenues increased $190 million, or 12% versus the fourth quarter of 2006. This performance was driven by "Transformers" and "Shrek the Third." In a crowded holiday home entertainment marketplace, "Transformers" was an unqualified hit, selling nearly 19 million units net worldwide, while "Shrek the Third" sold over 15 million units net. TV license fees were also up 23%, or $76 million, principally relating to mix and availability of titles. Current-year titles include the international distribution of "Mission: Impossible III," as well as "Dreamgirls" and "Norbit."</p>
          <p>The $34 million improvement in Filmed Entertainment operating income was principally driven by the Home Entertainment performance of "Transformers" and "Shrek the Third," and higher profit contributions from TV syndications and network TV sales. This growth was partially offset by the performance of certain fourth-quarter theatrical releases and a lower contribution from the home video catalog.</p>
          <p>Moving to taxes, full-year effective tax rate for adjusted fully diluted earnings per share from continuing operations was 36.6%, and the reported rate is 36%. The difference is related to discrete tax benefits realized this year. Free cash flow and share buybacks are the next area I'm going to cover.</p>
          <p>I'd like to spend a little bit of time on free cash flow. Operating free cash flow, as shown on page 5 of the web presentation, grew 9% in 2007 to $1.7 billion. As far as leverage goes, at the end of the year we had 8.2 billion of debt and capital leases outstanding, and our leverage ratio was 2.75. And as we have said in the past, we remain committed to maintaining our investment-grade rating. In addition, we continue to aggressively return capital back to our shareholders through our share buyback programs. During 2007, we repurchased 53 million shares, or approximately 8% of our outstanding shares at the beginning of 2007, for an aggregate purchase price of $2.2 billion. In fact, in the two years since the split, we have repurchased 15% of our outstanding shares. We plan to continue repurchasing our stock in a disciplined way, as we believe it is a great way to return value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our guidance. For the three-year period from 2008 to 2010, we expect to deliver low double-digit annual growth in diluted net earnings per share from continuing operations. This outlook is based off of 2007 adjusted diluted net earnings per share from continuing operations of $2.36.</p>
          <p>Now, I'd like to touch on a few points with respect to some of the near-term contributors to our outlook. As we continue to roll out "Rock Band" domestically, as well as internationally later this year, we expect that the lower relative operating margin of these sales will reduce Media Networks' margins through the first half of the year. In Filmed Entertainment, results can be significantly impacted by the timing, number, and mix of theatrical releases and associated P&amp;A expenses. As in 2007, the seasonality and profitability in 2008 will be weighted to the back half of the year. In the first half of the year, as Philippe mentioned, we will have a number of major films, including "Indiana Jones IV," "Iron Man," "Kung Fu Panda," and "Love Guru."</p>
          <p>In terms of capital expenditures, we are relocating several cable channels into new offices in 2008. These moves increase capital expenditures by 75 to $100 million in 2008. This increase is a one-time event. As we look forward to 2008, we are targeting a tax rate of 37.5%. We will refine this as we go through the year and get a better sense of the domestic versus international profitability mixes.</p>
          <p>Wrapping up, we believe we have made great progress in the past year in terms of sharpening our strategic focus, strengthening our competitive positions, and reinforcing our core brands. We've done this, while at the same time putting a greater focus on how we allocate and deploy our capital. We have healthy and growing businesses that by their nature, are not capital intensive. We are very efficient in generating free cash flow, and we have the highest return on capital of our large-cap peers. We will continue to focus on driving bottom-line growth, particularly free cash flow and EPS, and we look to do this by growing organically. We believe our brands and businesses are very well positioned to achieve our goals, and we are excited about our future.</p>
          <p>With that, thank you for listening, and now we'll turn the call over to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And we will take our first question from Anthony DiClemente with Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have two questions. First, on advertising growth. The plus 7% in the quarter, if you look across other cable nets, it was slightly higher, and then moving into '08. I guess my question is, a reason that it could be not the high single digit or double digit growth is because of the ratings, but the ratings have improved. So, the question is, what do you think needs to happen for that ad growth to kind of inch up beyond the 7%? And then the second question is, just on the margins, and I understand that in the quarter, "Rock Band" margins brought down the cable networks, but if you just isolate the domestic cable networks' margins, did they expand or contract in the fourth quarter? Maybe you can give us some color behind that. Thanks a lot, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anthony, on your first question relating to advertising growth, where we had a very good sequential improvement quarter-to-quarter, which does reflect improvements in ratings and the scatter market, we were pleased with the 7 plus percent growth. You did see some higher growth in some other networks that were generally older-skewing. A lot of the fall-off from broadcast networks benefited the older demos, and in fact we saw a lot of benefit in our TV Land and Nick at Nite networks. On a going-forward basis, with the kind of ratings momentum we have across several of our networks, clearly if we continue to maintain that, we will perform relatively well, we believe.</p>
          <p>Also, as we manage our ad inventory, as we provide our customers with integrated marketing solutions, we expect to do well. We gave you some guidance. We think that as to the first quarter, our domestic ad sales growth will be comparable to the growth we experienced in the fourth quarter. Beyond that, we'll see. And obviously, while we, as I mentioned in my remarks, we have as our advertisers many advertising recession-resistant industries, we are not completely immune to economic circumstances.</p>
          <p>As to your second question on margins ex "Rock Band," if you will, we had &#x2013; the margins in our Cable Networks group were slightly lower ex "Rock Band" than the prior year, but -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that ex, is that domestic? I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Combined.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Combined.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Combined. What about -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In '08 we expect ex "Rock Band" our margins to be comparable to what we had in '07.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But you just look at it on a combined basis. Is there any way you can talk about just isolating domestic in the fourth-quarter margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the fourth quarter it's essentially flat if you take out Rock Band.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Benjamin Swinburne with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon, guys. Tom, you made some comments about &#x2013; or maybe Philippe &#x2013; upfront about the international margins, and I think you said you saw additional opportunity for expansion there. That seems to be a little bit of an improvement in tone from the last call where you talked about sort of reaching levels that you thought were sort of the go-forward rate from here. Is there a change in your view on margin expansion internationally? Or maybe you could just give us some color on how much you think is left to go in those markets.</p>
          <p>And then second, anything on the film side that we should be looking for in '08 on the HD DVD migration out of HD DVD to Blu-ray for Paramount or any delays on the slate as a result of the strike that we should be factoring in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, as far as the international margins, what I've said is that we took a number of restructuring steps in '07, to result in a going-forward basis in a 10 to 15% improvement in margin points. We have achieved that in the restructuring. We now have a very efficient platform. We are growing our revenues; we've had strong performance in territories like the UK, Germany, Benelux, as Tom indicated. So we do expect that going from here with the rationalization of our cash flow organization that we have room for margin improvement, largely driven by revenue improvement on a going-forward basis, but there is still some efficiency opportunity.</p>
          <p>As far as HD DVD, we greatly valued our partnership with Toshiba and are happy we entered into the agreement with them. With the announcement they recently made, we are now free to release our titles on Blu-ray, and we will follow the consumer marketplace in determining what titles we release. But we are quite happy there's been a unification of this important new revenue stream for our whole industry.</p>
          <p>As far as the strike and its impact on the slate, it has not impacted us. We were well prepared. We had a very robust pipeline; we have a very solid slate for '08 and into '09. And as we go forward from there and beyond, we are, as I mentioned, very focused on building up our label strategies using the MTV, Nickelodeon, BET and Comedy Central brands to begin with &#x2013; as well as our franchised pictures, of which we have many,</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Michael Nathanson with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I have a couple for Tom on games and one for Philippe. Tom, on the game side, could you tell me what the operating profit impact was this quarter from the combined "Rock Band" and "Guitar Hero"? And then ultimately, where could profit margins go for "Rock Band" given the business module, which is more, let's say, equipment based?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, just to get you up on that one real quick, we're not going to release the profit margins or any of the details on that at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But could we talk about what type of business margins, what profit margins you get to with a "Rock Band" type of business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little too early to tell. There's a lot of pieces to the equation. One of the big pieces, down the road, will be how many songs were downloaded. We're doing really well right now, and we'll have to see how that business matures when we get a full install base and then how that business plays out year-after-year. So it's kind of hard to forecast. We're early into &#x2013; we've got four or five months behind us going into this business. So we're a little reluctant to get out there and start predicting margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then for Philippe --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On this &#x2013; there's an interesting component &#x2013; it's still a business with the songs and the other things we get into with this. It's a little bit like the razor, razor blade business. You get the platforms out there, and there are a lot of razor blades you can sell off of that, whether it's songs or other peripheral units or additional products and functionalities. So it's a very interesting business. As I mentioned, we think this is going to be a very good franchise for us for many years to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And you mentioned before that you're laser focused on the studio in terms of getting operating leverage. What will change in '08 to make this business more profitable, given how strong the revenue growth has been this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we &#x2013; again it's the continuing focus on the mix of our pictures, with a high emphasis on franchised pictures, a high emphasis on using our marketing muscle, high emphasis on efficiency and how we operate the business and how we market the movies. Again, our branding strategy will help in that regard, and as we go forward we are going to continue to move toward diversification of our business, which I will remind you after the split was a very pure motion picture studio. So we're building digital revenues, for example, which are very good from a margin standpoint. We are looking at ancillary opportunities, whether it's a theme park development, consumer products. And we're also beginning our efforts in television production, principally for cable, including our own cable networks. So as we move forward with that, we believe we have room to grow our margins and bottom line results in the Filmed Entertainment segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Doug Creutz with Cowen and Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yeah. Could you talk about a little bit &#x2013; obviously you've been growing your video game business, and we've seen two major, proposed at least, transactions in this space in the last three months. How are you thinking about it strategically? And are you interested in growing your business there significantly over where it is? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as the games business, we did acquire Harmonix which yielded the "Rock Band" game. We're going to build that platform. We entered into an agreement with Jerry Bruckheimer to help us develop games. We are making investment in the casual games space, that is principally organic. We think we have the assets within our organization to build a very interesting games business that incidentally ties into our brands. For example, "Rock Band" just really ties in well from a strategic standpoint, from a marketing standpoint, and otherwise to our music-based franchises. So that's our principal focus. We don't anticipate participating in this big battle that's going on between the pure game companies and building up their scope. We view the games business as an interesting business for us to grow organically with perhaps a modest relationship such as the ones I described, and like the Harmonix acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Spencer Wang with Bear Stearns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon. So my first question is for Philippe. I was wondering if you could just drill in a little bit more on the commercial ratings initiatives? I believe before initially some of your teenager-skewing networks saw about a double-digit impact from commercial ratings versus live ratings. Can you just maybe help us quantify with some of the new initiatives how that's currently trending?</p>
          <p>And then second for Tom just on CapEx, excluding the corporate, some of the new headquarters for some of the networks do you think, what's CapEx going to look like in '08 versus '07? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Spencer. On the commercial ratings, we've taken a number of initiatives, as I mentioned. VH1 is probably the network where we have the most shows that have been reformatted for the shorter three-commercial pods instead of two. And there we've seen about 200 basis points in improvement in the drop-off based on what we see so far. It's still early for all these initiatives. We see a lot of audience retention on specific initiatives that relate to having quizzes in the middle of the pods. When we have pod takeovers, the retention is much stronger. We've seen a lot of improvement in the "10 Spot," for example, on MTV. So it's accumulation of all these measures which have allowed us to so far feel pretty good about commercial ratings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then the CapEx -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, Spencer. In terms of CapEx, we think that 2008 excluding the build-out of the new space that we're going into, will be in the range from 225 to 250, which is pretty much equal to what we did in 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Jason Bazinet with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much. I believe on the call you talked about management's compensation being tied to returns on invested capital. I think you guys have very good ROICs, but it seems like the gap is a little bit wider depending on whether you calculate it with or without goodwill. Could you just talk a little bit about which ROIC measure you're being comped on? Is it with or without goodwill or both?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we are doing &#x2013; our compensation system just in general has several metrics associated with it: operating income, free cash flow, and then we have a number of other measures that relate to meeting strategic objectives. Those that are set in our budgets as well as in our long-range plans. We're introducing in '08 return on invested capital as one of those strategic objectives. So as &#x2013; we are in the process of educating our divisions and operating people as we go through the different areas this year. And as we head into next year's compensation system, it will be a more specified and larger component of our compensation system. So this is the first year we're really introducing that specific measurement to the troops.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, this is Tom. As we go through it, we're going to allocate the capital across the firm. The capital that we will initially allocate will be based on the market cap of the company. And then we will focus on their ability to improve that allocated market cap for each one of their divisions. So in effect, it would include goodwill, and implied goodwill on top of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Even including future goodwill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Including whatever the market cap suggests the goodwill of the company is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It really tries to approximate a hard value for the company, associated with the market, the stock price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Rich Greenfield with Pali Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. A couple questions. Looking at what you did with Noggin and The N, the split-up, wondering if you could give us some sense of how significant that could be relative to &#x2013; I think that the channel that you replaced was Nickelodeon Games and Sports. And the type of margin opportunity, as well as what other networks you could do something like that with? And I mean, in terms of a rebranding of a network or repositioning of a network; some of these smaller digital networks that you've had. What are the next things you kind of have your sights set on?</p>
          <p>And then a second question, just following up on the film business. The DreamWorks relationship on the live action side. A lot of press speculation about the relationship and what's going on there. Could you just give us an update on what you'd like to see happen, and kind of timeframe for when events play out? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Rich. As far as Noggin and The N, again, we just split up into two networks at the beginning of this year. So we're barely two months into it. But we're very encouraged by what we see so far. Noggin is seeing some great improvement in viewership. So far ratings are up, and certainly we hope to on both Noggin and The N having the extra hours that are more branded, and more relevant, we hope to monetize that as we go forward.</p>
          <p>As far as other digital nets that we have, which we have &#x2013; several of which work very well for us and for our customers and ultimate consumers. But as we go forward, we always look at new opportunities, new brands, new content, and clearly they're an asset for us. And we will continue to try to grow our brands using the digital nets as appropriate.</p>
          <p>Coming to DreamWorks, we have &#x2013; I've been spending a lot of time with Steven Spielberg. Every time I go to Los Angeles, as recently as last week, I spend some time with him. Last Friday he &#x2013; I was with him when he and Harrison Ford made a presentation to our international distributors for "Indiana Jones," he was absolutely terrific. Afterwards, he met with Brad and myself, and was discussing with us a pretty exciting idea he has for a franchise movie, and he told me, "I'm going to make the kind of franchise movies your talking about." And we're going to explore that with him.</p>
          <p>So he is, he's a great filmmaker. I personally enjoy him tremendously. We will have a relationship with him for a very long time to come in one form or another. And we both agree that we would proceed calmly, deliberately, with a lot of mutual respect, to see what structure the relationship takes. If he feels there is a different structure that works better for him in working with us, and vice versa, we'll explore it. So we don't have a specific timetable right now, and we'll just see how our relationship progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And from the standpoint of your film division's overall profitability, how important do you view the current relationship with DreamWorks live action being over the next few years, and the growth you're expecting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're looking &#x2013; we have to analyze our slate over multiyear periods, and we have to look at it strategically. As I've mentioned strategically over the long run, we do want to have a focus on brands and franchises. Clearly DreamWorks, more specifically Steven Spielberg, is an important component of franchises such as "Indiana Jones," which is a Paramount project he's obviously directing. And George Lucas is involved and Harrison is involved. And Steven was a producer of the Michael Bay-directed movie, "Transformers," will be involved in "Transformers II." So, as I've said, Steven Spielberg is someone who is important to us. We will be working with him because he has an involvement; we had involvement with him before on many of these franchises and sequels and other fresh projects. To me, that is the core of our relationship there, it's Steven Spielberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you sir. That question will come from Imran Khan with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Thank you for taking my questions. One quick question. Do you see potential accretion from the <mark type="inaudible" /> revenue stream resulting from the telcos' intention to provide video services? Or also, could you give us some color, like what kind of impact do you expect to see when that Comedy Central renegotiation comes out, and what's the timing of that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're already experiencing a healthy relationship with the telcos and some of the growth that you see in our affiliate category is reflective of that, and we see them as great distributors and great partners in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with regards to Comedy Central renegotiation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So with regards to Comedy Central, Comedy Central is a much more powerful brand and a much more successful network with a lot of great franchises than it was many years ago when many of the current affiliation agreements with Comedy Central were entered into. So as we go forth we expect to have constructive dialogue with our partners, both cable, satellite and telcos, about the value that we bring to them and to their consumers on Comedy Central. And we expect to get nice rate increases.</p>
          <p>But I think that's true also of our overall portfolio brands. We have 25% of ad-supported cable viewing and a much lower percentage, much lower percentage, of affiliated revenues. So yeah, we expect to see that grow and at the same time though, we will be providing good value through cooperation on VOD, on broadband and other initiatives, high-definition, with our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that does conclude our question-and-answer session. At this time I'd like turn the conference back over to Mr. Bombassei for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Want to thank everybody for joining us on our Fourth Quarter Earnings Call. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that does conclude our conference. We do thank everyone for your participation. You may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>