<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1169472" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>577</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Arun Sarin, Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Andy Halford, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4">Robert Grindle</participant>
      <participant id="5">Arun Sarin</participant>
      <participant id="6">Andy Halford</participant>
      <participant id="7">Simon Weeden</participant>
      <participant id="8">Vittorio Colao</participant>
      <participant id="9">Mark James</participant>
      <participant id="10">Justin Funnell</participant>
      <participant id="11">John Karidis</participant>
      <participant id="12">Aur&#xE9;lie Husson-Dumoutier</participant>
      <participant id="13">Nick Delfas</participant>
      <participant id="14">Paul Howard</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jerry Dellis</participant>
      <participant id="16">Terence Sinclair</participant>
      <participant id="17">Andrew Beale</participant>
      <participant id="18">Paul Donovan</participant>
      <participant id="19">Dean Tenerelli</participant>
      <participant id="20">Darren Ward</participant>
      <participant id="21">Christian Kern</participant>
      <participant id="22">Graham Ruck</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following presentations are being made only to and are only directed at persons to whom such presentations may lawfully be made. You may not disseminate any recording of this call in whole or in part to any member of the public or to any person to whom the communication may not lawfully be made. Any information in this communication relating to the price of which relevant investments are being brought or sold in the past or the yield on such investments cannot be relied upon as a guide to the future performance of such investments. These presentations do not constitute an offering securities or otherwise constitute an invitation or inducements to any person to underwrite, subscribe for or otherwise acquire securities in any company within the group.</p>
          <p>The presentations contain forward-looking statements, which are subject to risks and uncertainties because they relate to future events. In particular, such forward-looking statements include but are not limited to statements with respect to Vodafone's expectations as to expected savings from cost reduction initiatives; expectations as to levels of capital expenditure and operating expenditure; targeted revenue from the group's Total Communications initiatives; the anticipated impact of exchange rate movements on the group's results for the current fiscal year, the anticipated completion of acquisitions, the anticipated launch of operations and the group's expectations for revenue, adjusted operating profit, capitalized fixed asset additions and free cash flow for the 2009 financial year.</p>
          <p>Other factors, which may cause actual results to differ from these forward-looking statements, can be found by referring to the information under the headings Cautionary Statement Regarding Forward-Looking Statements and Principal Risk Factors and Uncertainties in Vodafone Group Plc's annual report for the year ended the 31st of March 2008. The annual report can be found in our website, www.vodafone.com.</p>
          <p>The presentations also contain certain non-GAAP financial information. The group's management believes these measures provide valuable additional information in understanding the performance of the group or the group's businesses because they provide measures used by the Group to assess performance. Although these measures are important in the management of the business, they should not be viewed as replacements for, but rather as complementary to the comparable GAAP measures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for joining us. I'm here with Andy Halford and we will be giving you our perspective on the first quarter and the progress we are making in the business. Vittorio Colao and Paul Donovan are here with us and they will join us for the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Overall, this was a more challenging quarter. In our European results, we clearly saw a weaker economic environment in Spain, but strong data revenue growth trends continue. In EMAPA growth remained strong in India at about 50% and whilst we continue to execute our turnaround in Turkey, growth has slowed here as expected.</p>
          <p>So, let me first turn to the numbers beginning with the group picture. Overall group revenues grew to &#xA3;9.8 billion, up 19.1% on last year, including a significant uplift for the movement in the euro-sterling exchange rate. On a pro forma basis, including India and with constant currency, growth was 3.7%. In Europe, where our markets remain competitive, total revenue was up 15.5% with 13.5% benefit from the euro movement and 2.2 from DSL acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Revenue declined by 0.2% on an organic basis with our strategy to drive increased usage offset by ongoing price reductions. Once again, we experienced strong organic growth in data with revenues up 26%.</p>
          <p>In EMAPA we continue to deliver good top line growth. Total revenue increased by 30.5%, reflecting in particular the acquisition of Vodafone Essar. On an organic basis total revenue growth in EMAPA of 9.2% was still driven substantially by customer growth and includes Turkey for the first time. Our customer franchise continues to strengthen. We now have over 269 million mobile customers on a proportionate basis and over 234 million customers on a statutory basis. Net additions were 9.1 million in the quarter. We posted 1.3 million net adds in Europe and 7.8 million in EMAPA including 5.1 million in India.</p>
          <p>Let me now take you through some of the important trends that we saw in the first quarter. In Germany, organic service revenue declined by 1.9% with customers continuing to adopt better value price plans and ongoing pressures on SMS and incoming revenues. Usage growth remains robust with outgoing call volumes up 19%. Data growth remains strong at 25% with good and strong trends in PC connectivity both in enterprise and consumer. Vodafone Germany is also proving to be a strong reseller of our core DSL with a 104,000 adds in the quarter.</p>
          <p>In Italy, organic service revenue growth was 0.6%, whilst the Bersani decree is no longer impacting the growth rate we've had a tougher comparative quarter due to new voice and messaging tariffs that benefited the first quarter last year. The business retains a strong focus on contract and business customers. Data revenue increased by over 40% again with strong PC connectivity growth and an increased contribution from mobile Internet.</p>
          <p>Service revenue declined by 2.5% in Spain on an organic basis. Competition has been intensifying for some time with rising penetration and new players. The Spanish economy has also weakened significantly and we had a strong quarter last year, which makes for a tougher comparison.</p>
          <p>These factors led to a decline in voice revenue with slowing customer growth and an acceleration in the rate of ARPU decline. Messaging revenue also fell largely reflecting the timing of promotions. Data revenue growth slowed due to the absence of the 100 day 100 car promotion this year and the introduction of price gaps.</p>
          <p>It is difficult to split precisely the reduction in growth from the prior quarter but we estimate around two-thirds from the economic and competitive factors and one-third from a tougher comparison. Unemployment is rising particularly in the migrant worker segment where we've been a strong performer. GDP growth is also slowing and we've seen rapid tariff optimization, which is easier in the Spanish contract market given lower monthly commitments.</p>
          <p>Whilst this has been a tough quarter for Spain there are a number of initiatives underway to reinvigorate growth and we should not forget how strong growth has been over a prolonged period.</p>
          <p>U.K. remains one of our most competitive markets with service revenue growth of 2.1%. Voice pricing pressures remain high combined with slightly lower usage growth. Messaging growth slowed, as we are a year on from the refresh of our text bundles. The data story remains positive with an increase in revenue growth back above 30% with 85,000 PC connectivity adds in the quarter including strong take up in our USB modems.</p>
          <p>While the competitive environment is clearly continuing to impact the U.K. business, we do feel there are signs of the current economic weakness although it is hard to split the two effects.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to EMAPA, and to India, and Turkey in particular. In India, we have continued to execute well. Total pro forma revenue growth in the first quarter was 52% with a year-on-year customer growth of 60%. Monthly net adds in the quarter improved to a record 1.7 million ahead of the launch of our Spacetel circles, which will occur later this year. During July, we exceeded the 50 million customer mark. We continue to execute on our plans in Turkey, but the competitive, political and economic environment is very challenging. Service revenue growth in the quarter was 3.7% and was hit by a large cut in termination rates. Adjusted for this growth, growth was nearer 11%. The next key step is to complete our ongoing overhaul of the network to enable us to compete more effectively in the market and this will be done by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., Verizon Wireless has posted another strong quarter with net adds of 1.5 million resulting in over 10% growth in customer base since last year. Verizon will report its June quarter on July 28. Other highlights of our EMAPA performance include continued strong organic service revenue growth of 18% in Egypt, 15% from Vodacom in South Africa and 8% in Romania.</p>
          <p>Before I turn to guidance, let me briefly tell you about the progress in our strategy. In terms of cost reduction, our major cost programs around IT, outsourcing, network supply chain, data centers are all established and delivering savings. Cost remains an important focus for the management team and from the beginning of this financial year we've started to implement a wide range of further initiatives to streamline our business processes and drive cost out of the business. For example, in IT we are consolidating software licensing maintenance agreements; data storage; we are rationalizing our property and our advertising production cost as well as centralizing our roaming activities. These are just some of the long list of ongoing initiatives in light of the current environment. Some of these of course will be accelerated to drive earlier savings. In addition, we are even more focused on commercial cost discipline particularly, acquisition and retention costs, advertising and publicity.</p>
          <p>Next, let's look at the Total Communications, which is now 15% of our revenues. Data revenues for the group has continued to be strong with a 29% organic growth. Growth is coming primarily from PC connectivity not only through strong business performance but increasingly from consumers as USB modems become more widespread. Across the group, we now have 29.9 million 3G devices including 3.1 million 3G connect cards mostly in Europe and double last year. We now have around 3.5 million handheld business devices up 115% on last year.</p>
          <p>Fixed line revenues increased to over &#xA3;600 million. We now have over 3.7 million fixed broadband customers in 13 markets across the group with 2.8 million in Germany, up 26% on last year.</p>
          <p>Finally, there have been a number of portfolio changes in the quarter. We've strengthened our fixed broadband position in Germany by buying out the minorities in Arcor. We've been awarded the second mobile license in Qatar and expect to launch services by the end of the financial year and most recently we agreed to take control of Ghana Telecom, a leading player in that market.</p>
          <p>Let me conclude by looking at our guidance. This has clearly been a more challenging quarter for the group particularly in Spain. Overall our pro forma growth rate in the quarter at 3.7% was somewhat below the growth rates implied by our guidance range for the year and although it's too early to see a clear pattern emerging, we are beginning to see a greater impact from the current economic environment than previously envisaged.</p>
          <p>There are also early signs of delays in handset replacement with lower than expected equipment revenue, which is good for our profitability. We have already been seeing an increase in our SIM-only activity and this is a trend we will encourage. As a result of these recent trends, we now see revenue around the bottom end of our outlook range. As I've said, we remain focused on driving costs out of the business and the current operating environment will see us even more focused. So we still see the outlook for the adjusted operating profit, CapEx, and therefore free cash flow, unchanged. This illustrates the resilience that I've discussed previously, and demonstrates the benefits of Vodafone's strategy and the diversity of its assets and products.</p>
          <p>I will now hand you over to Andy, who will take you through the quarter in greater detail. Andy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Arun and good morning everyone. In a moment, I will talk in more detail about the revenue trends across the group, but first I want to say a few words about our outlook statement. In May, at the time of our full-year results and in the subsequent road show, we were able to brief you on the basis of the first six weeks trading of the quarter. However, in June, there was a slowdown in our trading performance, notably in Spain, which as you would expect, we have been monitoring closely since then. I would stress we are reiterating the other elements of our guidance, notably operating profit and free cash flow.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about the revenue trends in more detail. I will comment further on guidance at the end. As Arun has already said, the group's first quarter organic and pro forma growth is lower than the final quarter of last year. On an organic basis, total revenue grew 1.7% in the quarter, sequential fall from 3.6%. Pro forma growth, in turn, has reduced from 6.1% to 3.7%, with Spain accounting for around half of this slowdown. So let me provide some more color on the drivers of this, starting with the Europe region.</p>
          <p>Total revenue in Europe reduced very slightly by 0.2% year-on-year on an organic basis, with an increasing customer base, voice usage, and strong data growth offset by pricing pressures and the continuing impact of termination rate reductions. This represents a slowdown from 1.5% growth in the previous quarter. Within this, organic service revenue in Spain slowed sequentially from growth of 5.2% in the fourth quarter, to a 2.5% decline in the first quarter. However, if we strip out Spain, organic service revenue in the rest of Europe combined only declined from 1.1% to 0.4%. Although there is some overlap between the dynamics of Spain and other markets, we do not see a direct read across the rest of Europe given two important factors.</p>
          <p>In recent years, we have performed very strongly in the Spanish migrant worker sector, which has been dominated by Spain's large construction sector. As a result of events in Spain, we believe we have been impacted disproportionately by this strong market position.</p>
          <p>Secondly, a prevailing postpaid pricing structure with a higher out-of-bundle component than we see in many other markets. As I said in Europe, excluding Spain, service revenue rose 0.4% on organic basis compared to 1.1% last quarter, with U.K. accounting for over half of the sequential slowdown. This is a robust performance, with a marginally slow grade primarily a function of strong take up of specific messaging tariffs in the U.K. and Italy in the comparable period, and some signs of economic weakness in the U.K.</p>
          <p>Breaking down this organic service revenue into the main constituent parts, I will start with voice revenue. Voice revenue was 3.5% lower year-on-year, broadly inline with a 3.0% decline in the previous quarter. Within this, outgoing voice revenue was 2.3% lower, inline with the previous quarter. Outgoing voice volumes grew 15%, offsetting effective price declines of a similar level. This usage growth was driven primarily by Italy and Germany, reflecting take-up of large contract voice bundles and prepaid usage initiatives.</p>
          <p>Incoming voice revenue in Europe declined by 5.7% at similar rates to the previous quarter. This 5% minute growth was more than offset by the impact of mandated termination rate cuts of around 11% in effective rate per minute. Messaging revenue grew at 2.9% on an organic basis, somewhat lower than the 7.5% in the previous quarter. This slowdown was most significant in Italy and the U.K., where strong take up of the infinity tariff in Italy and SMS bundles in the U.K. boosted the comparative period.</p>
          <p>Data revenue in Europe increased by 31%, with strong growth continuing across our main markets and sustaining the level of growth seen last quarter. Including Spain, data revenue reached &#xA3;552 million in Europe in the quarter. Increased penetration of 3G and business devices continue to be the main drivers of European data growth. In aggregate, data cards and handheld business devices reached 5.3 million, up 83% on last year. 3G devices have now reached 24% of our European customer base.</p>
          <p>Turning to fixed line services revenue, which represented 9% of European service revenue in the quarter, principally in Arcor. Arcor's DSL customer base reached 2.8 million at the end of June, up 26% on last year and led to a 3% service revenue growth. The lower revenue growth compared to the previous quarter reflects a lapping effect on carrier revenue, as well as a mixed shift towards wholesale, as Vodafone Germany added nearly 90% of Arcor's net adds in the quarter. Vodafone Germany now represents over 10% of Arcor's base, highlighting the ability to leverage our distribution channels in the fixed broadband market.</p>
          <p>If we now turn to the EMAPA region, revenue continues to be driven by the strong customer growth that Arun highlighted previously. Average mobile customers grew by around 18% year-on-year, driving organic growth in service revenue of 8.7%, lower than the 13.1% in the previous quarter, principally due to slower growth in Egypt, Australia and Romania. This, in turn, reflects a combination of increasing competition and rising penetration.</p>
          <p>In addition, Turkey is now included in the organic growth analysis. As Arun has said, a 34% cut in termination rates drove a slowdown in organic service revenue growth from 6.7% in the fourth quarter to 3.8% in the first quarter. This means that Turkey has been slightly diluted to EMAPA's growth in the quarter.</p>
          <p>India is excluded from our organic calculation but on a pro forma basis, total revenue growth remains above 50%, driven by the sustained momentum in customer growth discussed earlier.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to make a few comments on outlook. As Arun discussed, it is clear that revenue growth in the quarter is below the run rate implied by our guidance range set out in May, with the recent deterioration in Spain the main driver. We now believe our group revenue for the year will come in around the bottom of the outlook range. This will partly be due to Spain and the tougher U.K. environment.</p>
          <p>Another element of this shortfall is lower equipment revenue. We have mentioned before a belief that in a weaker economic climate we may see a lower rate of handset renewals and upgrades and we are seeing and, indeed, encouraging this in several of our markets. This reflects both a shift in customer behavior in response to pressures on consumer spending and our increased focus on SIM-only services and contract extensions without equipment upgrades to tailor our customer propositions accordingly. This can be good for our customers and for our bottom line.</p>
          <p>This factor contributes to our view that we do not expect the revenue weakness outlined to impact on our guidance for profit. We continue to see adjusted operating profit in the 11.0 to &#xA3;11.5 billion range for three primary reasons: First, some of the revenue shortfall is offset by lower acquisition and retention costs, as discussed. Second, as I just highlighted, there are a number of cost initiatives underway and our accelerated implementation will mean that we benefit this financial year. Finally, this operating environment will require an even more disciplined approach to commercial costs, such as advertising and publicity. Our margin expectations are therefore likely to be better than previously anticipated.</p>
          <p>On capital expenditure, we continue to see this being in the 5.3 to &#xA3;5.8 billion range, with investment in our growth operations, such as India, and maintaining capital intensity in Europe by balancing the need for investment with the expected return. Free cash flow expectations are similarly unchanged at 5.1 to &#xA3;5.6 billion.</p>
          <p>The current year outlook should also benefit further from recent favorable exchange rate movements, particularly with respect to revenue and to the sustained strength in the Europe. I have said in the past that a 1% increase in the euro relative to sterling would boost our annual revenue by about &#xA3;250 million relative to the 1.30 euro rate assumed in our outlook range and therefore if the first quarter average rate of 1.26 euros to sterling is sustained throughout the whole year, this will provide a revenue benefit of about &#xA3;750 million relative to our outlook assumptions. This clearly provides some offset to the top line pressures discussed earlier and we will update you as our half-year results in November.</p>
          <p>Before summing up I wanted to make quick comment on recent developments regarding two outstanding tax issues. In India, a hearing in the Mumbai High Court has recently concluded on the tax authorities' claim that capital gains tax is due on our acquisition of Vodafone Essar. We await the written verdict, but remain confident that we face no liability on this issue. In the U.K. the High Court recently ruled that CFC legislation is inconsistent with EU law. We view this as an important decision relating to a specific tax case for which we have provided over &#xA3;2 billion on our balance sheet, although we wait to see how the tax authorities respond before deciding on whether this provision remains appropriate.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll now hand back to the operator for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Question-and-answer session will be conducted electronically. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll take our first question today from Robert Grindle from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. When people delay upgrading their handsets to take a sort of SIM-only package does that also hit your service revenues as well as your equipment revenues? And then a second point on mobile data which seems to have strengthened a little bit in some markets, if you exclude Spain and Europe. Is the consumer picking up the toll on mobile data? Is there any sign of that at this stage? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy, you want to take the first one? I'll take the second.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the upgrades, we are offering increasingly in number of the markets an opportunity to take a lower ongoing airtime package in return for not taking equipment upgrade. So in the near-term that will actually take more out of the equipment revenues than it will take out of the airtime revenues. Although over the full life of the customer relationship the two will normalize more. So, hence while we get slight disproportionate negative impact from the total revenues in the near-term, albeit in profitability wise it's not too dissimilar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Robert on your second question on mobile data. Really two parts to this one is Mobile Connect cards where here in the U.K. for example we're doing roughly 30-35,000 dongles Mobile Connect cards additions every month. We've got a very good market share in that. And on mobile Internet where we're selling things for typically either &#xA3;5 or &#x20AC;7 all-you-can-eat kind of web browsing etcetera those products are growing well pretty much across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll take our next question today from Simon Weeden from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And can I talk just run into revision to revenue guidance a little bit more and in particular if you look at Spain and the slowdown this quarter versus that what we had in mind and I think you're pretty much at your lower revenue guidance straightaway without assuming any further deterioration as the year goes on. If you look at the coming quarter and how you exited the quarter particularly in Spain but not necessarily exclusively do you not see a full quarter impact of the sort of June slowdown potentially giving your worst outcome as the year progress and therefore the revenue guidance pretty much straightaway at risk as July comes in. And second sort of related to that how much further down would revenue have to go before you starting seeing a risk to the operating profit guidance and my guess is not much but I just wondered if you could give us the sense just how much margin protection you feel is viable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy, you want to take this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So obviously with having to watch on a almost sort of daily basis what the trends are going on and this is a sort of tricky one to monitor. We've gone back with each of our businesses including Spain, particularly Spain, to actually look at recent trends and we're working with this Spanish business on promotions and other activities that they can launch to try to address some of those. And so we've got a best view here as we presently see it as to how we think the balance of the year will outturn, but frankly we are early days on this and we are doing whatever we can to make sure we get back into the pack on that.</p>
          <p>In terms of the margin protection, we've said that we can still be in the profit range even if we were to drop to around the bottom of the revenue range. So, we clearly are working on the cost and essentially Spanish business with sort of negative 2.5% on this revenue growth as being the sort of the weaker area in Europe, but we are working on cost on other fronts and we are comfortable that working within that range, we will still be fine on the profit front. We'll see how each month goes by but our determination is obviously to keep the revenues there and towards the cost base as much as we possible can do to make sure the profit stays intact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy, can I just add a couple of things to it. In terms of the kinds of things we're doing, we obviously have things we're doing to stimulate revenue whether it's usage stuff whether it's DSL, whether it's data, so we've got a lot of things going on here that we hope will kind of bring home better revenues as time goes on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just follow up on the Spain point, I mean you've made points about maybe about a third of the reduction quarter-over-quarter and the growth rate is related to the comp. If you kind of take that into account, could you give us a sense of where Spain would be if the June run rate continues to the next quarter given the change in the comp versus the second fiscal quarter last year? I am talking about revenue growth there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean Simon we're not going to get into such huge levels of detail but we've taken a view on the recent run rates and on the sorts of activities that Arun has referred to and we got plans we carry forward. So, that's what we're working to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I will move to our next question from Will Drapher from Exicusion. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just a quick round robin on some of your European countries. Firstly, Greece, look like there's a fairly heavy fall in ARPU and I'm wondering why that was? Secondly, in France, a low level of subscriber adds just 6,000 proportionate. I wonder if you could give us some color on that? And thirdly, in the Netherlands, it appears that you are engaged in a pretty heavy competitive struggle with T-Mobile for a second or even third quarter and I am wondering how long you see that persisting in the Netherlands? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Vittorio you want to take those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. On Greece you might remember that we had declared that we wanted to be more competitive vis-&#xE0;-vis the competitors. We're working on prices, we're working on price of SMS, price of minutes, and it is basically in the context of a decline in market share which we did not want to go through. You also have to keep in mind that in Greece we have not launched the second brands therefore, we are working with tariff plans and under the existing umbrella brand to address the segments of the market use and kind of lower end of the market which usually our competitors address with other brands.</p>
          <p>In the Netherlands, actually, I think we are doing pretty well. We have gained revenue and profit share. You're right, you're absolutely right, it is a competitive market but the trend has been very positive and our strategy, which is based mostly on online direct sale and gaining market share is paying off. So I'm kind of optimistic that we are doing the right thing.</p>
          <p>On SFR I guess we need to wait for the 24th of July, when they report their numbers and so I would prefer to let them answer the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, we will now move to our next question from Mark James from Collins Stewart. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, I apologize if I missed it, but can you may be split out what the Spanish run rate was in June. I'm just thinking about the monthly sort of a sequential deterioration in Spain because this must be very marked given as you said you were on the road in early June. Second question was in respect of the, lower handset sales, are you able to put some numbers to that in terms of its impact on revenues or on volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so we did address the Spain profile. We have not given numbers within the month, I mean frankly the difficulty here is, if you take one or two months &#x2013; predicting trends of one or two month period is really not very easy thing to do. What we have done instead is done a very detailed bottom up exercise with the business, looking at each of the customers segments, looking at the spent profiles, looking at the promotions they've got coming up, and we've basically built up our forecast from that perspective.</p>
          <p>In terms of the lower handsets, I mean we've got revenues of over 2 billion or so, coming through from acquisition and retention, and we are seeing and we are indeed encouraging people to sort of hang on to handsets for a little bit longer, and we've not put a number on it but I suppose one observation I would make is that in going from sort of guidance range to lower end guidance range, we're about 0.9 billion of ranging on that mid points, the bottom is about 1%. You don't actually need particularly large swings on handset revenue which are not profit impacting to actually move this a reasonable proportion down the range and therefore the handsets in Spain really is the largest part of that movement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now move to Justin Funnell from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just a just a few questions, please. I was just wondering if another economy that we are seeing slowing down, quite fast I mean since Ireland. Just wondering just as a kind of benchmark, if you could compare what's going on in Spain, to Ireland, are you seeing a worse effect in Spain? Does that help us understand a bit more how much is the competitive dynamic in Spain?</p>
          <p>Secondly, we've obviously going forward going to try and model some sort of impact from the economy, just wondering if you'd care at this stage to try and speculate what the relationship between GDP growth and mobile spend might be. Now that we have to start modeling this in if you care to give us a steer on that at all. In terms of Italy, do you think you are actually winning some market share there? We noticed TI has pulled back a bit, has that helped your bets in Italy.</p>
          <p>And then finally, just trying to understand a bit more how customers are actually behaving as the economy affects them. In Spain you're talking about less usage on contracts. What about prepaid, are you are seeing in Spain or anywhere else, people not topping up as frequently. And generally in the U.K., is it just the slowdown in usage you are referring to, in terms of the economy effect that you are seeing, or is there other things as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vittorio, if you want to take some of the European questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I will quickly just touch them and then. Let me say, Ireland and Spain it's interesting, because there are similarities between the two economies but there are differences in the position of Vodafone in those two countries. Yes, both economies have got real estate booms and yes, both economies have got immigrants issues. However, in Ireland, we kind of come from the incumbent position, so we tend to be very strong in segments in terms of customer base, which are kind of the more traditional segments, while in Spain, we have been very strong. Thanks to our dynamism and things that Arun has described into the immigrant segment, into the kind of smaller medium enterprises linked to construction and linked to the real estate situation. If I had to say, in a way in Ireland, that the issue for us is much more being competitive with price and with bundles with the competitor. So, similarities in the two economies but different starting position. In a way, in Spain we've been incredibly successful in the last four years in terms of double-digit growth. And some of the segments in which we have topped into seem to be recently have been hit more by the economic slowdown.</p>
          <p>On Italy, I think we are doing well. We don't have the quarterly numbers from our competitors but it looks like we are doing well and we are both from a pricing and from a commercial cost point of view being acting successfully and in a way, which gives us some comfort about, how things are going. The behavior, I am not sure, I would describe the behavior of the customers the way you said. I don't think the customers are using less. I think, the customers as Andy has described tend to trade a kind of a lower price on a SIM-only tariff for getting a newer handsets later, six months later, a bit of time later, which makes sense because when a household is under economic pressure, probably you prefer to pay less on a monthly basis and not renew your handset. I want to stress as Andy said, if we manage well, this is not negative for the profits, because it's basically a trade off between acquisition, retention and better utilization of our networks. So, I wouldn't &#x2013; and again, it's early days, it's something that has happened very recently, we've been monitoring it and we'll see where it goes. And Justin your question about, kind of the relationship between GDP growth and mobile spending, frankly, we don't have a strong view on precisely what the correlation here is. What is clear to us is that the economies around the world are slowing and that's what's kind of modeled into our thinking. But we believe that our sector and we are reasonably resilient that of course needs to be tested as we go forward in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We take our next question today from John Karidis from MFG Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Very good morning to you. Is it possible, please, to be a little bit more specific about the competitive price, particularly in Spain and the U.K.? Who are the ones that cause the most problem? And is it predominantly price related or is it a sort of richness of bundles that are offered? And secondly, I didn't quite catch second point that makes the weakness in Spain country specific something about out-of-bundle minutes, if it is possible to enlarge on that, I'd be grateful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vittorio or Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, let me tell you the later bit, just in terms of my comments on the constructed bundles, what we got in the postpaid market in Spain is essentially lower price points bundles but lower minutes in them so high proportion minutes tend to be outside the bundle and therefore a sort of paid for on a per use basis, whereas in other markets where there are bigger bundles <mark type="inaudible" /> essentially. This sort of marginal minute does not necessarily appear to have a cost. So, the Spanish market has a high proportion of our customers who are actually paying what we'd call overage compared with markets like the U.K. or like Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, on the pricing question, I'm not sure, at the end of the day, pricing or bigger bundles are really two different things. If I look at the U.K., we are getting T-Mobile's clearly you might have seen it aggressive on the big &#xA3;30 bundle. We have three aggressive on the data tariffs and again it is either you go to &#xA3;15 or you say that &#xA3;15 are for five gig instead of three. So, at the end of the day, it is a price pressure. The positive thing if you want is that we still have some kind of good volume reaction, which means that customers use more. But of course, we have to face these things and to respond to these things.</p>
          <p>In general, the other element in the U.K. is a little bit of slowdown in foothold in the shops and again this is related to the general retailing situation. In Spain, we have more competition from the DNOs, and DNOs take advantage potentially of the situation that Andy has described. So the low commitment type of handsets and clearly we have a formidable competitors in Telef&#xF3;nica who is very entrenched in the high-end corporate, and in the kind of more traditional segments, a little bit the same way as we are in other markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I take our next question from Aur&#xE9;lie Husson-Dumoutier from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, gentlemen. Three questions. The first one is quite straight forward -- if you can give us the organic growth implied by the bottom ends of your management guidance. The second one, going back to Spain, looking at the numbers in the report today, we talk a lot about advancing the postpaid but prepaid work almost in a freefall that's a sort of 12% decline year-on-year, and I was just wondering if that is really basically &#x2013; you expect that could be repeated, going forward, for postpaid customers that when will end up &#x2013; when it will basically go towards the end of the contract before they trade down, and therefore I think it could be a sort of late impact on the postpaid cycle, and that one was likely possible to enlarge to discussions with the U.S. I appreciate that the U.S. haven't reported as yet.</p>
          <p>But do you reckon that continent's been a postpaid market, specifically been one of the major factor why so far it's not reacted to the weaken economy over there. And the third one, looking at your savings that you plan to make, two of them strike to me that, it really depends on what your competitor do, you're talking about the low acquisition cost and the discount on adverts and publicity. How confident you are that the competition will not increase from here? And what will be Vodafone's reaction if it actually does? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Andy, you want to take the organic growth, and Vittorio you take the European questions, I'll take the U.S. question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, roughly sort of a ranging, but order of magnitude, about 2% organic growth is sort of essentially what's implicit within that revised guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vittorio, on Spain...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, first, let me probably clarify a misunderstanding. I don't think we have said that we want to cut advertising spending. To be clear, we are rationalizing Arun has said, he's rationalization of advertising production costs, which is cost synergies, not pulling out of the market. And on the other comment that you have on acquisition, and a kind of commercial cost, I think you're right. Of course, it's something that depends on the market dynamics, but if the markets go more into lower prices, SIM-only type of offers, and customers need, or want, or prefer to replace the handsets instead of every 18 months, every 24 or later, almost logically, we should go for giving more for a lower price and saving on the commercial cost. But you're right, it depends on market dynamics.</p>
          <p>Okay, now then you had the prepaid and contagion on postpaid, the way we handle prepaid to postpaid migration is really basically, on a customer-by-customer basis. We try to consolidate customers when their usage and their profile justifies going to a postpay, it gives more stability, it gives better churn management, and it gives for us better opportunities to handle them. So I think it's a healthy thing, as long as you do it on an objective basis, which is the value the customer can bring. So, you mention Spain, I mean even in Italy, I can mention Italy as well, we don't have a particularly good performance on prepay, this quarter, but again it was kind of deliberate, because there is a part of the prepaid customers who are not worth a lot. So, my guess is, this is part of customer management is the answer and as long as the value is there, is right thing to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me just is it possible to enlarge the U.S. the question was also on the fact that U.S. being a postpaid market, so far has been pretty resilient, while you've seen in Spain, and then you also correctly say in Italy, the fact that it's not merely prepaid customer can adjust their consumption at will when they feel the pinch of the economy. Looking forward in the U.S., do you reckon that the fact that most of these consumers will go towards the end of the contract, can -- there is a risk that they will trade down? And they could be probably see the impact of the economy delayed, but also as a new kind of in Spain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me take this question here. First of all, let me remind everybody that Verizon will be announcing the results on July 28, so I'm going to have to be brief on this. So, first off, the kind of contract customers that you have in the U.S. quite different from the kind of contract customers that you have in Spain. If you look at the average spend the big bucket sizes that you have in the U.S. you look at the number of minutes, for example, that people have, and typically longer kind of contract times, sort of insulates what's going on in the U.S., and of course the big factor in the U.S. is really around the market structure and the fact that we have a weak fourth competitor and that is all accruing to the benefit. But let me not go any further, and give Verizon Wireless management a chance to kind of explain this in greater detail. As is obvious from the numbers that we're shown you, 1.5 million net adds is a very strong performance and we continue to see good performance in our Verizon Wireless company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now to our next question from Nick Delfas from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much. I'm just coming back to a question that Simon asked already, but just wanted to see if I can ask it a slightly different way. Obviously when you gave your guidance in May, you already knew some of the weaknesses in Spain, but presumably it got worse in late May and June. So, really the question is, should we be expecting a deterioration in that rate, say 1.5% for Q1, above 3% decline for Q2, is that a rational way to look at this? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean, as I said earlier, Nick, I entirely understand the question. It is the case that it was a little weak in the first month and weaker in the later two months and that's why we're doing the update now. Frankly, sort of two months of data is very difficult to actually draw a consistent theme or a consistent trend line off it. So, the business has done a detailed exercise, it has looked at what is happening in its customer base. It's looked at the promotions it's got coming up and it's done its own projections now going towards the balance of the year. When we've got another few months of data in evidence, then I think we will be much more comfortable with knowing exactly where this will end up, but at this point in time, it's just genuinely difficult and it's the primary reason why we've notched down the revenue guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will move to our next question now from Paul Howard from Cazenove. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for that. A couple of questions. Just going back on something you said before, did you say that the organic growth implied by your new guidance is around 2% for the group? I guess I'm just trying to understand why, if that's the right figure, that would represent an improvement on the first quarter, given that the economic situation feels like it's getting worse. And then secondly, just a question on EMAPA, could you give the figure for organic growth ex Turkey, just so we can see the trends, ex the introduction of Turkey, and again explain how they developed in the quarter and what the assumptions are for the rest of the year within those emerging markets? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So, on the growth rates, the two percent organic, first observation is the organic excludes India. So, obviously India needs to be overlaid on top of that; and secondly it does imply a modest improvement, but it is only modest. And that's going to be a combination of things: more DSL revenues coming through the backend of the year, renewed focus on promotions as we go forwards and so directionally that's where we're at. That where're we're focusing with the business and we'll come back later in the year, obviously, and report on how that's going. Turkey...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to follow-up on that, I guess it just feels a bit strange, given the trends deteriorated within the quarter and certainly economies are slowing globally, we wouldn't expect things to get worse even ex DSL? I'm just trying to understand what your link is between your &#x2013; the GDP trends you're assuming and the volume and revenue growth trends you're assuming?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's very difficult we're calling some of these very much at the margin whether it's plus 1% or it's plus 0.5%, or whatever, it's just genuinely tricky to do. Each of the businesses has got its own plan, it's got the promotions they are putting in place, it's doing things on equipment pricing, SIM-only pricing, it's the aggregation of a lot of efforts and lot of plans sort of going on in the individual businesses and really it's just difficult to say more than that, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and so on EMAPA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Turkey took about 0.4 percentage point off the organic growth rate of the region quarter-on-quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the trends within the quarter because that's obviously a slowdown from like I think it was 13% in Q4 for the rest &#x2013; for things like Egypt and Romania? Did things deteriorate at the backend of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was more progressive than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you we will now take our next question from Jerry Dellis from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning. It's Jerry Dellis of JP Morgan. Three questions, please. Firstly on Europe; Andy gave out some organic service revenue growth rates for Europe, excluding Spain I think you said that the trend had gone from 1.1% to 0.4%, I just wanted to confirm that 1.1 was for Q4 and it'd be useful to understand what the quarterly trend was prior to the Q4 stage just so that we can say something about the run rate here.</p>
          <p>The second question is just in terms of competitive pressure in your European market. So, you're finding that your competitors are generally sort of easing off here because everybody is experiencing the same sort of headwinds. And the third question is I guess that the shift in SIM-only takes away a major barrier which would ordinarily prevent smaller operators within European national markets from taking your customers i.e. the barrier in the past to a large extend being the handset subsidy. Is that something that you're concerned about going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy, you want to take the first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, let me take the first one. So, just to confirm Jerry that 1.1 was the fourth quarter, so I was saying it's 1.1 in the fourth quarter and 0.4% in the most recent quarter. The quarter prior to that third quarter, I think, was about 1.0% and in second quarter was about 1.9. There is a little bit of accounting adjustment in that but directionally I suppose that's sort of order in VAT in that period as well. So, prior quarter was 1.0 as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on competitive pressures etcetera, I don't think there is anybody backing off frankly when you think about what's going on here in the U.K. or what's going on in Spain or Italy or Germany, I think Europe remains competitive and Vittorio anything else you want to add to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's difficult to give a kind of uniform picture but you know as Arun has said in his introductory speech the average price reduction is still 13, 14%. In Europe, some markets a little bit more, some markets a little bit less but it changes by the quarter and with different initiatives and different things. So difficult to give a kind of uniform answer. The SIM-only barrier question, I think, what you say is true but up to a point. If you move actually resources from acquisition retention to pricing scale becomes important and especially if you think about data for example, we have almost in every country the best network in the country, the better performing in terms of speed and in terms of capacity. Brand matters, distribution matters, number of shops, number of point of sales. So at the end of the day, it's in a way healthier competition everybody can subsidize an answer, not everybody can have shops brand and network.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Then I move to our next question from Terry Sinclair from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I got two questions. First of all, I'd like to learn a little bit more about the timing of what went wrong in Spain. The construction slowdown has been underway for a long time at least your competitor moves that I am of aware in June. Why did the stuff fall apart for the past beginning of June? Is it to do with different promotions, contract expirations and has it continued to worse in June, July.</p>
          <p>The second question is about USB modem take up. This is a product, which I would have thought would be economically sensitive and I wonder if you've seen any weakness in any markets that we were to be aware of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy, you want to take the timing or Vittorio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, the trend there was the later two months were worse than the former two and in promotional sense Vittorio if you can just comment upon whether there were changes in the market that impacted in the second or third months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we have got some lapping effects but probably of the 7.5 points that go from one quarter to the other probably a couple of points 2.5 are lapping effects and the remaining is just the real thing. It has happened, you're right, quite sharply and quite &#x2013; I would say very concentrated in June and with some late May signals which of course we picked in June, however because the numbers coming in June. One thing that we're sure is the migrants' effect, people going home. As we said, we're stronger there that probably is another point, I don't know, 0.8 or 2 percentage points of the total. And it has apparently catalyzed more in the last part of the quarter. But it's very recent news so it's difficult for us to be more specific.</p>
          <p>On USB modems I would say it's one of the things that we like. You might have noticed that in the U.K. we're actually backed to 30% growth and we are betting on these things. There was an earlier question, yes, we are betting in the consumer space, we are pushing them heavily into revision. We're pushing them heavily for singles, for families without children and as Arun said, we get a fairly good share of this market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vittorio, the only thing I'd add to that is this is very early in its lifecycle so we are picking up people early in the lifecycle. These people are not that sensitive just kind of on the margin economics. They're using it for convenience et cetera. Some are using it as kind of cross elastic with wireless broadband or wire line broadband. So I think it's just early days and I don't think you'll find a high correlation between sales of USB and the current macroeconomic environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, our next question today comes from Guy Peety from Mcquary. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, hello gentlemen. Just a small one, Andy, on your outlook statement you suggested that there was going to be another incremental 700 million sterling of Fx benefit in the numbers if the exchange rate stay as they are. Is that now implied in your new guidance?</p>
          <p>On a secondary point and particularly in Spain are you worried about sort of incremental bad debt in the coming quarters as some of the migrant populations just abandon contracts?</p>
          <p>And then, a question for Vittorio, you mentioned that distribution is obviously one of your key opportunities to invest in and differentiate yourself. Given that some of your competitors have announced a more expansive network of retail distribution shops, especially in places like Spain, do you see there is an opportunity to increase your retail footprint in these market environments to try and sort of increase your customer retention? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Guy let me just take the first one. To try to simplify things, we have not done an Fx true up on the guidance ranges at this point in the year, and instead we will do that when we come to November. So the actuals have got the benefit of the Fx uplift for the first quarter, but in essence when we've talked about the revenue being at lower end of the range, we have said that on the basis of the same exchange rates as we have in the outlook originally, when we said that we expect the operating profits from free cash flows and CapEx to be the same as before, that is on the same basis as previously. If the present exchange rates do continue out through the rest of the year, then we would expect, roughly, that the revenue guidance would be uplifted by around &#xA3;750 million for the full year when we come to November.</p>
          <p>On your second question, which was on Spain and bad debt, we are obviously monitoring bad debt closely around the business. I think, fortunately, a good proportion of business is actually prepay, so we actually do get the cash in advance. The bad debt expense in the business is very, very small and we have seen a bit of an increase and part of that is in Spain, but overall, as a group, it's actually been sort of reasonably moderate, but Spain is the particular market to your question that we are focusing upon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on distribution, the answer to your question is yes, we are betting or we want to bet more on direct distribution, direct is not just the shops, it's shops, it's online and it's <mark type="inaudible" /> and the countries where we are making these investments are the U.K., Germany, and Greece, mainly. The other markets being already at a kind of we think satisfactory level and yes, we feel that managing our own customers is going to be essential and direct control over the channels is an important part of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today from Andrew Beale from Arete Research. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I was just wondering from your detailed work on Spain, can you give us a bit more of a sense of what's happening by sector and customer type? So that we can understand how broad based slowdown is versus concentration in the areas you've mentioned like construction, migrant workers and so on?</p>
          <p>Secondly, have you fully reflected in your new revenue in the guidance a much stronger percent SIM-only or is that &#x2013; are there potentially further adjustments to come as you see how you execute on that?</p>
          <p>And finally, in terms of cost reduction you've obviously highlighted advertising, acquisition and retention cost and so on, I'm sure below that there are a lot more cost programs. Can you give us a sense of some of the more material ones that will help you reduce cost? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On Spain, I think that the immigrant sort of part of the customer base is the most obvious area where we haven't seen the reduction, we have got a little bit of weakening, frankly across sort of a variety of the segments and across different sort of voice and data messaging products. So I wouldn't pull out any particular segment other than the sort of immigrant one.</p>
          <p>And secondly on SIM-only as I said earlier we have got 2 billion or so revenues coming from equipment sales and we have taken the view that we will be encouraging and structuring price plans to try to take out some of the equipment element off that and you only need small changes in that number to actually account for a reasonable proportion in the shift in the guidance range we have got. So, again market by market we are going through it but you can take it that we are now assuming that we will do a little bit more SIM-only than we were assuming a while ago and it isn't just about SIM-only because SIM-only is largely for new customers. It's as much about existing customers when they come up to reveal as to whether actually they need more a new device at the same stage or whether will do it on an ongoing air-time price plan.</p>
          <p>And on the cost reduction question, you are quite right, there are whole myriad of areas that we are looking at. We are looking at sort of the headcounts in the business and contractors and a whole variety of initiatives. It varies very much market by market. We do a lot of benchmarking in the business and frankly we'll just turn the heat up as we are doing at the moment on various areas to make sure that we squeeze even more out without damaging the business as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew if I may add some kind of color on that. First of all again I have to reiterate that because I don't want misunderstandings, we have not said advertising, we have said advertising production cost because advertising is different thing. In terms of cost, if you want a little bit of color, I would say initiatives grow under three headings: One is consolidation and elimination of activity; one is outsourcing; one is efficiency. On the consolidation and elimination, network is an important thing. We are putting together testing. We are putting together functions. We're putting together terminal testing. We have put together and we are reducing the cost &#x2013; we have a project to reduce the cost of logistics of terminals. And we are also consolidating property and trying to make property more efficient.</p>
          <p>In the outsourcing space, we are continuing with the IT development outsourcing off shoring project that you are very familiar with. We're working on customer care. We have done helpdesk and we're working on maintenance of IT contract.</p>
          <p>And I would say on the efficiency it's basically putting everything as much as possible under the same standards and then negotiating contracts at the central level which is why at the CapEx level and at the OpEx level you see that we are able to give still very good service but respect the commitments that we have made couple of years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, you want to add something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Andrew, in the EMAPA markets, we again have a very strong focus on cost control. In the markets with higher penetration, we are a kind of adopting the European standards of really capping OpEx growth and in those markets where we still have high growth we are seeking to make sure that is as efficient as possible. So for example, in India a major IT outsourcing, which goes further than we have done in our European operating companies, which we are doing together with IBM and again in the emerging markets, rapid introduction of ERP systems, which will allow us to grow our businesses, but without growing the traditional headcounts associated with them stand us in good state going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question today comes from Dean Tenerelli from T. Rowe Price. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I just had a question about how the economic slowdown is affecting the business, especially when I look at the use trends, specifically in Spain, which are pretty strong and actually accelerated in the second calendar quarter in growth why is it that the minutes of use don't get hit and you are seeing the effect over in ARPU?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we said, it's mainly a price effect. It's lower priced customer optimizing using big promotions and optimizing for a lower price and plus using different SIMs for again taking advantage of what is in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But doesn't that mean that it's more in effect of &#x2013; because if I look at it, and I didn't speak with you, I would assume it was the competitive environment. So, I guess it's hard to separate what is competition as opposed to what is economics. So what makes you think it's economic and not just competitive environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are absolutely right. It's very hard to separate the two. But clearly both factors are there. As we said clearly we see people optimizing themselves and clearly we see some segments in which we have been very successful, by definition retrenching and reducing their cost. How to separate exactly two things, especially considering that we really have it very recently studied, it's probably early to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, what you see is more consumers are chasing the cheaper promotions, so before the promotions could have been out there, but no one bothered to take them up, now people go after them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No it's not bother to take them up, it's to go beyond the optimal point. So going over and that's the mechanism of any promotion in any sector at the end of the day, which is to give something to the customers, which is <mark type="inaudible" /> the customer like it so much and they use it beyond the optimal point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dean the other thing is in every one of our markets we have a lot of usage stimulation programs. So there is part of the base that actually using quite a few minutes. There could be other parts of the base but are actually using it less but the part of the base that's using a lot of minutes are using them at a lower price. So you got two effects happening simultaneously.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Yeah, okay. All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now move to our next question from Darren Ward from Liberum Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes, just a couple of questions from me. Firstly, this effect that you have talked about a couple of times where the Spain problem is caused largely by the low minute monthly minimum commitment and high usage charges and overage charges. Where else do we see that in Europe? I know you said Italy and Germany didn't have that structure but could you just run us through any areas where you see that danger occurring in future?</p>
          <p>Secondly, just a question about data, can you give us any data on underlying volumes of data usage and how you are seeing network utilization at the moment and any pressure on CapEx, just looking a little bit ahead.</p>
          <p>And finally just a sideways question but on this immigration point, where are all the Spanish immigrants going back to and are you going to &#x2013; are they comfortable you've got representation and you are going to see usage growth and customer growth in those markets as a result of these people leaving Spain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So please go on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so just to say those in order. Spain is by someway the market in Europe that has got the highest proportion of customers who are paying outside of their bundles. So, I think there is really quite a big gap between Spain and any of the other markets. Certainly U.K. and Germany are probably down a half their levels and the Italian market being very sort of prepaid, it's somewhat different in its structure anyway.</p>
          <p>Data, we're seeing the volumes picking up, the revenues are picking up and obviously that is good news. As we said before, the network is coping with that fine. There are, as ever, some hotspots where we have some pressure but in terms of overall capital commitment, we have got savings on other fronts and we're focusing the investment instead on the sort of hotspot areas. So, we remain comfortable with the way that we are on the capital front.</p>
          <p>And in terms of immigrants and where they go back to, yes, it's a good question. I mean, we prefer they go back to a 100% owned Romanian business to a 20% owned Polish business I suppose, but time will tell us to where exactly they do return to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just specifically, I know you don't want to talk much about SFR because <mark type="inaudible" /> reporting, but is that a high overage market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think so. I think they're fairly big bundles generally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the date, I can just add, if what's behind the question is are people really using the 3 5 gig per month?  The answer is no. Clearly the average of the customers are at a fraction of that. There are as usual very few customers who kind of go beyond what we think is reasonable and we handle it commercially with the customers and then in case of very, very identified hotspot eventually adding some capacity but I would say for the time being we are well within our capacity limits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have fair usage policy..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a usage policy which by the way hit only a small part of customers but the average number in all markets is very reasonable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We now move to our next question, from Christian Kern from Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. I've got three questions if I may. The first one is like, on the visibility, you've reduced your guidance period when you give it from 18 months to 12 month so we probably would have expected a bit more visibility on a 12-month guidance frame versus the 18 months at half year. So, I was wondering what your views on visibility, has visibility clearly reduced is I guess the question here. And embedded in that, do you think that the economic slowdown could also be hitting Vodafone more specifically than the overall sector?</p>
          <p>And then the second question would be around market comments from market participants seeing downgrades from contract to prepaid customers, I believe that's different to the SIM-only move which you have been describing so far.</p>
          <p>The final one, if you have any updates with regard to your views to recent communications out of Brussels, specifically the MTR declaration. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the first one upon visibility. I mean I suppose for us, the difference has been that the economy generally has clearly been going through a more difficult period and as we go back to the point that's moving from the middle to the lower end of our revenue range is a 1% movement and trying to predict things to that degree of accuracy is really quite difficult. So I do think we need to see things in that sort of context, need to understand that a part of that adjustment is on the equipment side, which is not profit effecting for the current period and therefore it's just a part mathematically of what we're doing. So I think the biggest issue on visibility is just that if the economic environment does change, we are not going to be immune from that. And as I said a couple of times we saw more of a change in the May-June period than we had seen in the period immediately before that. The thing that's on the, are we as a sector going to suffer worse than the rest of the sector I think, if I pull out Spain just to go back to that point, the rest of Europe, 1.1% growth the previous quarter has become 0.4% and that is not a huge swing, it is a small swing, it is downwards but I guess compared with other sectors that probably would be a level of reduction that some of them might should be okay with. So I think we're still sort of in an okay space. And the rest of Spain has clearly been very tricky. But the rest of it 1.1 and 0.4% is not a huge swing. Contract prepaid, Vittorio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To me that is not just contract prepaid, SIM-only is a contract with 30 days commitment. So it's a contract in a way with a very limited commitment. To me the crucial thing is to do what's right, to make the commercial investment which is consistent and right with every type of customer segment and manage the three families, the kind of contractual German, U.K., big bundles customers in the appropriate way. The Italian prepaid which could be or Portuguese prepaid which could be still high value, but still they are prepaid, so you have to manage them on the assumption that they might go away next day. And then there is this in between thing, which is de facto, a contract with a very limited commitment. The issue for me is managing the cash per customer investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian, let me take your Brussels question. I think there are three components to Brussels, one is SMS roaming and I think the numbers that are being bandied about there with effect kind of middle of next year are sort of in the ballpark of what we have been talking to our shareholders about and we have kind of baked into our plans. The second part is around data roaming and thankfully I think there is no vigorous attempt to kind of have price caps here because it's a very young market as is known to everybody. We're all competing pretty hard in this sector and because it's a young market and competition is rife as it were, I don't think data roaming is likely to be regulated. It remains to be seen when the commissioners come back in the September-October time period. I think the core issue is around MTRs and our belief continues to be that this is a local European &#x2013; country-by-country regulatory thing, because it's local. And because you need cost models to be able to develop what the cost here are. And our sense is we are currently in the sort of eight, nine range going down to five, six range by the 2011 time period that's 15, 20% decline year-on-year. We are confident that, that is the right track to be on. But if you ask me where is the debate likely to be, I think the debate is likely to be on that and we will of course stay vigorous in terms of making sure that that is the outcome but of course there will be a debate and we will know more in the October time period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question today will come from Graham Ruck from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Good morning. I won't ask any questions about Spain. I was wondering how you are thinking about the balance sheet right now with I guess the trade-off between how prudent a buyback could be given obviously disappointing share price performance, but also wanting to retain flexibility as to &#x2013; potentially visibility isn't quite as high.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, could you elaborate a bit on how you are thinking about the 3G iPhone? Obviously you're going to benefit from it in 10 markets but then in some of your biggest markets you are going to be competing directly against it? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andy you want to do the balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Graham, and since the balance sheet, I mean we have the stated policy that the primary return to shareholders will be, the focus will be on the dividend side and but that we will keep an eye on the balance sheet, we will keep a look at what capacity we have got. We also <mark type="inaudible" /> on the credit ratings but equally to your point we are very mindful of where the share price is at the moment and I think it'll be fair to say we are keeping a very close eye on that issue at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vittorio on iPhone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think our position on the iPhone is being basically the same since the beginning. We think it's a good device and it will appeal to a number of customers. The market is very wide. There is many segments. There is people who like touch screen; people who don't like touch screen; people who like full qwerty and would even not consider having a normal keypad and people who hate the full qwerty. There is plenty of stuff around. Our offer is not just for the iPhone customers it is for everybody. So we have a wide range of products. Somewhere we have the iPhone, somewhere we don't but we will play like we have been playing for 10 years with all the devices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you think that the iPhone in that segment you're talking about will pressure subsidy level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think it's a good handset which attracts a high end of customers who really need a lot of data and a lot of usage. So at the end of the day as long as the ARPU is balanced with the subsidy, I don't see a big difference between the iPhone and many, many other devices that we have been pushing in the past sometimes even with less success with the customers. So again it is a matter of balance of what we can generate in ARPU especially data ARPU and subsidy in commercial costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, unfortunately I have to bring this to a close because we're out of time. We have a press call after this. The IR team will call those who did not get a chance to ask their questions. So, thank you for your patience. As you know this is my last reporting cycle and I want to thank all of you for your support for the last five years and for the advice and wisdom over the years. So, thank you very much for that. And I'd like to wish Vittorio and Andy and Paul and the team here the very best in the future and we'll keep you posted. The business is strong. It has the diversity with the kinds of businesses that we have in EMAPA and frankly we will work hard to find our footing in terms of revenue and usage and costs so we can kind of execute on the guidance that we have given. So with that thank you very much. Bye, bye for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>