<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1305193" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1536</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Leif Johansson, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mikael Bratt, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Olof Persson, President, Volvo Construction Equipment</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">H&#xE5;kan Karlsson, President, Volvo Bus Corporation</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">G&#xF6;ran Gummeson, President of Volvo Penta</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Staffan Zackrisson, President of Volvo Aero Corporation</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Leif Johansson, President, Volvo Bus Corporation</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Salvatore L. Mauro, President, Volvo Financial Services</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Christer Fredriksson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Olof  Persson</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Nico Dil</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Patrik Sjoblom</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Frederic Stahl</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Benjamin Maslen</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Colin Gibson</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Yann Benhamou</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Volvo Group Report on the first 3 months 2010 conference call.  At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. Please note that this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand the call over to CEO, Mr. Leif Johansson. Mr. Johansson, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you and most welcome to this conference call on the Volvo Group's first quarter 2010. I have in the room here with me, as we normally do our CFO and IR people, and also business area leaders in at this point in time spread around the world because of the different travel problems we have had. But all of us are participating in the call and we'll answer any questions that you may have. We are also talking to slides that have been made available on our site but I'll try to keep track of them as we talk you through the conference call here.</p>
          <p>Let me first start off by characterizing the first quarter on what is Slide 2 here, Group Highlights. As a quarter where we started seeing that we have come out of the financial crisis and, if you wish, into the real economy, the underlining real economy was a greater effect on the financial crisis which have impacted us dramatically over the past year &#x2013; the last year as you have seen. And what &#x2013; in reality what that means, that is when we speak to customers nowadays, they are talking about their ability to get jobs so and so and their ability to participate in road building or in real projects. And much of their focus in &#x2013; is in what they do in their normal work with our type of product rather than discussing with their banks or the financial institutes on whether they could get financing for &#x2013; to buy one of our products.</p>
          <p>In many ways, you can say that means that we have started seeing a coming back to a more normal economy. It is true to say that this is very much the case in Europe and North America where we have had terrible markets over the past many quarters now. And I'll come back and show you that &#x2013; what that looks like on the Truck side. Asia and South America still very strong and then North America we are saying we see early signs of increased market activity, more tender activity, and more real discussions with customers but still off of very, very low levels in North America, both on construction equipment and on Truck side.</p>
          <p>The first quarter also then we had an operating income of 2.8 cash flow, seasonally strong but still negative on 2.7 billion; and then a very good recovery in Volvo CE as they were really doing well especially in Asia and Olof Persson will speak a little more to that.</p>
          <p>Now the most obvious difference between first quarter this year and the first quarter last year was that we were in this quarter producing what we sold rather than selling off of inventory what we sold in the same quarter last year. That means, of course, that on the under-absorption we had a much stronger manufacturing result this quarter than we had in the first quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Also remember that in the first quarter last year we had very significantly much too many people. And we have parted with, since the downturn started in the second quarter of '08 until now, we have parted with more than 20,000 people. And or course that means that we have a much lower operating base from which to operate from in the first quarter this year compared to first quarter last year.</p>
          <p>If you look at the Slide 3 which says Volvo Group, and you have the net sales and operating income, it's interesting to note that we now have almost half of the Group's turnover outside of North America and Western Europe. And I think that says two things. One is that we have done very well in the world outside of Western Europe and North America and when we have taken positions like we have in South America, Asia, China, India and other markets that has done well for our ability to uphold against the downturn in North America and Western Europe.</p>
          <p>But I think it's also shows that North America and Western Europe are actually now traveling at historically low levels. And frankly, much below the trend lines where you could expect or we could expect North America and Western Europe to, over time, to come back. And we will see how we think that &#x2013; it's translated into a recovery even at low levels and at slow pace but still recovery in North America and Western Europe.</p>
          <p>If you look at the Sales side, for the first time in many quarters now we actually had a growth and if you translate and adjust for currencies we had double-digit growth in Q1 '10 compared to Q1 '09, and ended up with a shade below 60 billion SEK in sales in the quarter. And again, quite reasonable operating swing there in operating income from minus 8.1 in the relevant comparable quarter last year to 4.8% margin this time around.</p>
          <p>If we look at what's happened here, you can see cost reductions quite effective. Mikael will speak a little more to that. We see improved productivity and capacity utilization. We had much too high costs during all of 2009, and as you know then we took very dramatic actions to reduce costs. That, of course, comes into cost reductions, but it also actually increases productivity. And then when you look at capacity utilization and increased volumes, of course the fact that we are now beginning to produce what we sell produces a much better underlying manufacturing result in what we do.</p>
          <p>With that, let's switch to Slide 4 in the handout, the one that says Volvo Group Cash Flow, and Mikael?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Leif. I will start to report to you today about cash flow before we move into working capital and cost reductions here. As you can see on the slide here, we ended up in the quarter with negative cash flow of 2.7, which drives then from working capital of negative 4.5, partially then offset by the positive result that we could post now in the first quarter here. It's &#x2013; the first quarter is traditionally a weak cash flow quarter, so you see also the seasonal affects coming through in this quarter. I will talk a little bit more about the working capital aspects of the cash flow on my last slide here.</p>
          <p>So let's move on then to Page 5, and you will then see here that our net financial position has moved from the 71% we had in the fourth quarter to 76% in the first quarter, affected of course by the negative cash flows, so net financial position has come down to 45 billion negative here. It's certainly so that overall that we are moving in the right direction and heading back towards the 40% net debt to equity ratio that is our objective to be around over time here. So also, on the net financial position, it's really a seasonal effect you can see here.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, during quarter here, we have maintained a strong liquidity position. We have about 66 billion in liquid positions, where about 34 billion is related to cash and the rest is committed facility. We have also very limited maturities, both for 2010 and 2011. You really need to move into 2012 to see that we have any significant roll-overs that may be needed at the time.</p>
          <p>However, the little we needed to do during this year as to logistics has been done. We have prolonged some of the programs or funding structures that we have had. We have good support from our core banks and done a good work there jointly so we're glad to report that. So basically the work that was needed for 2010 is done; so good, strong financial position there, I would say.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Page 6, you'll see here that we clearly state our commitment to continue to focus on costs and on cash flow. We have talked to you about the 21 billion throughout the last quarters here and we certainly can tick that off. And I think the first quarter here is a very good sign that the cost reductions that we have been putting in place is giving the benefit we have been looking for here. But the work is, of course, ongoing to secure that we have sustainable cost control inside the company and that we have good pace in that work, I would say.</p>
          <p>Also on the working capital side, a lot of work has been done and we have now reduced the inventories to the same levels we have in the company right now and I think during this process we have also implemented a good principle for structure and discipline around inventory, which you can see here when you look at the quarter numbers is also giving good contribution. And looking at the working capital for the last couple of years here, we can see that it's also seasonal better strong first quarter we have to report this time.</p>
          <p>Also here, work is ongoing and will continue. We will have a cash flow very high on the agenda moving forward. As you know, we have cash conversion targets of 20 days; when we went into the crisis we were about 25 days. And currently we are at 41 coming back from quite high levels during 2009 here where we were up almost to 80 days &#x2013; a little above 80 days. So good progression when it comes to the working capital work here.</p>
          <p>And actually, the first quarter could even have been better if we hadn't some process-related issues on the receivables side in Brazil and Asia. And let me emphasize there, when I say process issues it's not any internal issues; it's really the fact that for Brazil, for example, where you have the phenomenal support and there is high level of sales in Brazil as we have also commented, resulting in that the banking system in Brazil we have covered a long queue of applications here to deal with. So we expect that to be resolved during the second quarter and we should see good positive cash flow effects coming through there.</p>
          <p>So let me finish here and hand over back to you, Leif. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's with that go back to the slide that says Trucks and Slide #7. And if you look at that you can see that on the Truck side we were basically flat in sales even though if you adjust that for the currency where we were in the low single digits of volumes up; and then operating margin at 4%, clearly much better than we were only a year ago.</p>
          <p>We do see some improving demand but it is important to recognize that demand, even though we see a gradient, is off of very low numbers. And I'll speak a little more into detail on that on the different markets. In general, we can say the same picture across to Group: Asia, much improving; Japan from a very low level; Europe and North America still at low levels but improving.</p>
          <p>If you look at what we have in focus now, obviously since we have begun to now produce what we sell we are much focused on making sure that we can get productivity in the upturn. To some extent you can say back productivity in the upturn because in when you have volume drops as big as we have had and still at very low levels you can say we lost some productivity in 2009. We aim to get that back in 2010 with the upturn there.</p>
          <p>Little concerned with the supply chain, even though we don't have any big problems to report to you in quarter 1. Most of our Tier 1 suppliers are actually now in a much better shape than they were a couple of quarters ago, so that's beginning to sort itself out. What we have experienced is some surprises in the Tier 1 and Tier 3 &#x2013; Tier 2 and Tier 3 suppliers. And as we see how that develops we hope that we can manage that. But just on the focus side here, we need to make sure that we can have our supply chain doing well. We have been quite successful with our supply chain financing. And we think that has worked well and will continue to work well for our Tier 1 suppliers.</p>
          <p>Strict cost control; obviously, when you've gone through the amount of cost reductions that we have done here it's important to recognize that we don't want unnecessary costs to seep back; and therefore, we are trying to hold real good discipline here in cost controls.</p>
          <p>We are also quite happy from a product point of view that we have commented that before. We had high R&amp;D costs during 2008 and 2009, and we had very specific aims with those high R&amp;D costs in that we were wanting to put our own Group engines into our Japanese acquisition, Nissan Diesel and UD. We're happy to report that we can do that now, both in the heavy-duty engine program with the new launching of the new Quon, but also in the medium-duty engine program with the launch of the UD Condor. And of course that was &#x2013; those were important synergy projects that we had in our sights when we bought Nissan Diesel.</p>
          <p>It's also rewarding to note that we have just introduced on the Truck side the new FMX, which is the construction vehicle of trucks, Volvo Trucks, and also a new distribution truck for &#x2013; regional distribution truck called FM, also FM Distribution. All of that came out of the fairly aggressive spending that we had on the Truck side in 2009 on the R&amp;D side so that we feel, now at least, is beginning to show good results here.</p>
          <p>If you go up to point 8 in the handout, there you see the European market, which we in our forecast leave as we did call it in the beginning of the year, which is about up 10%. As you have seen then in our order intake between Q4 and Q1 we are in that vicinity of about 12%.</p>
          <p>If you flip to the next slide, which is Slide 9, and to Heavy-duty Truck market North America then we are still calling that up 20 or 30%. You have noted, I think, that deliveries were up in the beginning of the year here. We will have a slower second quarter with the pre-buy effect and as we gradually then start to switch over, the market starts to switch over from '07 technology to '10 technology, we expect a stronger second half. But a trough there, if you wish, in Q2 in North America, but still with a call for the overall North American markets to be up between 20 and 30%.</p>
          <p>If you go to the next slide, Slide 10, there you see net order intake where you can say we are showing positive trends, and frankly if you take the Q1-to-Q1 comparison there at 118% up, that sounds impressive but you should remember that we were at very low levels in the past years here. So while that is good, it is also showing that we have operating at low volumes.</p>
          <p>And just as a total net order intake, you can say, if you compare here Asia with Europe, there you see 15,000 in Asia and 16,000 in Europe in our order intake. You see actually South America being bigger than North America. And again, that might mean that, for example, South America slightly on the high side, but North America definitely on the low side.</p>
          <p>If you do the comparison to the Q4/Q1 instead, then you see a 15% total increase there with North America down. We think most of that downside in North America is aimed at the switch between U.S. '07 and U.S. '10 technology, and will start to reverse itself again in the second quarter and third quarter. We'll see how that works out. Most of the orders there that were in the first quarter were, from our point of view, U.S. '10 technology. But many of our competitors, some of our competitors had more U.S. '07 engines available than we had and then South America slightly off there. South America and Brazil is traveling at high speeds, so we will see how &#x2013; where that comes out but altogether there a solid 15% improvement in order intake on the Truck side.</p>
          <p>That takes us to Slide 11 &#x2013; it takes us to Olof Persson, the President of Construction Equipment. Olof?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Leif. Q1 2010 was one of our best quarters, Q1 quarters, when it comes to sales and cash flow, and actually the best one in 10 years when it comes to the operating margin of 9%. There are basically two sides of this. One is that we are, of course, benefiting from an improving market situation, where we can see that Asia and then in particular China and International markets are moving upwards. We see that the North American and the European markets are flattening out.</p>
          <p>We have a good position in the Chinese market. Actually, China is now, in terms of revenue of new machine sales, by far our largest market in Q1 this year. So that's one side of the strong sales growth that we had in Q1 is that our &#x2013; we had a good position on the growth markets not only in China but also in South America, in particular Brazil.</p>
          <p>The other side is the internal activities we have done and which we have communicated over the last year and that goes very much in terms of cost savings and cost reductions. We have been talking to you about the new organization and the structural cost reductions that we're looking at between 500 million and 1 billion SEK on an annual basis. And I think we can conclude now that while we go through the structural cost savings we are actually on the 1 billion SEK level on a yearly savings. And that is cost that will not come back when the volumes are coming back.</p>
          <p>We have also worked a lot on the breakeven and we have been able to reduce the breakeven level compared to 2008 with 30%. And on the external side, we have been working very much on the market shares and the price realization and we have had in Q1 2010 a positive price realization if you look across the different markets around the world.</p>
          <p>We are looking into focus now continue to leverage our good positions in the BRIC countries. We have a lot of good activities together with the <mark type="inaudible" /> but also the road machinery where we are now looking at continuing strengthening our position in the BRIC markets so we can continue to leverage on that up turn.</p>
          <p>We will also focus very much on keeping the flexibility in our production system. Given the uncertainty of the markets going forward now, we want to be able to go up and down with the market and making sure that we, regardless of the market development, keep a very good leverage going forward here.</p>
          <p>And finally, I was at the Bauma show beginning of this week and I must say that there was a good spirit in the Bauma show. There was a lot &#x2013; greater interest in the Volvo stand and in the Volvo products and we have been launching a number of products in 2009. We came out with a number products and features also at the Bauma show now so left the Bauma show with a good, positive sentiment. So that was the report from Construction Equipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Olof, thank you. Let's look at Buses then. We have Slide 12 in the handout and then we have H&#xE5;kan Karlsson. H&#xE5;kan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, Leif. The global Bus market had a mixed development during the first quarter. A good general result in South America, International in Asia, but a very slow start, I will say, in North America Coach market, and in Europe.</p>
          <p>In U.S., we have us &#x2013; the truck guides; we have the shift over to U.S. 10, so it's a little tricky period just now. And in Europe, I think we have some positive effect from the financial crisis, especially in the City Bus segment.</p>
          <p>Our sales in the quarter was up 30%, mainly driven by North America transit buses, South America and Asia. And that means that we are now back with good performance in our company, Nova Bus, in U.S., Canada after the, I will say, severe delivery problems that we had in the second half of last year.</p>
          <p>We had positive results, 145 million SEK, 3% margin in the quarter. And the main contributor is the combination of good volumes, but also we did much more efficient cost structure. We have still some minor one-time cost events in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we continue to reduce costs through our breakeven activities and also through a fairly aggressive product cost reduction program. We have also been focusing on sales and order intake in the U.S. Coach market and Europe, because we still see no signs of recovery there, so we have to secure the volumes in the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>On the Product side, we continue to introduce new products; U.S. 10 and Hybrids will be in serial production in the second quarter. And we can see there the Hybrid sales is starting to improve and there are big interests in our solution, both in Europe but also in Asia, South America and Mexico. So are looking forward to our Hybrid sales growth the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>And that will be all from Volvo Bus system. Back to you, Leif.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. We have Slide 13, we have Volvo Penta and we have G&#xF6;ran Gummeson. G&#xF6;ran?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you Leif. The global markets for marine and the industrial engines have strengthened compared to the fourth quarter '09. And we have seen that the U.S. market, that had been tracking at historically low levels, that we see a demand increase for pleasure boats.</p>
          <p>Also in Europe, we have had a market recovery, but far from the demand that we had in the peak years in '07 and '08. In Asia, we had a slow start in the beginning of this year but the order intake and actual sales is picking up now and we see a good trend towards the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>We see that we continue to gain market shares in all our core segments. And the order intake and order book for our new products are gradually improving. Currency adjusted, we had a minor size increase compared to the first quarter '09 and we managed to improve our profitability and as you know we went from minus 97 to positive 121 million SEK.</p>
          <p>And the main reason for this positive development is actually the successful work we have done internally at all levels in our company, actually, to reduce cost and to establish a new break-even level for the operation. So in focus now moving forward it's of course to keep our ambitions to continue to deliver good operational leverage. And on the operating capital side, we have been successful in securing a positive cash flow and we are driving activities in order to balance the business risks in our operation of course and then to secure capital efficiency.</p>
          <p>We have launched a number of new products. And last week, during the General Assembly, we proudly received the Volvo Technology Award. We got the award for our innovation of a satellite-based dynamic positioning system that helps, actually, the boat drivers keep the boats positioned when waiting for, for instance then, for mooring, fueling, or et cetera.</p>
          <p>And we actually launched our electronic platform, that we call EVC, seven years ago and we are now actually introducing the fourth generation of this platform that enables us to introduce soft products like the dynamic positioning system. And we see that those products they deliver through customer value for owners and operators and professional operator, of course. And I can just tell you that you will expect and you will see a number of more exciting products of this kind in the years to come.</p>
          <p>That ends Volvo Penta, Leif.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, G&#xF6;ran. That takes us to Volvo Aero, Staffan Zackrisson. And if you flip with us to Slide 14 you have the slides that he will speak to. Staffan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First about the air traffic, we have seen a recovery. The passenger traffic up until February was a growth of 7.9% and especially strong was for cargo traffic that we coming in on a number of 28%. We have also seen orders coming in and picking up for the order intake for Airbus and Boeing was 160 aircrafts in first quarter versus last year's first quarter of 50. So that's also a very positive sign.</p>
          <p>If you go to the sales for the company, it was down 6%, but if we adjusted for currencies it's a plus volume of 5% for the company to at 1.9 million billion Swedish krona. Operating income improved to 152, with a 8% margin which was a major improvement versus the fourth quarter. What has driven that is, above all, lower cost levels in the company, somewhat higher volumes that leads to utilization in the shops and giving us by that a high productivity in the system. We have also seen the start of a recovery, and there were signs on the aftermarket activities, which have also contributed to the margin and op income.</p>
          <p>What's in focus for the future is to keep the cost management and improvement of product costs so we can get better productivity going forward; it's also to have the aftermarket business improving during the year and to be a better business than it has been in the last year. And what is happening in the Aircraft business is that a number of aircrafts are now being product renewed and rolled out, that's the Boeing Dreamliner, the C series, and the Airbus 350 XWB. And this will go on for a couple of years, so a absolute priority to the &#x2013; is the of execution of the new contracts for the engines for these aircrafts. And that line bodes well for Aero.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. That takes us to Slide 15 in the handout. We have Financial Services and Salv Mauro. Salv?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Leif. Looking at new retail financing, just about flat over the fourth quarter but we're defiantly seeing an upward trend as the business is starting to recover around the world. Operating income, for the third quarter in a row, just about flat. Obviously, we're still working with delinquencies and write-offs in many of the markets, but we're holding our head above water quite nicely and we see some improving trends.</p>
          <p>Overall, the markets have continued to be a bit volatile, but we're seeing definitely some stabilization in many of the mature markets, which is a very good sign. In particular, in Western Europe and U.S. the portfolio is beginning to stabilize after coming through a very challenging winter season, and new financing is picking up as orders for our sister business areas begin to increase. There may be a lag in penetration as our BFS bookings typically lag about a month or two behind sales.</p>
          <p>Looking at our market in Brazil, a very good success; came through the downturn in a very, very good way and actually we're continuing to grow that business. We're doing some very good work with the business areas in Brazil. We're supporting sales on both the Wholesale and Retail Finance Program sides while we're mitigating risk with good deal structuring and syndication efforts.</p>
          <p>We're trying something a bit new for VFS; we're looking at dealing with alliances and the first one we're trying in South Africa, a very important market for the Volvo Group. We struck an alliance with West Bank; they're one of South Africa's leading equipment finance companies with over 40 years of asset finance experience. And this alliance enables VFS to provide wholesale financing for UD Trucks, Nissan Diesel, of course; and retail finance products for pretty much the rest of the Volvo Group, Renault Trucks and Volvo Trucks as well.</p>
          <p>The financial services offerings will be distinctly branded: Renault Trucks Financial Services; UD Trucks Financial Services; and Volvo Financial Services. Off to a good start and we're hoping that this could be a model in some other countries for us around the world.</p>
          <p>In focus &#x2013; in China the construction sector shows great promise and opportunities. We've joined forces with Volvo Construction Equipment in developing what we think is a really good integrated competitive offer for the spring selling season. And it's showing early signs of success as evidenced by increasing credit application, volume and penetration.</p>
          <p>After restructuring VFS Eastern Europe under VFS Europe, we're looking to continue to improve our processes and support our customers primarily in Russia, Romania and Turkey, while finding financing solution for the rest of Eastern Europe. We're continuing our efforts in liquidating our repossessed inventory and we're seeing some signs of stabilization in the used truck market in those countries and we are working towards, I think, an improving trend which is good news.</p>
          <p>Finally, taking a look at our soft offer growth, we expect the finance volume to continue to grow while we see recoveries in most of our mature markets. VFS is also continuing to expand our geographic footprint with these third party alliances, especially in Asia. We're seeing some good success there. And the investments we've made in VFS in country operations where we're owning the company and providing the financing in China, Australia and Japan are now really beginning to show some good promise so those investments are starting to pay off.</p>
          <p>That's about it, Leif, for Volvo Financial Services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you, Sal. We have Slide 16 and let me do a couple of minutes of summary here before we go into the Q&amp;A period.</p>
          <p>You see earnings per share there with the operating profits flowing down to the bottom line at 0.83 krona per share compared to a loss of 2.09 last year. You see operating cash flow there at minus 2.7, along the lines that Mikael commented before; much better than last year as we then had a cash outlay of 15.7.</p>
          <p>Sales are 4% higher and, as you can see, foreign exchange adjusted about 12%. Most of that is driven in the non-truck port. The truck port was up about 4%. Operating income then decidedly better than last year as we have reduced our costs and then we are quite happy to see that we were able to meet with the deadlines of introducing our new trucks with Group engines, both in Japan, our new FMX system in Europe and then also India as we have very good and steady progress with our Volvo iShare relationship.</p>
          <p>In focus as we are looking in over the next quarter here, productivity, cost control, cash flow are high there. And then we are also seeing a demand recovering off of very, very low levels in Europe and North America where we will no doubt there increase slightly the production with that &#x2013; their increased demand.</p>
          <p>With that, let's conclude the presentation mode here and go into the Q&amp;A mode. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Christer Fredriksson from ABG is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Three questions. Firstly, you talked about that you had roughly 50% capacity utilization with trucks in Q1 at the press conference. What was it in Q4 and also if you could maybe talk about what capacity utilization would be roughly in Q2, if you had any idea?</p>
          <p>Secondly, seems for VCE you were up quite much in Q1. Still, order book seems to have expanded sequentially. So maybe you could give some colors on the order intake for VCE in Q1 and also about the lead times we see for the moment?</p>
          <p>And thirdly about VCE as well; this strategy that you talked about in the press conference for in the period 2010-2012, is that a new strategy in addition to this one being the structural savings that you already presented? That is can we expect more savings and structural savings in VCE in the coming two years? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think while Olof thinks about those two VCE questions, let me answer on the capacity side. I think we need to separate different capacities in what &#x2013; and how we comment them. When we say 50% capacity, then we are talking about technical capacity. If you just remember where we were in the first half of '08 and compared to where we are now, then we are at about 50% of that technical capacity.</p>
          <p>That does not mean that we could go up to or put a lot of capacity without adding more people in assembly work so we would have to add people into that. I would probably say that the total pace of production around 10% higher in Q1 compared to Q4. But you have to remember that Q4 started at a slower pace and then gradually we ramped up, and then we had all of the holiday seasons and everything else. So it's very difficult to compare total output. Total output, clearly, was higher in Q1, even though the running pace was not that much higher. And again, you have the holiday season and the ramp up during the fourth quarter there.</p>
          <p>We will be increasing slightly. And I think the increase probably is around 10% production rate in Q2 if you would take an overall measurement, different in different product categories.</p>
          <p>Let's see, then, Olof you had a question about sales and VCE order intake?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Order intake, yeah? I think the order book has shown the increase is of course a reflection of the order intake. And what we can say, I think, is that within the quarter, this quarter I would say, we start to see normal seasonality that we perhaps didn't see in the last year. That means that we are looking at the spring season, again, going back to Leif's comments about moving into a normal economy.</p>
          <p>We are, of course, now also aligned our inventory to the demand so the delivery times that we do have is within normal range I would say; that's giving all markets and all models in average. There are, of course, ups and downs if you go down to the very details.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the strategy it's very much reflecting our new global organization. And it's definitely focusing on getting the full synergies out of our global organization in terms of the production network, in terms of procurement, product development; but also in terms of technology in overall CVE. So it is a strategy, as I said, focused very much on getting all the synergies out of our West organization that we have around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Nico Dil from JPMorgan is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Three quick questions please. First of all, the question is really around the operating leverage going forward. Could we expect something similar here to what we've seen historically or is it going to be slightly more limited because of the cost savings that you've taken out?</p>
          <p>Second question is when I look at your truck forecasts in Europe I can't help but think that this appears quite conservative, if you're only looking at up 10%. I'm just looking at Slide #10 here, I see orders of around 15 to 60,000 trucks. Deliveries were around 50,000 trucks in 2009; 10% up means 55,000 trucks. Basically, I'm wondering whether I'm missing something here. So the question really is 50 to 60,000 truck run rate implies Europe up 20 to 30%. You're guiding for up 10%. What is the mismatch?</p>
          <p>Third question is around financial services. Delinquencies are really stopping here. When are we going to see the improving trends? When can it actually start to make a step up in terms of the operating profit here? Can we expect that in sort of the second half of the year or potentially even later or sooner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I think, Mikael, should we ask you on the operating leverage? Comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. As you know, we don't want to get into the forecasting business here so it's different to guide you in a little detail there. But, of course, the challenge now is for us to hold on to the cost savings as we move forward here. And obviously our ambition is to get as much leverage as possible out. But it's, of course, always easier in the beginning of an upturn to really get the big percentage number in terms of leverage than it is when it starts to move into a more normal growth here. But we will certainly do everything we can here to keep reasonable leverage going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Sal, do you want to talk about the Finance side there? Financial Services?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Leif. In a lot of our markets we're seeing stabilization. We're seeing improvement. We're starting to see some early trends that are, you know, somewhat positive. But I have cautious optimism, if I could say it that way. We're seeing some good results in liquidating inventory but as Mikael has said, in the Volvo Group we do not give forecasts, but we're seeing some improving trends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And let me give a few comments on this truck forecast, you can say. In the first quarter, it looked like we were aggressive. Now we are saying that we are now perhaps on the conservative side. And of course the reason is that we have seen now what we can confirm to see it to be a reasonable turn around. I think the method that you used on market shares and incoming orders, you have to realize that, or you remember that the order intake there is light and medium, also while the slide that we showed on Europe is heavy trucks only, and then light and medium have been somewhat more resilient. Still, we think that that the 10% is a good number and it might look slightly more conservative than it did last quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrik Sjoblom from Cheuvreux is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. One question; just if you could help us to understand a little bit how we should think of mix and pricing in the trucks? I just note that you have reported 4% organic growth, and still your volumes or deliveries were up 15. So obviously there's something minus 11 in that number. And I would assume that emerging markets may carry sort of a lower price tag per vehicle but could you just elaborate a little bit on what we should think or how we should think on price mix, et cetera going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you have a little of a currency factor, but I'm actually looking at Christa to see if we can provide you with some intelligent answers on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Big mix affect on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Big mix affect geographically, which is probably the biggest effect, I think. You could make a little between medium and heavy, also, I think perhaps, but ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can do an analysis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let's see if we can come back to you, Patrik on some more, for us to provide you with a meaningful answers. It's also different between different months, as you saw in the delivery statistics there. So we're looking at Christa here to sort that out a little more in detail for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Frederic Stahl from UBS is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. It's Frederic here at UBS. I had a question on &#x2013; well, two questions. First of all, if you look at Brazil it's clearly a strong market, but I'm still a bit surprised that the order momentum dropped as much as it did after admittedly two strong quarters, but the incentives are still in place, the economy is still on fire. And so I was just curious if you could give us some more color on what's happening in Brazil?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I'm curious about, you mentioned a couple of times in the call here that you want to increase flexibility in the Group, across the Group, and I was wondering if you could give us some examples on how you want to do that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on Brazil, I think the &#x2013; what's happening there was &#x2013; you remember, there's a very big fare in the last quarter, and that probably forwarded some of the order intake that should have come in this past quarter into the last quarter of 2009. We think that is most of the effect. We don't think that there is really a showing of double digit down of the market there. The fare distorted those numbers.</p>
          <p>Then on the flexibility side, it's very clear that we, in many parts of the world, had we think, at least with the flexibility requirements and the volatility that we have seen, we had too much fixed costs in terms of fixed employment. And therefore, we are coming into a greater flexibility, more temporaries; also manning companies, if you wish, consultancies, that type of situation. And then also you can say in general we have a trend to try to move fixed costs into more variable costs. That's through our supplier and our supply base, and especially in the non-automotive products and a number of activities like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben Maslen from Merrill Lynch is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, everyone. It's Ben Maslen from Merrill Lynch. Two questions, please. Firstly, your guidance of construction equipment growth in Asia for the year is 20 to 25%. You've done 55% in the first quarter so it implies a fairly sharp slowdown over the rest of the year. Is that a function of just hitting tougher comparatives? Or do you kind of bake in the idea that certain markets might slow or weaken going forward? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question, just on raw materials. Please say what you're seeing in terms of input costs pressure and how confident are you that you can put prices up enough going forward to offset that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Olof?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think there are two things here. One is, of course, that you have the normal season, the spring season coming up, which means that you have a drive in the beginning of the year now, in Q1. And then it's absolutely correct what you're saying: at the back end of the year it's hitting also comparisons that are tougher because of the upturn actually started the back end of last year in Asia. So that's the reason.</p>
          <p>I think on the raw material side we do, and we have commented that earlier before, we do see that as an issue in the next couple of quarters with the raw material inflation. We have Asia still at very high levels of market. And we possibly have then Europe and North America beginning to come back albeit from small, low levels.</p>
          <p>What we are concerned with, of course, are the basic of raw material, the steel, all of the rubber, et cetera that goes into trucks. We have a couple of tons of them, of steel, in any of our product. And we see a raw material pressure up certainly different in different categories of products; slightly different regionally and definitely different between different contracts that we have. But especially on the price side, given the new business models of the iron-ore producers and potentially what that means for not being able to do longer-term contracts. In steel, at least I think we can expect a greater volatility than what we have done before.</p>
          <p>Now typically, if you look at it over time, our industries in general, construction equipment and the Truck side, have been able to get raw material inflation across to our customers. So we have a history of being able to do that and we would certainly attempt to do that also. But exactly how that goes in between different quarters in a more volatile steel market is more difficult to forecast. But our intent, certainly, is to try to compensate for the raw material increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Maybe just a follow-up on Construction Equipment, if I may. Can you just say a little bit what's happening in the Chinese market? It's obviously been very strong for longer than most other markets over the last year or so. Any signs that that market could roll over a little bit as we go through this year, as the government pulls back kind of stimulus spending and other actions that's used to kind of keep the economy going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We didn't see anything of that in the first quarter. Looking forward into the next quarter to come, it's very difficult to say. Long term, it is a market that we feel will develop very good for us, but how that will go up and down in the different quarters it will be difficult to say, because it depends so much on the different activities that would come and there are a lot of discussion back and forth there in China about the different areas. But what we have seen so far, we don't see any rollover or any change in the positive outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Colin Gibson from HSBC is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Yeah, a couple of follow-up questions, please, from ones this morning. First of all, emerging market growth rates, you a number of times both on the press call this morning and now this afternoon have sounded slightly cautious notes; for example, on Brazilian growth in the press call this morning you said, I think you opened the question whether Chinese and Indian growth could continue at this pace indefinitely. I'm sure that all that's very sensible caution, but what do you think &#x2013; how big do you think the risk really is that at some time over the next few quarters, and perhaps going into 2011, that we do actually see growth rates come off sharply in emerging markets just as developed markets are recovering? Because I imagine that most analysts will default to a kind of assumption that emerging market growth continues whilst developed market growth recovers. And I'm just trying to understand in my own mind what the risks would be to that scenario.</p>
          <p>Second question, I think Scania have recently said they're ready for Euro 6. They have their own stand-alone Euro 6 solution and they're keen to get it on. And I'm sure everything that's gone there say right now is designed for consumption primarily in Wolfsburg and Munich, rather than people like me. But how does Volvo feel about Euro 6? Would you &#x2013; do you feel you're ready for Euro 6 already? Would you be happy, for example, if the Germans decided, like they did with Euro 5, that they should be pre-incentivizing Euro 6? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I think first of all on the emerging market and a little of our caution there. I think it's more based on long-time experience and I think you are &#x2013; you used the word to be reasonably cautious when things happen. When markets have grown for a long while, and they have, and when they're coming to high absolute numbers, then it's reasonable to expect that sooner or later they're going to have to at least slow up a little.</p>
          <p>And I think when it comes to Brazil, you can say Brazil has changed; the whole of the way we see that country. We used to always say that Brazil was always the country that had its future ahead of it but never actually were able to arrive at that future. Now we think they have arrived. They are doing well. There's nothing to complain about Brazil and you can actually become quite optimistic about it even long term. Still, we would say that with historic terms that there is a reason to be slightly cautious there.</p>
          <p>And you can probably make the same argument with India and China. As Olof was saying, we see nothing that would suggest us to be more cautious than what we are. We are certainly not planning for any downturn. But you have a situation now where the Chinese market often as big as the rest of the world and possibly in some product categories even bigger. Does that say something about the rest of the world, which means that they would have to come back up? Or does it say something that the Chinese market is too big? It's difficult. So we really have nothing to guide you there other than, you can say, a reasonable long life experience of how our markets typically go up and down.</p>
          <p>Then on the Euro 6 side, we are very comfortable from a technology point of view that we are proud to have just introduced U.S. 10. There is a lot of carryover between U.S. 10 and Euro 6. We are doing very well with U.S. 10. We think we are offering a much cleaner truck at reasonable cost increases, even though some customers might think that they are high. And we are also giving very good fuel efficiency. So we think Euro 6 will be well achieved.</p>
          <p>Overall, you can say, on this incentive program &#x2013; we are not against incentive programs but we frankly would prefer them to be on a European level rather than on a national state level. When you come into a situation where the Germans have one incentive program and the Dutch have another one and the Swedes have yet another one, that distorts markets. And it creates a situation where in some countries we would be delivering what you could call Euro 6 products and in some markets we wouldn't. So it actually sometimes creates more costs than it does really good things, even from an environmental point of view. But technologically, we are there.</p>
          <p>Let me just say that we have still very high expectations on the European Commission. You know, the European Commission haven't yet come up with any language what is really Euro 6? Aside from the levels of nitrogen oxides and particles, which we have no problems with and which have been over a long while, the actual wording of what Euro 6 really means and how to measure and certify, et cetera is not there at all. Frankly, it doesn't exist. And we think, actually the European Commission will need to advance and get remarkably quicker here for it to be meaningful to have any incentive period at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mitchell Hartlan from Swede Bank Market is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. A couple of questions here; firstly, on spare parts and after-market sales, that tends to be a driver for new equipment. Could you elaborate a little bit on the trends that you have been seeing in the divisions maybe on quarter-to-quarter and also maybe on year-over-year basis? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the best way to say that, in the beginning of the crisis, last part of 2008 and over 2009, we actually saw an impact on spare parts sales and service as many of our customers' products actually were parked. So we had a negative impact there and I think it probably bottomed out at around minus 10, minus 15 even in Europe on the Truck side. Now gradually over the past couple of quarters here we've seen that to start to come back up so one of the effects in Q1 against Q1 '09 was that we had double-digit better spare parts sales in Q1 this year compared to Q1 '09. And we see our customers' products rolling and working considerably more as we progress over the past couple of quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then just two other questions. On the tax rate, you're below 23% in the quarter. Is that sustainable for the year? And do you have a guidance for the future there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mikael, do you want to talk taxes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. No, you should not expect us to stay on 23. There was some one-time effects in this quarter and the guidance for the future is still the 30% tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on interest costs, have you &#x2013; could you elaborate a little bit on the &#x2013; your duration of your debt portfolio including swaps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as we have stated before here, we do not have any major maturities coming up the last &#x2013; in the next coming two years here. So it's really pushed out in time, the maturity here. But of course there is opportunity to pay down debt if we would come to that point moving forward. So there is certainly opportunities to bring down the interest debt when the cash flow start to come through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Patrik, Christa has actually done a little homework here in trying to sort out your question here about the mix and delivery volumes between Europe and the rest of the world. Christa?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick comment there. So as you saw the truck volumes globally were up 15% but it's quite a lot driven by the growth in India by iShare. So if you take out the iShare brand, then the volume growth is 8% compared to the 4% we have in revenues, FX adjusted. And then you also have to go into more deeper analysis on the mix there with Europe coming down, with high-priced products and some slower growth in international markets. But I would say that the iShare is the biggest impact there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. More questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yann Benhamou from Exane is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. This is Yann Benhamou from Exane. I have three questions. First one is you say that there was still inventories of used vehicles on the market. Do you have any idea of the excess inventories that you see on the &#x2013; in the U.S. and in Europe? In other words, how long does it take for to absorb this excess?</p>
          <p>Second question, could you remind us, what was the gap between retail and production last year for trucks and construction equipment? And finally do we have any idea of what was the cost of inventory reduction last year in terms of prices that you gave to clients in order to get rid of those inventories? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the third question, it's a question that we had many times during past year and it's almost impossible to answer that. I think we have said that a number of times. You want to have a catchall number there and we are &#x2013; you're dealing with many different product categories, many different markets and very unique situations.</p>
          <p>So I think we need to say that we can't really give you a good number. Not because we don't want to, but because we can't really assess that whole situation. We went through, you know, basically six quarters here of really strongly falling markets.</p>
          <p>The other one, which is the difference between what we sold and what we produced last year is easier. If you take on finished goods and new product then you can say we &#x2013; basically, the Group now has about half of our turnover, about 100 billion, which is population driven and after-market and sales driven and the other half are new product.</p>
          <p>And of that &#x2013; which is then give you another 100 billion, out of that we actually reduced inventories by 17% &#x2013; by 17 billion. Seventeen billion off of a hundred sales you can say then you are between 15 and 20% lower production than sales. So that's really good numbers to guide you in between the difference between our sales and productions of last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I can understand. But I guess that in Q1 last year it was particularly weak so this is on an average for 2009. But do you have any idea for Q1 specifically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think you could actually do the math yourself there. And we can do it for you if you, we &#x2013; I think we gave you inventory numbers for Q1 this year and last year. So I think if you go by the inventory numbers there you can actually see the effect quite well there on sales. We can help you with that I think with Christa if he follows that up later on.</p>
          <p>Inventories of used vehicles in general is beginning to be less of a problem. We even commented here that we see used vehicle prices on an upward trend as the markets are beginning to come back up. There are still pockets of used &#x2013; in our Group, still pockets of used vehicles, slightly too much like in Spain for example. But overall we don't &#x2013; we are beginning to say we don't have much of an issue on used vehicles. We still have some also in Eastern Europe. But overall, not a major issue any longer and prices beginning to come back up. My impression is that this is true in general for the industry. In general, we think our competitors might have slightly more but not for it to be a major issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So in other words you would say that there no hurdle left for people to ask for new trucks now even that inventories are off used vehicles are quite adjusted?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's actually what you're beginning to see with the improving order intake rate in Europe and North America, that our customers now are beginning to say with the now improved situation of better financing and many of the very attractively-priced used trucks gone, then let's go and take a look at the new truck instead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could we have one more final question there and then before we conclude?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Rodney Bridge from Societe Generale is on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just about everything's been asked. But there's still two little things; one is in Brazil. I mean you mentioned about the subsidized financing being going to expire in 2010 and perhaps we might seem like it's perhaps rolled over. But what's happening to the tax incentives?</p>
          <p>And then just one final thing on Aero. You mentioned you've got a lot of new contracts coming on. Should we assume that there's any margin difference in those new contracts, a), as they come in, and b), over the longer term? I mean will there be more profitable contracts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm looking around the table here on the tax incentives in the Brazilian market. It's &#x2013; we don't have any self-proclaimed experts on that so can we come back to you on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the Aero side, Staffan perhaps, you want to speak a little about how our business models work on Aero?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the contracts that are coming on is for a period being delivered now at year end starting delivering and we go on for a couple of years. It's &#x2013; the business model and the year ending business is the same and expectancies for the margins are achieved. There are no real changes there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, great to answer everyone for participating in the conference call of Q1 2010 and that closes the call. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This concludes today's Volvo Group reports. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>