<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1150749" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1536</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Leif Johansson, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mikael Bratt, Head of Corporate Finance and New Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Tony Helsham, President of Volvo Construction Equipment</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">H&#xE5;kan Karlsson, President of Volvo Bus Corporation</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">G&#xF6;ran Gummeson, President of Volvo Penta</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Olof Persson, President of Volvo Aero Corporation</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Salvatore L. Mauro, President of Volvo Financial Services</participant>
      <participant id="8">Julia Varesko</participant>
      <participant id="9">Leif Johansson</participant>
      <participant id="10">Fredric Stahl</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mikael Bratt</participant>
      <participant id="12">Tony Helsham</participant>
      <participant id="13">David Kramer</participant>
      <participant id="14">Salvatore Mauro</participant>
      <participant id="15">Mikael Brett</participant>
      <participant id="16">Andrew Casey</participant>
      <participant id="17">Peter Nesvold</participant>
      <participant id="18">Alexis Albert</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Volvo's Conference Call on the Report on the First Three Months 2008. It will start with a presentation and thereafter there will be a question-and-answer session. Please note that this conference is being recorded. The conference will be shared by Mr. Leif Johansson, CEO of Volvo. Mr. Johansson, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and most welcome to this first quarter 2008 telephone conference call. We are in G&#xF6;teborg this time around and we have around the table here our different business area leaders. But we also have our new CFO, Mikael Bratt, and they will speak in turn as we go through the different businesses. We will be using &#x2013; speaking to notes or slides that you can find on our site and we'll highlight when we switch the slides here.</p>
          <p>So look at the slide, the Group Highlights first quarter slide, number two. And, we have a business environment in the first quarter that was characterized by Europe and our best assessment would be to say that we are still at a reasonably good growth mode but slower growth than what we had in the fourth quarter in 2007. We'll come back into more detail on that and how to understand the order intake numbers, especially on trucks, et cetera, as we go through the conference call here. All in all, we think a fairly robust mixture in Europe.</p>
          <p>That's not true of North America. In the North America, we had a continued weak market and a little unlike what we were speculating in the fourth quarter of 2007 that the market would start to come back towards the end of the year. We don't really see that or at least we can just say we don't want to speculate to that. We did have some order intake increases in the first quarter here compared to first quarter last year. But we are little hesitant to really start putting production up there on the truck side; it's actually going the other way. We have decided to stay on the low production rates so as to not build inventory there.</p>
          <p>Japan is more like North America than it is Europe. There was a pre-buy affect there that we now have a slower market especially on the truck side.</p>
          <p>Contrary to that, we can say we have had a very strong development in Asia and other international markets and they continue to be very strong. This is also true of markets like the Middle East.</p>
          <p>And all in all, the combination there, if you look at our deliveries, the combination actually meant that North America did not grow very much in the quarter, basically flat. And with Asia growing as much as it did, that made Asia actually our second biggest continent after Europe.</p>
          <p>But sales were up 26%; operating income were up 22%, markedly better than quarter three or four last year. We were able to get better operating leverage as we grew with the business and offset then the downturn in North America. And when we look at our order book outside of the U.S., it continues to look very strong and long into the future. We'll take that more into detail as we come through the different numbers here.</p>
          <p>Slide three that says Net Sales shows you that we reached a milestone. We were &#x2013; we have been out and selling for almost 300 billion over the last 12 months, continue on our stronger growth there, and you could actually see Western Europe being up 17%; the Eastern Europe 37%; the Asia organically 27 and Asia with the acquisitions we have made ,134; the South America almost into the 20s here on growth.</p>
          <p>And, obviously, we are pleased with the acquisitions we have made and to the fact that they are now contributing to also to our bottom line. But even without the acquisitions, we have strong organic growth here with whole of the Group at 16 or Volvo CE at 38% organic growth. At about 300 billion and &#x2013; which is a good milestone to pass.</p>
          <p>If you look at the slide four that says Operating Income and we start from the bottom of that slide. We had a currency impact quarter-on-quarter, relevant quarter last year of about 400 million, most notably the Swedish crown dollar rate. And as always with Volvo the greatest impact of that is with VB and then Aero and Penta.</p>
          <p>We had a U.S. strike in our North American Volvo truck business to the cost of about 250 million and, obviously, on top of that the lack of deliveries that you can see in our sales numbers there. And we did take a bus restructuring charge of 120 million closing a fairly big facility in Finland as part of getting buses into better profitability than they have been over the past couple of quarters now.</p>
          <p>We also, because of the rules about how we amortize R&amp;D and spend R&amp;D, we have a difference between the quarters here of 429 million, quarter-on-quarter comparison, and obviously truck operations in the U.S. are far from where we would want them to be from a profitability point of view in truck share. The strike, of course, impact the truck operations in U.S.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, we have Volvo CE markedly better than the last couple of quarters here as they have cleaned up number of bottleneck issues in their different industrial operations, components especially. We have good development in Europe on the truck side. We have also &#x2013; are happy to report that we have been able to use the introduction of many new products to improve value and thereby price. On top of that, we had a quarter of good productivity relatively stable, relatively little disturbances in our production in Europe and international. And all of that combined, stands into a record quarter for us at 6.5 billion on very good growth in sales.</p>
          <p>If you flip to Volvo Group financial summary there, slide five, and have our new CFO, Mikael Bratt, to take us through that slide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Leif. Just a few additional comments to the financial results. But, firstly, I just want to point out that we have added some new information to this page, which you can see at the bottom half where we are presenting the EBITDA and EBITDA margin for our industrial operations. But I will come back to that shortly.</p>
          <p>As you have heard, a strong quarter with sales increases and operating results for industrial operations SEK 6.1 billion deriving from a slightly better gross income margin level of 23.7%, SEK 17.6 billion which <mark type="inaudible" /> up SEK 3.9 billion as compared to Q1 '07 and then due to better productivity, price management, as well as the volume in itself &#x2013; and the SEK 3.1 billion operating income and the negative effects from the currency as Leif spoke about as well as the strike in New River which resulted in negative SEK 250 million.</p>
          <p>If we then continue with R&amp;D expenses, which for the quarter is 3.3 billion -1 billion higher than the same period last year &#x2013; the main cause from this increase comes from acquired companies.</p>
          <p>Net effect from capitalization is negative SEK 340 million in the quarter and SEK 439 million effect in the year -of the year effect.</p>
          <p>S&amp;A 1.2 billion higher than in Q107 in absolute amounts but slightly better when you look at in relation to sales. There we have 10.8% compared 11.5% in Q107. Main part of the increase comes from acquired companies as well as expansion of our distribution network furthering the brand in Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>On the other operating income and expense, you see a swing of SEK 470 million to a negative of 172 million in the quarter. Main reason is the restructuring cost in Volvo Buses as Leif has talked about as well as the <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>With contribution from our customer finance operation of SEK 391 million in the quarter, we end up with 6.5 billion in operating income for the quarter, giving us the margin 8.5 for the group.</p>
          <p>In the quarter we had a net interest expense of SEK 62 million to be compared with an income of SEK 93 million in Q107. The reason behind the swing is primarily due to increased debt levels. In the quarter we also had a negative effect of SEK 294 million in other financial income and expenses. That's the result of market valuation of derivatives used to customer financing portfolio. And a negative impact is mainly due to the long-term interest rates. Last year we had a positive of SEK 16 million.</p>
          <p>On the tax side, we have effective tax rate of 31% equal to SEK 1.9 billion in taxes. And with that, we have earned income for the period of 4.2 billion, a margin of 5.5.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned in the beginning, we have introduced EBITDA and EBITDA margin in the report and here we are adding back depreciation and amortization from the operating income on the Industrial operations. This will help you to get better visibility of the underlying business performance.</p>
          <p>EBITDA is up 25% compared to Q107, to 8.7 billion and margin of 11.7. Operating cash flow from the Industrial operations is negative 3.3 billion in the quarter, about the same level as last year. As you know the first the quarter is traditionally a tough quarter and we see the same seasonal effects this year. With a negative cash flow in the quarter we end up with a net financial position of 6.5 billion negative in our Industrial operations side of the business equal to net debt equity ratio of 8.3% negative. It should then be compared to Q407 where we had 5.7% negative.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, it has clearly been beneficial for us to have a healthy balance sheet when servicing our debt. In the volatile debt market that has been, and we have managed to service the debt in an efficient way during the period.</p>
          <p>And with that I will end my part of the presentation. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Come to the slide that said Trucks, so slide six on the slides here and let me take you through the trucks and the order intake numbers there. In the quarter, obviously we were able to compensate the week demands in North America and the strike in New River Valley on the sale side, by strong demand in Asia and in Europe and also on the operating income side, so much so that we made 4.4 billion on sales of 51 in the quarter there</p>
          <p>If you look at our way we look forward you can then say we are still in the mode where we are very low on order books in Europe, and we are gradually increasing capacity and as you saw in our delivery schedules then, we have managed to get capacity up quite well between the two quarters that we compare with the first quarter also of last year. And we've done that through bottleneck investments but also improved productivity and that comes well. And we are still in a mode of trying to get even more production underway as our order books are still way into between 9 and 12 months on the different brands.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the next slide, which is heavy-duty truck market in Europe, we actually said before that we were forecasting the '08 market to between 5 and 10%. Now, we are actually saying 10% there, and what we are looking at is a better supply picture and availability of trucks, both in our own facilities but our assessment is also with our competitors, so much so that we will see a plus 10 growth there.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we have an order intake which is now beginning to take orders for the first quarter of 2009. Which of course in the history of the group is remarkably very, very high long order books. Had we said a couple of years ago that we would take orders and start filling quarters, there were 3 quarters or 4 quarters ahead of us that would have been really news.</p>
          <p>So one way to look at that is to say of course that it is a very robust market that even given these long order books and perhaps the uncertainty on the economy, we start filling up the quarters, there are 4 quarters ahead of us. And other one would be to say that's it's lower than the order intake we had when we were filling up these 12 months of order books in the first quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>So difficult to forecast there. But our total assessment of that is that we have orders in Europe that are robust and that are meeting with the projections through the end of '08 and then we would see as we go through the quarters how the order intake as we start filling the Quarter 1 '09, Quarter 2 '09 production.</p>
          <p>And at the same time if you take the look at the next slide, in North America we are now actually saying that we don't see the market coming up in '08. We actually see a flat market there for the rest of the year and we don't want to speculate and build inventories as you will see later on in the Mack presentation, Mack actually had a fairly good comparison on the order rate, but we would like to see that come through for a couple of more months here till we get production up again.</p>
          <p>But our basic scenario is still the same, that '09 is going to start to come up for two reasons. One is obviously you can speculate in that turnaround in the North American economy, but less that and perhaps more the fact that we expect a pre-buy effect similar to what we had in '06 come '09 then based on the new emission standards beginning in 2010.</p>
          <p>If you look at Volvo Trucks, slide nine, then you can see here a substantial order book. We are basically sold out for all of 2008 in Europe and International. As you can see our delivery is coming up and we are beginning now to book orders for the first quarter of '09 or second quarter of '09. And normally, that would be a very healthy development that we are taking orders with that far outlook. And at the same time, it's also fair to say that we do hear from of some of our customers a greater uncertainty than they had a year ago when they were looking at our order book. So we will need a couple of more quarters to see where that takes us but good news is so far that we've been able to start filling orders almost a year out.</p>
          <p>We have good margin improvement that is based on all the new products that we have released and also very good productivity. And we are right in the midst now of field testing the future hybrid refuse trucks, especially that's an attractive more segment for Volvo Trucks, as you know, and we have delivered our first two field prototypes on hybrids here in Sweden.</p>
          <p>If you look at Renault Trucks, there we have an even clearer situation. We basically did not open our books for delivery in 2009 in Q1 and obviously that makes comparisons reasonably easy. We see a situation where we have a greater amount of dealer orders for Renault Trucks. So therefore a little unwilling to speculate in what those might be. But we have in Q2 open our order books, and our assessment is the same that basically with Renault and Volvo, basically sold out for all of 2008 and then beginning to take orders for the first quarter and 2009.</p>
          <p>A robust picture and very good industrial productivity coming out of Renault Trucks and with that also better financial performance. And let me also say that we're very happy with the way we have introduced products as Renault Trucks. All of the new products there are doing very well, strengthening the brand image of Renault Trucks, and with that the ability to get better margins.</p>
          <p>Nissan Diesel, which is impacted negatively by the downturns, more and more economy than pre-buy effects as we go through the quarter, Japanese market is probably down 10 to 15%. So far we've been able to offset that with good export in especially into the areas around Japan and Asia which are still growing quickly and where we have the added enhancement of the Volvo Group organizational marketing structure for Nissan Diesel.</p>
          <p>Integration of work is on plan, and we expect to be on plan also when it comes to delivering synergies there that are favorable for the next couple of years.</p>
          <p>Mack Trucks on slide 12. As you can see, their deliveries were down 23% relevant quarter comparison again because of the U.S. '04 products still in the works that we were delivering in the first quarter of '07. But as you see order intakes, they're up 38%. And that's a little too early to say that we have a turnaround, we're actually saying we will wait that for another quarter. But it's clearly something that we are looking at.</p>
          <p>And then again, our basic scenario is that the U.S. market on the back of pre-buy should be coming up in '09 here. And that goes also true for construction equipment. We see there a real softening in the U.S. construction market, and quite frankly we have seen the U.S. construction market come down over a couple of quarters now. We will see how that runs through.</p>
          <p>Big discussion on rising diesel prices; in the main we would say that most of our customers or a very large majority of our customers have fuel clauses in their contracts, so it's more a matter of lagging how to get that across to our customer's customer. But obviously, still an issue in the industry as such.</p>
          <p>We have UAW negotiations ahead of us on the Mack side that impacts Macungie, Allentown and Hagerstown and, as you know, those are always a strain on the organization. We need to make sure that we can find terms and conditions that can make Mack and that configuration competitive also over the longer whole year.</p>
          <p>And we were able to introduce as part of the overall package of group engines plus you know we have now two engine families around the world, in the heavy-duty engine family we have a 9, 11 and a 13 and a 16 liter engine. In the Mack version that group engine is actually going into a new prestige truck what we say &#x2013; we call Titan, introduced in CONEXPO here in March, and with that, we are for the first time actually in a couple of decades coming back into the real prestige segment with a Mack Truck and a big powerful 16-liter engine.</p>
          <p>And again you can say show how we in the group count build a product range for example for Mack here because our Powertrain strategy that will give somewhat relatively low cost ability to compete in completely new segment. So we are happy and proud of that.</p>
          <p>With that let me switch to Construction Equipment, and we have Tony Helsham to speak here to slide 13, the one that says Construction Equipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Leif. The overall market condition for the Construction Equipment industry continues to be reasonably good. The continuing downturn in North America is compensated by strong development in other markets, so that the total global market is up 7% in the first quarter compared to the same period last year.</p>
          <p>In the Heavy segment, Europe was up 4% North America still down, and now 34% down; whilst Asia and other markets are up 41 and 28% respectively. In the Compact segment, Europe was down 10%, North America was down 21, and Asia and other markets were up 25 and 40% respectively.</p>
          <p>If you look at the financial performance, of course, we saw some fairly good improvements in the quarter with the top-line growth of 38%, and also the operating income grew at the same amount 38%. On the other hand, the result was negatively impacted by the currency effects that Leif mentioned, and also ongoing integration costs related to the newly acquired primarily Road Machinery business.</p>
          <p>The focus right now is to continue to work on improving the productivity and further reduce the bottlenecks in the production system, mainly in the components, and that work will continue for the balance of this year. And there is of course still ongoing work to be done with the integration of principally Road Machinery.</p>
          <p>Even if the global demand for construction machinery is still good, we notice a clear geographical shift where the trend is moving eastwards to Asia and also to other international markets, and we have to monitor this shift carefully to ensure we allocate the right products to the right markets with the strongest demands.</p>
          <p>And finally, I would like to mention the showing of our first-generation hybrid wheel loader also at the CONEXPO show in North America last month. In this first generation of hybrid wheel loaders we have a potential fuel saving of 10%, which represents a substantial saving for the operators of the equipment since more than one-third of the running cost of this type of equipment is fuel cost. And production of this hybrid wheel loader, this version of the hybrid wheel loader, is expected to begin during 2009.</p>
          <p>With that, Leif, I think we'll finish on Construction Equipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. We have Buses, slide 14; and we have H&#xE5;kan Karlsson, President of Buses, to speak to that slide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Leif. Bus market development in North America continue to slow down the coach market, while the city bus market I will say is still stable and performing fairly good in North America. In Europe, we foresee a flat total market with an increase especially in the city bus segment. There seems to be money put into the city bus segment so there we see a growth in front of us. Asia continue to grow especially with Chinese players now growing their export outside China. So we are meeting a fairly tough competition in the Asian region.</p>
          <p>We have some difficult quarters behind us and we have managed to maintain our sales volume, but reduced profitability. The main reason I will say is three then. First of all, we have a change in our product mix, moving from coaches into more city buses and there we have some slight lower margins on the city bus side compared to coaches.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we had as we have reported before some product problems in our city bus ranging in Europe. They are now totally solved and the factories are running well, very well I would say in the first quarter. And it's good to see them that the order intake here starts to pick up and we have an increase of the order intake, an 8%, during the quarter one and especially in the city bus range we saw some good orders coming in.</p>
          <p>Third element, that is significant negative currency development during the last 12 months. We produce in strong currency countries and sell in some of the weak countries. There is a swing of in about 10 to 20% there. So naturally we have a new level of profitability and margins in our Company and that we have addressed them in our profitability programs in all <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>The result in first quarter was on a breakeven excluding the one-time cost for closure of Tampere, in Finland, and it's clear that we have taken down the final decision to restructuring our Europe both industry and product structure, and that we will now close down the Tampere factory and that will be closed in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In focus going forward, the currency development requires an additional price increase, just now and we are implementing that, and our cost programs shows positive result in all regions and we will step-wise and implement these programs during 2008 and 2009.</p>
          <p>And important now in the second quarter is to manage the closure of the Tampere factory and also the <mark type="inaudible" /> support the employees in that region to get some new jobs and hopefully continue in the industry in somewhere else.</p>
          <p>So I think that is the report from Buses, Leif.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>That takes us to Volvo Penta, we have slide 15, and we have G&#xF6;ran Gummeson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Leif. We have had a continuous good development in the total business growth by 8%, and we see also strong growth in our industrial engine business, up actually 25%.</p>
          <p>In overall you can say, we have very much the same pictures for the rest of the Group, and we have a downturn in the marine market in the U.S. and we see a continuation of that. And we have managed to offset some of the effects there by gaining market shares in the U.S. market.</p>
          <p>In Europe the demand has been stable and in other parts of the world the demand has been very strong, for instance in China, India, Middle East and also in South America. We have strengthened our market shares in all segments where we are operating, and also actually in all the regions.</p>
          <p>The IPS system is doing very well and we are now increasing our capacity to be able to meet the global demand for that particular product. The strength in our operating margin is somewhat above 10% and driven by good price realization, and also the product mix, and thereby we have been able to compensate for the currency effects.</p>
          <p>In focus, going forward, now we are facing the boating season and we are preparing ourselves, and the network here to handle that in the best possible way in terms of service and support and also good lead times to our customers in the market. The low U.S. dollar makes it even more important for us also to handle the global pricing and in order to balance the competitive situation that we see is coming.</p>
          <p>And like I said earlier, we have had right now a strong growth of our industrial business and it's very positive that we have a growing share of power systems for the versatile market or for the versatile segment that is for engines then for forklifts, dozers, tractors, trains, et cetera. And of course we are using this momentum in the market in order to grow this business even further and thereby introducing a number of new industrial engines.</p>
          <p>That is in short Volvo Penta, Leif.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good volumes development there for the whole of the Group in terms of Powertrain.</p>
          <p>We have the slide 16, we have Volvo Aero and we have Olof Persson there to talk about the slide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Leif. On the market side we can conclude that activity remains high with good order intake of large aircrafts, both for Airbus and Boeing which have resulted in yet another record size of order backlog.</p>
          <p>Also when measuring the revenue <mark type="inaudible" />, we see that the market has increased with 3.5% in January and 6.5% in February. This high market activity is also reflected in the development of the order book for Volvo Aero.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, the value of the order book for our component business increased with 9%, measured in Swedish krona and actually 28% if you adjust for currency effects. We also continued to invest in our lightweight technology development, and the interest from customer and partners is increasing as we continue to deliver on the technology within this area.</p>
          <p>The high activity level in the market is also translated into solid sales growth in our business with some 10% volume increase if you adjust for currency divestments. And the good profitability within our component business continued on seeing the first quarter this year, however, with an increased negative headwind from a negative currency development. And we are focusing on mitigating that effect by further reduction of product costs and also by utilizing our U.S. manufacturing side to its maximum.</p>
          <p>And of course these activities will be increasing importance when we now ramp our production in a number of new delivery products. I think that was short from Volvo Aero.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good, we have Sal Mauro to speak about financial services. He made quite an extensive presentation at the press conference today, so if you want to look at that, you will have a lot more detail than we have time for now, let's have Financial Services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Leif, I'll keep it short. In the first quarter, we had very good volume of 9.9 billion, 14% increase from the quarter a year ago. Taking currency into effect, we had a portfolio growth of 16% from the first quarter in 2007, and I'm happy to say we're closing in on a milestone of a 100 billion SEK credit portfolio under management. We're seeing good volume from Eastern Europe, Latin America and Western Europe.</p>
          <p>Looking at the operating income of 381 for the quarter, which was I think good, we have after tax return on equity 12-month rolling average of 16.2%. I just like to draw everyone's attention that in the first quarter last year we changed the gearing of the Company our leverage point from 10% to 8%, which means more interest expense, but also for the small amount of equity a greater return.</p>
          <p>Taking out the effect of, let's say 2% for the leverage effect and 1% for some favorable tax adjustments, we're probably in a good range at about more normalized 13%, and of course our target is between 12 and 15% after-tax return on equity.</p>
          <p>We continue to score well on our customer satisfaction survey that has now become an annual event in all of our markets, listen closely to the customers and continue to make improvements on some of the constructive criticisms they give us. We are closely watching the North American portfolio, obviously we're going through a downturn in North America, we're much better positioned than we were during downturn in 2000-2001, and I believe the dealer body is also in better shape.</p>
          <p>We look at the diversification of the portfolio, which is one of our strengths, not only in products but also geographically. 48% of the portfolio was in Europe, 29% in North America, and now growing to 23% of the portfolio is in international, including Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>In focus, we're continuing to execute on new international opportunities, we're looking forward to opening up a new market this year in Chile and also growing with the Volvo Group and their acquisition strategy. We're looking to enter the Japanese markets some time in 2008-2009.</p>
          <p>We've done some very good work in restructuring our European operations. We're more inline with the BAs. We've given responsibility to some of our managers to look after individually to BAs in Europe, and I think that's early days, but it's working out very nicely. And of course we're continuing to be disciplined in our asset management. We're working with our customers, those that are having some problems, those that we feel can make it, we will modify their contracts to help them, but if we determine that they don't have the capacity to pay us back, we will repo the units and sell them in the quickest way possible. And I am happy to say that our inventory levels are at a good moderate level.</p>
          <p>We're continuing to improve our operations in the emerging markets and in order to manage some of the volumes that are coming in. All in all, a very good quarter for Volvo Financial Services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sal. And let me then sum up on the slide that says Group Summary here. We had SEK 2.07 per share in earnings and that translates it into a 19.2% return on equity there. Characterized then in the first quarter of 2008 by breaking the 300 billion rolling sales number, sales growth of 26%, and compensating really for a low development and I should say low value dollar in the U.S. And with that development and the strength and the acquisitions we have made in Asia, so much so that Asia is now, after greater Europe, our second largest market.</p>
          <p>And on the basis of much faster industrial productivity across the group, most notably in the Truck and the Construction Equipment side, we were able to get an operating income up to 22% on the growth of $0.26.</p>
          <p>In focus for 2008, we have reported a downturn in European truck orders compared to the first quarter 2007. There are different ways to look at that, we would right now take the robust view that it's very good news that we are filling up order books almost year out. And obviously as we go through the next couple of quarters we will know more how the European demand is shaping up.</p>
          <p>For the next couple of quarters, the challenge is to deliver what we have in order books and do that and give our capacity up to do it and at the same time get the different investments going. And as you know, we have made fairly big investments to get capacity up in Europe including the building of the Russian factory and building also of new engine capacity in Sweden. But that will not come on stream until the second half of '09.</p>
          <p>We are of course integrating acquisitions. I think it's an overall catch &#x2013; an overall statement. We could say that we have brought the Nissan Diesel and Lingong and Ingersoll Rand into Trucks or VCE respectively pulling down the averages but contributing very nice to its top line growth and also to the bottom line, but reducing the averages of those Trucks and VCE segments there.</p>
          <p>And then of course our intention is to continue to build on the international and strong Asian business that we have, doing that offsetting the weaker markets especially in the U.S. and in Japan.</p>
          <p>And with that let's open up for any questions you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have a question from Julia Varesko. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Julia Varesko from JPMorgan. My first question is on orders. If you have another quarter in Europe where orders decline 40%, let's say in Q2, were you going to start to look at adjusting production capacity down in Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are actually reading frankly that as fairly good news. If you remember, we are comparing here with a normal &#x2013; I was going to &#x2013; I want to use the word hysterical levels of over couple of quarters in '07 where we were building order books at twice our capacity. We now have on the business that normally has order books of three to four months, we now have order books of 10 to 12 months. And what we &#x2013; what is actually happening now is that we are taking orders and filling quarters &#x2013; slots in quarters that are four quarters out. And normally that is unheard of in our industry and it's still happening.</p>
          <p>So our total assessment overall is that we are looking at Europe as still a robust marketplace, slightly more I could say anecdotal uncertainty among customers when they place orders and, again, they are placing orders which is almost a year out for delivery. And we will see how this works out over the next couple of quarters. But certainly nothing that today would make us even touch the discussion on how to pull down volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when it comes to this 40% order decline, could you split that into Eastern Europe and Western Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think we can say it is probably so that the decline comparing to that number I would guess is slightly higher on the Western European side than it is on the Eastern European side. We were looking at Russia specifically in the morning here and we saw Russia is actually up evenly in that comparison. So probably slightly higher on the Western European side than on Eastern European side. But again, I think &#x2013; and we have tried to guide you as much as we can here &#x2013; if you look at the number that we are comparing with in Q1 2007, we were receiving orders which were twice our capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it has to be in that context.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would you &#x2013; do you prepare to give any view already for Europe for 2009 or is it too early?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's too early. I think we need a couple of quarters here with order intake and development before can do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Fredric Stahl from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, gentlemen. Fredric Stahl here from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The currency looked a bit low to me in the quarter. Are you prepared give us an indication on what that would like in the coming quarters? I also have a question on construction equipment and the profitability going forward with steel prices going up with your U.S. competition &#x2013; from what I understand &#x2013; pumping in equipment into Europe and whether you would be more &#x2013; give us some more detail on the production &#x2013; sorry the plant capacity increases in construction equipment, how much you increase in capacity and within what kind of equipment are we talking about. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the currencies here, should we ask Mikael to answer that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, of course, it's very difficult to predict to what will happen with the currencies moving forward here, but &#x2013; and we have a hedging policy in the Group here where we hedge 75% of our exposure six months out and, from seven to twelve months, we hedge 50% of our exposure. And if there are flows longer than that is also hedged fully. So we stick to that policy and, of course, we would see that all happens with the currency developing moving forward here. But to give that indication on the <mark type="inaudible" /> Group is impossible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Tony, industry capacities and our own capacities there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. First of all, there was a question related to the forward-looking profitability picture and, as we know, we don't give forward-looking views here. But I can say that, with respect to fuel prices, that is of course an industry-wide issue and all of us are facing the same pressure from the suppliers who've seem to be able to push through price increases almost at will and it has been an issue.</p>
          <p>What we have done recently, if you haven't been aware, is take an unprecedented position here in the industry in which we announced a 5% price increase for every product in every market starting in the middle of this year and rolling out the third and fourth quarters. And this is primarily down to protect the bottom line and to offset where we can, this pressure coming from the price of steel. And although I say we are contributing here to the inflation rate, the world inflation is our obligation to pass this onto the end users. And I could say that if we see the steel prices continuing to increase at the rate that they are, we'll take another serious look at the similar type approach. The good news is that some of our major competitors after seeing that we had increased the prices by 5% took a very similar approach and announced similar types of actions.</p>
          <p>When it comes to plant capacity increases, the major investment and the major activities revolve around additional and almost doubling the capacity of our components factory in the area of transmissions for wheel loaders, transmissions for articulated haulers, and transmissions for motor graders and axles for articulated haulers and wheel loaders. And on the back of the component increases, we intend to increase the production of articulated haulers in principle or in articulated haulers &#x2013; to a lesser extent wheel loaders.</p>
          <p>But also we have a big intention to continue to increase the capacity of excavators as the demand for the products that we acquired some years ago now from Samsung continues to exceed our supply. We need to look at one or two more facilities in different locations around the world and also some good news that we have now to take some decisions with respect to road machinery. The demand for the products that we acquired with Ingersoll Rand acquisition, actually the demand is now exceeding the supply on some products and we have to take some decisions there probably within the next few months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. David Kramer from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thanks. A couple of questions. First of all on the capacity increases that you're planning for the engines and gear boxes within the truck division, can you just confirm when they're coming on stream and, all else equal, are you expecting that to have an immediate benefit to your margins or is it a case that it could take a couple of quarters for that to get up to speed? Secondly, Nissan Diesel, and I noticed you didn't disclose any profitability details this quarter. Can you give us at least some qualitative comments on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. I think on the engine and gear boxes &#x2013; the main installations in fact is being done in the vacation time 2009, so it won't come on stream and really deliver &#x2013; be able to deliver higher volumes and towards the end quarter four in 2009. We are looking at that &#x2013; the capacity investments and we &#x2013; to the tune of about 20% increase and it's really the foundry there which is the big change that we can get foundry capacity up, which of course is very basic and with that comes machining then &#x2013; but about 20% capacity increase.</p>
          <p>But we are also looking at it as a good productivity investment. And we are expecting, over time that to make our manufacturing base in from <mark type="inaudible" /> more competitive and hopefully, over time, we &#x2013; if we can outperform our competitors in that, that would be able to get us &#x2013; get in to better margins also. We will certainly &#x2013; our intention is to try to achieve that.</p>
          <p>As always, when you make big investments and changes, there is a risk that it takes a couple of more months to run in than what we would have liked to see, but we are certainly doing everything we can to try to offset those risks. The risks are always there when you make big investments like that. But then we are talking about a couple of months also. We're not talking about anything that would put in question the investment of both manufacturing capacity there and productivity and, with that, we hope margins &#x2013; and hopefully that will put margins on the higher sales.</p>
          <p>Gear boxes is a similar situation. And gear boxes, we've had a run away success with our automatic gear box here. We have that now in very high proportion on the Volvo side. To some, we have it on proportion in Renault, but we are &#x2013; a big proportion in Renault, but we are limited there. And likewise, over time, we expect to see also Mack come in and benefit from automatic gear boxes there, but there we are really squeezed for capacity. And the investment we are making there, we might want to take that even further as we will evaluate over the next couple of quarters because of the much greater interest in on automatic gear box than we've had before.</p>
          <p>On the Nissan Diesel side, it's correct that we gave the breakdown numbers for Nissan Diesel and Ingersoll Rand and Lingong. We won't be able to do that in the future and that's really as a consequence of a much more integration. With Nissan Diesel, we have done the same process and integration efforts that we did with Mack and Renault, which means that consolidating in Volvo Powertrain Nissan Diesel with engine manufacturing, changing product programs, and putting them into that organization. And likewise, on 3P, which means that Nissan Diesel is benefiting from the &#x2013; all of their efforts at 3P but also contributing to that. So, over time it does not become especially meaningful for them to look at this as <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>But the overall assessment that we have is that the work we are doing with Nissan Diesel goes well. We confirmed the targets that we have set ourselves for synergies with that. We could probably say slightly good, slightly less strong Japanese markets and where what we could have wished for on the other hand doing well on the export side and so far been able to compensate the downturn in Japan with that. So, all in all, according to plan where we would like to see good work being done and I probably say the same thing about Ingersoll Rand and Lingong &#x2013; contributing nicely both top line taking down the average of margins so far but good programs to get that up also and, from the synergy and integration point of view, all according to plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. Maybe if I could have one final follow-up question on the negative valuation of derivatives for your customer finance portfolio. Can you talk a little bit about what you expect there? In other words, if US interest rates remain where they are for the rest of the year, can we expect a similar effect in the remaining quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> question on the customer finance portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually, just to clarify, customer finance match funds the entire portfolio with our treasury operation. I think Mikael was referring to inside treasury and how that works. And I don't know if &#x2013; Mikael, you want to comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct. That's the derivative we used in the treasury operation for this relating to the funding of the commercial finance operation. And also, in treasury we work with the rate loss matching on this kind of items. This is pure, I would say accounting IFRS question where we have not applied hedge accounting to these portion of the portfolio purely because it's too complicated to do. But that's a principle we are working and along the lines as I mentioned here. And what kind of effect you will see there I would say it's impossible to predict the number there and I don't think we should do that, but it's &#x2013; do not indicate that a mix matching is accounting issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. <mark type="inaudible" />, I have two question, please more specifically on the orders. First of all we see the 23% decrease in Brazil, does it reflect part of the decline ahead of the new aggregation of 2009? In North America regarding the 8% upturn, given that Mack is at 38%, does it mean that Volvo Trucks were flat? And then can we conclude that you had <mark type="inaudible" /> order concession during this strike? And finally, just concerned if we still have to book PPA adjustment for Nissan Diesel and construction equipment? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the Volvo Trucks and the North American market you can say we &#x2013; if you remember correctly, we had quite a reasonable order intake on Volvo Trucks in quarter four and it started good. But then we had the strike, and we think it became a situation there where customers were looking at striking factory and outputting orders there, while on the Mack side that looked more easy. I think we are looking at the strike though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And for Brazil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes I think Brazil; I don't have the real details there. But our overall assessment is that again, we have long order books there. We may be looking at a little of a pre-buy effect there also. But the overall &#x2013; at the same time we can say the overall economy in Brazil is very strong. So, all in all, we would probably say, steady as you go there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And let's see then we have the PPA adjustments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On the PPA side, for Nissan Diesel we are booking SEK 150 million in quarter one, and we have also closed the PPA balance in Q1 for Nissan Diesel cost. But it's something that's so radically posting down SEK 21 million in Q1 and that balance is still open, expecting to close the PPA balance for that during the surrounding Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Q2. So, if I understand well, there would be no PPA adjustments in Q2 for Nissan Diesel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Andy Casey from Wachovia Securities. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Couple of questions on construction equipment, first on the European forecast, it's kind of flat for full year, yet 1Q was down 6%. Can you help us understand what you're expecting to drive the improvement in the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think Andy, the best way to answer that is that we expect &#x2013; it's down for the first quarter in Europe, but that is including compact equipment which is down 10, and heavy equipment which is up 4. And I think you should read into this that we'll probably still see compact equipment in Europe head south, and we're expecting the heavy equipment to remain more or less flat or up a little bit, but not a lot of headwinds &#x2013; tailwinds there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, Tony, the flat here is related to heavy, not for -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mainly to heavy &#x2013; yes principally to the heavy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And then in North America, still on construction equipment, have you seen any increase in aggressive marketing tactics emerging over here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not overall, only &#x2013; and in fact I would have to say most &#x2013; all of the competitors have been pretty disciplined so far during this part of the down cycle. We saw some aggressive moves by Komatsu there whilst the Japanese yen was at a rate of about 100 to the $1. But that seems to have backed off now; we see is the big Caterpillar trying to free up a bit of inventory, but this is mainly on local programs, also perhaps in subsidizing the rate here on the finance side, but overall, still fairly disciplined.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And then one final question moving away from construction equipment and just kind of a blend of the Finance Group and the Truck Group. In North America, in the release you talked about delinquencies kind of increasing a little bit. Did they accelerate from Q4, and are you seeing any further deterioration of some of the used truck valuations? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Taking a look at the losses and the delinquencies, I think it started probably in the third quarter of 2007 and has been continuing through the fourth quarter and into the first quarter of 2008. We have to remember though that beginning of 2007 and 2006 were historically low levels of delinquencies, of write-offs and provision. To answer your question on the used truck and construction equipment values, we're seeing on the truck side, in Volvo Truck the values are actually holding quite nicely. What's different I think at this time of the cycle in North America is that there is a pretty good release valve of exporting trucks outside of North America that is helping us to maintain prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Same on CE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd probably say the same on CE here, that the pressure or the demand from other markets is not a position where you do a lot of aggressive marketing in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mrs. Julia Varesko. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello sir. I have a follow up on PPA just to make sure I understand it correctly. When you say you closed the PPA balance in Nissan Diesel, do you mean that there will be no balance sheet adjustments to the PPA value, or you mean that you will stop having this 150 per quarter altogether? And I also was wondering, could you quantify the acquisition impact on sales in trucks and construction equipment even if you can't do it for EBIT?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I should be clarify that; what I meant when I said that we will not have an adjustment on the PPA balance, I meant that the balance per se is closer to Q1, but we will continue to appreciate about 150 million SEK in the quarter moving forward when it comes to Nissan Diesel. So, I hope that it's clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's see, the numbers on the top line sales for acquisitions is excluded. Mikael you have those numbers. Good, the Nissan Diesel net sales for the quarter was 7.1 million SEK and Ingersoll Rand was about 1 billion SEK in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Peter Nesvold from Bear Stearns, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Leif.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, in Europe you had mentioned that the order intake, the bookings were down year-over-year because you hadn't opened up the 2009 window yet; was that the same case in South America because I am just trying to get little bit more color on why bookings were down double digits in that region as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for asking, Peter. Yes, the answer is yes, and we missed that when we answered the last question about Brazil. We had same situation there, and we are concerned with taking very long order books in Brazil where the inflationary environment that we had in Brazil. So the answer is absolutely, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it just inflation or is it also that you worry about speculative orders coming into the book? And sort of along that same theme, we had heard reports of a sizable cancellation at Volvo Trucks North America last month. I am curious, what kind of cancellation rates are you seeing regionally right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; typically I should say we don't see cancellation other than occasionally and so far we've been &#x2013; it's been very easy to get those replaced with other customers &#x2013; and frankly very, very small numbers. We are somewhat &#x2013; we are less concerned on Volvo Trucks Europe for example; there we have, in the main final customers already there and identified. We are a little more concerned which is why we took the attitude with Renault Trucks that we could have speculative dealer orders. And we didn't want to open up that route in the first quarter here. But it's something that we are watching very carefully; we don't think that we have soft order books; we think that the order books we actually see here now, because of some of the measures that we have spoken about and which ended up in the not so easy comparison with the first quarter of 2007 actually means that we have quite solid order books.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and last question, very briefly. It's more than clear to me, you talked at pretty helpful length about capacity increases on selected components. From your production rate currently in Europe, for overall OEM assembly, as this year progresses how much further do you expect your overall production capacity of Trucks in Europe to increase from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a history here of having been able to do a couple of percentage points per month actually if you look at what we've been able to do between quarter one '07 and quarter one '08. We are beginning to come to have a little more difficulty on that and that's not in the assembly category, it's more in the reel basics especially of engine and gear box production on the Truck side. So, I would expect a couple of percentage points more, but not as quick an increase of pace as we have been able to do between first quarter '07 and first quarter'08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Alexis Albert from Natixis Securities. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
          <p>&lt; Q &#x2013; Alexis Albert&gt;: Yes, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Alexis Albert, Natixis in Paris. Just a quick question regarding the North American truck markets. Can you tell us how prices are doing in the U.S. because actually I saw that International did incredibly well during the Q1 in terms of commercial business. So I just hope they are not being too much aggressive on the North American truck markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think in general, we are looking at a pricing environment which is reasonably healthy. And one of the benefits that I should say with the experience of having been here in the beginning of the decade of not producing for inventory and also have a fairly solid export market out of North America, has been a much, much better disciplined and industrial response by the whole of the industry to the downturn. We don't see big inventories, we don't see big buybacks, we don't see fairly aggressive pricing. I think everyone is determined to get the cost increases both in terms of emission standards and steel prices through to the customer, even if that means slightly slower growth rates than would otherwise be happening. So I think &#x2013; and you heard Sal here with the quite reasonable development on the portfolio et cetera. But I think all in all, a much, much better picture than we were in the beginning of the decade.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Can I just have a quick follow-up question regarding, not only prices but also residual values &#x2013; and I mean maybe you have seen that BMW took a provision yesterday. I know it's absolutely not the same business as we are speaking about, consumer, and you are more into the B2B business. Just would like &#x2013; if some more if you can just come back on the residual values and everything that you are doing to avoid any crisis &#x2013; not crisis but any huge provision? Can you just come back on that subject please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Just as a point of reference, in the Volvo Group the residual value exposure is typically taken by the business area, and the credit exposure or the credit risk is taken by Volvo Financial Services. So, within the books of Volvo Financial Services you will not see any reserves or provisions for residual values, those will be borne by the business areas. With that said, and the price development that we're seeing on the used truck and used construction equipment side, each BA would have to speak to that but it seems like it's been a pretty decent market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I would make that assessment that's &#x2013; being able to overlook on the business areas on the truck side. We don't think that we have big risks out there, and the most &#x2013; good thing to look at that is there'll actually be used prices coming down slightly but not dramatically, and on top again, this effect of having many used products go for the export markets also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank very much. Just a last question very, very quick -- just for my information. I've seen the refuse hybrid truck that you have shown us this morning, just to know &#x2013; I am sure it's a lot's more expensive that the regular ones though; so did you have any order right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not taking orders right now. These are the first, what we call field tests that we want to run with designated customers. And what we are doing right now is to have a release of waste, the garbage trucks like the ones that you saw; we have buses going to London, and we have re-loaders then coming up towards the middle of this year. So, we're not in the mood of taking any orders here. We are -- production starts really in the second half of '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And for re-loader &#x2013; for hybrid re-loader what's the difference in terms of prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't set those prices yet, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; I think what's the best way to say that is that we have a very clear assessment that if you look at even present oil prices, the customers who get their hands on these products will be able to have a very good payback.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. I think that concludes the session. We have couple of people here to catch flights. Thanks very much for joining us in this quarter conference call. We have our Investor Relations group open to answer any questions that you may have. Thanks for being with us. Have a good weekend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>