<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1427235" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1536</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive VP">Olof Persson</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer">Mikael Bratt</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Nico P. Dil</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Christer Johansson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Frederic Stahl</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Laura I. Lembke</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Yann Benhamou</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura">Vishal Singhal</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Securities (Paris) SAS">S&#xE9;bastien Gruter</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Volvo Report on the First Nine Months of 2011. Today I'm pleased to present Mr. Olof Persson, President and CEO. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Mr. Olof Persson, please begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and good morning and good afternoon to all of you and welcome to the third quarter 2011 report. If you please follow me to page two, but before I start I would like to introduce my colleagues around the table here is Mikael Bratt, CFO; and Christer Johansson, Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>So if you then follow me to page number two, looking at the sales per region, we can conclude that we have had a good development during the quarter, 15% growth and 22% if you exclude the currency impact.</p>
          <p>You can also see on the right-hand side of the slide, the distribution between the different regions. And interesting to see, I think, is now we know back to level of about 50% in the North America and Western Europe, Asia still a major part, but as you can see South America has grown and become a more &#x2013; and important part of our sales.</p>
          <p>If we then move to page three; you can then see the sales trend where we're now heading at the SEK 297 billion close to SEK 300 billion on a 12-months rolling coming from the SEK 48 billion two years ago and now we have this SEK 73 billion in the quarter.</p>
          <p>And you can also see that sales bridge per business area were the Trucks and CE, which I will come back to a little bit more in detail later. If we take just a few words from Buses, we see that 12% on the reported, I think, it was around 22%, if you were excluding the currencies, mainly increases we see here in South America. We have Brazil where it's a strong market, but also apart from Asia.</p>
          <p>In terms of Western Europe and in U.S. we see headwinds and a slower market, I would say, both on coaches and city buses.</p>
          <p>Penta 6% reported 11% if you do the currency adjustment. Penta has done a great job in actually mitigating the very slow both in Europe and in particularly in U.S. on the Marine side and compensated that with a good growth on the industrial engine side.</p>
          <p>Aero, minus 22% reported, if you take out the service businesses that we sold in U.S. and currency, it's actually a plus 7%. And again Volvo Aero is very well positioned in the different programs and for instance we have now Boeing 787, the Dreamliner, up flying which is a big part of our programs going forward on the engine side there.</p>
          <p>If you then follow me to page four; looking at the operating income on a 12-months rolling, SEK 25.5 billion and SEK 5.8 billion in the quarter. And moving swiftly over to the right-hand side, where we can see that we now are giving you the information about the FX effects per business area.</p>
          <p>And you can see that Trucks with SEK 0.5 billion <mark type="audio gap" /> (03:31-3:44). The SEK 700 million you see to the right, on other is the &#x2013; forward contracts we do have that is revaluated market-to-market and it's not allocated back to the business area.</p>
          <p>All-in-all SEK 1.8 billion in currency headwind this month and that means if you translate that into operating margin, it's actually a 2% operating margin. This represents a SEK 1.8 billion on the currency headwind.</p>
          <p>Page number five. Looking at operating capital, I think it's basically good news. We have a seasonable, very strong third quarter with a SEK 2.2 billion in positive cash flow. And we're now on a SEK 18.5 billion on a 12-months rolling.</p>
          <p>We also have good news in terms of the cash conversion cycle, where we now are down to 22 days. We thereby can say that we have compared to Q3 '09 for instance when we have 73, a much better cash efficiency.</p>
          <p>And you can see on the top line inventories these days &#x2013; inventories in days are flattening out on a stable level, giving also the fact that we have an increase in sales. I would say that in terms of inventory days, that's something we keep a very, very close eye on, giving the uncertainty in the market. Return on capital, you can see that we're moving from the minus 15% up to the 28%, it's not record level, but it's a good return that we present now in Q3.</p>
          <p>If we then dig on page six, a little bit closer into the Trucks, you can see the SEK 191 billion, almost SEK 200 billion in 12-months rolling. And moving our self from a SEK 30 billion in Q3 '09 up to SEK 48 billion. And if we look at the region-by-regions, you can see on the right-hand side of the slide that we have 18% in Europe, mainly driven by Northern Europe's long-haul business, but also some construction, but very slow growth in the southern part of Europe.</p>
          <p>In North America, we have seen a replacement cycle during the quarter, which we then have now fully utilized in the fact that we are introducing the U.S. truck machines, which are both more fuel efficient and more economically and thereby we see the customer has a business case to shift from older vehicles into our new ones.</p>
          <p>In South America, the growth is mainly driven by good GDP growth and demand, and then in particular, in Brazil. Asia that was sort of the growth engine, if you go back a few quarters or a year back, has now flattening out and it's mainly India, but also of course Japan. And I will come back to the market forecast a little bit later. But all-in-all going from SEK 41 billion to SEK 48 billion and a 22% growth, excluding currency in the quarter-over-quarter.</p>
          <p>On the operating income side, SEK 17 billion on a 12-months rolling. Again, an impressive turnaround I think from the minus SEK 2.3 billion two years ago, and now we're talking SEK 4 billion in the quarter, seasonally very strong. And operating margin is an all time high for a Q3 with 8.3%. And that is, of course, then despite the headwinds we have on the currency.</p>
          <p>On page number eight; again, we can see, and let's begin to, the other Volvo CE, coming now on a SEK 63 billion on 12-months rolling. You have a 27% growth excluding currency, but you can see the difference down to 18% is quite big. So the currency headwind is impacting of course CE.</p>
          <p>Again, region-by-region, the growth we see in Europe, the 20% on the right-hand side of the chart is mainly driven by an increase of both new and replacement, but we should remember that Europe is still far below the normal trend lines in the market.</p>
          <p>North America has driven by primarily I would say replacement. We have had a long period of low activity in the construction segment in U.S. And we see now that is picking up, but basically it's re-fleeting of rental fleets and also some, both in terms of operational leads but also in rents-to-rent fleets, seriously.</p>
          <p>Asia, we have managed &#x2013; this is particular China, we have managed to grow the business there in CE. We are remaining as the number one player on the Chinese market. We do see that we're taking market shares, and of course the market by itself has been hampered, particularly during the last month in terms of excavators due to the tightening of the credits. But I will talk a little bit more in detail about that when we come to the market forecast for next year.</p>
          <p>On the operating income for CE on [stet] Page #1 [Page #9] (9:33), we can see that we are rolling on SEK 6.8 billion and we have the margin coming in at 9.4%. If you would exclude that margin from the FX headwind, you would have to add another 1.8% to that, coming up to 11.2% in quarter.</p>
          <p>Now follow me to Page #10, which we now specify the operating leverage on the different business areas but also on the group industrial operations in total. As you can see then, we have a operating leverage, excluding FX, on the industrial of 18%, which I think is reasonably good. We are in a phase where we have increased the production.</p>
          <p>And in Trucks, for instance, you're looking at 19% operating leverage. Then we should remember that we have seen <mark type="ph" /> quite non-growth (10:34) in the North American market, which then have low volumes, so have some diluting effects to that. So I think that the 19% leverage operational is quite okay.</p>
          <p>When it comes to CE, you can see the big difference between 3% and 14%. I would like to comment two things on CE. One is, of course, that we are investing in the organic growth, as we have reported to you earlier. We have the big program of 55 new or updated products that we're going to launch over the next years to come.</p>
          <p>We're also addressing &#x2013; I think that is important &#x2013; we're also addressing this currency sensitivity by now investing in localization. We have it in India, we have it in Brazil, we have it in Russia. And we, of course, have it in U.S. with our big investments <mark type="ph" /> we're doing shipments for (11:23) in order to make sure that we are less sensitive over time here in Volvo CE for currency flow fluctuations.</p>
          <p>When it comes to Buses, I would say that the direction is definitely the right one. But both on margin side and on leverage side, I think we have more to do there. And we are looking into ways and means to increase both the margin, of course, but also the leverage.</p>
          <p>Penta, I think, has shown a good development over the last quarters, coming back from the crisis and now coming in with margins that are almost back to pre-crisis level. And they do that with a completely different mix. Penta is today 50% Marine and 50% Industrial Engine, and they have managed to do that in a good way.</p>
          <p>And then Volvo Aero is now coming on, on a 7.2% margin. We still have definitely ways to go in Volvo Aero. But with the specialization that we now have, and the fact that we have divested, and some years ago, we also closed down some of the activities in the service side, I do see now that Volvo Aero is actually very well positioned in the core competencies of components and in their specialization of lightweight components. And they have good participation in the different program.</p>
          <p>So all the prerequisites is there. Now it's a matter of executing, and I can show that we offset the dollar impact in particular, with good productivity intake now showing good return on all the investments that we have done there.</p>
          <p>Then since this morning's presentation there has been a number of questions around the currency impact, and therefore I've asked Mikael Bratt to give us on Page 11 a little bit more detailed comments around the impact that we've had on currency impact on operating income. So Mikael, why don't you take Slide #11, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Olof.</p>
          <p>Most of you have seen this slide before when we have gone through the currency FX in greater detail. We have made some modifications to it, however, but I will come to that.</p>
          <p>The breakdown of the SEK 1.8 billion that we have talked about earlier today is of course coming to large extent from the spot rates on the net flows. And behind that you have the main currency there effect coming from the dollar. Then we have the portion of the realized hedging contracts, 75 in change between the Q3 in '11 and '10. Revaluation of receivable and payables, the balance sheet items of course. And then we have the big impact coming from unrealized gains and losses from the hedging contracts. And here we have now breaking out for Q3 '11 the portion that is reallocated back to the business area. And out of the SEK 378 million that is isolated in Q3 2011, SEK 166 million is then allocated to the business area. Those SEK 166 million is a part of the net number you see on the previous slide Olof went through with you here. The reason why it's not anything in the Q3 '10 figure is of course that this was something we introduced during 2011 as you see on the note to the right-hand side there.</p>
          <p>And then of course we have also the revaluation of foreign subsidiaries when we translate the results back home to the Swedish currency which is our base currency. This means then out of the SEK 1.8 billion, SEK 1.1 billion is in the business area and then the remaining portion is left at group headquarters. So that is in brief the currency impact in the third quarter here, so I'll stop there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mikael.</p>
          <p>And now follow me to Page 12 and just conclude the quarter by &#x2013; let me say then that in whatever way you look at it, sales, operating income, operating margin and cash flow, it has been from a historical point a very strong third quarter. Over the six years that we show you here it's actually quarter number one.</p>
          <p>With that, leave the third quarter behind us and the reporting of that and then looking into the future a little bit and starting with order intake and deliveries for the Trucks on Page #13. You can then see there we have the plus 18% quarter-over-quarter coming from the 51,000 to almost the 60,000 order intake and the growth numbers you see there region by region, notably there is of course a strong development in North America but also in South America and I must say also that Europe is then quarter-over-quarter performing well.</p>
          <p>If you look at the right-hand side you'll see the book-to-bill ratio. We are done having the orders of 60,000 and we have deliveries of 55,000. So basically we are then having a book-to-bill 1:1. And of course, all the numbers as I said before is year-over-year, not quarter-over-quarter as it says there in the table.</p>
          <p>Then on Page #14 we are then talking about our forecast for this year in the different markets but also then our take on the markets for next year. And if I then start with Europe, and let me just spend one minute on how we have sort of come to the conclusion of the Europe and the other markets. What we have done is really go into all the facts that we have. We have looked at the statistics on the aging of the fleet in Europe. We have looked at the order intake ratio. We have, of course, listened very carefully to our main customer and activity levels. And we have also then make sure that we have weighted in all the uncertainty on the macroeconomic and country level that we have seen and really tried to take a temperature with the information that is available to us today. And, when we do all that, we come to the conclusion that we will see a decline &#x2013; or a small decline in Europe with 10% next year. That means by saying that we also have to make sure that our production rates are aligned to that and we are just working through that in the European production system to align our production rate in accordance with the minus 10%.</p>
          <p>In North America, you can see that we have take on 20% growth next year, coming from the 210,000 that we are forecasting today. Let me start with the 2011 estimate. We have lowered that to 210,000 and that is not so much on the market demand; it's more of an industrial capacity point of view. And, we have definitely seen, during the third quarter, some disturbance in ramping up. We have employed more than a thousand people. We have put in extra shifts in our American production system and that has led to some disturbances but I'm happy to report that it looks like we're through that now. The production rates are up and running towards next year's levels and we see then the continuation of that.</p>
          <p>The reason why we call North America plus 20% is basically we continue to see this replacement cycle on the long haul side that we have seen before. We do not see, in those 20%, any major rebound on the construction side so it's more of a continuation of a replacement demand as we can see it today.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, if we move to the green line, we call it 10% for the next year and basically this is a first quarter that we see in front of us that's going to be slow. It's partly &#x2013; or mostly due to the fact that you have emission legislation changing over from Euro III to Euro V. And, we might have some overhang in Brazil of Euro III trucks coming in to next year. Let me also state that we don't foresee any major pre-buy effect during this year. And, the reason for that is that the systems and the production systems in the industry are on very, very high utilization levels going forward.</p>
          <p>Underlying in Brazil, if you look at the positive side, is that we still see that we have an underlying growth in terms of GDP and activity levels going forward. We do have a very important show in Brazil this week &#x2013; or next week where we actually will then start to take orders on our Euro V trucks to be delivered in 2012. And that means that we will get better visibility on the Brazil side at that point in time.</p>
          <p>In Japan, we see now that the reconstruction work after the tsunami and earthquake is starting to show up in our order intake numbers. We have good development in the order intake in Japan. And, we foresee then that the market due to this will go up with 20%. But, it has to be said it's coming from historically very, very low volumes.</p>
          <p>So, to summarize the plus and minuses on the &#x2013; if we take those markets which you see here and if I have done the math correctly, I think number of trucks for next year is basically the same number in 2012 as it is in 2011 if you combine all these markets together.</p>
          <p>If we then shift over to Page 15, you can see the &#x2013; our takes on the VCE equipment. If I then start from the top with China; we have seen a slowdown in the second half of the year of China, mainly due to the season of course, but also to the credit tightening that the Chinese authorities has been doing over the year. We believe however that going into next year we will have and we see spring season coming with pretty high activity and with that with us into the next autumn we believe that we could be anything from flat to plus 10% in China, then based on very high volumes as you can see so that means in terms of number of units quite a few.</p>
          <p>When it comes to Europe and we believe that the activity level on construction out in Europe will still be there in order to support the 10% to 20% growth. And, again, even with this we will still be below the trend lines in Europe.</p>
          <p>North America, we see that the trend of re-fleeting and also building up the fleet going forward for activities levels that we have would support a 15% to 25% increase. South America is on all-time high already, and we see a small but still an increase.</p>
          <p>So, to summarize the VCE market conditions and environment, we are coming out of 2011 with reasonable to good growth in many markets and we continue to see that growth, albeit a little bit more modest growth but still growth in all markets.</p>
          <p>And, basically on Page 16 I would like to do a summary before we open up for questions and as I said before it's a historically very good Q3 with growth. We have had profitability. We have operational leverage excluding FX on 18% on Industrial Operations, and we have historically very strong cash flow with SEK 2.2 billion in the quarter.</p>
          <p>On the macroeconomic level and as I stated out, we're now calling the next year's market; we do that of course with the data, the visibility and the facts that we have today. And, of course, we are and we will continue to keep our flexibility. We do have around 19,000 people of our workforce as temporary consultants or manning companies. So, compared to 2008 we have much higher flexibility as well. So, we are keeping a very, very close eye on the development going forward here, but again, with the data we have today, we have then called the markets as I just presented.</p>
          <p>And, of course, our geographical footprint is balancing the whole thing. You can see that we do put on a little bit of an accelerator in U.S. in order to meet the delivery and the production paces that we see coming there. We apply a little bit of a brake in Europe to adjust ourselves in the 10% lower market conditions, and we of course will during Q1, in Brazil in particular, also making sure that we don't produce any trucks that the market doesn't &#x2013; can &#x2013; or want to take.</p>
          <p>So, with that, I would like to stop the presentation and open up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question from Mr. Nico Dil from JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to ask two questions please. First of all, on the truck orders in Europe in particular, just wondering how that progressed during the quarter, wondering what your exit rate was roughly in September or October. Secondly, on your Construction Equipment forecast, just wondering how in North America as well as in Europe, how this compares towards &#x2013; versus a replacement cycle demand level. So, just wondering how your guidance in North America up around 25% and in Europe up 10% to 20% in 2012, how that compares to a replacement level of demand. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, if you look at the order rate coming into, and I'm looking at Christer here since this is my first time, so I'm not....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me give you some flavor, Nico. You can say always in July, August you have a vacation period where you have low order intake activity and then you can &#x2013; we saw the pick-up in September coming through, especially on the Volvo side, while we saw a weakness in the renewal side, which had more, you can say, exposure towards the southern part of Europe. So normal, I would say, pickup of orders in September for Volvo Trucks, but then we saw a bit of a weakening again as we got into October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the CE side, I would say, in North America we have had the downturn for almost, I would say, three years now, when we have seen a decrease in the demand. That's meant also that we do see actually a lack of used equipment in the construction equipment. And the pricing on the used equipment is holding up very well or even increasing and that has also then triggered some business cases where we can see that the customers then go in and buy new machines.</p>
          <p>On top of that, you have for the large machines and you have an emission legislation which is coming into place as well, where we are, of course, very well positioned with all the new machines out to the market. In Europe I would call it a little bit more of a, I would say, not yet come back to historic trend lines and you can see in the different areas. And this is very much driven by a party's replacement, but the second one is also activity level in the northern part of Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a comment there, I mean even if we see a growth of 10%, 20%, we will still be on a 10-year low on absolute numbers in Europe and North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Frederic Stahl from UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon, gentlemen. It's Frederic here at UBS. I was wondering if you could give us a flavor for how the service and spare parts market is developing in Europe. And maybe if you can tell us what the differences are, if there are any, in terms of demand in Southern Europe versus Northern Europe.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, given that you're now providing us with a bit more information on the currency, I was hoping maybe you could break with habits and maybe give us an idea of what the currency impact could be in Q4. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the service side and the spare parts, I mean we haven't seen any deviation that we normally see. That means that is related to the mileage that we have on the fleets and the pickup of the mileage of the fleets. That goes both for the northern part of Europe and southern part, but of course there are different utilization rates.</p>
          <p>I also will say that we're holding up the pricing of the spare parts quite well. So giving historically what I have heard and what I've seen is that we're holding a rather normal pattern on the service and on the spare parts side.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the currency I'm looking at Mikael. Why don't you take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. As you know, Frederic, it's very difficult to predict currency impact going forward here. I mean there's a lot of moving parts involved here.</p>
          <p>I mean there is forward contracts that we will have at the end of the quarter that will be evaluated, and we haven't done all of them yet. We don't know the closing rate at the time and so forth. So I think it would be very difficult to give you any number based on that. And if I give you the number I have in mind right now it will probably not be the right one when I get to the end of the quarter anyway because of the moving parts here.</p>
          <p>So it's a very tricky area to forecast for you, I understand that, but I don't think we have the possibilities to get any closer than what we are today, really disclosing the real facts and figures at the end of the quarter here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sure. No problem. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Ms. Laura Lembke from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon. I've got three questions.</p>
          <p>And the first one is on your North American forecast, which you obviously lowered from 230,000 to 210,000 units. Now you're expecting 20% growth for 2012. And although I know you didn't have like a full year estimate previously, I'm just wondering if you could maybe give us an idea how this compares to your initial assumptions for the U.S. next year. So what do you have internally budgeted?</p>
          <p>Because, I mean, if we assume you have that initially up 20% as well, then obviously implicitly you just lowered your expectations from around 275,000 to 250,000 units. I'm just trying to get a better feel for what has really changed in your view in the U.S. market for 2012.</p>
          <p>Second question is on your tax rate. You're guiding for 30% for the full year, but you're at 28% at the nine-month stage. So I'm just wondering if the 30% is still valid and we should expect a big increase in the tax rate in Q4.</p>
          <p>And then just lastly, in your working capital, you have a quite a bit item, SEK1.7 billion of other changes. Year-to-date, that's at SEK4.3 billion so I'm just wondering what is reflected in this. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Let me take the first one. The answer to that question is that we saw, during the third quarter, with the ramp up and also the total industry capacity for 2011, that the previous forecast was going to be difficult to meet. And that's why we're now &#x2013; and again, I emphasize that this is more of an industrial ramp up and acceleration issue than a market demand ratio.</p>
          <p>The call for next year, we did much later. So basically we have taken that into consideration. So we did call for next year where we had a pretty good picture on what we had already. So there was no one sort of called before that.</p>
          <p>So we have not lowered expectation in that sense. We're just sort of doing the call for next year with actual facts that we have in place.</p>
          <p>For the other two questions, I hand over to Mikael and you can elaborate on those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. The tax rate remains at 30%, that's the guidance. Then, of course, when you look at the quarter like this, there are some specific countries &#x2013; there is a specific country that makes it a little bit different there. But I mean it's still around 30%. So continue to use that.</p>
          <p>On the SEK1.7 billion under other is related to a number of different items, as usual in other. But in this month &#x2013; in this quarter particularly &#x2013; there's two items that sticks out and make the number more significant than normal. And one is prepayment for some raw material we wanted to secure in Asia on the Construction Equipment side. And then on pension, we have also topped up in the extra addition of capital into the pension plans here to match the funding requirements that are needed <mark type="ph" /> in this country, the U.S. and (34:35) Sweden that makes up the bulk there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Yann Benhamou from Exane. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Yann Benhamou from Exane. Three questions please.</p>
          <p>First one, how do you anticipate the evolution of pricing in Brazil, given the fact that you will have capacity addition plus new entrants in the coming years, and those new players should have local production?</p>
          <p>The second question is related to your geographic mix in trucks next year. If I understand well, Europe and Latin should be down, while North America and Japan should be up. So the first two markets are, in my view, the most attractive, while the others are less attractive. Should we expect any significant impact on margins?</p>
          <p>And maybe a last question, and what kind of magnitude do you anticipate in terms of production cuts early 2012? And do you target any reduction in terms of inventories? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. When it comes to the pricing and the long-term pricing in Brazil &#x2013; and I assume your question is related to the trucks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, heavy trucks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I mean we will now &#x2013; if you take it on the short term, start to take the orders for our new Euro V. And if I remember correctly, the price increases we're going to have is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10%, yeah. Coming into the market. And that's going to be a price increase going forward. Then long term and what kind of effects newcomers will have, I mean that remains to be seen.</p>
          <p>Our main goal and target is and has been and will be to continue to grow in terms of market share, but do that with a profitable growth, and that's what we're going to focus on also going forward.</p>
          <p>Now we have to deal with the market situation as they come. It's very difficult to predict how that will pan out. And I think we do see now for the next year, and that's what we're planning for, that we will have the price increases coming with the new technology.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the mix in terms of geographic going up and down, it's also a mix in between. Regions are one thing, but you also see the different mixes between the long haul. In U.S., for instance, we start to see now the penetration rate we have had on our own engines and our own transmissions is also starting to show result in the spare parts, which is of course of great benefit and is important as well.</p>
          <p>So we're going to work very hard on the mix side, but what exactly that will pan out, that's a forward-looking statement that we don't do.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the cuts, I mean we are now and we have looked into the Swedish system and the Volvo system in particular, and we will cut now the production in line with what we have said in terms of the market. We are looking onto the renewal side and see what implications, if any, there are no decision taking there. We are still in the investigation phase.</p>
          <p>But in general you can say that, depending on mix, market mix, product mix, segment mix, there is a lot of details that has to be categorized. And we will then align our production to the market demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Vishal Singhal from Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:28).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening. I have basically three short questions. One is basically what level of reduction you can see in your production, which you can still manage before you start seeing the impact on your bottom line?</p>
          <p>Second, can you give us the status of your truck JV in China, how that is progressing, and what are your plans for China in longer term? And are you seeing any cancellation in your truck orders in Europe predominantly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me start to answer the first question about the reduction. I would like to answer it by saying that in total, right now, we have a flexibility in our workforce that corresponds to approximately 19,000 people. I think it's 17% that we do have. So that's a flexibility that we have today, that we didn't have if you go back to 2008.</p>
          <p>And <mark type="ph" /> when you go on then (39:33) exactly where those kind of levels are, it's difficult to judge. But with the calls that we do for the different markets, we will have a mixed picture with a reduction in Europe, a reduction in Brazil, but primarily down &#x2013; what we see now in the first quarter. And then you will have an uptick and the high production rates in U.S. as we go along, so it's a very mixed picture there.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the truck manufacturer in China, we have a very good and very good cooperation with our partner at DMV. And we are putting plans together in order to see how we can develop that joint venture, and that is something that we are working on right now. And in parallel to that, we are also looking into and see how we can and if possible to increase the sales of both the Volvo and the Renault Trucks in the so-called Western European segment in China.</p>
          <p>And then finally on the cancellation side, the answer is, no, we haven't seen any unusual cancellation rates. The cancellation rates are traveling at a very normal speed as we see it today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. S&#xE9;bastien Gruter from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, gentlemen. I have three questions. My first question would be on the FX impact on trucks. You said <mark type="ph" /> further back the (41:17) SEK 500 million negative FX impact from the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:20) profit in the division but the hit on sales was about SEK 2.5 billion and I'm just wondering why such a high flow-through on the FX impact? Is there any mark-to-market impact in this number or is it due to a production impact?</p>
          <p>My second question would be on the construction equipment in China. <mark type="ph" /> Kettia Pierre (41:43) mentioned that inventories, not in China, but in general, <mark type="ph" /> Kettia Pierre (41:47) mentioned that inventories at dealers were up in Q3 and came back to the historical average. And I wonder if you expect on same trend in general where do your inventories for your <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:00) products stand today?</p>
          <p>And my final question would be on Penta. I mean there was a very strong increase in profitability despite the production quotes, and you mentioned the mix to explain. I just wonder, is this due to particular activity or a geographical mix? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first question, I might give you Mikael, do you want to elaborate on the FX impact on the truck business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. The bulk of those SEK 500 million is of course coming from the net flow currency effect. As I showed you before here, the portion of the unrealized <mark type="ph" /> forward (42:42) contract that are mark-to-market there is only SEK 166 million going up to, this was to the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:48). So, and of those SEK 166 million truck is taking their share, so that definitely means that the flow is the big impact there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the inventory side in U.S., we haven't got any reports on that, that we are building any substantial inventory or building inventory there. There is of course, if you look at the Rents &#x2013; the Rents business there are now both a restocking of new machines but also a little bit of a build up in inventory, but there are no big things there that have been reported back to us in terms of inventory.</p>
          <p>When it comes to Penta there are two things there. One is of course as you hinted to in a volume and that means also a geographic mix. It's primarily in Asia where we have seen a good growth of Penta industrial engines with good profitability. But then in general, Penta has done a very good job when it comes to making sure that cost efficiency and making sure that the organization came out of the crisis in a lean and in a good way and that is a little bit also what shows here in the numbers coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. <mark type="ph" /> Declan Carland from BofA (44:15). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your estimates for the 2012 European market volumes appear significantly higher than one of your competitors. Can you tell me why you expect the market to be so much better than they do?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I &#x2013; what we have done, as I explained, and that is that we have taken all the facts that we see in our business, both statistics but also making sure that we are now talking to the customers. We have done making sure that we have brought in the uncertainty that we have in the market and so I think that at the end of the day this is our call. With the information that we see today, with the fact that we have &#x2013; we have put it together and this is the call we are doing for next <mark type="inaudible" /> (45:09).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think that was the last question or are there any other questions, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there are no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then I would like to thank you very much for being with us here this afternoon presenting this third quarter and I wish you all a good day, good evening and talk to you next time again. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>