<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1531476" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1536</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Olof Persson</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer, EVP-Finance &amp; Business">Anders Osberg</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Alex S. White</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Christer Johansson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="DNB Bank ASA (Broker)">Christer Magnerg&#xE5;rd</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="One Investments Holding SAGL">Peter Miles Testa</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="SEB Enskilda (Sweden)">Anders Trapp</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">Martin Viecha</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Fraser E. Hill</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the AB Volvo Report on 2012 Operations Conference. Today I'm pleased to present Olof Persson, President and CEO. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Olof, please begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, operator, and good afternoon/good morning to all of you and once again, welcome to this presentation of the fourth quarter 2012 for the Volvo Group. I would like to just stay a few seconds on the opening picture where you can see a wheel loader, and this now the new BRIC wheel loader that I have been talking about for a couple of years. And this is now the first Volvo branded wheel loader that is then really focusing on catching market volumes in the BRIC countries. We've launched it in China. We are starting to ramp up to production and I'm really excited to see how this will then turn out in the marketplace, in China and elsewhere in the BRIC countries.</p>
          <p>If you then you're then follow me into page number 2, Q4 in a snapshot. We have called this quarter a destocking quarter because that really reflects what we have been doing and that is very much in line with what we also discussed with you and said in the third quarter. And as you can see, the lower order intake in Q3 and heavy destocking in Q4 is one of the main activities then has led to &#x2013; and we will come back to that then, with a under-production as we call it compared to sales, with the low capacity utilization, but also then a substantial cut in inventories with SEK 5.4 billion, leading to a positive cash flow and also a net debt ratio which has gone down from some 44% down to 29%.</p>
          <p>We also have continued in our investments in R&amp;D, selling and CapEx for our future products and I will come back to that a little bit later in the presentation. But as you can see, we have had then about SEK 600 million expense increases in the R&amp;D and selling expenses compared to quarter four in 2011.</p>
          <p>We also have announced and we have been communicating the efficiency programs in Europe and Japan with a total restructuring charge of SEK 990 million, again, something that we do for the future. Again, we see it as an investment in order to better position our self in the future. This has led then to an operating margin of 1.6% and net financial debt reduced by SEK 12 billion. So we have actually been doing exactly what we said in the Q3 that we were supposed to do &#x2013; focus on the cash flow, focus on the balance sheet and making sure that we enter 2013 in a balanced production way.</p>
          <p>If you now follow me to page number 3 and I will come back more in detail on Trucks and CE and just mention a few words on the other business areas. Buses are still struggling in a very difficult market environment. We have had a tough quarter where the market both on the city bus and the coaches are still on a very low level. On top of that, we have a one-time charge here, restructuring charge for capacity adjustments in the European system and as you can see there, but even without that, it would have been a negative result.</p>
          <p>We are continuing to push forward with programs in buses. We are determined to make sure that we will be able to reduce the breakeven point on buses going forward here. On the slightly positive news when it comes to buses, we are gaining market shares on the city buses and also our new technology buses when it comes to hybrid, which we believe it's very much a future product, we are having great successes with selling our hybrid buses into different cities around the world.</p>
          <p>Volvo Penta, a seasonal weak quarter, normally both on the marine side and on industrial engine side, this is a &#x2013; the fourth quarter is normally a weak quarter, this not being an exception. On top of the market weakness, we also have had some investments in R&amp;D positioning Penta for the future when it comes to emission legislation from early this year for Tier 4 final emission legislation for industrial engines.</p>
          <p>Another good quarter for financial services, SEK 12 billion in new financing, and I would like to stress that what we see now is a very solid new financing. I think that the control mechanism and also the new businesses we take on board here is a solid one, and that is also reflected in the operating income of SEK 390 million. And I'm really pleased to report that financial services now are within the strategic target bracket of 12% to 15% return on equity.</p>
          <p>If you then follow me to page number 4, looking quickly into trends and actions in trucks. When it comes to the demand and order intake, I will come back to that on the next slide. We can conclude that our inventory levels, as I've said, has been substantially reduced and particularly then on the Renault Trucks side, where we have had a major focus of actually managing and getting the inventory on the right level. We have almost succeeded. We still have a little bit of inventory flush-out to be done in the first quarter here, but all-in-all, I think we have a good job.</p>
          <p>This has then resulted in a total inventory reduction of 5,300 trucks, whereof 3,700 in new truck and the rest being used trucks. When it comes to the implementation of actions, you can then see that we have, during quarter four, reduced the pace in trucks operations by 20%. And as you read it that we then comparing the in-going pace with the outgoing pace, and if you compare these two, we don't have an outgoing pace of minus 20%.</p>
          <p>And as I said, we also had the marketing activities in Europe to reduce the inventories and that was primarily on the Renault Trucks side. Where we're now looking into Q1, we will continue to manage and keep focus on the under-absorption and we will have to also look at the continued low capacity utilization in France. And when we look at the quarter, we will see that under-absorption will be there in January, it will be there also in February, and then we'll see that we will be more balanced in production coming into March.</p>
          <p>If we would then put some sort of a number to that absorption in the first quarter for the trucks, we're looking at around SEK 1 billion. And the reason for that is that we had a under-absorption during the fourth quarter which was a little bit uneven, when we actually had high or rather good production in October and then we did break at the back end of the fourth quarter and that is then coming also into the first quarter, where we actually say that the January production level is the low point, even comparing with December.</p>
          <p>We are ramping up the production of the new Volvo FH. We have seen and we are very pleased with order intake and acceptance of the new Volvo FH coming into the market. And the order intake is slightly ahead of our internal plans and targets that we have seen.</p>
          <p>We have then &#x2013; giving the situation with CE, we have reopened stop-days in the Volvo system here in Europe, and we also have decided to increase the production in Brazil as of March. And the reason for that, we can then discuss a little bit more if you follow me to page number 5, where we'll take a look at the total order intake. And if we start at the bottom of this table, you can see that we had an order intake of 52,145 trucks, minus 10% year-over-year and up 15% quarter-over-quarter, and with a book-to-bill ratio of 89%. The book-to-bill ratio is negatively affected by the 3,700 trucks that we cleaned out from the inventory, meaning that if we would add those back, you would be around the 95% book-to-bill ratio.</p>
          <p>Quickly looking into the different aspects or the different parts of order intake, we can note that the Volvo in Europe had a positive development both year-over-year and quarter-over-quarter. And we also see that the positive trend that we have seen in Q4 has continued for Volvo Europe into the first days or weeks here in the first quarter and hence, the decision to reopen some of the stop-days that were planned.</p>
          <p>Renault, year-over-year, minus 18%, we should though remember that we actually had some stoppage in the order intake due to the fact that we wanted to make sure that we really got the inventory out, so we didn't accept orders in certain regions from the Renault, and that's one of the reasons there. As the numbers that sticks out, I think in North America, Mack, minus 45% year-over-year. The explanation there is very tough comparison numbers from last year, where you remember that we had a very high activity level on the Mack, so that's a comparison number. Otherwise, we are on the plus side in North America quarter-over-quarter as well.</p>
          <p>And then finally in South America and Brazil, good year-over-year numbers, 24%, and we saw that of course already in the last quarter, and we see now quarter-over-quarter, it's another 2% up, and also the book-to-bill on 115%, which then of course is the basis for our decision to increase production in Brazil in March.</p>
          <p>Moving then to page number 6 in CE. I would like to say that the sales drop in CE is some 23%. The production in Q4 was 28% lower in Q4, and utilization at 40%. These are numbers that we haven't really seen since the crisis in 2008. In general, you can say that there is a big difference though ,that is that this time around, Volvo CE is profitable. Volvo CE has a good positive cash flow and Volvo CE also has the inventory lined up and also being in a good level compared to the demand that we have. And since May 2012, we actually have reduced the inventory in CE with 30%. So the destocking has going on for quite some time in CE which we believe is the absolute right thing to do, even though it is of course a slowdown that we have seen.</p>
          <p>We also &#x2013; if we look at the different markets there, China has been heavily impacted, minus 37%, but I'm really happy to report that we are actually getting the market share. We do have an all-time high 15% market share. And the price pressure comment that is there on the bullet number 3 is related to China, there has been price pressures. But since we have managed our inventory in a good way, since we make sure that we do have a balance in there, I think we have managed that in a good way.</p>
          <p>When it comes to action for Q1, prepare for spring season production. That is of course the number one priority. How the spring season will go, we don't really know yet. We will have to wait and see but we are ready. We have the inventory in line, we have the production lined up, so we will see how that turns out when we start to see the order intake coming from that. We also have some other movements, and I talked about the BRIC Loaders <mark type="ph" /> that we have (18:02) in China which is <mark type="ph" /> a big deal there (18:06).</p>
          <p>I talked about the R&amp;D and the selling expenses being on a high level and really, to illustrate this, and I would like you to follow to page number 7. And this is a &#x2013; I think it's a good visual description on the enormous amount of things we are actually doing now. It's a little bit of a crescendo when you talk about actually renewing our fleet, position ourselves for the future and making sure that we are a stronger company going into the years to come.</p>
          <p>We have of course the new Volvo FH and a launch process right now and then we are, as I said before, really happy with the acceptance there. The BRIC Loader just coming out now, starting to ramp up to production. We are in the final stages of getting everything ready for the renewal launch, which will come in June with a new line up for Renault. At the same time, we then are finalizing the new Tier 4f engines for the construction and the industrial engine side and of course, the Euro 6 here in Europe when it comes to emission legislation.</p>
          <p>On top of that, we also then are working very diligent with our new value truck platform, which then is a range of products based on the same platform. And that is not only the product by itself. We're also building up an industrial system around that with investment in, for instance, Thailand, Kaluga, even though that's not really for the platform, and then in Bangalore, India, and also we're looking into China here. So I think this picture actually says more than a thousand words when it comes to describing that we are in a very, very exciting part of our development in the Volvo Group going forward.</p>
          <p>Moving into number 8 and coming back to the standard slide now, showing you what is the big issues that has been related to the strategy, and we will not and cannot show you all the activities we're doing because we have now defined the 35 roadmaps and 400 main activities, thousands of smaller activities which are allocated, defined and now into operations since January 1.</p>
          <p>Three years equals 36 months. We have used up January, that means that we have 35 months to go in order to succeed achieving the targets that we have set out. And you see the different activities, everything from reduction of consultants, consolidate the industrial footprint in Japan, IT projects prioritization and of course the Dongfeng and the reorganization in Europe and right-sizing in Japan. So there's a lot of thing going on both in terms of positioning ourselves in the future both in terms of the strategic and structural things we're doing and of course, also making sure that we are dealing with the ups and downs in the market that we have seen.</p>
          <p>And with that, I hand over to Anders Osberg to talk a little bit more about the balance sheet and the financial issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. So we turn over to page number 9 and say a few words about the cash flow and investment side. Here we can see that our cash flow of SEK 4.7 billion for the quarter is of course -was driven by the SEK 6.7 billion release of working capital and it's mainly explained of course by the inventory reduction as the main contributor. Also, we can see that on a 12-month rolling, we are still in negative territory, largely explained of course by the fact that we don't get the contribution from the operating income this quarter as before.</p>
          <p>Turning over to the investment on the right-hand side, we see there that we are in a high pace of the investments. We know that and we can relate back to a previous slide on the massive product renewals, of course, and that explains the bar there that is still on a high level of course in 2013, and then moving downwards in 2014 onwards, but we are on a high level.</p>
          <p>We can see, for instance, that we are still of course on a very high level on the tangible side with the tooling, for instance for India, Russia and Thailand, that's major reasons. We can also conclude that on the rental fleet side, we are now decreasing on the renewal of that. And also we can conclude that we still have a R&amp;D capitalization on a high level but that is also on a downward trend for the second part of this year.</p>
          <p>Then if we turn to page number 10 and look on the capital efficiency measures, we can conclude there that we are still trailing on a fairly good level, around 30 days on the CCC days on the capital efficiency side. Also on the number of inventory days, and that is despite the drop of sales, we have kept the number of inventory says fairly stable. On the ROC on the same page, we now see that we are on a 17%, of course, lower than the 29%, largely explained by the lower operating income.</p>
          <p>Then if you follow me to page number 11, we have concluded before that the net financial debt was reduced by some SEK 12 billion over the quarter, largely explained then by the positive cash flow, the divestment of Volvo Aero and some positive currency impact, primarily the Japanese yen. And now of course that means that we can record a net debt over equity at a 29% level excluding pensions for the quarter, and that has kept the balance sheet at a stable level as we have said before. On the right-hand side, we also would like to display the suggestion from the Board of Directors to the AGM, which is a dividend of SEK 3, a yield just above 3% right now.</p>
          <p>Then on the last, I think, page, page number 12, we have also included some guidance for you on reporting changes for 2013. I will not go through all the details here. You're welcome to ask us questions about it in the Q&amp;A, but it's mainly a guidance on the R&amp;D capitalization and on amortization. It is also some of the accounting changes for the pensions, and there are also some other changes that we make during the year of 2013.</p>
          <p>So I think by that, I'll leave the word back to Olof.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Anders, and by that, we conclude the presentation and open up for questions and you will then get answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Mr. Alex White from JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon everybody. It's Alex White at JP Morgan. But two questions, please. Firstly, could you quantify for us the over-absorption benefit in Q1 2012 and Q2 2012 in both trucks and construction equipment? And secondly, in construction equipment on the mining side, are you beginning to see stabilization there or does demand continue to deteriorate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let's &#x2013; Christer will take the over-capacity issue and then I will then comment on the mining. I will say that we see a stabilization but it is still on, of course, very low level or low levels compared to before, and it's a little bit different in different regions around the world, but at least I will say that we see a stabilization. Where it will go from here, though, it's very difficult to say because we don't see any sort of clear indication. And that's why was &#x2013; and especially for the spring season which is normally a very strong season as you know for CE, we have prepared ourselves for it, so we will be able to respond to it, but we will have to see how that develops.</p>
          <p>And Christer, have you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, if we look at the absorption rates in the, you can say, first quarter of 2012, for trucks you could say it was about minus <mark type="ph" /> 100% (26:43), and in the second quarter, it was also about minus <mark type="ph" /> 100% (26:47); for construction equipment, likewise about minus <mark type="ph" /> 100% (26:52) both Q1 and Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So <mark type="ph" /> 100% (26:59) under-absorption, do you mean in those quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Christer Magnerg&#xE5;rd from DNB. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Well, a follow-up on that. Did you have an absorption effect for 2011 as well, would be much appreciated. Secondly, order intake in Latin America in Q4 was strong, but it was not the kind of quarter growth as we saw for some of the competitors grew for the 50% growth quarter-over-quarter. Is that due to your intention of raising prices, or is there any other factors?</p>
          <p>Thirdly on construction equipment, the sales were a bit lower than I expected. Was that a destocking problem from &#x2013; in the dealerships, the dealers are destocking, affecting your sales more than maybe the underlying market? Or does your Q4 reflect the market demands for the moment? And finally on the currency for VCE, why that was so positive in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I look at you, Christer, on absorption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have to come back with you too on that one. We don't have that with us here and now. It was &#x2013; but it was clearly a good utilization of the industrial system and we had good, you can say, production levels in relation to the staffing levels we had. So it was a over-absorption, but I don't have the number with me now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the sales in Latin America, and in Brazil in particular then, you can say that we have made sure enough then that we maintain prices. We also have a pricing increase during the fourth quarter. And I must say that looking at our own numbers, where we are in terms of market shares, where we are in terms of positioning ourselves with the Euro 5 and the trucks we're selling, in Brazil in particular, I must say that I'm really pleased with the development I see.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the VCE sales, we are looking at both at the &#x2013; and we are looking very much at, I should say, on the pipeline <mark type="ph" /> and network (29:24), that is the total inventory out also on the dealer's side. And when we talk about the destocking and getting in line, I will say that is reflected all the way in. Meaning that what you see in the sales there is actually the &#x2013; as far as we can see, the underlying demand that we had during the quarter.</p>
          <p>And then on the currency issue, the positive thing there is, I guess, it's currency movements, but I'll leave it to you, Christer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll have to look up the details, but you can say it's primarily balance sheet items revaluations, as well as the derivatives that we are using that are also being realized and, you can say, changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can supply you with the breakdown on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Yes, two more things. Firstly on the theoretical, but it seems you had over-absorption in 2011, and then you have the long-term mission of raising profitability by 300 basis points from 2011. Is that including the over-absorption effect? How should we think of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Basically, you should think about the absorption issue being something that you basically, theoretically again now, is of course a zero-sum game. So we do not &#x2013; when we look at the 300 basis points over time, that is sort of &#x2013; with an anticipation and that we are theoretically perfect in terms of getting our production and everything right, so it's <mark type="ph" /> zero in there (31:04).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just finally, on construction equipment, you say that the capacity utilization was 40% in the quarter, and that was down 28% from last year. And if I don't remember wrong, Q4 2011 was quite okay. So that means that you should have &#x2013; had lost here like 55%, 60% capacity utilization despite the strong quarter. Do you have over-capacity in the system? Do you need more restructuring in construction equipment? Or is there anything else that I should remember?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think that we are, if you look at the system as such, I think we are adding capacity where we believe we're going to grow from and we have invested in productivity in the other ones. What is really important for the CE part is that we are implementing very good flexibility. That means that, both on the breakeven point <mark type="ph" /> or say (32:00) but also making sure that we have good flexibility. And there, we are taking steps in the right direction definitely, but we also have more to do on that side when we're looking at &#x2013; over the next cycle there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Peter Testa from One Investment. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks very much for taking my questions. Just three quick ones. One is just if you could help us understand, on Renault, what you're doing on repositioning the product versus Volvo to try to <mark type="ph" /> sub (32:35) differentiate and can give it some more commercial momentum? The second is just on China. I understand there's not a lot of visibility into Q2, but I was wondering if you had any comment on sort of softer items such as, would you see any change in discounting, or do you see any utilization changes or spares increases in your business in China, to give some sort of sense of movement?</p>
          <p>And then the last one is, you've described a couple of points like overhead under-absorption sustained in Q1 and higher launch costs this year depressing margins. Can you give us some feeling for what's happening in 2013 to boost margins, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If you look at Renault and differentiation, that is a major part of our brand positioning work that we are doing right now. And the positioning there will then be sort of manifested also when we get with the new launches that is coming out now. So that will then give us, in the markets in Europe and in elsewhere internationally, a good possibility to actually do a differentiation which is then optimal for the other. And we had presented, and I presented on Capital Markets Day, the work that we're doing there, and we're continuing that and that is progressing really well actually, so we're looking forward to that.</p>
          <p>I should, however, say that repositioning a brand is nothing you do from one quarter to the other. This is of course something you have to work on, but we have that in mind now when we do the reorganization and restructuring in the European sales network, that is, we have that very much in the front line to see that we have an organization that also supports and makes sure that this repositioning is happening.</p>
          <p>In China, I will say that we &#x2013; here you see that the machine utilization basically is minus 10% year-over-year. So I would say that we call it a little bit of bottoming out, and where it goes from here, it's a little bit too early to say. And I would like to see the spring season &#x2013; the data coming in there before we can actually call it. We have maintained, as you can see in our report, the market estimation for China, and that is the best we can see now.</p>
          <p>And the last question &#x2013; sorry, that was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was just, you described a couple of points which the overhead under-absorption will sustain in 2013. You have launch costs in 2013 depressing margins. We're trying to understand what you would point to as the main items expected to benefit or push margins up in 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and that's a good one. And if you look at the 20 targets, the 25 roadmaps that we have, the 35 months that we have to implement there, and of course, all of these will not come at the back end. There will be some that is more back loaded than other, but we will start to see effects of all the activities that we're doing.</p>
          <p>Now one effect is, for instance, the restructuring in Europe. We have said that the impact there is SEK 600-something million on a yearly basis, full effect in 2014 but of course, we're going to start to see effect of that already in 2013, in the back end of 2013. So there are a number of things that are in the pipeline, based on the strategic objectives that we have, that will come through here. But how much it is, exactly when it comes and so on and so forth, that we will report to you when it happens. We don't give any guidance on that, other than the ones that we have given you in, for instance, the restructuring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for the answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Anders Trapp from SEB. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Just a bit of a follow-up on the Renault repositioning. Basically I wonder, when you sort of have launched the new Renault line-up and the new Volvo FH, should we expect <mark type="ph" /> a big (36:55) sort of difference in positioning between the two brands have increased or decreased?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would definitely say that the product by itself has &#x2013; the repositioning and the differentiation has increased. The other part of this is &#x2013; and that's one thing. The other thing is that we also get a commercial system that optimize the differentiation in the absolute best way, and that is exactly what this reorganization is doing.</p>
          <p>So if you look into 2014, for instance, what you're looking at then is a completely new line up on the Volvo side and the Renault side with the differentiation. You have a reorganized European sales networks that are supporting this. And that is of course a lot of hard work. But generally, you can say that all across the investments that we do during 2013, then turns into and become income from 2014 and onwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Also you have the &#x2013; clarification maybe perhaps on the R&amp;D and market &#x2013; or R&amp;D rather, costs in the &#x2013; visible in the P&amp;L in 2013, if that is actually going to be higher than in 2012, or higher than the level &#x2013; or rate, rather, we saw in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anders, Christer here. I will say it should be reasonably stable in the P&amp;L. You will probably see a fairly high first half, because then we will continue to spend a lot to launch all the products. And as we start to see those product launches coming through, you can say the burn rate in R&amp;D should gradually start to come down towards the second half of the year. But then, on the other hand, we will start to amortize more than we are capitalizing. So some headwind in the first half, I would say, on the P&amp;L side. And then I would say in the second half, fairly neutral.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Compared to the full year level of &#x2013; compared to the Q4 level, because Q4 was a bit &#x2013; quite considerably higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would say the Q4 level is the level we will have now in the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Operator, there was no more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Martin Viecha from Redburn. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. This is Martin Viecha from Redburn. Thanks for taking my questions. I would have three questions, if I may. According to my calculation, a destock of 3,700 vehicles equals to roughly four days of sales. Do you have any idea how many more vehicles will need to be destocked in early 2013?</p>
          <p>The second question is that I noticed that the truck backlog decreased by about 13,000 trucks in 2012, which I think is quite a bit. When do you see backlog going back up and is that going to involve further production cuts? And thirdly, if you just could give us any color on the situation in Russia regarding this truck recycling tax. How do you see situation developing in further quarters? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think that on the first &#x2013; on the destocking activities, as I said, I think that, as we look at the demand going forward, we have &#x2013; the destocking and the inventory reduction that we've done, we have a few more in &#x2013; on the Renault side, but otherwise I think we're pretty much in balance. On the order intake, I'm looking at you, Christer...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know how you have calculated the backlogs because we don't give that externally, but you can say nevertheless, we have seen the backlogs or the order book starting to increase now again in both Europe, Brazil and the U.S, while it's still a bit downward trend in Asia. But the big markets in Europe, North America and Brazil are &#x2013; the backlogs are increasing a bit and that is the reason why we are opening up some more production slots in March both in Brazil and Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the Russian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I missed the Russians.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Recycling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The recycling fee?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take your question once again, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, basically I just wanted to ask regarding the Russian recycling fee. I understand that the European OEMs are not able to get the status of the local producer which means that European truck makers have to pay this tax. From my understanding, it's very difficult to transfer this cost on to the customer. What is your experience and how do you see this developing in future quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We were actually excluded from the recycling fee initially when it was launched in September because we have committed ourselves to buy a cab plant in Russia in Kaluga that will be up and running in the second half of 2014. However, then we got the news in November that we were no longer exempted from this and therefore, we had a bit of a stock problem and of course, we couldn't move those &#x20AC;5,000 to the customers because they had already committed price from us.</p>
          <p>What we will do now in the beginning of this year is of course trying to push that recycling fee into the customer hands. But it will probably take a while because you don't just increase a sticker price by &#x20AC;5,000. It will depend a bit on how our competitors are doing also. But we are pushing now in the next few months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just a quick follow-up on that backlog issue. I've noticed that your book-to-bill in Europe has been below 1 for three quarters in a row. So I'm struggling to figure out how can the European backlog go up if book-to-bill is below 1 for three quarters in quarters in a row? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we have a different type of destocking and other type of you can say movement in there with light duty trucks, etc. So I would say it's just as of recently that you will see the order books starting to move up a bit. And it's no dramatic increases, if I put it that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Fraser Hill from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Good afternoon. Thanks for taking my questions. Just on the European market, I was just interested in your perspective on inventory levels across the market. Obviously, you seem to have got yours into shape heading into 2013. From your perspective, do you think that the industry as a whole has got fairly healthy inventory levels? And what are you seeing on pricing from your competitors at the moment? Is that remaining disciplined or is there still some challenges there from the competition?</p>
          <p>Secondly, in Europe as well with regards to the pre-buy discussion. I know you've got a flat forecast for the year but getting towards the end of the year, are you expecting an uplift still and if so, how are you going to adjust your production footprint for any uplift that might come? And I think finally just on the Chinese construction equipment market, what's your perspective on inventory levels across wheel loaders and hydraulic excavators? If you've got any idea of how months inventory you think there might be across the industry as a whole. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we're looking at the &#x2013; thank you very much for your questions. I think that when it comes to the pricing issue &#x2013; and I leave the market inventory to you, Christer and also on the Chinese side there, these two &#x2013; I think that in general, you can say that we have experienced some spots and some segments with some price pressure in EU in the fourth quarter but in generally, there is absolutely no sort of general price pressure all over the map and that is a little bit of a mixed feeling, generally you can say are holding up quite reasonable. The same goes for spare parts. Even though it's a little bit lower volumes on the spare parts side than we have seen before, but the pricing is holding up.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the pre-buy, we just have to wait and see. We haven't seen anything. And I think I should also then highlight the way we look at the market. Yes, it's a flat market but we also say that's it's a little bit like a reverse 2012 where you're actually now going to see a slow start in the beginning of the year and mathematically, you would then see a stronger ending and gradual improvement over the year. And &#x2013; but when it comes to the pre-buy, I think it's too early to call and we will have to wait and see if we're going to get any effects of that.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the production system, we are definitely ready to do any adaptations that we need, and that's why it was so important to me that we came into this year with an inventory level that gives us that flexibility to go up and down in the production system when we see the market is moving. And then that's why we put such a focus on that in Q4.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the inventory levels on market side, Christer, in the EU and Chinese construction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say in Europe on trucks, it feels like inventories are in reasonably good shape. The exception could be Russia where it's a bit too much inventory. But otherwise, no big issue for the industry. When it comes to China construction equipment, I would say there is still too much inventory out in the dealer networks. That is putting some pressure on pricing and down payments, as some dealers are having financial difficulty and trying to generate cash. We'll see. I think if we have a decent spring season, that should support and help the industry to clean up some of that coming in to the summer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Floyd Angolus from AXE (48:23). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I just wanted to have an idea of the levels of CapEx spend, cash CapEx that you expect for 2013 versus 2012, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Anders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Our easy guidance there is that you can expect pretty much the same levels or flat levels then, going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe with the leasing portfolio, investments will decrease.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean there, you will see a decreasing trend, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And maybe a second question if I may. Just a quick highlight on the change in accounting for the pension system, can you re-summarize what it is about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well this is a change in the IAS 19. What we do here is to give you a bit of guidance here on how the previous corridor method is removed and the use of the discount rate now for our plan assets puts a lot of volatility into the system there. And really, what happens there is &#x2013; and this really why we put down the guidance, is that the pension liabilities are recognized once since we can't have them off balance anymore, they go up with SEK 15 billion and that in effect has also an effect on the equity. And this is primarily also why we now prefer to show our net debt over equity excluding pension, because with a discount rate like this going up and down, it just creates too much volatility in the system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough, so but just for my understanding, the SEK 15 billion increase is purely due to the change in discount rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you could say that. This is nothing changed, this is an accounting treatment that has changed under the IAS <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:17)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, absolutely. I was just to understand correctly where the increase actually came from. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, to give you some more comment. The pension that has been there but has been off-balance sheet due to the corridor method...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it should be recorded as actuarial losses instead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah. That's fine. It was just the change year-over-year. Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If there is no further questions, I want to thank you all for joining and welcome you back then on the Q2 &#x2013; Q1 report in 2013. Thank you very much and have a good day. Bye bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>