<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1227700" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1011</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christine Ritz, Group Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dipl. Wirtsch.-Ing. Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch, Member of the Board of Management; Responsible For Finance and Controlling</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Detlef Wittig, Executive Vice President, Group Sales and Marketing</participant>
      <participant id="4">Gregor Claussen</participant>
      <participant id="5">Christine Ritz</participant>
      <participant id="6">Detlef Wittig</participant>
      <participant id="7">Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch</participant>
      <participant id="8">John Lawson</participant>
      <participant id="9">Thierry Huon</participant>
      <participant id="10">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="11">Albrecht Denninghoff</participant>
      <participant id="12">J&#xFC;rgen Pieper</participant>
      <participant id="13">Ranjit Unnithan</participant>
      <participant id="14">Jose Asumendi</participant>
      <participant id="15">Adam Jonas</participant>
      <participant id="16">Arndt Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="17">Max Warburton</participant>
      <participant id="18">Frank Biller</participant>
      <participant id="19">Christiaan Hetzner</participant>
      <participant id="20">Christoph Rauwald</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to today's Volkswagen AG First Quarter 2009 Results Conference Call. For your information, today's conference is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to your host today, Ms. Christine Ritz, Group Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Volkswagen's conference call for the first three months of 2009. I am joined today by Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch, Member of the Board of Management, Volkswagen AG, responsible for Finance and Controlling; and by Detlef Wittig, Executive Vice President, Volkswagen AG, responsible for Group Sales and Marketing.</p>
          <p>As usual you can also follow the webcast and download the chart from our website www.volkswagenag.com/ir. Questions can be sent by email or called in. Before we start, I would like to mention that after the speech of Mr. P&#xF6;tsch and Mr. Wittig, we will first respond to the questions of analysts and later answer those of journalists.</p>
          <p>Last week, we published our group numbers for the first quarter just ahead of our AGM with further detail contained in our Interim Report issued this morning. I would now like to ask Mr. P&#xF6;tsch to give a few comments on the highlights from the report before Mr. Wittig goes into detail of the deliveries to customers. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, also a warm welcome from my side to this conference call. The worldwide financial crisis has clearly spread into the wider economy and we have felt the impact here at Volkswagen with an extremely weak first quarter with sales dropping 15.7%.</p>
          <p>Despite this trend, we were able to post a positive operating result of &#x20AC;312 million. This was thanks in part to around &#x20AC;600 million one-off gain from the sale of our heavy truck business in Brazil. Without this one-off gain, we lost money at the operating level which was in line with our expectations given the decisive actions taken to reduce output with lower production including short time working and other measures with a clear focus on reducing stock in the logistic chain from factory to dealer.</p>
          <p>With the lower financial result, profit before tax remains just in the black at &#x20AC;52 million, significantly below the 1.4 billion of the first quarter of 2008. Profit after tax for the first quarter was &#x20AC;243 million benefiting from deferred tax income. Despite lower earnings, we continued to invest in the future with a CapEx ratio of 5.5%, ensuring that Volkswagen will emerge from the crisis stronger with a wider geographic footprint and with more attractive fuel-efficient products will continue to delight our customers and grow our business. And at the same time, we improved our automotive net liquidity to &#x20AC;10.7 billion with a positive net cash flow of &#x20AC;2.55 billion, thanks in particular to the significant reduction in stocks.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to hand over to Mr. Wittig, who will take you through our sales development. Mr. Wittig?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and welcome also from my side, ladies and gentlemen. Developments on the global financial markets clearly impacted the world car market from the second half of 2008 and now up and into the first quarter of 2009. The first chart here shows the progressive development of the world car market in comparison to previous year, by quarter, and you can clearly see that from quarter three last year, the world market went down by 6.9% and then reached a level of minus 19%, minus 20% in the fourth quarter of last year and this level being continued in the first quarter of this year, minus 20.7%, so we can see that this trend has still not hit the rock bottom level obviously.</p>
          <p>The next chart compares our performance. In the darker columns with the showing of the total market and you can clearly see that in contrast to the total market, our group deliveries to customers developed significantly better in each quarter, which results in &#x2013; clearly in a good performance and gaining market share at the same time.</p>
          <p>Our deliveries in quarter one and quarter two of last year 2008 were still positive, were still increasing. However, from the fourth quarter, our deliveries also were slowing down and went below previous year and the total for last year was at as you know still a positive result of 0.6% over and above last year.</p>
          <p>The first quarter here, we have broken it down into a monthly progression and you can see that from January with a minus 21% to February with minus 8.5% and now in March last month with minus 5.9%, we see a progressive improvement of our sales, of our deliveries to customers, and as compared with the total market showing we are fairing much better than the total market, again gaining global &#x2013; on a global basis market share. The first quarter result then as compared with previous year is minus 10.7% as compared with the total market in the first quarter of minus 20.7%.</p>
          <p>The next chart shows our performance in the first quarter of this year compared to the last quarter on a regional base. And again, compared with the total market progression, you see on the left side in each area, the red column show the total market performance and our performance just beside that. You can see first of all, the North American market went down by &#x2013; the car market went down by minus 36%, we went down by 15%, so half the margin. So, we are doing much better in North America than the total market.</p>
          <p>Western Europe, 16.3% down, the total market and we are down by 15% in the first quarter, so a slight improvement of our market position in Western Europe as well. You can see a major difference in Eastern Europe, the way the market is down in total by minus &#x2013; roughly minus 40%, we are down by minus 25%. We will have a closer look at Eastern Europe and Russia one chart later. And down below you do see South America on one hand, on the left side and on the right side Asia-Pacific we were even able to increase our deliveries to customers by one to 3% while the total markets there in South America and in Asia-Pacific went down. So, from a global point of view and broken down into region &#x2013; into regional areas, we are doing better in all the areas than the total market &#x2013; the total car market.</p>
          <p>Looking again at our deliveries to customers by market areas in comparison with last year; first of all, the total Volkswagen Group number is 1.4 million cars sold to customers which is a minus of 10.7% as mentioned a little earlier. In Western Europe, we sold 650,000 cars, which is a minus of 15.6%. However within Western Europe, we do have Germany where we are up, our sales are up by 4.8% mainly because of the government's scrappage incentive program.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, we are also down by minus 25% again to total market minus 35%, but within the Eastern European figures there is Russia where we were able to increase even our sales by plus 15%. This performance is certainly highly appreciated because it is against the trend of the total market in Russia which went down by 40%.</p>
          <p>North America, as mentioned before, and South America, the plus 1.1% is mainly driven by our Brazilian sales and we are up in Brazil by roughly 8%. Asia-Pacific, the plus 3.2% again is very much driven by our sales performance in China. In China, we sold 6% more cars than in the period of last year.</p>
          <p>The next chart breaks down our total sales in the first quarter of 1.4 million down by brands and here you can see that especially the Volkswagen Passenger Car brand was able to manage a downturn of only 4.8% and this is a very mixed picture because there was a strong decline of our sales in Europe outside Germany in North America and South America as we have seen on previous slide, but the sales performance was very much supported by a very positive performance in Germany and Brazil and in China. Audi sales were down by 16% down to 210,000 cars with losses in nearly all major areas due to the downsizing impact on the premium segment worldwide. However, as compared with Audi's premium competitors, Audi outperformed all their premium competitors in each area.</p>
          <p>&#x160;koda decreased deliveries by 17.5% and that is especially due to the weak Central and Eastern European markets where the focus of the &#x160;koda sales are, and also of the strong Czech currency. Sales suffered a major decline of minus 23% and we have to look at the performance especially of SEAT in the total market, their home market, and that is certainly a challenge for SEAT because the Spanish market, their home market, was down by over 43% and looking at this development of the home market still the SEAT performance was reasonably good and again influenced by &#x2013; negatively influenced by the home market. Bentley was down by 55% in quarter one due to very weak markets &#x2013; premium markets especially in the United States and in the U.K., two of the most strong sales areas of Bentley.</p>
          <p>Our Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles showed a decline of their deliveries to customers by 31% and here we have to compare also our performance in the light commercial total market and again looking at the trend there which is much worse than in the passenger car market, it goes beyond the 30% minus, also the showing of our commercial vehicles is positive as far as positioning and market share is concerned. &#x160;koda is included within the group on a quarterly basis here with 11,300 trucks.</p>
          <p>Now turning to a few highlights of our new models because again our sales performance is certainly not only driven by scrappage schemes of various countries, but especially by the introduction of new models and we will be able to continue the strong support of new model introduction this year in 2009 throughout the year because we will have over 60 new models launched to the market &#x2013; to the various world markets this year. Of these 60 new models built, 33 models [will] be totally new models or new model variations.</p>
          <p>Turning to Volkswagen; first of all, you will see the New Polo, successor &#x2013; the Polo successor, the Polo as we call it internally A05. The market launch in the second quarter, so next quarter, and you can see from the picture the highly characteristic design-oriented car, the very clear and authentic personality. And I think as far as the segment is concerned, which we compete with the Polo, the A0 segment it offers, the Polo offers the best combination of quality and driving pleasure. A look and feel of high quality, material, high quality services, high quality appeal. And as far as technology is concerned, it will at the same time also make a benchmark in the segment with gears &#x2013; with double shift gear boxes, TSI engines and so forth. And what is even &#x2013; what is very much interesting in these times, the New Polo shows the greatest possible economy in compliance with CO2 standards, and New Polo will start at 109 gram CO2 and we will follow-up with the Polo BlueMotion version a little later with 87 gram CO2.</p>
          <p>Turning to Audi; the A5 convertible Cabriolet as we say, launched in April. It's created certainly from one of the most beautiful of our Coup&#xE9; models, the A5, equipped with a distinctive and essential soft top and the finest of technologies. And it will certainly add to the success not only of the A5 Coup&#xE9;, but of its predecessor model, the A4 Cabriolet.</p>
          <p>&#x160;koda; with the Yeti, &#x160;koda will redefine off-road as a sympathetic and sensible and strong product placement. This car, the Yeti, will be launched in August this year. The world premiere took place at Geneva Motor Show. And the Yeti is a result of compact-sized powerful appearance optimized engines, certainly great on and off-road driving performances, unique and modern, and likable and also strong design, high seating position, and a very MPV-like flexibility of its rear seats.</p>
          <p>SEAT; SEAT launched &#x2013; just launched in the market the new Exeo range and a little later we will &#x2013; and which will take place in July, we will add to the SEAT Exeo, the Exeo ST version, the Sports Tourer as Combi version and this model not only extends the range of &#x160;koda going to the medium segments but it focus at the same time on leisure activities and we will certainly see a very high sort of influx of private customers there. Again, attractive segment orientation of SEAT, attractive combination of style, performance and functionality, and positioning once more SEAT as Auto Emoci&#xF2;n.</p>
          <p>So, I would like to return the word to Ms. Ritz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Wittig. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, can you take us through the financials please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course I can, and I will get started with sales revenue. Sales revenue which as you know excludes our Chinese joint ventures which we report at equity in the financial result fell by 11.2% to &#x20AC;24 billion. Scania contributed 1.6 billion to sales revenue meaning that on a like-for-like basis the reduction in revenue was even greater, that's just over 17%.</p>
          <p>Now looking at the details; the drop in sales translated into a &#x20AC;4.4 billion negative impact on sales revenue. Currency mainly the British pounds had a further negative impact of 0.5 billion. Our Financial Services Division reported a positive 0.4 billion swing this quarter particularly benefited from the sale of leased vehicles.</p>
          <p>Turning now to operating profit which declined by &#x20AC;1 billion to &#x20AC;0.3 billion. Unsurprisingly, given the sales figures we have reported, volume, price, and mix had a significant negative impact with currency proving a further break on our performance of combined &#x20AC;2.1 billion. Our intense focus on costs, both on our products and with regards to our overheads, continues to produce results with a combined improvement of &#x20AC;0.6 billion.</p>
          <p>As announced last week, we benefited from a book gain of further &#x20AC;0.6 billion on the sale of our heavy truck business in Brazil to MAN. While on the subject of trucks, demonstrating the strength of the Scania brands in the face of a very dramatic fall in global demand, Scania came in with a positive result before the purchase price accounting adjustments resulted in a small loss. And to complete this chart, the Financial Services reported a small decline of &#x20AC;0.1 billion.</p>
          <p>The next two charts focus on the cash flow and the liquidity of the Automotive Division. Operating cash flow improved 35.6% to around &#x20AC;3 billion. These positive performances substantially related to a dramatic improvement in working capital. In total, in the first three months of 2009, excess inventory in the Volkswagen Group and in our dealer network has been reduced by 140,000 units and we continue to work on further measures to balance customer demand with production capacity. This led to an improvement of close to &#x20AC;1 billion versus the year-end 2008.</p>
          <p>Our CapEx ratio stood at 5.5% for the first quarter, clearly the lower revenue impacts the calculation here but it is also a demonstration of how we have continued to invest in our new plants in the U.S., India and Russia as well as in advanced fuel-efficient powertrain. Not to forget exciting new models such as the New Polo as Mr. Wittig pointed out the Audi all-roads and the &#x160;koda Yeti as well as the SEAT Exeo ST and other models coming to the market this year and next. Although we are submitting all investments to rigorous scrutiny, we believe that the demand for new exciting fuel-efficient cars remains and as the world will emerge from recession, we are determined to continue to invest in the future. Investments we are making now will pay off as demand rises.</p>
          <p>For the first three months of 2009, our reported cash flow from investing activities stood at a net of 425 million. If you exclude the impact of equity investments, specifically the sale of our truck business in Resende to MAN, the comparable figure stood at &#x20AC;1.7 billion versus 1.3 in 2008, that's an increase of 36.5%. Together, net cash flow for the Automotive Division was a positive net &#x20AC;2.6 billion.</p>
          <p>I'd like to move to liquidity; the improvement in operating cash flow supported by the impact of lower cash flows from investing activities and here the impact of course of the sale of our Brazilian truck business at just over 1 billion had a major influence where significant sectors in driving the liquidity in the Automotive Division up to &#x20AC;10.7 billion.</p>
          <p>As we face one of the most difficult economic situations ever, faced by the automotive industry this strong financial base will ensure that we have the ability to face the challenge of the market while continuing to invest in our future.</p>
          <p>Let's turn now to the financial performance of the individual brands. The negative sales development was only partially offset by our cost improvement measures resulting in a significant decline in earnings across all of our brands, with the exception of commercial vehicles which benefited from the sale of our activities in Resende with a net plus of &#x20AC;528 million.</p>
          <p>Volkswagen Cars fit to a negative 279 million reflecting lower volume and sales revenue. Audi's operating result was a positive 363 million. Similarly &#x160;koda's results fell to &#x20AC;28 million with an adverse exchange rate impact adding to the burden of lower sales. SEAT dropped to an operating loss of &#x20AC;145 million. Scania showed a positive 46 million before purchase price allocation. Financial Services reported a positive &#x20AC;156 million, that's a slight reduction on the first quarter of 2008. And finally, Chinese markets continued to grow in the first quarter recording a proportional operating profit of &#x20AC;101 million up 38% on the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now this leads me to our 2009 outlook, which you can read in detail in the Interim Report. With its nine brands and young fuel-efficient model range, the Volkswagen Group is well prepared for the current economic and market situation. For this reason we believe that the Volkswagen Group will perform better than the market as a whole and will be able to gain market share during the crisis.</p>
          <p>Group sales revenue in 2009 will be lower than in the previous year. Rising refinancing cost and worsening of the country mix will serve as an additional drag on earnings. We will counter this trend in particular through disciplined cost and investment management, and the continuous optimization of processes within our "18 plus" strategy. The high volatility of market developments does not commit any reliable forecast to be made for the rest of fiscal year 2009. However, based on an extremely weak business in the first three months of 2009, we continue to expect that our earnings will not reach the level of previous years.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the Volkswagen Group is facing unprecedented challenges in the markets. While we keep one eye on our long-term objectives, we also remain focused on our short-term needs to manage cash. And the needs to ensure our stocks are well balanced to customer demand and also to ensure that we are as efficient as possible with the resources available to us in terms of costs and investment demands. In the face of these challenges, we expect the Volkswagen Group to close 2009 with a profit. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. P&#xF6;tsch. We will now move to the Q&amp;A session starting first with the questions from analysts please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The question and answer session will be conducted electronically. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We're coming to our first question from Gregor Claussen from Commerzbank. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello, everybody. I had some questions, if I may. The first one is regarding current month April, can you tell us how April is going and do you already have some visibility therefore on the second quarter and the development of working capital? My second question is, well we saw in Q1 some &#x2013; a deteriorating mix in pricing figures, for example, Volkswagen minus 4.8% in sales and in revenues minus 20%. So, are we going to see something similar in Q2 and maybe ongoing? And my third question would be on the net cash, as far as I remember that was a rough guidance for the net cash by the end of 2009 of some &#x20AC;5 billion and now we have some &#x20AC;10.7 billion, do you think that &#x20AC;5 billion is still adequate figure which assume some eight to 10 billion to be more realistic? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. So, Gregor has three questions for us. The first question is with regard to our business in April, if we can give some further details and &#x2013; about the visibility in the second quarter? The second question is again about the second quarter, the impact of mix and pricing. And the last question was if we can give a guidance with regard to the net cash in 2009? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I will try to answer your first question. As far as April is concerned, we do see a total market that again looks like dropping by roughly 20% as compared with last year. So what we have seen in the first quarter total market's going down by roughly 20% continues in April as far as our group sales are concerned, we do see also as compared with the total market a much bigger &#x2013; a better figure for us but still, yes, we will be below last year, say in the area of less than 10% below last year, it could be 8%, 9%, 10%, that's the area. So we continue &#x2013; as a summary, we continue to see a still falling total world market, but we do see a continuation of improvement of our sales as compared with the previous &#x2013; with the months of the previous year and as far as the second quarter is concerned, we do see a slight improvement of our showing as compared with the first quarter but still below last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I can add on this the other questions concerning mix and pricing; first of all, which clearly has to be seen in relationship with the existing market situations in most of our developed markets where clearly speaking cars which address a more premium segment of the market are in not the most easiest position for the simple reason that part of the market just sect-wise are taking on the customer side a waiting position until they take decisions to buy a new car and the other thing is, and that's also very normal for the economic phase where we are currently sitting in is that part of very traditional customers in these segments just for psychological reasons have difficulties to take a decision on buying a new premium car. So that is one key influencing factor which is very normal in these type of economic framework conditions.</p>
          <p>The other one is that you are well aware that in quite a few countries, there are incentives available which create a certain priority <mark type="audio gap" /> that the product mix of the situation. And that's why our assumption is that at least for some time we have to assume that this development will continue on.</p>
          <p>On the net cash side and the working capital side, clearly, I do not want to repeat the statement I already made in terms of our outlook for the full year which is very difficult to give because it's clear this is heavily depending on how the market develops further. But, we believe that we have a good chance to end the year with a positive net cash flow position and this of course also means that we are continuing on reasonably high level of liquidity &#x2013; of net liquidity in our Automotive Division which is just adequate to the actual market conditions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. That was very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're now moving to our next question, it's from John Lawson from Citi. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and good afternoon. First question, could you give us an indication perhaps, Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, of how much more working capital opportunity you see in reducing inventories at least? I guess the billion [1 billion] improvement you made was actually for a rather smaller number than the 140,000 units which you described as coming out of inventory, I think in your own and your dealer business in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Second point, I think in your report today, you do highlight the failure to get a qualified majority at that preference shareholder meeting that was held last week. Does this matter to you at all or will you simply leave this business now to next year to try again?</p>
          <p>And finally, I think a couple of your competitors have agreed or are looking to agree emergency measures with their, on their German labor cost for 2009, I wondered whether you felt under any pressure to emulate them? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, thank you very much. John Lawson has three questions for us. So, the first question is with regard to working capital and our &#x2013; the reducing of our stocks at the Volkswagen AG and in our dealer network. The second question is with regard to the result of the preference shareholder meeting last week, if we can give some further information on which plans we have? And the last question is about labor costs in Germany if we have any plan to reduce these? Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the first question, in terms of more opportunities on the working capital side, let me just go back to what we said commenting on the figures for the 31st of December 2008 where we said that in spite of a lot of counter measures we ended the year with excess inventory and we gave a number of which was a number not much less than 200,000 cars of excess inventory.</p>
          <p>Now, it is important to understand that the 200,000 cars do not only refer to what is sitting on our balance sheet. It's to a significant part also excess inventory on the dealer side. And &#x2013; but we're saying that it was possible to reduce that number of excess inventory by around 140,000 in the first quarter, then we have to keep the imagination that first of all of course the reduction is taking place on the dealer side until it's effective within the framework of Volkswagen itself. So this means, there are some decent opportunities left to work on the working capital side.</p>
          <p>Although I do not want to raise too high-flying expectations on that, because what we're &#x2013; at least in one of the scenarios we are foreseeing that the incentive situation in some markets might give us the chance to step the sales and volume side of the business up a bit against the first quarter as Mr. Wittig explained. Now that clearly also goes in line with being able to deliver and that is of course creating some limitations on a further more significant reduction of inventory but nevertheless there are further opportunities.</p>
          <p>Now, as you rightly say to the other question, we were not able to pass through our points with the regards to our preference shares. There was no real project to be funded by this action that's why that was just so to say precaution which we wanted to do on a more formal side, that's why it's not creating any challenge for us and I should say at this point also that we have a tool in reserve anyway by our ordinary shares where we can, if we ever wanted, organize something and we have this approval until 2011. So from that end we can wait until 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the various actions taken by one of the other competitors are concerned, I think it is important to look at the situation in Volkswagen. They are clearly, and I think you've got to say at this point, we have to very respectfully say that there was an enormous support in terms of flexibility &#x2013; to create flexibility in our company specifically also by our German employees. And we will need this flexibility further on. When I'm saying this I'm meaning that there was a very substantial support to embark on short time working first of all and within reasonably short framework, to be willing to also talk about additional shifts even during the weekends is I think something which recommends a fair treatment and that's why currently there are no ideas and plans of any such emergency actions with regard to our people.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Can we have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We are now moving to our next question from Thierry Huon from Exane. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. It's Thierry Huon from Exane BNP. I've got three questions, the first one is to know if we could have a split between the price and mix and the volume effect of the 1.8 billion mentioned in the presentation? The second question related to the CapEx, what we should expect for the full year in terms of CapEx? And the last question is about the operating leverage that we could derive from the numbers you provided. We see that Volkswagen Passenger Cars is at around 20% which seems to be a strong achievement. Is this kind of operating leverage is sustainable over the year or was it due to specific mergers put in place during Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Thierry.  So, you have three questions for us. So, first question is if we can give some more information about price and mix effect, the figure of 1.6 billion if we can split that up? Then the second question is if we can give a guidance for CapEx for 2009? And the last question is about the Passenger Car Volkswagen brand about the operating leverage if, what we can expect here for the long-term? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the first question is concerned, I'd like to start with a few general remarks on volume, price and mix. Certainly we have seen the volume effect, 170,000 cars in the first quarter less sales, that's a major impact and we can see this on the revenue and operating profit numbers. As far as the price and mix effect is concerned, there is certainly no room left actually for price increases and that's why on this side, there is no negative, but also no positive, no major positive influence.</p>
          <p>As far as mix is concerned, there are various factors that we're taking into consideration. Mix is, first of all, is influenced by the downsizing trend as far as the model segments are concerned that was mentioned earlier by Mr. P&#xF6;tsch already. Yes, we are selling more smaller cars with less contribution margin than high-end cars with higher profit contribution and as far as mix is concerned we have a difference also in country mix.</p>
          <p>Our strongest sort of revenue and profit area is certainly Western Europe and Western Europe is very much down except Germany. So there is a mixed picture as far as Western Europe in total is concerned. Yes, we have a better situation due to the incentive program in Germany and the sales increase in Germany at higher profit contribution but at the same time we have a much more lower sales volume in the other Western European countries, so eating up the profit contribution from the German market. And as far as the shift still in our sales are concerned around about to markets outside Europe those markets have much lower profit contribution. So from a country mix point of view, we certainly have an additional negative influence.</p>
          <p>And in order to support sales in those markets where incentive schemes or government incentive schemes are running we have to sort of contribute as well. So we have to increase our sales support money or sales support budgets there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I can continue on with the further questions. And maybe I can get started again stating that out of the of course the three elements, price, mix and volume, of course volume is more than 90% of the effect and the other thing which is to be said which leads to the question concerning the operating leverage at Volkswagen Passenger Cars is that to understand the key figures of the first quarter, it is important to recognize that while we were reducing stock, it consequently means that our production volume was cut back much more substantially than sales volume which obviously created an enormous negative impact on our P&amp;L and under these circumstances I think even as the Volkswagen Passenger Car turned up with a negative numbered performance was quite positive and we will see this in the upcoming quarters. So, we assume a positive figure if mark-to-market don't turn further to negative also for Volkswagen Passenger Cars.</p>
          <p>And as far as CapEx is concerned, this is only just to repeat that the core point here which is we do further very consequently support all the strategic projects. Now, this is to be found of course as far as product related projects are concerned on the one hand and of course, as you are well aware, we are creating new manufacturing locations in India, in Russia, in the U.S., there is no intent to cut short on that, so that's the strategic ones and a few more we are supporting while the more general projects are significantly reduced and, therefore, we believe that for the full year, we'll be able to again produce a CapEx number which is at around 6% in spite of the fact that we are in a very substantial investment phase at Volkswagen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We're now moving to Horst Schneider from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Horst Schneider from HSBC. Three questions, if I may. First one is on Audi; Audi's certainly presented here very strong EBIT margin in that industry environment and it strikes as its operational gearing at Audi was quite low particularly compared to some peers or maybe you can give some more explanations what's led you to that strong margin performance at Audi, particularly if some special items were included here? I had a look in the Audi Q1 report, but I have not seen any explanation if maybe some provisions were reversed or if that had influenced here the number, so that will be helpful.</p>
          <p>Then second one is again regarding the outlook, I guess that you have by now fairly good visibility on the second quarter, so maybe you can make some statements if you expect to make positive earnings here in the second quarter? And the third question is related to your market share gains, I would be interested if you use particularly your Financial Services at the moment here to gain market share? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, we have three questions from Horst today. So, the first question is, if you can give some more information on the strong margin of Audi in the first quarter? The second question is, if we can give some more details or guidance for the second quarter with regard to earnings? And the last question is if we use Financial Services to gain market share? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me first of all address the first question on Audi and a little bit ironically speaking, I could say, I didn't expect you to find anything in the first quarter of Audi other than this is just very excellent company. And in fact there are no one-offs included. If you recall a couple of our conference calls last year then we many fold times said, well, Audi is moving in the right direction, but of course the P&amp;L is burdened by a record number of model introductions which of course eat up some of the profit margins. In spite of this we've seen a record result last year. And of course on that basis, Audi is even under much more difficult circumstances just continuing on, on this. We are the market leader in Europe and we still can say that there is, always in relative terms, a substantial demand for these excellent cars and we've clearly the one of the most modern product portfolios ever. So, I could of course talk long on this, but to cut a long story short, it's an excellent company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question on the outlook of the second quarter. And, of course, in a given economical framework one is also well advised to eat the cake only once if it's on the table. But I think the circumstances supports to say that we're counting on a positive result for the second quarter. And to the third question and Mr. Wittig will be a little bit more specific on how we are gaining market share. The contribution I can give at this point is that we and &#x2013; I read this comment as ever, we deal with Financial Services at a strict arm's length principles. So, that's why there is no specific approach taken by Financial Services. It's of course the close cooperation with our automotive brands which just brought to fruition but there is no special action carried out. And I would like to leave it to Mr. Wittig to comment a little bit on our market share gains.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, first of all, we can see that we are gaining market share in all areas in the world which at the same time indicates that it is not only artificially driven by sales support or financial support or Financial Services measures. There must be more behind it and obviously it is a strong product. It is a fresh and new product and maybe we are happy to have a cycle &#x2013; product cycle that fits the actual trend in the market also but it is mainly product driven that's what we can say &#x2013; but that's what we can say, and mainly product driven I refer to all the introduction especially on the Volkswagen side of the New Golf last year and some model variations of the Golf and at the same time also improved Golf Plus version and we can still see a strong showing of the Tiguan and we do see and expect a major contribution this year on the New Polo also. So it's more cars that support the sales progress and the market share gains of Volkswagen, and it is the same situation on the &#x160;koda side because Fabia is in the market and the Fabia variations are in the market and it's not a old car yet but still a young and fresh as far as &#x160;koda is concerned with the addition of the Yeti this year, this will certainly continue, a compact smaller SUV.</p>
          <p>As far as SEAT is concerned, despite of the negative impact of the home market of the sort of downturn of the home market, the new Ibiza is doing very well because we are gaining as far as the new Ibiza is concerned with SEAT market share in all European countries and as you know SEAT is very much concentrating on Europe.</p>
          <p>And when I look at the world map, we have &#x2013; we have mentioned this in our press release. We're actually at the world market share of 11%. So, we're improving very much. So, we're one point &#x2013; three points ahead of last year's situation. And we're gaining market share in Western Europe, up from 18.6% last year up to 20.6, which is two percentage points more, which is a lot. We're gaining market share in Russia. We've more or less nearly doubled our market share in Russia. As a group, we are now on the fourth ranking &#x2013; the fourth position in the Russian market.</p>
          <p>In the United States, we were able to increase our market share up to 2.6% and Brazil from 24 up to 26% and so forth and so forth. So, it's across the world and again it is driven by product in Brazil for instance the New Golf as I mentioned a year before, the New Golf Plus, Volkswagen is concerned worldwide but especially in Europe and so forth. And we do see a continuation of this trend, because these new cars are still young in the market and we will add to these new cars more cars, more new models as I've mentioned before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We're now moving to Albrecht Denninghoff from BHF, excuse me. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, it's Albrecht Denninghoff from BHF. I've a question in the report as mentioned that there has been a repayment of capital increase in the Financial Services Division, could you give an indication about the amount and how this influenced liquidity and which positions in the industrial part of the cash flow statement? That would be the first question. And then the second question is that the underproduction of sales, is this really the biggest explanation for the 1.8 billion profit decline in volume, price, mix on the 4.5 billion revenue decline, because I'm still wondering why this revenues grew upwards and the marginal income seems to be about 15 to 20% and if it goes in the other direction it is 40% and on the same time, the distribution costs did not increase significance. Were there any asset write-downs or impairments on the inventory, I mean, you still have on &#x2013; in your books at the end of the quarter or something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so we have two questions from Albrecht. So the first question is with regard to the capital increase of FX or the repayment, if you can give an outlook, or if you give some information on the impact on the cash flow and liquidity? And the second question is about again, the explanation of the 1.8 million (sic) [1.8 billion] revenue decline, if you can give some further details?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, as far as the repayment of the capital increase is concerned, that's an amount of &#x20AC;600 million and it's due to the good development of our direct bank business. It is the case that any additional capital increase would not be very efficient way of course to support the performance of our Financial Services entity. As far as the 1.8 is concerned, can I give any further explanation other than that the volume part is by far the biggest influencing factor at this point? And we, I should say, of course, after we're able to reduce our stock situation very significantly already in the first quarter, we, of course, we don't plan on any asset write-downs in this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, you can confirm that you have not done any reevaluation of your &#x2013; the cars you book on your inventories at the end of March? And have you already completed your program in the &#x2013; clear out of the inventory pipeline or is it still good considerable amount of cars like 50,000 cars are to come in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Albrecht has one question with regard to inventories what are our plans for the second quarter, and if there is no reevaluation of cars in inventory at the end of the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's again we haven't done any reevaluation at the end of the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're now moving to J&#xFC;rgen Pieper from Metzler. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, lady and gentlemen. I have two questions. The first is on China to get a better understanding for the market, is it fair to say that China is back on a sustainable growth trend? So, possibly the first market worldwide to look &#x2013; to begin to look rather healthy again or is it too early to call that?</p>
          <p>And the second one is on Porsche, we have tons of media reports recently about strategic changes and massive changes in the corporation in the merger of Volkswagen-Porsche. Mr. P&#xF6;tsch is it a realistic option and a possibility from your point of view to bid at some point for the operations of Porsche like many of the press people writes nowadays?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. So J&#xFC;rgen has two questions for us, first question, is China back on a sustainable growth trend? And the second question is on Porsche, if you can give some further information, if there are any plans or options to bid for Porsche?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the first question is concerned, China, the China market development, yes, we can confirm that the growth rates in China are back to what the Chinese would call normal and we do see for this year a forecast of the Chinese total passenger car market at a level of roughly six million cars, could be a bit less, could be a bit more even, as compared with the 5.5 million cars of last year. And the indication of &#x2013; by the end of last year was that the market could go even below 5.5 million but with the incentive program and some other measures in the Chinese market of the government, the market is growing and it's &#x2013; besides of the Indian market, those are the only two markets where we can say that they are getting out of the difficult situation as the first emerging markets in the world besides of Brazil, I must mention, but yes we see a positive trend and the continuous positive trend of the Chinese market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the Porsche subject, I can only repeat what we already said which is more or less the Management Board at Volkswagen has been considering the question on what possibilities there are to undertake next steps on the close cooperation which we have with Porsche, and of course, you can be absolutely assured that Volkswagen &#x2013; what is dealing in the best interest of Volkswagen. There are, clearly speaking, no decisions regarding this subject.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Well, the next question please, and I'm really sorry but due to the limited period of time, I would like to ask you now to raise one question only. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We're now moving to Ranjit Unnithan. Please go ahead sir. He is from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my question. My question is on the operating profit slide that you had. On the fixed cost depreciation, it was a 500 million positive, could you break that down for us? Was that largely the short-time week or were there sort of other components of savings that also showed up there? And should we expect sort of a similar run rate for the remainder of the year, so in other words, would it translate into roughly a 2 billion savings in the year, if you can answer that, that would be great?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Ranjit. So we have one question about the analysis of the operating profit, the improvement by &#x20AC;0.5 billion, if we can split up what is fixed cost and depreciation and actually what is our outlook or guidance for 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, as you see from the operating profit slide, we were able to tune up with significant improvement on the fixed cost side and this refers first of all to a lot of efforts which we've put into this subject. It's one of our cornerstones in our program to very significantly reduce the cost of the business. Nevertheless the very specific situation which I've pointed out which means that we had to reduce production by more than 20% in the first quarter had a certain impact here, so that's why you cannot just simply take the number shown in the first quarter by four to have the full year number. I think it can be expected that we achieve further improvements, but it should be somewhat less than the proportion of development throughout the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We're now moving to RBS and Mr. Jose Asumendi will now have our question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jose Asumendi from RBS. Just one question please, on the negative financial result, the 261 million, I was wondering if you could give a bit more light to the figure and if it's reasonable run rate per quarter to assume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Jose. You asked the question about the negative financial result, if we can give some more information and what is really the full-year forecast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, the change compared to the prior year relates primarily to a lower net amount of interest and securities income and smaller positive contribution from our equity investments which is, of course, on the one hand related to moving Scania from an equity position to a full consolidation. And of course, it's also to another extent related to a lower performance if you take the total of all our equity participations.</p>
          <p>The other point is that to interpret the financial result, these are almost easy as we have all the various fair valuation issues there for derivatives, for example, then of course another important factor is the discount of the accruals on long-term provisions. And certainly, if there are any extraordinary issues, it's also to be taken into consideration. That's why also the volatility is reasonably high for these reasons.</p>
          <p>Our outlook statements focus principally on the operating result in which we think the success of our core business is better represented. We expect a high negative triple digit million financial result for the full year 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Adam Jonas from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks and good evening. Just one kind of strategic or the operational question about you and your largest and most important strategic partner Porsche; when you think of how you operate with Porsche currently, would you describe the ability to cooperate as one of total freedom? Are you able to do whatever you want to do in terms of new technologies, new products, and commercial opportunities with good freedom or would you say that there are some limitations that could be facilitated if the structure was changed and you can work more closely with Porsche? Can you elaborate on that, please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you Adam. You are interested in our freedom to do &#x2013; to make decisions on technology products and so on, if we can give some information here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think in terms of trying to understand how we cooperate with Porsche, I think it's first of all necessary that we have the right view in, and the right view I believe is that Porsche is our largest shareholder, is of course interested in the long-term success of the Volkswagen Group. And as the Porsche management truly understands the auto business, both sides will benefit from any cooperation. So, in that sense, it should be very clear that the limiting factor of embarking on any kind of new technology innovation or whatever it is, is more our requirement of course to achieve the necessary returns on this rather any influence by Porsche. In that sense, I think the Volkswagen management is free in the sense that of course we have to respect our return targets which were established by the Volkswagen Management Board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>From Credit Suisse, Arndt Ellinghorst is going to have our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you and good afternoon to everybody. Just one question for Mr. Wittig, and then just a quick clarification please. Mr. Wittig, scrapping is probably getting the auto award of the year in many regions of the world. Now, if we look at past or beyond the positive effects of scrapping premiums that's currently helping the industry over this huge macro downturn. And are you afraid that this could lead to a major headache for the industry potentially in 2010 and if we get a bit more precise for instance on the German market, I think we should expect something like 3.6 million units this year, would you share all of you that next year we could talk about numbers of 2.6 million, since there's been quite a pull forward from car sales into this year?</p>
          <p>And then just a quick clarification from Mr. P&#xF6;tsch please, on J&#xFC;rgen Pieper's question on Porsche, can you rule out today that you are not buying or can you rule out that you're buying any assets from Porsche SE please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Arndt. You have two questions for us. The first question is for Mr. Wittig with regard to the scrapping incentives, what major impact do we expect for the industry in 2010 especially in the German market? And the second question is on Porsche again if we can rule out that we would buy any assets today? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, we do have an experience of close to 10 years back what happened after scrappage incentive schemes ran out in other European markets in France and in Spain. And yes, there is always a drop in the market after running out of these schemes. But, we have to look at it this time with a different view because when we check who is sort of coming and trading in cars and the 10 years old cars, are these potential buyers for new cars or not?</p>
          <p>As we do see here, with the first analysis that we have done roughly as far as the total market is concerned, roughly 50% of those who had purchased new cars under this scrappage scheme had no intention at all to buy new cars. They were either delaying their product &#x2013; their purchase decision or most probably were &#x2013; into the used car markets there are a lot of buyers who are only into used car markets every three, four years. And again what we see from our analysis that 50% of the customers that the total market does see in these days had no intention to buy new cars at all. So, they are not dropping out of future new car buyer schemes in any case.</p>
          <p>As far as Volkswagen is concerned, we've gone further and our analysis tells us that roughly 70% of the customers that we do see on the Volkswagen side also on the &#x160;koda and on the SEAT side, who bought Volkswagen had never the intention to buy Volkswagen before. So, we have gained incremental customers, incremental sales. When I say it's incremental, this is not anticipated or substitution then for new cars in 2010. Yes, the one answer is we will see a reduction of the total market in Germany. We will see a reduction of our sales volume again, but it's not one to one and it's not 50%, but it's much less next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very clear. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Porsche question, I can only say that the Volkswagen Management Board has been considering the question on what possibilities there are to undertake any next steps on the close cooperation with Porsche. You can rest assure that the Volkswagen Board is dealing in the best interest of Volkswagen. It is already said there are no decisions regarding this subject.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we have time for three last questions from analysts. So, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Max Warburton from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Max Warburton from Bernstein. Another question on Porsche please. Dr. P&#xF6;tsch, you were very helpful to the analysts and investors in VW last year giving a clarification of how the Supervisory Board would have to decide on a domination agreement. Could you be as open this time in any decision about buying Porsche's operating business? Would it need to be put to a vote to the Supervisory Board, does Lower Saxony effectively have a veto over this or is it a decision that can be made by the Management Board which is the Board you keep referring to? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Max. You have one question about Porsche and a possible domination agreement if that has to be approved by the Supervisory Board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I don't know, if you can still hear me, sorry, that wasn't the question. The question was any decision to buy Porsche's operating business, does that have to be put to the Supervisory Board and does Lower Saxony have a veto, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm sorry. So, to buy any assets or operation business unit if that has to be approved by the Supervisory Board and what is the role of Lower Saxony?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, you are absolutely right that I principally tend to be supportive and helpful but there are situations where I can't be helpful because clearly speaking in terms any decision-making processes, within hypothetical ones which you are referring to, I do not want to give any inside rulings of the Supervisory Board as a segue, we're talking of a hypothetical issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just, with Scania, when the decision was taken to buy the Scania business of Porsche, was that put to the Supervisory Board or is that decision made at the Management Board level, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's of course been put to the Supervisory Board, of course, as I said already, I don't want to comment on any processes within the Supervisory Board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Now we take the last question from an analyst please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We are now moving to Frank Biller from BBW Bank. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Frank Biller from LBBW. Just a quick one on Scania PPA maybe you can guide us a bit through what's coming within the next quarters or the year 2009 and 2010, if it touch 56 million figure like in the first quarter or is it much higher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Frank. So, you have a question about the PPA of Scania, what effect do we expect for the next quarters and for 2010? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the number of the first quarter should be a good running number for this and next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, now let's take a question from journalists please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our question is from Christiaan Hetzner from Reuters. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just had a couple of questions really quickly, just on the Porsche issue, if you could just at least say whether you are very concerned about the level of net debt at Porsche since that is really a pretty substantial amount, 9 billion? And could you potentially extend any loans to them or use your own cash in anyway to help out their financial situation apart from possibly buying assets? And then just in terms of your net cash position of 10.7 billion, could you give us an update about where this position would be if you were to exclude Audi from those figures, would you still be net cash positive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Christiaan. So we have two questions, the first question is the, would like to comment the financial situation of Porsche and the next question is about the net cash position, what would be the right figure if we exclude Audi? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as the first question is concerned, clearly we generally do not wish to comment on the financial position of other companies, and therefore, any related questions are just I think not to be answered. In terms of the net cash number and I would assume you are referring to the first quarter 2009, then this would even be positive if you would take out Audi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so it seems that one question is left from a journalist. Sir please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're now moving to Christoph Rauwald from Dow Jones. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, Christoph Rauwald, Dow Jones Newswires at Frankfurt. Apart from the recent speculation about interesting things like cash settled options and credit conditions, your colleague Mr. <mark type="inaudible" /> has enjoyed an excellent reputation for example for a successful currency hedging in recent years. Are there any plans that Volkswagen and Porsche could cooperate on the financial operations in the future following up on Mr. Winterkorn and your earlier statements to press ahead with the partnership this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we have the last question now, again on Porsche, if we could imagine to cooperate or if we would like to cooperate on financial business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I think in principle terms there is nothing to be ruled out for a potential cooperation as we many fold times said that we want to develop things further but, also before thinking about additional things it's important to keep in mind that we're currently developing the next generation of the Colorado projects, that's mainly the Porsche Cayenne and the Volkswagen Touareg. We're developing a common hybrid system together and just recently we started delivering fuel engines to Porsche and just to be a little more complete, I should say also that sort of Porsche Panamera which was recently launched at the auto show in Shanghai. Our Hanover plant delivers the painted body, so there is a lot of things underway and in that sense I think, of course, we &#x2013; in the last years, we were stepping up this close cooperation to the new level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. This was the last question I would like to come to an end and I also would like to thank you very much for taking part in our conference call. Enjoy the rest of the afternoon. Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That will conclude today's conference call. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>