<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1297958" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call - Q&amp;A Session</title>
    <date>2010-03-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1011</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Christine Ritz, Group Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="analyst">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Martin Winterkorn</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Lothar Lubinetzki</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Hans Dieter P&#xF6;tsch</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Christian Klingler</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Daniel Schwarz</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Adam Hull</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Thierry Huon</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Francisco Garcia Sanz</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">John Lawson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">John Buckland</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen. I would also like bid you a very warm welcome to Autostadt. This morning the entire Board of Management already has detailed explanations concerning the business development and strategy of the group, but there might still be a couple of questions which have not been addressed and answered yet. And this is why as announced, the Board of Management will be happy to take questions from the analysts and investors.</p>
          <p>As you know, we will start immediately with the Q&amp;A session. Please wait for the microphone. We really need a microphone so that we can all hear you and please also indicate your name before you speak. Okay, Mr. Breitsprecher [Oppenheim Research GmbH], then Mr. Lubinetzki [MainFirst Schweiz AG]. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question concerning Suzuki. What is the effect of the corporation with Suzuki on the plans concerning the UP!? Will the UP! be built together with Suzuki? Might there be a delay in the launch of this family? Could you just tell us more about it?</p>
          <p>Secondly, I have a question concerning compensation of the Board of Management. Will you, in addition to your remuneration as members of the Board of Management of Volkswagen, do you also get a remuneration in your function as members of the managing board of Porsche SE?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Breitsprecher, concerning of the Suzuki and UP!, certainly there were discussions and comparisons between the small Suzuki and the UP! concept, but we decided to complete the UP! according to the plan as planned.</p>
          <p>For the gentlemen Mr. Winterkorn and Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, there will be probably be an additional compensation but the Supervisory Board of Volkswagen AG decided that everything that exceeds 20% of the normal compensation by Volkswagen would have to be offset against it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When we analyze the Q4 figures, there are two things that I find striking. First of all, wholesale in the fourth quarter is significantly above retail and the order of magnitude is approximately 130,000 units. That's more or less the gap or discrepancy. Is it anticipating your expected business in 2010, or why do we have such a difference?</p>
          <p>Secondly, when we look at the development of the gross profit margin in the fourth quarter, then it is unchanged or at the same level as in the third quarter while expenses for sales, financing, or marketing have risen considerably. Could you explain that? Could you explain where this comes from? And also could you explain how we should interpret these figures as we look to the year 2010, what it means for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now first of all concerning your question about wholesale and retail, now our understanding here should be that the worldwide stock value, not only what they carry on our books but this also includes our dealership organization, our trading organization that we have come from or that we had achieved an absolute low, a record low. When you look at the first quarter of 2010, this value no longer corresponded to our definition of what we consider to be an ideal level of stock and inventory. So in other words, it was necessary to start filling the pipeline once again. As soon as the slight recovery in a couple of markets really happens and this is what we expect, this trend will actually continue. We will continue along these lines. So for 2010, you may expect that the level of production will exceed the level of deliveries to customers.</p>
          <p>Concerning the gross margin for 2009, the comparison between the third and the fourth quarter, let me just tell you that the associated expenses as usual of course also includes risk adjustments which I would almost say traditionally has to during the fourth quarter. And you also note that there are certain residual values, which we have to determine and we then also assess the current statistics. And dealer risk is another topic that we have to assess very carefully before we prepare the annual financial statements. So this is certainly a one-off expense, a certain one-off expense which will not be continued in the year 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then let's move over this side and then Mr. Schneider and then Mr. Schwarz from Commerzbank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Horst Schneider from HSBC. I have three questions, first of all a question concerning walk-down 2010. This is a question that I was asking Mr. Stadler. Now pricing, should we get a negative net pricing at the group level or flat pricing or should there be a slightly negative price effect? I think you already said about raw material prices that we don't have to expect any major burdens. But could you just comment on currencies, the influence of currencies, what kind of impact this could mean?</p>
          <p>And cash flow in 2010, you are saying that you don't have ideal stock levels anymore and that restocking or replenishing might have to take place. Does that mean that cash flow in 2010 might be rather on the negative side?</p>
          <p>And the third question goes to Mr. Winterkorn. If I look the overall structure of the group, I find that it is very complex. It has always been very complex, but certainly because of these acquisitions it has become even more complex. Then I read the reports in the newspaper from the last few weeks. I am getting the impression that it's becoming increasingly difficult to manage this complexity. So how can you make sure that you will handle this complexity in the future? Will you have a more decentralized management approach in your organization? And also in this context also, it's not necessarily related to complexity than quality provisions, provisions or accrual for quality. Would that mean that you have to set up more high accruals and provisions for quality in the future for the group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me first of all comment on the questions, Mr. Schneider, relating to the financial issues. I think I can give you a very compact answer. As far as pricing is concerned, we expect a flat or level development. And as far as currencies are concerned, as I said before, a negative effect will occur once again, but on a much smaller scale than in 2009. And as far as net cash flow is concerned, we expect a positive figure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Schneider, I don't know where you see this complexity. Let me first of all say that here on the panel, you see seven members of the Managing Board, not five but seven, so it's a 40% increase. So you have more members on the Managing Board. As far as capacity is concerned, that might be important to realize. I don't think that we have made the structure of the group more complicated. I would rather say that it has become clearer and more transparent.</p>
          <p>And as far as decentralizing or centralizing is concerned, we manage our group according to the same principle of brand. The brand is the brand; the group is the group, and every brand has its own headquarters, its own finance department, its own development, and its own design department. But naturally, all of this then is brought together at a group level be it for the product, the market decisions, of course it all comes together at a group level as well. So I think we are in a very comfortable situation here and my colleagues here on the panel probably would confirm it and I believe Mr. Stadler with his function as CEO of Audi also feels very comfortable and thinks it's a good position.</p>
          <p>Now accruals for quality, now let me be very plain here. The objective is to reduce these accruals of provisions. We expect that the accruals, provisions for quality will become lower. And we've come to a point as far as quality ratings are concerned &#x2013; I'm looking at Mr. Klingler. Some of our dealers are in fact saying we don't have enough warranty work. We don't get enough work under warranty.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me touch very briefly on that subject. I can only confirm it. When I talk to the dealers, to the retailers, I increasingly get the question or they're asking me the question. How can we compensate for the improvement in quality by means of other business? We are working on concepts to compensate for it. But on the other hand, dealers say we are really going in the right direction as far as quality is concerned and this is also confirmed by the studies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Mr. Schwarz?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel Schwarz, Commerzbank. I just have a question about the capital increase. If you do issue convertible bonds, would those funds be envisioned to be 4 billion from the capital increase or is that part of the capital increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me first of all say that people shouldn't misunderstand this. We don't know down to the last dime what the capital increase will be. That's not true, but we did talk about the general order of magnitude, about four. And we therefore think that in view of this four, we could use different instruments. So all in all, we would have something along those lines, about that order of magnitude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Adam?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Adam Hull, WestLB, three questions, firstly on your provisions. When I look at the balance sheet, I see the provisions for sales obligations rose 8.4% last year. In absolute terms, they are at very high level of 11.4 billion. Could you give us a bit of an indication what's going on there? I mean we sorted out these numbers yesterday, but it seems the rest of the business has reported 11% increase in those provisions. Could you just say if there's anything specific there, and whether we should be seeing any cash outflows, particularly relating to that in 2010?</p>
          <p>And secondly on the effects of the scrapping incentives, it's very hard for us from the outside to try and gauge the size of the positive impact. We presume you're making relatively little money on the scrapping cars. But can you just give some indication of is there a risk that the VW brand actually goes into a loss into 2010, or do you think you can maintain the kind of profits you achieved in 2009?</p>
          <p>And then finally on working capital, you had a very big inflow last year. Could you just give us some indication of what you're thinking in terms of possible outflow in 2010? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to begin with the answer about the change in provisioning. Here you really have to see quite simply that there is a series of issues we've got to take into account, and I did in fact already mention some of these. We have dealer risk, residual values, and things like that. And of course the situation we've got there is something that perhaps is not too simple. It won't develop too simply, and we took account of these things in 2009. And of course this did influence our provisioning in that year.</p>
          <p>Now to reiterate, I'd like to say that to a great extent this was a one-off effect. We can't rule out the possibility that with regard to some of these things, for instance residuals, where we believe that in the United States for example, the residual situation is improving. So it's quite possible that we might see improvements in this regard in the foreseeable future. But in any case, we are well prepared for difficult times and this was demonstrated by the fact that we've had a negative impact on our earnings in 2009.</p>
          <p>Now maybe I can answer the question too about working capital right now. Development of working capital 2010, well as you saw 2009, we saw a significant decrease in stocks, more than 6 billion we took out of working capital. I was also saying previously that as far as stocks are concerned, we had reached a certain minimum point, and we believe that in 2010 the group will grow considerably. So in terms of working capital, we will see more capital tied up and not a release of capital for this year, for 2010. However, we're quite confident that we're going to able to improve our performance in terms of results to compensate for that. We'll have positive net cash flow in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the environmental bonus, the Cash for Clunkers program, I would just like to say that last year in Germany &#x2013; but not just in Germany, we benefited from these programs. The group had about 520,000 orders coming in as a result of these programs and we think that the actual additional volume was about 310,000.</p>
          <p>So we're also well prepared for developments after these programs. We have market estimations that we've done for the post-Cash for Clunkers period, and so far they look to be quite correct. And unlike some competitors, we were able to sell higher category vehicles during the Cash for Clunkers program period and we did make good profits here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, you had a question. Okay, it has been answered. Thierry, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's Thierry Huon from Exane BNP Paribas. During the first presentation, you mentioned the fact that you should be able to reduce the loss at SEAT by some comprehensive plan. Could you elaborate a bit on that? What do you intend to do to improve the situation as we should expect Spain to remain a tough market this year? And on the light commercial vehicle side, adjusted for the one-off from within there, you had a severe loss in 2009. What could we expect for 2010 and how would you deal with this situation? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to our plan of our measures, our action plan proceeded well. The foundations have remained the same as they always have been as we define them. We need higher market penetration outside of Spain. And now for 2009 the development of market share in Germany Austria, Switzerland was quite good, also in France. We've got to continue to work on these. There's lots of potential here. And we're working on a plan for Central and Eastern Europe to up our market shares there even further, and one foundation for this is our new models. We began with the Exeo last year, the sedan and the ST. And now we've got the Ibiza ST has been launched, and the Sharan, that will be &#x2013; sorry, sorry. Sharan, that's VW. SEAT is the Alhambra.</p>
          <p>So these are our two pillars: A), higher market penetration in markets we're already represented in today. We really don't have the position there that we would have due to the potential of the brand, that's one. And then two, we're working on our model policy with new models and a broader basis and now new models with the Ibiza family and the Alhambra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I can add one small point about what Mr. Garcia said &#x2013; to what Mr. Garcia said. First of all, it's quite obvious that in view of estimations of market developments in SEAT's core markets, utilization of capacity won't be easy, and that's why we have made the decision to take the Q3, the new Audi small SUV, and build it in Martorell, and that will help us to absorb quite a considerable amount of our fixed costs. And obviously in this situation in terms of cost and investments too we are continuing to focus on these things at SEAT.</p>
          <p>Then with regard to your second question, that was about light commercial vehicles. And if you compare these two things, let me say they're not comparable because SEAT has a problem that markets that we have given SEAT as their task, these markets are in a catastrophic situation to a great extent. In terms of commercial vehicles, we have to say that we've got a typical cyclical problem. Apart from that, the business model is actually okay.</p>
          <p>Commercial customers, however, in 2009 to a great extent ordered very, very few cars, and this is cyclical. As the economy picks back up, that will substantially improve. In addition to that, we've got the new product, the Amarok that we build in Argentina that has been given an outstanding response by the press and actually by customers too, will be delivered soon. And I think that in terms of light commercial vehicles, we won't succeed in getting completely back in the black in 2010. But compared to 2009, the results will be substantially improved. One thing we must not forget is the T5 because that has been given a big facelift, new engines. On the average, they consume 20% less and this will help our Commercial Vehicles division.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John Lawson in the second row, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I'm John Lawson from Citi. Can I first ask about your joint venture operations? It looks like the net income of the joint ventures was around 800 million, which is an impressive number. I guess we've also heard already that China contributed 770 million or so pro rata of the operating income level. So first question, is it reasonable to assume that as they have before that the Chinese joint ventures delivered at least as much at the net level as they did at the operating level?</p>
          <p>Second question relating to your new joint venture, Porsche Zwischenholding, I guess that it has had some sort of first-time effect in the accounts, and I wondered if you could share that with us and also help us understand whether there is any systematic adjustment on PPA which might be required for that new joint venture going forward.</p>
          <p>And then finally, I think Dr. Winterkorn said that there would be a market downturn on markets in Western Europe and Germany. Could we just be clear what number your business plan has worked out on for the European marketplace? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now first of all, the Chinese joint ventures. Now first of all, let me come back to the year 2009. It's approximately 700 million proportionate profit or earnings that we have generated here. And in our financial result, this was recorded as income or profit. And I think there are justifiable expectations here. We have good reasons to expect that in 2010, the amount that we will see here will be even higher. So we expect even more, a higher amount in 2010.</p>
          <p>And at this point, I would like to make another thing clear again, namely that in spite of a fairly comprehensive investment program in China, Dr. Heizmann in the first round of discussions already shared quite a few details with you. So in spite of this investment program, we still hope that the level of payout is going to be very high. That's what we expect for dividend payout. And the dividend payout for the year 2009, which amounted to almost 370 or approximately 370 million, now this dividend payout will increase significantly in the current year. So in China, we still expect or we continue to expect a very positive business development.</p>
          <p>Now Porsche, the topic of Porsche, if I understood your question correctly, first of all, I must say that it's still true that Porsche is the most profitable car maker. And naturally, the level is slightly reduced compared to the times when these segments performed better than at the moment. This segment has seen better times and of course the level is reduced accordingly, but we can also see that in the case of Porsche, in the operating company, we have two-digit return on sales. That's what we are going to achieve in the current fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know how we usually treat our equity stake for investments, and we have the same kind of purchase price allocation at Porsche which then leads to write-down or depreciation. And in fiscal year 2009, this had a negative effect amounting to approximately 70 million. That was a negative effect. This was the amount of write-down or depreciation, and the contribution from operating result was of course a positive one. That's why we assume that these depreciations or write-downs on PPA, on Purchase Price Allocation, will also determine the years 2010 and 2011 will be an important contribution in 2010 and 2011.</p>
          <p>Let me repeat the numbers I gave you in the first round of discussions. In 2009, our write-down on the previously allocated assets was absorbed in our result, amounting to 480 million. Approximately 480 million was absorbed in our result. Also the composition was slightly different because the write-down amount is currently going down, is declining, while the write-down at Porsche has only just begun. And this amount will be approximately on the same level again in 2010. We will have to absorb more or less the same amount. Just to make sure that there is no misunderstanding, of course in our forecasts or in our assessments of future developments, this has been fully taken into account as we take steps to improve our operating profit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now you had a question relating to the markets and development of the markets in Western Europe. In our plan, we are assuming approximately 10% decline overall in Western Europe including Germany for passenger cars and commercial vehicles. This is the decline we expect. But for a couple of weeks we have been observing a slight recovery of the business and the silver lining on the horizon, and we cannot rule out that our previous estimate was too conservative or too pessimistic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine, thank you. Mr. Gehrke, almost at the very back, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jochen Gehrke, Deutsche Bank. I have a question about electric cars. Professor Winterkorn, you said that you, the Volkswagen Group, will be the first to mass-produce these cars. Now could you briefly describe that the business model you're imagining there, in particular with regard to residual values for batteries? What do you think is the best way to tackle this issue, in particular with regards to leasing contracts?</p>
          <p>Then secondly North America, the development in the marketplace there is something that has been having a negative impact on your group for a long time. The pricing environment is much more positive than it has been in the past few years. Do you have an update for us about the breakeven plan? Most recently I understood you to say that in 2012 &#x2013; 2013, you can imagine becoming profitable. Now assuming better market pricing, do you think it might be possible earlier?</p>
          <p>And then last but not least I have a question about the German market. Last year, we saw a major decline in residual values. How is this impacting your dealer loss ratios, in particular with regard to wholesale financing? And then what do you think about pricing in the next few years in view of the petrol competition going on and what do you think about the shakeout in the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the subject of battery technology, electric vehicle technology, and the business about the &#x2013; and the question about the business model we're imagining, we're preparing different business models. I deliberately said that currently costs for batteries are too high. We're still talking about per kilowatt hour 500 to &#x20AC;1,000 per kilowatt hour.</p>
          <p>Now this is a subject we're going to definitely be discussing intensively in the automotive industry together with our partners in politics and with our partners at utility companies. And our cautious assumptions we made demonstrate that we've got to be able to manage the technology, the costs. And we've got to take into account customer behavior. And therefore, it will take &#x2013; it will be a few days before we're going to be able to say what business model will actually be applied. To put one thing very clearly and frankly though, I do not believe that we will be leasing batteries, swapping batteries just like people's underwear. I think that this business environment is too complicated for that.</p>
          <p>I'd like to answer some other questions, financial questions. Mr. Klingler will then tell you about the structures in the market with regard to these questions. But let me first of all say that with regard to residual values, we know that naturally volume developments and incentives really reflect these. And therefore, it was no surprise that we had the low point in the United States very early because the crisis hit the US earliest. In the meantime though, we are seeing a clear improvement there. The market is beginning to normalize over there. And as you know in that market over there, we are in a special position with our vehicles, especially since we have the greatest fuel efficiency with our cars. And naturally in terms of residual values, we haven't been hit as hard as others as a result.</p>
          <p>And we do see that one impact of the Cash for Clunkers programs is that residual values have been coming under pressure in Germany. And in this context, we believe that we're going to have to be patient for a while. But when the market normalizes to a certain extent, residual values will improve too. My point actually is this. We are very conservative. We've prepared very conservatively for possible developments, and this even includes possible programs that would take account of the specific German situation, in which to a certain extent dealers guarantee residuals to ensure that the cars can be marketed in line with market requirements.</p>
          <p>And then with regard to dealers, I'd like to say briefly that we know that the dealers are facing a difficult time now, so we have to expect a certain shakeout. And to answer your financial aspect questions, I can say that. And I'd also like to tell you with regard to my answer about other provisions that we have prepared well for these possible problems. Then I'd like to say, Mr. Klingler, maybe you could add something with regard to market related aspects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me tell you about the fundamental issue of residuals. Last year residuals went down substantially at the end of the year. In many markets they did recover, as we saw, but not just in the US. In the United Kingdom too that happened.</p>
          <p>In Germany, we're at a level of stability to a certain extent. We don't have any higher losses at dealerships, not substantially. That was the question first of all because: A), we acted and reacted really quickly. We did risk management in all countries where it was necessary. Liquidity management, stock management approaches were taken. So I can say very clearly that in this regard, we really can look forward, go ahead without any big losses. And of course, as has been mentioned, we're in a special situation with the dealer network. That's well known; we communicated that. There will be a certain shakeout if you have a dealer network that's prepared for an overall sales level of 4 million and in the future it will be 3.3 &#x2013; 3.4 million vehicles that might happen. But this is being done in collaboration with the dealers and with our dealer councils. So we are on the right track there.</p>
          <p>Then the second question was how we're preparing for the further cutthroat competition, escalating competition in the future. We have the impression that competition today is already quite strong. In many markets, we see that many manufacturers are focusing on liquidity, and we believe that this might be something we could do. We're more cautious with incentives than our competition. And if we do incentives, we ensure that these are incentives campaigns that do not negatively impact residual value, so that later on when the cars are sold, we don't have the residual value problem. We're succeeding in doing that, and we've seen that in the past we've been do that, and we therefore don't have major losses or depreciation of these figures as a result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Mr. Schneider you had a question. Otherwise no one is raising their hand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Horst Schneider, HSBC once again. Now since we've talked about residuals so much, and Mr. P&#xF6;tsch, you said you made provisions for that, maybe you can give us some figures on how high your provisioning is for lower residual values and dealer risks in 2009. How high were those? And then secondly with regard to net cash flow, you didn't use the definition of free cash flow, but in net cash flow you're not including the capital increase probably. I just want to make sure I understand that correctly. I can imagine what you mean, but I want to ask that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll begin with that. That wasn't of course included in the definition. So let me cover a couple of things at once, residual values and dealers and a few other subjects too. As I said previously, we have made provisions for these and that's close to 1 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Schneider once again and then we go to one of the ones farther in the back of this room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how much of this 1 billion in Q4, could you say that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I forgot this figure. Really I don't know the figure. Sorry, it doesn't come to my mind now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now let's move over to the left hand side. I can see some hands here. Or does anybody still have a question? We are at your disposal if you have questions but I believe that we have given you information &#x2013; Adam Hull, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two things, I'm just wondering. You're potential R&amp;D spending, last year you did 5.8 billion. Could you give us some guidance for the next two, three years or so? And then secondly on the question I asked earlier on the VW brand, obviously there has been a big impact positive on the scrapping side; could you just give us a little bit more of a handle for the scale of the benefits? And really thinking about 2010, is it feasible that division goes into loss or do you think you can maintain the profits you had in 2009? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, the answer to the question how much we spend, how much the cash spending is, we said that as far as investments are concerned, 6%. We want to stick to the 6% level for CapEx.</p>
          <p>And the second major issue, namely the research and development expenses, we would like to more or less spend or maintain our spending at the same level as in previous years. We will leave that more or less unchanged. Now light commercial vehicles, I think I already said something about light commercial vehicles before, namely that we definitely want to improve in 2010, but we do not believe that we can actually break even.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The question was &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; the question was on VW brand and not on the commercial vehicle, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now for Volkswagen passenger cars, I would like to repeat as I said before. In 2010 we will see a significant improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is one last question and we are happy to take it, John Buckland.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>John Buckland, MF Global. To get some further clarification because maybe the translation didn't come through properly through my headset, on the capital increase, does the amount of money that you will raise through the convertible bonds, is that included in the more than 4 billion or is it in addition to the more than 4 billion? In other words, will the capital increase excluding convertible be more than 4 billion?</p>
          <p>And then on the timing, it had been said by member of the Supervisory Board that March would be a good year &#x2013; a good time for the rights issue. But in your speech this morning, you said it would happen in the first half. Does that mean that maybe March isn't a good time for the rights issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, first of all once again on that question of the capital increase, I want to say this once again very clearly. Around 4 billion, this is the order of magnitude. Or the capital increase will be around 4 billion and we will have this capital increase in order to strengthen our capital base. And for this purpose possibly not only a capital increase, but other measures, additional measures might be used. For instance an issue of convertible bonds, that is a possibility. So the formula I would suggest is all included, so it's an all-inclusive approach.</p>
          <p>Second question, yes, there were couple of comments according to which this capital increase was to take place in March. That was suggested, but let me tell you that nothing definite has been decided yet. No definite resolution has been taken yet. We will do it whenever the timing is best for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. Thank you for participating. Thank you for your questions. We still have some time left before the factory tour. If you want to have a cup of coffee or some cake, we can continue our talk. Otherwise all those of you who would like to participate in the factory tour, please make sure that at half past two or 2:45 at the latest you are at the welcome desk because from there, there will be shuttle to the factory tour. So thank you very much and I wish you all a safe trip home.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>